<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:48:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/please-forgive-me-elon-musk-after-billionaire-vinod-khosla-demands-apology-for-spreading-false-claims-6646580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Reacts After Vinod Khosla Demands Apology For Spreading False Claims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/please-forgive-me-elon-musk-after-billionaire-vinod-khosla-demands-apology-for-spreading-false-claims-6646580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:09:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prominent Indian-American businessman Vinod Khosla and billionaire Elon Musk had a public war of words over a land battle in California and an allegedly altered image of a sign on a beach.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prominent Indian-American businessman Vinod Khosla and billionaire Elon Musk had a public war of words over a land battle in California and an allegedly altered image of a sign on a beach. It all started after Elon Musk posted a seemingly AI-generated picture of a beach sign that read "No plebs allowed. Property of Vinod Khosla" - a reference to a 16-year-long legal battle Mr Khosla has undertaken to restrict the use of his private property to access the public Martins Beach, <em>Forbes </em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sharing the image on X on Saturday, Mr Musk claimed that Mr Khosla had put it up on his property. However, the billionaire venture capitalist vehemently denied putting up any such sign and demanded an apology from Mr Musk after his "lie" resulted in negative press for him. "You owe me an apology for spreading falsehoods. I think this post of yours needs a community comment for being a fraudulent photo. I have never put up this sign or anything even remotely like this. I presume it is AI generated but you can verify that," wrote Mr Khosla.&nbsp;</p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Musk then responded to Mr Khosla in his trademark style. "Sorry, I made a sign about you restricting access to a public beach. That was so extremely terrible. Please forgive me," the billionaire wrote.</p>

<p><strong>Take a look below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sorry I made a sign about you restricting access to a public beach.<br />
<br />
That was so extremely terrible.<br />
<br />
Please forgive me ?</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1837969224532480175?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Notably, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/maryroeloffs/2024/09/23/billionaire-vinod-khosla-demands-apology-after-elon-musk-slams-him-on-x-the-feud-explained/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Forbes</em></a>, Mr Khosla bought a piece of land in 2008 that previously served as a paid parking lot for Martins Beach south of San Francisco. Mr Khosla has said he no longer wants the privately owned property to be publicly accessible and has been battling with the state over the issue for almost two decades, including a rejected appeal to the Supreme Court in 2018.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-on-viral-picture-with-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-goes-viral-6644695">Is Musk "Dating" Meloni? What He Said On Viral Pic With Italy PM</a></strong></p>

<p>Elon Musk, however, used this issue to fuel a longstanding dispute between the pair that has seen them trade barbs over the 2024 election, the development of artificial intelligence and immigration issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Previously, the two have also publicly argued about ChatGPT parent OpenAI. Mr Khosla has also called a conversation between Mr Musk and Donald Trump "dumb". Mr Musk, on the other hand, claimed Mr Khosla was "deranged about Trump". The billionaires even sparred on X over Mr Trump's false claims about Haitian immigrants.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8sbhru18_vinod-khosla-elon-musk_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Khosla bought the piece of land in 2008.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-tragic-tale-of-2-west-bank-teenagers-freed-in-gaza-truce-6646578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Tragic Tale Of 2 West Bank Teenagers Freed In Gaza Truce]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-tragic-tale-of-2-west-bank-teenagers-freed-in-gaza-truce-6646578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 16:08:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Newly freed from an Israeli prison, Wael Masha rode atop friends' shoulders through the streets of his West Bank refugee camp before bursting into his home to kiss his mother's feet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Newly freed from an Israeli prison, Wael Masha rode atop friends' shoulders through the streets of his West Bank refugee camp before bursting into his home to kiss his mother's feet.</p>

<p>Less than a year later, those friends carried the 18-year-old's body through the same streets after Israeli forces killed him in an air strike, describing him as an armed militant who posed a threat to Israeli forces.</p>

<p>His journey was not unique: Masha is one of at least three Palestinians born in the Israeli-occupied West Bank who were arrested as teenagers, released during a brief truce in the Gaza war last November, then killed in intensifying Israeli military operations in the territory.</p>

<p>Israel says its raids and air strikes in the West Bank, which it has occupied since 1967, reflect the scope of the security threat it faces from Palestinian combatants.</p>

<p>His family and others like them say Israel is fuelling the problem it claims to be fighting, arresting young men -- Masha was 17 when he was taken into custody -- then abusing them in custody, ultimately driving them to seek revenge.</p>

<p>What is not in dispute is that Masha embraced "jihad" after his release, and knew where it would lead.</p>

<p>In his will, he instructed his mother: "When you hear the news of my martyrdom, God willing, do not cry, but ululate."</p>

<p>While some memorial posters show Masha brandishing an automatic weapon, his mother remembers him differently.</p>

<p>"He loved studying and repairing computers and mobile phones," Hanadi Masha told AFP in the family home in Balata refugee camp, east of Nablus, surrounded by pictures of her smiling son.</p>

<p>Perhaps this interest could have turned into a career, she added.</p>

<p>But "after he got out of prison, he had a grudge because of everything he saw inside".</p>

<h2><strong>'SHOCK' BEHIND BARS</strong></h2>

<p>The fallout from the nearly year-old war in Gaza has reverberated across the West Bank, where the health ministry says at least 680 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli forces and settlers since Hamas's October 7 attack.</p>

<p>Israeli officials say 24 Israelis, including troops, have been killed in Palestinian attacks during the same period.</p>

<p>Even before the war, Israeli round-ups of Palestinian men were common, including the one in November 2022 in which Masha was detained.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Prisoners' Club advocacy group says there are at least 250 Palestinians under the age of 18 currently in Israeli custody.</p>

<p>"The occupation does not hesitate to arrest children under 18 years old... The widespread arrests have nothing to do with any armed action," said Hilmi al-Araj of the Palestinian civil society group Hurryyat.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities took Masha to Megiddo prison in northern Israel and sentenced him to two and a half years on charges they never disclosed to his family.</p>

<p>His surprise release came during a weeklong truce in Gaza in November 2023, the only one of the war so far, during which Palestinian militants released 105 hostages seized on October 7, the Israelis among them in exchange for 240 Palestinians held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Once out, Masha recounted a host of abuses: being instructed to kiss the Israeli flag, being burned with cigarette butts.</p>

<p>His father Bilal said the experience was "a huge shock" that "changed things completely" for him.</p>

<p>"My son entered as a cub and came out as a lion," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>'PRIME OF LIFE'</strong></h3>

<p>Israel has not explained the precise circumstances of Masha's death, and his parents say they do not know what he was doing when an Israeli strike killed him on August 15.</p>

<p>They only know that the day before the strike Masha said he received a threatening phone call from an Israeli officer warning: "It's your turn."</p>

<p>The details are clearer for Tariq Daoud, a second Palestinian teenager who was detained with Masha and released on the same day of the November truce.</p>

<p>Like Masha, Daoud said he was beaten at Megiddo prison, his brother Khaled told AFP at the family home in Qalqilyah, where children wear necklaces featuring his face.</p>

<p>Khaled said the abuse produced false confessions from Tariq -- aged 16 when he was arrested -- on charges including possessing an illegal firearm and attempting to build explosives.</p>

<p>Incarceration "shattered all his ambitions", which had included potentially becoming an engineer or a doctor, Khaled said.</p>

<p>Instead he joined Hamas's armed wing.</p>

<p>In the same week that Masha was killed, Tariq opened fire on an Israeli settler in Azzun, east of Qalqilyah, and Israeli troops shot him dead at the scene, both Khaled and the Israeli military said.</p>

<p>Israeli officials have not yet released his body, but Khaled still visits his plot at the Qalqilyah cemetery every day to water the flowers.</p>

<p>"I go because I feel that there is something of his presence," Khaled said.</p>

<p>Back in the Balata camp, Masha's mother Hanadi has found her own ways to honour her son, talking about him with his four younger siblings and stroking pictures of his beard -- just like she playfully greeted him when he was alive.</p>

<p>Shortly after Masha's death, the institute where he had been taking classes told her he had been awarded certificates in mobile phone repair and cybersecurity.</p>

<p>His mother attended the graduation ceremony on his behalf.</p>

<p>"He was a young man in the prime of life," she told AFP through tears.</p>

<p>His time behind bars "planted the idea of resistance in his head."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/npv1cr14_gaza-truce-tragic-tale-of-two-teenagers-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The family of Wael Masha, 18, killed in an Israeli airstrike on the Balata camp on August 15.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mit-students-disrupt-israeli-professors-talk-steal-pizza-in-bizarre-protest-6646463]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[MIT Students Disrupt Israeli Professor's Talk, Steal Pizza in Bizarre Protest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mit-students-disrupt-israeli-professors-talk-steal-pizza-in-bizarre-protest-6646463]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:50:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The professor expressed frustration, stating that "facts don't matter to them" and that the students were reciting pre-determined statements rather than engaging with his actual account.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of students at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) interrupted an Israeli professor, Shahar Kvatinsky's lecture with an odd protest that included pizza stealing and war criminal claims.</p>

<p>Kvatinsky, a visiting lecturer at the University of Toronto, was discussing his experiences as an Israel Defence Forces (IDF) reservist officer in Gaza after the October 7th tragedy at an event organised by the MIT Israel Alliance. He described the Israeli military's stringent rules of engagement and related stories of discovering weapons hidden in residential buildings.</p>

<p>The normally uneventful lecture took an odd turn, though, when one student quietly left the room, taking four pizza boxes meant for the audience. This student, along with others, berated Kvatinsky during Q&amp;A, outlining charges of war crimes and calling him a "murderer." Other students did the same, citing reports of IDF soldiers raping women that had already been proven false.</p>

<p>With increasing frustration, Kvatinsky stated that "facts don't matter to them" and that the students weren't really listening to his explanation but were only reciting prepared lines.</p>

<p>Only more mayhem ensued as two more students stole five more pizzas and fled the room, and a third student pulled out a sign that said, "MIT Jews oppose genocide," as he was leaving the lecture.</p>

<p>Will Sussman, an MIT computer science student who attended the event, posted on social media about the event.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I won't repeat everything the anti-Israel students said to tonight's guest speaker at <a href="https://twitter.com/MIT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MIT</a>, Prof. Shahar <a href="https://twitter.com/kvatinsky?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Kvatinsky</a>. But there's one thing I can't stop thinking about:<br />
<br />
They took nine pizzas.<br />
<br />
First a student took four pizzas, left, and came back to call the veteran professor a… <a href="https://t.co/3Kuy0BppuJ">pic.twitter.com/3Kuy0BppuJ</a></p>
— Will Sussman (@WillSussmanPhD) <a href="https://twitter.com/WillSussmanPhD/status/1836616151058518080?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>There's one thing I can't stop thinking about: the protesting students took nine pizzas, said Will Sussman.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n2kqc77g_antiisrael-students-at-mit_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-Israel students at MIT disrupted a lecture by an Israeli professor.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-us-keeps-accusing-russia-of-meddling-in-its-elections-6646409]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: The Real Reason US Keeps Accusing Russia Of Meddling In Its Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-us-keeps-accusing-russia-of-meddling-in-its-elections-6646409]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:45:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The truth is that the ongoing allegations and counter-allegations of election interference are just one front in a larger information war between the West and Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mccprka_us-russia_625x300_25_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Earlier this month, the US administration sounded the alarm on Russia's alleged attempts to sway the upcoming presidential election through fake accounts spreading propaganda and disinformation. In the US, the move is understood to be Russia's broader strategy to undermine American democracy, with US intelligence officials labelling Moscow as the "primary threat to elections".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is also investigating Iran's involvement in targeting the presidential campaigns of Donald Trump and Kamala Harris. However, US officials assert that Russia is the more formidable foe, with a clear preference for Donald Trump as their candidate of choice. The US government has seized 32 internet domains connected to the influencers, who were allegedly paid by Moscow to spread fake news. It has also sanctioned 10 individuals and two entities allegedly linked to these efforts&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Russia Facing Allegations Since 2016</strong></h2>

<p>This is the third consecutive presidential election in which American officials have accused Russia and President Vladimir Putin of attempting to influence outcomes. It was a huge issue during the 2016 election too. The FBI still lists 12 Russian military officers as "most wanted" for their role in hacking and meddling in that election. These officers, members of Russian military intelligence, were indicted by Special Counsel Robert Mueller's team in 2018. The indictments allege that they hacked Democratic Party emails and systems and leaked information to influence the election in favour of Donald Trump. Subsequently, hundreds of documents were leaked to Wikileaks. A federal arrest warrant was issued for these 12 officers after a grand jury in a US District Court found them responsible for conspiracy to interfere with the election. Their presence on the FBI's "most wanted" list underscores the ongoing tensions between the US and Russia regarding election interference and cyber-espionage.</p>

<p>Moscow has consistently refuted these allegations, with President Vladimir Putin personally denying the claims in various interviews and press conferences. Even Donald Trump came to Putin's defence, as he once told reporters, "He [Putin] said he didn't meddle. Every time he sees me he says, 'I didn't do that', and I really believe that when he tells me that he means it."</p>

<h2><strong>Western Hypocrisy</strong></h2>

<p>The Kremlin accuses the US and other Western powers of hypocrisy, citing numerous examples across decades in which America was accused of meddling in the elections of so many countries. Indeed, the West - particularly the US - has a long-standing track record of influencing elections, backing military coups, providing covert financial support and disseminating political propaganda in foreign countries to advance its own geopolitical interests. The Central Intelligence Agency's (CIA) long history of alleged involvement in elections and regime changes in other countries is well-documented, with many declassified documents serving as evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prof Dov H. Levin's research for Carnegie-Mellon University involved looking at the election meddling by both the US and the Soviet Union during the Cold War. He claims that both countries were found to have interfered in 117 elections between WWll and 2000; the US was involved in two-thirds of them. According to him, in more recent times, 21 election interventions took place between 1990 and 2000, of which 18 were by the US. The alleged meddling by the USSR (later Russia) remained shrouded in secrecy, while the US had been more transparent in some cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The declassified CIA documents highlight the role of US operations in the overthrow of Iran's Mohammed Mossadegh's government in 1953, Chile's Salvador Allende in 1973, and, more recently, its efforts towards regime changes in Venezuela as well as in Ukraine in 2014, when the pro-Russian President Viktor Yanukovych's government was overthrown.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the most recent example, Sheikh Hasina, after resigning from office on August 5 and fleeing the country, &nbsp;suggested that the US had a hand in her political downfall. This wasn't the first time she had made such claims - in 2022, she had accused the US of attempting to undermine her rule. Her allegations have been echoed by some non-Western leaders, who accuse the US and other powerful nations, such as France and Britain, of using their influence to destabilise their governments.</p>

<h2><strong>Propaganda And Fake News</strong></h2>

<p>The truth is that the ongoing allegations and counter-allegations of election interference are just one front in a larger information war between the West and Russia. It's a battle of narratives, with Western media largely backing the West and Russian media championing Putin's perspective. Interestingly, Russian media has historically been dismissed by the West because of the Kremlin''s tight control over it. But the Western media, long proud of its impartiality, faces accusations of spreading propaganda and even fake news to further Western interests. For example, a few weeks after Russia's invasion of Ukraine, the Western media carried fake news about Putin's health. It suggested Putin was suffering from a mystery illness and may not survive for long. All mainstream Western media carried this lie. And no apologies were offered when it was found to be unfounded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Janusz Bugajski, a renowned expert on Eastern European and Russian affairs and author of many scholarly books, is a senior fellow at the Jamestown Foundation in Washington, D.C. Following Russia's invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, Bugajski wrote a book titled Failed State: A Guide to Russia's Rupture. In that, he explored the potential disintegration of Russia. Last year, he told me that the Russian Federation's disintegration was inevitable. "I would say it would be a long process, a rolling process, it would be different in different parts of the country. I would say the war in Ukraine would certainly accelerate the process because you have an increasing number of casualties, particularly from poorer parts of Russia and particularly from ethnic parts of Russia who are usually discriminated against in Russia anyway," he said. Many in the West buy into his claim. Putin has often moaned about how the West was working to break up his country.</p>

<h2><strong>No One Is Equipped To Challenge Western Media's Dominance</strong></h2>

<p>In the ongoing information war, Russia appears to be at a disadvantage, with many believing it's already losing or will ultimately lose. This perspective is rooted in history, as Western media has consistently dominated the narrative, often to the detriment of regional media outlets.</p>

<p>Consider the example of the 2003 invasion of Iraq, where Western media spread the now-infamous claim that Saddam Hussein possessed Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD). Despite the lack of evidence, this narrative persisted, and regional media, including Al Jazeera Arabic (Al Jazeera English came into being in 2006), struggled to counter the misinformation. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This phenomenon isn't isolated to the Middle East. Dutch Investigative journalist Bette Dam, whose work focuses on Afghanistan and how the Western media reported on the conflict, argues that Western media often promotes war by presenting one-sided stories, failing to explore underlying reasons for conflicts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the Cold War, Western media played a key role in promoting narratives that aligned with its governments' anti-communist stances. Media outlets were used as instruments of soft power, designed to promote liberal democratic values and present the Soviet bloc as an ideological enemy. These strategies were openly acknowledged by governments, often justified as necessary to counter Soviet disinformation.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The West-East Flow</strong></h2>

<p>Historically, ever since professional journalism came into being, the flow of information and news has always happened from the West to the East. It is the Western media that consistently shapes the narrative and influences public opinion by setting the global agenda every day. Of course, there are now disruptions to this flow, but countering the Western media narrative has proven hard. This dominance was evident, say, in the difference in coverage of the January 2014 attacks in France and Nigeria, where the former received extensive international attention while the latter was largely overlooked. The Westernisation of media perpetuates cultural imperialism, spreading Western ideals and values.</p>

<p>Ultimately, many people, especially young, have lost trust in mainstream media and have been switching over to social platforms to get their news and other information, including about the latest allegations and counter-allegations for election meddling in the US. This erosion of trust should be a wake-up call for traditional Western media.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/e3o9vh8o_us-russia_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapores-population-surges-crosses-6-million-mark-for-1st-time-ever-6642985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore's Population Surges - Crosses 6 Million-Mark For 1st Time Ever]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/singapores-population-surges-crosses-6-million-mark-for-1st-time-ever-6642985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:39:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Singapore's population has reached a record high of 6.04 million, rising two per cent from last year, as the manpower-constrained city-state took in more foreign workers, according to an official report.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singapore's population has reached a record high of 6.04 million, rising two per cent from last year, as the manpower-constrained city-state took in more foreign workers, according to an official report.</p>

<p>The figure was released on Tuesday by the Prime Minister's Office (PMO) in the annual Population in Brief report by the National Population and Talent Division.</p>

<p>The population figure has crossed the six million mark for the first time in Singapore's history.</p>

<p>Of the 6.04 million people in the city-state as of June 2024, there were 4.18 million residents and about 1.86 million non-residents, which comprise the foreign workforce, migrant domestic workers, dependants and international students.</p>

<p>According to the report, the non-resident population jumped by about 5 per cent from last year.</p>

<p>The increase was seen across most 'work pass' types, with work permit holders contributing most to the rise (44 per cent of the non-resident population), followed by migrant domestic workers (15 per cent of the non-resident population).</p>

<p>"The (non-resident) population is diverse, and its size and composition fluctuate depending on our economic and social needs," Channel News Asia reported, citing the report.</p>

<p>"As Singapore is fundamentally labour constrained, the foreign workforce complements our local workforce and allows companies to access a broader range of skills from the global labour pool," said the report.</p>

<p>It also reiterated that Singapore's total population is likely to be "significantly" below 6.9 million by 2030, referring to a figure included in a Population White Paper released in 2013.</p>

<p>The NPTD of the Prime Minister's Office had said in the white paper that the city-state's total population could range between 6.5-6.9 million by 2030. This sparked a public outcry, after which the government clarified the figure was not a forecast or target but for planning purposes.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/89bmn648_singapore-generic-singapore-skyline-generic-pixabay_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Singapore's population has reached a record high of 6.04 million, rising 2% from last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/even-a-squirrel-meryl-streep-on-womens-rights-in-afghanistan-6646241]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Even A Squirrel...": Meryl Streep On Women's Rights In Afghanistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/even-a-squirrel-meryl-streep-on-womens-rights-in-afghanistan-6646241]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:26:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American actor Meryl Streep has said a "squirrel has more rights" than a girl in Afghanistan, adding her voice to a call by Afghan women to end the Taliban government's severe restrictions on their lives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American actor Meryl Streep has said a "squirrel has more rights" than a girl in Afghanistan, adding her voice to a call by Afghan women to end the Taliban government's severe restrictions on their lives.</p>

<p>Taliban authorities have implemented an austere interpretation of Islamic law since returning to power in Afghanistan in August 2021 following the withdrawal of US-led forces.</p>

<p>Women and girls have borne the brunt of restrictions -- including being barred from public parks, universities and singing in public -- which the United Nations has labelled "gender apartheid".</p>

<p>"A squirrel has more rights than a girl in Afghanistan today because the public parks have been closed to women and girls by the Taliban," Ms Streep said on Monday during a discussion on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly in New York.</p>

<p>"A bird may sing in Kabul, but a girl may not, and a woman may not in public," the Oscar-winning actor said.</p>

<p>"I feel that the international community as a whole, if they came together, could affect change in Afghanistan, and stop the slow suffocation of an entire half (of) the population."</p>

<p>The Taliban government, which is yet to be recognised by any other country, published a widely criticised law in August further tightening restrictions on women's lives.</p>

<p>While many of the measures had been informally enforced since the Taliban's takeover in 2021, their formal codification sparked an outcry from the international community and rights groups.</p>

<p>The "vice and virtue" law dictates that a woman's voice should not be raised outside the home and that women should not sing or read poetry aloud.</p>

<p>It requires them to cover their entire body and face if they need to leave their homes, which they should only do "out of necessity".</p>

<p>Asila Wardak, a leader of the Women's Forum on Afghanistan, said at the UN discussion Afghan women were there to remind world leaders that "this fight is not only an Afghan fight" but "a global fight against extremism."</p>

<p>Speaking about the situation of Afghan women during the General Assembly this week was "a small sign of hope" for them, said Fawzia Koofi, a former member of parliament in Kabul.</p>

<p>"But it's not enough," she said, calling for the appointment of a UN special envoy to put pressure on the Taliban government.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said that discrimination against women was causing major damage to Afghanistan.</p>

<p>"Educating girls is one of the fastest ways to kick-start economic development and improve the health, well-being and prosperity of communities and entire societies," Guterres said.</p>

<p>"Women's participation and leadership has proven benefits for peace and security, social protection, environmental stability and more," he said.</p>

<p>"Afghanistan faces serious challenges in all these areas."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/bcqn5k4_meryl-streep_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Streep made the comments during a discussion on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-sri-lankas-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-has-called-for-a-snap-general-election-5-facts-6646125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Sri Lanka's President Has Called For A Snap General Election - 5 Facts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-sri-lankas-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-has-called-for-a-snap-general-election-5-facts-6646125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 15:11:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka will hold a parliamentary election on November 14, the government announced on Tuesday, less than two months after the island nation elected Anura Kumara Dissanayake as its new President.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">
	<p><strong>RIDE MOMENTUM</strong><br />
	<br />
	Dissanayake polled 5.6 million votes, or 42.3%, in Saturday's poll, a massive boost to the 3% he managed in the last presidential election in 2019. His nearest rival, opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, won 32.8%.<br />
	<br />
	The Marxist-leaning leader will hope to ride the same wave of approval and consolidate power in the 225-seat parliament.</p>
	</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>SUPPORT FROM PARLIAMENT </strong><br />
	<br />
	Dissanayake ran as a candidate for the National People's Power alliance, which includes his Janatha Vimukhti Peremuna (JVP) party. The coalition held just three seats in the current parliament elected in August 2020, prompting the new president to dissolve the legislature to try to strengthen his hand.<br />
	<br />
	Despite his executive powers as president, fulfilling his pro-poor campaign promises of reducing taxes and freeing up public revenue for tax relief and investment will prove difficult without backing from parliament.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>IMF PROGRAMME</strong><br />
	<br />
	A four-year, $2.9 billion IMF bailout programme has helped Sri Lanka boost reserves, stem a fall in its currency and tame runaway inflation to kickstart a tentative economic recovery. But the austerity measures linked to the bailout angered many, who have pinned hopes of a better future on their next leader.<br />
	<br />
	During campaigning, Dissanayake said he wanted to slash taxes and revisit the terms of the IMF bailout, promising to bring change for those reeling under the austerity measures. But passing a budget will be hard without support in parliament.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>DEBT REWORK </strong><br />
	<br />
	Sri Lanka is in the middle of restructuring about $25 billion foreign debt. Getting parliamentary support will strengthen Dissanayake's hand in negotiations with bondholders, who may in turn find policy clarity from the new president reassuring.<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><strong>CABINET NUMBERS </strong><br />
	<br />
	The lack of numbers in parliament has also meant that Dissanayake was unable to name a fully-fledged cabinet of ministers after taking office on Monday.<br />
	<br />
	He named Harini Amarasuriya as prime minister with five portfolios, while Vijitha Herath was given charge of six ministries, including foreign affairs. Dissanayake kept key ministries such finance, defence and energy to run himself.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/l3h650gk_sri-lanka-parliament-dissolved-reuters_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka will hold a general election on November 14 after the new President dissolved Parliament.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quite-a-stir-strange-fish-with-alien-features-found-on-us-beach-6646003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Quite a Stir": Strange Fish With Alien Features Found On US Beach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/quite-a-stir-strange-fish-with-alien-features-found-on-us-beach-6646003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:56:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 6.9-foot-long ocean sunfish (Mola mola) was recently discovered on an Oregon beach, sparking interest from locals and experts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A gigantic ocean sunfish measuring 6.9 feet in length was spotted along the shores of Hug Point State Park in Arch Cape, Oregon. The creature, commonly known as a Mola Mola, caught the attention of local aquatic experts and stirred interest among beachgoers.</p>

<p>A local institution, the Seaside Aquarium, posted pictures of the dead sunfish on its Facebook page, saying it was unusually big and caused a lot of attention. While an average is to be considered at 6.9 feet, Mola mola can really go up to an astonishing 10 feet in length and weigh up to 5,000 pounds. This giant sunfish is but one example of the rich and diverse marine life existing off the coast of Oregon.</p>

<p>"Another Mola Mola has washed ashore at Hug Point State Park, and it is creating quite a stir. While it has been dead for quite some time, it is still an interesting site. If you want to go see it, we recommend heading to Huge Point at low tide and head north towards the waterfall. Three sunfish have washed ashore since June in Clatsop County. Two were ocean sunfish (Mola mola), and the other one was a hoodwinker sunfish (Mola tecta)," wrote Seaside Aquarium on Facebook.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="767" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FSeasideAquarium%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0nCFoZJnDb3efVT9sfPFXemnYkiYk8f6fbvwmmQahaM8EdPwm9JMSAHBRuB3tCCMpl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>"It is not unusual for these guys to wash ashore, as they do reside off the Oregon Coast. We are getting more reports because of the stir that the Mola tecta caused when it washed in (it was the first Mola tecta documented in Oregon, but that is likely because it has just recently been described and designated as a new species). People are aware that we are interested in documenting these strandings and collecting information from them.</p>

<p>The most recent sunfish at Hug Point was 6.9 feet long, which is average size for our area; however, they can get up to 10 feet long and weigh up to 5,000 pounds. They feed heavily on jellyfish, which are in huge abundance this time of year," the institution added.</p>

<p>The Seaside Aquarium shared images of the sunfish, showing its grey, wrinkled body in a state of decay. This marks the third sunfish to wash ashore in Clatsop County since June.</p>

<p>One of the previous sunfish discoveries, a hoodwinker sunfish, was spotted in June. This 7.3-foot-long creature, also known as a Mola tecta, is a relatively new species, only identified in the past decade. The June discovery was believed to be one of the largest hoodwinker sunfish ever observed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/guo7sj5g_seaside-aquarium_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Seaside Aquarium shared pictures of the dead fish on Facebook.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-the-axis-of-resistance-can-it-challenge-israel-military-power-6645992]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is the Axis of Resistance? Can It Challenge Israel's Military Power?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-the-axis-of-resistance-can-it-challenge-israel-military-power-6645992]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:54:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 558 people have been killed across southern Lebanon following Israel's largest aerial offensive against Hezbollah since the onset of the Gaza war on October 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">At least 558 people have been killed across southern Lebanon following Israel's largest aerial offensive against Hezbollah since the onset of the Gaza war on October 7. The Lebanese health ministry reported that around 1,650 have been wounded, with nearly 100 women and children among the dead. Meanwhile, Gaza faces a deepening humanitarian crisis as relentless Israeli airstrikes have killed over 40,000 Palestinians and displaced nearly the entire population.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">At the heart of this conflict lies the <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-palestine-gaza-explained-axis-of-resistance-and-irans-proxy-network-across-middle-east-4534061 ">Axis of Resistance</a>, an informal alliance of state and non-state actors united against Western influence and Israeli aggression&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>What is the Axis of Resistance?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">The Axis of Resistance is a coalition led by Iran. It includes various militant groups and political organisations like Hezbollah in Lebanon, Syria's Assad regime, Hamas in Gaza and the Houthis in Yemen. These groups, backed by Iran's military expertise and financial resources, have intensified their opposition to Israeli actions, especially since the war in Gaza escalated after last October.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Iran's primary tool in coordinating these forces is the Quds Force, a division of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), which is responsible for conducting covert operations and supporting militant groups across the region. Iran uses this network to solidify its influence and confront Israel and Western allies in the Middle East.</p>

<p dir="ltr">On multiple occasions, Yemen's Houthi movement, which has aligned itself with Iran and Hezbollah, have claimed responsibility for launching missiles and drones towards Israel. Yemen's Defence Minister Mohamed Nasser Al-Atifi recently declared that the Houthis were prepared to continue targeting Israeli forces after the Jewish state's attack on Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Iran has methodically built this alliance over decades. It has long been accused of providing financial aid and military training to various factions within the Axis, especially Hezbollah and Hamas. According to US estimates, Iran provides around $700 million annually to Hezbollah and over $100 million to Palestinian groups, including Hamas and Islamic Jihad.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Can the Axis of Resistance challenge Israel?</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">The Axis of Resistance presents a significant military and ideological challenge to Israel. The country's military capabilities, backed by the US and advanced defence technology like the Iron Dome, give it a substantial advantage in terms of firepower and defence systems.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Groups like Hezbollah and Hamas, meanwhile, rely on asymmetric warfare, using rocket attacks, guerilla tactics and underground networks to combat Israel's superior conventional military strength.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In Lebanon, Hezbollah remains Israel's primary concern due to its proximity and large arsenal. A full-scale war between Hezbollah and Israel would likely be devastating for both sides, as Hezbollah's rockets could overwhelm Israeli defences, while Israeli airpower could inflict severe damage on Lebanon.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In Gaza, Hamas continues its resistance, despite heavy Israeli bombardment. The humanitarian crisis in Gaza is deepening, with over thousand Palestinians reportedly killed and lakhs displaced since the conflict began.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0dre2om4_lebanon-israel-attack_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-man-jailed-for-30-years-for-criticising-government-on-social-media-report-6645859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Saudi Man Jailed For 30 years For Criticising Government On Social Media]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/saudi-man-jailed-for-30-years-for-criticising-government-on-social-media-report-6645859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:39:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Saudi court sentenced a retired teacher to 30 years' jail for criticising the government on social media, less than two months after his death sentence was overturned, his brother said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Saudi court sentenced a retired teacher to 30 years' jail for criticising the government on social media, less than two months after his death sentence was overturned, his brother said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The death sentence against Mohammed al-Ghamdi highlighted what critics describe as heightened repression under Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, the Gulf kingdom's de facto ruler.</p>

<p>Prince Mohammed addressed the case in an interview with Fox News that aired in September 2023, saying the government was "ashamed" over it and expressing hope the outcome could be changed.</p>

<p>Ghamdi's death sentence was overturned on appeal in August.</p>

<p>But the appeals court sentenced him to 30 years imprisonment on the same charges, his brother Saeed al-Ghamdi, an Islamic scholar who lives in Britain, told AFP.</p>

<p>Mohammed al-Ghamdi had been sentenced to death in July 2023 by the Specialised Criminal Court, which was set up in 2008 to deal with terrorism-related cases.</p>

<p>The former teacher, who is in his 50s, was arrested in June 2022.</p>

<p>The case against him was at least partly built on posts criticising the government and expressing support for "prisoners of conscience" like the jailed religious clerics Salman al-Awda and Awad al-Qarni, his brother has previously said.</p>

<p>His account on social media platform X had only nine followers, the Gulf Centre for Human Rights said when his legal troubles came to light last year.</p>

<p>The charges he faced included conspiracy against the Saudi leadership, undermining state institutions and supporting terrorist ideology, sources briefed on the details said at the time.</p>

<p>"This about-face in judgements testifies to the dramatic state of the kingdom's politicised judicial system," Saeed al-Ghamdi said on X.</p>

<p>"My brother is not guilty to be arrested and tried in this way," he added.</p>

<p>The Saudi authorities could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch and Saeed al-Ghamdi reported last month that another brother, 47-year-old Asaad al-Ghamdi, had been sentenced to 20 years over critical social media posts.</p>

<p>There was no word on Tuesday on whether judges would also review Asaad al-Ghamdi's sentence.</p>

<p>Under Prince Mohammed, Saudi Arabia has been pursuing an ambitious reform agenda known as Vision 2030 intended to transform the formerly closed-off kingdom into a global tourism and business destination.</p>

<p>However, Saudi authorities continue to take heat for the country's rights record and restrictions on free speech in particular.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g039625_courtroom-generic-pixabay_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Saudi court sentenced a retired teacher to 30 years' jail for criticising government on social media]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-iran-backed-hezbollah-is-attacking-israel-despite-death-of-its-top-commanders-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6645836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Hezbollah Is Attacking Israel Despite Death Of Its Top Commanders]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-iran-backed-hezbollah-is-attacking-israel-despite-death-of-its-top-commanders-pager-attacks-in-lebanon-6645836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:34:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's assault on Iran-backed Hezbollah over the past week, including the targeting of senior commanders and the detonation of booby-trapped pagers and walkie-talkies, has left it reeling.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah's flexible chain of command, together with its extensive tunnel network and a vast arsenal of missiles and weapons it has bolstered over the past year, is helping it weather unprecedented Israeli strikes, three sources familiar with the Lebanese militant group's operations said. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-journalist-thrown-off-screen-as-israeli-missile-strikes-during-live-interview-6645562">Israel's assault on Hezbollah</a> over the past week, including the targeting of senior commanders and the detonation of booby-trapped pagers and walkie-talkies, has left the powerful Lebanese Shiite militant group and political party reeling.</p>

<p>On Friday, Israel killed the commander who founded and led the group's elite Radwan force, Ibrahim Aqil. And since Monday, Lebanon's deadliest day of violence in decades, the health ministry says more than 560 people, among them 50 children, have died in air barrages.</p>

<p>The Israeli military chief of staff Herzi Halevi said on Sunday that Aqil's death had shaken the organisation. Israel says its strikes have also destroyed thousands of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-conflict-hezbollah-fires-ballistic-missile-at-mossad-base-near-tel-aviv-6644843">Hezbollah</a> rockets and shells.</p>

<p>But two of the sources familiar with Hezbollah operations said the group swiftly appointed replacements for Aqil and other senior figures killed in Friday's airstrike in Beirut's southern suburbs. Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah said in an Aug. 1 speech that the group quickly fills gaps whenever a leader is killed.</p>

<p>A fourth source, a Hezbollah official, said the attack on communication devices put 1,500 fighters out of commission because of their injuries, with many having been blinded or had their hands blown off.</p>

<p>While that is a major blow, it represents a fraction of Hezbollah's strength, which a report for the U.S. Congress on Friday put at 40,000-50,000 fighters. Nasrallah has said the group has 100,000 fighters.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decades-of-covert-conflict-the-israel-lebanon-shadow-war-6636815">Ghosts Of Beirut: 40-Year Shadow War, Spy Ops Between Israel And Lebanon</a></strong></p>

<p>Since October, when Hezbollah began firing at Israel in October in support of its ally Hamas in Gaza, it has redeployed fighters to frontline areas in the south, including some from Syria, the three sources said.</p>

<p>It has also been bringing rockets into Lebanon at a fast pace, anticipating a drawn-out conflict, the sources said, adding that the group sought to avoid all out war.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's main supporter and weapons supplier is Iran. The group is the most powerful faction in Tehran's "Axis of Resistance" of allied irregular forces across the Middle East. Many of its weapons are Iranian, Russian or Chinese models.</p>

<p>The sources, who all asked not to be named because of the sensitivity of the matter, did not provide details of the weapons or where they were bought.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's media office did not reply to requests for comment for this story.</p>

<p>Andreas Krieg, a senior lecturer at the School of Security Studies at King's College London, said that while Hezbollah operations had been disrupted by the past week's attacks, the group's networked organisational structure helped make it an extremely resilient force.</p>

<p>"This is the most formidable enemy Israel has ever faced on the battlefield, not because of numbers and tech but in terms of resilience."</p>

<h3><strong>POWERFUL MISSILES</strong></h3>

<p>Fighting has escalated this week. Israel killed another top Hezbollah commander, Ibrahim Qubaisi, on Tuesday. For its part, Hezbollah has shown its capacity to continue operations, firing hundreds of rockets towards Israel in ever deeper attacks.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Hezbollah said it had targeted an Israeli intelligence base near Tel Aviv, more than 100 km (60 miles) from the border. Warning sirens sounded in Tel Aviv as a single surface-to-surface missile was intercepted by air defence systems, the Israeli military said.</p>

<p>The group has yet to say whether it has launched any of its most potent, precision-guided rockets, such as the Fateh-110, an Iranian-made ballistic missile with a range of 250-300 km (341.75 miles). Hezbollah's Fateh-110 have a 450-500 kg warhead, according to a 2018 paper published by the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300">Hezbollah's rocket attacks</a> are possible because the chain of command has kept functioning despite the group suffering a brief spell of disarray after the pagers and radios detonated, one of the sources, a senior security official, said.</p>

<p>The three sources said Hezbollah's ability to communicate is underpinned by a dedicated, fixed-line telephone network - which it has described as critical to its communications and continues to work - as well as by other devices.</p>

<p>Many of its fighters were carrying older models of pagers, for example, that were unaffected by last week's attack.</p>

<p>Reuters could not independently verify the information. Most injuries from the exploding pagers were in Beirut, far from the front.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-faces-biggest-israeli-attack-in-4-decades-all-about-the-1982-lebanese-war-6636511">1982 Lebanon War: Israeli Invasion Which Gave Birth To Hezbollah Militants</a></strong><br />
<br />
Hezbollah stepped up the use of pagers after banning its fighters from using cellphones on the battlefield in February, in response to commanders being killed in strikes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If the chain of command breaks, frontline fighters are trained to operate in small, independent clusters comprised of a few villages near the border, capable of fighting Israeli forces for long periods, the senior source added.</p>

<p>That is precisely what happened in 2006, during the last war between Hezbollah and Israel, when the group's fighters held out for weeks, some in frontline villages invaded by Israel.</p>

<p>Israel says it has escalated attacks to degrade Hezbollah's capabilities and make it safe for tens of thousands of displaced Israelis to return to their homes near the Lebanon border, which they fled when Hezbollah began firing rockets on Oct. 8.</p>

<p>Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahus-message-for-people-of-lebanon-after-deadly-strikes-10-points-6635347">Benjamin Netanyahu's government</a> has said it prefers to reach a negotiated agreement that would see Hezbollah withdraw from the border region but stands ready to continue its bombing campaign if Hezbollah refuses, and does not rule out any military options.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's resilience means the fighting has raised fears of a protracted war that could suck in the U.S., Israel's close ally, and Iran - especially if Israel launches, and gets bogged down in, a ground offensive in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel's military did not respond to a request for comment for this story.</p>

<p>Iran's President Masoud Pezeshkian warned on Monday of "irreversible" consequences of a full blown war in the Middle East. A U.S. State Department official said Washington disagreed with Israel's strategy of escalation and sought to reduce tensions.</p>

<h3><strong>UNDERGROUND ARSENAL</strong></h3>

<p>In what two of the sources said was an indication of how well some of Hezbollah's weapons are hidden, on Sunday rockets were launched from areas of southern Lebanon that had been targeted by Israel shortly before, the two sources said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is believed to have an underground arsenal and last month published footage that appeared to show its fighters driving trucks with rocket launchers through tunnels. The sources did not specify if the rockets fired on Sunday were launched from underground.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Monday's barrage had destroyed tens of thousands of Hezbollah rockets and munitions.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-1982-to-2024-a-42-year-history-of-bloodshed-between-israel-hezbollah-6636042">1982 to 2024: A 42-Year History Of Bloodshed Between Israel, Hezbollah</a></strong><br />
<br />
Israel's military said long-range cruise missiles, rockets with warheads capable of carrying 100kg of explosives, short-range rockets, and explosive UAVs were all struck on Monday.</p>

<p>Reuters could not independently verify the military claims.</p>

<p>Boaz Shapira a researcher at Alma, an Israeli think tank that specializes in Hezbollah, said Israel had yet to target strategic sites such as long-range missiles and drone sites.</p>

<p>"I don't think we are anywhere near finishing this," Shapira said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's arsenal is believed to compromise some 150,000 rockets, the U.S. Congress report said. Krieg said its most powerful, long-range ballistic missiles were kept below ground.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has spent years building a tunnel network that by Israeli estimates extends for hundreds of kilometres. The Israeli military said Monday's air strikes hit Hezbollah missile launch sites hidden under homes in southern Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hezbollah has said it does not place military infrastructure near civilians. Hezbollah has issued no statement on the impact of Israel's strikes since Monday.</p>

<h3><strong>TUNNELS</strong></h3>

<p>The group's arsenal and tunnels have expanded since the 2006 war, especially precision guidance systems, leader Nasrallah has said. Hezbollah officials have said the group has used a small part of the arsenal in fighting over the past year.</p>

<p>Israeli officials have said Hezbollah's military infrastructure is tightly meshed into the villages and communities of southern Lebanon, with ammunition and missile launcher pads stored in houses throughout the area. Israel has been pounding some of those villages for months to degrade Hezbollah's capabilities. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Confirmed details on the tunnel network remain scarce.</p>

<p>A 2021 report by Alma, an Israeli think tank that specializes in Hezbollah, said Iran and North Korea both helped build up the network of tunnels in the aftermath of the 2006 war.</p>

<p>Israel has already struggled to root out Hamas commanders and self-reliant fighting units from the tunnels criss-crossing Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It is one of our biggest challenges in Gaza, and it is certainly something we could meet in Lebanon," said Carmit Valensi, a senior research fellow at the Institute for National Security Studies in Tel Aviv, a think-tank.</p>

<p>Krieg said that unlike Gaza, where most tunnels are manually dug into a sandy soil, the tunnels in Lebanon had been dug deep in mountain rock. "They are far less accessible than in Gaza and even less easy to destroy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nu1riq3o_hezbollahiran_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fighting has escalated this week]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tells-hillary-clinton-i-love-you-after-being-trapped-by-wife-jill-biden-6645824]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Tells Hillary Clinton 'I Love You' After Being 'Trapped' By Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-tells-hillary-clinton-i-love-you-after-being-trapped-by-wife-jill-biden-6645824]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:31:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden professed his admiration for former First Lady Hillary Clinton and stated that he loved her for defending him in public after he was "trapped" by his wife, Jill Biden, to give a speech in New York City.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden professed his admiration for former First Lady Hillary Clinton and stated that he loved her for defending him in public after he was "trapped" by his wife, Jill Biden, to give a speech in New York City. It all happened at the Clinton Global Initiative's summit on Monday evening.</p>

<p>Mr Biden, who dropped out of the presidential race against Donald Trump in the November 5 US election, was not scheduled to address the event. He came there to support Jill Biden. He was later called to the stage to accept the Global Citizen Award.</p>

<p>"I — this is what you call being trapped," Biden said, thanking the former first couple, Bill and Hillary Clinton. Biden said he was not going to make a "long" speech "because I didn't think I was going to be talking about this."</p>

<p>Noting he had known the Clintons for a long time, Biden said that it was fair to say that he was one of the earliest supporters of Bill Clinton's presidency.</p>

<p>"... because what I saw in you was not an incredible intellect but a decency that you talked — you gave me credit for. It was always about the other guy, always about somebody else," he added.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, then went on to thank Hillary Clinton for helping him.</p>

<p>"Hillary, I want to thank you — and I maybe shouldn't do this publicly — but thank you personally for the way you have helped me, the way you've spoken up for me with such passion.&nbsp; I can't tell you — I — you can ask Jill.&nbsp; I — anyway, I — I love you.&nbsp; I love you," he said.</p>

<p>To this, the former first lady responded, "Thank you," while her husband had his arm around her shoulder. In the meantime, Jill Biden clapped lightly while looking on. Earlier, the Clintons extended their support to Biden following his debate with former US president Donald Trump on June 27.</p>

<p>"The choice in this election remains very simple. It's a choice between someone who cares about you—your rights, your prospects, your future—versus someone who's only in it for himself. I'll be voting for Biden," Hillary Clinton wrote on X, a day later.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The choice in this election remains very simple.<br />
<br />
It's a choice between someone who cares about you—your rights, your prospects, your future—versus someone who's only in it for himself.<br />
<br />
I'll be voting Biden. <a href="https://t.co/mxkpLIOEux">https://t.co/mxkpLIOEux</a></p>
— Hillary Clinton (@HillaryClinton) <a href="https://twitter.com/HillaryClinton/status/1806686107632877647?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>However, Biden soon exited the US presidential race, paving the way for US Vice President Kamala Harris to be the Democratic nominee against Trump. The two had their first presidential debate on September 10. It lasted for almost 1 hour and 45 minutes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dogb6v8k_joe-biden_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-faces-no-confidence-vote-in-parliament-6645699]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canadian PM Justin Trudeau Faces No-Confidence Vote In Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-faces-no-confidence-vote-in-parliament-6645699]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:16:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's main rival in Canada's parliament on Tuesday introduced a motion of no confidence in the ruling Liberals, in the first major test of his unpopular minority government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's main rival in Canada's parliament on Tuesday introduced a motion of no confidence in the ruling Liberals, in the first major test of his unpopular minority government.</p>

<p>Following a debate in the House of Commons, a vote on the long-shot Conservative motion is scheduled on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Far ahead in public opinion polls, Tory leader Pierre Poilievre has been itching for a snap election since the leftist New Democratic Party (NDP) earlier this month tore up a coalition agreement with the Liberals, leaving the Trudeau administration vulnerable to being toppled.</p>

<p>Kicking off the debate, a combative Poilievre railed against Trudeau for what he said was a failure to address soaring costs of living, a housing crisis and crime, while doubling the national debt.</p>

<p>He said the promise of Canada, "after nine years of Liberal government, is broken."</p>

<p>If elected prime minister, he said he would legislate "a common sense plan to axe the tax (on carbon emissions), build the homes, fix the budget and stop the crime."</p>

<p>During an appearance in New York on the Late Show with Stephen Colbert on Monday evening, Justin Trudeau acknowledged that Canadians are facing "a really tough time."</p>

<p>"People are hurting. People are having trouble paying for groceries, paying for rent, filling up the tank," and "are looking at change," he said.</p>

<p>But he vowed to "keep fighting."</p>

<p>At a news conference at the United Nations on Tuesday, Trudeau criticized Poilievre for suggesting "the best way to get through these difficult times is to cut services and programs that Canadians rely on."</p>

<p>"I'm thinking about how we can best help Canadians," he said.</p>

<h2><strong>LIBERALS HOLDING ON</strong></h2>

<p>The no-confidence motion is not expected to succeed after two smaller political factions have signaled they will side with the government and vote against it.</p>

<p>But Poilievre has vowed to keep trying, with another opportunity to bring down the government to be presented in early October.</p>

<p>Trudeau swept to power in 2015, and has managed to hold on by defeating two of Poilievre's predecessors in 2019 and 2021 ballots.</p>

<p>The deal with the New Democratic Party to prop up the Liberals would have kept his government in office until late 2025.</p>

<p>But the NDP, seeing its alignment with the Liberals hurting its own popularity, exited the deal early.</p>

<p>According to a recent Angus Reid poll, the Conservatives are well ahead of the Liberals, with 43 percent of voting intention against 21 percent for the ruling party. The NDP is at 19 percent.</p>

<p>In Canada's Westminster parliamentary system, a ruling party must hold the confidence of the House of Commons, which means maintaining support from a majority of members.</p>

<p>The Liberals currently have 153 seats, versus 119 for the Conservatives, 33 for the Bloc Quebecois, and the NDP 25.</p>

<p>Political analysts who spoke to AFP suggest an election likely won't happen until at least spring 2025.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j9q62jac_justin-trudeau-reuters-trudeau-canada-parliament-reuters_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau's main rival in Canada's parliament on Tuesday introduced a motion of no confidence]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-journalist-thrown-off-screen-as-israeli-missile-strikes-during-live-interview-6645562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Israeli Missile Hits Lebanon Journalist's Home During Live Interview]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-journalist-thrown-off-screen-as-israeli-missile-strikes-during-live-interview-6645562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:09:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Lebanese journalist sustained injuries when an Israeli missile struck his home while he was conducting a live TV interview. Fadi Boudaya, the editor-in-chief of Miraya International Network, was seen losing his balance and thrown off-screen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Lebanese journalist sustained injuries when an Israeli missile struck his home while he was conducting a live TV interview. Fadi Boudaya, the editor-in-chief of Miraya International Network, was seen losing his balance and thrown off-screen the moment the missile hit his home.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The footage, now viral on social media, showed Boudaya mid-sentence, which quickly turned into a scream when the explosion occurred. Fortunately, he sustained only minor injuries in the incident.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WINDOWS AND WALLS SHATTER AND COLLAPSE ON A JOURNALIST, NEARLY KILLING HIM<br />
<br />
Fadi Boudia,editor of the Maraya International News Network,nearly dies live as IDF missiles attack his home in Beqaa,eastern ????????,just as he begins a Skype interview for a live program in the video above. <a href="https://t.co/ucJls46IGC">pic.twitter.com/ucJls46IGC</a></p>
— Malcolm X (@malcolmx653459) <a href="https://twitter.com/malcolmx653459/status/1838307199073800563?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The journalist, reportedly considered sympathetic towards Hezbollah, later reassured his followers through X. “Thank you to everyone who called, texted, checked in and to everyone who felt any emotion,” he wrote. “Thank God, I am fine, thanks to God and His blessings upon us, and we return to continue our media duty in support of the resistance. Thank you from the bottom of my heart.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="ar">شكراً لكل من اتصل وراسل واطمأنّ، وشكراً لكل من شعر بأية عاطفة.<br />
الحمدلله انا بخير بفضل الله ونعمته علينا، ونعود لمتابعة واجبنا الإعلامي سنداً للمقاومة.<br />
شكراً لكم من القلب</p>
— Fadi Boudaya (@Fadi_Boudaya) <a href="https://twitter.com/Fadi_Boudaya/status/1838523270083010630?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The attack on Fadi Boudaya comes amid escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah, the Iran-backed militant group. Since the Gaza war erupted last October, both sides have been involved in intense cross-border conflict, with recent hostilities reaching new heights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The situation worsened following a cyber attack on Hezbollah members, during which their communication devices – pagers and walkie-talkies – were targeted. Hezbollah accused Israel of orchestrating the attacks.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon killed more than 550 people, including 50 children. That evening, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu released a video message, urging Lebanese citizens to evacuate their homes. “Once the operation is finished, they can return to their homes,” he said.&nbsp;<br />
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OspjXp19h8M?si=gjRJ7KBwAY-6SOPb" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
On Tuesday, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300">Israeli airstrikes in Beirut</a> killed Ibrahim Qubaisi, the head of Hezbollah's missile division. The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed Qubaisi's death, saying he was a key figure in Hezbollah's missile operations. Alongside Qubaisi, at least two other high-ranking commanders were reportedly killed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The strikes, targeting the Dahiyeh suburb, came amid intense cross-border clashes, with Hezbollah firing over 300 rockets at northern Israeli cities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/19p4cnc8_lebanon-journalist-bomb-during-live-interview-_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack on Fadi Boudaya comes amid escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-new-zealand-on-chinas-rare-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-test-serious-concern-6645603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Serious Concern": Japan, New Zealand As China Conducts Rare Missile Test]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-new-zealand-on-chinas-rare-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-test-serious-concern-6645603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:02:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China test-launched an intercontinental ballistic missile on Wednesday, firing it into the Pacific Ocean in its first such exercise in decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China said it test-launched an intercontinental ballistic missile on Wednesday, firing it into the Pacific Ocean in its first such exercise in decades. The launch sparked protests from other countries in the region, with China's neighbour Japan saying it had not been given advance notice and expressing "serious concern" about Beijing's military build-up.</p>

<p>Beijing has stepped up its nuclear development and boosted defence spending in recent years, with the Pentagon last October warning China was developing its arsenal more quickly than the United States had anticipated.</p>

<p>China held more than 500 operational nuclear warheads as of May 2023 and is likely to have more than 1,000 by 2030, it said.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the Chinese military's Rocket Force "launched an ICBM... carrying a dummy warhead to the high seas in the Pacific Ocean at 08:44 on September 25, and the missile fell into expected sea areas", the defence ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>An analyst told AFP such tests were very rare.</p>

<p>"This is extremely unusual and likely the first time in decades that we've seen a test like this," said Ankit Panda, Stanton Senior Fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.</p>

<p>"(The test) likely speaks to China's ongoing nuclear modernisation manifesting in new requirements for testing," he added.</p>

<h3>'Serious concern'</h3>

<p>China's defence ministry, however, called the firing a "routine arrangement in our annual training plan".</p>

<p>"It is in line with international law and international practice and is not directed against any country or target," it said.</p>

<p>Japan, however, said it was given "no notice from the Chinese side in advance", with a government spokesman adding that Beijing's military build-up was a "serious concern".</p>

<p>New Zealand also said the launch of the missile, which landed in the South Pacific, was "an unwelcome and concerning development".</p>

<p>A spokesman for Wellington's foreign minister vowed to consult with Pacific allies further as details become clear.</p>

<p>Beijing first test-fired an ICBM into the South Pacific in the 1980s.</p>

<p>But since then, Panda told AFP, it has typically conducted such tests in its own airspace.</p>

<p>In 2021, the United States said it was "very concerned" about reported hypersonic missile testing by China.</p>

<h3><strong>Third-largest stockpile</strong></h3>

<p>The United States and China in November held rare talks on nuclear arms control, part of a bid to ease mistrust ahead of a summit between leaders Joe Biden and Xi Jinping.</p>

<p>But in July, Beijing said it had suspended negotiations with the United States on nuclear non-proliferation and arms control in response to Washington's weapons sales to Taiwan.</p>

<p>In an annual report, the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI) listed China as having the world's third-largest stockpile of nuclear warheads, after Russia and the United States.</p>

<p>This year, Beijing announced it would increase its defence budget -- the world's second-largest -- by 7.2 percent.</p>

<p>The boost comes as China increasingly squares off with the United States and its regional partners from the South China Sea to Taiwan.</p>

<p>This month, senior military officials from China and the United States held "in-depth" talks as part of a bid by the powers to avoid wider tensions escalating into conflict.</p>

<p>Since its first atomic test in 1964, China has been content to maintain a comparatively modest arsenal and has maintained that it would never be the first to use nuclear weapons in a conflict.</p>

<p>In recent years, under President Xi, it has begun a massive military modernisation drive that includes upgrading its nuclear weapons to not only deter foes but also be able to counter-attack.</p>

<p>But Beijing's secretive Rocket Force, which carried out Wednesday's test and oversees the country's nuclear arsenal, has also been the target of an aggressive, wide-ranging anti-graft campaign.</p>

<p>In July, Beijing announced that Sun Jinming, the former chief of staff of the force, had been placed under investigation for corruption.</p>

<p>Its head, Li Yuchao, was replaced last July.</p>

<p>And Li Shangfu was ousted last year after only seven months as defence minister following a lengthy absence from public view.</p>

<p>Other disgraced generals include Wei Fenghe, who once headed the Rocket Force and who later became China's defence minister from 2018 to 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9glcm1n_china-missile_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sandwiched-between-india-and-china-6645383]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Don't Want To Be Sandwiched...": New Lanka President's India-China Plans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sandwiched-between-india-and-china-6645383]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:34:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake - Sri Lanka's new Marxist President - has said he wants to avoid being "sandwiched" between India and China but recognises each as a "valued partner", as he tries to resolve a financial crisis roiling his country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/anura-kumara-dissanayake" target="_blank">Anura Kumara Dissanayake</a> - Sri Lanka's new Marxist President - has said he wants to avoid being "sandwiched" between India and China but recognises each as a "valued partner", as he tries to resolve a financial crisis that has roiled his country since 2019 and led to a sovereign default in April 2022.</p>

<p>The former grassroots leader made it clear he intends to steer clear of geopolitical rumblings in South Asia or the Indian Ocean region. He acknowledged that each can provide much-needed financial aid but said he also wanted closer ties with the West, the Middle East, and even Africa.</p>

<p>The remarks were made in an interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://monocle.com/shop/product/2546171/issue-176/" target="_blank">The Monocle</a>, a global affairs and lifestyle magazine, in early September (before his election win was confirmed), in which he spoke about his foreign policy.</p>

<p>"There are many power camps within a multipolar system... but we won't be part of that geopolitical fight, nor will we be aligned with any party. We also don't want to be sandwiched, especially between China and India. Both are valued friends and we expect them to become closer partners."</p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake, 55, a previously fringe Left leader, was catapulted into the limelight after winning the presidential election; he pulled over 42 per cent of the votes.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-marxist-leader-anura-kumara-dissanayaka-wins-sri-lankas-presidential-elections-6625013" target="_blank">Marxist Leader Anura Dissanayake Wins Sri Lanka's Prez Polls</a></p>

<p>Rumoured close ties to China raised eyebrows, particularly in Delhi, which expressed concerns over Beijing's growing influence on Sri Lanka, which sits on key shipping lanes in the Indian Ocean. Added to that, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3279800/sri-lanka-seek-maximum-support-china-under-new-leader-dissanayake-analysts-say" target="_blank">South China Morning Post</a> claimed Beijing expects Dissanayake will seek "maximum support" via foreign direct investment.</p>

<p>That report cited an economics professor from the University of Colombo as saying it is "highly probable" Mr Dissanayake would prefer to work with Beijing over Delhi.</p>

<p>However, Mr Dissanayake has, publicly at least, sought to reassure both Delhi and the United States, which too is wary of China's growing influence.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-rise-of-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sri-lankas-new-president-6628769" target="_blank">The Rise Of Lanka's Anura Dissanayake From Grassroots To President</a></p>

<p>Speaking to an Indian publication on voting day (on Saturday), Mr Dissanayake said India is "crucial" to his country's hopes for economic stability and regional security.</p>

<p>"We will consider how our economic measures impact our country (while) recognising the importance of India's support in our development efforts," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theweek.in/news/world/2024/09/24/dont-want-to-be-sandwiched-between-india-china-sri-lankan-president-anura-on-his-foreign-policy.html" target="_blank">The Week</a>.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has spoken to Mr Dissanayake, stating he looks forward to working closely with him to further strengthen the Indo-Lanka multifaceted cooperation. Mr Modi's post on X also contained a reference to Colombo's "special place" in Delhi's Neighbourhood First policy.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-congratulates-anura-dissanayake-for-victory-in-sri-lankan-presidential-poll-6626358" target="_blank">PM Congratulates Dissanayake For Victory In Sri Lankan Polls</a></p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake responded, "I share your commitment... Together, we can work towards enhancing cooperation for the benefit of our peoples and the entire region."</p>

<p>The Sri Lankan leader also played down fears - expressed by both Delhi and Washington - his country would become a military base for Beijing; as recently as last month three Chinese Navy ships were berthed at Colombo Port, at the same time as India's front-line warship, INS Mumbai, docked.</p>

<p>"We are committed to maintaining our sovereignty and will not become subordinate to any power in this geopolitical race..." Mr Dissanayake said this month.</p>

<p>Delhi has played a key role - recognised by the International Monetary Fund, which has provided a $3 billion bailout programme - in guiding Colombo through the ongoing financial crisis, having provided aid - food, medicines, fuel, etc., - worth nearly $4 billion since the storm broke.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imf-to-work-with-sri-lankas-new-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-on-3-billion-loan-6635752" target="_blank">IMF To Work With Sri Lanka's New President On $3 Billion Loan</a></p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake, however, has said he will try to renegotiate the IMF's loan conditions, some of which led to tax hikes and spending cuts, which many in Colombo said actually exacerbated the cost-of-living crisis that sparked the violent protests of 2019 and 2020. Reviewing the debt plan, though, risks delaying additional loans he needs to meet fiscal criteria before more funds are released.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b7jfm6hs_sri-lankan-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-reuters_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake won Sri Lanka's first presidential polls since the financial crisis (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-117-freed-70-dead-but-fate-of-64-hostages-still-held-in-gaza-unknown-6645229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[117 Freed, 70 Dead, But Fate Of 64 Hostages Still Held In Gaza Unknown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-117-freed-70-dead-but-fate-of-64-hostages-still-held-in-gaza-unknown-6645229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:12:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For Hamas, the hostages are key bargaining chips to negotiate a truce with Israel and seek the release of Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Hamas militants staged the worst-ever attack on Israel, they took back into the Gaza Strip 251 hostages, some of them already dead. A year later, 64 people, including two children, are still in captivity and Israel believes they are alive.</p>

<p>For the Palestinian militant group that rules the Gaza Strip, the hostages are key bargaining chips to negotiate a truce with Israel and seek the release of Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Here is what we know about the hostages still held in Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>52 men, 10 women, two children</strong></h3>

<p>Of the 251 hostages seized by militants on October 7, 2023, 117 have been freed, most of them women, children and foreign workers.</p>

<p>Most were released during a week-long truce in late November in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Nearly a year later, Israel believes 64 hostages still held in Gaza are alive.</p>

<p>The army has confirmed 70 others are dead, 33 of whose bodies are still in Gaza.</p>

<p>The military has repatriated the bodies of 37 hostages who either died in Gaza or were killed on October 7 and taken to the territory.</p>

<p>Of the 64 thought to be alive, 57 are Israelis, though some of them have more than one nationality. Another six are Thai nationals and one is Nepalese.</p>

<p>Fifty-two are men and 10 are women. Eleven are military personnel.</p>

<p>Two are children.</p>

<p>The youngest hostage, Kfir, was just eight-and-a-half months old when he was kidnapped. The other is his brother Ariel, who was only four years old when he was taken to Gaza.</p>

<p>Hamas has said the two children are dead, but Israel has not confirmed this.</p>

<h3><strong>No proof of life</strong></h3>

<p>Since the truce ended on December 1, only seven other hostages have been freed alive, all during Israeli military operations.</p>

<p>With no proof of life, uncertainty remains over whether the 64 are still alive.</p>

<p>The armed wing of Hamas said on August 12 that its fighters had shot and killed an Israeli hostage and injured two others.</p>

<p>Hamas has announced on several occasions deaths of hostages that have not been confirmed by Israel, leaving families in agonising limbo.</p>

<h3><strong>Bodies taken to Gaza</strong></h3>

<p>On October 7, Hamas militants took several dead back into Gaza with them, including 10 Israeli soldiers' bodies.</p>

<p>At least 28 other hostages have died in the territory since the start of the war.</p>

<p>Three were killed in error by the Israeli army on December 15, 2023. They were Yotam Haim, 28, Samer El-Talalqa and Alon Shamriz, 26.</p>

<p>The Israeli army accuses Hamas of executing six others in August: Hersh Goldberg-Polin, Carmel Gat, Eden Yerushalmi, Alexander Lobonov, Almog Sarusi and Ori Danino.</p>

<p>They were found dead by soldiers in a tunnel in Rafah, in southern Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>Festival, kibbutz survivors</strong></h3>

<p>Most of the hostages were taken during the attack on the Nir Oz kibbutz and on the Nova music festival.</p>

<p>At Nir Oz kibbutz, of the at least 76 hostages taken on October 7, 40 were released alive. Another 20 are still in Gaza and believed to be alive. The remaining 16 are dead.</p>

<p>Only 17 people abducted from the festival are thought to be alive and still being held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Only nine of at least 43 hostages taken from Nova have been released, while 17 others have died.</p>

<h3><strong>Whole families</strong></h3>

<p>On October 7, whole families were taken to Gaza. For them, the November 2023 truce brought relief but also the heartache of leaving loved ones behind.</p>

<p>French-Israeli children Eitan, Erez and Sahar were freed but their fathers Ohad Yahalomi and Ofer Kalderon are still being held.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nutnuvbg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmers-faux-pas-goes-viral-i-call-for-return-of-sausages-6645103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['I Call For Return Of Sausages From Gaza': UK PM's Faux Pas Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmers-faux-pas-goes-viral-i-call-for-return-of-sausages-6645103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:54:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer's slip of the tongue came while he was speaking at the Labour Party conference in Liverpool, as he meant to say "hostages".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video of UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer calling on Hamas to return "the sausages" as he urged a peaceful solution to the Gaza war with Israel went viral on Tuesday. Starmer's slip of the tongue came while he was speaking at the Labour Party conference in Liverpool, northwest England, as he meant to say "hostages".</p>

<p>Having first called for "restraint and de-escalation at the border between Lebanon and Israel", Starmer moved on to the Gaza conflict.</p>

<p>"I call again for an immediate ceasefire in Gaza, the return of the sausages," he said, before quickly correcting himself with "the hostages" as applause rang out around the conference hall.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">? NEW: Keir Starmer calls for the ‘return of the sausages' in Gaza, before correcting to ‘hostages'<a href="https://t.co/T71PHGKh6m">pic.twitter.com/T71PHGKh6m</a></p>
— Politics UK (@PolitlcsUK) <a href="https://twitter.com/PolitlcsUK/status/1838572221461062107?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"And a recommitment to the two-state solution, a recognised Palestinian state alongside a safe and secure Israel," he continued.</p>

<p>Almost as soon as the words had left Starmer's mouth, the video went viral on X and by Tuesday evening it was the second most shared content.</p>

<p>British media were quick to jump on Starmer's mistake, with the left-wing Guardian calling it a "gaffe" and the right-wing Daily Mail noting a "faux-pas".</p>

<p>Starmer was referring to the nearly year-long war that broke out after the attack by Hamas militants on Israel on October 7 last year and the Israeli ground invasion of Gaza that followed.</p>

<p>Recent escalation has seen Israel and the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah move to the brink of all-out war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r20darb8_keir-starmer_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer during his speech on the third day of the annual Labour Party conference in Liverpool]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran-moves-were-already-made-6644974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Moves Were Already Made": Trump Claims "Big Threats" On His Life By Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran-moves-were-already-made-6644974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:35:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump's campaign team said in a statement Tuesday that US intelligence had warned the former president of "real and specific" threats from Iran to assassinate him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Wednesday there were "big threats" on his life posed by Iran after the Republican presidential candidate's campaign team said US intelligence warned him of "real and specific" threats from Tehran.</p>

<p>"Big threats on my life by Iran. The entire US Military is watching and waiting," Trump wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>"Moves were already made by Iran that didn't work out, but they will try again. I am surrounded by more men, guns, and weapons than I have ever seen before," he said, following increased scrutiny of the US Secret Service since two attempts on Trump's life this year.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign team said in a statement Tuesday that US intelligence had warned the former president of "real and specific" threats from Iran to assassinate him.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if the threats referred to by the campaign and Trump himself were new or threats that have previously been reported.</p>

<p>"President Trump was briefed earlier today by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence regarding real and specific threats from Iran to assassinate him in an effort to destabilize and sow chaos in the United States," campaign communications director Steven Cheung said in the statement.</p>

<p>"Intelligence officials have identified that these continued and coordinated attacks have heightened in the past few months, and law enforcement officials across all agencies are working to ensure President Trump is protected and the election is free from interference," he added.</p>

<p>The campaign did not elaborate on the claims, which come as world leaders scramble to try to avert hostilities between Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israel escalating into a wider regional war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran has rejected accusations that it is trying to kill Trump this summer, shortly after a gunman opened fire at a rally in Pennsylvania, killing one person and wounding the presidential candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Days after the July 13 assassination attempt, US media reported that authorities had received intelligence on an alleged Iranian plot against the Republican, prompting his protection to be boosted. Iran rejected the "malicious" accusations.</p>

<p>"If they do 'assassinate President Trump,' which is always a possibility, I hope that America obliterates Iran, wipes it off the face of the Earth -- If that does not happen, American Leaders will be considered 'gutless' cowards!" Trump wrote on his social media platform, Truth Social, at the time.</p>

<h3><strong>Iranian cyberattackers</strong></h3>

<p>US intelligence agencies have also accused Iran of a hack targeting Trump's campaign, alleging Tehran is seeking to influence the 2024 election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A joint statement from the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency this month said Iranian cyberattackers had offered "stolen, non-public" material from Trump's campaign to staff for his then-White House rival, President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"Foreign actors are increasing their election influence activities" as Election Day in November approaches, the statement said, singling out Russia, Iran and China as "trying by some measure to exacerbate divisions in US society for their own benefit."</p>

<p>The US agencies said the Iranian cyberattackers had also attempted to share the information stolen from the Trump campaign with US media organizations. It did not name the outlets.</p>

<p>Iran has also vehemently denied those accusations.</p>

<p>The campaign of Trump's presidential election rival, Democrat Kamala Harris, said on August 13 that it too had been targeted by foreign hackers, but did not give an indication of which country was believed to be behind the attempt.</p>

<p>Americans cast their ballots on November 5. Polls show Trump and Harris, who launched her campaign after Biden dropped out earlier this summer, are neck and neck.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6amhn82_moves-were-already-made-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunshots-fired-at-harris-campaign-office-in-arizona-2nd-time-in-two-weeks-6644963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunshots Fired At Kamala Harris' Campaign Office, 2nd Time In Two Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunshots-fired-at-harris-campaign-office-in-arizona-2nd-time-in-two-weeks-6644963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:32:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At the time of the incident, the Democratic campaign office in Tempe, located just east of Phoenix in Arizona, was unoccupied and nobody was injured in the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Multiple gunshots were fired at a campaign office of US Vice President Kamala Harris in Arizona, police said. The gunshot damage from several bullets, believed to have been fired sometime after midnight on Monday, was discovered at the Democratic campaign office near Southern Avenue and Priest Drive in Tempe, the city police told The New York Post.<br />
<br />
“No one was inside the office during the overnight hours, but this raises concerns about the safety of those who work in that building, as well as those nearby,” Public Information Officer Ryan Cook said.<br />
<br />
According to the Tempe Police Department, the matter is currently being looked upon as a potential property crime. In footage aired by the local TV stations, two bullet holes were seen in a door, while two others were in windows of the office.<br />
<br />
Currently, the investigators are analysing the evidence collected from the party office, while additional measures have been taken to tighten the security of the staff members and others in the area, police said.<br />
Shockingly, this was the second time criminal damage was reported at the property in as many weeks.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Earlier, the front windows of the office were shot by what appeared to be a BB gun or pellet gun, just after midnight on September 16. So far, no arrests have been made in either incident, while the authorities investigate all possible angles and motives.<br />
<br />
In a statement, Sean McEnerney, the Arizona Democratic Party coordinated campaign manager, thanked the city police for swiftly taking action on the matter.<br />
<br />
“We are grateful to Tempe Police for coming quickly to the scene and are fortunate no one was present or injured,” McEnerney said.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris' Arizona visit</strong></h3>

<p>The twin shootings at the local campaign office of the party took place days before US Vice President Kamala Harris was scheduled to touch down in Arizona, a key battleground state in the November 5 presidential election in the US.<br />
<br />
As per reports, Harris will campaign across the Grand Canyon State during her visit.<br />
<br />
Further, sources told The New York Times that Harris plans to visit the US-Mexico border on Friday, seeking to counter Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's advantage with voters on the immigration issue.</p>

<h3><strong>Assassination attempt on Trump</strong></h3>

<p>The alleged attack on the local campaign office in Arizona comes on the heels of the second assassination attempt on former US president Donald Trump at his West Palm Beach golf course on September 15.<br />
<br />
Ryan Routh, the gunman, was uncovered by a Secret Service agent, who spotted the muzzle of a rifle sticking out of the bushes. The agent fired before Routh had the chance to fire a single shot. Soon after, Routh allegedly dropped his rifle and fled in a car, but was arrested in 40 minutes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/if09613_kamala-harris_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>