<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 11:18:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamys-prediction-on-joe-bidens-re-election-bid-comes-true-6159220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy's Prediction On Biden, Kamala Harris Comes True, Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamys-prediction-on-joe-bidens-re-election-bid-comes-true-6159220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 11:02:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for re-election as president of the US and endorsed his deputy Kamala Harris to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American businessman-turned-politician Vivek Ramaswamy had predicted some eight months ago that incumbent President Joe Biden would not be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Joe Biden</a> announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for re-election as president of the United States and endorsed his deputy <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-joins-presidential-race-who-will-be-her-running-mate-6158830#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Kamala Harris</a> to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>“Best way to predict the future: just follow the incentives. It's shocking how precisely right you can be, right down to the exact timing,” Ramaswamy, a 38-year-old Republican, said in a social media post along with the video interview with Fox News last November, soon after Biden announced his decision.</p>

<p>“Yeah, all his predictions have come true,” Tesla CEO and X owner Elon Musk said in response. “Wish it weren't so,” Ramaswamy responded.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yeah, all his predictions have come true</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1815093642366980353?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Wish it weren't so. <a href="https://t.co/upKkCY2iY2">https://t.co/upKkCY2iY2</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1815094952050737167?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In his interview with Fox News, Ramaswamy had said: “I think that the reality is the managerial class around Biden has lost their use for him. This has been obvious to me since last year to play out the incentives. He is not the strongest candidate they can put up. And these people, they have stopped at nothing to keep Donald J Trump out of office,” he said.</p>

<p>The Indian-American, who then was the Republican presidential candidate in the primaries along with former president Donald Trump, said that two candidates – Kamala Harris and Michelle Obama – were possibly to be picked by the Democrats.</p>

<p>“Let's give credit where credit is due. For almost a year one man has been saying “Biden won't be the Democratic nominee” and predicting a last-minute blindside. People called him crazy,” Tristane Tate, a social media influencer, said, applauding Ramaswamy for his prediction coming true. Ramaswamy had made a similar prediction during one of the Republican presidential debates.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The anatomy of how a “conspiracy theory” became reality, in just 18 months. <a href="https://t.co/yU4wlnJ6oK">pic.twitter.com/yU4wlnJ6oK</a></p>
— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) <a href="https://twitter.com/VivekGRamaswamy/status/1815089834278690991?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“‘I remember corporate media reporters sneering and laughing when Vivek Ramaswamy made this point in the debate. They're not laughing now!” Raheem Kassam, a journalist, said on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tf9f5pcg_vivek-ramaswamy-joe-biden_625x300_28_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy had predicted eight months ago that Joe Biden would not be the presidential nominee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-simpsons-prediction-comes-true-joe-biden-out-kamala-harris-in-6159125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['The Simpsons' Prediction Comes True: Joe Biden Out, Kamala Harris In]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-simpsons-prediction-comes-true-joe-biden-out-kamala-harris-in-6159125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:44:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has ended his reelection bid and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the new Democratic nominee.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has ended his reelection bid and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the new Democratic nominee. The sudden change is similar to a development predicted years ago in the popular animated series <em>The Simpsons.</em></p>

<p>In the 17th episode of the 11th season, which aired in 2000, Lisa Simpson became the first female president of the US. She is seen in an outfit similar to what Kamala Harris wore at Joe Biden's inauguration, hinting at her rise to the presidency in future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The episode also points to a predecessor who left behind a budget crisis for President Lisa to manage, strongly suggesting a real estate mogul (Donald Trump) had previously held the office.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The 17th episode of the 11th season of The Simpsons shows Lisa Simpson as the first female president of the United States, dressed similarly to Kamala Harris at Joe Biden's inauguration.<br />
<br />
This episode, which aired in 2000, strongly suggests that real estate mogul Donald Trump… <a href="https://t.co/zvFZ5RVLl8">pic.twitter.com/zvFZ5RVLl8</a></p>
— Shadow of Ezra (@ShadowofEzra) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShadowofEzra/status/1815106589239726422?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Simpsons has a history of making eerily accurate and satirical references to global events. Some of their previous predictions include the rise of smartwatches, Donald Trump's presidency, Disney's acquisition of 20th Century Fox and Finnish economist Bengt R Holmstrom winning the Nobel Prize for his work.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Most recently, a cartoon showing the former president lying in a coffin went viral. This comes after the recent <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-did-the-simpsons-predict-trump-assassination-attempt-6115400 ">attempted assassination</a> of Trump.</p>

<p>Joe Biden <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671">dropped out of the US presidential race</a> on Sunday, saying it was in the "best interest of my party and the country" to step aside. His withdrawal was widely anticipated following his abysmal performance in the June debate against Trump. The announcement came unexpectedly while he was recovering from COVID-19 at his Delaware beach house.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kamala Harris received significant backing from key Democratic figures, including Hillary Clinton and California Governor Gavin Newsom, who is also a potential rival for the nomination.</p>

<p>The Democratic fundraising group ActBlue reported Harris received $27.5 million in small-donour contributions within just five hours.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/8o3p0a6g_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_22_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden dropped out of the US presidential race on Sunday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/nvidia-ai-ai-chip-china-ai-nvidia-preparing-version-of-new-flagship-ai-chip-for-chinese-market-sources-say-6159124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Preparing New Flagship AI Chip For Chinese Market, Sources Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/nvidia-ai-ai-chip-china-ai-nvidia-preparing-version-of-new-flagship-ai-chip-for-chinese-market-sources-say-6159124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:44:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nvidia will work with Inspur, one of its major distributor partners in China, on the chip which is tentatively named the "B20"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia is working on a version of its new flagship AI chips for the China market that would be compatible with current U.S. export controls, three sources familiar with the matter said.<br />
<br />
The AI chip giant in March unveiled its "Blackwell" chip series, which is due to be mass produced later in the year. Within that series, the B200 is 30 times speedier than its predecessor at some tasks like serving up answers from chatbots.</p>

<p>Nvidia will work with Inspur, one of its major distributor partners in China, on the launch and distribution of the chip which is tentatively named the "B20", two of the sources said.</p>

<p>The sources declined to be identified as Nvidia has yet to make a public announcement.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Nvidia declined to comment. Inspur did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Washington tightened its controls on exports of cutting-edge semiconductors to China in 2023, seeking to prevent breakthroughs in supercomputing that would aid China's military.</p>

<p>Since then, Nvidia has developed three chips tailored specifically for the Chinese market.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aqaknihg_nvidia_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sources declined to be identified as Nvidia has yet to make a public announcement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-tycoon-on-trial-for-146-million-fraud-in-corruption-crackdown-6159062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vietnamese Tycoon On Trial For $146 Million Fraud In Corruption Crackdown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-tycoon-on-trial-for-146-million-fraud-in-corruption-crackdown-6159062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:36:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former Vietnamese property and aviation tycoon charged with $146 million in fraud and stock market manipulation went on trial in Hanoi Monday, the latest corruption case targeting the communist country's business elite.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former Vietnamese property and aviation tycoon charged with $146 million in fraud and stock market manipulation went on trial in Hanoi Monday, the latest corruption case targeting the communist country's business elite.</p>

<p>Trinh Van Quyet, who owned the FLC empire of luxury resorts, golf courses, and the budget Bamboo Airways, had nearly $2 billion in stock market wealth before his arrest, according to state media estimates.</p>

<p>But on Monday the 48-year-old -- handcuffed and dressed in a white shirt -- was led into court by police officers.</p>

<p>The trial comes just days after the death of former Communist Party of Vietnam leader Nguyen Phu Trong, who is credited with spearheading a crackdown on graft at the highest levels.</p>

<p>Trong, 80, died on Friday at a military hospital in Hanoi "due to old age and serious illness", the party said, a day after announcing he was standing down to seek medical care.</p>

<p>Tycoon Quyet is accused of illegally pocketing more than $146 million between 2017 and 2022.</p>

<p>Following his arrest in March 2022, 49 other alleged accomplices were picked up -- including his two sisters and the former chairman of the Ho Chi Minh Stock Exchange and its chief executive officer.</p>

<p>According to the prosecution indictment, Quyet set up several stock market brokerages and registered dozens of family members to, ostensibly, trade shares.</p>

<p>But police said while orders to buy shares were placed in hundreds of trading sessions -- pushing up the value of the stock -- they were cancelled before being matched.</p>

<p>The case is part of a national corruption crackdown that has swept up numerous officials and members of Vietnam's business elite in recent years.</p>

<p>In April, a top Vietnamese property tycoon sentenced to death in a $27 billion fraud case, launched an appeal against her conviction.</p>

<p>The head of one of Vietnam's top soft drinks companies, meanwhile, was jailed for eight years in April in a $40 million fraud case.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6jf8nq6g_court-room_625x300_22_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The tycoon is accused of illegally pocketing more than $146 million between 2017 and 2022.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-zealand-deaths-linked-to-online-suicide-kits-sold-by-canadian-chef-6158980]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 New Zealand Deaths Linked To Online "Suicide Kits" Sold By Canadian Chef]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/4-new-zealand-deaths-linked-to-online-suicide-kits-sold-by-canadian-chef-6158980]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 10:21:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New Zealand coroner has formally linked four deaths to the sale of "suicide kits" bought online from a former Canadian chef, according to findings published Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New Zealand coroner has formally linked four deaths to the sale of "suicide kits" bought online from a former Canadian chef, according to findings published Monday.</p>

<p>Coroner Alexandra Cunninghame found that three students, aged 18 to 21, and one 40-year-old personal trainer killed themselves after buying kits from businesses linked to Canadian <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canadian-man-charged-with-murder-for-assisting-100-suicides-across-40-nations-4659337">Kenneth Law</a>.</p>

<p>Canadian police believe Law sent as many as 1,200 "suicide kits" to people in more than 40 countries between 2020 and his arrest last year -- specifically targeting vulnerable people online.</p>

<p>Canadian prosecutors allege the kits contained a food additive that can kill if misused.</p>

<p>Law was arrested in May 2023 and charged in Canada with 14 counts of murder and a further 14 counts of aiding and counselling suicide.</p>

<p>He has denied the charges.</p>

<p>Alerted by Interpol, several other countries have launched investigations.</p>

<p>In Britain, at least 272 people purchased products from Law's websites and 88 of them died, police there have said.</p>

<p>In Italy, nine buyers have been identified and at least one victim has died.</p>

<p>The Canadian victims were both male and female between the ages of 16 and 36, according to police.</p>

<p>New Zealand's Suicide Prevention Office has asked internet service providers to block Law's website in New Zealand, the coroner added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/srfkddmo_kenneth-law-suicide-kits-x-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadian police believe Kenneth Law sent 1,200 "suicide kits" to people in more than 40 countries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-nancy-pelosi-yet-to-endorse-kamala-harris-for-presidential-job-6158594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Barack Obama, Nancy Pelosi Yet To Endorse Kamala Harris For Presidential Job]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obama-nancy-pelosi-yet-to-endorse-kamala-harris-for-presidential-job-6158594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 09:58:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Barack Obama, former Speaker Nancy Pelosi and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer have yet to make their stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Barack Obama, former Speaker Nancy Pelosi and Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer have yet to make their stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination. This even as a slew of Democrat Party leaders on Sunday displayed a show of support for Vice President Kamala Harris as their new presidential candidate, Politico reported.</p>

<p>Former President Barack Obama in a post on the platform Medium said "We will be navigating uncharted waters in the days ahead. But I have extraordinary confidence that the leaders of our party will be able to create a process from which an outstanding nominee emerges."</p>

<p>The statement, however, stops just short of officially backing Harris for the top job. Obama's endorsement of Harris will be critical given that the Democratic National Convention is being held between August 19 to 22 on Obama's home turf of Chicago.</p>

<p>Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi's reaction to the withdrawal of Joe Biden from the presidential race was one of effusive praise for Biden but had nothing to suggest that she had endorsed Harris.</p>

<p>"President Joe Biden is a patriotic American who has always put our country first. His legacy of vision, values and leadership make him one of the most consequential Presidents in American history. With love and gratitude to President Biden for always believing in the promise of America and giving people the opportunity to reach their fulfilment," she said on X.</p>

<p>After President Joe Biden endorsed her to be the new Presidential nominee, Harris got support from several Democrats like former President Bill Clinton, and former Democratic Presidential nominee Hillary Clinton. In a statement, the Clintons said "We are honoured to join the President in endorsing Vice President Harris and will do whatever to support her."</p>

<p>Congressman Ro Khanna also endorsed Kamla Harris saying "I am proud to endorse Kamala Harris as our nominee. Her trailblazing candidacy as the first African American woman and first Asian American will be a jolt of energy in our party. Our party can now run on a message of hope and a vision for the future."</p>

<p>Congressman Jim Clyburn representing South Carolina's 6th Congressional district said he echoed President Biden's endorsement of Harris.</p>

<p>"I echo the good judgement he demonstrated in selecting Vice President Harris to lead this nation alongside him, and I am proud today to follow his lead in support of her candidacy to succeed him as the Democratic Party's 2024 nominee for President," he said.</p>

<p>The goal now for the supporters of Harris is to get enough backers on board to help her win the nomination when the Democratic National Convention gets underway.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro, who has been spoken of as a potential Vice Presidential running mate to Harris called for the party to unite behind her and focus on winning the election.</p>

<p>"The best path forward for the Democratic Party is to quickly unite behind Vice President Harris and refocus on winning the presidency. the contrast in this race could not be clearer and the road to victory in November runs right through Pennsylvania this collective work began. I will do everything I can to help elect Kamala Harris as the 47th President of the United States," Shapiro said in a statement on X.</p>

<p>With barely a month to go before the Democratic party convenes in Chicago the task before them is tough, Donald Trump already has a head start and only a united front can hope to wrest the initiative from him.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/qmmgrfao_barack-obama-kamala-harris-facebook-ndtv-file-photo_625x300_12_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama is yet to make his stand clear on endorsing Kamala Harris for the Presidential nomination.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-on-joe-biden-dropping-out-of-2024-presidential-race-right-thing-to-do-6158649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Right Thing To Do": Indian-Americans On Biden Quitting Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-americans-on-joe-biden-dropping-out-of-2024-presidential-race-right-thing-to-do-6158649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 09:57:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden did the "right thing" by dropping out of the 2024 presidential race, prominent members of the Indian-American community have said, noting that this must have been a hard decision for him to make but one he took to put "America]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden did the “right thing” by dropping out of the 2024 presidential race, prominent members of the Indian-American community have said, noting that this must have been a hard decision for him to make but one he took to put “America first.”</p>

<p>Biden, 81, announced on Sunday that he decided to give up running for re-election as president of the United States and endorsed his deputy Harris to be the presidential nominee of the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>“While I acknowledge President Biden's decision to drop out of this race, I accept that decision as his last act to preserve American exceptionalism and as an ‘America First' decision,” New York-based eminent Indian-American attorney Ravi Batra told PTI.</p>

<p>"Thank you, Joe Biden, for doing what must have been the hardest decision for you, and yet what every soldier on the battlefield does - give our last best measure to America,” he said.</p>

<p>Al Mason, prominent New York-based global real estate advisor and entrepreneur who also advises international education institutions, said that it was expected that Biden would drop out of the 2024 presidential race.</p>

<p>“He did the right thing. He is a good man, but he could never win against Trump. In fact Biden's endorsed candidate Kamala Harris too cannot beat Trump. She has no appeal in the battleground states,” Mason said.</p>

<p>Batra said Biden has served the United States with distinction and his 50-year career, especially as Senate Foreign Relations chair and then as President Barack Obama's vice president are “remarkable”. He added that the citizens of the country are at their core not Democrats or Republicans or Independents but are Americans first.</p>

<p>Biden has done his “finest duty by dropping out, knowing that he cannot be a standard bearer for the Democratic Party and win against” Republican presidential nominee former US President Donald Trump who after being shot at during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, “in a moment of extreme personal crisis had the strength of heart and mind on the stage with a face bloodied to put up his fist and say ‘Fight'.” “After all, that's what all we Americans do. We fight for democracy. We fight for meritocracy, because if we don't fight it's all over. It's game over,” Batra said.</p>

<p>Mason said Trump is “impossible” to beat, even more so now with his 39-year-old Vice Presidential candidate Senator J D Vance, who has great appeal in states like Arizona, North Carolina, Michigan, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/368soaeo_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden decided to give up running for re-election as president of the United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-joins-presidential-race-who-will-be-her-running-mate-6158830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Kamala Harris Joins Presidential Race, Who Could Be Her Running Mate?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-kamala-harris-joins-presidential-race-who-will-be-her-running-mate-6158830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 09:52:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after President Joe Biden announced his decision to step down from the 2024 race to the White House, Vice President Kamala Harris, in a statement on X, said was "honored to have the President's endorsement"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after President Joe Biden announced his decision to step down from the 2024 race to the White House, Vice President Kamala Harris, in a statement on X, said was "honored to have the President's endorsement and my intention is to earn and win this nomination."</p>

<p>With Ms Harris' entry in the US Presidential elections, the speculation about who could be her Vice President pick has begun. Among the names doing the rounds is Arizona Senator Mark Kelly. Within minutes of Harris' post, Senator Kelly put out a message on the microblogging site X sharing his support for her. "Kamala Harris is the right person to defeat Donald Trump and lead the country into the future." he said.</p>

<p>Senator Kelly was elected in December 2020 as a senator from Arizonan to fill out the remainder of John McCain's term. A navy veteran, who served as a combat pilot in Operation Desert Storm in Iraq and Kuwait, the lawmaker is also a former NASA astronaut. His first space mission was in 2001 aboard Space Shuttle Endeavour and a decade later, he commanded the Space Shuttle's final mission.</p>

<p>Senator Kelly has taken on the Republicans over issues like abortion and said Trump and his running mate JD Vance need to be kept out of office to restore abortion rights. In October last year, he travelled to Tel Aviv with a group of Senators and was reported to have pledged support for Israel in its war against Hamas.</p>

<p>Another possible running mate for Ms Harris, North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper has also backed her nomination. "She has what it takes to defeat Donald Trump and lead our country thoughtfully and with integrity," he said.</p>

<p>With a background in law, he took over as Attorney General in 2000. He was elected Governor in 2016 and re-elected in 2020. Governor Cooper has worked to combat the opioid crisis in North Carolina and is credited with launching the state's first Opioid Action Plan in 2017. He also helped formulate Carolina's first children's health insurance initiative.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro also endorsed Harris even as his name cropped up as a possible Vice Presidential candidate. Governor Shapiro said he will do everything he can to help elect Kamala Harris as the 47th President of the United States. As the Governor of the state where Donald Trump was shot at a week ago, Governor Shapiro condemned the attack saying, "Violence targeted at any political party or political leader is absolutely unacceptable."</p>

<p>Governor Shapiro assumed the office of the Governor of Pennsylvania last year in January. In 2016, he &nbsp;was elected as Pennsylvania's Attorney General. In 2020, when the Republicans alleged the election was rigged, he defended Pennsylvania's election result, winning in court dozens of times before and after Election Day. During his tenure as Attorney General, he exposed the Catholic Church's decades-long cover up of child sexual abuse, identifying 301 predator priests and thousands of victims - and spurring investigations across the United States.</p>

<p>Kentucky Governor Andy Beshear is another leader speculated to be Ms Harris' running mate. At 46, he is one of the youngest Governors in US. Before being elected Governor, he served as the Attorney General. As Governor he has acted against legislation banning abortion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dr036ijg_kamala-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-african-police-uncover-multimillion-dollar-meth-lab-on-farm-6158412]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South African Police Uncover Multimillion-Dollar Meth Lab On Farm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-african-police-uncover-multimillion-dollar-meth-lab-on-farm-6158412]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 08:12:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The South African Police Service (SAPS) and the Directorate for Priority Crime Investigation, known as the Hawks, raided the property.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in South Africa have arrested four individuals, including two Mexican nationals, after discovering a multimillion-dollar drug manufacturing lab on a farm in the country's north, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/20/africa/south-african-police-uncover-meth-lab-farm-intl/index.html"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.</p>

<p>The South African Police Service (SAPS) and the Directorate for Priority Crime Investigation, known as the Hawks, raided the property in Groblersdal following reports of suspicious activity, according to a SAPS statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Upon searching four structures on the farm, police discovered large quantities of chemicals used in the production of illicit drugs, such as acetone and crystal meth, with an estimated street value of 2 billion South African rand ($109.4 million).</p>

<p>The four suspects arrested on Friday include the farm owner and two Mexican nationals. Police added that the Hawks are not ruling out the possibility of further arrests.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sapsHAWKS?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#sapsHAWKS</a> The Minister of Police, Mr Senzo Mchunu, MP, welcomed the outstanding arrests effected in the discovery of a clandestine drug lab worth R2 billion in Groblersdal on 19 July 2024 by a joint team of Limpopo Hawks and Limpopo SAPS. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/DrugsOffTheStreets?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#DrugsOffTheStreets</a> ML… <a href="https://t.co/9ErFydp0Th">pic.twitter.com/9ErFydp0Th</a></p>
— SA Police Service ?? (@SAPoliceService) <a href="https://twitter.com/SAPoliceService/status/1814626426521342258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>"What makes this different from other [seizures] is the involvement of Mexican citizens," Katlego Mogale, national spokesperson for the Hawks told Reuters, adding: "It means that our task has just become very difficult."</p>

<p>It is unclear whether the seized drugs were meant for the South African market or export.</p>

<p>The Mexican Ministry of Foreign Affairs stated that its embassy in South Africa had not received the necessary consular notification and is in contact with local authorities to gather details about the case and the alleged involvement of Mexicans.</p>

<p>The suspects are scheduled to appear in Groblersdal Magistrate's court on Monday to face charges of manufacturing, dealing, and possessing illicit drugs, according to the police.</p>

<p>In January, police reported that around 131 drug labs had been shut down across the country since 2019. During the festive season last year, more than 19,000 people were arrested for drug possession.</p>

<p>So far this year, the Hawks have discovered 10 secret drug labs and arrested 34 people as part of their ongoing war on drugs in the country, the statement said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7kvs3ip8_south-african-police_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police added that the Hawks are not ruling out the possibility of further arrests.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biggest-fundraising-day-for-democrat-group-after-biden-exits-2024-race-6158309]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hours After Biden Drops Out, Kamala Harris Receives $46 Million Donation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biggest-fundraising-day-for-democrat-group-after-biden-exits-2024-race-6158309]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 07:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic fundraising group ActBlue said Sunday evening that it had seen its biggest single-day haul of the 2024 election after US President Joe Biden dropped out and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic fundraising group ActBlue said Sunday evening that it had seen its biggest single-day haul of the 2024 election after US President Joe Biden dropped out and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"As of 9pm ET, grassroots supporters have raised $46.7 million through ActBlue following Vice President Kamala Harris' campaign launch. This has been the biggest fundraising day of the 2024 cycle," said a post on X by the group, which facilitates online fundraising for Democratic candidates.</p>

<p>Biden's withdrawal had been widely expected at some point. The announcement finally came with no warning as he recovered from Covid at his Delaware beach house.</p>

<p>In a letter posted on X, Biden said it had been the "greatest honor of my life" to be president. He said he would address the nation later this week. The White House later said he had no public events scheduled for Monday.</p>

<p>"While it has been my intention to seek reelection, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and focus solely on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term," he wrote.</p>

<p>Shortly after, he offered his "full support and endorsement" for Harris, with his campaign filing official notice to change its name to "Harris for President."</p>

<p>Endorsements began streaming in for Harris almost immediately from Democratic big shots as well as those seen as potential rivals for the nomination, such as California Governor Gavin Newsom.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/p4muj2a_joe-biden_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-american-billionaire-vinod-khosla-vs-elon-musk-over-donald-trump-as-us-president-6158231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Lies, Cheats, Rapes": Indian-Origin Billionaire vs Elon Musk Over Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-american-billionaire-vinod-khosla-vs-elon-musk-over-donald-trump-as-us-president-6158231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 07:22:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prominent Indian-American businessman Vinod Khosla and billionaire Elon Musk engaged in a war of words this morning after Joe Biden dropped out of the presidential race against Republican rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prominent Indian-American businessman Vinod Khosla and billionaire Elon Musk had a public war of words hours after US President Joe Biden dropped his re-election bid against Republican rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Biden has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party's new nominee</p>

<p>While the stunning move throws Democrats into fresh turmoil ahead of the November 5 election. But it could also reenergize the demoralized party, with Kamala Harris swiftly confirming her goal to become America's first woman president and to "defeat Donald Trump."</p>

<p>Soon after the announcement, Vinod Khosla called for an "open convention" for the Democrats to decide on "a more moderate" candidate.</p>

<p>Time to have an open convention and get a more moderate candidate who can easily beat @realDonaldTrump. @GovWhitmer and @GovernorShapiro would be a great thing for America not held hostage between MAGA extremists and DEI extremism. Unique opportunity for a better moderate path. Every socially liberal, climate and fiscal voter should want it to balance our approach,"&nbsp;&nbsp;the ace venture capitalist posted on X - earlier known as Twitter.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Time to have an open convention and get a more moderate candidate who can easily beat <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/GovWhitmer?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GovWhitmer</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/GovernorShapiro?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GovernorShapiro</a> would be a great thing for America not held hostage between MAGA extremists and DEI extremism. Unique opportunity for a better moderate path.…</p>
— Vinod Khosla (@vkhosla) <a href="https://twitter.com/vkhosla/status/1815092590787920377?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>Responding to the post, Elon Musk - the CEO of X, Tesla and SpaceX - made a strong pitch for former US president Donald Trump and his running mate JD Vance.</p>

<p>"Come on, Vinod. Trump/Vance LFG!!," Musk posted on X.</p>

<p>In response, Mr Khosla asked Elon Musk if he would want his children to be like the Republican presidential contender and said that he can't support someone (Donald Trump) who "lies, cheats and demeans women".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Hard for me to support someone with no values, lies, cheats, rapes, demeans women, hates immigrants like me. He may cut my taxes or reduce some regulation but that is no reason to accept depravity in his personal values. Do you want President who will set back climate by a decade in his first year? Do you want his example for your kids as values?," Mr Khosla said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hard for me to support someone with no values, lies, cheats, rapes, demeans women, hates immigrants like me. He may cut my taxes or reduce some regulation but that is no reason to accept depravity in his personal values. Do you want President who will set back climate by a… <a href="https://t.co/2E7FqQUjH2">https://t.co/2E7FqQUjH2</a></p>
— Vinod Khosla (@vkhosla) <a href="https://twitter.com/vkhosla/status/1815096257867923740?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>A venture capitalist, Vinod Khosla is the co-founder of Sun Microsystems. Mr Khosla is known to be a prominent Democratic political donor, and has contributed over $1.4 million in the current campaign.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Elon Musk shot back, saying Trump doesn't hate him. "In fact, I think he likes you. Meet him and find out for yourself. I'm not suggesting that Trump is without flaws, however we need an administration that is more likely to be meritocratic and promote individual freedoms over the heavy hand of government," he argued.</p>

<p>The Tesla CEO said many years ago, that was the Democratic Party, but now, "the pendulum has swung to the Republican Party".</p>

<p>Vinod Khosla replied: "But abandon climate and "drill baby drill? Be MAGA (Make America Great Again) and abandon NATO and American leadership and moral authority? I was a socially liberal registered fiscal Republican till climate made me switch to Independent."</p>

<p>Musk retorted that civilisation does need oil and gas for quite some time. "I don't think we should demonise an industry that is essential for humanity to function. However, as you know, sustainable energy production and consumption is growing very rapidly and is tracking to exceed use of hydrocarbon fuels. That will happen no matter what Trump does," he argued.</p>

<p>He further said that for NATO, the amount contributed by the United States is "absurdly higher than other allies".&nbsp;"Why are American taxpayers paying for the defense of Europe when Europe is fully capable of doing so itself?" said Musk.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/59v82oc8_trump_625x300_22_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has endorsed Kamala Harris as the Democratic Party's new nominee]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-trailblazer-eying-americas-last-glass-ceiling-6158160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Trailblazer Eyeing America's Last Glass Ceiling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-trailblazer-eying-americas-last-glass-ceiling-6158160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 07:03:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For years Kamala Harris faced criticism that she was not up to the job of being a heartbeat away from the US presidency. Now, she finds herself feted by Democrats as their best hope to stop Donald Trump's comeback.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For years Kamala Harris faced criticism that she was not up to the job of being a heartbeat away from the US presidency. Now, she finds herself feted by Democrats as their best hope to stop Donald Trump's comeback.</p>

<p>Despite blazing a trail as the first woman, Black and South Asian vice president in the nation's history, the 59-year-old Democrat long struggled with approval ratings as bad or worse than President Joe Biden's.</p>

<p>The last 12 months, however, have revealed a transformed Harris.</p>

<p>And with Biden's endorsement in hand, after he stunned the world by dropping his own reelection bid Sunday, she's suddenly on the cusp of history.</p>

<p>In a statement full of plaudits for Biden's achievements in office -- it was "unmatched in modern American history," she said -- Harris vowed to "earn and win" the nomination.</p>

<p>"I will do everything in my power to unite the Democratic Party -- and unite our nation -- to defeat Donald Trump," she said.</p>

<p>Harris will hope she has done the hard work to earn her full party's backing in the midst of the political crisis.</p>

<p>As the aging Biden seemed to visibly fade over the last year, his "veep" emerged as a force on the campaign trail, pushing for abortion rights and reaching out to core voters, including suburban women and Black men.</p>

<p>With a fondness for the f-bomb and her family nickname of "Momala" going viral, she has also finally started to cut through the noise to voters who previously paid scant attention.</p>

<p>Harris has won praise in party circles by staying loyal to the 81-year-old president even as political vultures began circling his candidacy.</p>

<p>She now appears likely to face Trump -- a brutal battle against a candidate who defeated Hillary Clinton in her bid to become the first female president in 2016.</p>

<h2>'Ready to serve'</h2>

<p>A child of immigrant parents -- her father was from Jamaica and her mother from India -- Harris grew up in Oakland, California, in an activist household that saw her attend her first rallies in a stroller.</p>

<p>Her focus on rights and justice saw her build an impressive CV, becoming California's first Black attorney general and the first woman of South Asian heritage elected to the US Senate.</p>

<p>Harris then went up against Biden in the 2020 primaries. In one stinging attack, she criticized him for allegedly opposing the busing of students to segregated schools.</p>

<p>"There was a little girl in California who was part of the second class to integrate her public schools, and she was bused to school every day. And that little girl was me," she said in a barbed attack on her future boss.</p>

<p>But as his running mate, she consolidated the coalition that helped defeat the incumbent Trump in 2020.</p>

<p>Her transition to the White House, however, proved difficult.</p>

<p>Critics said she was underwhelming and gaffe-prone in a job that has been known to flummox many officeholders.</p>

<p>Struggling to carve out a role, she was tasked by Biden with getting to the roots of the country's illegal migration problem, but fumbled and then got defensive in response to a question during a visit to the Mexican border.</p>

<p>Unusually high staff turnover fed rumors of discontent in the vice presidential office.</p>

<p>And Republicans -- often resorting to stereotypes her supporters branded as sexist and racist -- relentlessly targeted her as being unfit to take over, should the worst happen to America's oldest-ever president.</p>

<p>Harris told the Wall Street Journal in February: "I am ready to serve. There's no question about that."</p>

<h2>'Momala'</h2>

<p>Things began to change as the 2024 race got underway.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign repeatedly deployed Harris to battleground states to hammer home the party's message on abortion rights; she became the first vice president to visit an abortion clinic.</p>

<p>Gradually, she began to draw more engaged and fired-up crowds.</p>

<p>Some of the outreach was, however, cringe-inducing. Earlier this year, she was mocked after she told chat show host Drew Barrymore that her family sometimes called her "Momala," and Barrymore replied, "We need you to be Momala of the country."</p>

<p>But voters seemed to be switching on.</p>

<p>A clip of her quoting her mother as often saying, "You think you just fell out of a coconut tree?" became a meme, with a rising sense among supporters that now could be her time.</p>

<p>If elected, Harris would break one of the highest glass ceilings left for women in the United States -- that of occupying the country's top office.</p>

<p>Her husband, Douglas Emhoff, would also be breaking new ground, moving from being the current Second Gentleman to the country's first First Gentleman.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h0ho4s7g_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-republicans-call-for-joe-bidens-resignation-democrats-and-family-hail-legacy-6158130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Republicans Call For Biden's Resignation, Democrats Hail Legacy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-republicans-call-for-joe-bidens-resignation-democrats-and-family-hail-legacy-6158130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 06:54:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leading Democrats were quick to hail Joe Biden's legacy on Sunday after the US president's historic decision to end his reelection bid, while Republicans instead demanded his resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leading Democrats were quick to hail Joe Biden's legacy on Sunday after the US president's historic decision to end his reelection bid, while Republicans instead demanded his resignation.</p>

<p>From former presidents to current lawmakers, Biden's party faithful rallied around him as he passed the torch to Vice President Kamala Harris, endorsing her to take on Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Harris herself praised Biden's "selfless and patriotic act," saying in a statement that his accomplishments are "unmatched in modern American history, surpassing the legacy of many Presidents who have served two terms in office."</p>

<p>In a joint statement, former president Bill Clinton and ex-secretary of State Hillary Clinton said they "join millions of Americans in thanking President Biden for all that he accomplished."</p>

<p>With less than a month until the party's scheduled nominating convention, they too threw their weight behind Harris.</p>

<p>"Now is the time to support Kamala Harris and fight with everything we've got to elect her. America's future depends on it," the Clintons said.</p>

<p>Barack Obama, who picked then-senator Biden as his running mate in 2008, called him a "patriot of the highest order," but warned of "uncharted waters in the days ahead" -- and stopped short of endorsing Harris.</p>

<p>Former House speaker Nancy Pelosi, who still wields immense influence among Democratic lawmakers and had reportedly been pushing for Biden's exit, called him "a patriotic American who has always put our country first."</p>

<p>"His legacy of vision, values and leadership make him one of the most consequential Presidents in American history," the California representative said in a statement, expressing her "love and gratitude."</p>

<p>The two top Democratic leaders in Congress also praised Biden's legislative accomplishments without endorsing a replacement.</p>

<p>"President Joe Biden is one of the most accomplished and consequential leaders in American history," House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries said in a statement.</p>

<p>"His decision of course was not easy, but he once again put his country, his party, and our future first," Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer said.</p>

<h3><strong>Republican fury&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Republican leaders, including Trump, slammed Biden's presidency and called for the 81-year-old to resign.</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe Biden was not fit to run for President, and is certainly not fit to serve -- And never was! ... We will suffer greatly because of his presidency, but we will remedy the damage he has done very quickly. MAKE AMERICA GREAT AGAIN!" Trump, 78, posted on his Truth Social network.</p>

<p>Senator JD Vance, Trump's pick for running mate, said Biden "has been the worst President in my lifetime and Kamala Harris has been right there with him every step of the way."</p>

<p>House Speaker Mike Johnson meanwhile said that "if Joe Biden is not fit to run for president, he is not fit to serve as president."</p>

<p>"He must resign the office immediately," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>Many Republicans in recent days openly called for Biden, who was trailing Trump in polling, to stay in the race -- arguing replacing him would be "undemocratic."</p>

<p>Mitch McConnell, the top Senate Republican, claimed "the Democratic Party has been busy in recent weeks trying to upend the expressed will of the American people in primary elections across the country."</p>

<p>"We cannot afford four more years of failure," he added in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Family&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Biden's family offered loving support to their patriarch figure, as his five-decade political career now heads to a close.</p>

<p>First Lady Jill Biden reposted her husband's statement on X announcing his exit with a simple two-heart emoji.</p>

<p>Granddaughter Naomi Biden said on X she is "nothing but proud today of my Pop, our President, Joe Biden, who has served our country with every bit of his soul and with unmatched distinction."</p>

<p>Hunter Biden, the president's son, said his father's "unconditional love has been his North Star as a President, and as a parent."</p>

<p>His statement, shared by his daughter Naomi, concluded: "Thank you, Mr. President. I love you, Dad."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r5eouhrg_joe-biden-new_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republican leaders, including Donald Trump, slammed Joe Biden's presidency and called for him to resign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippines-china-reach-arrangement-for-south-china-sea-resupply-missions-6157948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Philippines, China Reach "Arrangement" For Reef Resupply Missions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/philippines-china-reach-arrangement-for-south-china-sea-resupply-missions-6157948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 05:54:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Philippines and China have agreed on an "arrangement" for resupplying Filipino troops stationed on a South China Sea reef, Manila said Sunday, after a series of escalating confrontations in the disputed waters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Philippines and China have agreed on an "arrangement" for resupplying Filipino troops stationed on a South China Sea reef, Manila said Sunday, after a series of escalating confrontations in the disputed waters.</p>

<p>A remote outpost on Second Thomas Shoal has been a focus of clashes between Chinese and Philippine ships in recent months as Beijing steps up efforts to push its claims to almost the entire South China Sea.</p>

<p>A Filipino sailor lost a thumb in the latest June 17 confrontation when Chinese coast guard members wielding knives, sticks and an axe foiled a Philippine Navy attempt to resupply its troops.</p>

<p>Sunday's announcement follows talks between the Philippines and China this month when they agreed to increase the number of communication channels to resolve maritime disagreements between them.</p>

<p>"The Philippines and the People's Republic of China have reached an understanding on the provisional arrangement for the resupply of daily necessities and rotation missions to the BRP Sierra Madre in Ayungin Shoal," the Philippine foreign ministry, using the Filipino name for Second Thomas Shoal.</p>

<p>The foreign ministry did not provide details of the arrangement, but said both sides recognised the need to "de-escalate the situation in the South China Sea and manage differences through dialogue and consultation".</p>

<p>China's embassy in Manila did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>A handful of Filipino troops are stationed on the rusty BRP Sierra Madre warship that was deliberately grounded on Second Thomas Shoal in 1999 to assert Manila's claims to the area.</p>

<p>They require frequent resupplies for food, water and other necessities as well as transport for personnel rotations.</p>

<p>Earlier Sunday, Manila said the resupply missions would remain a Philippine operation, after Washington vowed to "do what is necessary" to support them.</p>

<p>"As far as the RORE (rotation and resupply mission) is concerned, we're keeping it as a purely Philippine operation utilising Philippine ships, personnel and leadership," National Security Council assistant director-general Jonathan Malaya told AFP.</p>

<p>"That may change depending on the guidance from top management but that's the direction or policy at present."</p>

<p>Malaya's remarks came after White House National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan said the United States "will do what is necessary" to ensure the Philippines can continue to resupply its troops on the contested atoll.</p>

<p>"We will continue to support the Philippines and stand behind them as they take steps to be able to ensure that," Sullivan said during the Aspen Security Forum conference in Colorado.</p>

<p>Malaya said the National Security Council appreciated the US offer and the Philippines would continue consultations as treaty allies.</p>

<p>Manila has a mutual defence pact with the United States which requires both parties to come to the other's defence in case of an "armed attack" against vessels, aircraft, military and coast guard anywhere in the Pacific theatre, which Washington says includes the South China Sea.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/62pg4sd_philippines-and-china-agreement_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-at-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-view-on-key-business-topics-6157916]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Look At US Vice President Kamala Harris' View On Key Business Topics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-at-us-vice-president-kamala-harris-view-on-key-business-topics-6157916]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 05:41:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris is potentially poised to become the Democratic presidential nominee in the November election. Here are her views and actions related to some key business topics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris is potentially poised to become the Democratic presidential nominee in the November election. Here are her views and actions related to some key business topics.</p>

<h3><strong>Tech Regulation</strong></h3>

<p>As California attorney general, Harris sued eBay in 2012, alleging anticompetitive hiring practices surrounding a no-poaching agreement with Intuit that led to a nearly $4 million settlement in 2014.</p>

<p>In 2015, she compelled startup Houzz to hire a chief privacy officer after allegations that the home design app had recorded sales calls without proper notification and consent.</p>

<p>One of her signature issues was curtailing the distribution of pornography on social media, particularly "revenge porn," a practice involving the posting of explicit photos without the subject's consent. She took credit for a pressure campaign that led to Facebook, Alphabet's Google, Microsoft and others taking measures to remove certain explicit images.</p>

<p>"I cannot emphasize enough how leaders in technology have stepped up," said Harris at a news conference then. "I'm not suggesting any of them were happy to get a call from the AG saying, 'Come in, we want to talk with you.' But they all did. They did."</p>

<h3><strong>Big Tech</strong></h3>

<p>As a candidate for California attorney general, Harris reportedly assured potential donors that she was "a capitalist." She has generally been seen as cozy with prominent tech executives and investors, the local industry in her home Bay Area. She attended the wedding of Sean Parker, an early Facebook executive. Her brother-in-law, Tony West, is the chief legal officer for Uber.</p>

<p>She also accepted donations from Reid Hoffman, a prominent venture capitalist and co-founder of Linkedin, as well as billionaire John Doerr and venture capitalist Ron Conway. Big tech executives also supported her, including Sheryl Sandberg, then chief operating officer of Facebook, and Marc Benioff, the billionaire CEO of Salesforce.</p>

<h3><strong>Climate And Energy</strong></h3>

<p>Harris' climate and energy positions are similar to Biden's. But throughout her career she has made clear that clean energy and environmental justice are priorities.</p>

<p>When Biden announced Harris as his running mate in the 2020 race, he emphasized her tough stance against big oil when she served in key roles in California, noting lawsuits she had launched both as San Francisco's district attorney from 2004 to 2011 and then as the state's attorney general until January 2017, when she became a U.S. senator.</p>

<p>Last year, Harris made her debut at international climate negotiations, announcing a $3 billion commitment to the Green Climate Fund and making her first major international speech focused on climate.</p>

<p>As vice president, Harris has also been involved in Environmental Protection Agency policy rollouts that tackled long-standing environmental justice issues, such as a multibillion-dollar program to replace lead pipes and lead paint around the country.</p>

<h3><strong>Artificial Intelligence</strong></h3>

<p>As vice president, Harris has been particularly outspoken on artificial intelligence. She warned against the "existential" threat of AI and said it could "endanger the very existence of humanity," in a November 2023 address.</p>

<p>In meeting with tech execs like Microsoft's Satya Nadella, OpenAI's Sam Altman and Alphabet's Sundar Pichai, Harris warned that they have a "moral" obligation to guard against AI's possible dangers.</p>

<p>She backed an AI executive order from Biden that seeks stronger protections for consumers, singling out AI-generated scam calls and the impacts of unlabeled AI-generated content.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dr036ijg_kamala-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris' climate and energy positions are similar to Biden's]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tougher-tone-on-israel-steady-on-nato-what-a-kamala-harris-foreign-policy-could-look-like-6157890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What A Kamala Harris Foreign Policy Could Look Like]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tougher-tone-on-israel-steady-on-nato-what-a-kamala-harris-foreign-policy-could-look-like-6157890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 05:31:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris is expected to stick largely to Joe Biden's foreign policy playbook on key issues such as Ukraine, China and Iran but could strike a tougher tone with Israel over the Gaza war if she replaces the president at the top of t]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris is expected to stick largely to Joe Biden's foreign policy playbook on key issues such as Ukraine, China and Iran but could strike a tougher tone with Israel over the Gaza war if she replaces the president at the top of the Democratic ticket and wins the U.S. November election.</p>

<p>As the apparent frontrunner for the nomination after Biden dropped out of the race and endorsed her on Sunday, Harris would bring on-the-job experience, personal ties forged with world leaders, and a sense of global affairs gained during a Senate term and as Biden's second-in-command.</p>

<p>But running against Republican candidate Donald Trump she would also have a major vulnerability - a troubled situation at the U.S.-Mexico border that has bedeviled Biden and become a top campaign issue. Harris was tasked at the start of his term with addressing the root causes of high irregular migration, and Republicans have sought to make her the face of the problem.</p>

<p>On a range of global priorities, said analysts, a Harris presidency would resemble a second Biden administration.</p>

<p>"She may be a more energetic player but one thing you shouldn't expect - any immediate big shifts in the substance of Biden's foreign policy," said Aaron David Miller, a former Middle East negotiator for Democratic and Republican administrations.</p>

<p>Harris has signaled, for instance, that she would not deviate from Biden's staunch support for NATO and would continue backing Ukraine in its fight against Russia. That stands in sharp contrast to a pledge by former president Trump to fundamentally alter the U.S. relationship with the alliance and the doubts he has raised about future weapons supplies to Kyiv.</p>

<h3><strong>Staying On The Course On China?</strong></h3>

<p>A lawyer by training and a former California attorney general, Harris struggled in the first half of Biden's term to find her footing, not helped by being saddled early on with a major part of the intractable immigration portfolio amid record crossings at the U.S.-Mexico border.</p>

<p>That followed a failed 2020 presidential campaign that was widely considered lackluster.</p>

<p>If she becomes the nominee, Democrats will be hoping Harris will be more effective at communicating her foreign policy goals.</p>

<p>In the second half of Biden's presidency, Harris - the country's first Black and Asian American vice president - has elevated her profile on issues ranging from China and Russia to Gaza and become a known quantity to many world leaders.</p>

<p>At this year's Munich Security Conference she delivered a tough speech slamming Russia for its invasion of Ukraine and pledging "ironclad" U.S. respect for NATO's Article 5 requirement for mutual self-defense.</p>

<p>On China, Harris has long positioned herself within Washington's bipartisan mainstream on the need for the U.S. to counter China's influence, especially in Asia. She would likely maintain Biden's stance of confronting Beijing when necessary while also seeking areas of cooperation, analysts say.</p>

<p>Harris has made several trips aimed at boosting relations in the economically dynamic region, including one to Jakarta in September to fill in for Biden at a summit of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN). During the visit, Harris accused China of trying to coerce smaller neighbors with its territorial claims in the disputed South China Sea.</p>

<p>Biden also dispatched Harris on travels to shore up alliances with Japan and South Korea, key allies who have had reason to worry about Trump's commitment to their security.</p>

<p>"She demonstrated to the region that she was enthusiastic to promote the Biden focus on the Indo-Pacific," said Murray Hiebert, a senior associate of the Southeast Asia Program at Washington's Center for Strategic and International Studies.</p>

<p>While she could not match the "diplomatic chops" Biden had developed over decades, "she did fine," he added.</p>

<p>However, like her boss, Harris has been prone to the occasional verbal gaffe. On a tour of the Demilitarized Zone between South and North Korea in September 2022 to reassert Washington's support for Seoul, she mistakenly touted a U.S. "alliance with the Republic of North Korea," which aides later corrected.</p>

<p>If Harris becomes her party's standard-bearer and can overcome Trump's lead in pre-election opinion polls to win the White House, the Israel-Palestinian conflict would rank high on her agenda, especially if the Gaza war is still raging.</p>

<p>Although as vice president she has mostly echoed Biden in firmly backing Israel's right to defend itself after Hamas carried out a deadly cross-border raid on Oct. 7, she has at times stepped out slightly ahead of the president in criticizing Israel's military approach.</p>

<p>In March, she bluntly criticized Israel, saying it was not doing enough to ease a "humanitarian catastrophe" during its ground offensive in the Palestinian enclave. Later that month, she did not rule out "consequences" for Israel if it launched a full-scale invasion of refugee-packed Rafah in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>Such language has raised the possibility that Harris, as president, might take at least a stronger rhetorical line with Israel than Biden, analysts say.</p>

<p>While her 81-year-old boss has a long history with a succession of Israeli leaders and has even called himself a "Zionist," Harris, 59, lacks his visceral personal connection to the country.</p>

<p>She maintains closer ties to Democratic progressives, some of whom have pressed Biden to attach conditions to U.S. weapons shipments to Israel out of concern for high Palestinian civilian casualties in the Gaza conflict.</p>

<p>But analysts do not expect there would be a big shift in U.S. policy toward Israel, Washington's closest ally in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Halie Soifer, who served as national security adviser to Harris during the then-senator's first two years in Congress, from 2017 to 2018, said Harris' support of Israel has been just as strong as Biden's. "There really has been no daylight to be found" between the two, she said.</p>

<h3><strong>Iran Nuclear Threat</strong></h3>

<p>Harris could also be expected to hold firm against Israel's regional arch-foe, Iran, whose recent nuclear advances have drawn increased U.S. condemnation.</p>

<p>Jonathan Panikoff, formerly the U.S. government's deputy national intelligence officer for the Middle East, said the growing threat of "weaponization" of Iran's nuclear program could be an early major challenge for a Harris administration, especially if Tehran decides to test the new U.S. leader.</p>

<p>After a series of failed attempts, Biden has shown little interest in returning to negotiations with Tehran over resuming the 2015 international nuclear agreement, which Trump abandoned during his presidency.</p>

<p>Harris, as president, would be unlikely to make any major overtures without serious signs that Iran is ready to make concessions.</p>

<p>Even so, Panikoff, now at the Atlantic Council think tank in Washington, said: "There's every reason to believe the next president will have to deal with Iran. It's bound to be one of the biggest problems."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/scc1vsuo_kamala-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Harris presidency would resemble a second Biden administration.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidens-exit-from-us-election-offers-opportunities-pitfalls-for-democrats-6157831]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden's Exit From US Election Offers Opportunities, Pitfalls For Democrats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bidens-exit-from-us-election-offers-opportunities-pitfalls-for-democrats-6157831]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 05:18:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden's withdrawal from the US election offers Democrats the precious opportunity for a late reset in a campaign that was going badly -- but ushers in an uncertain few weeks that will make or break their chances against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden's withdrawal from the US election offers Democrats the precious opportunity for a late reset in a campaign that was going badly -- but ushers in an uncertain few weeks that will make or break their chances against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>Grassroots voters will hope to be better served than they were during the initial nomination race, when Democrats put up no serious competition to the 81-year-old president's candidacy despite worries over his age.</p>

<p>"Remarkable leadership shown by Joe Biden. Now it falls to the (Democrats) to show equal leadership by having an open process to determine the best candidate(s) to take on Trump-Vance in November," said entrepreneur Andrew Yang, who ran against Biden for the party's nomination in 2020.</p>

<p>"The goal should be simple -- to win," he wrote on X.</p>

<p>With Biden's endorsement, Vice President Kamala Harris, 59, starts out in the strongest position to replace him and may be able to consolidate support in the coming days -- a coronation that would allow Democrats to turn their fire on Trump.</p>

<p>If that doesn't happen then a chaotic -- and potentially damaging -- fight for the votes of almost 4,000 delegates at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago in just four weeks looks more likely.</p>

<p>The party's national chairman Jaime Harrison promised a "transparent and orderly process" to replace Biden, the first president since Democrat Lyndon B. Johnson in 1968 not to seek a second term.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala the prosecutor</strong></h3>

<p>His campaign began collapsing after his dismal debate performance against Trump last month prompted concerns over his advanced years and mental capacity.</p>

<p>Trump, who would be 82 at the end of a second term, appeared more robust -- but opposition from a younger candidate would turn the spotlight on his speeches and interviews, where he often appears incoherent and confuses names.</p>

<p>Several rising Democratic stars -- all younger than 60 -- have been floated as Biden alternatives, including governors Josh Shapiro, Gretchen Whitmer and Gavin Newsom.</p>

<p>Whitmer immediately appeared to suggest she would not be running and Newsom has previously said he would not challenge Harris, but neither explicitly ruled themselves out.</p>

<p>A campaign led by Harris and backed up by a moderate midwestern running mate could present the best chance for Democrats -- helping turn out more women, who historically vote in greater numbers than men and are a weakness for Trump.</p>

<p>Harris would also give Democrats a chance to redefine the race at their convention as a clash of cultures between a former prosecutor and a convicted felon.</p>

<p>"While she has largely been in the shadows for the last four years it is time for Kamala the prosecutor... to make her comeback," said Sara Sadhwani, an assistant professor of politics at Pomona College in Claremont, California.</p>

<p>A new survey from Democratic polling firm Public Policy Polling released Thursday found that Harris -- with the right running mate -- could defeat Trump and Vance in Pennsylvania and Michigan, two of the three "Blue Wall" states seen as critical to electing a Democratic president.</p>

<h3><strong>Clean break?</strong></h3>

<p>Ryan Waite, a political marketing expert from Brigham Young University-Idaho, told AFP a contested nomination might actually benefit Democrats by depriving Trump of headlines for several months.</p>

<p>"A new Democrat candidate will benefit from a short vetting window and significant earned media impact right before the election," he told AFP. "The story is now who will it be and that will take the air out of the room through their convention."</p>

<p>Any new nominee other than Harris would represent a clean break and be immune from much of the criticism directed at the Biden administration over high inflation, the border crisis and the chaotic withdrawal from Afghanistan.</p>

<p>But while Harris would likely inherit all of the Biden campaign's cash reserves -- about $94 million as of July -- other candidates may have to share the money with down-ballot candidates.</p>

<p>They would also have to make the case anew for endorsements from some of the Biden-Harris campaign's most influential backers, such as the United Auto Workers union. Harris herself could also face this problem, of course.</p>

<p>Republicans have suggested that they might challenge any late substitutions in the courts but Marc Elias, the Democrats' top election lawyer vowed that the eventual nominee would be on all 50 state ballots.</p>

<p>"There is no basis for any legal challenge. Period," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/j9gprgd_biden-harris_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several rising Democratic stars have been floated as Biden alternatives (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-democratic-party-us-state-chairs-back-kamala-harris-to-be-presidential-nominee-report-6157801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All Democratic Party US State Chairs Back Harris To Be Presidential Nominee]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-democratic-party-us-state-chairs-back-kamala-harris-to-be-presidential-nominee-report-6157801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 05:05:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[All 50 Democratic party state chairs have thrown their weight behind Vice President Kamala Harris to be the party's new presidential nominee, according to sources familiar with the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All 50 Democratic party state chairs have thrown their weight behind Vice President Kamala Harris to be the party's new presidential nominee, according to sources familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>The chairs held a conference call on Sunday after President Joe Biden announced he was stepping aside as the party's candidate.</p>

<p>There was "full support" in backing Harris to be at the top of the ticket, one source said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/117kg64_kamala-harris-new_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There was "full support" in backing Harris to be at the top of the ticket, one source said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-vow-huge-retaliation-against-israel-for-deadly-port-strike-6157740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthis Vow "Huge" Retaliation Against Israel For Deadly Port Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-vow-huge-retaliation-against-israel-for-deadly-port-strike-6157740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 04:42:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi rebels on Sunday promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel for a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as regional fallout widens from months of war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthi rebels on Sunday promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel for a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as regional fallout widens from months of war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Israeli strike, the first claimed by Israel in Yemen, set oil tanks ablaze at the vital port and came a day after the first fatal attack by the Houthis in Israel.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Israel said it intercepted a missile fired from Yemen and struck targets in southern Lebanon. Residents of southern Gaza reported combat in the Rafah area.</p>

<p>The fighting across the region came ahead of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's trip this week to Washington, which has been trying to secure a ceasefire in the more than nine-month war between Israel and Palestinian militants Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Netanyahu's office said he was sending a negotiating team -- it was unclear where -- for new talks on a deal under which hostages held by Hamas would be freed.</p>

<p>But Saudi Arabia's foreign ministry warned Israel's attack on Hodeida "aggravates the current tension in the region and halts the ongoing efforts to end the war in Gaza".</p>

<p>Dozens have been killed since Saturday across Gaza, the civil defence agency in the Hamas-run territory said, including in strikes on homes in the central Nuseirat and Bureij areas and near southern Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Residents said a major operation was underway in a district west of Rafah, where they reported heavy artillery and clashes.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Abdul Malik al-Houthi, chief of the Iran-backed group, said the Hodeida strikes would lead to "further escalation and more attacks targeting Israel". He said the deadly Houthi drone attack on Tel Aviv had opened "a new phase" in operations.</p>

<p>Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree said the rebels' "response to the Israeli aggression against our country is inevitably coming and will be huge".</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said the fire left raging by the strikes on rebel-held Hodeida port "is seen across the Middle East and the significance is clear".</p>

<p>Gallant warned of further operations if the Houthis "dare to attack us" after the rebel strike hit Tel Aviv, at least 1,800 kilometres (1,119 miles) from Yemen.</p>

<p>It appeared to be the first to pierce Israel's intricate air defences but an analyst said Houthi drones do not pose a "strategic threat" to Israel.</p>

<h3><strong>Fuel storage tanks</strong></h3>

<p>In Hodeida, six people were killed and 83 wounded, health officials said in a statement carried by Houthi media.</p>

<p>AFPTV images showed heavy flames and black smoke spiralling into the sky from burning oil tanks. Debris covered the dock where equipment was damaged.</p>

<p>Hodeida port is a vital entry point for fuel imports and international aid for rebel-held areas of Yemen, a country where the United Nations says more than half the population needs humanitarian assistance.</p>

<p>Analysts say the strike on Hodeida will likely only embolden the Houthis. They have already withstood since January repeated United States and British strikes aimed at deterring recurrent Houthi attacks on shipping.</p>

<p>The rebels also endured thousands of air raids during nearly a decade of war against forces backing Yemen's internationally-recognised government.</p>

<p>On Sunday, the Israeli military said it had intercepted a missile fired from Yemen towards the Red Sea resort town of Eilat. The rebel spokesman said ballistic missiles were fired towards the port.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, Iran-backed and Hamas-allied Hezbollah said it fired Katyusha rockets and drones at northern Israel after Israeli strikes hit a weapons depot and wounded six civilians.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, which reported three more of its fighters killed, said Israel's strikes on its Yemeni allies marked "a new, dangerous phase".</p>

<h3><strong>Netanyahu to Washington</strong></h3>

<p>The Gaza war was triggered by Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 42 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Vowing to destroy Hamas, Israel has killed at least 38,983 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the Gaza health ministry.</p>

<p>The war has left most of Gaza's population displaced, much of the housing and other infrastructure destroyed, and essential goods in short supply as the UN says diseases are spreading.</p>

<p>Israel has started vaccinating its troops in Gaza against polio and supplying vaccines for the Palestinian population after health agencies said the virus was found there, the military said.</p>

<p>The war has brought Israelis to the streets, sometimes in their tens of thousands, demanding a deal to free remaining hostages.</p>

<p>On Sunday they protested at Ben Gurion International Airport near Tel Aviv ahead of Netanyahu's meetings in the United States where he will be under pressure to reach a ceasefire with Hamas.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ddur9gvg_hodeida-port_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Hodeida, six people were killed and 83 wounded]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reactions-to-president-joe-bidens-decision-to-not-seek-re-election-6157688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How US Reacted To President Joe Biden's Decision To Not Seek Re-Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reactions-to-president-joe-bidens-decision-to-not-seek-re-election-6157688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 04:26:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden on Sunday ended his reelection campaign. He said in a letter posted on social media platform X that he would remain in office until the end of his term and address the country later this week on his decision.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. President Joe Biden on Sunday ended his reelection campaign. He said in a letter posted on social media platform X that he would remain in office until the end of his term and address the country later this week on his decision.</p>

<p>Below are reactions from politicians, industry and advocacy groups and other observers.</p>

<h3><strong>Vice President Kamala Harris</strong></h3>

<p>"I am honored to have the president's endorsement and my intention is to earn and win this nomination," Harris said in a statement. "I will do everything in my power to unite the Democratic Party - and unite our nation - to defeat Donald Trump and his extreme Project 2025 agenda."</p>

<h3><strong>Former President Donald Trump</strong></h3>

<p>In a phone call with CNN minutes after Biden announced his exit from the 2024 race, former President Trump responded, "He is the worst president in the history of our country. He goes down as the single worst president by far in the history of our country." Trump also said he thought Vice President Kamala Harris will be easier to defeat than Biden would have been, according to CNN.</p>

<h3><strong>Former President Barack Obama</strong></h3>

<p>"I also know Joe has never backed down from a fight. For him to look at the political landscape and decide that he should pass the torch to a new nominee is surely one of the toughest in his life. But I know he wouldn't make this decision unless he believed it was right for America," the former president said in a statement. "I have extraordinary confidence that the leaders of our party will be able to create a process from which an outstanding nominee emerges."</p>

<h3><strong>Chuck Schumer, Senate Majority Leader</strong></h3>

<p>"Joe Biden has not only been a great president and a great legislative leader but he is a truly amazing human being. His decision of course was not easy, but he once again put his country, his party, and our future first. Joe, today shows you are a true patriot and great American," the Democrat said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Elise Stefanik, House Republican Conference Chairwoman</strong></h3>

<p>"If Joe Biden can't run for re-election, he is unable and unfit to serve as President of the United States. He must immediately resign," Stefanik said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Independent Presidential Candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr.</strong></h3>

<p>"I commend President Biden for stepping down. His infirmities were evident to any unbiased observer from the beginning. It was this progressive deterioration - and his abandonment of Democratic Party principles - that prompted me to enter the race and ensure American voters had a viable, vigorous alternative to Donald Trump," Kennedy said in a post on X.</p>

<h3><strong>Hakeem Jeffries, House Democratic Leader</strong></h3>

<p>"America is a better place today because President Joe Biden has led us with intellect, grace and dignity. We are forever grateful," Jeffries said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Steve Scalise, House Majority Leader</strong></h3>

<p>"Democrat party bosses just proved that they have absolutely no respect for their own voters. After lecturing others about democracy, they just forced Joe Biden off the ticket-trashing the primary choice of 14 million of their own voters," Scalise, a Republican, said on X.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Congressional Black Caucus Political Action Committee</strong></h3>

<p>"Americans and democracy-loving people world owe Joe Biden a debt of gratitude. The Congressional Black Caucus PAC joins President Biden in fully supporting Kamala Harris as our party's nominee," the organization said in a statement posted to X.</p>

<h3><strong>Nancy Pelosi, Former House Speaker</strong></h3>

<p>"President Joe Biden is a patriotic American who has always put our country first. His legacy of vision, values and leadership make him one of the most consequential Presidents in American history. With love and gratitude to President Biden for always believing in the promise of America and giving people the opportunity to reach their fulfillment. God blessed America with Joe Biden's greatness and goodness."</p>

<h3><strong>Gavin Newsom, Governor Of California</strong></h3>

<p>"President Biden has been an extraordinary, history-making president - a leader who has fought hard for working people and delivered astonishing results for all Americans. He will go down in history as one of the most impactful and selfless presidents," Newsom posted on X.</p>

<h3><strong>Nanette Barragan, Chair Of The Congressional Hispanic Caucus</strong></h3>

<p>"I am with you @JoeBiden - I endorse @KamalaHarris as our Democratic nominee &amp; will work tirelessly to make sure she is elected our next President in November," Barragán said in a post on X.</p>

<h3><strong>South Carolina Democratic Congressman Jim Clyburn</strong></h3>

<p>"I echo the good judgment [President Biden] demonstrated in selecting Vice President Harris to lead this nation alongside him, and I am proud to follow his lead in support of her candidacy to succeed him as the Democratic Party's 2024 nominee for president," Clyburn said in a statement</p>

<h3><strong>Andy Beshear, Governor Of Kentucky</strong></h3>

<p>Beshear, whose name has also been floated as a possible contender as president or vice president, praised Biden for acting "in the best interest of our country, and our party" and "for a successful presidency that got big, important things done."</p>

<p>"Now it is time for our nation to come together," he added in his post on X.</p>

<h3><strong>Peter Welch, US Senator</strong></h3>

<p>Welch, the first Democratic Senator to call on Joe Biden to drop his reelection run, on Sunday praised the president for ending his quest, saying he showed "good judgment and great humility" and "put the country first."</p>

<p>"It was an agonizing decision," Welch said in an interview with Reuters. "Every fiber of his being wanted to continue to fight and to beat Trump again."</p>

<p>Welch declined to endorse Harris, who he acknowledged was the frontrunner to replace Biden.</p>

<p>The Democrats should have "an open process so that whoever our nominee is, including Kamala, has the strength of having a process that shows the consensus position of the party," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Barbara Lee, US Representative</strong></h3>

<p>Lee, a former chair of the Congressional Black Caucus, said in a phone interview there is "no other option" but to choose Harris as the party's nominee.</p>

<p>"She is the best vice president," Lee said. "She is experienced, capable and smart. She has been a part of the Biden-Harris legacy that needs to continue."</p>

<h3><strong>Gretchen Whitmer, Governor Of Michigan</strong></h3>

<p>"President Biden is a great public servant who knows better than anyone what it takes to defeat Donald Trump. His remarkable work to lower prescription drug costs, fix the damn roads, bring supply chains home, address climate change, and ensure America's global leadership over decades will go down in history. My job in this election will remain the same: doing everything I can to elect Democrats and stop Donald Trump, a convicted felon whose agenda of raising families' costs, banning abortion nationwide, and abusing the power of the White House to settle his own scores is completely wrong for Michigan," Whitmer said on X.</p>

<h3><strong>United Auto Workers</strong></h3>

<p>"Vice President Kamala Harris walked the picket line with us in 2019, and along with President Biden has brought work and jobs back to communities like Lordstown, Ohio, and Belvidere, Illinois. That's the legacy President Biden leaves and that's the work we will continue to build on as a union," the union said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>Dick Durbin, Senator And Majority Whip</strong></h3>

<p>"Throughout his public career, Joe Biden always put country first. His four years as President made it clear that he was determined to put our country back on track and restore the soul of our nation. America will be forever grateful for all he has given to this country," Durbin posted on X.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>The Clintons</strong></h3>

<p>"We are honored to join the President in endorsing Vice President Harris and will do whatever we can to support her," the Clintons said in a statement. &nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/c16a9oko_biden_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden ended his reelection campaign on Sunday after fellow Democrats lost faith in his mental acuity]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>