<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 08:23:27 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-photos-show-iran-expanding-missile-production-report-6061393]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Photos Show Iran Expanding Missile Production: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-photos-show-iran-expanding-missile-production-report-6061393]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 07:26:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Recent satellite imagery shows major expansions at two key Iranian ballistic missile facilities that two American researchers assessed are for boosting missile production, a conclusion confirmed by three senior Iranian officials.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recent satellite imagery shows major expansions at two key Iranian ballistic missile facilities that two American researchers assessed are for boosting missile production, a conclusion confirmed by three senior Iranian officials.</p>

<p>The enlargement of the sites follows an October 2022 deal in which Iran agreed to provide missiles to Russia, which has been seeking them for its war against Ukraine. Tehran also supplies missiles to Yemen's Houthi rebels and the Lebanese militia Hezbollah, both members of the Iran-backed Axis of Resistance against Israel, according to U.S. officials.</p>

<p>Images taken by commercial satellite firm Planet Labs of the Modarres military base in March and the Khojir missile production complex in April show more than 30 new buildings at the two sites, both of which are located near Tehran.</p>

<p>The images, reviewed by Reuters, show many of the structures are surrounded by large dirt berms. Such earthworks are associated with missile production and are designed to stop a blast in one building from detonating highly combustible materials in nearby structures, said Jeffrey Lewis of the Middlebury Institute of International Studies at Monterey.</p>

<p>The expansions began at Khojir in August last year and at Modarres in October, Lewis said, based on images of the sites.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran's arsenal is already the largest in the Middle East, estimated at more than 3,000 missiles, including models designed to carry conventional and nuclear warheads, experts say.</p>

<p>Three Iranian officials, who asked not to be identified because they were not authorized to speak publicly, confirmed that Modarres and Khojir are being expanded to boost production of conventional ballistic missiles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Why shouldn't we?" said one official.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A second Iranian official said some of the new buildings would also allow a doubling of drone manufacturing. Drones and missile components would be sold to Russia, drones would be provided to the Houthis and missiles to Hezbollah, the source added.</p>

<p>Reuters was unable independently to confirm the Iranian officials' comments.</p>

<p>Iran's mission to the United Nations did not respond to a Reuters request for comment on the expansion of the complexes. Tehran has previously denied providing drones and missiles to Russia and the Houthis. Hezbollah's media office did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Houthi spokesperson Mohammed Abdulsalam said a boost in Iran's weapons manufacturing would not have any impact in Yemen because the Houthis develop and manufacture aircraft independent of Iran.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lewis analyzed the Planet Labs imagery with Decker Eveleth, an associate research analyst at CNA, a Washington thinktank, as part of a Middlebury project that monitors Iranian missile infrastructure.</p>

<p>"We know that Russia is on the hunt for low-cost missile capabilities, and it has gone to Iran and North Korea," said Lewis.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moscow and Pyongyang&nbsp;have denied the transfer of North Korean missiles to Russia. The Russian embassy in Washington and North Korea's mission to the United Nations did not immediately respond to requests for comment for this story.</p>

<p>The two U.S. researchers said in separate interviews that it was not clear from the photos what kinds of missiles would be produced at the new facilities, which still appeared to be under construction.</p>

<p>Any increase in Tehran's missile or drone production would be concerning to the United States, which has said that Iranian drones help sustain Russia's assault on Ukrainian cities, and to Israel as it fends off attacks from Iran-backed groups, including Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The U.S. Office of the Director of National Intelligence declined to comment on the reseachers' analysis.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A U.S. National Security Council spokesperson declined to confirm their assessment, adding that the United States has implemented various measures, including sanctions, intended to constrain Iranian missile and drone production and exports.</p>

<p>&nbsp;Reuters in February reported that Iran had sent surface-to-surface ballistic missiles to Russia for use against Ukraine. Iran denied providing the weapons. Washington said it could not confirm the transfers but it assumed Tehran intended to provide missiles to Moscow.</p>

<p><strong>NEW BUILDINGS, DIRT BERMS&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Shahid Modarres and Khojir are overseen by the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), the elite paramilitary organization that plays a central role in Iran's missile and nuclear programs. It controls large segments of the Iranian economy and answers directly to Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>

<p>The complexes have long been associated with the development and production of Iran's short- and medium-range ballistic missiles and rockets for the country's space program.</p>

<p>On Nov. 12, 2011, a massive explosion destroyed a large swath of Shadid Modarres associated with solid fuel missiles, killing 17 IRGC officers. They included Gen. Hassan Moqaddam, regarded by Iran as the "architect" of its ballistic missile program.</p>

<p>Construction at Shahid Modarres, which began again after the 2011 explosion, accelerated last year, the second Iranian official said.</p>

<p>"I think the Iranians may have chosen not to berm the buildings (before the explosion) because they didn't want to draw attention to them," said Lewis. "They learned the hard way."</p>

<p>Eveleth and Lewis said the sites' long history with Iran's missile program – Shahid Modarres is considered by some experts as its birthplace - and the numerous dirt berms support their assessment that Tehran is expanding ballistic missile production.</p>

<p>"When we see where you basically have an entire production line that is bermed like that, that's usually missiles," said Eveleth.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5urkctb8_iran-missile-production-reuters_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The images show many of the structures are surrounded by large dirt berms.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-bar-owner-gets-13-years-in-jail-for-raping-minor-in-singapore-6064237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Bar Owner Gets 13 Years Jail For Raping Minor In Singapore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-bar-owner-gets-13-years-in-jail-for-raping-minor-in-singapore-6064237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:38:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian-origin Singaporean bar owner was sentenced to jail for 13 years and four weeks on Monday and will receive nine strokes of the cane for raping a runaway 17-year-old girl after allowing her to work for him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin Singaporean bar owner was sentenced to jail for 13 years and four weeks on Monday and will receive nine strokes of the cane for raping a runaway 17-year-old girl after allowing her to work for him.</p>

<p>Raj Kumar Bala, 42, was convicted of a charge each of raping and molesting the victim and pleaded guilty to a third charge of harbouring a runaway under the Children and Young Persons Act, Channel News Asia reported.</p>

<p>Defence lawyer Ramesh Tiwary said his client has asked to be released on bail pending appeal, according to the channel's report.</p>

<p>The court heard that the victim was 17 in February 2020 when she ran away from the Singapore Girls' Home.</p>

<p>She found out about a job opportunity at Bala's Don Bar and Bistro in Dunlop Street in the Little India precinct of hotels, motels and eateries through another runaway who was working there.</p>

<p>The other runaway was also sexually assaulted by Bala in a charge that stood down for the time being.</p>

<p>The victim went down to the bar to interview for the job and met Bala, who described the job duties to her, including serving customers and making drinks.</p>

<p>He offered her the role, saying she could stay at the bar with other runaways.</p>

<p>The victim worked at the bar for a few days, but police received a tip-off about people who absconded and worked there. They raided the place in the early hours of February 22, 2020.</p>

<p>The victim fled with another girl to escape the raid, before being picked up by Bala.</p>

<p>He drove them to his condominium, telling them they could stay there, before drinking alcohol with the girls.</p>

<p>He raped the victim while she was heavily intoxicated and also engaged in sex acts with the other girl.</p>

<p>The victim left the condo and surrendered herself to the home in July 2020, but told her case worker only in August 2020 that she was raped.</p>

<p>Justice Mavis Chionh noted the "considerable personal harm" inflicted on the victim, who blames herself as to how she came to be in an intoxicated state that led to her rape.</p>

<p>Her testimony in court, which was corroborated by her former boyfriend, illustrated how the trauma from her past would be revived in a way that negatively affects her well-being, the judge noted.</p>

<p>She said Bala knew that the victim was young and on the run from police, and she was dependent on him for income and shelter.</p>

<p>Bala faces other pending charges and is yet to make a decision on what he intends to do with them, according to the report.</p>

<p>The bar owner faces 22 more charges relating to five other victims, mainly for sex offences, according to a report by "The Straits Times". These charges are pending in court.</p>

<p>He is accused of raping and molesting a victim identified in court documents as B1, raping and sexually assaulting a victim identified as B5 and raping, molesting and threatening another victim identified as B6.</p>

<p>He is also accused of sexually penetrating a minor under the age of 16, identified as B7, and molesting and causing alarm to another victim, identified as B8. PTI GS RC</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/0htt5beg_india-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-a-strategic-partner-says-us-ahead-of-pm-modi-putin-bilateral-talks-6064135]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India A Strategic Partner, Says US Ahead Of PM Modi-Putin Bilateral Talks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-a-strategic-partner-says-us-ahead-of-pm-modi-putin-bilateral-talks-6064135]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 06:00:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is a strategic partner with whom it engages in a full and frank dialogue, the United States said on Monday as Prime Minister Narendra Modi held a bilateral meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;India is a strategic partner with whom it engages in a full and frank dialogue, the United States said on Monday as Prime Minister Narendra Modi held a bilateral meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow.</p>

<p>"India is a strategic partner with whom we engage in a full and frank dialogue. And that includes our concerns about their relationship with Russia," State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller said.</p>

<p>He was responding to questions on PM Modi's Moscow visit for bilateral talks with Putin.</p>

<p>"We did just see Modi, like (Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor) Orban, meet with (Ukrainian) President (Volodymyr) Zelenskyy. We thought that was an important step to take. And we would urge India, as we do any country when it engages with Russia, to make clear that any resolution to the conflict in Ukraine needs to be one that respects the UN charter, that respects Ukraine's territorial integrity, Ukraine's sovereignty," Miller said.</p>

<p>"I will look to Prime Minister Modi's public remarks to see what he talked about. But as I said, we made quite clear directly with India our concerns about their relationship with Russia. So we would hope India and any other country, when they engage with Russia, would make clear that Russia should respect the UN charter, should respect Ukraine's sovereignty and territorial integrity," he said in response to a question.</p>

<p>Putin on Monday night welcomed PM Modi at his official residence at Novo-Ogaryovo for a "private engagement" during which he praised the visiting Indian leader for the work he has done for the country's progress.</p>

<p>This is PM Modi's first trip to Russia since its invasion of Ukraine more than two years ago.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2glhci08_modi-putin_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is PM Modi's first trip to Russia since its invasion of Ukraine more than two years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/90-gazans-displaced-amid-war-with-israel-says-un-6064119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[90% Gazans Displaced Amid War With Israel, Says UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/90-gazans-displaced-amid-war-with-israel-says-un-6064119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 05:55:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UN humanitarians have said 90 per cent of Gazans were displaced, some multiple times, as more evacuations were ordered and poor or no security hampers aid and fuel deliveries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UN humanitarians have said 90 per cent of Gazans were displaced, some multiple times, as more evacuations were ordered and poor or no security hampers aid and fuel deliveries.</p>

<p>The UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) said on Monday that the Israeli military instructed on Sunday and Monday tens of thousands of people living in 19 blocs of apartments in Gaza City to evacuate immediately.</p>

<p>On Sunday, some residents were ordered to evacuate to western Gaza City, while the order on Monday included areas that people had fled to a day earlier and instructed them to evacuate to shelters in Deir al Balah, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"The two directly affected areas encompass 13 health facilities that were recently functional, including two hospitals, two primary healthcare centres and nine medical points," OCHA said, adding that 13 out of 36 hospitals in the Gaza Strip are only partially functional.</p>

<p>The office said that with nine out of every 10 people estimated to be displaced in Gaza, new waves of displacement are mainly affecting people who have already been displaced multiple times, only to find themselves forced to flee again under shelling. They were forced to reset their lives repeatedly without any of their belongings or any prospect of finding safety or reliable access to essential services.</p>

<p>"People, especially children, spend long hours queueing to collect water each day," OCHA said.</p>

<p>"Access to emergency health care is also a challenge, particularly given limited communications coverage to contact emergency services, high transportation costs to reach hospitals ($26 roundtrip) and the long walking distance of at least 3 km to reach the nearest medical point."</p>

<p>In northern Gaza, the aid partners especially highlighted the lack of safe shelters for up to 80,000 IDPs (Internally Displaced Persons) who were forced to hastily flee from Shuja'iyeh and other parts of eastern Gaza City following evacuation orders in late June. Many were found sleeping amid solid waste and rubble, with no mattresses or enough clothing, and some had sought shelter in partially destroyed UN facilities and residential buildings.</p>

<p>The Israeli military designated these same areas as evacuation zones, forcing many of the same families, including young children and the elderly, to go through successive waves of displacement over the past two weeks, the office said.</p>

<p>OCHA said that insecurity, damaged roads, the breakdown of law and order, and access limitations continue to hamper movement along the main humanitarian cargo route between Kerem Shalom crossing and Khan Younis and Deir al Balah.</p>

<p>"This has resulted in critical shortages of fuel and aid commodities to sustain humanitarian operations, in addition to increasing the risk of spoilage and infestation of stranded supplies (especially food) due to extremely high temperatures," the office added.</p>

<p>The humanitarians said the Food Security Sector (FSS) reports that the shortages forced partners to provide reduced food rations in central and southern Gaza in June and undermined their ability to keep bakeries and community kitchens running.</p>

<p>According to OCHA, only seven out of the 18 bakeries supported by humanitarian partners remain operational in Gaza, all in Deir al Balah, and six bakeries already working at partial capacity have now been forced to completely cease operations due to the lack of fuel.</p>

<p>The office said that in the absence of cooking gas and a stable flow of food supplies, community kitchens are also struggling to operate, resulting in a reduced number of cooked meals prepared throughout Gaza.</p>

<p>As of the end of June, about 600,000 cooked meals prepared in 190 kitchens were distributed daily to families across the strip, compared to more than 700,000 in the first half of June.</p>

<p>OCHA said it meant that displaced households rely on burning wood and plastic from furniture and waste to cook, exacerbating health risks and environmental hazards.</p>

<p>As for cooking, humanitarian partners said they continue to distribute wheat flour and canned food that enter northern Gaza through the Erez West crossing. No commercial trucks have been entering the area for months.</p>

<p>A joint assessment by the UN Food and Agriculture Organisation and the UN Satellite Centre estimated that about 57 per cent of Gaza's cropland and one-third of its greenhouses were damaged.</p>

<p>The FSS reported a near-total lack of protein sources, such as meat and poultry, on the local market, and only a few types of locally produced vegetables are available at unaffordable prices.</p>

<p>The sector reported that continued military operations in Rafah and recent displacement from eastern Khan Younis, where significant agricultural production was concentrated before the war, have resulted in additional damage to greenhouses. It forced more people to leave their farms unattended, further destabilising food systems.</p>

<p>OCHA said that on Friday, Medecins Sans Frontieres (MSF) reported that its teams at Nasser Medical Complex were "running on emergency medical stocks" and all departments were overwhelmed by patients, far exceeding the available bed capacity.</p>

<p>MSF said the Nasser Medical Complex is the main site on which field hospitals rely to sterilise their equipment, and if the facility is left without electricity, several field hospitals will also cease functioning.</p>

<p>It said the hospital has been unable to bring any medical supplies into Gaza since the end of April, including most recently on Wednesday, when the Israeli authorities denied trucks carrying MSF medical aid entry into the Gaza Strip due to ongoing hostilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1f89n3jg_gaza_625x300_02_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-struck-terrorists-operating-from-gaza-school-6064007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says It Struck "Terrorists" Operating From Gaza School]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-struck-terrorists-operating-from-gaza-school-6064007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 05:12:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army said Monday that it had struck "several terrorists" in central Gaza who were allegedly using a school in the Nuseirat area as "cover".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army said Monday that it had struck "several terrorists" in central Gaza who were allegedly using a school in the Nuseirat area as "cover".</p>

<p>"A short while ago, based on intelligence and using precise munition, the IAF struck several terrorists who were conducting terrorist activities, using the structures of a school in the area of Nuseirat as cover," the army said in a statement, referring to the Israeli Air Force.</p>

<p>A source at the Al-Awda hospital in Nuseirat told AFP that it had received several wounded people for treatment after an attack against a school run by the UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA.</p>

<p>Israel's army said Hamas and Islamic Jihad "systematically violate international law, exploiting civilian structures and population as human shields for terror attacks against the State of Israel".</p>

<p>On Saturday the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza said 16 people were killed in an Israeli strike on a school housing displaced people in Nuseirat.</p>

<p>At the time, the army said its aircraft had targeted "terrorists" operating around the Al-Jawni school in Nuseirat, which is run by UNRWA.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza entered its 10th month on Sunday.</p>

<p>The conflict erupted with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel that resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza, including 42 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel responded with a military offensive that has killed at least 38,193 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to data from the territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/1k6ecrdo_israel-gaza-war_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The war in Gaza entered its 10th month on Sunday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-stands-firm-says-running-race-to-end-despite-criticism-6063836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Stands Firm, Says "Running Race To End" Despite Criticism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-stands-firm-says-running-race-to-end-despite-criticism-6063836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:14:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has vowed he will be "running this race to end "of the November election, despite private calls from Democrats to drop out.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;US President Joe Biden has vowed he will be "running this race to end "of the November election, despite private calls from Democrats to drop out.</p>

<p>Biden stood firm and told congressional Democrats in a letter on Monday that he would continue his election bid despite mounting concerns about his mental fitness.</p>

<p>Biden said that he wouldn't be running again, "if I did not absolutely believe that I could beat Donald Trump."</p>

<p>"I want you to know that despite all the speculation in the press and elsewhere, I am firmly committed to staying in this race, to running this race to the end, and to beating Donald Trump," he added.</p>

<p>Further, he also stated, "We have 42 days to the Democratic convention and 119 days to the general election," Biden said in the letter distributed by his reelection campaign</p>

<p>In the letter, Biden calls for unity among his party, emphasising the need for a collective effort to defeat former President Donald Trump in the upcoming election.</p>

<p>"Any weakening of resolve or lack of clarity about the task ahead only helps Trump and hurts us. It's time to come together, move forward as a unified party, and defeat Donald Trump," said Biden.<br />
The letter comes after a group call with House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, in which four congressmen were explicit in urging Biden to step aside some deep-pocketed donors have also reportedly expressed discomfort, with Hollywood's Rob Reiner, who regularly donates to Democratic candidates, saying he thinks Biden should step aside "we lose our democracy if Trump wins."</p>

<p>At the same time, some of the president's biggest supporters are re-doubling the fight for Biden's presidency, insisting there is no better way to beat Trump in what many see as among the most important elections of a lifetime.</p>

<p>On Sunday, a leadership call was organised by House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, where several top House Democrats are urging President Joe Biden to step aside from the 2024 campaign, expressing deep concerns about his potential impact on the Democratic Party's chances in the upcoming elections.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/cef7h56g_joe-biden_625x300_06_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-meet-new-british-pm-starner-starmer-tomorrow-6063810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden To Meet New British PM Starmer Tomorrow]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-to-meet-new-british-pm-starner-starmer-tomorrow-6063810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 04:02:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden will hold his first face-to-face talks with Britain's new Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the White House on Wednesday, the White House said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;U.S. President Joe Biden will hold his first face-to-face talks with Britain's new Prime Minister Keir Starmer at the White House on Wednesday, the White House said on Monday.</p>

<p>Biden also will host an event on Thursday with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy at the NATO summit, which is taking place this week in Washington, national security spokesperson John Kirby told reporters.</p>

<p>Biden plans to "underscore the importance of continuing to strengthen the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom" in his meeting with Starmer, White House spokesperson Karine Jean-Pierre said in a statement.</p>

<p>She said the two leaders would have the opportunity to discuss U.S.-UK cooperation across a range of issues from Ukraine to the Israel-Gaza war, and ensuring that Iran does not obtain nuclear weapons, as well as confronting Iranian-backed Houthi threats to commercial shipping.</p>

<p>The leaders also will discuss furthering cooperation in areas such as protecting advanced technologies and developing climate and clean energy solutions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/b3loe32_biden-afp_625x300_18_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden will hold his first face-to-face talks with Britain's new Prime Minister Keir Starmer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-is-not-being-treated-for-parkinsons-white-house-6063517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Is Not Being Treated For Parkinson's: White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-is-not-being-treated-for-parkinsons-white-house-6063517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 02:27:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden is not being treated for Parkinson's disease, the White House said on Monday, after reports surfaced that a doctor specializing in the malady had visited the White House eight times over the past year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. President Joe Biden is not being treated for Parkinson's disease, the White House said on Monday, after reports surfaced that a doctor specializing in the malady had visited the White House eight times over the past year.</p>

<p>Concerns that the president might be suffering from an undisclosed illness have risen since Biden's stumbled in his June 27 debate with Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The New York Times said White House visitor logs show that Dr. Kevin Cannard, a neurologist who specializes in movement disorders and recently published a paper on Parkinson's, visited the White House eight times from last summer through the spring of this year.</p>

<p>During an acrimonious briefing, White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre refused to confirm Cannard's visit, saying she wanted to respect the privacy of all involved for security reasons.</p>

<p>She said Biden had seen a neurologist three times connected to Biden's annual physical exams.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She said Biden had seen a neurologist three times connected to Biden's annual physical exams.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-elect-masoud-pezeshkian-reiterates-support-for-hezbollah-6063454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran President-Elect Reiterates Support For Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-elect-masoud-pezeshkian-reiterates-support-for-hezbollah-6063454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 02:07:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's president-elect Masoud Pezeshkian on Monday reaffirmed the Islamic republic's support for Lebanon's Hezbollah group and condemned Israel's actions against Palestinians.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's president-elect Masoud Pezeshkian on Monday reaffirmed the Islamic republic's support for Lebanon's Hezbollah group and condemned Israel's actions against Palestinians.</p>

<p>The statement, issued to Hezbollah's chief Hassan Nasrallah on the IRNA official news agency, was one of the first foreign policy comments from Pezeshkian since his victory in Friday's presidential election runoff.</p>

<p>Tehran provides financial and military support to Hezbollah, which was created at the initiative of Iran's Revolutionary Guards after arch-foe Israel overran Beirut in 1982 during Lebanon's civil war.</p>

<p>In a reference to Hezbollah and allied groups, Pezeshkian said: "The support of the resistance is rooted in the fundamental policies of the Islamic Republic of Iran."</p>

<p>He said he was confident the "resistance movement" would stop its arch-foe Israel's "warmongering and criminal policies" in Gaza, where Israel has for nine months been at war with Hezbollah's Palestinian ally, Hamas.</p>

<p>Since the war in Gaza began, Hezbollah and Israel have exchanged near-daily fire over Lebanon's border, triggering global alarm about the potential for all-out war as fighting escalates.</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Iran's foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani said Tehran "will not hesitate to support the Lebanese nation" and Israel "must be aware of the consequences of any adventurous action in the region, especially towards Lebanon."</p>

<p>Reformist Pezeshkian defeated ultraconservative Saeed Jalili, a former nuclear negotiator, in the election which was brought forward after the death of president Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash.</p>

<p>After the vote, Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz said the election result was a "clear message of demand for change and opposition" from the Iranian people.</p>

<p>On Saturday Nasrallah congratulated Pezeshkian on his election victory and emphasised Tehran's role as a "strong" supporter of regional "resistance" groups.</p>

<p>The Shiite Muslim movement is a key part of the Axis of Resistance -- an alliance of pro-Iran armed movements that oppose Israel and the United States.</p>

<p>The alliance also includes Yemen's Huthi rebels and fighters in Iraq, as well as Hamas.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gc3222b4_masoud-pezeshkian_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran President elect said he was confident the "resistance movement" would stop Israel's "warmongering".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-pm-modi-to-raise-ukraine-sovereignty-with-vladimir-putin-during-meet-6063327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Urges PM Modi To Raise Ukraine "Sovereignty" With Putin During Meet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-pm-modi-to-raise-ukraine-sovereignty-with-vladimir-putin-during-meet-6063327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 01:25:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States called Monday on Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi to emphasize Ukraine's territorial integrity as he met in Russia with President Vladimir Putin on the eve of a NATO summit in Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States called Monday on Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi to emphasize Ukraine's territorial integrity as he met in Russia with President Vladimir Putin on the eve of a NATO summit in Washington.</p>

<p>"We would urge India, as we do any country which engages with Russia, to make clear that any resolution to the conflict in Ukraine needs to be one that respects the UN Charter with respect to Ukraine's territorial integrity, Ukraine's sovereignty," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>"India is a strategic partner with whom we engage in a full and frank dialogue, and that includes on our concerns about the relationship with Russia," he said.</p>

<p>Miller said, however, that he was unaware of specific conversations with India about PM Modi's visit to Russia.</p>

<p>The United States has built strong relations with India, seeing it as a powerful partner in the face of the rise of China, with President Joe Biden inviting PM Modi for a state visit a year ago.</p>

<p>India has a longstanding relationship with Moscow dating to the Cold War and has refused to join Western sanctions over the Ukraine war, instead turning to Russia for discounted energy imports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tom2907g_pm-modi_625x300_09_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi met Russian President Vladimir Putin in Moscow on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-could-be-worlds-hottest-year-as-june-breaks-records-6063105]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2024 Could Be World's Hottest Year As June Breaks Records]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2024-could-be-worlds-hottest-year-as-june-breaks-records-6063105]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:19:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Last month was the hottest June on record, the EU's climate change monitoring service said on Monday, continuing a streak of exceptional temperatures that some scientists said puts 2024 on track to be the world's hottest recorded year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month was the hottest June on record, the EU's climate change monitoring service said on Monday, continuing a streak of exceptional temperatures that some scientists said puts 2024 on track to be the world's hottest recorded year.</p>

<p>Every month since June 2023 - 13 months in a row - has ranked as the planet's hottest since records began, compared with the corresponding month in previous years, the European Union's Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S) said in a monthly bulletin.</p>

<p>The latest data suggest 2024 could outrank 2023 as the hottest year since records began after human-caused climate change and the El Nino natural weather phenomenon both pushed temperatures to record highs in the year so far, some scientists said.</p>

<p>"I now estimate that there is an approximately 95% chance that 2024 beats 2023 to be the warmest year since global surface temperature records began in the mid-1800s," said Zeke Hausfather, a research scientist at U.S. non-profit Berkeley Earth.</p>

<p>The changed climate has already unleashed disastrous consequences around the world in 2024.</p>

<p>More than 1,000 people died in fierce heat during the haj pilgrimage last month. Heat deaths were recorded in New Dehli, which endured an unprecedentedly long heatwave, and amongst tourists in Greece.</p>

<p>Friederike Otto, a climate scientist at Imperial College London's Grantham Institute, said there was a "high chance" 2024 would rank as the hottest year on record.</p>

<p>"El Nino is a naturally occurring phenomenon that will always come and go. We can't stop El Nino, but we can stop burning oil, gas, and coal," she said.</p>

<p>The natural El Nino phenomenon, which warms the surface waters in the eastern Pacific Ocean, tends to raise global average temperatures.</p>

<p>That effect subsided in recent months, with the world now in neutral conditions before cooler La Nina conditions are expected to form later this year.</p>

<p>C3S' dataset goes back to 1940, which the scientists cross-checked with other data to confirm that last month was the hottest June since the 1850-1900 pre-industrial period.</p>

<p>Greenhouse gas emissions from burning fossil fuels are the main cause of climate change.</p>

<p>Despite promises to curb global warming, countries have so far failed collectively to reduce these emissions, pushing temperatures steadily higher for decades.</p>

<p>In the 12 months ending in June, the world's average temperature was the highest on record for any such period, at 1.64 degrees Celsius above the pre-industrial average, C3S said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ae640rl_moscow-heatwave-_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Climate change has unleashed disastrous consequences around the world in 2024. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-beryl-kills-2-knocks-out-power-as-it-churns-across-texas-6063076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storm Beryl Kills 2, Knocks Out Power As It Churns Across Texas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-beryl-kills-2-knocks-out-power-as-it-churns-across-texas-6063076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:08:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tropical Storm Beryl's howling winds and torrential rain killed at least two people, closed oil ports, grounded hundreds of flights and knocked out power to more than 2 million homes and businesses in southeast Texas on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tropical Storm Beryl's howling winds and torrential rain killed at least two people, closed oil ports, grounded hundreds of flights and knocked out power to more than 2 million homes and businesses in southeast Texas on Monday.</p>

<p>Beryl, the season's earliest Category 5 hurricane on record, weakened from a hurricane after pounding the coastal Texas town of Matagorda with dangerous storm surges and heavy rain before moving across Houston, the US National Hurricane Center (NHC) said.</p>

<p>The storm, which was expected to rapidly weaken as it moved inland, swept a destructive path through Jamaica, Grenada, and St. Vincent and the Grenadines last week. It has killed at least 12 people in the Caribbean and Texas.</p>

<p>In Texas, a 53-year-old man and a 74-year-old woman were killed in two incidents by trees that fell on their homes in the Houston area on Monday, according to Harris County officials.</p>

<p>The state's energy industry, the nation's biggest producer of US oil and natural gas, braced for Beryl's impact as the powerful storm slowed refining activity and prompted the evacuation of some production sites.</p>

<p>"Life-threatening storm surge and heavy rainfall is ongoing across portions of Texas. Damaging winds ongoing along the coast, with strong winds moving inland," the NHC said even as Beryl began to lose strength.</p>

<p>Following warnings that it could be a deadly storm for communities in its path, residents had rushed to board up windows and stock up on fuel and other essential supplies.</p>

<p>Before daybreak, strong gusts and torrential rain lashed cities and towns such as Galveston, Sargent, Lake Jackson and Freeport, television footage showed. By late morning, many fallen trees blocked roads in Houston as the worst of the storm passed, with persisting winds and some road flooding, rendering lanes on major freeways impassable. The city barricaded flooded areas.</p>

<p>In video posted on social media by Houston's local ABC station, crews using a life jacket and ladder fire truck rescued a man from a truck on a flooded stretch of freeway.</p>

<p>In a late morning press conference, Houston Mayor John Whitmire urged people to shelter in place. He noted that flood waters exceeded 10 inches (25 cm) across most of the city.</p>

<p>"We're literally getting calls across Houston right now asking for first responders to come rescue individuals in desperate life safety conditions," Whitmire said.</p>

<p>The storm had strengthened into a Category 1 hurricane as it crossed the warm waters of the Gulf of Mexico before making landfall. But the NHC said it was now expected to weaken rapidly as it moves across land, as hurricanes typically do, before becoming a tropical depression on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Beryl was expected to barrel over eastern parts of the state through the day before moving into the Lower Mississippi Valley and the Ohio Valley on Tuesday and Wednesday, the NHC said.</p>

<p>"People in the path of Beryl's track should not let their guard down this week," Accuweather said in a statement, warning of possible tornadoes as far away as Ohio and possible flash flooding as far north as Detroit.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden is being regularly updated about the storm while administration officials remain in close contact with state and local counterparts, a White House official said.</p>

<p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the US Coast Guard had prepositioned staff to assist with search and rescue efforts, with FEMA also readied with water, meals and generators to boost local response efforts, according to the Biden administration.</p>

<p>Schools said they would close as the storm approached. Airlines canceled more than 1,300 flights, and officials ordered a smattering of evacuations in beach towns. Small businesses in Houston, including package delivery services and chiropractors, delayed openings or were closed on Monday.</p>

<p>More than 2 million homes and businesses in Texas have lost power, according to local utilities and PowerOutage.us data.</p>

<p>Several counties in southeastern Texas - including Houston, where many US energy companies are headquartered - are under a flash-flood warning as thunderstorms unleashed up to nearly 12 inches (30 cm) of rain in some areas.</p>

<p>Resident Gary Short said he was most concerned about possible flooding, which the NHC warned was expected across parts of Texas into Monday night.</p>

<p>"I'm more worried about the rain than anything," he said as he filled up cans with gasoline at a service station on Sunday. "Other than that, not too concerned. Just getting ready."</p>

<p>Closures of major oil-shipping ports around Corpus Christi, Galveston and Houston ahead of the storm could disrupt crude oil exports, along with shipments of crude to refineries and motor fuel from the plants.</p>

<p>Some oil producers, including Shell and Chevron, evacuated personnel from their Gulf of Mexico offshore production platforms ahead of the storm.</p>

<p>Marathon Petroleum Corp's refinery in Texas City, Texas was hit by a power interruption on Monday amid the storm, the company said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1s12b1bg_hurricane-beryl_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In Texas, a 53-year-old man and a 74-year-old woman were killed due to the storm]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-regulator-orders-inspection-of-boeing-airplanes-over-oxygen-mask-issue-6062926]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Regulator Orders Inspection Of Boeing Airplanes Over Oxygen Mask Issue]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-regulator-orders-inspection-of-boeing-airplanes-over-oxygen-mask-issue-6062926]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 23:36:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US aviation regulators said Monday that more than 2,600 Boeing 737 airplanes would need to be inspected, due to concerns that passenger oxygen masks could fail in emergencies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boeing confirmed on Monday that it had reached a deal with the US Department of Justice over two fatal 737 MAX crashes, with court documents showing the planemaker set to plead guilty to fraud.</p>

<p>The agreement comes after prosecutors concluded Boeing flouted an earlier settlement addressing the disasters, in which 346 people were killed in Ethiopia and Indonesia more than five years ago.</p>

<p>"We have reached an agreement in principle on terms of a resolution with the Justice Department," Boeing said in a statement.</p>

<p>Families of crash victims immediately filed an objection to the deal, arguing that it "unfairly makes concessions to Boeing that other criminal defendants would never receive."</p>

<p>Catherine Berthet, who lost her daughter Camille in the 2019 Ethiopian Airlines crash -- involving a 737 MAX 8 -- said the deal reflects "weakness and manifest contempt for the victims' families and public interest."</p>

<p>Court papers filed in Texas on Sunday said the company had agreed to plead guilty to "conspiracy to defraud the United States" during the certification of MAX airplanes.</p>

<p>The plea deal would see Boeing avoid a criminal trial and instead agree to a series of terms that includes a fresh $243.6 million fine.</p>

<p>The company will also be required to make a minimum investment of $455 million in "compliance and safety programs."</p>

<p>Such changes at the firm will be overseen by an independent monitor appointed by the government for a three-year term.</p>

<p>The company's board of directors will also be required to meet the families of crash victims.</p>

<p>The high-profile agreement follows the DOJ finding in May that Boeing failed to improve its compliance and ethics program, in breach of a 2021 deferred prosecution agreement (DPA) in the wake of the MAX crashes.</p>

<p><strong>- Families reject 'generous' deal -</strong></p>

<p>The families of victims will ask the court to reject the plea deal at an upcoming hearing.</p>

<p>"The generous plea agreement rests on deceptive and offensive premises," said the objection filed by their legal team Sunday.</p>

<p>In a statement shared by her lawyers, Berthet added that the agreement shows the DOJ's "deafness" despite an alarming rise in incidents.</p>

<p>The original DPA was announced in January 2021, over charges that Boeing knowingly defrauded US aviation regulators.</p>

<p>That agreement required Boeing to pay $2.5 billion in fines and restitution in exchange for immunity from criminal prosecution.</p>

<p>A three-year probationary period was set to expire this year.</p>

<p>But in January, Boeing was plunged back into crisis mode when a 737 MAX flown by Alaska Airlines was forced to make an emergency landing after a fuselage panel blew out mid-flight.</p>

<p>The incident launched a new wave of scrutiny into Boeing's manufacturing and safety practices, with formal probes initiated by US regulators and Congress.</p>

<p>In a May 14 letter to the court overseeing the MAX case, DOJ officials said that Boeing flouted its obligations under the DPA by "failing to design, implement, and enforce a compliance and ethics program to prevent and detect violations of the US fraud laws throughout its operations."</p>

<p>The conclusion opened up the company to possible prosecution, with Boeing initially arguing it had not violated the 2021 agreement.</p>

<p>DOJ representatives briefed families in late June on the proposed plea deal and the company was given until July 5 to accept the offer, or face a possibly damaging trial.</p>

<p>Boeing was meanwhile met with fresh negative news on Monday, with the US Federal Aviation Administration announcing that over 2,600 737 jets would need inspections, amid concerns that passenger oxygen masks could fail in emergencies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hbjdqobo_beoing-737_625x300_08_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 2,600 Boeing 737 airplanes would need to be inspected, said US aviation regulators]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-tsmc-trillion-dollar-taiwanese-chip-giant-6062871]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About TSMC, Trillion-Dollar Taiwanese Chip Giant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-about-tsmc-trillion-dollar-taiwanese-chip-giant-6062871]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 23:24:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwanese semiconductor titan TSMC briefly joined a rarefied club of companies valued at more than $1 trillion on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwanese semiconductor titan TSMC briefly joined a rarefied club of companies valued at more than $1 trillion on Monday.</p>

<p>Here are five things to know about the Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company:</p>

<p><strong>'Godfather'</strong></p>

<p>MIT and Stanford graduate Morris Chang founded TSMC in 1987 after an extensive tech industry career in the United States.</p>

<p>Taiwan's government was trying to set up a semiconductor industry that would compete with the countries, such as Japan, that led the sector at the time.</p>

<p>TSMC has become one of the world's most important companies in the nearly four decades since -- a leader in producing the chips that help run everything from smartphones to advanced robots.</p>

<p>Chang, who was born in mainland China in 1931, retired from TSMC in 2018. He was revered in Taiwan by then and often described as the "godfather" of the island's chip industry.</p>

<p>Taiwan awarded him one of its highest medals of honour in April.</p>

<p><strong>AI boom</strong></p>

<p>Thanks to the revolution in artificial intelligence sparked by the success of ChatGPT, TSMC has been riding a massive wave of demand for the advanced semiconductors needed to train and run AI apps.</p>

<p>It works closely with AI leader Nvidia, which became the world's most valuable traded company in June with a market capitalisation of around $3.3 trillion.</p>

<p>TSMC also supplies Nvidia competitors Qualcomm and AMD, among others, and such is the demand for its chips that production has been reportedly booked for years in advance.</p>

<p>Arguably its best-known client is Apple, which relies on TSMC chips for the latest iPhones and MacBooks.</p>

<p>"We have established a research pipeline for technology to enable leading-edge AI devices, circuits, and systems for decades to come," TSMC says on its website.</p>

<p><strong>Fears about China</strong></p>

<p>Taiwan is one of the most important links in the supply chain for semiconductors, the lifeblood of the modern global economy, and TSMC is its crown jewel.</p>

<p>However, China claims the self-ruled island as its territory and has not ruled out the use of force to bring it under its control.</p>

<p>Beijing has ramped up pressure on Taipei in recent years, including with large-scale military drills, sparking worries in capitals and boardrooms around the world about its chip industry.</p>

<p>US Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo told a Congressional hearing in May that a Chinese invasion of Taiwan and seizure of TSMC would be "absolutely devastating".</p>

<p>"Right now, the United States buys 92 percent of its leading-edge chips from TSMC in Taiwan," she said.</p>

<p><strong>US, Japan expansion</strong></p>

<p>TSMC has faced pressure to diversify away from Taiwan, where the bulk of its factories are based, to guard against any further escalation of the tussle between Washington and Beijing.</p>

<p>It is building two "fabs" -- manufacturing plants -- in the United States and announced plans for a third in April, bringing its total investment in the state of Arizona to $65 billion.</p>

<p>But its US projects have faced obstacles in the past year, which the company attributed to a lack of human resources because making chips requires highly specialised skills.</p>

<p>TSMC also launched an $8.6 billion plant in Japan this year -- a coup for the country as it vies with the United States and Europe to woo top chip firms with huge subsidies.</p>

<p>With "strong" Japanese government support, TSMC has announced a second factory to make more advanced chips. The firm is also planning a new factory in Germany -- its first in Europe.</p>

<p><strong>Quake threat</strong></p>

<p>Geopolitics is not the only worry for TSMC and Taiwan's chip industry.</p>

<p>The island is prone to natural disasters, too.</p>

<p>It sits on the "Ring of Fire", an arc of intense seismic activity along the Pacific Rim, and -- much like neighbouring Japan -- has a long history of catastrophic quakes.</p>

<p>TSMC was one of the firms that halted production because of a 7.4-magnitude earthquake in April this year, the most severe to hit Taiwan in decades.</p>

<p>It told customers the impact from the quake was minimal.</p>

<p>TSMC has invested in a number of seismic resistance features at its facilities to reduce damage and casualties, including an earthquake early warning system, according to its website.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2ostahr_tsmc-generic_625x300_08_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[TSMC has become one of the world's most important companies in the nearly 4 decades (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-putin-hosts-pm-modi-at-his-official-residence-for-private-engagement-6062754]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Hosts PM Modi At His Official Residence For "Private Engagement"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-russia-visit-putin-hosts-pm-modi-at-his-official-residence-for-private-engagement-6062754]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 23:08:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday evening welcomed Prime Minister Narendra Modi at his official residence at Novo-Ogaryovo for a "private engagement".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Monday evening welcomed Prime Minister Narendra Modi at his official residence at Novo-Ogaryovo for a "private engagement".</p>

<p>"A meeting of two close friends and trusted partners," the Spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs posted on X.</p>

<p>"PM @narendramodi welcomed by President Vladimir Putin of Russia at his official residence at Novo-Ogaryovo for a private engagement," it said, sharing some photographs of the meeting.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A meeting of two close friends and trusted partners.<br />
<br />
PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> welcomed by President Vladimir Putin of Russia at his official residence at Novo-Ogaryovo for a private engagement.<br />
<br />
An occasion for the two leaders to cherish &amp; celebrate ??-?? friendship. <a href="https://t.co/g3DuNyowHG">pic.twitter.com/g3DuNyowHG</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1810362956854735128?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It is an occasion for the two leaders to cherish &amp; celebrate India-Russia friendship, it said.</p>

<p>In his first trip since the start of Moscow's invasion of Ukraine, Prime Minister Modi on Monday travelled to Russia to hold summit talks with President Putin on Tuesday -- a visit that is being seen as having a wider geopolitical context and signalling.</p>

<p>Shortly after landing in Moscow, PM Modi said he is looking forward to deepening bilateral partnership in futuristic areas and that stronger ties between India and Russia will "greatly benefit our people".</p>

<p>India seeks to play a "supportive role" for a peaceful and stable region, the prime minister said in his departure statement.</p>

<p>PM Modi was received at the Vnukovo-II airport by Russia's First Deputy Prime Minister Denis Manturov. The Russian first deputy minister also accompanied the Indian prime minister to his hotel from the airport, officials said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ir6kg8f_putin-hosts-modi_625x300_08_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi will hold summit talks with President Putin on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-court-rejects-imran-khans-plea-for-weekly-whatsapp-call-with-his-sons-6062744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Rejects Imran Khan's Petition For Weekly WhatsApp Call With Sons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-court-rejects-imran-khans-plea-for-weekly-whatsapp-call-with-his-sons-6062744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 23:07:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Rawalpindi court on Monday rejected Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) founder and former Prime Minister Imran Khan's plea for a weekly WhatsApp call with his sons, ARY News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Rawalpindi court on Monday rejected Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) founder and former Prime Minister Imran Khan's plea for a weekly WhatsApp call with his sons, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Notably, Imran Khan had filed a petition and sought permission to have a conversation with his sons via WhatsApp once a week.</p>

<p>However, the jail administration asserted that there is no legal provision that allow prisoners to communicate with their relatives through WhatsApp. The court had earlier said that Imran be allowed to talk with his children twice a month, who currently reside in the UK with their mother Jemima Khan, according to ARY News.</p>

<p>Earlier, the former Pakistan Prime Minister had submitted an application to Rawalpindi Anti-Terrorism Court (ATC) after he was denied a telephonic conversation with his sons from Adiala Jail. In the petition, the PTI founder had argued that he has been denied to speak with his sons despite being allowed to do so by law.</p>

<p>The ATC, presided over by Judge Malik Aijaz Asif, had sought a response from the jail administration, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, an anti-terrorism court, a day earlier, reserved its decision on Imran Khan's interim bail requests in cases associated with the May 9 incidents in 2023, including the Jinnah House and two other cases, Pakistan-based The Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>During the hearing on Saturday, Imran lawyer, Barrister Salman Safdar, argued that the PTI founder was being targeted for political reasons.</p>

<p>"In my entire career, I have never seen so many cases against a single individual. Those who were actually inciting against institutions at the scene were not arrested," Safdar alleged."How could a case be filed against him when he was in custody at the time of the crime?" PTI chief's lawyer questioned.</p>

<p>In response, the government's lawyer argued that according to a special branch report, Imran Khan had asked his followers to target civil and military installations if he got arrested.The prosecutor said, "The directive to attack military installations across Pakistan resulted in the events that transpired." After hearing arguments from both sides, the court reserved its verdict on the PTI founder's interim bail requests, The Express Tribune reported.</p>

<p>On May 9 last year, violent clashes broke out across Pakistan after former prime minister Imran Khan was arrested. The protests were held in remote and major cities as the party workers were agitated due to Mr Khan's arrest, with Balochistan, Punjab, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, and Islamabad summoning the armed forces to ensure law and order, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Army installations, including the Corps Commander's house in Lahore, had come under attack during the protests by PTI workers. Notably, the PTI founder was named as the main accused in all the May 9 riots cases.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t32m7b7o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poltical-turmoil-airport-strikes-frances-challenges-ahead-of-paris-olympics-2024-6062737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Political Turmoil, Airport Strikes: France's Challenges Ahead Of Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poltical-turmoil-airport-strikes-frances-challenges-ahead-of-paris-olympics-2024-6062737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 23:06:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France was plunged into political turmoil on Monday three weeks before hosting the Olympics, while a call for strikes at Paris airports added fresh uncertainty to the already tense build up.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France was plunged into political turmoil on Monday three weeks before hosting the Olympics, while a call for strikes at Paris airports added fresh uncertainty to the already tense build up.</p>

<p>The run-up to the world's biggest sporting event is usually fraught for host nations, but French President Emmanuel Macron added unexpected complexity last month by calling snap parliamentary elections.</p>

<p>A second round of voting for the National Assembly on Sunday delivered a hung parliament, making it hard to know who will be in key government positions when the Games open on July 26.</p>

<p>"Our country is facing an unprecedented political situation and is getting ready to host the world in a few weeks," Prime Minister Gabriel Attal stressed on Sunday evening as he offered his resignation.</p>

<p>Macron has asked the ambitious 35-year-old to remain at his post "for the time being to ensure the stability of the country", a statement from the presidency said.</p>

<p>It is unclear whether the head of state will seek to keep a caretaker government in place until the Paris Games close on August 11, but a left-wing alliance that topped Sunday's vote is already pushing to name a candidate to replace Attal.</p>

<p>The fate of Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin, who has overseen security preparations for the Games, is also in the balance.</p>

<p>"What organisers worry about the most are things like delinquency and crime, and of course terrorism, as well as traffic conditions," Paul Dietschy, a history and sports professor at the Universite of Franche-Comte in France, told AFP.</p>

<p>"The interior minister is the most important position."</p>

<p>Darmanin said last week that if the far-right National Rally or hard-left France Unbowed party formed a government, then he would resign immediately.</p>

<p>"The Olympic Games have been very well-prepared. Everyone knows it and everyone welcomes it," he told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>Disruption threat</strong></p>

<p>Elsewhere on Monday, unions representing workers at ADP, which runs the capital's two main airports, said they had called for a strike next week to demand Olympics bonuses for all staff and a "massive" recruitment plan.</p>

<p>Paris's airports will be the main gateway into France for foreign visitors to the Olympics, with up to 350,000 people expected to transit there daily, as well as most athletes and their equipment.</p>

<p>The strike on July 17 will occur just before athletes are set to arrive to take up residence in the newly built Olympic village in northern Paris.</p>

<p>ADP has built new temporary over-sized baggage terminal at Charles de Gaulle airport to handle specialised sports equipment such as kayaks and bikes.</p>

<p>Ahead of the 1998 football World Cup in France, the last time the country hosted such a major sporting event, pilots at national carrier Air France went on strike on the eve of kick-off along with taxi drivers and other transport workers.</p>

<p>Police, air traffic controllers, rubbish collectors, central government employees, metro and train drivers as well as firefighters have all made pay demands ahead of the Olympics, seeking to use the leverage.</p>

<p>Chief Olympics organiser Tony Estanguet has called for a "truce" between unions and employers during the competition.</p>

<p>"I want us to welcome the world in the best possible conditions and we don't want to spoil the party," he told French television in February.</p>

<p><strong>Excitement?</strong></p>

<p>Estanguet and the International Olympic Committee were both blindsided by Macron's election gamble so close to the start of the Paris Games -- as were most government ministers and voters.</p>

<p>The prospect of the far-right taking power was seen by many observers as a risk that would undermine France's image -- and the themes of diversity and openness stressed by Paris 2024.</p>

<p>Estanguet "must be feeling very happy since last night," said David Roizen, an Olympics specialist at the left-leaning Jean-Jaures Foundation think-tank in Paris.</p>

<p>Paris 2024 figures have also sought to stress that senior civil servants with responsiblity for Games-related issues like security and transport will remain in place even if the cabinet changes.</p>

<p>The Games can count on "the continuity of the state", the Paris organising committee told AFP, adding they had worked "night and day in previous weeks to be ready."</p>

<p>In France, the election has entirely overshadowed the build-up to the sporting extravaganza, with the local media paying more attention to the political manoeuvrings than the new sports facilities nearing completion around the capital.</p>

<p>"If Macron hadn't dissolved the parliament, then there would be a bit more passion for the Games," Dietschy said. "You don't really feel excitement building. Most French people have been focused on the election."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pjc0hv0g_paris-olympics-2024_625x300_08_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paris's airports will be the main gateway into France for foreign visitors to the Olympics]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-says-firmly-committed-to-staying-in-presidential-race-6062615]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says "Firmly Committed" To Staying In Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-says-firmly-committed-to-staying-in-presidential-race-6062615]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 22:47:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden urged Democratic lawmakers Monday to either back his reelection campaign or challenge him at the party convention next month as the US president's reelection bid entered a critical week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden urged Democratic lawmakers Monday to either back his reelection campaign or challenge him at the party convention next month as the US president's reelection bid entered a critical week.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old doubled down on his defiance of calls to step aside, after a disastrous debate against Republican rival Donald Trump last month turbocharged fears that he is too old to serve a second term.</p>

<p>Biden will be under extra scrutiny this week as he hosts a summit of NATO leaders in Washington, with many allies seeking reassurance amid polls forecasting that the isolationist Trump will win in November.</p>

<p>Biden called in to MSNBC's "Morning Joe" television program to say that he was "confident" the "average voter out there still wanted Joe Biden."</p>

<p>Sounding angry in the telephone interview, Biden said he was "getting so frustrated by the elites... in the party."</p>

<p>"Any of these guys that don't think I should run -- run against me. announce for president, challenge me at the convention," he added.</p>

<p>In a blitz of action to start the week, Biden also penned a lengthy letter to Democratic Party lawmakers that saying "I decline" to stand down.</p>

<p>"I am firmly committed to staying in the race," Biden wrote.</p>

<p>"The question of how to move forward has been well-aired for over a week now. And it's time for it to end."</p>

<p><strong>NATO summit</strong></p>

<p>Biden must overcome concerns sparked by the debate, during which repeatedly lost his train of thought, mangled his syntax and spoke with a raspy voice.</p>

<p>He has blamed jetlag and a cold.</p>

<p>But on Sunday four senior congressmen said on a call with party lawmakers that it was time for Biden to bow out, according to US media.</p>

<p>Democrats this week return from a brief recess to Capitol Hill under pressure to either fall in line behind the president or urge him to step aside.</p>

<p>Tuesday, when the NATO summit begins, could prove a turning point: party lawmakers are expected to hold their regular caucus meeting, which could coalesce any bid to force him out.</p>

<p>Biden's performance at the summit marking the 75th anniversary of the NATO alliance will also be closely watched. He is due to attend several meetings and give his first press conference since the debate debacle.</p>

<p>Many European countries are fearful of a return of Trump, as the 78-year-old has long criticized the defense alliance, voiced admiration for Russian strongman Vladimir Putin, and insisted he could bring about a quick end to the war in Ukraine.</p>

<p><strong>Busy schedule</strong></p>

<p>After a barnstorming day of campaign events in swing state Pennsylvania on Sunday, Biden has no public events scheduled for Monday, which he is expected to spend preparing for the summit.</p>

<p>First Lady Jill Biden, a fierce defender of the president, is scheduled to campaign for him instead in Georgia, Florida and North Carolina.</p>

<p>On Friday the president picks up the campaign trail once more, heading for the battleground state of Michigan, before going to his beachside home in Rehoboth, Delaware.</p>

<p>With election day just four months away and the party convention in mid-August, the clock is ticking on any move to replace Biden as the nominee.</p>

<p>Biden and his team appear determined to dig in for the siege, with the campaign unveiling an intense schedule for later in July, including an avalanche of TV spots and trips to key states.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7geecs9o_biden_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden penned a lengthy letter to Democratic Party lawmakers saying "I decline" to stand down. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-safe-on-space-station-to-address-earth-on-july-10-6062384]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams, Safe On Space Station, To Address Earth On July 10]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-safe-on-space-station-to-address-earth-on-july-10-6062384]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 22:04:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is safe and continues helping with research and maintenance of the International Space Station, said American space agency NASA.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is safe and continues helping with research and maintenance of the International Space Station, said American space agency NASA after her return to Earth was delayed, which sparked fears about the safety of the crew that flew on board the Boeing Starliner spacecraft to the space station on June 5. She will discuss the crew's mission in a live address from the space station on July 10 at 8.30 pm.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore have already spent over a month in the space station on a trip that was originally supposed to be 10 days long due to a series of technical glitches in the Boeing Starliner.</p>

<p>Currently, the ISS is hosting nine crew members who are continuing their planned activities, said NASA. Ms Williams, in the last four weeks on the ISS, has helped disassemble and empty racks for future missions and also assessed air flow in the filters. Her crewmate, Mr Wilmore, joined another NASA astronaut Tracy Dyson on July 2 to load trash and discarded gear inside the Cygnus spacecraft, said NASA. Cygnus, built by Northrop Grumman, is scheduled to be released from the ISS's Unity module later this month for disposal over the South Pacific Ocean, ending its five-and-a-half-month stay at the orbiting lab. On the same day, the crew also checked up on the quiescent Boeing Starliner awaiting its return to Earth.</p>

<p>The crew's work on the ISS, which is like a mini city the size of a football field in space, is of immense significance. The space station, which weighs 419 tonnes and costs over $150 Billion, has been hosting astronauts since 2000. The crew there experiences 16 sunrises daily in its orbit, making the upkeep of the space station a crucial and challenging task.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Riding atop the Boeing Starliner on its first crewed mission, Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore reached the ISS on June 6. She was supposed to return on June 14, however, the return trip was delayed till June 26 due to some technical glitches on the spacecraft. Failing to return on June 26 as well, no new date has been disclosed by NASA.</p>

<p>The space agency and Boeing, while announcing the delay in a statement, said, "NASA and Boeing leadership are adjusting the return to Earth of the Starliner Crew Flight Test spacecraft with agency astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams from the International Space Station. The move off Wednesday, June 26, deconflicts Starliner's undocking and landing from a series of planned International Space Station spacewalks while allowing mission teams time to review propulsion system data."<br />
The delay has been attributed to five helium leaks on the Starliner and technical issues in five of its 28 thrusters. Experts say a minimum of 14 thrusters are required for a safe trip back.</p>

<p>While Ms Williams' trip to the ISS has faced an indefinite extension, NASA says the crew is not pressed for time to leave the station since there are plenty of supplies in orbit, and the station's schedule is relatively open through mid-August.</p>

<p>However, Boeing is facing heat for the unexpected obstruction technical glitches in its spacecraft's maiden {test} mission. According to some experts, the same problems that beset the Boeing Company in its aviation business may be plaguing its space business as well. Recently, Boeing CEO David Calhoun was grilled by US Senators regarding the aviation giant's safety culture and transparency during his first appearance before the US Congress.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/gjvc42uo_sunita-williams-in-iss_625x300_08_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sunita Williams helped disassemble and empty racks for future missions on the ISS]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-makes-apology-calls-to-ex-mps-after-uk-election-loss-6061579]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak Makes Apology Calls To Ex-MPs After UK Election Loss]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-makes-apology-calls-to-ex-mps-after-uk-election-loss-6061579]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 08 Jul 2024 20:01:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former British prime minister Rishi Sunak spent the weekend calling the Conservative Party candidates who lost their seats in the general election last week to apologise for the party's worst performance at the ballot box, with just 121 seats in the]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former British prime minister Rishi Sunak spent the weekend calling the Conservative Party candidates who lost their seats in the general election last week to apologise for the party's worst performance at the ballot box, with just 121 seats in the House of Commons.</p>

<p>Several former members of Parliament told 'The Daily Telegraph' about the "very sympathetic call" they received from the British Indian MP, who won his own seat of Richmond and Northallerton in Yorkshire and remains the Leader of the Opposition until the Tories elect his successor.</p>

<p>The 44-year-old had apologised to his party colleagues and the nation in his farewell speech at 10 Downing Street on Friday, when he also announced his resignation as Tory leader after the Labour Party won a landslide victory with 411 MPs in a 650-seat Commons.</p>

<p>"He took the time to ring me on a Saturday night and I think he's taken the time to ring other MPs. He was ringing to say that he was incredibly sorry that I'd lost my seat," an unseated Tory MP was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>"To all the Conservative candidates and campaigners who worked tirelessly but without success, I am sorry that we could not deliver what your efforts deserved," Sunak said in his speech last week.</p>

<p>Frontrunners to replace him as party leader are working behind-the-scenes to shore up their support. Former home secretary Suella Braverman, who has been openly critical of Sunak's leadership, is among the contenders but her campaign received an early blow as one of her supporters switched loyalties to her former home office colleague, Robert Jenrick.</p>

<p>Others lining up for the race include two more former home secretaries Priti Patel and James Cleverly and former business secretary Kemi Badenoch. Further former ministers from the Sunak Cabinet, Victoria Atkins and Tom Tugendhat, are also likely to throw their hat in the ring when the contours of the contest are devised by the party's 1922 Committee - which will be electing its new chair after the election.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the new Prime Minister, Keir Starmer, spent his first weekend in office travelling to different parts of the United Kingdom starting with Scotland. He will then embark on his first foreign visit as PM for the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO) meeting in Washington to set the tone for his Labour government's relations with US President Joe Biden's administration and other international allies.</p>

<p>On Saturday, he spoke to Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and the leaders agreed to meet at the "earliest opportunity".</p>

<p>"Discussing the Free Trade Agreement, the prime minister said he stood ready to conclude a deal that worked for both sides. The leaders hoped to meet at the earliest opportunity," a Downing Street spokesperson said about the call.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2n7un21_rishi-sunak-resignation-speech_625x300_06_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He had apologised to his party colleagues and the nation in his farewell speech (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>