<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 02 Jul 2024 01:07:28 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-shoots-down-5-aerial-targets-over-crimea-says-governor-6013334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Shoots Down 5 Aerial Targets Over Crimea, Says Governor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-shoots-down-5-aerial-targets-over-crimea-says-governor-6013334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 02 Jul 2024 01:07:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia shot down five aerial targets over Crimea on Monday, the Russian-installed governor of the Crimean port of Sevastopol, Mikhail Razvozhayev, said on his Telegram channel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia shot down five aerial targets over Crimea on Monday, the Russian-installed governor of the Crimean port of Sevastopol, Mikhail Razvozhayev, said on his Telegram channel.</p>

<p>Fragments of the downed targets fell in the coastal area and near Balaklava, which is a part of the Sevastopol agglomeration.</p>

<p>Razvozhayev, who had initially reported four downed targets, said there had been no injuries. He said a number of fires had been reported in forested and open areas and windows had been smashed in one building.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia shot down five aerial targets over Crimea on Monday. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-visa-fee-hike-for-international-students-will-affect-indians-6013115]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Australia's Visa Fee Hike For Foreign Students Will Affect Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-visa-fee-hike-for-international-students-will-affect-indians-6013115]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:06:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia has more than doubled the cost of student visa fees for international students from $710 to $1,600, a move which will impact lakhs of Indians planning to study in this country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia has more than doubled the cost of student visa fees for international students from $710 to $1,600, a move which will impact lakhs of Indians planning to study in this country.</p>

<p>The move has triggered outrage from student representatives who say that the price hike will drive potential students to competitors, ABC News reported on Monday.</p>

<p>From July 1, the international student visa fee has risen to $1,600 from $710. The federal government said the additional revenue will help fund initiatives in education including cuts to graduate debt, financial support for apprentices, and the ongoing implementation of its migration strategy, the report said.</p>

<p>"International education is an incredibly important national asset and we need to ensure its integrity and quality," Minister for Education Jason Clare said in a statement.</p>

<p>According to the Indian High Commission in Canberra, the number of Indian students enrolled for studying in Australia is estimated at around 1,20,277 as of August 2023, making Indian students the second largest cohort of foreign students in Australia.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Yeganeh Soltanpour, the national president of the Council of International Students Australia, slammed the decision, noting the fee increase, combined with high deposit costs, places extra strain on international students, the ABC report said.</p>

<p>"The possibility of spending all that money only to face rejection is quite disheartening for many students. It has caused many in the student community to explore other options and competitive countries," she said.</p>

<p>Phil Honeywood, CEO of the International Education Association of Australia, told the ABC that the announcement was the "last straw" for the international education sector, which has already suffered from a slowdown in visa approvals.</p>

<p>"We are really in danger of losing a USD 48 billion a year industry," he said, adding that it will "heavily impact" on relationships with our Indo-Pacific neighbours who rely on Australia to deliver world-class qualifications to young people. He warned that this change could drive prospective students to the United Kingdom, Australia's closest competitor, which currently charges $900 for student visa fees.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-07/t8d2vrek_australia-generic-sydney-generic-sydney-opera-house-pixabay_625x300_29_July_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian students are second largest cohort of foreign students in Australia. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-orders-review-of-ruling-on-contentious-social-media-laws-6013109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Supreme Court Orders Review Of Ruling On Contentious Social Media Laws]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-supreme-court-orders-review-of-ruling-on-contentious-social-media-laws-6013109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:04:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Supreme Court on Monday ordered lower courts to review a pair of Republican-backed state laws that imposed restrictions on social media companies to moderate content, sidestepping a ruling on their constitutional validity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Supreme Court on Monday ordered lower courts to review a pair of Republican-backed state laws that imposed restrictions on social media companies to moderate content, sidestepping a ruling on their constitutional validity.</p>

<p>Tech industry trade groups, which welcomed the decision, had challenged the laws passed in 2021 by conservative Republican lawmakers in Florida and Texas as part of a broader pushback against perceived anti-conservative bias by major platforms such as Meta-owned Facebook and X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>The companies denied that they were censoring conservative viewpoints under the guise of content moderation, as their advocates argued that the laws quashed the platforms' own First Amendment rights under the US Constitution.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court declined to rule on whether it was constitutional for states to pass such legislation, leaving the two laws in limbo as it instructed the lower courts for a thorough review.</p>

<p>Florida's measure bars social media platforms from pulling content from politicians, a law that was passed after former president Donald Trump was suspended from Twitter and Facebook in the wake of the January 6, 2021 assault on the US Capitol.</p>

<p>In Texas, the law stops sites from pulling content based on a "viewpoint" and is also intended to thwart what conservatives see as censorship by tech platforms such as Facebook and YouTube against right-wing ideas.</p>

<p>Neither law has gone into effect due to the litigation.</p>

<p>The challenge to the laws were brought by associations representing big tech companies, the Computer &amp; Communications Industry Association (CCIA) and NetChoice, who argue that the First Amendment allows platforms to have the freedom to handle content as they see fit.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Orwellian' -</strong></p>

<p>"We are encouraged that a majority of the court has made clear that the government cannot tilt public debate in its favored direction," CCIA president Matt Schruers said in a statement.</p>

<p>"There is nothing more Orwellian than government attempting to dictate what speech should be carried, whether it is a newspaper or a social media site."</p>

<p>The decision was also welcomed by tech advocacy groups.</p>

<p>"The government does not have the right to impose rules on how companies like Meta and Google should accomplish" platform accountability measures, said Nora Benavidez, senior counsel at the watchdog Free Press.</p>

<p>"These laws would have further ratcheted up the amount of hate and disinformation online while undermining both the meaning and the intent of the First Amendment," she added.</p>

<p>But other advocates cautioned that the decision must not absolve tech firms of their responsibility to address threats to public safety and democracy.</p>

<p>"Today's unanimous opinion ensures platforms can enforce their community and safety standards during a critical election year," said Nicole Gill, executive director of the watchdog Accountable Tech.</p>

<p>"But make no mistake: this is not an excuse for platforms to continue to shrug off their role in the desecration of democracy and proliferation of a myriad of societal harms."</p>

<p>Monday's decision comes after the Supreme Court last week rejected a Republican-led bid to curb government contact with social media companies to moderate their content.</p>

<p>The decision handed a win to President Joe Biden's administration and top government agencies ahead of the presidential vote in November, allowing them to continue notifying major platforms including Facebook and X about what they deem as false or hateful content.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/186j3rl8_social-media-app_625x300_23_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The decision was also welcomed by tech advocacy groups.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-syria-north-korea-sued-for-providing-hamas-support-in-us-court-6013075]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran, Syria, North Korea Sued For Providing Hamas Support In US Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-syria-north-korea-sued-for-providing-hamas-support-in-us-court-6013075]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:57:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 100 victims and relatives of victims of the Oct. 7 attack by Hamas militants in Israel sued Iran, Syria and North Korea on Monday, accusing the countries of providing Hamas support and demanding at least $4 billion in damages.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 100 victims and relatives of victims of the October 7 attack by Hamas militants in Israel sued Iran, Syria and North Korea on Monday, accusing the countries of providing Hamas support and demanding at least $4 billion in damages.</p>

<p>The lawsuit filed in federal court in Washington, D.C., by the Anti-Defamation League is the largest case against foreign countries in connection with the attack, and the first backed by a Jewish organization, the ADL said in a press release.</p>

<p>It accuses the three countries of providing financial, military and tactical support to Hamas. The US government has designed Iran, Syria and North Korea state sponsors of terrorism.</p>

<p>More than 1,200 people were killed in the attack and 250 others were taken hostage, according to Israeli tallies. The complainants in the case include US citizens injured on October 7, as well as relatives and the estates of victims killed in the attack.</p>

<p>Israel's offensive in Gaza in response has killed nearly 38,000 people, according to Gazan health officials, and left the enclave in ruins.</p>

<p>"Iran is the world's leading state sponsor of antisemitism and terror - along with Syria and North Korea, they must be held responsible for their roles in the largest antisemitic attack since the Holocaust," ADL Chief Executive Jonathan Greenblatt said in a statement.</p>

<p>Iran already faced several similar lawsuits in connection with the October 7 attack.</p>

<p>The Iran, North Korea and Syria missions to the United Nations in New York did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>It is common for countries accused of state-sponsored terrorism to ignore lawsuits in the US and not to honor judgments against them in US courts.</p>

<p>If the defendants are found liable, the complainants hope to tap the US Victims of State Sponsored Terrorism Fund, which Congress created in 2015 to compensate individuals who have won judgments against state sponsors of terrorism.</p>

<p>But the fund has run low, prompting several members of Congress to introduce legislation in May that would enhance funding and guarantee annual payments to victims.</p>

<p>Monday's lawsuit seeks at least $1 billion of compensatory damages and $3 billion of punitive damages.</p>

<p>"While nothing will ever undo the unbearable pain Hamas caused our family or the brutal losses we've suffered, we hope this case will bring some sense of justice," complainant Nahar Neta, whose American-born mother Adrienne Neta was killed on October 7, said in a statement.</p>

<p>The law firm of Crowell &amp; Moring also represents the complainants.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6gq7ft38_jonathan-greenblatt_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran already faced several similar lawsuits in connection with the October 7 attack. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-charged-for-breaching-eu-tech-rules-over-pay-or-consent-model-6013016]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Charged For Breaching EU Tech Rules Over Pay Or Consent Model]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-charged-for-breaching-eu-tech-rules-over-pay-or-consent-model-6013016]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:46:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms was charged by EU antitrust regulators on Monday for failing to comply with landmark tech rules as they took aim at the US company's newly introduced pay or consent advertising model.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms was charged by EU antitrust regulators on Monday for failing to comply with landmark tech rules as they took aim at the US company's newly introduced pay or consent advertising model, already the target of privacy regulators and activists' ire.</p>

<p>The tech giant launched the no-ads subscription service for Facebook and Instagram in Europe last November, saying users who consent to be tracked get a free service which is funded by advertising revenues. Or they could pay for an ad-free service.</p>

<p>The European Commission, which acts as the EU competition enforcer, said the binary choice breaches the bloc's Digital Markets Act (DMA) which seeks to rein in the power of Big Tech, as it sent its preliminary finding to Meta.</p>

<p>It said the binary choice forces users to consent to the combination of their personal data and fails to provide them a less personalised but equivalent version of Meta's social networks.</p>

<p>"We want to empower citizens to be able to take control over their own data and choose a less personalised ads experience," EU antitrust chief Margrethe Vestager said in a statement.</p>

<p>Meta said its model complied with a ruling from Europe's top court.</p>

<p>"Subscription for no ads follows the direction of the highest court in Europe and complies with the DMA. We look forward to further constructive dialogue with the European Commission to bring this investigation to a close," a Meta spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Meta can tweak its advertising model to stave off a fine of as much as 10% of its global annual turnover if found guilty of DMA breaches. The Commission has until March next year to wrap up its investigation.</p>

<p>Privacy activists and privacy watchdogs have also taken issue with Meta's advertising model.</p>

<p>Reuters was the first to report that the EU competition enforcer would charge Meta with non-compliance under the Digital Markets Act.</p>

<p>The charge against Meta came a week after the EU watchdog issued its first DMA charge against Apple for not complying with the new rule.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/o6cm085g_meta-generic-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta said its model complied with a ruling from Europe's top court. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-food-medicine-gaza-hospital-chiefs-israel-detention-ordeal-6013006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[No Food, Medicine: Gaza Hospital Chief's Israel Detention Ordeal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/no-food-medicine-gaza-hospital-chiefs-israel-detention-ordeal-6013006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:42:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the Gaza Strip's biggest hospital said on Monday after being freed from more than seven months of detention that he had been "tortured" by Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the Gaza Strip's biggest hospital said on Monday after being freed from more than seven months of detention that he had been "tortured" by Israel.</p>

<p>Al-Shifa hospital director Mohammed Abu Salmiya was among dozens of Palestinians released and returned to Gaza for treatment, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>Abu Salmiya said he and other prisoners were put through "severe torture" in Israeli prisons, after being detained since the October 7 cross-border attacks by Hamas.</p>

<p>"Several inmates died in interrogation centres and were deprived of food and medicine," according to Abu Salmiya, who said he still had a broken thumb.</p>

<p>"For two months no prisoner ate more than a loaf of bread a day," he added.</p>

<p>"Detainees were subjected to physical and psychological humiliation."</p>

<p>The medical chief said no charge had ever been made against him.</p>

<p>Israel's Shin Bet intelligence agency said it had decided on the release with the Israeli military "to free up places in detention centres".</p>

<p>The agency said it "opposed the release of terrorists" who had taken part in attacks on Israeli civilians "so it was decided to free several Gaza detainees who represent a lesser danger".</p>

<p>However commenting on X, formerly Twitter, National Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir called Abu Salmiya's release "with dozens of other terrorists" a "security abandonment".</p>

<p>Israeli forces detained Abu Salmiya during one of a number of raids on Al-Shifa.</p>

<p><strong>Emotional reunions</strong></p>

<p>Israel's military has accused Hamas of using hospitals in the Gaza Strip as a cover for military operations. It has raided Al-Shifa and other hospitals, and says it has found tunnels and other infrastructure.</p>

<p>The Hamas group, which has run the territory since 2007, denies the allegations.</p>

<p>Al-Shifa hospital has been reduced to rubble by successive raids since Israel launched its assault on Gaza after the October 7 Hamas attacks.</p>

<p>After crossing back to Gaza near the city of Khan Yunis, five detainees were admitted to Al-Aqsa hospital and the others were sent to hospitals in Khan Yunis, a medical source said.</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent at Deir al-Balah saw some detainees in emotional reunions with their families.</p>

<p>Abu Salmiya was not the only top medical practitioner detained.</p>

<p>The Gaza European hospital in Khan Yunis said the head of its orthopaedic unit, Bassam Miqdad, was among those freed on Monday.</p>

<p>In May, Palestinian rights groups said a senior Al-Shifa surgeon had died in an Israeli jail after being detained. The Israeli army said it was unaware of the death.</p>

<p>The war started with Hamas's October 7 attack which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,900 people, also mostly civilians, according to Gaza's Hamas-run health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bn0aes2_mohammed-abu-salmiya_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The medical chief said no charge had ever been made against him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepalese-spiritual-leader-buddha-boy-for-10-years-over-child-sex-abuse-6012950]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepalese Spiritual Leader 'Buddha Boy' For 10 Years Over Child Sex Abuse]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepalese-spiritual-leader-buddha-boy-for-10-years-over-child-sex-abuse-6012950]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:36:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Nepali court on Monday sentenced a man whose followers believe him to be a reincarnation of Buddha to 10 years in prison for child sexual abuse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Nepali court on Monday sentenced a man whose followers believe him to be a reincarnation of Buddha to 10 years in prison for child sexual abuse.</p>

<p>Ram Bahadur Bomjan, known as "Buddha boy" by his devotees, became famous as a teenager after followers said he could meditate motionless for months without water, food or sleep.</p>

<p>He was convicted of child sexual abuse last week by the court in Nepal's southern town of Sarlahi.</p>

<p>"He has been sentenced to 10 years in jail," Sadan Adhikari, registrar at the district court, told AFP.</p>

<p>Bomjan was also fined 500,000 Nepali rupees ($3,743).</p>

<p>The 33-year-old guru has a devout following but has long been accused of physically and sexually assaulting his followers, and had been hiding from authorities for several years.</p>

<p>Nepal's Central Investigation Bureau arrested him in January at a house on the outskirts of the capital Kathmandu.</p>

<p>Police said he was caught with bundles of cash amounting to 30 million Nepali rupees and another $22,500 in foreign currency.</p>

<p>Dozens of assault complaints were filed against Bomjan in 2010.</p>

<p>He said he beat the victims because they disturbed his meditation.</p>

<p>An 18-year-old nun also accused Bomjan of raping her at a monastery in 2018.</p>

<p>Police opened another investigation against him the following year, after family members reported the disappearance of four of his devotees from one of his ashrams.</p>

<p>Before he went on the run, Bomjan still commanded a legion of followers.</p>

<p>At one point, tens of thousands of people gathered to witness his reputed miracles of meditation deep in the jungle.</p>

<p>Aged 16, Bomjan disappeared for nine months to wander the wilderness of eastern Nepal, prompting a round-the-clock vigil by Buddhist monks who prayed for his safe return.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/emf93dhg_buddha-boy_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bomjan was also fined 500,000 Nepali rupees ($3,743) (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-issues-new-southern-gaza-evacuation-warning-6012908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Issues New Southern Gaza Evacuation Warning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-issues-new-southern-gaza-evacuation-warning-6012908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:30:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli army on Monday issued a new evacuation order for parts of Khan Yunis and Rafah in southern Gaza, with witnesses reporting that many were fleeing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli army on Monday issued a new evacuation order for parts of Khan Yunis and Rafah in southern Gaza, with witnesses reporting that many were fleeing.</p>

<p>Hundreds of thousands had already left Rafah ahead of and during a ground offensive launched by Israeli troops on the southernmost city since early May.</p>

<p>The warning for Al-Qarara, Bani Suhaila and other towns in the two governorates, made on social media and in an official statement, came hours after Israel said 20 "projectiles" were fired into Israel from the Khan Yunis region.</p>

<p>The attack was claimed by the armed wing of the Palestinian group Islamic Jihad. Israel had already staged air strikes in Rafah on Monday.</p>

<p>"Fear and extreme anxiety have gripped people after the evacuation order," said Bani Suhaila resident Ahmad Najjar. "There is a large displacement of residents."</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres's spokesman said "it just shows yet again, that no place is safe in Gaza, more efforts need to be made to protect civilians".</p>

<p>"It's another stop in this deadly circle of movement that the population in Gaza has to undergo on a regular basis," added the spokesman, Stephane Dujarric.</p>

<p>Since launching its ground offensive in Gaza on October 27, Israeli forces progressively moved south in the Palestinian territory, seeking to destroy Hamas battalions, though fighting has restarted in the north.</p>

<p>The war began with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza including 42 the army says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,900 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tvebgnig_gaza_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-25-injured-due-to-strong-turbulance-on-air-europa-flight-report-6012893]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 25 Injured Due To "Strong Turbulance" On Air Europa Flight: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-25-injured-due-to-strong-turbulance-on-air-europa-flight-report-6012893]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:27:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Air Europa Boeing plane made an emergency landing in Brazil Monday after several people were injured by "strong turbulence" on a flight from Madrid to Montevideo, the airline said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Air Europa Boeing plane made an emergency landing in Brazil Monday after several people were injured by "strong turbulence" on a flight from Madrid to Montevideo, the airline said.</p>

<p>The 787-9 Dreamliner was diverted to the airport of Natal in northeastern Brazil on its way to the Uruguayan capital, the Spanish company said on X, adding that passengers who suffered injuries "are receiving attention."</p>

<p>Uruguay's foreign ministry said in a statement that passengers in need of medical attention were taken to the Monsenhor Walfredo Gurgel hospital in Natal. Several have already been discharged.</p>

<p>A Uruguayan diplomatic source told AFP "between 25 and 30" people were injured, but the number was not final.</p>

<p>Most suffered "mild trauma" and "at first sight, no one's life is at risk," said the source.</p>

<p>Air Europa said a plane will leave from Madrid later Monday to pick up the passengers in Natal and continue the journey to Uruguay.</p>

<p>In May, a 73-year-old British man died and several other passengers and crew suffered skull, brain and spine injuries when a Singapore Airlines Boeing 777 hit severe turbulence on a flight from London and was forced to make an emergency landing in Bangkok.</p>

<p><strong>Worse turbulence</strong></p>

<p>Air safety experts say passengers are often too casual about wearing seatbelts, leaving them at risk if the plane hits unexpected turbulence.</p>

<p>Scientists also say that so-called clear air turbulence, which is invisible to radar, is getting worse because of climate change.</p>

<p>A 2023 study found the annual duration of clear air turbulence increased by 17 percent from 1979 to 2020, with the most severe cases increasing by more than 50 percent.</p>

<p>Monday's incident was the latest drama involving a Boeing plane, after a fuselage panel blew out of an Alaska Airlines 737 MAX in January as well as two crashes in 2018 and 2019 that killed 346 people in total.</p>

<p>In March, the US aviation giant announced the departure of CEO Dave Calhoun as it faced intense scrutiny on safety and manufacturing standards.</p>

<p>The company announced earlier Monday it had reached a deal to buy its subcontractor Spirit in a move it said would boost safety and quality control.</p>

<p>Boeing this week also faces a key turning point with the Department of Justice, which concluded in May the company could be prosecuted for violating a 2021 deferred prosecution agreement reached following the two fatal 737 MAX crashes.</p>

<p>A lawyer for the victims' families said Sunday that the DOJ was offering Boeing a plea deal that would allow it to avoid a trial.</p>

<p>Victims' families have called for the criminal prosecution of Boeing and its executives, and are seeking a nearly $25 billion fine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/q503tpp_air-europa-turbulance_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Air Europa said a plane will leave from Madrid later Monday to pick up the passengers in Natal]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-to-establish-gandhi-king-development-foundation-by-october-6012411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India, US To Establish Gandhi-King Development Foundation By October]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-us-to-establish-gandhi-king-development-foundation-by-october-6012411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 22:09:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The statement of intent was signed during the visit by US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan to India last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India and the United States signed a statement of intent to formally establish the Gandhi-King Development Foundation (GKDF) by October this year, which aims to address global development challenges. The statement of intent was signed during the visit by US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan to India last month.</p>

<p>"This significant step, occurring during White House National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan's visit to India, builds on the U.S. Congress's passage of the Gandhi-King Scholarly Exchange Initiative Act in December 2020, sponsored by Representative Gregory W. Meeks, which authorized USAID to create the Gandhi-King Development Foundation," the US Embassy in India said in a press release.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The U.S. &amp; India are partnering to advance the Gandhi-King Development Foundation. Designed to embody the shared principles of Mahatma Gandhi &amp; Martin Luther King Jr., the Foundation will promote inclusive &amp; sustainable development. Read more here: <a href="https://t.co/aaphPlKbJ2">https://t.co/aaphPlKbJ2</a> <a href="https://t.co/0bxtFgd2Vd">pic.twitter.com/0bxtFgd2Vd</a></p>
— USAID India (@usaid_india) <a href="https://twitter.com/usaid_india/status/1807746742231732501?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><script src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"></script><br />
US Ambassador to India, Eric Garcetti emphasized that this foundation is built on the principles of Mahatma Gandhi and Martin Luther King Jr, two iconic leaders who promoted non-violent resistance and civil rights. Mr Garcetti stressed that the foundation showcases the shared commitment of both countries to work together towards global progress.</p>

<p>"The Gandhi-King Development Foundation represents a transformative partnership between the United States and India, rooted in the visionary ideals of Mahatma Gandhi and Martin Luther King Jr The foundation underscores our shared commitment to forging global progress by leveraging our collective strengths," he said.</p>

<p>US Agency for International Development (USAID) Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Anjali Kaur, who signed the Statement of Intent in New Delhi, said the foundation will promote inclusive and sustainable development.</p>

<p>"USAID is proud to support the Gandhi-King Development Foundation, which will promote inclusive and sustainable development, symbolizing the friendship and common values of the United States and India," she said.</p>

<p>US Congressman and Ranking Member of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, Gregory W Meeks expressed gratitude to be a part of this process and affirmed that this initiative will strengthen the bonds between both nations.</p>

<p>"I was glad to witness this important progress towards establishing the Gandhi-King Development Foundation, which will further strengthen the bonds between the United States and India. The Foundation will honour two visionary leaders and leverage the strength of our private sectors to address important issues such as public health, climate change and air pollution, and the empowerment of women," Mr Meeks said.</p>

<p>The Gandhi-King Development Foundation will operate locally in India, utilizing both public and private resources to advance India's national and global development objectives. These include addressing climate change, reducing tuberculosis, improving water and sanitation, minimizing the health impacts of air pollution, enhancing education outcomes, and promoting economic empowerment for women.</p>

<p>"The Gandhi-King Development Foundation signifies a groundbreaking partnership between the United States and India to address global development challenges," the embassy's statement added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/akid6c3_gandhiking-development-foundation_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Gandhi-King Development Foundation will operate locally in India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-4-hurricane-beryl-makes-landfall-on-caribbean-island-of-carriacou-6012213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Category 4 Hurricane 'Beryl' Makes Landfall On Caribbean Island]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-4-hurricane-beryl-makes-landfall-on-caribbean-island-of-carriacou-6012213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 21:34:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beryl, the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, slammed into the Caribbean island of Carriacou, which is part of Grenada, on Monday as a powerful Category 4 storm, the National Hurricane Center said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Beryl slammed into the Caribbean island of Carriacou on Monday, producing "life-threatening conditions" including disastrous winds, according to US trackers, after the storm strengthened into a powerful Category 4 storm.</p>

<p>With the "extremely dangerous eyewall" moving over the island, which is part of Grenada, the US National Hurricane Center warned residents "not leave their shelter as winds will rapidly increase."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">1200 PM AST Jul 1 Position Update: Extremely dangerous <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Beryl?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Beryl</a> is producing catastrophic winds and life-threatening storm surge in the southern Windward Islands. For the latest information visit <a href="https://t.co/tW4KeGe9uJ">https://t.co/tW4KeGe9uJ</a> <a href="https://t.co/xgMxdNrd5W">pic.twitter.com/xgMxdNrd5W</a></p>
— National Hurricane Center (@NHC_Atlantic) <a href="https://twitter.com/NHC_Atlantic/status/1807805378140475635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The eye of Beryl made landfall on Carriacou Island at 1510 GMT, the NHC reported on X, adding in a bulletin that it was creating "catastrophic winds and life-threatening storm surge."</p>

<p>Posting a video showing large waves, the Office of the Prime Minister of Grenada wrote on Facebook that the tri-island state was "experiencing intense winds and damage."</p>

<p>"This is an extremely dangerous and life-threatening situation," the NHC said. "Residents should not leave their shelter and remain in place through the passage of these life-threatening conditions."</p>

<p>Experts say that such a powerful storm forming this early in the Atlantic hurricane season -- which runs from early June to late November -- is extremely rare.</p>

<p>"Only five major (Category 3+) hurricanes have been recorded in the Atlantic before the first week of July," hurricane expert Michael Lowry posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"Beryl would be the sixth and earliest this far east in the tropical Atlantic."</p>

<p>Grenada Prime Minister Dickon Mitchell urged citizens to quickly seek shelter and respect an island-wide curfew ordered for 7:00 pm to 7:00 am Tuesday morning.</p>

<p>Farther northeast in the Caribbean, officials in Barbados said the island was buffeted by high winds and pelting rain, but appeared to have avoided disaster, reporting no injuries so far.</p>

<p>Barbados seems to have "dodged a bullet," Minister of Home Affairs and Information Wilfred Abrahams said in a video, but nonetheless "gusts are still coming, the storm-force winds are still coming" he said, warning residents to remain inside until the all-clear.</p>

<p>Barbados, Grenada, plus Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, and Tobago were all under hurricane warnings, the NHC said, while a hurricane watch or tropical storm warnings or watches were in effect for Jamaica, Martinique, Trinidad, St Lucia, and parts of the Dominican Republic and Haiti.</p>

<p>A state of emergency was declared in Tobago, the smaller of the two islands that make up Trinidad and Tobago, with schools ordered closed on Monday, top official Farley Augustine said.</p>

<p>A meeting this week in Grenada of the Caribbean regional bloc CARICOM was postponed.</p>

<p><strong>Extreme weather</strong></p>

<p>Beryl became the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season early Saturday morning and quickly strengthened to Category 4, the first ever to reach that level in June, according to NHC records.</p>

<p>A Category 3 or higher on the Saffir-Simpson scale is considered a major hurricane, and a Category 4 storm packs sustained winds of at least 130 miles per hour (209 kilometers per hour).</p>

<p>As Beryl struck Carriacou, it was packing maximum sustained winds that had increased to 150 mph, the NHC said.</p>

<p>Beryl is expected to remain powerful as it moves across the Caribbean, the NHC said, warning residents and officials in the Lesser Antilles, Hispaniola, Jamaica, the Cayman Islands and the remainder of the northwestern Caribbean to carefully monitor its progress.</p>

<p>The US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration said in late May that it expects this year to be an "extraordinary" hurricane season, with up to seven storms of Category 3 or higher.</p>

<p>The agency cited warm Atlantic Ocean temperatures and conditions related to the weather phenomenon La Nina in the Pacific for the expected increase in storms.</p>

<p>Extreme weather events including hurricanes have become more frequent and more devastating in recent years as a result of climate change.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/8ujjnk48_hurricane-generic-_625x300_29_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Winds will rapidly increase within the eyewall. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-has-some-immunity-from-prosecution-as-ex-president-us-supreme-court-6012125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Has Some Immunity From Prosecution As Ex President: US Supreme Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-has-some-immunity-from-prosecution-as-ex-president-us-supreme-court-6012125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 21:21:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Supreme Court ruled Monday that Donald Trump enjoys some immunity from prosecution as a former president, a ruling that will likely delay his trial for conspiring to overturn the 2020 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Supreme Court ruled Monday that Donald Trump enjoys some immunity from prosecution as a former president, a ruling that will likely delay his trial for conspiring to overturn the 2020 election.</p>

<p>The 6-3 decision split along ideological lines comes four months ahead of the election in which Trump is the Republican candidate to take on Democrat Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Conservative Chief Justice John Roberts, in his majority opinion, said a president enjoys "absolute immunity" from criminal prosecution for official acts taken while in office.</p>

<p>"There is no immunity for unofficial acts," Roberts said, sending the case back to a lower court to determine which of the charges facing the former president involves official or unofficial conduct.</p>

<p>The three liberal justices dissented, with Justice Sonia Sotomayor saying "never in the history of our Republic has a President had reason to believe that he would be immune from criminal prosecution if he used the trappings of his office to violate the criminal law."</p>

<p>"With fear for our democracy, I dissent," she said.</p>

<p>Trump's original trial date in the election case had been for March 4, well before his November rematch with President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>But the Supreme Court -- dominated by conservatives, including the three appointed by Trump during his term in office -- agreed in February to hear his argument for presidential immunity, putting the case on hold while they considered the matter in April.</p>

<p>Facing four criminal cases, Trump has been doing everything in his power to delay the trials at least until after the election.</p>

<p>On May 30, a New York court convicted Trump on 34 felony charges of falsifying business records to cover up a sex scandal in the final stages of the 2016 presidential campaign, making Trump the first former US president ever convicted of a crime.</p>

<p>His sentencing will take place on July 11.</p>

<p>The New York hush money case was considered the weakest of the four cases by many legal experts, but likely the only one that will see trial before the vote.</p>

<p>By filing many pre-trial motions, Trump's lawyers have managed to put on hold the three other trials, which deal with his attempts to overturn the 2020 election results and hoarding top-secret documents at his home in Florida.</p>

<p>If reelected, Trump could, once sworn in as president in January 2025, order the federal trials against him closed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/trbnmngo_donald-trump_625x300_02_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["There is no immunity for unofficial acts," said Chief Justice (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-let-90-minutes-define-4-years-jill-biden-on-joe-bidens-debate-performance-6011464]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Won't Let 90 Minutes Define 4 Years": Joe Biden's Wife On Debate Fiasco]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-let-90-minutes-define-4-years-jill-biden-on-joe-bidens-debate-performance-6011464]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 20:00:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She said, "We will continue to fight," and claimed that Mr Biden "will always do what's best for the country."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a shaky debate performance on Thursday night, political analysts and several US media organisations have been calling for US President Joe Biden to drop out of the 2024 election race. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-rally-behind-biden-after-shaky-debate-performance-with-trump-6004687">Democratic leaders rallied behind Mr Biden</a> following his poor performance last week, as the White House denied a report he was meeting with family to assess his candidacy. Now, his wife and First Lady Jill Biden has spoken about the debate and has said that they "will continue to fight".</p>

<p>Talking to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vogue.com/article/first-lady-jill-biden-august-2024-cover-interview"><em>Vogue </em></a>from Camp David where the family was spending the weekend, she told the magazine "will not let those 90 minutes define the four years he's been president."</p>

<p>She continued, "We will continue to fight," and claimed that Mr Biden "will always do what's best for the country."</p>

<p>Notably, President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters and there have been calls from some Democrats for him to step aside for a new candidate. Despite weak poll numbers and questions about his age, he has stuck to his plan to seek a second term.</p>

<p>On June 27, the 81-year-old's performance in the presidential debate, rekindled calls for him to step away. When responding to a question about the economy posed by a CNN anchor, the POTUS, who is often observed stuttering and freezing during public events, seemed to lose his train of thought. When asked if voters felt "worse off" under his presidency, the Democrat committed yet another error.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, President<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-know-i-am-not-young-man-but-joe-biden-after-poor-debate-showing-5994162"> Joe Biden said after the debate </a>that he would defeat Republican rival Donald Trump in the presidential election, giving no sign he would consider dropping out of the race. He said, "I know I'm not a young man, to state the obvious. I don't walk as easy as I used to, I don't speak as smoothly as I used to, I don't debate as well as I used to."</p>

<p>"I would not be running again if I didn't believe with all my heart and soul that I could do this job. The stakes are too high," he said at a rally.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/re7vinl_jill-and-joe-biden_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/gemini-ai-google-ai-after-meta-ai-gemini-ai-rolls-out-inside-google-messages-6010796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Meta AI, Gemini AI Rolls Out In Google Messages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/gemini-ai-google-ai-after-meta-ai-gemini-ai-rolls-out-inside-google-messages-6010796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 18:27:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This development follows Google's recent announcement and the initial introduction of Gemini AI on other platforms like Gmail, according to GSM Arena.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google has begun rolling out an exciting update to its Messages app, integrating Gemini AI to enhance functionality and user interaction directly within chats.</p>

<p>This development follows Google's recent announcement and the initial introduction of Gemini AI on other platforms like Gmail, according to GSM Arena.</p>

<p>The Gemini AI integration aims to streamline user experience by providing quick access to artificial intelligence capabilities without leaving the Messages app.</p>

<p>Users will notice a new floating action button positioned above the "Start chat" button in the lower-right corner of the interface, facilitating easy access to the AI service.</p>

<p>Although the feature is currently not widely available, Google assures users that Gemini AI functions similarly to its standalone counterpart on Android devices, as per GSM Arena.</p>

<p>This integration allows users to ask questions, receive information, or issue commands seamlessly while continuing their conversations within Messages.</p>

<p>It's important to note that Gemini AI respects user privacy by not scanning private conversations.</p>

<p>However, interactions with the AI chatbot are not end-to-end encrypted, prompting users to exercise caution when sharing sensitive information.</p>

<p>Google also provides options for users to manage their chat history with Gemini, allowing storage customization from default settings of 18 months up to 36 months or as low as 3 months.</p>

<p>Regarding privacy concerns, Gemini AI does not track user location beyond general details derived from IP addresses or home addresses to provide relevant information.</p>

<p>As the update continues to roll out, users can look forward to enhanced capabilities and streamlined interactions within the Messages app.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/1o72d03o_gemini-ai_625x300_07_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google has announced integration of Gemini AI across platforms]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-charged-with-abusing-and-starving-2-of-her-adopted-children-before-murdering-them-6010354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Charged With Starving 2 Adopted Children Before Murdering Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-charged-with-abusing-and-starving-2-of-her-adopted-children-before-murdering-them-6010354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 17:30:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During a press conference, police said they have the forensic evidence to support allegations of torture, starvation, and isolation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 63-year-old woman in the US has been arrested and charged with killing two of her adopted children after their bodies were discovered inside a burn barrel. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/north-carolina-mom-charged-blake-deven-death-b2571404.html">Independent</a></em>, two of Avantae Deven's adopted children, Blake and London Deven, hadn't been seen for years.&nbsp;London was last seen in 2019, but&nbsp;her mother never reported&nbsp;her missing. Blake hasn't been seen since 2022, but Deven didn't report him missing until earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Authorities in Fayetteville, North Carolina were alerted of the situation in 2023 after one of her surviving foster children made a mental health call to police. When cops investigated the multiple homes the family had lived in, they found remains at multiple residences.&nbsp;Detectives found a burn barrel with partial human remains inside it. Forensic tests revealed that they belonged to a female aged 15 to 19 and a male aged 7 to 10.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Investigators believe that Deven abused the children and ultimately killed and&nbsp;dismembered them.&nbsp;As per&nbsp;NBC affiliate <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wral.com/story/avantae-deven-given-no-bond-in-first-court-appearance-could-face-death-penalty/21500933/">WRAL</a></em>, London died of starvation and neglect while testing continues on the boy's remains.</p>

<p>More chilling details released by the authorities this week revealed that the siblings, along with three other adopted children, had lived in brutal conditions while in the care of Deven. Blake and London were adopted by Deven in 2013 and 2011 respectively, according to court documents obtained by&nbsp;<em><a href="https://abc11.com/missing-fayetteville-children-blake-deven-911-call-buddhist-retreat/14735061/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">ABC11</a></em>.</p>

<p>They were kept in a small, dark room and given little to no food.&nbsp;They were allegedly able to "earn" food by writing hundreds of paragraphs to apologise for their behaviour. The children told social workers that they were also beaten at times to the point where they would have needed medical assistance.</p>

<p>During a press conference, police said they have the forensic evidence to support allegations of torture, starvation, and isolation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''We believe he (Blake) was mentally abused and starved. His body could not sustain the inhumane treatment. Then, Avantae developed a plan to hide Blake's remains. She forced another person in the household to participate,''&nbsp;Sgt. Locklear said. London Deven died ''in the same painful way that Blake died, starvation and neglect,'' Mr Locklear added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Deven is now facing two counts of first-degree murder, concealment of death, kidnapping and felony child abuse, according to the Fayetteville Police Department.&nbsp;&nbsp;She is being held at the Cumberland County Detention Center with no bond.</p>

<p>"All of us have soft spots for children and cases with children are the most difficult that we deal with. The fact that this involves allegations of the abuse in the death of children was certainly the thing that grabbed my attention first, particularly how the allegations suggest the way they died,''&nbsp;Cumberland County District Attorney Billy West said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9gt6g9eo_avantae-deven_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Investigators believe that Deven abused the children and ultimately killed and dismembered them.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-shoot-and-kill-13-year-old-who-wielded-replica-gun-6010023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Police Shoot And Kill 13-Year-Old Who Wielded Replica Gun]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-police-shoot-and-kill-13-year-old-who-wielded-replica-gun-6010023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:54:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nyah Mway produced what appeared to be a handgun when the police attempted to frisk him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 13-year-old boy was shot and killed by police in New York's Utica on June 28 after he wielded a replica gun, as per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/13-year-old-boy-shot-and-killed-by-police-in-new-york-8671733"><em>People Magazine</em></a>. Around 10 pm, Police Officer Patrick Husnay along with two other officers were patrolling an area where "at least two" robberies had taken place recently. The cops went up to Nyah Mway and another boy, also aged 13, who "were in the immediate vicinity of the previous robbery at nearly the same time of day," based on the traits of suspects in a June 27 crime, according to the release from the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=877233874446674&amp;id=100064802073577&amp;ref=embed_post">Utica Police Department</a>.</p>

<p>The two teenagers were the subject of an attempted citizen stop by the authorities. However, the teen escaped and produced what appeared to be a handgun when the police attempted to frisk him, according to the preliminary information.</p>

<p>The press release mentioned, "In one of the incidents that occurred on June 27th, the suspects were described as one Asian male and one dark skinned male, with one being on foot and the other on a bicycle. Based on the listed identifying factors from the robbery, officers approached Nyah Mway and the other juvenile as they matched the robbery suspects' descriptions and were in the immediate vicinity of the previous robbery at nearly the same time of day."</p>

<p>It added, "When the officers asked and went to pat frisk Nyah Mway, he immediately fled on foot. While fleeing he produced a replica GLOCK pellet gun from the front of his body, and during the 51 and 53 second mark on Officer Patterson's BWC, points the weapon directly at Officer Patterson and the other officers."</p>

<p>According to the authorities, Officer Husnay then shot the teen with his duty firearm. The 13-year-old was transported to a hospital, however, he died as a result of his injuries. The Utica Police Department released<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1Pox0_Tpfyv7Qx0NqSwsXn7x4JrhY9368"> bodycam footage</a> of the incident as well as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/15uEANYzlhU54NuAoyNnf9FtbwdSfnbzc">pictures </a>of the pellet gun.</p>

<p>According to <em>ABC News</em>, all three cops have been sent on administrative leaves. Further, a vigil was organised after his death. Several people including his family members attended the event.</p>

<p>The 13-year-old's sister, Thoung Oo, created a GoFundMe page to "raise funds for his funeral, legal expenses to seek justice, and family expenses including counselling." She said that her brother "was returning home from an 8th grade graduation barbecue" at the time of the shooting. He was an outgoing kid who loved to go biking and play with his friends and family.</p>

<p>Ms Oo said, "He has never gotten in trouble with law enforcement before, he was a good kid. The UPD video cam, the witness testimonies, and stories they told my family don't add up, especially when they told my parents (who don't speak English at all) that there was a shoot out. We need answers."</p>

<p>Nyah had just graduated from eighth grade two days before the tragedy, according to his sister. She continued, "Because of this tragedy, I will never get to see him grow up. Nyah leaves behind our mother, father, and 3 siblings. Our family moved to America nine years ago as refugees from Myanmar to find a better life safe from law enforcement killings and ethnic cleansing. Our parents and grandparents did not flee war &amp; corrupt military to be persecuted by American police."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kamqcc2o_us-teen_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nyah had graduated from eighth grade two days before the tragedy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-for-joe-to-go-former-white-house-photographer-urges-biden-to-drop-out-after-trump-debate-6009960]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Time For Joe To Go": Ex White House Photographer Urges Biden To Drop Out]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-for-joe-to-go-former-white-house-photographer-urges-biden-to-drop-out-after-trump-debate-6009960]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:48:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[He claimed that White House aides have known for months that Joe Biden's mental health has been deteriorating but they covered it up ahead of the debate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a rocky debate performance on Thursday night, political analysts and several US media organisations have been calling for US President Joe Biden to drop out of the 2024 race. Now, the former White House deputy director of photography under the Biden administration&nbsp;has also joined the growing chorus.</p>

<p>In an Instagram story after the debate, Chandler West wrote, "It's time for Joe to go," <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/30/top-aides-shielded-biden-white-house-debate">Axios</a></em> reported.</p>

<p>"I know many of these people and how the White House operates. They will say he has a 'cold' or just experienced a 'bad night,' but for weeks and months, in private, they have all said what we saw last night—Joe is not as strong as he was just a couple of years ago. The debate was not the first bad day … it's not gonna be the last," Mr West<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/AlexThomp/status/1807388534069764154"> wrote.</a></p>

<p>He further claimed that&nbsp;White House aides have known for months that Joe Biden's mental health has been deteriorating but&nbsp;covered it up ahead of the debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Several unnamed current and former Biden aides told Axios that the president is mentally engaged from 10 a.m. to 4 p.m., but outside of this time frame, he is more likely to have verbal lapses and fatigue.</p>

<p>Notably, President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters and there have been calls from some Democrats for him to step aside for a new candidate.&nbsp;Despite weak poll numbers and questions about his age, he has stuck to his plan to seek a second term.</p>

<p>However, the 81-year-old president's alarming presidential debate performance on June 27, has renewed calls for him to step aside. Biden, frequently seen fumbling and freezing during public events, appeared to lose his train of thought while answering a question by a CNN anchor on the economy. The Democrat made yet another mistake while answering a question on voters feeling "worse off" under his presidency.</p>

<p>If Joe Biden withdraws his name, delegates from 50 states will have to look for a replacement at the earliest.&nbsp;Vice President Kamala Harris, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer and Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro are among the names that can represent the party.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/257p3v2_joe-biden-ians_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Biden's age is a particular concern with voters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-stock-market-trading-is-ai-going-to-change-the-way-we-invest-in-stock-markets-6009735]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Is AI Going to Change The Way We Invest In Stock Markets?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-stock-market-trading-is-ai-going-to-change-the-way-we-invest-in-stock-markets-6009735]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence (AI) has made inroads on multiple fronts in our lives. And investing in stock markets is the latest one set to be transformed by advancements in AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial Intelligence (AI) has made inroads on multiple fronts in our lives. And investing in stock markets is the latest one set to be transformed by advancements in AI. Retail investors are no longer solely reliant on human analysis by asset managers to make profit-making decisions, with AI revolutionising the investment landscape one day at a time.</p>

<p>According to American consulting firm Mercer, 9 out of 10 asset managers around the world use or intend to use AI in some capacity. This highlights the potential of AI for stock market management, the world's largest investment advisory firm said.</p>

<p>One of the obvious ways AI possesses the capability to reshape investments is the processing of financial data in real-time, giving data-based insights at a speed that's unmatched by humans. AI does not only analyse large data sets, but also recognises patterns and relationships in the data that can easily be missed by the human eye. Investment platforms like Alpha Vantage, Trade Ideas, and Macroaxis have already integrated AI tools to enhance the trading experience for its users, although at a premium charge.</p>

<p>AI can also discover unexpected connections between different financial assets (such as stocks and bonds) and other market determining factors, such as supply and demand. It can analyse non-market factors such as domain traffic for a company website to predict stock market performance.</p>

<p>AI can analyse alternative sources of data such as weather forecast and container ship movements to understand their effect on stock markets. A comparative advantage of using AI is the scalability and speed with which data can be processed.</p>

<p>Algorithmic trading, which uses mathematical models with set rules and human oversight, has been in use since the 1980s. This has been revolutionised by recent advances in AI, with AI algorithms capable of processing data in a much more efficient manner, automating decision-making and minimising human error. AI algorithms excel at processing unstructured data such as news articles and social media sentiments, assessing stock markets in real time.</p>

<p>In India, Zerodha, one of the market leaders in trading stocks, has integrated AI tools to provide personalised trading advice to its users. Other market competitors, like Upstox, have also taken to AI for integrating Chatbots. Indian firms have not yet, however, provided a real-time AI-driven solution for stock market trading. This is mainly due to the expensive nature of this technology, with a US-based web application giving these services at $300 a month for a basic subscription that allows only three daily updates.</p>

<p>Industry trends and demands suggest that India is set to take AI for its growing stock market industry, which recently hit an all-time high in market capitalisation in May this year, standing at nearly $5,000 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tqpokjj_stocks_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[AI powered stock market trading promises to be more reliant]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-europe-is-jittery-over-a-possible-return-of-trump-6009695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Europe Is Jittery Over A Possible Return Of Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-europe-is-jittery-over-a-possible-return-of-trump-6009695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:14:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In Europe, Biden's poor showing, which dramatically increased Trump's chances of being re-elected, has stirred up a lot of anxiety about what a second Trump term could mean for Europe's security and Ukraine's future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/kjveud4g_trump_625x300_01_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>President Joe Biden's shaky performance against his rival, Donald Trump, in the first presidential debate on Thursday has sent shockwaves across both sides of the Atlantic. In the US, a CBS News/YouGov poll on Sunday suggested that 72% of registered voters believed Biden did not have the mental fitness to serve as President. Biden is 81 and Trump is 78, but those who watched the debate would have noticed that Biden made his rival look a lot younger. More worrying for the Democratic Party was that the poll indicated that 45% of registered Democrats wanted Biden to step aside for another candidate.</p>

<p>In Europe, Biden's poor showing, which dramatically increased Trump's chances of being re-elected, has stirred up a lot of anxiety about what a second Trump term could mean for Europe's security and Ukraine's future. A Polish news website summed up the continent's worry: "Trump proved once again that his potential victory is bad news for NATO, Ukraine, and by extension, Poland."</p>

<p>Many Europeans believe that Europe's future without a strong US embrace is uncertain. They fear that if Trump wins in the November Presidential election, Europe's security won't be guaranteed. Trump has said he would end the Russia-Ukraine war, and if it ends with the current status quo, it could be seen more as a defeat for NATO than for Ukraine.</p>

<h2><strong>NATO Summit At A Critical Juncture</strong></h2>

<p>Amidst this anxiety, leaders of the 32-member NATO alliance are meeting in Washington from July 9 to 11 to celebrate its 75th anniversary. But with the ongoing war in Ukraine and Trump's comments in Thursday's debate, there won't be much to celebrate. Trump's views on NATO and Ukraine have cast a shadow over the summit. During the debate, Trump once again chastised European NATO members for not contributing enough to the alliance's budget, an issue that is most certainly to be discussed. Also, the Russian war in Ukraine will be at the top of the agenda, including the issue of Ukraine's membership in NATO.</p>

<p>One of the main reasons European leaders are apprehensive about Trump's potential re-election is his critical stance on NATO during his presidency. He pushed for increased defence budgets among European NATO members. Although this led to some increases, it was often accompanied by harsh rhetoric and threats of withdrawing US support. Many European countries have committed to contributing 2% of their GDP to NATO's budget by the end of this year. With over 3.5% contribution, the US remains the largest contributor to the alliance.</p>

<h2><strong>The Reality Of NATO Contributions</strong></h2>

<p>In his constant complaints about Europe not paying enough for NATO, Trump misses a vital point. The reality is that the US uses NATO to maintain its authority over Europe. Critics argue that America exerts disproportionate influence within the alliance, directing its strategic priorities and military actions, hoping Europe will follow suit. Historically, whether it is the US invasion of Iraq and Afghanistan or bombings over Libya, the European members of NATO have always supported the US.</p>

<p>The US's stand on the Israel war in Gaza is fully supported by Britain and many European members of NATO. Many ordinary Europeans feel that their governments' foreign policy is subservient to the US.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Europe's Broader Concerns</strong></h2>

<p>Europe doesn't only fear Trump's views on NATO and Ukraine - we might recall that during Trump's presidency, several key international agreements and partnerships were abandoned or renegotiated, often to the dismay of European allies. The U.S. withdrawal from the Paris Climate agreement, the Iran nuclear deal, and various trade agreements created significant rifts. European leaders, who valued these agreements for global stability and environmental protection, are concerned that Trump's re-election would lead to more isolationist policies and a diminished US role in global leadership.</p>

<p>In February, Trump stunned the US political class by saying he would "encourage" Russia "to do whatever the hell they want" to NATO allies who do not spend enough on defence. The statement created a huge controversy, and though Trump's popularity kept growing, it further exacerbated European insecurity. Many fear that Trump's transactional, isolationist, and disruptive style of governance would challenge and possibly destroy the current transatlantic relationship.</p>

<h2><strong>Historical Context And European Efforts</strong></h2>

<p>Trump, however, is not the only president to have questioned NATO's burden on the US. President Dwight Eisenhower also believed that European nations should eventually be able to defend themselves without relying on the US, suggesting that NATO should not be a permanent solution. More recently, a Republican Senator wondered when Europe would learn to stand on its own feet.<br />
Signs of Europe's Efforts to Reduce US Dependence</p>

<p>Trump's potential return to the White House has led Europe to start preparing for a "Trump-proof" NATO. Many optimists in Europe's academic circles believe the continent can become an independent force in a multipolar world, arguing that Europe has the resources to fend for itself. The continent has contributed more financially to Ukraine's war efforts than the US. Many European countries have begun investing in rebuilding their defence capabilities, which they had reduced since NATO began providing security in 1949.</p>

<p>In April, French President Emmanuel Macron advocated for a more independent European foreign policy, saying it was time for Europe to be more united and independent. In a speech at Sorbonne University in Paris, Macron said the continent was "too slow and lacks ambition" and that the 27-member European Union needs to become a superpower, defend its own borders, and speak with one voice if it wants to survive and thrive.</p>

<p>A Europe without the NATO security cover might be music to Russia's ears, but the continent could descend into chaos from internal quarrels if the US were to leave the alliance. Historically, Germany, France, and Britain were often at war, culminating in the two world wars. Since then, it has been peaceful and prosperous, thanks mainly to the US.</p>

<p>But since Trump's last time in power (2016-2020), the European Union has been working seriously on strengthening the Common Security and Defense Policy (CSDP), increasing defence budgets, and enhancing military cooperation among member states. Initiatives like the European Defense Fund (EDF) and Permanent Structured Cooperation aim to develop joint military projects and improve defence readiness. Additionally, countries such as France and Germany are advocating for a more integrated European army to ensure the continent can independently manage its security and respond to potential threats.</p>

<p>As Trump's potential re-election looms, the NATO summit will give Europe an opportunity to seek the security guarantee regardless of who the US president is. But it will be wise to start preparing to strengthen its own defence capabilities to reduce dependency on the US. One can argue that in case Trump is re-elected, it might hurt the Europeans. That is why instead of trying to strike for a Trump-proof NATO, it will be more beneficial for Europe to continue to prepare itself for a US-free NATO.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ovq0gji8_trump_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-woman-24-dies-on-qantas-flight-from-melbourne-to-new-delhi-6009454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Woman, 24, Dies On Qantas Flight From Melbourne To New Delhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-woman-24-dies-on-qantas-flight-from-melbourne-to-new-delhi-6009454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 15:41:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident happened on June 20 when 24-year-old Manpreet Kaur boarded the aircraft ready to fly from Melbourne to Delhi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin woman, who was on her way to visit family in India for the first time in four years, died on a Qantas flight just before takeoff in Australia. The incident happened on June 20 when 24-year-old Manpreet Kaur boarded the aircraft ready to fly from Melbourne to Delhi, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/woman-dies-on-international-qantas-flight/news-story/41934ac049c5f9712e37f3a2680b1e2a">news.com.au</a> reported. However, Ms Kaur suffered a&nbsp;medical episode soon after boarding the plane at Tullamarine Airport.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a friend, the 24-year-old student reportedly ''felt unwell'' hours before arriving at the airport but managed to board the flight without any issues. But when she&nbsp;went to put on her seatbelt, Ms Kaur fell to the floor and ''died on the spot.''</p>

<p>''When she got on the plane, she was struggling to put her seatbelt on. Just before her flight started, she fell in front of her seat and died on the spot,''&nbsp;her friend Gurdip Grewal told the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.heraldsun.com.au/subscribe/news/1/?sourceCode=HSWEB_WRE170_a_NEW&amp;dest=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.heraldsun.com.au%2Fnews%2Fvictoria%2Ftributes-flow-for-student-who-died-on-qantas-flight-at-melbourne-airport%2Fnews-story%2Faaa561d3d6ab09d15bcf3533312abdab&amp;memtype=anonymous&amp;mode=premium&amp;v21=GROUPA-Segment-2-NOSCORE">Herald Sun.</a></em></p>

<p>A Qantas spokesman said flight crew and emergency services had attempted to provide medical assistance. It is understood that she likely died of tuberculosis</p>

<p>Her roommate said Ms Kaur worked at Australia Post and wanted to become a chef. The woman's friend&nbsp;Mr Grewal launched a GoFundMe in a bid to raise money for her family.</p>

<p>''Hi, my name is Gurdip Grewal and I'm fundraising for Manpreet Kaur. She was a student from my village and going home. She died in a plane during take-off at Melbourne Airport.</p>

<p>Our dear friend Manpreet left us too soon, leaving a void in our lives that can never be filled. As we grieve her passing, we want to come together to honour her memory and support her family in their time of need. As we say our final goodbyes, every contribution, big or small, brings us closer to our goal. Your support means the world to us and Manpreet's family,'' he wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Victoria Police are preparing a report for the coroner.&nbsp;A Qantas spokesperson told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/woman-dies-on-international-qantas-flight/news-story/41934ac049c5f9712e37f3a2680b1e2a">news.com.au</a> that their “thoughts are with her family and loved ones”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/l831esmo_manpreet-kaur_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Her roommate said Ms Kaur worked at Australia Post and wanted to become a chef.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>