<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:29:19 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-india-head-manish-tiwary-resigns-6276986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon India Head Manish Tiwary Resigns]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-india-head-manish-tiwary-resigns-6276986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:15:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amazon India country head Manish Tiwary has left the e-commerce firm, a spokesperson for the company told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon India country head Manish Tiwary will step down in October after an eight-year stint with the e-commerce giant, the company said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Mr Tiwary has another role elsewhere, Amazon said, without elaborating.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/iea3toug_amazon-generic_625x300_17_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strikes-kill-8-in-jenin-tubas-as-west-bank-violence-escalates-6276941]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 Palestinians Killed In Israel Strikes In West Bank As Violence Escalates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strikes-kill-8-in-jenin-tubas-as-west-bank-violence-escalates-6276941]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:09:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces killed at least four people in the volatile city of Jenin in the occupied West Bank, medics said on Tuesday, following a night of violence in which four others were killed in clashes near Tubas, close to the border with Jordan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces killed at least four people in the volatile city of Jenin in the occupied West Bank, medics said on Tuesday, following a night of violence in which four others were killed in clashes near Tubas, close to the border with Jordan.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it conducted two separate air strikes in the West Bank, hitting armed operatives, but gave no details.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Red Crescent confirmed that four people were killed in the strikes against two vehicles in Jenin, one of the most explosive flashpoints in the West Bank. Another person was critically wounded.</p>

<p>The strikes came during an operation in Jenin in which footage shared on social media showed a column of armoured personnel carriers entering the city and armoured bulldozers digging up roads.</p>

<p>With Israel bracing for an expected Iranian response to the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week, the West Bank violence underscored the multi-front security challenge facing Israeli forces, 10 months after the start of the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israeli forces have killed hundreds of Palestinians in the West Bank and East Jerusalem since the start of the war, many of them armed fighters but many also stone-throwing youths or uninvolved civilians.</p>

<p>At the same time, at least 13 Israelis have been killed in attacks by Palestinian attackers. On Tuesday, a female border guard was wounded in a stabbing attack by a Palestinian man using a screwdriver during an inspection of a bus at a checkpoint on the outskirts of Jerusalem.</p>

<p>The attacker was shot dead, the police said.</p>

<p>Overnight, the Palestinian health ministry said at least four Palestinians were killed and seven others injured by Israeli fire in the town of Aqaba, close to the city of Tubas.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/o0vurml8_israel-strikes-west-bank-afp_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli forces have killed hundreds of Palestinians in the West Bank and East Jerusalem. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/air-france-transavia-extend-beirut-flight-suspension-amid-mideast-tensions-6276904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Air France, Transavia Extend Beirut Flight Suspension Amid Mideast Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/air-france-transavia-extend-beirut-flight-suspension-amid-mideast-tensions-6276904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:05:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The resumption of flights to Lebanon's capital, which have been halted since July 29, "will be subject to a new assessment of the local situation," the airline told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Air France said Tuesday that its flights and that of its low-cost subsidiary Transavia to Beirut will be suspended through at least Thursday because of fears that the Gaza war could spread.</p>

<p>The resumption of flights to Lebanon's capital, which have been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/air-france-transavia-halt-beirut-flights-until-tuesday-over-security-concerns-6254810" target="_blank">halted since July 29</a>, "will be subject to a new assessment of the local situation," the airline told AFP.</p>

<p>The two French airlines first stopped servicing the route after Israel vowed to retaliate following rocket fire from Lebanon that killed 12 people in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>Tensions have soared further in the past week as Iran and its allies vowed revenge for the high-profile killings of Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr in Lebanon and Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran, both blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has been exchanging near-daily fire with Israeli forces across the border between Lebanon and Israel.</p>

<p>Air France said it "is constantly monitoring developments in the geopolitical situation of the territories served and overflown by its aircraft, to ensure the highest level of flight safety and security."</p>

<p>The airline added "the safety of its customers and crews is its number one priority."</p>

<p>Air France said customers with reservations for flights to or from Beirut scheduled before and including August 18 to postpone or cancel their trip free of charge.</p>

<p>German carrier Lufthansa has suspended flights to Beirut, Tehran and Tel Aviv until August 12.</p>

<p>Air France said its flights to and from Tel Aviv are operating normally.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/956bdi4g_beirut-beach-afp_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The airline added "the safety of its customers and crews is its number one priority." (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-uk-government-expands-jail-capacity-to-tackle-rioters-6276894]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Expands Jail Capacity As 400 Arrested Over Anti-Immigrant Riots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-uk-government-expands-jail-capacity-to-tackle-rioters-6276894]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 18:05:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The unrest has prompted India, Australia, Nigeria and other countries to warn their citizens to stay vigilant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The British government has increased its prison capacity to help tackle violent, week-long anti-immigrant riots that have prompted a growing number of countries to warn their citizens about the dangers of travelling in Britain.</p>

<p>Riots across a number of towns and cities have erupted following the murder of three girls at a Taylor Swift-themed event in Southport, a seaside town in northern England, after false messaging on social media wrongly identified the suspected killer as an Islamist migrant.</p>

<p>The Justice department, which is being forced to release some prisoners early as it battles a jail overcrowding crisis, said nearly 600 prison places had been secured to accommodate those engaged in violence.</p>

<p>About 400 people have been arrested so far.</p>

<p>"My message to anyone who chooses to take part in this violence and thuggery is simple: the police, courts and prisons stand ready and you will face the consequences of your appalling acts," Justice Secretary Shabana Mahmood said.</p>

<p>The unrest has prompted India, Australia, Nigeria and other countries to warn their citizens to stay vigilant.</p>

<p>Riva Peacock, a 22-year-old retail worker in Liverpool, where rioters clashed with police over the weekend, said the violence was shocking.</p>

<p>"There are a lot of people that blame immigrants for the state of this country," she told Reuters. "It's just a real shame that some of the most vulnerable people in our society have been used as a scapegoat for these issues."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer has vowed a reckoning to those who have attacked Mosques and hotels holding migrants, hurled bricks at the police and counter protesters, and looted shops and burnt cars.</p>

<p>Police on Tuesday charged a 28-year-old man with stirring up racial hatred over Facebook posts linked to the disorder. A 14-year-old pleaded guilty to violent disorder.</p>

<p>On Monday night trouble flared in Plymouth, southern England, and again in Belfast in Northern Ireland, where hundreds of rioters threw petrol bombs and heavy masonry at officers, and set a police Land Rover on fire.</p>

<p>A message online says immigration centres and law firms aiding migrants would be targeted on Wednesday.</p>

<p><strong>WIDESPREAD VIOLENCE</strong></p>

<p>In the first widespread outbreak of violence in Britain for 13 years, hundreds of men, some women and children have attacked hotels housing asylum-seekers from Africa and the Middle East, chanting "get them out" and "stop the boats," in reference to asylum seekers arriving in southern England on small dinghies.</p>

<p>They have also pelted mosques with rocks, unverified videos online have shown some ethnic minorities being beaten up and one man photographed at a protest in Sunderland on Friday had a swastika tattooed on his back.</p>

<p>In Birmingham, Britain's second largest city, videos online on Monday evening showed a group of Asian men gathering with Palestinian flags after reports that anti-migrant protesters may target the area.</p>

<p>Reporters on the scene said they were met with hostility and videos appeared to show one white man being attacked in a pub.</p>

<p>The prospect of clashes between white and ethnic minority groups revived memories of race riots that broke out in Oldham and other northern English towns in 2001 - which an official report later attributed to a lack of social cohesion, with two communities living parallel lives.</p>

<p>The government has said riots in recent days were not a proportionate response to concerns about immigration, but violence whipped up by far-right agitators and supported by football hooligans and young people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b945jndo_uk-protest-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[About 400 people have been arrested so far.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-dhaka-video-amid-bangladesh-violence-indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-torched-6276721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: What Remains Of Indira Gandhi Centre, Torched Amid Dhaka Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-dhaka-video-amid-bangladesh-violence-indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-torched-6276721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:45:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid chaos in Bangladesh - where violent protests over a jobs quota has seen over 400 deaths and forced Sheikh Hasina to resign Prime Minister - a video has emerged of destruction of the Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid chaos in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">Bangladesh</a> - where violent protests over a jobs quota has seen over 400 deaths and the enforced resignation of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a> as Prime Minister - a sobering video has emerged of destruction wrought on the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/search?searchtext=Indira-Gandhi-Cultural-Centre" target="_blank">Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre</a> in Dhaka's Dhanmondi area.</p>

<p>On Monday as violence raged across the Bangladeshi capital - shocking videos shared online showed vehicles set ablaze and homes of ruling Awami League leaders vandalised - a mob set fire to the cultural centre and Bangabandhu Bhaban, which is a museum dedicated to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-sheikh-rehana-49-years-apart-sheikh-rehanas-second-fateful-flight-with-sister-hasina-6275820#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories_lastestImg" target="_blank">Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, Mrs Hasina's father and the country's tallest leader</a>, who was assassinated in 1975.</p>

<p>The video, sourced from Reuters and shared online by ANI, shows the building's charred exterior of and the contrast between the scorch marks and verdant green of the lawns paint a stark image. On the front, where once the sign read Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre, now only the letters 'G', 'N', 'A' remain, with broken windows and twisted metal rods from an awning staring mournfully.</p>

<p>The ground at the front entrance to the centre is covered with debris.</p>

<p>The video also shows several young men - it is unclear who they are - wandering around the centre's grounds. They seem to be carrying away debris, including what seems to be large pipes. It also shows half-burnt bags, possibly items from the gift shop inside the cultural centre, lying on the ground.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Bangladesh: Aftermath of looting and arson at Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre, Dhaka. Violent unrest erupted in the national capital yesterday, 5th August.<br />
<br />
(Video Source: Reuters) <a href="https://t.co/yObqaEbMtp">pic.twitter.com/yObqaEbMtp</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1820782603001270448?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The extent of the looting and destruction becomes clear when the video shows a room that has been stripped completely clean. The paint has been burnt off the walls revealing chipped bricks.</p>

<p>Another scene shows dozens of old-school VHS tapes, presumably from the archives section, lying broken on the ground and a person walking across them, crunching the tapes under their feet.</p>

<p>Inaugurated in March 2010, the Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre promoted bilateral cultural ties between India and Bangladesh by organising seminars, workshops and engaging India-based teachers for classes on yoga, and classical music and dances, such as Kathak and Manipuri.</p>

<p>Run by the Indian Council for Cultural Relations, it had a library with over 21,000 books.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/protesters-damage-indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-in-bangladesh-capital-6269158" target="_blank">Mob Razes Indira Gandhi Centre, Bangabandhu Museum In Dhaka</a></p>

<p>The violence that consumed the Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre and Bangabandhu Bhaban extended across large parts of Dhaka over the past few days, including the Prime Minister's residence, which was overrun and ransacked by protesters shortly after Sheikh Hasina quit and fled the nation.</p>

<p>Protesters reportedly also damaged four Hindu temples.</p>

<p>Mrs Hasina, 76, escaped on a military aircraft. She is now at an unspecified location in India. Sources said Mrs Hasina expressed a desire to stay but New Delhi made it clear it cannot be a long-term host.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-no-provision-for-what-uk-said-on-sheikh-hasina-asylum-reports-6275013#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"No Provision For...": What UK Said On Sheikh Hasina Asylum Reports</a></p>

<p>The ousted leader has reportedly applied to the United Kingdom for asylum.</p>

<p>Earlier today External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar addressed Parliament on the Bangladesh issue and said the Indian government is keeping a close eye on developments across the border.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/we-are-in-close-touch-with-indian-community-in-bangladesh-s-jaishankar-in-parliament-6275167#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">"Sheikh Hasina Requested To Come, Situation Still Evolving": S Jaishankar</a></p>

<p>Briefing the Lok Sabha and Rajya Sabha on the "still evolving" situation, India's response, and the status of an estimated 19,000 nationals in that country, Mr Jaishankar said the government is in "close and continuous touch" with the Indian community and called on the host nation to provide security.</p>

<p>On the question of minorities (over 90 per cent of Bangladeshis are Muslims), he said, "We are monitoring the situation with regard to minorities. There are reports of initiatives to ensure their protection. We welcome that... but will remain deeply concerned till law and order is visibly restored."</p>

<h3><strong>What Next For Bangladesh?</strong></h3>

<p>A new "interim government" - to be advised, most likely, by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus - is believed to be taking shape in the crisis-hit country. This follows the release from jail - ordered by President Mohammed Shahabuddin - of former PM Khaleda Zia, who was convicted of corruption.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-student-leader-nahid-islam-key-faces-in-new-bangladesh-government-6274762" target="_blank">Ex-PM, Nobel Winner, Student Leader: Key Faces In New Government?</a></p>

<p>In speculation that has emerged (inevitably so) since Mrs Hasina quit, three key names or groups are at the forefront, two of whom are the Army, which took charge after Mrs Hasina quit, and which may have given her a 45-minute ultimatum; and her nemesis and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia, who was jailed in 2018 for corruption and whose release was ordered by President Mohammed Shahabuddin.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7gmge0p_indira-gandhi-cultural-centre-dhaka_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-opposition-leaders-jamaat-activists-granted-bail-amid-unrest-6276718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Opposition Leaders, Jamaat Activists Granted Bail Amid Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-opposition-leaders-jamaat-activists-granted-bail-amid-unrest-6276718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:44:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rights groups accused Hasina's security forces of abducting and disappearing some 600 people -- including many from the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party and the banned Jamaat-e-Islami, the country's largest Islamist party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Families of political prisoners secretly jailed in Bangladesh under the autocratic rule of ousted premier Sheikh Hasina waited desperately Tuesday for news of their relatives, as some of those missing were released.</p>

<p>"We need answers," said Sanjida Islam Tulee, a coordinator of Mayer Daak, meaning "The Call of the Mothers", a group campaigning for the release of people detained by Hasina's security forces.</p>

<p>Rights groups accused Hasina's security forces of abducting and disappearing some 600 people -- including many from the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party and the banned Jamaat-e-Islami, the country's largest Islamist party.</p>

<p>Tulee told AFP that at least 20 families gathered outside a military intelligence force building in a northern Dhaka neighbourhood, waiting for news of their relatives.</p>

<p>Former prime minister Khaleda Zia, a bitter rival of Hasina, was also released from years of house arrest.</p>

<p>Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman announced Monday that Hasina had resigned after weeks of deadly protests, and the military would form a caretaker government.</p>

<p>Hours later President Mohammed Shahabuddin -- after a meeting with the army chief -- said it had been decided to free all those arrested during the student protests, as well as key opposition leader Zia.</p>

<p>"People who were detained between July 1 and August 5 as part of the anti-discrimination protests are being freed, and already many have been freed," Shiplu Zman, a press secretary of the president, said.</p>

<p>Former premier Zia, 78, chairperson of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) is in poor health and was largely under house arrest after being sentenced to 17 years in prison for graft in 2018.</p>

<p>"She is now free," A.K.M Wahiduzzaman, a BNP spokesman, told AFP.</p>

<h3><strong>What happened to others?</strong></h3>

<p>Among the most high profile of those released on Tuesday was opposition activist and lawyer Ahmad Bin Quasem, son of Mir Quasem Ali, the executed leader of Jamaat-e-Islami.</p>

<p>"He was released from secret detention this morning," family friend and relative Masum Khalili told AFP. "He had a medical check-up, his condition is stable."</p>

<p>Quasem, a British-educated barrister, was abducted -- allegedly by security forces in plainclothes -- in August 2016.</p>

<p>Others released include former brigadier-general Abdullahil Aman Azmi, abducted in 2016, Jamaat-e-Islami said in a statement.</p>

<p>His father Ghulam Azam, the former head of Jamaat-e-Islami, died in prison in 2014.</p>

<p>Security forces during Hasina's rule were accused of detaining tens of thousands of opposition activists, killing hundreds in extrajudicial encounters, and disappearing their leaders and supporters.</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch last year said security forces had committed "over 600 enforced disappearances" since Hasina came to power in 2009, and nearly 100 remain unaccounted for.</p>

<p>Hasina's government denied the allegations of disappearances and extrajudicial killings, saying some of those reported missing drowned in the Mediterranean while trying to reach Europe.</p>

<p>"We heard Ahmad Bin Quasem has been released," Tulee said. "But what happened to others?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8c86snag_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rights groups accused Hasina's security forces of abducting and disappearing some 600 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strike-kills-5-hezbollah-fighters-as-cross-border-violence-rages-6276699]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Kills 5 Hezbollah Fighters As Cross-Border Violence Rages]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-strike-kills-5-hezbollah-fighters-as-cross-border-violence-rages-6276699]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:41:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed five Hezbollah fighters in the south on Tuesday, with the group claiming attacks on northern Israel, including one with explosive drones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Lebanese security source said an Israeli strike killed five Hezbollah fighters in the south on Tuesday, with the group claiming attacks on northern Israel, including one with explosive drones.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily fire with Israel in support of its ally Hamas since the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Tensions have soared in the past week as Iran and its allies vowed revenge for the high-profile killings of Hezbollah's top military commander Fuad Shukr and Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh, both blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said an "Israeli enemy raid on a house in the town of Mayfadun", near the southern city of Nabatiyeh, killed five people.</p>

<p>The dead "were all Hezbollah fighters", a security source told AFP, requesting anonymity because the matter is sensitive.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its air force "struck a Hezbollah military structure in the area of Nabatiyeh" that was being used "to advance terror attacks" against Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah claimed several attacks on Israel on Tuesday, including one with "explosive-laden drones" targeting a barracks north of the coastal town of Acre.</p>

<p>Israel's Magen David Adom emergency service said paramedics were treating "a 30-year-old male in serious condition and a 30-year-old woman in mild to moderate condition with shrapnel injuries... and evacuating them to the Galilee Hospital in Nahariya", near Acre.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said its latest attacks were in response to an air strike on the southern village of Ebba on Monday that the Israeli military said targeted a commander in the group's elite Radwan Force.</p>

<p>Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah is set to give a televised speech at 5:00 pm (1400 GMT).</p>

<p>The cross-border violence since October has killed at least 555 people in Lebanon, mostly fighters but also including at least 116 civilians, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, including in the annexed Golan Heights, 22 soldiers and 25 civilians have been killed, according to army figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i6fk4h4g_israelhezbollah_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cross-border violence since October has killed at least 555 people in Lebanon (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-resigned-and-where-she-is-now-6276592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina Resigned, And Where She Is Now]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-resigned-and-where-she-is-now-6276592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:30:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's prime minister and fled the country on Monday following weeks of deadly protests that began as demonstrations by students against government job quotas but surged into a movement demanding her resignation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh's prime minister and fled the country on Monday following weeks of deadly protests that began as demonstrations by students against government job quotas but surged into a movement demanding her resignation.</p>

<p>Here are details of the protests that led to end of Hasina's long reign as Bangladesh prime minister:</p>

<h3><strong>Sheikh Hasina Resigns And Flies To India</strong></h3>

<p>Hasina, 76, left Dhaka on Monday in a military aircraft and landed at an airfield at Hindon near Delhi in the evening, two Indian government officials told Reuters.</p>

<p>India's foreign ministry said on Tuesday that Hasina apparently decided to resign after a meeting with the leaders of the security forces. At a short notice she requested New Delhi for permission to come to India while Bangladesh authorities simultaneously sought flight clearance.</p>

<p>According to the latest information, she is still in India.</p>

<h3><strong>Bangladesh President Dissolves Parliament</strong></h3>

<p>President Mohammed Shahabuddin dissolved parliament on Tuesday, paving the way for the formation of an interim government following Hasina's resignation. The president also freed Bangladesh Nationalist Party chairperson Begum Khaleda Zia, a former prime minister and Hasina's arch rival, from house arrest.</p>

<p>Student leaders who spearheaded the movement that led to Hasina's overthrow said they want Nobel Peace laureate Muhammad Yunus to be chief adviser of the interim government.</p>

<h3><strong>Calls For Sheikh Hasina To Step Down</strong></h3>

<p>The Students Against Discrimination group, which was at the forefront of last month's job quota protests, led the latest demonstrations.</p>

<p>The protests to reform the quota system paused after the Supreme Court scrapped most of them on July 21. Protesters, however, returned last week demanding a public apology from Hasina for the violence, restoration of internet connections, reopening of college and university campuses and release of those arrested.</p>

<p>By the weekend, the demonstrations spiralled into a campaign seeking Hasina's overthrow as demonstrators demanded justice for people killed last month.</p>

<p>The students' group called for a nationwide non-cooperation movement starting Sunday with a single-point agenda - Hasina must resign.</p>

<h3><strong>Why Did Protesters Want Sheikh Hasina's Resignation?</strong></h3>

<p>The protesters blame Hasina's government for the violence during the protests in July. Hasina's critics and rights groups have accused her government of using excessive force against protesters, a charge the government denied.</p>

<h3><strong>What Did Sheikh Hasina Say About The Protests?</strong></h3>

<p>Hasina and her government initially said students were not involved in the violence during the quota protests and blamed the Islamist party Jamaat-e-Islami and the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) for the clashes and arson.</p>

<p>But after violence erupted again on Sunday, Hasina said that "those who are carrying out violence are not students but terrorists who are out to destabilise the nation".</p>

<p>The students' group declined Hasina's offer for talks to resolve the crisis.</p>

<h3><strong>What Triggered The Job-Quota Protests?</strong></h3>

<p>Demonstrations started at university campuses in June after the High Court reinstated a quota system for government jobs which favoured relatives of veterans of Bangladesh's war of independence, overturning a 2018 decision by Hasina's government to scrap it.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court suspended the high court order after the government's appeal and then dismissed the lower court order last month, directing that 93% of jobs should be open to candidates on merit.</p>

<h3><strong>Flagging Economy, Unemployment</strong></h3>

<p>Experts also attribute the current unrest in Bangladesh to stagnant job growth in the private sector, making public sector jobs, with their accompanying regular wage hikes and privileges, very attractive.</p>

<p>The quotas sparked anger among students grappling with high youth unemployment, as nearly 32 million young people are out of work or education in a population of 170 million.</p>

<p>The flagging economy, once among the world's fastest growing on the back of the country's booming garments sector, has stagnated. Inflation hovers around 10% per annum and dollar reserves are shrinking.</p>

<h3><strong>Hasina Won January Election</strong></h3>

<p>Hasina retained power for a fourth straight term in an election in January boycotted by the BNP, which accused her Awami League of trying to legitimise sham elections.</p>

<p>BNP said 10 million party workers were on the run ahead of the election with nearly 25,000 arrested following deadly anti-government protests on Oct. 28. Hasina blamed the BNP for instigating anti-government protests that rocked Dhaka ahead of the election and left at least 10 people dead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina retained power for a fourth straight term in an election in January boycotted by the BNP]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-us-man-killed-newlywed-wife-21-and-left-head-in-shower-cops-6276590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[23-Year-Old US Man Killed Newlywed Wife, 21, And Left Head In Shower: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/23-year-old-us-man-killed-newlywed-wife-21-and-left-head-in-shower-cops-6276590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:29:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 23-year-old man in the United States has been sentenced to 40 years in prison for the horrific murder and beheading of his newlywed wife.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 23-year-old man in the United States has been sentenced to 40 years in prison for the horrific murder and beheading of his newlywed wife. According to the<em> New York Post</em>, Jared James Dicus' trial concluded on Wednesday, more than a year after he brutally murdered his wife, 21-year-old Anggy Diaz, in their home near Houston. He pleaded guilty to the murder and was sentenced to four decades in prison with his earliest parole date not until 2043.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/us-news/jared-james-dicus-pleads-guilty-to-murder-of-wife-anggy-diaz/"><em>Post</em></a>, the pair had only tied the knot in October 2022. Officials revealed that in January 2023 Mr Discus' parents made a frantic call, reporting a possible death at their property. On arrival, police found Ms Diaz's body in a pool of blood after she was stabbed multiple times. Her severed head was discovered in the shower.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 23-year-old was later nabbed by police and admitted to detectives that he had murdered his new wife. The reason behind the gruesome act hasn't been made public, but cops have revealed that they had previously responded to domestic violence-related calls at the couple's home. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Waller County does not tolerate domestic violence. Heinous crimes like this one will not go unanswered," Waller County District Attorney Sean Whittmore said in a statement last week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We will seek justice for the victims of domestic violence and send a message to the perpetrators that here, we fight for our victims," he added.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fox26houston.com/news/jared-dicus-waller-county-sentenced-decapitation-wife-leaving-head-shower.amp"><em>Fox26 Houston</em></a>, police said Mr Discus used a kitchen knife to commit the murder. "Everything happened on the property. And all parts and pieces were recovered and submitted for evidence," Sheriff Troy Guidry said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-elections-reveals-who-should-be-kamala-harris-vice-president-pick-6258711">'Nostradamus' Of US Elections Reveals Who Should Be Kamala Harris' Vice President Pick</a></strong></p>

<p>Separately, Mr Whittmore pointed out that potential mental health issues were raised during the pretrial phase of the case. However, a psychiatrist declared Mr Dicus fit to stand trial.</p>

<p>Now, the plea agreement prevents Jared James Dicus from appealing the verdict and sentence. The pre-trial deal was also struck after Mr Discus was deemed competent for trial amid questions over his mental capacity. The District Attorney's Office consulted with the victim's family before finalizing the agreement and sentencing.</p>

<p>Mr Whittmore also expressed gratitude to the Waller County Sheriff's Office for their thorough investigation and service to the victim's family and the community.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/3eb3kf1_us-police-generic_625x300_14_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pair had only tied the knot in October 2022. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-uk-minister-criticises-elon-musk-for-irresponsible-comments-6276580]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Minister Criticises Elon Musk For "Irresponsible" Comments On Riots]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-riots-uk-minister-criticises-elon-musk-for-irresponsible-comments-6276580]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:28:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The rioters have targeted mosques and hotels housing asylum seekers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A UK government minister on Tuesday slammed American tech billionaire Elon Musk for his "unacceptable" comments on social media about far-right riots gripping England and Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>The owner of X drew criticism for writing on the site on Sunday that a British "civil war" was inevitable. He sparked further ire on Monday with a provocative reply to a tweet by UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer.</p>

<p>"Use of language such as a 'civil war' is in no way acceptable," said justice minister Heidi Alexander, branding Musk's comments "deeply irresponsible".</p>

<p>"We are seeing police officers being seriously injured, buildings set alight, and so I really do think that everyone who has a platform should be exercising their power responsibly," she told Times Radio.</p>

<p>Riots by anti-immigrant demonstrators have spread across England following the murder of three children at a Taylor Swift-themed dance party in Southport, northwest England, on Monday last week.</p>

<p>They have been fuelled by online disinformation that the stabbing suspect was a Muslim asylum seeker. He is 17-year-old Axel Rudakubana, who was born in Britain.</p>

<p>The rioters have targeted mosques and hotels housing asylum seekers, forcing the government to provide emergency security to Islamic places of worship.</p>

<p>In a post on X on Monday, Starmer vowed to apply "criminal law online as well as offline", adding that "we will not tolerate attacks on mosques or on Muslim communities".</p>

<p>Musk replied: "Shouldn't you be concerned about attacks on *all* communities?"</p>

<p><strong>'No justification'</strong></p>

<p>His original "civil war" post came in a reply to another X user blaming the riots on "the effects of mass migration and open borders".</p>

<p>Starmer's spokesperson said Monday there was "no justification" for the comment.</p>

<p>Influencer Andrew Tate and far-right, anti-Islam figurehead Tommy Robinson are among people promoting false claims about Rudakubana on X.</p>

<p>Starmer's spokesperson also blamed "bot activity online", suggesting that the false rumours could have been "amplified with the involvement of state actors".</p>

<p>EuropeInvasion, an anti-immigrant X account with hundreds of thousands of followers, still has a post up falsely claiming that the attacker was "confirmed to be Muslim".</p>

<p>An AI-generated image depicting Muslim men chasing a child wearing a British flag has over 900,000 views.</p>

<p>Technology minister Peter Kyle met representatives from TikTok, Meta, Google, and X on Monday and warned that social media users spreading misinformation will have "nowhere to hide".</p>

<p>Musk -- who has reduced content moderation on the platform since taking over Twitter, instead relying on user-written "community notes" -- regularly voices support for right-wing causes and politicians like Donald Trump in the US and Javier Milei in Argentina.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0h3vsl6o_elon-musk-_625x300_02_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starmer's spokesperson said Monday there was "no justification" for the comment.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-ex-it-minister-detained-while-trying-to-flee-country-report-6276564]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Ex IT Minister Detained While Trying To Flee Country: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-ex-it-minister-detained-while-trying-to-flee-country-report-6276564]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:25:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's former Information and Technology Minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak was detained at the Dhaka International Airport today while he was trying to leave the country]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's former Information and Technology Minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak was detained at the Dhaka International Airport today while he was trying to leave the country. The military, which has formed an interim government in the violence-hit country, detained the former minister a day after the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Mr Ahmed was approached by airport officials while he was waiting at the VIP lounge of the Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport, as per reports. He was later detained by Air Force officials.</p>

<p>He was trying to fly to India, where Ms Hasina also fled to on Monday as protesters forced their way into her palace, according to several reports.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bangladesh witnessed scenes of chaos and anger yesterday, its deadliest day since anti-government protests began in early July, with police reporting mobs launching revenge attacks on Sheikh Hasina's allies.</p>

<p>Offices of her party Awam League across the country were torched and looted.</p>

<p>Protesters stormed parliament and burnt TV stations. Footage showed some smashing the statue of Ms Hasina's father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, the country's independence hero.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina landed at a military airbase near New Delhi on Monday evening. As per sources, she wanted to transit on to London. However, there has been no confirmation of the former Prime Minister's schedule or, about her location since then.</p>

<p>The UK government, meanwhile, has said their immigration rules do not allow individuals to travel to their country to seek asylum or temporary refuge. "Individuals seeking asylum must do so in the first safe country they reach," the UK Home Office told NDTV.</p>

<p>The unrest in Bangladesh began last month against civil service job quotas. What started as protests later escalated into wider calls for Sheikh Hasina to stand down. She was made to resign by the military that, as per sources, gave her a "45-minute ultimatum".</p>

<p>The army chief met President Mohammed Shahabuddin late Monday, alongside key opposition leaders, with the president's press team saying it had been "decided to form an interim government immediately".</p>

<p>Shahabuddin also ordered the release of prisoners from the protests, as well as former prime minister and a bitter rival of Ms Hasina, Khaleda Zia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6pt1kpt8_zunaid-ahmed-palak_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zunaid Ahmed Palak was detained at the Dhaka international airport.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spy-couple-reveals-undercover-life-to-russian-tv-returns-from-slovenia-6276505]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Two Russian Spies Went Deep Undercover With Their Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spy-couple-reveals-undercover-life-to-russian-tv-returns-from-slovenia-6276505]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:19:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artyom Dultsev and Anna Dultseva, a married couple who spent years posing as Argentine expats in Slovenia while acting as "illegals", returned to Russia to a hero's welcome last week, with their two children, Sofiya, 11, and Daniil, 9.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-spy-couple-s-kids-had-no-clue-they-were-russians-till-they-landed-in-moscow-6252971" target="_blank">Two sleeper agents</a> returned to Russia in a prisoner exchange have spoken to state television about breaking the news to their Spanish-speaking children that they were in fact Russian.</p>

<p>Artyom Dultsev and Anna Dultseva, a married couple who spent years posing as Argentine expats in Slovenia while acting as "illegals", returned to Russia to a hero's welcome last week, with their two children, Sofiya, 11, and Daniil, 9.</p>

<p>Such spies live abroad long-term under assumed identities. In 2010, a similar couple returned to Russia in a prisoner swap after bringing up their sons as Canadians.</p>

<p>In their first interview since the exchange, which returned at least four Russian agents, the Dultsevs talked to Rossiya television channel at a foreign intelligence facility.</p>

<p>The Dultsevs were convicted in Slovenia last month for spying.</p>

<p>"We told the children that we are Russian, that they are Russian, that we are the Dultsevs" Dultseva said, smiling, recalling the conversation on the plane from Ankara.</p>

<p>Her husband said their daughter "had emotions, she started crying a little bit."</p>

<p>Their son "reacted more calmly to this but very positively" he added.</p>

<p>Dressed in pink shirt and dark jeans, the couple walked hand in hand with their children, who had been placed in foster care after their arrest in December 2022.</p>

<p>Dultseva was shown praising her children in Spanish -- "muy bien" -- as they said their first phrases in Russian.</p>

<p>She said she had found it hard to speak Russian again.</p>

<p>"You don't think in the language (Russian) -- you are controlling yourself all the time and when we arrived we realised we couldn't speak," she said.</p>

<p>Russia, whose president is a former KGB agent, has praised the couple's dedication.</p>

<p>"They are high-class specialists -- such people give their whole life to serving the motherland and make sacrifices a normal person can't understand," the interview's voiceover said.</p>

<p>"The Dultsevs brought up their children as Spanish-speaking Catholics.. Now they are about to find out what borscht is."</p>

<p>The interviewer gave the children a toy Cheburashka, a Soviet-era children's character.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin hugged Dultseva, who wept as she stepped onto Russian soil Thursday.</p>

<p>"When I saw the honour guard out of the window of the plane, I started crying and Sofiya said: 'This is the first time I've seen you crying,'" she said.</p>

<p>Dultseva said she felt "huge gratitude to our country, huge gratitude to Vladimir Vladimirovich (Putin)."</p>

<p>While in prison, "we didn't doubt for a moment that the country remembered us, that Russia and the (secret) service were behind us," Dultsev said.</p>

<p>Dultsev is from the Russian region of Bashkortostan and Dultseva is from the city of Nizhny Novgorod, Russian TV reported.</p>

<p>Dultseva vowed they would continue working "to serve Russia".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/597ko6bs_freed-russian-spies_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Such spies live abroad long-term under assumed identities (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-executes-man-for-killing-police-officer-during-mahsa-amini-protests-6276497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Executes Man For Killing Officer During Mahsa Amini Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-executes-man-for-killing-police-officer-during-mahsa-amini-protests-6276497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:17:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran executed a man on Tuesday after the courts convicted him of killing a Revolutionary Guards officer during nationwide protests in 2022, the judiciary said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran executed a man on Tuesday after the courts convicted him of killing a Revolutionary Guards officer during nationwide protests in 2022, the judiciary said.</p>

<p>"Gholamreza Rasaei was executed this morning (Tuesday) in Kermanshah prison" in western Iran for "stabbing to death a Revolutionary Guards colonel during the illegal protests in November 2022," the judiciary's Mizan Online website reported.</p>

<p>The 2022 protests were sparked by the death in custody of 22-year-old Mahsa Amini, who had been arrested for an alleged breach of Iran's strict dress code for women.</p>

<p>Hundreds of people were killed, including dozens of security personnel, and thousands more arrested over what officials labelled as foreign-instigated "riots".</p>

<p>Mizan said Rasaei was sentenced to death in October 2023 in accordance with Islamic Sharia law on "retribution" and the verdict was later upheld by the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>His execution brings to 10 the number of people executed on charges of murder or other violence against security force personnel during the protests</p>

<p>Covering the neck and head has been compulsory for women in Iran since a few years after the 1979 Islamic Revolution.</p>

<p>For a while after the protests, women increasingly violated the dress code but in recent months police have taken tougher steps against women who ignore the rules.</p>

<p>Iran executes more people per year than any other nation except China, according to human rights groups including Amnesty International.</p>

<p>Iran generally carries out executions by hanging.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/f413hjng_mahsa-amini_625x300_17_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 2022 protests were sparked by the in custody death of 22-year-old Mahsa Amini. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-freed-day-after-rival-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6276150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Ex PM Khaleda Zia Freed Day After Rival Sheikh Hasina's Ouster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-freed-day-after-rival-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6276150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:38:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Khaleda Zia is in poor health, confined to a wheelchair with rheumatoid arthritis and struggling with diabetes and cirrhosis of the liver.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's uncompromising ex-prime minister Khaleda Zia has been released from years of house arrest after her bitter enemy Sheikh Hasina was ousted as premier and fled as protesters broke into her palace.</p>

<p>The ferocious rivalry between the two women -- born in blood and cemented in prison -- has defined politics in the Muslim-majority nation for decades.</p>

<p>Zia, 78, was sentenced to 17 years in prison for graft in 2018 under Hasina's rule.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, was ousted on Monday after mass protests, with the army chief declaring the military would form an interim government.</p>

<p>Orders were then issued for the release of prisoners from the protests, as well as Zia.</p>

<p>Zia is chairperson of the key opposition Bangladesh National Party (BNP). Party spokesman AKM Wahiduzzaman told AFP Tuesday that she "is now freed".</p>

<p>She is in poor health, confined to a wheelchair with rheumatoid arthritis and struggling with diabetes and cirrhosis of the liver.</p>

<p><strong>Decades-long feud</strong></p>

<p>The enmity between Zia and Hasina is known popularly in Bangladesh as the "Battle of Begums", with "begum" a Muslim honorific in South Asia for powerful women.</p>

<p>Their feud has its roots in the murder of Hasina's father -- the country's founding leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahman -- along with her mother, three brothers and several other relatives in a 1975 military coup.</p>

<p>Zia's husband Ziaur Rahman was then the deputy army chief and effectively took control himself three months later.</p>

<p>He kickstarted economic recovery in poverty-stricken Bangladesh with privatisations but was killed in another military coup in 1981.</p>

<p>The BNP mantle fell to his widow, then a 35-year-old mother of two young sons who was dismissed by critics as a politically inexperienced housewife.</p>

<p>Zia led opposition to dictator Hussain Muhammad Ershad, boycotting sham elections in 1986 and mounting street protests.</p>

<p>She and Hasina joined forces to push Ershad out in a wave of protests in 1990 and then faced off in Bangladesh's first free polls.</p>

<p>Zia won and led from 1991-96, and again in 2001-2006, as she and Hasina alternated in power.</p>

<p><strong>Mutual dislike</strong></p>

<p>Their mutual dislike was blamed for a January 2007 political crisis that prompted the military to impose emergency rule and set up a caretaker government. Both were detained for more than a year.</p>

<p>Hasina won elections in December 2008 by a landslide and led uninterrupted until she fled to India in a helicopter on Monday.</p>

<p>She had tightened her grip on power by detaining tens of thousands of BNP members. Hundreds also disappeared.</p>

<p>Zia was convicted and jailed in 2018 on graft charges her party rejected as politically motivated.</p>

<p>She was later released into house arrest on condition she neither took part in politics nor went abroad for medical treatment.</p>

<p><strong>Son in exile</strong></p>

<p>Zia's first cabinet was hailed for liberalising Bangladesh's economy in the early 1990s, sparking decades of growth.</p>

<p>However, her second term as the premier of an Islamist-allied coalition was marked by graft allegations against her government and sons.</p>

<p>There was also a series of Islamist attacks, one of which killed more than 20 people and almost claimed Hasina's life.</p>

<p>The anti-crime Rapid Action Battalion police unit Zia created has been accused of hundreds of extrajudicial killings.</p>

<p>Her eldest son Tarique Rahman led the BNP from exile in London while she was in jail but he was convicted in absentia and sentenced to life in prison over his alleged role in a bomb attack on a Hasina rally in 2004.</p>

<p>The BNP says the charges were a politically motivated attempt to expel Zia's dynasty from politics.</p>

<p>Zia won respect for her resolute attitude, although her inability to compromise left her unable to cut deals with important allies at home or abroad.</p>

<p>That defiance extended even to the death of her youngest son from a heart attack in Malaysia in 2015.</p>

<p>Hasina went to her home to offer sympathy and condolences but Zia did not open the door.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2as3jkt_khaleda-zia_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zia, 78, was sentenced to 17 years in prison under Sheikh Hasina's rule.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-loses-antitrust-case-all-you-need-to-know-6276139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Google Antitrust Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-loses-antitrust-case-all-you-need-to-know-6276139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:36:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ruling comes after a 10-week trial and is a major victory for the US Justice Department, which filed the lawsuit nearly four years ago. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a landmark decision, US District Judge Amit Mehta has ruled that Google's dominance in the search market is a result of illegal monopolistic practices. The judge found Google's actions have stifled competition and innovation, and that the company's default search agreements with device manufacturers and browsers are a key factor in its market dominance.</p>

<p>Here is a breakdown of what happened:</p>

<h2><strong>The case against Google</strong></h2>

<p>The ruling comes after a 10-week trial and is a major victory for the US Justice Department, which filed the lawsuit nearly four years ago. Google has announced plans to appeal the decision. The core accusation is that Google spent billions on exclusive deals to maintain its dominance in the search engine market, violating US antitrust laws.</p>

<h2><strong>What are antitrust laws?</strong></h2>

<p>Antitrust laws are regulations that promote fair competition by preventing monopolies, anti-competitive practices, and other activities that could harm consumers or other businesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the United States, key laws include the Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890, which prohibits monopolies and actions that restrain trade, and the Clayton Antitrust Act of 1914, which addresses specific unfair practices. The Federal Trade Commission Act of 1914 established the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to investigate and prevent unfair competition.</p>

<p>The FTC and the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice (DOJ) enforce these laws. They investigate companies and take action if they find any violations.</p>

<h2><strong>The DoJ's arguments</strong></h2>

<p>The DoJ argued that Google's agreements with wireless carriers, browser developers, and device manufacturers, especially Apple, were anti-competitive. In 2021, Google reportedly paid over $26 billion to companies like Apple to make its search engine the default option on devices like iPhones and browsers like Safari and Mozilla.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google's search-based advertising is a major revenue source, generating $175 billion in 2022. For comparison, Microsoft's Bing made about $12 billion. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Google has an 89.2 per cent share of the market for general search services, increasing to 94.9 per cent on mobile devices.</p>

<h2><strong>Google's defence</strong></h2>

<p>Google argued its dominance was due to the quality of its search engine. They plan to appeal the decision, stating that while the ruling recognises their search engine's quality, it restricts their ability to make it readily available.</p>

<h2><strong>District Judge's verdict</strong></h2>

<p>The trial spanned several months, with testimonies from Google CEO Sundar Pichai and other top executives. Judge Amit Mehta's 277-page decision labelled Google a "monopolist" and highlighted the sheer volume of Google's search queries compared to rivals. Mehta noted that Google "enjoys an 89.2% share of the market for general search services, which increases to 94.9% on mobile devices." He concluded that while Google violated antitrust laws, it did not have "anticompetitive effects."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The judge acknowledged that while Google's search engine is widely recognised as the best available, its market share is significantly bolstered by these agreements. The judge pointed out that other search engines, like Microsoft's Bing, can capture significant market share when not overshadowed by Google's default status. For instance, Bing holds an 80% share of the search market on the Microsoft Edge browser. He then ruled against the tech giant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US Attorney General Merrick Garland called the decision an "historic win for the American people," saying that no company is above the law.</p>

<h2><strong>Implications</strong></h2>

<p>Following the ruling, Google's parent company Alphabet's shares fell by 4.6%.</p>

<p>The court will now decide on the remedies Google must undertake. This could include restrictions on Google's ability to enter into exclusive deals.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google's president of global affairs, Kent Walker, said the company intends to appeal the decision.</p>

<p>Jonathan Kanter, head of the DoJ's antitrust division, believes the ruling will pave the way for innovation and protect access to information. Meanwhile, the Consumer Choice Centre, a lobbying group, criticised the decision as a step in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>The ruling is part of a broader crackdown on Big Tech. The DoJ has another pending case against Google related to digital advertising, and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has filed lawsuits against Amazon and Meta.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l3dququ_google-logo_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-stands-to-lose-a-lot-if-middle-east-tensions-turn-into-a-full-blown-crisis-6276066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Here's Everything India May Lose If Middle East Plunges Into A Full-Blown War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-stands-to-lose-a-lot-if-middle-east-tensions-turn-into-a-full-blown-crisis-6276066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:27:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Modi's huge investment in West Asia diplomacy and increased engagements may come unhinged if tensions spread and engulf the region in a wider war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/emejv7eo_middle-east_625x300_06_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>When Prime Minister Narendra Modi came to power in 2014, it was clear that India's West Asia policy needed a facelift - even a reset. He made multiple official visits to the region over the next few years and managed to forge strong bilateral ties with the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Iran, and Israel. It is fair to say that he struck a fine balance between the Arab countries and Palestinians on the one hand and Israel on the other, though some might claim - without credible evidence - that he has tilted slightly towards Israel. The proof of his deft West Asia foreign policy is that India enjoys the goodwill of both sides.</p>

<p>However, Israel's campaign in Gaza in response to Hamas's October 2023 attacks overshadows Modi's Middle East policy. With the spectre of a wider war looming over the region, stiffer challenges are likely. The Middle East has been teetering on the brink of chaos as India watches holding its breath.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Brazen Act&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>It is believed that Iran and its regional armed groups, the so-called "Axis of Resistance", are preparing to respond to the assassination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh. Though Israel has not commented on the assassination, Haniyeh's killing is being attributed to it; in any case, Israel has claimed responsibility for killing a senior Hezbollah leader in Beirut last week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Targeting a special guest of Iran in the heart of its capital barely hours after he had attended a ceremony to inaugurate the country's newly elected President, Masoud Pezeshkian, was an act as daring as it was provocative. It also proved to be extremely humiliating for Iran and its powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guards (IRGC), the force chiefly responsible for the country's security.</p>

<h2><strong>Iran In A Quandary</strong></h2>

<p>Iran is under compulsion to take action. But it doesn't appear to be interested in escalating the crisis. If it doesn't do anything, the country will be in danger of losing respect and prestige among its supporters. If it takes action, tensions may escalate and spiral out of control. Regardless of these complexities, the rhetoric for revenge is running strong within Iran. "This crime of the Zionist regime will face a harsh and painful response from the powerful and huge resistance front," the IRGC said in a statement. Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, described Haniyeh's killing as a provocation to escalate the conflict in the region and said that it was his country's duty to avenge the assassination.</p>

<p>More than the timing of Iran's retaliation, it will be the scale of its attack that will determine Israel's response. According to Axios, a security analysis group, "US officials expect any Iranian retaliation to be from the same playbook as their April 13 attack on Israel, but potentially larger in scope, and it could also involve Hezbollah in Lebanon". Iran had on April 13 fired more than 200 missiles at Israel in retaliation for an airstrike in Syria that killed a top Iranian general. This was the first time Iran had attacked Israel from its soil. The latter retaliated, but it was a limited response.<br />
However, Haniyeh's killing is different, and his assassination under the protection of the powerful IRGC has embarrassed Iran deeply. Both a response and a non-response can prove to be costly.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>How India Will Be Affected</b></h2>

<p>It is nearly certain that the war in the region would unleash a maelstrom of consequences, threatening to upend India's economy, energy security, and strategic partnerships. With its 9 million-strong diaspora, trade ties, and its geopolitical interests deeply entrenched in the region, India cannot afford to remain a bystander.</p>

<p>Despite diversifying its energy purchase, India continues to rely heavily on the Gulf countries for its oil imports. They account for more than 50% of its oil needs. Disruptions in supply chains because of war would push the price up, which, in turn, would adversely affect India's economy. The instability could increase import costs, reduce economic growth, and create inflationary pressures, thereby undermining India's energy security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The region is a vital trading partner for India. The bilateral trade with the UAE and Saudi Arabia alone amounts to over $100 billion annually. A widening conflict could disrupt both exports, such as textiles and machinery, and imports, notably oil and fertilizers. These disruptions would negatively impact India's GDP growth, employment in export-oriented industries, and the balance of payments. All of this makes for a substantial economic challenge.</p>

<h2><strong>Diaspora And Remittances</strong></h2>

<p>India currently receives the largest remittances sent to any country by its overseas population. According to the World Bank, remittances to India in 2023 crossed $120 billion, with 18% of it coming from Indian workers based in the UAE alone. If you add Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Bahrain, and Oman, their contributions go up to 30%. Escalating conflict could reduce these remittances and force many expatriates to return to India. This migration would strain India's social and economic infrastructure, creating additional challenges for the country's economy. Heightened border security concerns, and the potential for a refugee influx, all pose significant threats to India's stability. The humanitarian challenges would include providing adequate food, shelter, and medical care, as well as ensuring the safety and security of both the refugees and the host communities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Global trade and economic disruptions stemming from potential escalations would also affect India's economy as it would lead to reduced trade and investment and increasing economic uncertainty. These factors could exert recessionary pressures on India's economic landscape, complicating its growth prospects. In the longer term, it could also affect India's progress towards becoming the world's third-largest economy.</p>

<h2><strong>Strategic Partnerships</strong></h2>

<p>Under Prime Minister Narendra Modi's leadership, India has emerged as an influential partner of various Middle Eastern countries, such as Iran, Israel, the UAE, and Saudi Arabia. Conflicts in the region could impact energy cooperation, defence and security partnerships, and regional diplomatic efforts, potentially destabilising these strategic relationships.</p>

<p>Last year during the G20 summit in Delhi, the India-Middle East-Europe Corridor (IMEC) was announced ostensibly to counter China's Belt and Road Initiatives. But the project's future now appears to be in jeopardy. With tensions rising in the region, it might be difficult to take the programme forward. Its declared aim was to establish a seamless trade route connecting India, the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Israel, and Europe. The idea was that it would enhance economic integration, trade, investments, and cooperation. But for now, the priorities of the partner countries have shifted.</p>

<h2><strong>India Has Been Here Before, But That's Not Enough</strong></h2>

<p>India has the experience of dealing with crises emanating from wars in the region. During the Gulf Wars, India's handling of refugee crises and the airlifting of its citizens from Kuwait showcased its capacity for large-scale evacuation and crisis management. In 1990, following Iraq's invasion of Kuwait, around 1,70,000 Indians were stranded in Kuwait and Iraq. India undertook a massive airlift operation to evacuate its citizens, coordinating with airlines and using military and civilian aircraft. This operation, spanning nearly two months, became one of the largest civilian evacuations in history, demonstrating India's logistical and diplomatic capabilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the 2003 Iraq War, although the scale was smaller compared to the first Gulf War, India was again proactive in evacuating its nationals. The government, through its embassies in the region, provided support and facilitated the return of Indians. The evacuation efforts were undertaken with an express need to ensure the safety of Indian citizens, providing necessary travel documents and arranging transport back to India.</p>

<p>Modi's huge investment in West Asia diplomacy and increased engagements may come unhinged if tensions spread and engulf the region in a wider war. For now, India and the global community should hope that the crisis passes over soon. For that to happen, the ceasefire in Gaza could be a big first step.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/38u33fbo_middle-east_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-palestinians-killed-in-gaza-in-24-hours-as-heavy-fighting-continues-6276024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[45 Palestinians Killed In Gaza In 24 Hours As Heavy Fighting Continues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-palestinians-killed-in-gaza-in-24-hours-as-heavy-fighting-continues-6276024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces killed 45 Palestinian fighters in Gaza over the past day, the military said on Tuesday, after heavy fighting in which Hamas said it destroyed two armoured personnel carriers during an ambush near the city of Rafah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces killed 45 Palestinian fighters in Gaza over the past day, the military said on Tuesday, after heavy fighting in which Hamas said it destroyed two armoured personnel carriers during an ambush near the city of Rafah.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the Hamas official in charge of smuggling operations was among those killed and that his death significantly hit their ability to bring weapons and military equipment into the besieged enclave.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, air strikes killed five Palestinians in the Al-Bureij camp, in the central Gaza Strip, medics said, while two others were killed in a separate air strike in Rafah, near the southern Gaza border with Egypt.</p>

<p>Hamas does not provide casualty numbers for its fighters.</p>

<p>The Islamist movement's armed wing said its fighters destroyed the two Israeli troop carriers in an ambush east of Rafah, where heavy fighting has been reported for weeks. There was no confirmation from the Israeli military.</p>

<p>With Israel braced for a possible attack in the north by Iran and the Iranian-backed Hezbollah group, it faces a multi-front threat, 10 months after the start of the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The territory's health ministry said Israeli military strikes have killed at least 30 Palestinians and wounded 66 others in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>"Many victims are still under the rubble and on the roads, where the teams of the ambulance and civil emergency service can't reach," the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>In the larger Palestinian territory, the West Bank, Israeli forces also killed at least eight people on Tuesday and overnight.</p>

<h3><strong>Tank Shelling</strong></h3>

<p>Hamas-led fighters set off the Gaza war last year, when they rampaged through Israeli communities around the Gaza Strip, in a surprise attack, killing 1,200 Israelis and foreigners and seizing some 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies, in the most deadly single day attack on Israel in its history.</p>

<p>In response, Israel has conducted a relentless assault on Gaza that has reduced much of the heavily populated coastal strip to ruins and killed more than 39,000 Palestinians, according to local health authorities.</p>

<p>The figure does not distinguish between fighters and civilians but Israeli authorities estimate their forces have killed or incapacitated some 14,000 fighters, around half the total Hamas force estimated at the start of the war.</p>

<p>Most of Gaza's population has been displaced multiple times since the start of the war and the fighting has brought misery to thousands trapped in overcrowded tent shelters.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli tank shelling continued overnight in Bureij, Al-Maghazi, Nuseirat, and Deir Al-Balah, in the central Gaza Strip, where tens of thousands of displaced families from all over the enclave have sought temporary refuge.</p>

<p>Residents and Hamas media said tanks made a brief advance earlier on Tuesday in Al-Zahra City northwest of Nuseirat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ss9mn2t_israel-gaza-war_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has conducted a relentless assault on Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-climbers-rescue-porters-body-a-year-after-k2-summit-6275998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistani Climbers Rescue Porter's Body A Year After K2 Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-climbers-rescue-porters-body-a-year-after-k2-summit-6275998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climbers recovered the body of a Pakistani porter from K2 mountain, a climbing federation confirmed Tuesday, a year after he died while other climbers made a record-breaking ascent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climbers recovered the body of a Pakistani porter from K2 mountain, a climbing federation confirmed Tuesday, a year after he died while other climbers made a record-breaking ascent.</p>

<p>Muhammad Hassan Shigri slipped and fell from the most dangerous pass during a night climb and was left dangling upside down on a rope before fellow climbers were able to pull him up and attempt to revive him.</p>

<p>He died on the pass known as the "Bottleneck" as dozens of climbers in different teams continued towards the summit.</p>

<p>The climbers included Norwegian record-breaker Kristin Harila who, along with her Nepali guide Tenjin "Lama" Sherpa, that night became the fastest person to summit the world's 14 highest mountains.</p>

<p>"The rescue team made history and turned the impossible into possible," Karrar Haidri, Secretary of the Alpine Club of Pakistan told AFP of the recovery of Shigri's body last Wednesday.</p>

<p>He said it was an "unprecedented rescue, the first of its kind on K2".</p>

<p>The recovery was completed by a team of five climbers led by Naila Kiani, a Pakistani high-altitude mountaineer who was contacted by Shigri's family and backed by the Pakistan army.</p>

<p>Shigri's body was returned to his family for burial.</p>

<p>"We want to thank Naila Kiani and the porters who did this great job. To bring the dead body back was a big wish of the family," his cousin Aslam Naz Shigri told AFP over the phone.</p>

<p>Climbers were criticised at the time for stepping over Shigri's body but Harila said she and her team "did everything we could for him".</p>

<p>An investigation by the Gilgit and Baltistan provincial government's tourism department found Shigri was not prepared with sufficient clothing and was an inexperienced high-altitude porter, and that despite the dangerous conditions, some climbers had attempted to save him -- but it was too late.</p>

<p>Porters, also called sherpas in the Himalayas, are highly skilled professionals who specialise in the logistics of mountain climbing.</p>

<p>Rescue missions are high-risk operations even on the most common routes on K2 and bodies can be left behind for months, or even years, until the weather allows for them to be recovered on foot.</p>

<p>K2, standing at 8,611 metres (28,251 feet) on the Pakistan-China border, is 238 metres shorter than Everest but is considered more technically challenging.</p>

<p>Pakistan is home to five of the world's 14 mountains above 8,000 metres. Four foreign climbers have fallen to their deaths in separate incidents on Pakistan mountains this summer climbing season.</p>

<p>French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines made the fastest ascent of K2 in 10 hours, 59 minutes and 59 seconds in July, slashing by more than half the previous record for reaching the summit without bottled oxygen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ktvvlcb_mountaineering_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rescue missions on K2 are high-risk, and bodies can be left behind for years. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-remains-found-inside-a-crocodile-in-australia-believed-to-be-that-of-40-year-old-tourist-6275974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Human Remains Found Inside Crocodile After Man Goes Missing In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-remains-found-inside-a-crocodile-in-australia-believed-to-be-that-of-40-year-old-tourist-6275974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:14:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred at a location known as Crocodile Bend, popular among tourists for crocodile sightings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Human remains have been found inside a 16-foot crocodile suspected of killing a man in Australia. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/australasia/australia-cooktown-crocodile-attack-human-remains-b2591775.html">Independent</a></em>, the remains are believed to be of David Hogbin, a 40-year-old man from New South Wales, who went missing after falling into the Annan River in Queensland.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incident occurred at a location known as Crocodile Bend, popular among tourists for crocodile sightings. Mr Hogbin&nbsp;was fishing on the banks of the Annan River in Cooktown with his wife and children about 2pm on Saturday when he slipped into the water.&nbsp;His wife attempted to rescue him but was unable to do so.</p>

<p data-apitype="text" data-contentid="K7KBYIXJX5CNJLGV75LEAZABQE" data-el="text" data-scroll-measured="true" data-scroll-pos="5" data-testid="drop-cap-letter" dir="null">''Dave's final, selfless act was to save the life of Jane, his wife of 10 years, and to ensure their three beautiful boys still had their mum. Dave fell down into the river below, and despite being tall, strong and fit, the conditions of the terrain meant Dave was unable to get himself out of the water. Dave's final, decisive act was to let go of Jane's arm when he realised she was falling in, despite knowing she was his only lifeline,'' Mr Hogbin's sister-in-law told&nbsp;<a href="https://www.news.com.au/national/queensland/news/dads-selfless-final-act-before-fatal-crocodile-attack-in-queensland/news-story/72a7140759ca5f22bb263ad1b0a390eb" rel="nofollow">news.com.au</a>.</p>

<p data-apitype="text" data-contentid="K7KBYIXJX5CNJLGV75LEAZABQE" data-el="text" data-scroll-measured="true" data-scroll-pos="5" data-testid="drop-cap-letter" dir="null">The crocodile was found 2.5 miles from where Mr Hogbin disappeared. Further testing is being conducted to confirm the identity of the remains.</p>

<p>Wildlife rangers later euthanized the crocodile, which had distinctive scars on its snout, matching witness descriptions.</p>

<p>''Wildlife officers have humanely euthanised a large crocodile that is believed to be responsible for the fatal attack on the Annan River. The animal had markings on its snout that were consistent with it being the target animal. Wildlife officers are removing the animal from the creek and will hand it over to the Queensland Police Service,'' said the Department of Environment, Science and Innovation.</p>

<p>A<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/support-dave-hogbins-family-after-tragic-crocodile-attack?attribution_id=sl:4660fe30-5c77-43a3-846c-0eb5df7b89e4&amp;utm_campaign=pd_ss_icons_ai&amp;utm_content=amp1v4&amp;utm_medium=customer&amp;utm_source=twitter"> GoFundMe</a> has been set up by family friend Alex Ward, to help Jane and the family in the aftermath of their loss.</p>

<p>There have been three fatal crocodile attacks in Australia this year. A 12-year-old girl was killed in a crocodile attack on July 2, and a 16-year-old boy was killed while swimming off a Queensland island on April 18.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The crocodile population has exploded across Australia's tropical north since the predators became a protected species in the early 1970s.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kjcmo3mg_crocodile_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wildlife rangers later euthanised the crocodile]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-launches-drone-attack-at-israel-6275900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon's Hezbollah Launches Swarm Of Drones At Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-launches-drone-attack-at-israel-6275900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:05:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Hezbollah source told Reuters that its retaliation for Israel's killing of a top commander last week was yet to come.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's armed group Hezbollah launched a series of drone and rocket attacks into northern Israel on Tuesday but warned that its much-anticipated retaliation for Israel's killing of a top commander last week was yet to come.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it launched a swarm of attack drones at two military sites near Acre in northern Israel, and also attacked an Israeli military vehicle in another location.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said a number of hostile drones were identified crossing from Lebanon and one was intercepted. It said several civilians were injured to the south of the coastal city of Nahariya. Reuters TV footage showed one impact site near a bus stop on a main road outside the city.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Israeli military said sirens sounded around Acre, but that turned out to be a false alarm. It said its air force struck two Hezbollah facilities in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>Fears are rising that the Middle East could be tipped into full-blown war following vows by Hezbollah to avenge Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr's killing, and by Iran to respond to the assassination in Tehran last week of the head of Palestinian group Hamas.</p>

<p>A Hezbollah source told Reuters that "the response to the assassination of commander Fuad Shukr has not yet come."</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, four people were killed in a strike on a home in the Lebanese town of Mayfadoun, nearly 30 km (19 miles) north of the border, medics and a security source said.</p>

<p>Two additional security sources said those killed were Hezbollah fighters, but the group had not yet posted its usual death notices.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and the Israeli military have been trading fire for the last 10 months in parallel with the Gaza war, with the tit-for-tat strikes mostly limited to the border area.</p>

<p>Last week, Israel killed Shukr, Hezbollah's senior-most military commander, in a strike on the group's stronghold in the southern suburbs of Lebanon's capital Beirut.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's leader, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, vowed revenge, but said the response would be "studied." He is set to speak on Tuesday at the one-week memorial for Shukr.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m0rve7dg_hezbollah_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah launched swarm of attack drones in northern Israel (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>