<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 08:36:32 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-zimin-a-uk-based-russian-chef-who-criticised-vladimir-putin-found-dead-in-serbia-hotel-7014924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK-Based Russian Chef Who Criticised Putin Found Dead In Serbia Hotel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alexei-zimin-a-uk-based-russian-chef-who-criticised-vladimir-putin-found-dead-in-serbia-hotel-7014924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 08:12:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian television chef, who was an outspoken critic of President Vladimir Putin's war in Ukraine, has been found dead in Serbia, the BBC reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian television chef, who was an outspoken critic of President Vladimir Putin's war in Ukraine, has been found dead in Serbia, the <em>BBC </em>reported. Alexei Zimin, 52, was considered a household name in Russia before he left the country after criticising the Kremlin's annexation of Crimea in 2014. He set up his new home and businesses in London but remained the host of a popular cookery show on Russian broadcaster NTV. However, the show was axed after he posted an anti-war message on social media following the full-scale Russian invasion of Ukraine in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Zimin was found dead in a hotel room in Belgrade, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c7049jn5kd3o" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>BBC </em></a>reported citing Russian media. He had travelled to the Serbian capital to promote his new book about Britain Anglomania.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Serbian authorities have said that there were "no suspicious circumstances" related to Mr Zimin's death and that an autopsy and toxicology report was ongoing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Katerina Ternovskaya, co-owner of the restaurant where the 52-year-old had presented his book, said people were "in shock" adding that "the last time we have seen him, he was smiling and in a great mood". "The dinner was wonderful and Alexei was very happy," she said.</p>

<p>Mr Zimin's restaurant in the UK also confirmed the chef's death on Instagram. "To us, Alexei was not only a colleague but also a friend, a close companion with whom we shared many experiences - good, kind, and at times sorrowful," the restaurant said. "We are profoundly grateful for the kind words we have received today in Alexei's memory. We share this painful loss with you. The entire ZIMA team extends our heartfelt condolences to Alexei's family and mourns alongside them," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCT2YZei4Gc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCT2YZei4Gc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCT2YZei4Gc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCT2YZei4Gc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by ZIMA Russian Restaurant (@zimarestaurant)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Notably, Mr Zimin was a prominent critic of Russia's war in Ukraine. After he posted a video on social media of him singing an anti-war song, his Russian TV show 'Cooking with Alexei Zimin' was abruptly cancelled by the network NTV.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-polls-blames-incorrect-prediction-on-elon-musk-and-explosion-of-disinformation-7014725">&nbsp;'Nostradamus' Of US Polls Blames Incorrect Prediction On Elon Musk And "Explosion" Of Disinformation</a></strong></p>

<p>At the beginning of the war in 2022, the chef also wrote several anti-war statements on Instagram saying, "bring our soldiers home" and "The idea is unoriginal. Stop the war. Withdraw troops and bring our soldiers home".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Like everyone who grew up in the USSR, I was brought up with the fairly common sense belief that war is the worst thing that can happen. There is no excuse for it and even if there were, now it's too late to make excuses. As Rosenbaum sang. Gotta stop this madness and 'War is not poker'" he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since moving to the UK, Mr Zimin reportedly had not been back to Russia. He previously said that he and his restaurant Zima in central London, which has donated money to Ukrainian refugees, had been the target of threats.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/npkmmveo_alexei-zimin_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Zimin was found dead in a hotel room in Belgrade.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-polls-blames-incorrect-prediction-on-elon-musk-and-explosion-of-disinformation-7014725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Nostradamus' Of US Polls Blames Musk, Disinformation For Wrong Prediction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-polls-blames-incorrect-prediction-on-elon-musk-and-explosion-of-disinformation-7014725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 07:10:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Allan Lichtman, often dubbed the "Nostradamus" of US Presidential Polls, is blaming the "explosion" of disinformation and billionaire Elon Musk for his incorrect prediction that Kamala Harris would win the 2024 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Allan Lichtman, often dubbed the "Nostradamus" of US Presidential Polls, is blaming the "explosion" of disinformation and billionaire Elon Musk for his incorrect prediction that Kamala Harris would win the 2024 election. Mr Lichtman, a professor at American University, is renowned for accurately forecasting nine of the last ten US elections. However, last week, the historian and political scientist took a loss on his remarkable record by predicting that Vice President Kamala Harris would win the 2024 presidential race. Now, speaking to <em>News Nation</em>, Mr Lichtman provided a deeper explanation for his incorrect forecast and pointed to conservative media platforms and Elon Musk, who pored millions into Donald Trump's campaign, as a factor in his inaccurate prediction.</p>

<p>"Number one, disinformation. We've always had disinformation, but disinformation has exploded to an unprecedented degree. You talked about a grievance election, but a lot of that grievance was driven by disinformation," Mr Lichtman told the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nWGzHXLTFHw">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The political scientist continued by naming X (formerly Twitter) owner Elon Musk, who appeared at some of Donald Trump's campaign rallies and became one of the loudest media cheerleaders. He claimed that Mr Musk's microblogging platform was used to spread misinformation about issues like immigration, hurricane relief and the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We've seen something brand new this time - billionaire Elon Musk putting his thumb on the scales," Mr Lichtman said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's been reported that his misinformation had had billions, literally billions of views and this has spread to every aspect of this election," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-matga-movement-a-deadly-tiktok-trend-glorifying-poisoning-men-after-trumps-win-7006527">Deadly 'MATGA Movement' Emerges In US After Trump's Presidential Win, Here's What It Is</a></strong></p>

<p>Mr Lichtman's method for forecasting the presidential election results was based on a historical index model he dubs the "Keys to the White House". This unique system analyses the political landscape through the lens of 13 true-false statements focused on the incumbent president's party. If six or more of the statements are false, then the challenger is predicted to win.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the interview with <em>News Nation</em>, the academic acknowledged that his method "maybe" needs to be changed in light of last week's events. "The premise of the keys is that a rational, pragmatic electorate decides whether the White House party has governed well enough to get four more years. But if the views of the White House party are controlled by disinformation, particularly driven by those who are so rich that they have extraordinary influence beyond anyone else, then maybe the premise of the keys need to be changed," Mr Lichtman said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/moment-nostradamus-of-us-elections-realised-donald-trump-would-win-6961747">Allan Lichtman</a> has been forecasting the results of US presidential elections since 1984. He has accurately predicted the last nine out of 10 presidential races. Previously, he even forecasted that Mr Trump would be impeached during his presidency - which he was, twice.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9007hmq_allan-lichtman_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Allan Lichtman picked Vice President Kamala Harris to win the 2024 presidential race.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-heads-for-snap-elections-today-results-likely-on-friday-7014695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Heads For Snap Elections Today, Results Likely On Friday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-heads-for-snap-elections-today-results-likely-on-friday-7014695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 07:01:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka votes today in a second national election in as many months with a deeply divided opposition struggling to recover from a crushing defeat at presidential polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka votes Thursday in a second national election in as many months with a deeply divided opposition struggling to recover from a crushing defeat at presidential polls.</p>

<p>The snap parliamentary election was called by the new President Anura Kumara Dissanayake -- the South Asian island's first leftist leader -- after he won polls on a promise to combat graft and recover the country's stolen assets.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's party is widely tipped to sweep Thursday's parliamentary vote with analysts saying the opposition is in disarray.</p>

<p>The 55-year-old leader is seeking a two-thirds majority in the 225-member legislature to press ahead with reforms after the country's economic meltdown in 2022, when then president Gotabaya Rajapaksa was ousted.</p>

<p>Polls for 17.1 million voters choosing between 8,800 candidates, open at 7:00 am (0130 GMT) on Thursday and close at 4:00 pm, with initial results expected Friday.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's JVP, or the People's Liberation Front, is the main constituent of the National People's Power (NPP) coalition of professionals seeking to form the next government.</p>

<p>The NPP held just three seats in the outgoing assembly.</p>

<p>Dissanayake had been an MP for nearly 25 years and was briefly an agriculture minister, but he distanced himself from traditional politicians accused of leading the country to its worst economic crisis two years ago.</p>

<p>His JVP party led two insurrections in 1971 and 1987, leading to the loss of at least 80,000 lives, but Dissanayake took power peacefully in elections on September 21.</p>

<p>'Foregone conclusion'</p>

<p>Despite previous promises to renegotiate a controversial $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund (IMF) bailout secured by his predecessor Ranil Wickremesinghe, Dissanayake has chosen to maintain the agreement with the international lender.</p>

<p>The country's main private sector lobby, the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce, is tacitly supporting Dissanayake and expects him to press ahead with reforms.</p>

<p>"Continuing reforms... could encourage both investor confidence and fiscal discipline, setting a foundation for sustainable growth," CCC Secretary Bhuwanekabahu Perera told AFP ahead of voting.</p>

<p>He said Dissanayake's approach to governance "may lean toward a balanced socialist-democratic model that acknowledges market realities."</p>

<p>An IMF delegation is due in Colombo on Thursday to review economic progress before releasing the next tranche of $330 million of the bailout loan.</p>

<p>Opposition leader Sajith Premadasa, who had campaigned to take part in a coalition government, vowed in his final campaign rally he would "put pressure" on Dissanayake to honour promises of tax cuts.</p>

<p>Poll monitors and analysts note that Thursday's election had failed to generate the level of enthusiasm -- or violence -- seen at previous polls.</p>

<p>Political analyst Kusal Perera said there was little campaigning by opposition parties.</p>

<p>"The opposition is dead," Perera said. "The result of the election is a foregone conclusion."</p>

<p>Over 60 senior politicians from the previous administration have opted to stay out.</p>

<p>The outgoing parliament was dominated by the party of former president Mahinda Rajapaksa -- the Sri Lanka Podujana Peramuna (SLPP), or the People's Front -- but it has since splintered.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Rajapaksa is not contesting, but his son Namal, a former sports minister, is seeking re-election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mtpl92o8_sri-lanka_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dissanayake's party is widely tipped to sweep Thursday's parliamentary vote.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-ex-democrat-tulsi-gabbard-appointed-us-intelligence-chief-7014631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Tracker: Ex-Democrat Tulsi Gabbard Appointed US Intelligence Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-ex-democrat-tulsi-gabbard-appointed-us-intelligence-chief-7014631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 06:45:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump is set to return to the White House after his victory over Kamala Harris in the November 5 US presidential elections. The 78-year-old leader Republican has secured all seven swing states.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, who is set to return to the White House after his victory over Kamala Harris in the November 5 US presidential elections, has appointed former Democrat Tulsi Gabbard as his US Intelligence Chief. The 78-year-old leader has secured all seven swing states, including Arizona, Georgia, Pennsylvania, Michigan, Wisconsin, North Carolina, and Nevada.</p>

<p>On Wednesday evening (IST), Trump met President Joe Biden in the Oval Office of the White House where Biden welcomed&nbsp;Trump&nbsp;and congratulated him following his victory, saying that he looks forward to a smooth transition."Congratulations, looking forward to having a, like we said, smooth transition -- do everything we can to make sure you're accommodated, and what you need. And we're going to get a chance to talk about some of that today," Biden said in the meeting with&nbsp;Trump.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are live updates on Donald Trump's return to White House:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r92i04ro_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has begun announcing several key appointments in his Cabinet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-florida-senator-marco-rubio-as-secretary-of-state-7014420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Nominates Florida Senator Marco Rubio As Secretary Of State]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-nominates-florida-senator-marco-rubio-as-secretary-of-state-7014420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 05:36:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Wednesday nominated Florida senator and outspoken China hawk Marco Rubio for secretary of state.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Wednesday nominated Florida senator and outspoken China hawk Marco Rubio for secretary of state.</p>

<p>Donald Trump said in a statement that Rubio is "a very powerful Voice for Freedom" and "a fearless Warrior who will never back down to our adversaries."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jq7vm1lg_marco-rubio_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said in a statement that Marco Rubio is "a very powerful Voice for Freedom"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-team-making-list-of-pentagon-officers-to-fire-report-7014357]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Team Making List Of Pentagon Officers To Fire: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-team-making-list-of-pentagon-officers-to-fire-report-7014357]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 05:15:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Members of President-elect Donald Trump's transition team are drawing up a list of military officers to be fired, potentially to include the Joint Chiefs of Staff, two sources said, in what would be an unprecedented shakeup at the Pentagon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Members of President-elect Donald Trump's transition team are drawing up a list of military officers to be fired, potentially to include the Joint Chiefs of Staff, two sources said, in what would be an unprecedented shakeup at the Pentagon.</p>

<p>The planning for the firings is at an early stage after Donald Trump's Nov. 5 election victory and could change as Donald Trump's administration takes shape, said the sources, who are familiar with the Trump transition and requested anonymity to speak candidly about the plans.</p>

<p>One of the sources questioned the feasibility of a mass firing at the Pentagon.</p>

<p>It was also unclear if Trump himself would endorse the plan, although in the past he has railed extensively against defense leaders who have criticized him. Trump has also spoken during the campaign of firing "woke" generals and those responsible for the troubled 2021 pullout from Afghanistan.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign did not immediately respond to request for comment.</p>

<p>The second source said the incoming administration would likely focus on U.S. military officers seen as connected to Mark Milley, Trump's former chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</p>

<p>Milley was quoted in the book "War" by Bob Woodward, which was published last month, calling Trump "fascist to the core" and Trump's allies have targeted him for perceived disloyalty to the former president.</p>

<p>"Every single person that was elevated and appointed by Milley will be gone," the second source said.</p>

<p>"There's a very detailed list of everybody that was affiliated with Milley. And they will all be gone."</p>

<p>The Joint Chiefs of Staff include the highest ranking officers in the U.S. military and comprise the heads of the Army, Navy, Marines, Air Force, National Guard and Space Force.</p>

<p>The disclosure of plans to fire senior leaders of the U.S. armed forces comes a day after Trump picked as his defense secretary Pete Hegseth, a Fox News commentator and veteran who has signaled a willingness to clean house at the Pentagon.</p>

<p>"The next president of the United States needs to radically overhaul Pentagon senior leadership to make us ready to defend our nation and defeat our enemies. Lots of people need to be fired," Hegseth said in his 2024 book "The War on Warriors: Behind the Betrayal of the Men Who Keep Us Free."</p>

<p>It is unclear if Hegseth's lack of management experience could complicate his Senate confirmation and if a more traditional alternative for the position would carry out such sweeping dismissals.</p>

<p>GENERAL BROWN TO BE AMONG THE FIRST FIRED</p>

<p>Hegseth has also taken aim at Milley's successor, Air Force General C.Q. Brown, asking whether he would have gotten the job if he were not Black.</p>

<p>"Was it because of his skin color? Or his skill? We'll never know, but always doubt - which on its face seems unfair to CQ. But since he has made the race card one of his biggest calling cards, it doesn't really much matter," he wrote.</p>

<p>The first source familiar with the transition planning said Brown would be among the many officers to leave.</p>

<p>"The chiefs of the Joint Chiefs and all the vice chiefs will be fired immediately," the source said, before noting that this was still only early planning.</p>

<p>Some current and former U.S. officials have played down the possibility of such a major shakeup, saying it would be unnecessary and disruptive at a time of global turmoil with wars raging in Ukraine and the Middle East.</p>

<p>The first source said that it would be difficult bureaucratically to fire and replace a large swath of senior U.S. military officials, suggesting the planning could be bluster and posturing by Trump allies.</p>

<p>But the second source suggested the Trump camp believed the Joint Chiefs of Staff needed to shrink due to perceived bureaucratic over-reach.</p>

<p>Such cuts could be endured in an organization the scale of the U.S. military, the source said.</p>

<p>"These people are not irreplaceable. They are very replaceable. And then the other thing too is there is no shortage of people that will step up," the source said.</p>

<p>"In World War Two, we were very rapidly appointing people in their 30s or people competent to be generals. And you know what? We won the war."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i3dmpfmo_-pentagon-building_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One of the sources questioned the feasibility of a mass firing at the Pentagon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-chinese-president-xi-jinping-to-meet-in-peru-on-saturday-7014331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden, Chinese President Xi Jinping To Meet In Peru On Saturday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-chinese-president-xi-jinping-to-meet-in-peru-on-saturday-7014331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 05:09:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping will meet Saturday at the APEC summit in Peru, in what will likely be their last encounter before Donald Trump returns to the White House, US officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>US President Joe Biden and Chinese President Xi Jinping will meet Saturday at the APEC summit in Peru, in what will likely be their last encounter before Donald Trump returns to the White House, US officials said.</p>

<p>The meeting will be the third between the leaders of the world's two biggest economies and their second since a major ice-breaking set of talks in California a year ago.</p>

<p>"We expect this will be their last meeting as presidents," a senior US administration official told reporters on condition of anonymity on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"With that in mind, we expect the president will use the opportunity to take stock of efforts to responsibly manage competition."</p>

<p>Trump has already signaled a confrontational approach with Beijing for his second term, picking a number of outspoken China hawks for key foreign and defense positions in his top team.</p>

<p>The Republican has also promised to slap 60-percent tariffs on Chinese imports, leading to fears of a renewed trade war.</p>

<p>The Biden administration official would not be drawn on whether he would try to advise China on how to deal with Trump -- or if he would advise Trump on how to deal with China.</p>

<p>"This is a difficult, complicated, consequential relationship," the official said.</p>

<p>"The president has been pretty clear that he even admits the competitive aspects of the relationship, we need to find ways to manage it responsibly."</p>

<p>Biden heads to Lima on Thursday for the APEC summit on Friday and Saturday for his swansong at the major gathering of Asia-Pacific economies.</p>

<p>He will then become the first US president to visit the Amazon rainforest in Brazil, before traveling to Rio de Janeiro for his final summit of the G20 countries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/t633r7jg_joe-biden-xi-jinping_625x300_29_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden heads to Lima on Thursday for the APEC summit on Friday and Saturday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-diabetes-rate-has-doubled-in-last-30-years-reveals-study-7014320]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global Diabetes Rate Has Doubled In Last 30 Years, Reveals Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-diabetes-rate-has-doubled-in-last-30-years-reveals-study-7014320]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 05:04:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The percentage of adults suffering from diabetes across the world has doubled over the past three decades, the biggest rises coming in developing countries, a study said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The percentage of adults suffering from diabetes across the world has doubled over the past three decades, the biggest rises coming in developing countries, a study said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The serious health condition affected around 14 percent of all adults worldwide in 2022, compared to seven percent in 1990, according to the new analysis in The Lancet journal.</p>

<p>Taking into account the growing global population, the team of researchers estimated that more than 800 million people are now diabetic, compared to less than 200 million in 1990.</p>

<p>These figures include both main types of diabetes. Type 1 affects patients from a young age and is more difficult to treat because it is caused by an insulin deficiency.</p>

<p>Type 2 mainly affects middle-aged or older people who lose their sensitivity to insulin.</p>

<p>Behind the global numbers, national figures varied widely.</p>

<p>The rate of diabetes stayed the same or even fell in some wealthier countries, such as Japan, Canada or Western European nations such as France and Denmark, the study said.</p>

<p>"The burden of diabetes and untreated diabetes is increasingly borne by low-income and middle-income countries," it added.</p>

<p>For example, nearly a third of women in Pakistan are now diabetic, compared to less than a tenth in 1990.</p>

<p>The researchers emphasised that obesity is an "important driver" of type 2 diabetes -- as is an unhealthy diet.</p>

<p>The gap between how diabetes is treated in richer and poorer countries is also widening.</p>

<p>Three out of five people aged over 30 with diabetes -- 445 million adults -- did not receive treatment for diabetes in 2022, the researchers estimated.</p>

<p>India alone was home to almost a third of that number.</p>

<p>In sub-Saharan Africa, only five to 10 percent of adults with diabetes received treatment in 2022.</p>

<p>Some developing countries such as Mexico are doing well in treating their population -- but overall the global gap is widening, they said.</p>

<p>"This is especially concerning as people with diabetes tend to be younger in low-income countries and, in the absence of effective treatment, are at risk of life-long complications," said senior study author Majid Ezzati of Imperial College London.</p>

<p>Those complications include "amputation, heart disease, kidney damage or vision loss -- or in some cases, premature death," he said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q6bajo8g_diabetes_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India alone was home to almost a third of that number. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-ex-democrat-tulsi-gabbard-as-director-of-national-intelligence-7014234]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Names Ex-Democrat Tulsi Gabbard As Director of National Intelligence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-names-ex-democrat-tulsi-gabbard-as-director-of-national-intelligence-7014234]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 04:37:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Wednesday named former Democrat Tulsi Gabbard, who has opposed US support for Ukraine and met Syria's president Bashar al-Assad, as his incoming Director of National Intelligence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Wednesday named former Democrat Tulsi Gabbard, who has opposed US support for Ukraine and met Syria's president Bashar al-Assad, as his incoming Director of National Intelligence.</p>

<p>The Republican president-elect said Tulsi Gabbard, a veteran and one-time Democratic White House contender, would "bring the fearless spirit that has defined her illustrious career to our intelligence community."</p>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard thanked Trump "for the opportunity to serve as a member of your cabinet to defend the safety, security and freedom of the American people. I look forward to getting to work."</p>

<p>The former Hawaii congresswoman switched sides from the Democrats and backed Trump earlier this year, helping him during his debate preparations against Kamala Harris, and had been expecting a reward for lining up behind the former president.</p>

<p>She has long held isolationist foreign policy views and embraced a number of conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard made false claims in 2022 about there being US-sponsored biolabs in Ukraine -- a key trope of Russian propaganda justifying Moscow's invasion that year.</p>

<p>She demanded US military withdrawal from Iraq and Syria during her 2020 presidential run.</p>

<p>In 2019, Hillary Clinton said that Russia was grooming a US Democratic candidate for a third-party run, in comments that were apparently directed at Tulsi Gabbard -- and strongly rejected by her.</p>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard also had a controversial 2017 meeting with Syria's Assad at the height of the country's bloody civil war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/df5n2i28_tulsi-gabbard_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tulsi Gabbard thanked Donald Trump "for the opportunity" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-6-soldiers-killed-during-combat-in-lebanon-says-israeli-army-7014229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Soldiers Killed During Combat In Lebanon, Says Israeli Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-6-soldiers-killed-during-combat-in-lebanon-says-israeli-army-7014229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 04:30:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel suffered one of its deadliest days of its ground offensive against Hezbollah in Lebanon on Wednesday when six of its soldiers were killed in combat near the border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Israel suffered one of its deadliest days of its ground offensive against Hezbollah in Lebanon on Wednesday when six of its soldiers were killed in combat near the border.</p>

<p>The soldiers "fell during combat in southern Lebanon", the army said in a statement. Their deaths mean 47 Israeli troops have been killed in combat with Hezbollah since September 30, when Israel sent ground forces into Lebanon.</p>

<p>The army's announcement came after Israel's new Defence Minister Israel Katz said there would be no easing-up in the war against Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on X shared an image of the "Golani" Brigade symbol -- the unit the soldiers killed belonged to -- a green olive tree against a yellow background, with a broken heart emoji.</p>

<p>Since September 23, Israel has stepped up its bombing campaign in Lebanon, mainly targeting Hezbollah strongholds in south Beirut and in the east and south of the country. On September 30, it sent in ground troops.</p>

<p>It came after nearly a year of cross-border exchanges of fire, launched by Hezbollah in support of its Palestinian ally Hamas following their October 7, 2023 attack on Israel that triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Earlier on Wednesday, an Israeli strike hit Aramoun, a densely-packed area south of Beirut which is located outside Hezbollah's traditional strongholds, which the health ministry said killed eight people.</p>

<p>Lebanese state media on the same day reported a third wave of Israeli raids on Hezbollah's south Beirut bastion in 24 hours.</p>

<p>The Israeli army meanwhile said it had intercepted some of the "five projectiles" that had crossed from Lebanon into Israeli territory.</p>

<p>Katz told senior military commanders on his first visit to the border region since his appointment last week that Israel would "make no ceasefires, we will not take our foot off the pedal, and we will not allow any arrangement that does not include the achievement of our war objectives".</p>

<p>Katz added: "We will continue to strike Hezbollah everywhere."</p>

<p>Israel's objectives include disarming Hezbollah and pushing the operatives beyond the Litani River, which flows across southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>After Katz's address, another air strike hit a Beirut suburb Wednesday evening after a warning by Israel's military for residents to evacuate.</p>

<p><strong>'No time left'</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah said on Wednesday it had fired ballistic missiles at the Israeli army's headquarters in the commercial hub of Tel Aviv, which also houses the defence ministry.</p>

<p>Contacted by AFP, the Israeli army spokesperson's unit said it would "not to react to Hezbollah's allegations".</p>

<p>Lebanese authorities say more than 3,360 people have have been killed since October last year when Hezbollah and Israel began engaging in cross-border clashes.</p>

<p>Rocket fire from Lebanon on Tuesday killed two residents of the northern Israeli city of Nahariya. The deaths bring to 45 the number of civilians killed in northern Israel as a result of rocket fire from Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Islamic Jihad group, an ally of Hamas, released a video earlier on Wednesday of an Israeli hostage held in Gaza, identifying himself as Sasha Trupanov.</p>

<p>When Hamas operatives staged the October 7 attack, they took 251 hostages into the Gaza Strip. Some were already dead. Of those, 97 are still held hostage, while 34 are confirmed dead but their bodies remain in Gaza.</p>

<p>Trupanov's mother, Lena, in a statement published by the Hostage and Missing Families Forum campaign group, urged the hostages' immediate release. They have no time left."</p>

<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza on Wednesday said at least 43,712 people have been killed in more than 13 months of war between Israel and Palestinian operatives.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2225v5kg_israel-army_625x300_10_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it had fired ballistic missiles at Israeli army's headquarters (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-lawmaker-matt-gaetz-as-pick-for-attorney-general-7014203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Announces Lawmaker Matt Gaetz As Pick For Attorney General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-lawmaker-matt-gaetz-as-pick-for-attorney-general-7014203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Nov 2024 04:23:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump announced firebrand lawmaker Matt Gaetz as his pick for attorney general Wednesday, naming a fierce defender who would be well-placed to make good on the president-elect's threats of revenge against political foes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump announced firebrand lawmaker Matt Gaetz as his pick for attorney general Wednesday, naming a fierce defender who would be well-placed to make good on the president-elect's threats of revenge against political foes.</p>

<p>"Few issues in America are more important than ending the partisan Weaponization of our Justice System," Donald Trump posted on social media. "Matt will end Weaponized Government... and restore Americans' badly-shattered Faith and Confidence in the Justice Department."</p>

<p>Matt Gaetz, a Floridian and a US congressman since 2017, is among Donald Trump's most controversial nominations as he looks to fill out his cabinet after victory against Democrat Kamala Harris in last week's presidential election.</p>

<p>Donald Trump has called for retribution against many perceived political foes whom he baselessly accuses of wielding the might of the Justice Department against him in politically motivated prosecutions.</p>

<p>Democrats fear Matt Gaetz, 42, will help him weaponize the department to launch exactly those types of "show trial" prosecutions.</p>

<p>As attorney general, Matt Gaetz would drive all aspects of the work of the Justice Department, which for years has carried out an investigation into sex trafficking and obstruction of justice allegations involving him.</p>

<p>Matt Gaetz, who denies all wrongdoing, was told last year that there would be no charges against him, but he remains the subject of a House ethics investigation.</p>

<p>Police began looking at Matt Gaetz as they were investigating his friend, former tax collector Joel Greenberg, who was sentenced in 2022 to a prison term of 11 years after admitting to sex trafficking a minor and other charges.</p>

<p>In September, Matt Gaetz said in a statement he would no longer help congressional investigators, accusing them of leading a "political payback exercise" and calling the probe "uncomfortably nosy."</p>

<p>Republican and Democratic senators immediately voiced doubts that Gaetz's nomination would survive the confirmation process, which can involve intense questioning during difficult, fraught hearings.</p>

<p>Matt Gaetz will likely only be able to lose three Republicans and still get the green light from the Senate.</p>

<p>CNN, citing unnamed sources reported that House Republicans were meeting behind closed doors when news of Matt Gaetz's nomination emerged -- prompting "an audible gasp from the members in the room."</p>

<p>Republican Iowa Senator Joni Ernst said Matt Gaetz would have "his work cut out for him," according to Scripps News, which also reported that the party's Alaska Senator Lisa Murkowski said: "Do you think he's a serious candidate? Not as far as I'm concerned."</p>

<p>A third senator from the party's political middle, Susan Collins, told reporters she was "shocked" by the announcement.</p>

<p>"That shows why the advice and consent process is so important, and I'm sure that there will be a lot of questions raised at his hearing."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rsp3stg_matt-gaetz-trump_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Matt Gaetz has been a US congressman since 2017. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-administration-to-give-boost-to-incredibly-important-us-india-ties-7013291]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Administration To Give Boost To "Incredibly Important" US-India Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trumps-administration-to-give-boost-to-incredibly-important-us-india-ties-7013291]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:48:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's presidential election victory has brought optimism to India-US relations, with key appointments and initiatives signalling a stronger partnership between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's presidential election victory has brought optimism to India-US relations, with key appointments and initiatives signalling a stronger partnership between the two nations. Marco Rubio, Mike Waltz, Vivek Ramaswamy and Kash Patel are expected to play pivotal roles in shaping this relationship.</p>

<h2><strong>MARCO RUBIO</strong></h2>

<p>India is optimistic about Donald Trump's US election victory, especially after his likely pick for Secretary of State, Marco Rubio. Mr Rubio has consistently backed stronger US-India ties to counter China's growing influence in the Indo-Pacific region, and his pro-India and anti-Pakistan stance bodes well for New Delhi.</p>

<p>Mr Rubio's bill, introduced in July, aims to bolster the US-India partnership and counter "expansionist" China's influence in the region. He believes increasing strategic relations with New Delhi is crucial, especially given India's challenges against China's aggression. The bill proposes treating India on par with US allies like Japan, Israel, and South Korea regarding technology transfers, supporting India's response to territorial threats.</p>

<p>During Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to the US in 2023, Mr Rubio released a statement saying, it is crucial that the Biden Administration, and the US Congress, prioritise this incredibly important relationship. Our nations' economic and security interests overlap on many of the most pressing issues, especially the growing hostility of the Chinese Communist Party in the Himalayas and in the Indian Ocean.</p>

<p>This potential status would solidify India-US tech and military ties. Additionally, the bill seeks to bar Pakistan from receiving security assistance if found sponsoring terrorism against India. Mr Rubio has historically been critical of Pakistan, urging former Secretary of State Rex Tillerson to designate it a "country of particular concern" for religious freedom violations in 2017.</p>

<p>Overall, Trump's victory and Marco Rubio's nomination bring optimism for India-US relations, promising a stronger, more strategic partnership.</p>

<h3><strong>MIKE WALTZ</strong></h3>

<p>President Trump's appointment of Mike Waltz as National Security Adviser is expected to strengthen US-India ties, particularly in defence. Mr Waltz, a vocal China critic and co-chair of the Congressional India Caucus, has long advocated for deeper cooperation between the two nations to counter China's growing influence in the Indo-Pacific.</p>

<p>His leadership may lead to expanded military cooperation, joint exercises, and enhanced sharing of defence technologies, aligning US and Indian strategic interests.</p>

<p>As a China hawk, Mr Waltz's appointment is particularly promising for India, which has its own geopolitical concerns about China's growing aggression. Mr Waltz's criticism of Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau also aligns with India's concerns. Overall, Mr Waltz's appointment is expected to enhance US-India cooperation in both security and economic spheres.</p>

<h3><strong>ELON MUSK AND VIVEK RAMASWAMY</strong></h3>

<p>The Department of Government Efficiency or DOGE, co-led by Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy, is set to revolutionise the US government's inner workings by slashing bureaucracy and streamlining operations. While this initiative isn't directly linked to foreign policy, it could have a ripple effect, making it easier for Indian businesses to operate in the US and vice versa, thus boosting US-India economic cooperation.</p>

<p>As Donald Trump begins his second term, strengthening US-India relations remains a top priority, with a sharp focus on countering China's growing influence and expanding bilateral partnerships in key areas like defence, trade, and technology. The foundation for this cooperation was laid during Trump's first term, with significant developments in strategic cooperation and shared geopolitical goals.</p>

<p>With the US Congress set to confirm the electoral results on January 6, 2025, and the presidential inauguration scheduled for January 20, 2025, India can expect a strengthened partnership with the United States under Trump's second term.</p>

<h3><strong>KASH PATEL</strong></h3>

<p>Apart from the cabinet, there is also Kashyap 'Kash' Patel who majorly lost out on an important role - CIA chief. It has now been bagged by John Ratcliffe.</p>

<p>However, Kash Patel is being included in the Trump Administration. His presence in the Trump administration could have significant implications. He is an Indian-origin American attorney and as a loyalist to Trump, Mr Patel's appointment may strengthen ties between the two nations, particularly in counter-terrorism efforts.</p>

<p>His personal experience as an immigrant has shaped his views on immigration, leading him to back Donald Trump's tough stance on the issue. Mr Patel advocates for securing borders while still allowing lawful immigration, striking a balance between national security and economic needs. This nuanced approach reflects his background as the son of Indian immigrants and his own journey to becoming a key figure in Trump's administration.</p>

<p>As Trump begins his second term, strengthening US-India relations remains a top priority, focusing on countering China's influence and expanding bilateral partnerships in defence, trade, and technology. With key appointments and initiatives in place, India can expect a strengthened partnership with the United States.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/s0ltn3ig_trump-modi-afp_625x300_22_September_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As Trump begins his second term, strengthening US-India relations remains a top priority]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-pick-john-thune-as-next-us-senate-leader-7013239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Republicans Pick John Thune As Next US Senate Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/republican-pick-john-thune-as-next-us-senate-leader-7013239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:40:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Republicans in the US Senate picked John Thune as the chamber's new leader Wednesday as lawmakers scrambling to prepare for President-elect Donald Trump's new administration rejected his camp's favored candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Republicans in the US Senate picked John Thune as the chamber's new leader Wednesday as lawmakers scrambling to prepare for President-elect Donald Trump's new administration rejected his camp's favored candidate.</p>

<p>Thune, who already holds a junior leadership position, bested John Cornyn of Texas in a run-off to replace outgoing party leader Mitch McConnell, having already seen off Florida's Rick Scott, who was seen as most aligned with Trump.</p>

<p>"This Republican team is united behind President Trump's agenda, and our work starts today," Thune, who represents South Dakota, said in a brief statement.</p>

<p>The Senate -- the upper chamber of Congress -- jealously guards its independence and institutional authority, and its leadership election was seen as a clue into how much leeway members intend to give Trump.</p>

<p>Cornyn had the longer history in the chamber, while Thune was always seen as most aligned with the traditionalist wing of the party led by McConnell.</p>

<p>Trump insiders had preferred Scott, an ardent loyalist who had promised to do the president-elect's bidding.</p>

<p>Trump's allies campaigned aggressively against Thune and Cornyn, pressuring individual senators in a push that has sparked a backlash -- but Trump was wary of Scott's unpopularity and did not publicly endorse him.</p>

<p>Trump threw down a challenge Sunday to any prospective leader, demanding that they allow "recess appointments" -- the naming of cabinet members while the Senate is adjourned, bypassing the body's normal confirmation process.</p>

<p>Thune -- along with the others -- passed Trump's loyalty test by replying that he was open to the idea.</p>

<p>Scott's cheerleaders -- a group that includes tech billionaire and Trump confidant Elon Musk, and far-right media personality Tucker Carlson -- questioned Thune's commitment to the incoming president, dredging up past opposition.</p>

<p><strong>Decisive win</strong></p>

<p>Trump is expected to further test lawmakers with a series of controversial moves, not least pardoning many of the people convicted of crimes related to the 2021 storming of the Capitol.</p>

<p>Other members have winced at the Republican president-elect's plans for steep, across-the-board import tariffs, although most are behind his tax cut extension -- which is expected to add significantly to the national debt.</p>

<p>The House and the Senate kicked off their frantic "lame-duck" session on Tuesday.</p>

<p>California is still counting ballots, but Republicans are widely expected to keep the House, handing the party total control of Washington after they claimed the Senate and White House last week.</p>

<p>The top priority for both parties in both chambers is funding the government to keep federal agencies open after December 20, with Republicans mulling a stop-gap measure that would keep the lights on into March.</p>

<p>The entire House of Representatives -- Democrats as well as Republicans -- gets to vote on the speaker, meaning Mike Johnson has to wait until the new Congress convenes in January to find out if he can hang on to the gavel.</p>

<p>"Republicans in the House and Senate have a mandate, it's true. It was a decisive win across the nation," Johnson told reporters on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"The American people want us to implement and deliver that America First agenda."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tkdteebg_john-thune-us-senate_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[John Thune was always seen as most aligned with the traditionalist wing of the party. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/welcome-back-says-biden-as-he-congratulates-trump-at-the-white-house-meet-7013183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Welcome Back": Biden Congratulates President-Elect Trump At White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/welcome-back-says-biden-as-he-congratulates-trump-at-the-white-house-meet-7013183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:30:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden welcomed Donald Trump back to the White House on Wednesday, in a show of civility to a bitter rival who failed to extend him the same courtesy four years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden welcomed Donald Trump back to the White House on Wednesday, in a show of civility to a bitter rival who failed to extend him the same courtesy four years ago.</p>

<p>The US president and president-elect shook hands in front of a roaring fire in the Oval Office as they pledged a smooth transition -- a stark contrast to Trump's refusal to recognize his 2020 defeat.</p>

<p>"Welcome back," Biden, 81, said as he congratulated the 78-year-old Trump and offered brief opening remarks to the man he has repeatedly slammed as a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>Biden, who dropped out of the election in July but saw his successor Kamala Harris lose to Trump last week, said he was "looking forward to having a smooth transition" and pledged to do "everything we can to make sure you're accommodated."</p>

<p>As the two presidents with a combined age of 159 years shook hands, Biden appeared to look down while Trump leaned forward and looked him in the eyes.</p>

<p>Trump riled up a mob that attacked the US Capitol in 2021 and ran a brutal and divisive election campaign this year -- but sought to strike a gracious tone on his return visit to the White House.</p>

<p>"Politics is tough, and in many cases it's not a very nice world. It is a nice world today and I appreciate it very much," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump added that the transfer of power would be "smooth as you can get" -- despite the fact that his transition team has not yet signed some key legal documents ahead of his inauguration as president on January 20.</p>

<p><strong>No Melania</strong></p>

<p>Absent from the occasion was incoming first lady Melania Trump, who was a shadowy presence on the campaign trail and spent much of Trump's first term away from the White House.</p>

<p>Outgoing First Lady Jill Biden joined Biden in welcoming Trump and "gave Mr. Trump a handwritten letter of congratulations for Mrs Trump," the White House said.</p>

<p>The only other people in the room for talks after the handshake were Biden's chief of staff Jeff Zients and Trump's incoming chief of staff Susie Wiles, the White House said.</p>

<p>Biden was expected to push during the meeting for Trump to continue US support for Ukraine's fight against Russia, which the Republican has called into question.</p>

<p>Biden's Oval Office invitation restored a presidential transition tradition that Trump tore up when he lost the 2020 election, refusing to sit down with Biden or even attend the inauguration.</p>

<p>But by the time Trump took his last flight from the White House lawn on January 20, 2021, he had also been repudiated by many in his own party for having stoked the assault on the Capitol.</p>

<p>That period of disgrace soon evaporated, however, as Republicans returned to Trump's side, recognizing the billionaire's unique electoral power at the head of his right-wing movement.</p>

<p><strong>Third term?</strong></p>

<p>Trump enters his second term with a near total grip on his party and is expected to take both chambers of Congress -- while the Democrats are in disarray.</p>

<p>Ahead of the White House visit, Trump addressed Republicans from the House of Representatives at a Washington hotel.</p>

<p>An ebullient Trump suggested that he could even be open to a third term in office -- which would violate the US constitution.</p>

<p>"I suspect I won't be running again unless you say, 'He's good, we got to figure something else,'" he said, drawing some laughter.</p>

<p>Former reality TV star Trump, who has promised to be a "dictator on day one," is moving quickly to fill out his administration, picking a host of ultra-loyalists.</p>

<p>He was accompanied at the meeting with Republicans by the world's richest man Elon Musk, whom he named on Tuesday as head of a new group aimed at slashing government spending.</p>

<p>He also nominated Fox News host and army veteran Pete Hegseth as his incoming defense secretary. An opponent of so-called "woke" ideology in the armed forces, Hegseth has little experience similar to managing the world's most powerful military.</p>

<p>Trump named South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem -- an ally who famously wrote about shooting her dog because it did not respond to training -- as head of the Department of Homeland Security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fn547nk_trump-biden_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden appeared to look down while Trump leaned forward and looked him in the eyes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-may-not-return-to-white-house-full-time-as-first-lady-heres-why-7012963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Melania Trump May Not Move To White House Full Time As First Lady]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/melania-trump-may-not-return-to-white-house-full-time-as-first-lady-heres-why-7012963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:52:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In her second go-round as first lady, Melania Trump is reportedly planning to spend the majority of her time between New York City and Palm Beach.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Melania Trump will likely not call the White House her home for the next four years while her husband Donald Trump serves as the US President. Discussions are still ongoing about how and where the incoming first lady will spend her time in her unelected but high-profile role on the world stage, CNN reported, quoting multiple sources.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In her first move toward bucking the traditions, 52-year-old Melania Trump has skipped the traditional and symbolic meeting with outgoing First Lady Jill Biden at the White House as President Joe Biden hosts the president-elect in the Oval Office on Wednesday (November 13).</p>

<p>Sources attributed Ms Trump's absence to a prior scheduling conflict related to her eponymous memoir, and her office also confirmed on X that she would not attend the meeting.</p>

<p>The move indicates that Ms Trump, who had already spent four years in the White House, will have even more autonomy the second around.</p>

<p>I'm not anxious because this time is different. I have much more experience and much more knowledge. I was in the White House before. When you go in, you know exactly what to expect, Ms Trump recently told Fox News during a friendly interview while promoting her book.</p>

<h2>FLOTUS TO SPEND TIME IN NYC, FLORIDA</h2>

<p>In her second go-round as first lady, she is reportedly planning to spend the majority of her time between New York City and Palm Beach, Florida. However, despite her absence from the White House, Ms Trump would still likely be present at major events and would have her own platform and priorities as first lady.</p>

<p>"Melania Trump has developed a life and circle of friends in Florida over the past four years and is likely to continue to spend a lot of her time there," CNN report quoted sources as saying.</p>

<p>The incoming first lady is also likely to spend a significant amount of time at Trump Tower in New York, where her son Barron Trump, 18, is attending New York University.</p>

<p>Her Husband also doesn't have any qualms with her absence and there is no internal backlash among the president-elect's team," a source told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/13/politics/melania-trump-white-house/index.html" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>Speculation about Melania Trump's living situation have swirled for months. In June, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.axios.com/local/washington-dc/2024/06/24/melania-trump-dc-first-lady-sightings" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Axios</a> reported that if the Republican leader returned to the White House, his wife would live elsewhereperhaps at Mar-a-Lago, where the president-elect is expected to spend a large amount of time, or in Manhattan, where her son is studying.</p>

<p>If reports are true, Melania will become a trend breaker, as all of her predecessorsaside from Anna Symmes Harrison, whose husband died a month into his term, and Bess Truman, who lived across the street during renovationshave lived predominantly in the White House since it was built in 1800.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pss7t7io_donald-trump-melania-trump-afp_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump reportedly doesn't have any qualms with Melania Trump's absence from White House]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-climate-draft-shows-deep-divide-on-funding-for-poorer-nations-at-cop29-7012948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Climate Draft Shows Deep Divide On Funding For Poorer Nations At COP29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-climate-draft-shows-deep-divide-on-funding-for-poorer-nations-at-cop29-7012948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:50:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fresh draft of a UN climate deal released Wednesday offers wide-ranging options to raise funding for poorer countries, signalling that tough negotiations remain at the COP29 talks in Baku.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fresh draft of a UN climate deal released Wednesday offers wide-ranging options to raise funding for poorer countries, signalling that tough negotiations remain at the COP29 talks in Baku.</p>

<p>Landing a new agreement to boost money for climate action in developing countries is the top priority of negotiators at the summit in Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>But it is deeply contentious, and consensus has eluded negotiators from nearly 200 nations for the better part of a year.</p>

<p>Most developing countries favour an annual commitment from wealthy countries of at least $1.3 trillion, according to the latest draft of the long-sought climate finance pact.</p>

<p>This figure is more than 10 times the $100 billion annually that a small pool of developed countries -- among them the United States, the European Union and Japan -- currently pay.</p>

<p>Some donors are reluctant to promise large new amounts of public money from their budgets at a time when they face economic and political pressure at home.</p>

<p>"It is their responsibility to convince their electorate," a key negotiator from a developing country told AFP.</p>

<p>An earlier version of the draft was rejected outright by developing countries, which considered the proposed terms weighted too heavily toward wealthy nations.</p>

<p><strong>Three options&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Fresh submissions were called, and the new document summarises three broad positions.</p>

<p>The first argues that rich, industrialised nations most responsible for climate change to date pay from their budgets.</p>

<p>The second option calls for other countries to share the burden, a key demand of developed countries, while the third puts forward a mix of the two.</p>

<p>A bloc of least-developed nations, mostly from Africa, are asking for $220 billion while small-island states at threat from rising seas want $39 billion.</p>

<p>Brazil's environment minister, Marina Silva, said "there is a convergence that these resources must be in the order of trillions" in public and private money.</p>

<p>Another Brazilian official, Andre Correa do Lago, criticised the negotiating tactics of richer nations.</p>

<p>"We think that the discussion was diverted by developed countries instead of responding as they should by the rules of negotiation that are taking place," he told reporters.</p>

<p>Friederike Roder from Global Citizen, a non-government organisation, said the draft proposes "more concrete options" for an agreement on a total amount and "specific objectives" for the poorest and most vulnerable nations.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, this search for precision stops there. The proposals aimed at clearly defining what constitutes climate finance, and ensuring close and transparent monitoring, remain insufficient," she told AFP.</p>

<p>The latest 34-page draft reflects all the options on the table, said David Waskow, director at the World Resources Institute, a think tank.</p>

<p>"Negotiators now need to work to boil it down to some key decisions for the ministers to wrestle with next week," he said.</p>

<p>COP29 runs until November 22 but climate talks often run into overtime.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0le4r4t8_cop29_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Developing countries favour an annual commitment from wealthy countries of at least $1.3 trillion. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cia-official-charged-over-leak-of-classified-intel-on-israel-iran-plans-7012914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[CIA Official Charged Over Leak Of Classified Intel On Israel-Iran Plans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cia-official-charged-over-leak-of-classified-intel-on-israel-iran-plans-7012914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:43:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A CIA official has been charged in connection with a leak of classified US intelligence documents about Israel's plans for a retaliatory strike on Iran, The New York Times reported Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A CIA official has been charged in connection with a leak of classified US intelligence documents about Israel's plans for a retaliatory strike on Iran, The New York Times reported Wednesday.</p>

<p>Asif Rahman, who worked abroad for the Central Intelligence Agency, was arrested in Cambodia by the FBI and was to appear in a federal court in Guam on Thursday, the newspaper said.</p>

<p>It said Rahman, who held a top secret security clearance, was indicted in Virginia last week with two counts of willful retention and transmission of national intelligence information.</p>

<p>Iran unleashed a wave of close to 200 ballistic missiles on Israel on October 1 in retaliation for the killings of Tehran-backed senior figures in Hamas and Hezbollah. Israel retaliated with a wave of strikes on military targets in Iran in late October.</p>

<p>The classified documents, circulated on the Telegram app by an account called Middle East Spectator, described Israeli preparations for a possible strike but did not identify any actual targets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/70m664jo_iran_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The classified documents described Israeli preparations for a possible strike. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-thanks-biden-for-pledge-of-smooth-power-transfer-at-white-house-7012701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Power Transition Will Be "As Smooth As You Can Get", Says Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-thanks-biden-for-pledge-of-smooth-power-transfer-at-white-house-7012701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:16:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump thanked President Joe Biden for pledging a smooth transfer of power as the victorious Republican made a historic return visit to the White House on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump thanked President Joe Biden for pledging a smooth transfer of power as the victorious Republican made a historic return visit to the White House on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Politics is tough, and in many cases it's not a very nice world. It is a nice world today and I appreciate it very much," Trump said after the two men shook hands in the Oval Office.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, added that the transition would be "smooth as you can get."</p>

<p>Biden greeted Trump in front of a roaring fire, offering him congratulations and saying: "Welcome back."</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Biden invited his sworn rival to the White House -- despite the fact that Trump, who refused to admit his 2020 election loss, never afforded Biden the same courtesy.</p>

<p>Biden, who dropped out of the election in July but saw his successor Kamala Harris lose to Trump last week, said he was "looking forward to having a smooth transition."</p>

<p>"We'll do everything we can to make sure you're accommodated, (have) what you need," he told Trump.</p>

<p><strong>Triumphant Trump&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Their talks after the public handshake may have been a bitter pill to swallow for Biden, who branded Trump a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>Biden was expected to push during the meeting for Trump to continue US support for Ukraine's fight against Russia, which the Republican has called into question.</p>

<p>Ahead of the White House visit, Trump addressed Republicans from the House of Representatives at a Washington hotel near the Capitol, which a mob of his supporters marched in 2021 to try to reverse his election loss.</p>

<p>An ebullient Trump suggested that he could even be open to a third term in office -- which would violate the US constitution.</p>

<p>"I suspect I won't be running again unless you say, 'He's good, we got to figure something else,'" he said, drawing some laughter.</p>

<p>Trump's party looks set to take both chambers of Congress and consolidate his extraordinary comeback.</p>

<p>He was accompanied at the meeting with Republicans by the world's richest man Elon Musk, whom he named on Tuesday as head of a new group aimed at slashing government spending.</p>

<p>Trump has launched a flurry of nominations as he moves swiftly to name his administration.</p>

<p><strong>Picking his team</strong></p>

<p>Biden's Oval Office invitation restored a presidential transition tradition that Trump tore up when he lost the 2020 election, refusing to sit down with Biden or even attend the inauguration.</p>

<p>Then-president Barack Obama had welcomed Trump to the White House when the tycoon won the 2016 election.</p>

<p>But by the time Trump took his last Marine One flight from the White House lawn on January 20, 2021, he had also been repudiated by many in his own party for having stoked the assault on the Capitol.</p>

<p>That period of disgrace soon evaporated, however, as Republicans returned to Trump's side, recognizing his unique electoral power at the head of his right-wing movement.</p>

<p>Trump enters his second term with a near total grip on his party and the Democrats in disarray.</p>

<p>He has spent the week since the election at his Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida assembling his top team, as the world watches to see how closely he sticks to his pledges of isolationism, mass deportations and sweeping tariffs.</p>

<p>Trump named Space X, Tesla and X boss Musk, and businessman Vivek Ramaswamy, to lead a "Department of Government Efficiency ('DOGE')" -- a tongue-in-cheek reference to an internet meme and cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Trump is moving quickly to fill out his administration, picking a host of ultra-loyalists.</p>

<p>Trump nominated Fox News host and army veteran Pete Hegseth as his incoming defense secretary. An outspoken opponent of so-called "woke" ideology in the armed forces, Hegseth has little experience similar to managing the mammoth US military budget and bureaucracy.</p>

<p>Trump named South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem -- an ally who famously wrote about shooting her dog because it did not respond to training -- as head of the Department of Homeland Security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sntp5mg_trump-biden_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump added that the transition would be "smooth as you can get."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-governments-efficiency-panel-headed-by-elon-musk-might-work-7012643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Musk's US Government Efficiency Panel Might Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-governments-efficiency-panel-headed-by-elon-musk-might-work-7012643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:05:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has tasked Elon Musk with setting up a panel to streamline the US government. Although the president-elect has said little about how this group would operate, Musk has previously set an ambitious goal of cutting $2 trillion of spending.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has tasked Elon Musk with setting up a panel to streamline the US government. Although the president-elect has said little about how this group would operate, Musk has previously set an ambitious goal of cutting $2 trillion of spending.</p>

<p>Here is how this new panel, which will be headed up by Musk, the world's richest person, and former Republican Presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy, might work.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DOES MUSK WANT TO CUT?</strong></p>

<p>Musk said at a Trump rally at Madison Square Garden in October that the federal budget could be reduced by "at least" $2 trillion. Discretionary spending, including defense spending, is estimated to total $1.9 trillion out of $6.75 trillion in total federal outlays for fiscal 2024, according to the Congressional Budget Office, suggesting Musk's target would be very difficult to meet.</p>

<p>Musk, whose companies include the electric vehicle maker Tesla and commercial space company SpaceX, has a deep knowledge of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Pentagon, agencies he has extensive contracts with for rockets, satellites and other space operations.</p>

<p>He has also tussled with regulators within the Department of Transportation, including the Federal Aviation Administration, which has a say in his company's rocket launches, and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, which is investigating autonomous driving functions in his cars.</p>

<p>Ramaswamy, who founded pharmaceutical company Roivant Sciences, has worked with the Food and Drug Administration, an agency he has previously called "corrupt". On social media site X in 2023 he added that "Countless FDA regulations and actions are hypocritical, harmful &amp; unconstitutional."</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAVE MUSK AND TRUMP SAID ABOUT THE PANEL?</strong></p>

<p>Trump in a statement on Tuesday said the panel would "provide advice and guidance from outside of government," on slimming down the government, cutting regulations, reducing spending and restructuring federal agencies.</p>

<p>Trump wants to abolish the Department of Education, and leave states in control of schooling, and decimate what he terms the "deep state" - career federal employees he says are clandestinely pursuing their own agendas.</p>

<p>Trump and Musk have suggested the panel will be able to make dramatic cuts, but generally speaking large budgetary actions are the remit of Congress. They can take advice from outside panels like the proposed efficiency panel, or disregard it.</p>

<p>In an effort to be transparent, Musk said the panel will post its "actions" for public comment.</p>

<p>"Anytime the public thinks we are cutting something important or not cutting something wasteful, just let us know!" he said on X.</p>

<p>He also mentioned a list of "dumb" spending, which he noted would be "extremely entertaining".</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IS THE PRECEDENT FOR THE EFFICIENCY PANEL?</strong></p>

<p>Former President Ronald Reagan announced in February 1982 that he would form a group of private sector experts to recommend ways to eliminate inefficiency and waste. That June, he issued an executive order forming the President's Private Sector Survey on Cost Control in the Federal Government, which became known as the Grace Commission for its chairman J. Peter Grace, the former CEO of W.R. Grace and Co.</p>

<p>Grace raised money to fund the effort through a foundation. About 150 business leaders volunteered their time on an executive committee that oversaw 36 Grace Commission task forces, which reviewed agencies or functions.</p>

<p>The Commission issued a report in January 1984 with some 2,500 recommendations, and the various task forces came out with reports as well.</p>

<p>"Most of the recommendations, especially those requiring legislation from Congress, were never implemented," the Reagan Library said.</p>

<p>In March 2017, Trump signed an executive order that aimed to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and accountability of federal agencies and to "eliminate or reorganize unnecessary federal agencies." It directed each federal agency to submit a proposed plan to reorganize. He also signed a separate executive order to place "regulatory reform" task forces and officers within federal agencies.</p>

<p>Trump also tried to kill at least 19 agencies but was unsuccessful during his first term. He called for eliminating the Overseas Private Investment Corporation that helps spur private investment in foreign development projects and the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. He also tried to cut funding for Amtrak, subsidies for rural airline service and the Special Olympics.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT EXPERIENCE DOES MUSK HAVE WITH COST CUTTING?</strong></p>

<p>After Musk bought the social media app Twitter, he laid off roughly 3,700 employees, or half its workforce, as advertisers pulled spending. Hundreds more employees subsequently resigned. He later renamed the social media site "X", but its valuation has shrunk dramatically under Musk's ownership.</p>

<p>Musk has had much greater success in space. SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket slashed launch costs with its reusability, sprouting new satellite markets and giving rise to the company's fast-growing Starlink constellation, which has disrupted the established satellite communications industry and helped shape modern military strategies and turned SpaceX into a major defense contractor.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT ARE THE RULES FOR A PANEL LIKE THIS?</strong></p>

<p>The committee would likely operate under the Federal Advisory Committee Act, a 1972 law ensuring panels provide advice that is prompt, objective and open to the public. It also mandates cost controls and record keeping requirements that apply to the roughly 1,000 committees with some 60,000 members advising the President and the executive branch at any given time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u864ihd8_elon-musk_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Elon Musk have suggested the panel will be able to make dramatic cuts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-talks-of-constitution-breaking-3rd-term-as-president-details-here-7012449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Hints At Constitution-Breaking 3rd Term As President. Details Here]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-talks-of-constitution-breaking-3rd-term-as-president-details-here-7012449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 21:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, who has recently been elected for a second term as President of the United States, has told House Republicans that he might consider a constitution-breaking third term in office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, who has recently been elected for a second term as President of the United States, has told House Republicans that he might consider a constitution-breaking third term in office. President-elect Trump, who has a penchant for making controversial statements, said "I suspect I won't be running again unless you (supporters) say otherwise".</p>

<p>During his speech to fellow Republicans elected to the House of Representatives, Mr Trump said, "I suspect I won't be running again unless you say, 'He's good, we got to figure something else'." His statement at a hotel in Washington DC ahead of his meeting with President Joe Biden was cheered by his supporters.</p>

<p>It is common knowledge that there are provisions in place in the US Constitution which restricts a US President from standing for re-election for a third term, but how safe are those safeguards? Here's a look at whether Donald Trump can run again for presidency in 2028.</p>

<p>The 22nd Amendment of the United States Constitution stops any President from running for a third term, so if Donald Trump wants to seek a third term, he will first have to scrap that amendment. Doing so is a daunting task as it requires the President to garner an overwhelming amount of support from Congress as well as state legislatures. This is something that Trump is unlikely to be able to achieve.</p>

<p>According to an article in US-based news website <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/383616/trump-third-term-constitution-22nd-amendment" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Vox</a>, which interviewed a law professor from Stanford University who specialises in constitutional interpretation, a question about the possibility of such a Constitutional amendment was asked. His reply was clear - "No, there are none. This will be his last run for President," the law professor said.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT IS THE 22nd AMENDMENT?</strong></h2>

<p>The 22nd Amendment of the US Constitution says that a President can have two terms in office and no further. It is applicable to Presidents, both in consecutive and non-consecutive terms.</p>

<p>According to Section 1 of the 22nd Amendment of the Constitution of the United States, "No person shall be elected to the office of the President more than twice, and no person who has held the office of President, or acted as President, for more than two years of a term to which some other person was elected President shall be elected to the office of the President more than once. But this Article shall not apply to any person holding the office of President when this Article was proposed by the Congress, and shall not prevent any person who may be holding the office of President, or acting as President, during the term within which this Article becomes operative from holding the office of President or acting as President during the remainder of such term."</p>

<p>While Section 2 states that "This article shall be inoperative unless it shall have been ratified as an amendment to the Constitution by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years from the date of its submission to the States by the Congress."</p>

<h3><strong>HISTORY OF THE 22nd AMENDMENT</strong></h3>

<p>The provision to restrict US Presidents strictly to a maximum of two terms first came into force in 1951, when both Republicans and Democrats had demanded for such a provision to be in place. This was because former US President Franklin D Roosevelt was elected to the highest office for an unprecedented four times. In 1945, he had died in office during his fourth term.</p>

<p>Though Roosevelt was the only President to be elected more than two times, American lawmakers from both parties had decided that the presidential terms must have a ceiling limit, and hence the 22nd Amendment came into force, restricting all Presidents then on to a maximum of two terms.</p>

<p>Since US's first President and founding father George Washington had served for a maximum of two terms, both parties agreed that this was the legacy to be followed.</p>

<h3><strong>CAN AN AMENDMENT IN THE US CONSTITUTION BE REPEALED?</strong></h3>

<p>The checks and balances in place to ensure that an Amendment to the Constitution is not easily repealed are watertight. It dissuades and discourages amendments from being scrapped or repealed. However, it is not impossible.</p>

<p>In order to do so, a bill for such order would have to be agreed to by two-thirds majority (67 per cent) of both the House and the Senate. The House of Representatives has 435 members, of which 290 must vote for such a revocation. Similarly, in the Senate, which has 100 members, 67 must agree with it. That is not all. Should a bill be passed by the House and the Senate, it then goes to each of the states - which need to pass it with a three-fourths majority, and since the United States of America are 50 states, 38 of them would have to agree to it.</p>

<p>It is safe to assume that to cross all three hurdles would be highly unlikely for Donald Trump.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1oqbsaio_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump hints at running for President for a third term - something that is not constitutional]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>