<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:44:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-latest-attack-donald-trumps-son-eric-trump-calls-meghan-markle-spoiled-apple-6281839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Latest Attack, Trump's Son Eric Calls Meghan Markle "Spoiled Apple"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-latest-attack-donald-trumps-son-eric-trump-calls-meghan-markle-spoiled-apple-6281839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:28:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eric Trump, the son of former US President Donald Trump, has expressed his disdain for Prince Harry and Meghan Markle, suggesting his father may deport the couple, should he win the US presidential election come November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eric Trump, the son of former US President Donald Trump, has expressed his disdain for Prince Harry and Meghan Markle, suggesting his father may deport the couple, should he win the US presidential election come November.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"You can happily have those two [Meghan and Harry] back. We'll happily send them back from America," Eric Trump said in an interview with <a href="https://www.gbnews.com/royal/meghan-markle-prince-harry-bad-apples-donald-trump-eric ">GB News</a> on Sunday. "You can have them back over here, but I'm not sure if you want them anymore. We might not want them anymore, it feels like they're on an island of their own."</p>

<p>He praised the royal family as a "beautiful" and "sacred Institute" but took a swipe at Meghan Markle's past career as a Hollywood actress, calling her a "spoiled apple" and saying, "You can always have bad actors in everything."</p>

<p>Eric Trump mentioned he held a deep admiration for the late Queen Elizabeth II, adding he and his father "had so much respect" for her. He fondly recalled his father's interactions with Queen Elizabeth during his presidency, from 2017 to 2021.</p>

<p>After her death in 2022, Donald Trump praised her "historic and remarkable reign" on his Truth Social platform. Eric Trump also shared a personal connection to the royal family, revealing that his late mother, Ivana Trump, "had a great relationship" with Princess Diana, Prince Harry's mother.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Eric Trump's recent comments insulting Prince Harry and Meghan Markle are not the first time the Trump family has publicly criticised the couple. His father, Donald Trump, has been vocal about his dislike for the couple, particularly Markle, whom he has accused of being "disrespectful" to the royal family.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March, Trump suggested that the royal couple, who have been living in California since 2020, may need to relocate due to Harry's admission of drug use in the US, as revealed in his memoir 'Spare'. The former US President stated that Harry should not have "special privileges" and that "appropriate action" must be taken if he lied on his US visa application.</p>

<p>Previously, at the CPAC in February, Donald Trump declared that he "wouldn't protect" Harry, calling him an "embarrassment" and stating that he "betrayed the queen". He also predicted that Harry and Meghan Markle's marriage would "end bad" in a 2022 interview with Piers Morgan.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/vbst8spg_eric-trump-meghan-markle_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Eric Trump took a swipe at Meghan Markle's past career as a Hollywood actress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-refused-to-suppress-protest-sealing-sheikh-hasinas-fate-6280790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Refused To Suppress Protest, Sealing Sheikh Hasina's Fate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-refused-to-suppress-protest-sealing-sheikh-hasinas-fate-6280790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:17:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The night before long-time leader Sheikh Hasina abruptly fled Bangladesh amid deadly protests, her army chief held a meeting with his generals and decided that troops would not open fire on civilians to enforce a curfew.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The night before long-time leader Sheikh Hasina abruptly fled Bangladesh amid deadly protests, her army chief held a meeting with his generals and decided that troops would not open fire on civilians to enforce a curfew, two serving army officers with knowledge of the discussions told Reuters.</p>

<p>Gen. Waker-Uz-Zaman then reached out to Hasina's office, conveying to the prime minister that his soldiers would be unable to implement the lockdown she had called for, according to an Indian official briefed on the matter.</p>

<p>The message was clear, the official said: Hasina no longer had the army's support.</p>

<p>Details of the online meeting between military top brass and the message to Hasina that she had lost their backing have not previously been reported.</p>

<p>They help to explain how Hasina's 15-year rule, during which she brooked little dissent, came to such a chaotic and sudden end on Monday, when she fled from Bangladesh to India.</p>

<p>The nationwide curfew had been imposed after at least 91 people were killed and hundreds injured in nationwide clashes on Sunday, the deadliest day since student-led protests against Hasina began in July.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Army spokesman Lt. Col. Sami Ud Dowla Chowdhury confirmed the Sunday evening discussions, which he described as a regular meeting to take updates after any disturbance. He did not provide details when presented with additional questions about decision-making at that meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina could not be reached and her son and advisor, Sajeeb Wazed, did not respond to repeated requests for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reuters spoke to ten people familiar with the events of the past week, including four serving army officers and two other informed sources in Bangladesh, to piece together the final 48 hours of Hasina's reign. Many of them spoke on condition of anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina, who has ruled Bangladesh for 20 of the last 30 years, was elected to a fourth term leading the country of 170 million in January, after arresting thousands of opposition leaders and workers. That election was boycotted by her main rivals.</p>

<p>Her iron-fisted grasp on power has been challenged since summer by protests triggered by a court ruling to reserve government jobs - heavily coveted amid high youth unemployment - for certain segments of the population. The decision was overturned but the demonstrations had quickly morphed into a movement to oust Hasina.</p>

<p>Zaman has not publicly explained his decision to withdraw support from Hasina. But the scale of the protests and a death toll of at least 241 made supporting Hasina at all costs untenable, three former senior Bangladesh army officers told Reuters.</p>

<p>"There was a lot of uneasiness within the troops," said retired Brig. Gen. M. Sakhawat Hossain. "That is what probably (put) pressure on the chief of army staff, because the troops are out and they are seeing what is happening."</p>

<p>Zaman, who is related to Hasina by marriage, had showed signs of wavering in his support for the prime minister on Saturday, when he sat on an ornate wooden chair and addressed hundreds of uniformed officers in a town hall meeting. The military later made some details of that discussion public.</p>

<p>The general declared that lives had to be protected and called on his officers to show patience, said army spokesman Chowdhury.</p>

<p>It was the first indication that Bangladesh's army would not forcefully suppress the violent demonstrations, leaving Hasina vulnerable.</p>

<p>Retired senior soldiers such as Brig. Gen. Mohammad Shahedul Anam Khan were among those who defied the curfew on Monday and took to the streets.</p>

<p>"We were not stopped by the army," said Khan, a former infantry soldier. "The army has done what he had promised the army would do."</p>

<p><strong>'SHORT NOTICE'</strong></p>

<p>On Monday, the first full day of the indefinite nationwide curfew, Hasina was holed up inside the Ganabhaban, or "People's Palace", a heavily-guarded complex in the capital Dhaka that serves as her official residence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Outside, on the streets of the sprawling city, crowds gathered. Tens of thousands of people had answered protest leaders' call for a march to oust the leader, streaming into the heart of the city.</p>

<p>With the situation spiralling out of her control, the 76-year-old leader decided to flee the country on Monday morning, according to the Indian official and two Bangladesh nationals familiar with the matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hasina and her sister, who lives in London but was in Dhaka at the time, discussed the matter and flew out together, according to a Bangladesh source. They left for India around lunch, local time.</p>

<p>Indian foreign minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar told parliament on Tuesday that New Delhi had urged "various political forces with whom we were in touch" to resolve the situation via dialogue throughout July.</p>

<p>But as crowds gathered in Dhaka on Monday ignoring the curfew, Hasina decided to resign "after a meeting with leaders of the security establishment", he added. "At very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India."</p>

<p>A second Indian official said it was "diplomatically" conveyed to Hasina that her stay had to be temporary for fear of negatively impacting Delhi's ties with the next government in Dhaka. India's Ministry of External Affairs did not immediately return a request for comment.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, whom the protesting students want to lead the interim government after Hasina's ouster, told The New Indian Express newspaper that India had "good ties with the wrong people... Please revisit your foreign policy."</p>

<p>Yunus wasn't immediately available for an interview.</p>

<p>Late in the afternoon on Monday, a Bangladesh Air Force C130 transport aircraft landed at Hindon air base outside Delhi, with Hasina on board.</p>

<p>There, she was met by Ajit Doval, India's powerful national security advisor, according to the Indian security official.</p>

<p>Delhi had fought to carve Bangladesh out of East Pakistan in 1971. After Hasina's father was assassinated in 1975, Hasina took refuge in India for years and built deep links with her neighbour's political elite.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Returning to Bangladesh, she gained power in 1996, and was seen as more sensitive to India's security concerns than her political rivals. The Hindu-majority nation also regarded her secular stance as favourable for the 13 million Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>But back in Bangladesh, resentment still lingered even among retired soldiers that Hasina had been allowed to leave.</p>

<p>"Personally, I feel that she should not have been given a safe passage," said Khan, the veteran. "That was a folly."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The nationwide curfew had been imposed after at least 91 people were killed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-new-hamas-leader-also-referred-as-dead-man-walking-6281845]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar: New Hamas Leader, Also Referred As "Dead Man Walking"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-new-hamas-leader-also-referred-as-dead-man-walking-6281845]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:14:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After a career in the shadows, spent in Israeli prisons and the internal security apparatus of Hamas, Yahya Sinwar has emerged as leader of the Palestinian group in the middle of a full-blown war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a career in the shadows, spent in Israeli prisons and the internal security apparatus of Hamas, Yahya Sinwar has emerged as leader of the Palestinian group in the middle of a full-blown war.</p>

<p>Sinwar, who until now was the movement's Gaza chief, replaces Ismail Haniyeh, whose killing in Tehran last week sent tensions soaring across the Middle East and raised fears of a coordinated attack on Israel by Iran and its regional proxies.</p>

<p>By choosing him as the group's chief Hamas "is sending a strong message to the occupation that Hamas continues its path of resistance", a senior Hamas official told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sinwar stands accused of masterminding the group's October 7 attacks, the worst in Israel's history, which left 1,198 dead and 251 taken hostage according to an AFP tally and Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of that attack, the Israeli military insisted he was a "dead man walking", although Sinwar has not been seen since.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack was probably a year or two in the planning, "took everyone by surprise" and "changed the balance of power on the ground", said Leila Seurat of the Arab Centre for Research and Political Studies (CAREP) in Paris.</p>

<p>The ascetic 61-year-old is a security operator "par excellence", according to Abu Abdallah, a Hamas member who spent years alongside him in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>"He makes decisions in the utmost calm, but is intractable when it comes to defending the interests of Hamas," Abu Abdallah told AFP in 2017, after his former co-detainee was elected Hamas's leader in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>Punishing collaborators</strong></p>

<p>After October 7, Israeli military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Richard Hecht called Sinwar the "face of evil" and declared him a "dead man walking".</p>

<p>Born in the Khan Yunis refugee camp in southern Gaza, Sinwar joined Hamas when Sheikh Ahmad Yassin founded the group around the time the first Palestinian intifada began in 1987.</p>

<p>Sinwar set up the group's internal security apparatus the following year and went on to head an intelligence unit dedicated to flushing out and mercilessly punishing -- sometimes killing -- Palestinians accused of providing information to Israel.</p>

<p>According to a transcript of an interrogation with security officials published in Israeli media, Sinwar professed to have strangled an alleged collaborator with a keffiyeh scarf in a Khan Yunis cemetery.</p>

<p>A graduate of the Islamic University in Gaza, he learned perfect Hebrew during his 23 years in Israeli jails and is said to have a deep understanding of Israeli culture and society.</p>

<p>He was serving four life terms for the killing of two Israeli soldiers when he became the most senior of 1,027 Palestinians released in exchange for Israeli soldier Gilad Shalit in 2011.</p>

<p>Sinwar later became a senior commander in the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, the military wing of Hamas, before taking overall leadership of the movement in Gaza.</p>

<p>While his predecessor, Haniyeh, had encouraged efforts by Hamas to present a moderate face to the world, Sinwar has preferred to force the Palestinian issue to the fore by more violent means.</p>

<p>The health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza says Israel's withering aerial and ground assault launched in response to the October 7 attacks has killed at least 39,653 people in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p><strong>'Radical and pragmatic'</strong></p>

<p>Sinwar dreams of a single Palestinian state bringing together the Gaza Strip, the occupied West Bank -- controlled by Mahmud Abbas's Fatah party -- and annexed east Jerusalem.</p>

<p>According to US think-tank the Council on Foreign Relations, he has vowed to punish anyone obstructing reconciliation with Fatah, the rival political movement with which Hamas engaged in factional fighting after elections in 2006.</p>

<p>That coming together remains elusive, but the prisoner releases resulting from the brief November truce agreement with Israel have seen Hamas's popularity soar in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Sinwar has pursued a path of being "radical in military planning and pragmatic in politics", according to Seurat.</p>

<p>"He doesn't advocate force for force's sake, but to bring about negotiations" with Israel, she said.</p>

<p>The Hamas chief was added to the US list of the most wanted "international terrorists" in 2015.</p>

<p>Security sources outside Gaza say that Sinwar has taken refuge in the network of tunnels built under the territory to withstand Israeli bombs.</p>

<p>Vowing in November to "find and eliminate" Sinwar, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant urged Gazans to turn Sinwar in, adding "if you reach him before us, it will shorten the war".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qbag8ago_yahya-sinwar-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar stands accused of masterminding the group's October 7 attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-awami-league-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-hindu-homes-targeted-as-mobs-run-amok-after-sheikh-hasina-exit-6281773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Hindu Homes Targeted As Mobs Run Amok After Sheikh Hasina Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-awami-league-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-hindu-homes-targeted-as-mobs-run-amok-after-sheikh-hasina-exit-6281773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:00:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scores of Hindu temples, business establishments and temples in Bangladesh have been attacked by violent mobs after Sheikh Hasina was ousted as Prime Minister, according to a community association.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scores of Hindu temples, business establishments and temples in Bangladesh have been attacked by violent mobs after Sheikh Hasina was ousted as Prime Minister, according to a community association. While leaders of the movement that toppled the Awami League government have appealed to people not to target the Hindu minority, concerns have been raised about their safety. In a silver lining, several voices have come out in support of Hindus and some temples are being guarded by Muslims and Hindus together.</p>

<p>Hindus account for nearly 8 per cent of Bangladesh's 17 crore population, and a large section of this community has traditionally backed Sheikh Hasina's Awami League. This is due to Sheikh Hasina's strong ties with India and Awami League's posturing as a largely secular force as compared to the opposition that comprises hardline forces.</p>

<p>With the government toppled and the new administration yet to take charge, mobs are running amok, targeting police stations, prisons, Awami League leaders' homes and Hindu establishments.</p>

<p>Tarique Rahman, BNP leader and son of former PM Khaleda Zia, is among the key voices that have appealed for calm.</p>

<p>"I call upon the people of Bangladesh to display restraint and calm in the midst of this transitional moment on our democratic path. It is our duty to protect all Bangladeshis, irrespective of religion and politics, from discriminatory violence, and not to harass any particular community, create division, or seek vengeance. Muslims, Hindus, Christians, Buddhists, believers, atheists - no one will be left behind or be prejudiced on our democratic path; together, we are all proudly Bangladeshis," he has said in a post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Homes Stormed, Looted</strong></p>

<p>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council has told Reuters that 200-300 homes, mainly those owned by Hindus, and businesses had been targeted since Monday. About 15-20 Hindu temples had been vandalised and 40-odd people injured, though not seriously, the organisation's general secretary Rana Dasgupta said.</p>

<p>"The communal atrocities erupted hours before she resigned. Although there is no killing, there is injury. Houses and businesses of minorities, especially Hindus, as well as temples, have been targeted, looted, damaged," he said.</p>

<p>Dhaka-based development professional Avirup Sarkar has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy77vgmjlzo">told BBC</a> that his cousin lives in Netrokona, about 100 km from Dhaka. Hours after Sheikh Hasina fled the country, she called Mr Sarkar. "She sounded terrified. She said the house had been attacked and plundered by a mob," he has told BBC. Mr Sarkar's cousin told him that 100 people armed with sticks had stormed the house, smashed furniture, TV, bathroom fittings and doors. They had also taken cash and ornaments. They did not assault anyone in the house.</p>

<p>"You people are descendants of Awami League. This country is in a bad shape because of you. You should leave the country," the mob shouted at the residents, according to the BBC report.</p>

<p><strong>Journalists, Artists Targeted</strong></p>

<p>Pradip Kumar Bhowmik, a journalist with Daily Khoborpatra, died after being assaulted during a mob attack on Rayganj Press Club in Sirajganj, local media has reported. Three other journalists were injured. A total of 25 journalists were injured in incidents of assaults across the country, The Daily Star reported. Many of them are Muslims.</p>

<p>In Dhaka's Dhanmondi, a violent mob attacked Bangladeshi singer Rahul Ananda's ancestral house and burned his musical instruments and furniture. His family members managed to escape the attack. Folk band Joler Gaan, which Rahul Ananda sings for, has put up a video of their last recording in the now gutted room, and questioned the "fire of rage and revenge".</p>

<p><strong>Muslims Join Hindus In Guarding Temples</strong></p>

<p>Amid reports of minorities and temples being targeted, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/353914/temples-in-dhaka-being-guarded-by-students-and">Dhaka Tribune sent a correspondent to three temples</a> and found Hindus and Muslims guarding the places of worship. At Dhakeshwari National Temple, local resident Raj Ghosh said, "Both Muslim and Hindu neighbours are guarding to protect the temple. Some individuals have used this temple for their own benefit. We acknowledge their efforts in developing it, but they have forcibly removed us from the temple."</p>

<p>Ranjan Kumar Das, another resident, said, "There is fear that this temple could be targeted. Last night, some students and local Muslims were with us. They provided their contact details for help in case we were attacked. Our Muslim brothers who have stood beside us are setting an example."</p>

<p>At Ramna Kali Temple, Dhaka University student Rafid Azad is on guard. He said groups are taking turns to guard the temple. Asked who is behind the attacks on temples, he said, "We have seen examples of many countries where, when a regime fails, some people spot an opportunity. We can not say clearly who is attacking the temples. Whoever is behind this is doing a horrible thing."</p>

<p>He said the new government should ensure fundamental rights, including religion and freedom of speech. "Obviously, we do not want a bigoted government, we want a government for everyone."</p>

<p>At ISKCON Swamibag temple, there are no guards, but two posters read, "You are our brothers, do not fear" and "Bangladesh is for all of us". ISKCON member Durlav Harinam Das told Dhaka Tribune, "In this area, we have good relations with everyone, so there is no reason for fear."</p>

<p><strong>India Is Concerned</strong></p>

<p>The safety of minorities in Bangladesh is high on New Delhi's list of priorities, the government has said. Addressing the Parliament on the situation in the neighbouring country, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said India is "deeply concerned" over the situation in Bangladesh, especially about the minority community. "We are monitoring the situation with regard to the status of minorities. There are reports of initiatives by various groups and organisations to ensure their protection and well-being. We welcome that, but will naturally remain deeply concerned till law and order is visibly restored," he said.</p>

<p>The minister said New Delhi is in "close and continuous" touch with the Indian community in Bangladesh through diplomatic missions.</p>

<p>Also in focus is the safety of Indian nationals currently in Bangladesh. The minister said there are about 19,000 Indian nationals in Bangladesh, 9,000 of them students. Most students have returned after the students protests against Sheikh Hasina gathered steam. Many Indians are now returning. An Air India chartered flight brought back 205 Indians, including six infants, this morning.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/utc6dteg_hasina_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina quit as Bangladesh PM and fled the country amid violent protests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asif-merchant-who-is-asif-merchant-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-6281531]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Asif Merchant, Pak Man Arrested For Plot To Kill Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/asif-merchant-who-is-asif-merchant-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-6281531]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 10:24:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US has charged a Pakistani man, who allegedly has ties to Iran, with attempting to carry out assassinations of American politicians.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US has charged a Pakistani man, who allegedly has ties to Iran, with attempting to carry out <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-had-planned-protests-as-diversion-6280100">assassinations of American politicians</a>.</p>

<p>Federal prosecutors said Asif Merchant, 46, orchestrated a plot to kill an unidentified politician or US government officials on American soil.</p>

<p>This case has led the US government to increase security for former US President Donald Trump and other officials. While the criminal complaint does not mention Trump explicitly, multiple sources have told reporters that one of the intended targets of the alleged plot was Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Asif Merchant</strong></h3>

<p>Asif Merchant, also known as "Asif Raza Merchant", is a 46-year-old Pakistani national. He has two wives, one each in Pakistan and in Iran, as well as children in both countries.</p>

<p>According to his travel records, Asif frequently travels to Iran, Syria and Iraq, the US Justice Department said.</p>

<h3><strong>How Asif plotted</strong></h3>

<p>The court papers said the plot involved multiple elements - stealing documents or USB drives from a target's home; planning protests, and killing a politician or government official.</p>

<p>Asif Merchant made up code names for each element in the plot - "tee-shirt" for protests, "flannel shirt" for stealing documents, "fleece jacket" for the assassination, and "yarn-dye" for their meetings.</p>

<p>To entice the person he contacted first, who informed officials, Merchant told him he had an uncle in the "yarn-dyed" business in Pakistan and he could go into business with them.</p>

<p>For his plans, Asif Merchant hired people he thought were hitmen, but who were actually undercover agents. He asked one government source he believed was an assassin for hire to explain how "the target" would die in different scenarios.</p>

<h3><strong>How his plot failed</strong></h3>

<p>Asif Merchant's plot failed because he tried to recruit FBI agents for the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>He was arrested on July 12 as he was getting ready to catch a flight out of the country.</p>

<p>In mid-June, Merchant met with people he thought were hitmen. They were undercover US law enforcement officers (the UCs) in New York.</p>

<p>He told them he wanted them to steal documents, arrange protests at political rallies, and kill a "political person".</p>

<p>The plot would have to be carried out after he left the country, and they would be told who the target was either in the last week of August or the first week of September, Merchant told the undercover officers.</p>

<p>Merchant arranged to pay USD 5,000 in cash as an advance for the assassination services and successfully delivered this payment on June 21.</p>

<p>Following this transaction, he made plans to leave the country on July 12, 2024, one day before Donald Trump's assassination attempt. However, law enforcement intervened and arrested him before he could leave, the court document said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/urc6du9_asif-merchant_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Asif Merchant, also known as "Asif Raza Merchant", is a 46-year-old Pakistani national.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-you-be-my-running-mate-kamala-harris-request-to-tim-walz-over-the-phone-6281472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Let's Win This": How Kamala Harris Chose Tim Walz Over Phone Call]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-you-be-my-running-mate-kamala-harris-request-to-tim-walz-over-the-phone-6281472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 10:14:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tim Walz, 60, is a veteran of the Army National Guard and a former high school social studies teacher and football coach.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris has chosen Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate, a decision that came as a surprise to many.</p>

<p>With only 16 days to take a call on her potential Vice-President, Harris chose Walz, who was left off early lists of likely running mates.</p>

<p>Harris asked Walz to join her race to the White House during a phone conversation with him.</p>

<p>"Listen, I want you to do this with me," the Democratic nominee told the Governor. "Would you be my running mate?" she can be heard asking Walz&nbsp;in a video posted to her Instagram account.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-V0IwTp8ZY/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-V0IwTp8ZY/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-V0IwTp8ZY/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-V0IwTp8ZY/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Kamala Harris (@kamalaharris)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Tim Walz responded that he would be "honoured" to join the ticket.</p>

<p>"The joy that you are bringing back to the country, the enthusiasm that's out there, it'll be a privilege to take this with you across the country," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Walz, 60, is a veteran of the Army National Guard and a former high school social studies teacher and football coach. He was elected to Congress in 2006 and won six terms representing a rural area of Minnesota that typically leaned conservative.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris praised Walz for his dedication and service to the nation. "You understand our country, you have dedicated yourself to our country in so many different and beautiful ways," she said. "I have just the utmost respect for you."</p>

<p>As they concluded their telephonic conversation, Harris stressed their shared vision. "We're going to do this, we're going to win, and we're going to unify our country and remind everyone that we're fighting for the future."</p>

<p>"Let's do this. Let's win this thing," Walz echoed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Walz gained traction online with his folksy mannerisms and viral comments calling Republican nominee Donald Trump and his running mate, Ohio Senator JD Vance, "weird". His unconventional style, including fueling his campaign with Diet Mountain Dew, has made him a historic choice.</p>

<p>Soon after the official announcement was made, the Democratic Presidential candidate and her Vice Presidential pick made their first campaign stop in Philadelphia on Tuesday. The Democratic duo stood before a packed house at Temple University as the electric crowd of thousands exploded when the two walked out on stage together.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris' selection of Walz as her running mate has been a fundraising boon for the Democratic presidential ticket, raising more than $20 million since the announcement.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pn32afg8_kamala-harris-tim-walz_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris asked Tim Walz to join her race to the White House during a phone call with him.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-names-bald-eagle-as-national-bird-200-years-after-it-became-countrys-symbol-6281356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Names Bald Eagle As National Bird, 200 Years After It Became Its Symbol]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-names-bald-eagle-as-national-bird-200-years-after-it-became-countrys-symbol-6281356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 09:51:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The bald eagle was specifically chosen by America's Founding Fathers since it is a native of the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States Senate passed a bill that officially crowns the bald eagle as America's national bird, over 200 years after it became the symbol of the country. The raptor's status as an official emblem has been restored after the bill, proposed by Minnesota Democrat Amy Klobuchar, was approved by a unanimous vote, as per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/us-news/senate-finally-names-bald-eagle-the-official-national-bird-242-years-after-it-became-a-symbol-of-america/"><em>New York Post.</em></a></p>

<p>"For more than 240 years, the bald eagle has been synonymous with American values, yet it is still not officially our national bird," Senator Cynthia Lummis said in a<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.lummis.senate.gov/press-releases/lummis-mullin-legislation-to-make-the-bald-eagle-the-national-bird-passes-the-senate/"> press release</a> after the bill passed. "Today's bipartisan passage brings us one step closer to solidifying the eagle's place as an enduring symbol of our freedom, and I look forward to seeing this legislation pass the House and signed into law soon," it added.</p>

<p>Notably, the eagle has been used as a national symbol since the Roman era. The bird can be seen throughout the remnants of the destroyed empire, including on its infamous 'SPQR' governmental seal.</p>

<p>The bald eagle was specifically chosen by America's Founding Fathers since it is a native of the region. Although some have migrated a little further beyond the borders, the bird primarily lives and breeds in the United States, with a few living in Canada and Mexico, according to the National Park Services.</p>

<p>Although the bald eagle was never officially recognised as the official bird, its status as one of the country's most recognizable symbols was cemented in 1782 when it was added to the seal of the independent United States. According to the National Museum of American Diplomacy, it wasn't even the first animal to be considered for inclusion. It took the place of a simple, white eagle that was originally intended to be on the seal.</p>

<p>Several committees tried and failed to create the seal before giving the job to Charles Thomson, then the Secretary of Congress.&nbsp;He then combined the work of all three committees, which was adopted in June 1782 by the Continental Congress, making it the Great Seal of the United States. However, the Founding Fathers had bigger problems at hand in the wake of the American Revolution. Eventually, the idea was shelved and its legal status was lost in discussions.</p>

<p>Uncertainty surrounding bald eagle sightings during the 20th century further increased people's curiosity about the bird. Since they were seen as a national symbol, they were hunted excessively. This led to the introduction of the Bald Eagle Protection Act, which forbade their shooting or sale in 1940, contributing to the population's stabilization.</p>

<p>However, many American farms started using dichlorodiphenyltrichloroethane or DDT, after World War II to keep invading insects away. The chemical's runoff destroyed the local fish populations in water bodies, which were the bald eagle's main source of food. The majority of the bald eagles that consumed these poisoned fish became sterile. According to the National Wildlife Federation, a small percentage of the birds were still able to reproduce, but their eggs were too weak and frequently smashed when the birds attempted to nest.</p>

<p>Six years after DDT was outlawed, in 1978, the bird was listed as endangered. Further, several conservation and breeding initiatives, along with rigorous adherence to the 1940 protection statute, enabled them to be ultimately taken off the list in 2007 and they are thriving to this day.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/917o36no_bald-eagle_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 1978, the bird was listed as endangered.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-major-interview-with-elon-musk-ahead-of-us-presidential-elections-2024-6281316]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Announces "Major" Interview With Elon Musk Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-announces-major-interview-with-elon-musk-ahead-of-us-presidential-elections-2024-6281316]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 09:47:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk had last month endorsed Donald Trump's presidential candidacy after he was injured in an attempted assassination in Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump has announced that he will be interviewed by billionaire CEO and entrepreneur Elon Musk next week.</p>

<p>"On Monday night I'll be doing a major interview with Elon Musk," the former president wrote on his Truth Social media platform. "Details to follow," Trump added, as reported by US publications including The Hill newspaper.</p>

<p>The Republican presidential nominee was recently interviewed at his Mar-a-Lago residence by live streamer Adin Ross.</p>

<p>Trump noted that the interview with Ross helped the streaming platform 'Kick' break its viewing record.</p>

<p>Last month, Musk, who owns the social media platform X, endorsed Trump's candidacy after the former president was injured in an attempted assassination in Pennsylvania. This endorsement marked a departure from the usual self-declared neutrality maintained by social media platform leaders, as reported by The New York Times.</p>

<p>Following the January 6, 2021, attack on Capitol Hill, Trump's account was permanently suspended by Twitter (now X) under its previous ownership. However, under Musk's ownership, the account was reinstated.</p>

<p>According to a Wall Street Journal report, Musk, who also owns SpaceX and Tesla, pledged USD 45 million per month to a new political action committee backing Trump. The America PAC will primarily focus on voter outreach and registration efforts to counter the Democrats' traditionally strong campaigns.</p>

<p>Trump's planned talk with Musk comes after Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris selected Minnesota Governor Tim Walz as her running mate.</p>

<p>On August 4, The Washington Post reported that five secretaries of state planned to send an open letter to Musk on Monday, urging him to "immediately implement changes" to X's AI chatbot Grok, after it shared false information suggesting that Kamala Harris was not eligible to appear on the 2024 presidential ballot. The letter, spearheaded by Minnesota Secretary of State Steve Simon and signed by his counterparts Al Schmidt of Pennsylvania, Steve Hobbs of Washington, Jocelyn Benson of Michigan, and Maggie Toulouse Oliver of New Mexico, urges Musk to ensure voters have accurate information in this critical election year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rp6rg4v_elon-musk-donald-trump_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-man-enslaved-for-26-years-in-filthy-caravan-to-receive-rs-12-crore-compensation-6280965]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Man Enslaved For 26 Years In Filthy Caravan To Receive Rs 3.75 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-man-enslaved-for-26-years-in-filthy-caravan-to-receive-rs-12-crore-compensation-6280965]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 08:22:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Rooney family exploited homeless men for over two decades, resulting in 15 deaths. In 2017, 11 family members were imprisoned for 79 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man has been awarded 352,000 pounds (Rs 3.75 crore approx), as compensation for being held captive and enslaved by a wealthy family, the Rooneys, for over two decades, according to <em>The Metro</em>. The victim, known only as 'Victim A', was subjected to unimaginable cruelty, forced to live in squalid caravans on the family's traveller site in Lincolnshire.</p>

<p>The Rooney family is alleged to have been running a regime of terror for over twenty years, exploiting vulnerable homeless men. Some were brutally pounded while being made to work for little or no wages, accommodated in pathetic conditions where their basic requirements remained neglected. Some were even told that they would be killed if they refused to comply with their demands.</p>

<p>According to the<em> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/06/inside-filthy-caravan-man-kept-a-slave-fed-scraps-26-years-21372295/?ico=mosaic_home">News Outlet,</a> </em>Photographs of the caravans show a shocking image of privation with dirty beds, no food, and unsanitary conditions. Moreover, the captors also frequently fed the victims with scraps and treated them in contempt.</p>

<p>Fifteen other men who shared that fate ended up dying before justice could be served. During this, the Rooney family had amassed a fortune of more than 1.5 million pounds while their victims were enduring unimaginable suffering.</p>

<p>In 2017, eleven members of this family were imprisoned for combined 79 years for their crimes. Their heinous acts still lead to devastating consequences in the lives of those victims.</p>

<p>The 352,000 pounds compensation to be paid to Victim A will go some way toward underpinning his financial security, enabling him to receive the necessary care. This, however, cannot in any way be held to remove the years of torment they all suffered at the hands of their captors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/obcbc1o8_caravan_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The victim endured brutal conditions and extreme deprivation. (Representative Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/serena-williams-says-she-was-denied-access-to-paris-restaurant-staff-explains-incident-6280837]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Serena Williams Says Paris Restaurant Denied Entry, Staff Explains Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/serena-williams-says-she-was-denied-access-to-paris-restaurant-staff-explains-incident-6280837]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:47:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The restaurant said, "We do always try to make space for walk-in guests but sometimes this is not possible."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Serena Williams has criticised a Michelin-starred restaurant in Paris, alleging that she was not allowed to enter with her children. The Olympian said she and her family were not permitted to enter The Peninsula's rooftop restaurant, L'Oiseau Blanc, in a post published on X (formerly Twitter). Ms Williams wrote in the post that she had never been refused entry while her family was there.</p>

<p>"Yikes @peninsulaparis I've been denied access to the rooftop to eat in a empty restaurant of nicer places but never with my kids. Always a first. #Olympic2024," she said on the microblogging website.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yikes <a href="https://twitter.com/peninsulaparis?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@peninsulaparis</a> I've been denied access to rooftop to eat in a empty restaurant of nicer places ? but never with my kids. Always a first. ?<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Olympic2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Olympic2024</a> <a href="https://t.co/lEGJR5WoEn">pic.twitter.com/lEGJR5WoEn</a></p>
— Serena Williams (@serenawilliams) <a href="https://twitter.com/serenawilliams/status/1820507655250850058?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Maxime Mannevy, a staff member at the Peninsula's rooftop restaurant, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://variety.com/2024/tv/news/serena-williams-slams-paris-restaurant-olympics-1236095987/"><em>Variety </em></a>that Ms Williams appeared "unrecognizable" when she arrived pushing a stroller alongside another lady. "When she came there were only two tables available and they had been reserved by clients of the hotel," she said, adding that she was not working when Ms Williams visited the restaurant.</p>

<p>"My colleague didn't recognize her and feels terrible, but he told her what he would have told any other client, which is to wait downstairs in the bar for a table to become available. That was absolutely nothing personal."</p>

<p>The restaurant reacted to the Grand Slam champion's claim, with employees reiterating their reasons for turning away Ms Williams and her children from a table. "In response to Ms Williams' tweet, for whom we have the utmost admiration and respect, as we do for all our esteemed guests, we reiterate our deepest apologies that we were not able to offer her a table at our rooftop bar when she arrived with her family and without a reservation," the hotel said in a statement to the <em>New York Post.</em></p>

<p>They said, "We do always try to make space for walk-in guests but sometimes this is not possible."</p>

<p>"On August 5th, our rooftop bar was indeed fully booked, and the only unoccupied tables at that time belonged to our gourmet restaurant, L'Oiseau Blanc, which was also fully reserved. As an alternative, Ms Williams was offered an outside table downstairs at the hotel's La Terrasse Kl&amp;#233;ber. We have always been honored to welcome you and will always be to welcome you again," the statement added.</p>

<p>The 23-time Grand Slam champion initially came to Paris in late July, just in time for the "unforgettable" Olympic opening ceremony, which she attended as a torch bearer. Along with fellow tennis champion Rafael Nadal, nine-time medallist Carl Lewis, French greats Zinedine Zidane, Teddy Riner, Marie-Jose Perec, and Tony Parker, Ms Williams joined a long tradition of athletes carrying the torch. She has also won four Olympic gold medals over the course of her career.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k4d8hm1g_serena-williams-_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The restaurant reacted to the Grand Slam champion's claim.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-had-planned-protests-as-diversion-6280100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Man Arrested For Plot To Kill Trump, Had Planned Protests As Diversion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-man-arrested-for-plot-to-kill-donald-trump-had-planned-protests-as-diversion-6280100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:43:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani citizen has been charged in an elaborate plot that reads like a spy thriller to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani citizen has been charged in an elaborate plot that reads like a spy thriller to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p>US Attorney General Merrick Garland, who announced the charges against Asif Merchant on Tuesday, indicated that the target was Trump, but did not name him.</p>

<p>"For years, the Justice Department has been working aggressively to counter Iran's brazen and unrelenting efforts to retaliate against American public officials for the killing of Iranian General Qassem Soleimani," he said.</p>

<p>Trump was the US President who ordered the killing of Iranian Major General Qassem Soleimani in Baghdad in 2020, which points the assassination plot towards Trump.</p>

<p>According to court documents, others may also have been intended victims because of the mention of targets in the plural.</p>

<p>Federal Bureau of Investigation(FBI) Chief Christopher Wray said, "This dangerous murder-for-hire plot exposed in today's charges allegedly was orchestrated by a Pakistani national with close ties to Iran and is straight out of the Iranian playbook."</p>

<p>The alleged plotter, who is also known as Asif Raza Merchant, told officials that he has two wives, one each in Pakistan and in Iran, as well as children in both countries.</p>

<p>In the complaint filed in the Federal court in Brooklyn, the plot reads like a spy thriller with an elaborate scheme to burglarise the home of a target, creating diversions with protests and rallies, and killing the politician.</p>

<p>It also included a show of bonding between Merchant, 46, and the undercover officers he thought were professional killers.</p>

<p>The court papers said the plot involved multiple elements: stealing documents or USB drives from a target's home; planning protests, and killing a politician or government official.</p>

<p>Merchant made up code names for each element in the plot: "tee-shirt" for protests, "flannel shirt" for stealing documents, "fleece jacket" for the assassination, and "yarn-dye" for their meetings.</p>

<p>To entice the person he contacted first and who informed officials, Merchant told him that he has an uncle in the "yarn-dyed" business in Pakistan and he could go into business with them.</p>

<p>He asked the government source he thought was an assassin for hire to explain how the target would die in different scenarios.</p>

<p>The revelation about this plot comes less than a month after the July 13 failed assassination attempt on Trump in Butler, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>However, there does not seem to be a connection between the plot by Merchant and that attempt, which officials have said was carried out by a lone wolf, a person unconnected to any group or organisation.</p>

<p>The plot failed because Merchant tried to recruit FBI agents for the assassination attempt.</p>

<p>"Fortunately, the assassins Merchant tried to hire were undercover FBI agents," said Christie Curtis, the Acting Assistant Director of the New York FBI Field Office.</p>

<p>He was arrested on July 12 as he was getting ready to catch a flight out of the country.</p>

<p>Merchant arrived in the US in April from Pakistan after spending time in Iran, according to the version of the plot in court papers.</p>

<p>He contacted a person he thought could help him and that person reported it to law enforcement and became a confidential source.</p>

<p>In mid-June, Merchant met with people he thought were hitmen, but were undercover US law enforcement officers (the UCs) in New York.</p>

<p>He told them he wanted them to steal documents, arrange protests at political rallies, and kill a "political person".</p>

<p>The plot would have to be carried out after he left the country and in either the last week of August or the first week of September they would be told who the target was, Merchant told the undercover officers.</p>

<p>He received $5,000 from overseas and made a down payment to the undercover agents.</p>

<p>According to the court papers, one of the agents said after getting the money, "Now we know we're going forward. We're doing this," to which Merchant responded: "Yes, absolutely."</p>

<p>Political violence is a constant worry in the US.</p>

<p>Last week, a man was arrested in Virginia for allegedly threatening to kill the Democratic Party presidential nominee Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris needs to be put on fire alive. I will do it personally if no one else does... I want her to suffer a slow agonising death," Frank Lucio Carillo posted on a right-wing social media site, according to the FBI complaint in a Federal court.</p>

<p>He also allegedly threatened President Joe Biden and FBI Chief Wray.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/3jt8ehu_donald-trump-afp-_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Asif Merchant received $5,000 from overseas and made a down payment to the undercover agents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resignation-bangladesh-violence-muhammad-yunus-nobel-laureate-to-lead-bangladeshs-army-backed-interim-government-6280806]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate To Lead Bangladesh's Army-Backed Interim Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-sheikh-hasina-resignation-bangladesh-violence-muhammad-yunus-nobel-laureate-to-lead-bangladeshs-army-backed-interim-government-6280806]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:39:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been named the head of the military-backed interim government after the ouster of Sheikh Hasina amid massive protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>Student leaders whose protest campaign culminated in Ms Hasina's ouster met with Army Chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman and President Mohammed Shahabuddin late last evening, and the decision was taken to "to form an interim government with Muhammad Yunus as its chief," the President's office announced.</li>
	<li>The Bangladeshi Army has reshuffled several generals, demoting some seen as close to Sheikh Hasina, and sacking Ziaul Ahsan, a commander of the feared Rapid Action Battalion paramilitary force. Former Prime Minister and BNP chairperson Khaleda Zia, 78, was also released from years of house arrest yesterday.</li>
	<li>Rights groups have alleged that hundreds of Hindu houses, businesses and temples have been vandalised since the fall of Sheikh Hasina government.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina, 76, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-named-chief-adviser-of-interim-government-6280732">was forced to resign as Prime Minister Monday</a> evening after weeks-long protests over a jobs quota killed over 400 people. She fled Dhaka reportedly after the Bangladesh Army gave her a 45-minute ultimatum.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon airbase, near Delhi, on Monday in a Bangladesh military aircraft and is unlikely to move out of India for the next couple of days, people familiar with the matter said.</li>
	<li>Sources had said she wanted to go to London to claim sanctuary,&nbsp;but her son Sajeeb Wazed has dismissed the speculation. Asked about multiple reports about UK's "silence" her request for asylum and revocation of her visa by the US, Mr Wazed said, "The reports about her requesting asylum are incorrect. She has not requested asylum anywhere. So the question of UK or US not responding yet is not true".</li>
	<li>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said the government is giving time to Sheikh Hasina to "recover" and let them know about her next move. "At very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India. We simultaneously received a request for flight clearance from the Bangladesh authorities," he said.</li>
	<li>Mr Jaishankar also briefed the leaders of all parties about the situation in the violence-hit nation and the steps taken by the Indian government to address the potential security, economic, and diplomatic repercussions of this situation.</li>
	<li>He said that the government is in touch with the Bangladeshi Army to ensure the safety of Indian nationals and the minorities in Bangladesh amid violence.</li>
	<li>The anti-government rallies that began in June against civil service job quotas escalated into some of the worst unrest of Sheikh Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/o11iaaio_bangladesh_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Violence: Muhammad Yunus is 84 years old]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blames-delta-for-its-struggle-to-recover-from-global-outage-6278497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Blames Delta For Its Struggle To Recover From Global Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blames-delta-for-its-struggle-to-recover-from-global-outage-6278497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft blamed Delta Air Lines on Tuesday for its dayslong struggle to recover from a global cyber outage that led it to cancel more than 6,000 flights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft blamed Delta Air Lines on Tuesday for its dayslong struggle to recover from a global cyber outage that led it to cancel more than 6,000 flights.</p>

<p>A software update last month by global cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike triggered system problems for Microsoft customers, including many airlines. But disruptions subsided the next day at other major U.S. carriers while persisting at Delta.</p>

<p>Microsoft said its preliminary review suggested that Delta, unlike its competitors, apparently had not modernized its IT infrastructure.</p>

<p>Delta, however, said it has invested billions of dollars in IT capital expenditures since 2016, in addition to the billions it spends every year in IT operating costs.</p>

<p>"Delta has a long track record of investing in safe, reliable and elevated service for our customers and employees," a company spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The flight disruptions stranded hundreds of thousands of travelers and are estimated to cost the Atlanta-based airline $500 million. Delta is also facing an investigation from the U.S. Transportation Department for the disruptions.</p>

<p>It has hired prominent litigator David Boies of Boies Schiller Flexner, known for high-stakes business cases, to seek damages from both CrowdStrike and Microsoft.</p>

<p>Last week, Delta's CEO Ed Bastian told CNBC that while the airline heavily relies on the two tech companies, they had failed to deliver an "exceptional service." In the interview, he also said that Microsoft had the "most fragile platform."</p>

<p>In a letter, Mark Cheffo, a lawyer for Microsoft, called the airline's comments "incomplete, false, misleading, and damaging to Microsoft and its reputation."</p>

<p>Cheffo said Microsoft's software had not caused the CrowdStrike incident, but the tech giant immediately offered to assist Delta at no charge. Its CEO Satya Nadella emailed Bastian, but never got a reply, he added.</p>

<p>Microsoft said its employees repeatedly offered to help Delta following the outage, but the U.S. carrier turned them down. It accused the airline of using services of other technology providers for its crew-tracking and scheduling system and alleged it as a likely reason for declining its help.</p>

<p>Cheffo said Microsoft will "vigorously" defend itself if Delta files a lawsuit.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike has also rejected Delta's claim that it should be blamed for flight disruptions. The cybersecurity firm said its CEO had personally reached out to Bastian to offer onsite assistance, but received no response.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qeogglgg_delta-airlines-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Delta said it has invested billions of dollars in IT capital expenditures since 2016.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-named-chief-adviser-of-interim-government-6280732]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[20 Leaders Of Sheikh Hasina's Party Found Dead In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-named-chief-adviser-of-interim-government-6280732]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:19:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize laureate Muhammad Yunus was named chief adviser of Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday, a day after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following a violent crackdown on a student-led uprising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Peace Prize laureate Muhammad Yunus was named chief adviser of Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday, a day after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following a violent crackdown on a student-led uprising.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus was appointed to the post by Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin after he held meetings with student leaders and chiefs of the three military services, local media reported late on Tuesday, citing a statement and officials from the president's office.</p>

<p>Student protesters had threatened more demonstrations if parliament was not dissolved.</p>

<p>The movement that toppled Hasina rose out of demonstrations against public sector job quotas for families of veterans of Bangladesh's 1971 independence war, seen by critics as a means to reserve jobs for allies of the ruling party.</p>

<p>About 300 people were killed and thousands injured in violence that had ripped through the country since July.</p>

<h3><strong>Here are the LIVE updates on Bangladesh unrest:</strong><br />
&nbsp;</h3>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n344til8_bangladesh-parliament-unrest-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest Updates: About 300 people were killed and thousands injured in violence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-after-shunning-politics-6280701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Poor Man's Banker To Leading Bangladesh: Muhammad Yunus's Journey]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-after-shunning-politics-6280701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 07:09:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh is pinning its hopes on one of the nation's most acclaimed intellectuals to bring stability to a country scarred by coups and political upheaval.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh is pinning its hopes on one of the nation's most acclaimed intellectuals to bring stability to a country scarred by coups and political upheaval.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus, whose work alleviating poverty won him a Nobel Peace Prize, was named the head of a new interim government on Tuesday following the sudden ouster of Sheikh Hasina as prime minister this week. Though he's mostly stayed away from politics, Yunus is one of Bangladesh's most famous faces and brings considerable clout with Western elites.</p>

<p>Restoring normalcy to Bangladesh won't be a small feat for Yunus. Over the past few weeks, clashes between protesters and security personnel cost the lives of more than 300 people, one of the worst outbreaks of violence in the South Asian nation's history. And while Hasina lifted millions out of poverty through garment exports, economic growth has lately stalled in Bangladesh, prompting the International Monetary Fund to step in with bailout funds.</p>

<p>The military-backed appointment of Yunus to temporarily lead Bangladesh is a remarkable turn of events for the economist. Over the past couple of years, Yunus has spent much of his time inside Dhaka's courtrooms, fighting about 200 charges against him and his associates, including allegations of money laundering and graft. He and his supporters say Hasina's government was behind the legal pressure and perhaps saw him as a threat to her power. She denied those accusations.</p>

<p>Yunus, 84, is best known for founding Grameen Bank and pioneering microcredit - providing tiny business loans to the world's poorest people, most of them women. Though he's spent much of his life in the public eye, politics is largely unexplored terrain. In 2007, the Bangladeshi government splintered, and the military seized power. Yunus, who'd never run for office, considered forming a new party to fill the vacuum, but ultimately scrapped the idea within a few weeks.</p>

<p>"I feel very uncomfortable with politics," he said in an interview earlier this year.</p>

<p>Yunus brings star power to the role and is a popular choice with many Western governments. His supporters span industries and continents. Over the years, he's cultivated friendships with European royals, business titans like Richard Branson and the Clintons, who helped Yunus expand his microcredit initiatives to the US. His friends say he's a rare visionary with a genuine commitment to Bangladesh and uplifting the poor.</p>

<p>"He is the voice of the people left behind," said Paul Polman, a former chief executive of Unilever Plc and a close friend. "He's a moral leader. He's not somebody who likes to talk about himself. He likes to talk about the people he serves."</p>

<p>That reputation has endeared him to many in Bangladesh, including the military, which had previously supported his first foray into politics. After winning the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006, thousands of Bangladeshis crowded venues just to hear him speak. Many still bow and touch their hearts when they see him. Over the past decade, Yunus has focused on expanding dozens of social businesses, including ones that offer free health care, vocational training and phone services to poorer Bangladeshis.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4dhpif0g_muhammad-yunus-bloomberg_625x300_07_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Muhammad Yunus in his office in Dhaka.<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Bloomberg</span></p>
</div>

<p>Whether Yunus pivots more deliberately into politics - or simply fills a hole before elections are held - remains unclear. As protesters swarmed Dhaka's streets in recent weeks, Yunus spoke out publicly against the violence and characterized Hasina's crackdown as a threat to democracy - but he made no mention of ambitions to take a more formal role in shaping a new government.</p>

<p>"I'm not a politician," he said in the interview earlier this year. "This is the last thing I will ever do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b23juut8_muhammad-yunus-bloomberg_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus is one of Bangladesh's most famous faces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-antitrust-ruling-may-pose-20-billion-risk-for-apple-report-6280471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Antitrust Ruling May Pose $20 Billion Risk For Apple: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-antitrust-ruling-may-pose-20-billion-risk-for-apple-report-6280471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:47:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Apple's lucrative deal with Google could be under threat after a U.S. judge ruled that the Alphabet-owned search giant was operating an illegal monopoly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple's lucrative deal with Google could be under threat after a U.S. judge ruled that the Alphabet-owned search giant was operating an illegal monopoly.</p>

<p>A potential remedy for Google to avoid antitrust actions could involve terminating the agreement, which makes its search engine a default on Apple devices, Wall Street analysts said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Google pays Apple $20 billion annually, or about 36% of what it earns from search advertising made through the Safari browser, for the privilege, according to Morgan Stanley analysts.</p>

<p>If the deal is undone, the iPhone maker could take a 4-6% hit to its profit, the analysts estimated.</p>

<p>The pact runs until at least September 2026 and Apple has the right to unilaterally extend it for another two years, according to media reports in May that cited a document filed by the Department of Justice in the antitrust case.</p>

<p>"The most likely outcome now is the judge rules Google must no longer pay for default placement or that companies like Apple must proactively prompt users to select their search engine rather than setting a default and allowing consumers to make changes in settings if they wish," Evercore ISI analysts said.</p>

<p>Apple's shares were trading flat on Tuesday, underperforming a recovery in the broader market after Monday's global selloff. Alphabet was little changed, after falling 4.5% in the previous session.</p>

<p>"The message here is that if you've got a dominant market position with a product, you'd better avoid the use of exclusive agreements and make sure any agreement you make gives the buyer free choice to substitute away," said Herbert Hovenkamp, a professor of law at the University of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>To be sure, the "remedy" phase could be lengthy, followed by potential appeals to the U.S. Court of Appeals, the District of Columbia Circuit and the U.S. Supreme Court. The legal wrangling could play out into 2026.</p>

<p><strong>AI TILT</strong></p>

<p>Still, if the tie-up is scrapped, Apple will have several options including offering customers alternatives such as Microsoft Bing to customers, or potentially a new search product powered by OpenAI.</p>

<p>Analysts agree that the ruling will speed up Apple's move towards AI-powered search services. It recently announced that it would bring OpenAI's ChatGPT chatbot to its devices.</p>

<p>In a shift away from exclusive deals that would help Apple ward off regulatory scrutiny, the company has said it is also in talks with Google to add the Gemini chatbot and plans to add other AI models as well.</p>

<p>Apple is also revamping Siri with AI technology, giving it more control to handle tasks that had proven tricky in the past such as writing emails and interacting with messages.</p>

<p>While those efforts are expected to make little money in the coming years, they could help capitalize on the new technology.</p>

<p>"Apple could see this as a temporary setback, especially since it earns a lot from the Google search deal, but it is also an opportunity for them to pivot to AI solutions for search," said Gadjo Sevilla, analyst at Emarketer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-01/ahh14fto_google-apple-logo-reuters_625x300_28_January_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If the deal is undone, the iPhone maker could take a 4-6% hit to its profit, the analysts estimated.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-calls-to-swiftly-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-6280440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Calls To "Swiftly Eliminate" New Hamas Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-calls-to-swiftly-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-6280440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:32:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar, who was appointed by Hamas as the group's new political leader replacing Ismail Haniyeh who was killed in Tehran last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar, who was appointed by Hamas as the group's new political leader replacing Ismail Haniyeh who was killed in Tehran last week.</p>

<p>"The appointment of arch-terrorist Yahya Sinwar as the new leader of Hamas, replacing Ismail Haniyeh, is yet another compelling reason to swiftly eliminate him and wipe this vile organisation off the face of the Earth," Foreign Minister Israel Katz said in a statement on social media site X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n6di67mg_israel-katz_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's foreign minister called on Tuesday to "swiftly eliminate" Yahya Sinwar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-advertisers-over-boycott-6280356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now It Is War": Elon Musk's X Sues Advertisers Over Boycott]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-sues-advertisers-over-boycott-6280356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 05:01:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X sued an advertising group and several large corporations on Tuesday accusing them of causing billions of dollars of losses by "illegally" boycotting the social media platform.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X sued an advertising group and several large corporations on Tuesday accusing them of causing billions of dollars of losses by "illegally" boycotting the social media platform.</p>

<p>"We tried peace for 2 years, now it is war," the billionaire founder of Tesla and SpaceX said on X, which he acquired in late 2022.</p>

<p>The antitrust suit, filed in a federal court in Texas, targets the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA), Unilever, Mars, CVS Health and Orsted, a Danish energy company.</p>

<p>It accuses WFA, through an initiative known as the Global Alliance for Responsible Media (GARM), of conspiring with the companies and others to "collectively withhold billions of dollars in advertising revenue" from X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<p>A number of advertisers left Twitter following Musk's takeover amid concerns about the level of content moderation under the new ownership and Musk's own controversial musings on the site.</p>

<p>X CEO Linda Yaccarino, in a video posted on the platform on Tuesday, said X was the victim of a "systematic illegal boycott."</p>

<p>"They conspired to boycott X which threatens our ability to thrive in the future," Yaccarino said. "No small group of people should be able to monopolize what gets monetized."</p>

<p>X is seeking a jury trial and unspecified damages.</p>

<p>According to The New York Times, citing internal company documents, X earned $114 million in revenue in the United States in the second quarter of this year, down 25 percent from the first quarter and down 53 percent from the same period last year. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The lawsuit was filed one day after Musk filed suit in California against OpenAI, accusing its co-founders Sam Altman and Greg Brockman of betraying the artificial intelligence company's founding mission.</p>

<p>Musk invested in the San Francisco-based OpenAI in 2015 but left three years later.</p>

<p>He is accusing OpenAI, Altman and Brockman of fraud, conspiracy and false advertising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8trrs42_elon-musk_625x300_15_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We tried peace for 2 years, now it is war," X CEO Elon Musk said in a post.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deeply-concerned-about-reports-of-violence-in-bangladesh-us-6280301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Deeply Concerned About Reports Of Violence In Bangladesh: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/deeply-concerned-about-reports-of-violence-in-bangladesh-us-6280301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 04:42:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has expressed deep concerns about the continued violence in Bangladesh including attacks on members of religious or political groups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The United States has expressed deep concerns about the continued violence in Bangladesh including attacks on members of religious or political groups.</p>

<p>"We are deeply concerned about continued reports of violence in Bangladesh - including violence directed at members of religious or political groups. We are equally concerned about reports of violence against police and law enforcement," a State Department spokesperson told PTI on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"We repeat our call for de-escalation on all sides and a return to calm. This is not a time for retribution or revenge," the spokesperson said in response to a question. "As a friend and partner to the Bangladeshi people, the United States will continue to support Bangladesh's democratic aspirations and promote respect for human rights for all," said the spokesperson.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is going through an unprecedented crisis with Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, who was in power for 15 years, resigning and fleeing the country after a protest against a jobs quota scheme snowballed into a massive agitation against her and her government. More than 300 people have died during the past few tumultuous weeks.</p>

<p>The Hindu American Foundation (HAF) said reports about such incidents including ransacking, and in some cases burning, of Hindu temples have come from across Bangladesh.</p>

<p>While the full extent to which religious minorities are being targeted in this greater unrest is not yet fully clear, the picture is deeply concerning, the HAF said in a statement.</p>

<p>"These attacks are heartbreaking, but unsurprising. It is well documented that prior to the toppling of Sheikh Hasina's government, Bangladesh's Hindu population has been targeted and harassed in sections of the country for many years now," HAF director of Policy Research Anita Joshi said.</p>

<p>"The Bangladesh military is reportedly forming an interim government, and so we urge local law enforcement and military leadership to ensure the safety of all Bangladesh's religious minorities, protecting their homes, business, and places of worship in this moment of turmoil," Mr Joshi said.</p>

<p>"The HAF has also called on the US State Department to work with Bangladesh's military leaders and interim government to immediately protect religious minorities from violence as the country seeks to restore order," Mr Joshi said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8qd6fj9g_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Unrest: More than 300 people have died during the past few tumultuous weeks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-tolerate-attacks-on-troops-in-middle-east-warns-us-6280240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Not Tolerate" Attacks On Troops In Middle East, Warns US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-not-tolerate-attacks-on-troops-in-middle-east-warns-us-6280240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 04:29:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States will not tolerate attacks on American troops in the Middle East, Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said Tuesday, after rocket fire in Iraq wounded seven US per]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States will not tolerate attacks on American troops in the Middle East, Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin said Tuesday, after rocket fire in Iraq wounded seven US personnel.</p>

<p>The Monday attack was the third in just over three weeks on Ain al-Assad base in western Iraq, which hosts American troops as well as other personnel from the US-led coalition against the Islamic State jihadist group.</p>

<p>"Make no mistake, the United States will not tolerate attacks on our personnel in the region," Austin told a news conference in Annapolis.</p>

<p>A US defense official said earlier in the day that the attack wounded five American military personnel and two contractors, all of whom are in stable condition.</p>

<p>A Pentagon statement on a call between Austin and his Israeli counterpart Yoav Gallant described the rocket fire as an "Iran-aligned militia attack on US forces" and said the two agreed that it "marked a dangerous escalation."</p>

<p>Such attacks were frequent early in the war between Israel and Hamas Palestinian militants in Gaza, but until recently had largely halted.</p>

<p>The latest rocket fire comes as fears grow of an attack by Iran and its allies on Israel in retaliation for the killing of top Hamas and Hezbollah figures in strikes either blamed on or claimed by Israel.</p>

<p>The killings are among the most serious series of tit-for-tat attacks that have heightened fears of a regional conflagration stemming from the Gaza war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/bu1pmqlg_lloyd-austin_625x300_23_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin warned Tuesday after seven troops injured in rocket attack in Iraq.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>