<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:02:33 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ready-to-work-with-bangladesh-interim-government-6288190]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ready To Work With Bangladesh Interim Government, Says US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ready-to-work-with-bangladesh-interim-government-6288190]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:02:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States Wednesday said it is ready to work with the interim government of Bangladesh as the country charts a democratic future for its people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States Wednesday said it is ready to work with the interim government of Bangladesh as the country charts a democratic future for its people.</p>

<p>"We continue to monitor developments in Bangladesh, and we obviously have seen the appointment of Muhammad Yunus as the leader of an interim government," State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters at his daily news conference.</p>

<p>"We think the interim government will play a vital role in establishing long-term peace and political stability in Bangladesh," Miller said responding to questions on the fast-moving development in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>A State Department spokesperson, meanwhile, told PTI, "All decisions regarding the interim government should respect democratic principles, rule of law, and the will of the Bangladeshi people." "We understand Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus has agreed to lead Bangladesh's interim government. We stand ready to work with the interim government, as it charts a democratic future for the people of Bangladesh," the spokesperson said in response to a question.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Mohammad Yunus is set to take oath as the head of Bangladesh's interim government on Thursday, as he made a fervent appeal to everyone to stay calm and "refrain from all kinds of violence" to make the best use of "our new victory".</p>

<p>As authorities scrambled to bring the law and order situation under control, Army chief Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman on Wednesday announced that the interim government will take oath around 8 pm on Thursday. He said the advisory council may have 15 members.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/i0j7i4ug_matthew-miller_625x300_07_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US official said that all decisions regarding the interim government should respect democratic rules.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swifts-vienna-shows-cancelled-after-alleged-terror-attack-threat-6288136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift's Vienna Shows Cancelled After Alleged Terror Attack Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swifts-vienna-shows-cancelled-after-alleged-terror-attack-threat-6288136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 03:43:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Vienna leg of a tour by American mega-star Taylor Swift has been cancelled after Austria arrested a man in connection with an Islamist attack plot, the organisers said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Vienna leg of a tour by American mega-star Taylor Swift has been cancelled after Austria arrested a man in connection with an Islamist attack plot, the organisers said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Authorities had earlier confirmed the arrest of a 19-year-old Islamic State (IS) group sympathiser for allegedly planning an Islamist attack in the Vienna region, warning he had a "focus" on Swift's three upcoming shows.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"With confirmation from government officials of a planned terrorist attack at Ernst Happel Stadium, we have no choice but to cancel the three scheduled shows for everyone's safety," Barracuda Music said on Instagram.</p>

<p>The organisers added that all would-be concert-goers would have their tickets refunded. About 65,000 spectators were expected at each show scheduled for Thursday, Friday and Saturday.</p>

<p>The man, who had pledged his allegiance to IS "in recent weeks", was detained in Lower Austria about an hour from the capital early on Wednesday, Austria's top security chief Franz Ruf told a press conference.</p>

<p>"We have established corresponding preparatory acts and also that there is a focus of the 19-year-old perpetrator on the Taylor Swift concerts in Vienna," Ruf said.</p>

<p>He said that chemical substances had been seized at the suspect's home.</p>

<p>A second person believed to have been in contact with the suspect was arrested in Vienna.</p>

<p>According to initial investigation findings, both suspects radicalised themselves on the internet.</p>

<p>In November 2020, a convicted IS sympathiser went on a shooting rampage in downtown Vienna, killing four and wounding 23 others before police shot him dead.</p>

<p>It marked the Alpine nation's first deadly jihadist attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7kupi45g_taylor-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift's three concerts in Vienna have been cancelled over suspect terror attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-raises-concerns-over-peaceful-transfer-of-power-after-november-elections-6288048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If Trump Loses...": Biden Raises Concerns Over Peaceful Transfer Of Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-raises-concerns-over-peaceful-transfer-of-power-after-november-elections-6288048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 03:16:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said an interview with CBS he is "not confident at all" there will be a peaceful transfer of power to Kamala Harris if Donald Trump loses November's election, according to an extract broadcast Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said an interview with CBS he is "not confident at all" there will be a peaceful transfer of power to Kamala Harris if Donald Trump loses November's election, according to an extract broadcast Wednesday.</p>

<p>"If Trump loses, I'm not confident at all," Biden told the US network in the interview, which was due to air fully on Sunday. "He means what he says. We don't take him seriously. He means it -- all the stuff about 'if we lose there'll be a bloodbath.'"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/uj0lr04_joe-biden_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden expressed his concern over the peaceful transfer of power after November election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-could-return-on-another-craft-in-february-if-needed-nasa-6287423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Could Return On Another Craft In February If Needed: NASA]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-could-return-on-another-craft-in-february-if-needed-nasa-6287423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:18:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA said on Wednesday that astronauts delivered to the International Space Station by Boeing's Starliner could return on SpaceX's Crew Dragon in February 2025 if Starliner is still deemed unsafe to return to Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA said on Wednesday that astronauts delivered to the International Space Station by Boeing's Starliner could return on SpaceX's Crew Dragon in February 2025 if Starliner is still deemed unsafe to return to Earth.</p>

<p>Starliner spacecraft launched in June carrying two astronauts to the ISS in a high-stakes test mission required before NASA can certify the spacecraft for routine astronaut flights.</p>

<p>But the mission, initially expected to last about eight days, has been drawn out far longer by an array of problems with the craft's propulsion system that Boeing and NASA have been scrambling to fix.</p>

<p>Those problems have called into question Starliner's ability to safely return to Earth its crew, veteran NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams. NASA has been examining whether a Crew Dragon capsule will have to bring them home instead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bl93e5h_sunita-williams-from-space_625x300_10_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starliner spacecraft launched in June carrying Sunita Williams, Butch Wilmore (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-garment-factories-reopen-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-6287179]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Garment Factories Reopen After Sheikh Hasina Ousted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-garment-factories-reopen-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-6287179]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 23:26:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Garment factories in Bangladesh, forecast to account for 90% of the country's exports, reopened on Wednesday after production was disrupted by violent protests that ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Garment factories in Bangladesh, forecast to account for 90% of the country's exports, reopened on Wednesday hoping to swiftly resume full operations after production was disrupted by violent protests that ousted Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina this week.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country on Monday after around 300 people were killed and thousands injured in a crackdown on student-led protests since July.</p>

<p>Garment and textile factories which supply major western brands such as H&amp;M, Zara and Carrefour had been forced to shut under curfews.</p>

<p>"We lost a total of four days, it is too early to make an estimate of the loss. There was little physical damage to factories," Miran Ali, vice president of the Bangladesh Garment Manufacturers and Exporters Association (BGMEA), told Reuters.</p>

<p>"I am hopeful that in the next few days, we will see complete normalisation," he said. "I'm confident our buyers will stand by our side."</p>

<p>He added that H&amp;M, which buys from about 1,000 factories in Bangladesh, had already said it would not seek discounts due to the delays. The world's second largest fashion retailer told Reuters on Wednesday its suppliers' factories were gradually reopening and it welcomed steps taken for greater stability in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>At a factory belonging to apparel maker Urmi Garments in Dhaka, the mainly female employees were back operating sewing machines.</p>

<p>"We are poor people depending on daily wages and overtime. If we sit back home, how can we run our families?" 38-year old Razia Begum, an employee at the factory, told Reuters.</p>

<p>Factory manager Emdadul Haq said the factory had lost 228,000 pieces of production worth $107,000. In all, Urmi, which counts H&amp;M, Japan's Uniqlo and Britain's Marks and Spencer among its clients, had lost about $2.2 million across three units, he said.</p>

<p>Though factories were reopening, there could be some damage to trade. Hula Global, an Indian apparel producer that serves Western clients, said on Monday it would redirect production for the rest of this year from Bangladesh to India to avert risk.</p>

<p>Pankaj Tuteja, Mumbai-based head of operations at Dragon Sourcing, which helps firms find suppliers, told Reuters that while it expected big brands such as Zara and H&amp;M to stick with Bangladesh, some firms that looked elsewhere could stay away.</p>

<p>"Once the client, then the factories, have invested so much time and money they will not just immediately run back, even when there's political stability. That can have a long-term impact for Bangladesh," Tuteja said.</p>

<p>But Bangladesh would remain attractive because of costs that are 15-25% lower than elsewhere, and 0% tariffs, Tuteja added.</p>

<p>The International Monetary Fund expects the ready-made garments industry will account for 90% of Bangladesh's $55 billion annual exports in the financial year 2024.</p>

<p>Bangladesh was the third-largest exporter of clothing in the world last year, according to the World Trade Organization.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gfht34qo_bangladesh-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Though factories were reopening, there could be some damage to trade (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-as-war-enters-11th-month-6287126]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Vows To "Eliminate" New Hamas Chief As War Enters 11th Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-vows-to-eliminate-new-hamas-chief-as-war-enters-11th-month-6287126]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 23:17:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel vowed to "eliminate" new Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, the alleged mastermind of the October 7 attack, whose appointment further inflamed regional tensions as the Gaza war entered its 11th month on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel vowed to "eliminate" new Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, the alleged mastermind of the October 7 attack, whose appointment further inflamed regional tensions as the Gaza war entered its 11th month on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The naming of Sinwar to lead the Palestinian group came as Israel braced for potential Iranian retaliation over the killing of his predecessor Ismael Haniyeh last week in Tehran.</p>

<p>Speaking at a military base on Wednesday, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel was "determined" to defend itself.</p>

<p>"We are prepared both defensively and offensively," he told new recruits.</p>

<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz said late Tuesday that Sinwar's promotion was "yet another compelling reason to swiftly eliminate him and wipe this vile organisation off the face of the earth".</p>

<p>Sinwar -- Hamas's leader in Gaza since 2017 -- has not been seen since the October 7 attack, which was the deadliest in Israel's history.</p>

<p>A senior Hamas official told AFP that the selection of Sinwar sent a message that the organisation "continues its path of resistance".</p>

<p>Hamas's Lebanese ally Hezbollah congratulated Sinwar and said the appointment affirms "the enemy... has failed to achieve its objectives" by killing Hamas leaders and officials.</p>

<p>Analysts believe Sinwar has been both more reluctant to agree to a Gaza ceasefire and closer to Tehran than Haniyeh, who lived in Qatar.</p>

<p>"If a ceasefire deal seemed unlikely upon Haniyeh's death, it is even less likely under Sinwar," according to Rita Katz, executive director of the SITE Intelligence Group.</p>

<p>"The group will only lean further into its hardline militant strategy of recent years," she added.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken told reporters that it was up to Sinwar to help achieve a ceasefire, saying he "has been and remains the primary decider".</p>

<p>Civilians in both Israel and Gaza met Sinwar's appointment with unease.</p>

<p>Mohammad al-Sharif, a displaced Gazan, told AFP: "He is a fighter. How will negotiations take place?"</p>

<p>In Tel Aviv, logistics company manger Hanan, who did not want to give his second name, said Sinwar's appointment meant Hamas "did not see fit to look for someone less militant, someone with a less murderous approach".</p>

<p><strong>Hezbollah vows response</strong></p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah has also pledged to avenge the deaths of Haniyeh and its own military commander Fuad Shukr in an Israeli strike in Beirut hours earlier.</p>

<p>In a televised address to mark one week since Shukr's death, Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah said Tuesday his group would retaliate "alone or in the context of a unified response from all the axis" of Iran-backed groups in the region.</p>

<p>The United States, which has sent extra warships and jets to the region, urged both Iran and Israel to avoid an escalation.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden had calls with Jordan's King Abdullah II, the Qatari emir, Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani, and Egyptian President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"No one should escalate this conflict. We've been engaged in intense diplomacy with allies and partners, communicating that message directly to Iran. We communicated that message directly to Israel," Blinken told reporters.</p>

<p>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian told his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron in a telephone call that the West "should immediately stop selling arms and supporting" Israel if it wants to prevent war, his office said.</p>

<p>The Jeddah-based Organisation of Islamic Cooperation met on Wednesday to discuss the situation in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Gambian Foreign Minister Mamadou Tangara, whose country currently chairs the bloc, said the "heinous" killing of Haniyeh risked "leading to a wider conflict that could involve the entire region".</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on Haniyeh's killing but confirmed it had carried out the strike on Shukr.</p>

<p>It held the Hezbollah commander responsible for a rocket attack in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 children.</p>

<p><strong>Flights cancelled</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli troops throughout the Gaza war.</p>

<p>The group said Tuesday that six of its fighters were killed in Israeli strikes on south Lebanon and that it had launched "dozens of Katyusha rockets" at a military base in the Golan Heights in retaliation.</p>

<p>Numerous airlines have suspended flights to Lebanon or limited them to daylight hours.</p>

<p>The Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip, triggered by the Palestinian group's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel, has already drawn in Iran-backed militants in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>The Hamas attack resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian Hamas operatives seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,677 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>The toll included two dozen deaths in the past 24 hours, according to ministry figures.</p>

<p>Israel said that its air force had "struck dozens of terror targets throughout the Gaza Strip" over the past day.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qbag8ago_yahya-sinwar-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar has not been seen since the October 7 attack (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-china-reacted-to-kamal-harris-running-mate-pick-tim-walz-6286450]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How China Reacted To Kamal Harris' Running Mate Pick Tim Walz]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-china-reacted-to-kamal-harris-running-mate-pick-tim-walz-6286450]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 21:14:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US presidential candidate Kamala Harris's choice of Tim Walz as her running mate has raised eyebrows, and plenty of questions, in China, which he first visited in 1989, the year the military crushed pro-democracy protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US presidential candidate Kamala Harris's choice of Tim Walz as her running mate has raised eyebrows, and plenty of questions, in China, which he first visited in 1989, the year the military crushed pro-democracy protests.</p>

<p>Demonstrators spent weeks on Beijing's Tiananmen Square demanding democracy before the military conducted a deadly crackdown on June 4, 1989.</p>

<p>Mr Walz was married on the fifth anniversary of that politically sensitive date.</p>

<p>Discussion of the events at Tiananmen is strictly censored in China but many social media users made veiled references Wednesday to the timing of Mr Walz's stint in the country.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old Minnesota governor and former schoolteacher has visited China dozens of times, including on summer trips with student groups for sightseeing and cultural exchange.</p>

<p>He first travelled there in 1989, moving to Foshan, a city in China's southern Guangdong province, for a year of teaching English at a local high school, according to media reports at the time.</p>

<p>Mr Walz married his wife Gwen on June 4, 1994, an article in a local US newspaper said.</p>

<p>"He wanted to have a date he'll always remember," his wife was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, social media users in China questioned the timing of Mr Walz's 1989 arrival in the country and suggested ulterior motives.</p>

<p>"He came to China at a time of turmoil, clearly with a special mission," one user commented on the platform Weibo.</p>

<p>"Is he from the CIA?" another wrote.</p>

<p>"Look at the year and you can't help but be sceptical," chimed in a third.</p>

<p><strong>'Definite influence'</strong></p>

<p>Mr Walz has pushed back against the assertion that the United States and China are necessary adversaries, a view widespread in Washington in recent years as trade and geopolitical disagreements with Beijing mount.</p>

<p>"I lived in China and as I said I've been there about 30 times," he told farming news website Agri-Pulse in a 2016 interview.</p>

<p>"But if someone tells you they're an expert on China they're probably not telling you the truth because it's a complex country," he said.</p>

<p>But despite his positive comments on Chinese people and culture, Mr Walz has also been critical of its government, telling local US media in 1990 that with "proper leadership" the country could achieve great success.</p>

<p>In 2016, while representing Minnesota in the US House of Representatives, he met with the Dalai Lama, the exiled Tibetan spiritual leader denounced by Beijing as a dangerous separatist.</p>

<p>China's foreign ministry told AFP Wednesday that it would not comment on Ms Harris's choice of Mr Walz as a running mate, calling the election an internal affair of the United States.</p>

<p>"We hope the US side can work with the Chinese side to move in the same direction," the statement said.</p>

<p>Social media users wondered what Mr Walz's personal connection to their country might mean if elected.</p>

<p>"If Harris is elected President, Vice President Walz will have a definite influence on her China policy," one user wrote.</p>

<p>And under one post featuring Mr Walz's comments from a 2016 interview in which he pointed out that the United States and China had potential for cooperation, other users waxed sceptical.</p>

<p>"2016 was a previous era," one wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Don't negligently assign a persona to your opponent."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2lkd1fqg_kamala-and-tim_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz has pushed back against the assertion that US and China are adversaries (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-head-muhammad-yunus-acquitted-a-day-ahead-of-swearing-in-6286330]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Interim Caretaker Acquitted Of Labour Charges Before Swearing-In]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-head-muhammad-yunus-acquitted-a-day-ahead-of-swearing-in-6286330]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 20:59:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Bangladeshi court on Wednesday overturned a conviction against Mohammed Yunus, a day before the Nobel winner is set to return to lead a caretaker government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Bangladeshi court on Wednesday overturned a conviction against Mohammed Yunus, a day before the Nobel winner is set to return to lead a caretaker government.</p>

<p>"Professor Muhammad Yunus and three of his colleagues have been acquitted of labour charges," one of his lawyers, Khaja Tanvir Ahmed, told AFP.</p>

<p>"The court earlier this year sentenced them to six months in prison."</p>

<p>He was sentenced in January for the labour charge, but immediately bailed pending appeal and later travelled abroad.</p>

<p>All four had denied the charges and, with courts accused of rubber-stamping decisions by ousted leader Sheikh Hasina's government, the case was criticised as politically motivated by watchdogs including Amnesty International.</p>

<p>"The labour court granted an appeal, and acquitted them," Ahmed said.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old Muhammad Yunus, known as the "banker to the poorest of the poor", was awarded the Peace Prize in 2006 for his work loaning small cash sums to rural women, allowing them to invest in farm tools or business equipment and boost their earnings.</p>

<p>But his public profile in Bangladesh earned him the hostility of Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus was hit with more than 100 criminal cases, but the labour trial was the only conviction.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina was ousted on Monday after weeks of mass protests and fled to India.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/udobbb28_muhammad-yunus_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 84-year-old Muhammad Yunus is known as the "banker to the poorest of the poor" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-issues-evacuation-orders-in-north-gaza-after-fresh-hamas-strikes-6286252]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Issues Evacuation Orders In North Gaza After Fresh Hamas Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-issues-evacuation-orders-in-north-gaza-after-fresh-hamas-strikes-6286252]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 20:47:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces on Wednesday issued new evacuation orders to Palestinians in areas of north Gaza after Hamas operatives fired a fresh volley of rockets into Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces on Wednesday issued new evacuation orders to Palestinians in areas of north Gaza that were among the first to be hit at the start of the war with Hamas in October, after Hamas operatives fired a fresh volley of rockets into Israel.</p>

<p>Army spokesperson Avichay Adraee posted the evacuation orders for several districts in Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya, two now largely destroyed towns into which Israeli tanks swept at the outset of Israel's ground invasion.</p>

<p>"Hamas and terrorist organisations are firing rockets from your area towards the State of Israel. The IDF will act forcefully and immediately against them," Adraee said in the message sent by text and social media to Palestinian residents.</p>

<p>"For your own safety, evacuate immediately to the known shelters in the center of Gaza City," the army spokesman said.</p>

<p>In a nearby Gaza City neighbourhood, Al-Tuffah, an Israeli airstrike on a house killed three Palestinians, medics said.</p>

<p>Later on Wednesday, 10 Palestinians were killed in two separate Israeli strikes in Khan Younis in southern Gaza. Medics said one strike killed three people on a motorcycle west of Khan Younis, while seven others were killed in tank shelling that hit a tent encampment in Abassan town, east of the city.</p>

<p><strong>Multiple Fronts</strong></p>

<p>Fighting has continued in the Gaza Strip even as Israel braces for an expected assault in its north from Iran and its close Lebanese ally Hezbollah after the July 31 assassination in the Iranian capital Tehran of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>The Israeli military says it has killed dozens of Hamas operatives in recent days and on Wednesday said troops had hit weapons-making facilities in the teeming district of Deir al-Balah in central Gaza, where tens of thousands of Palestinians displaced by the fighting have taken shelter.</p>

<p>In other central areas, Israeli tanks shelled Nuseirat and Bureij, two of Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps. Israel says Hamas operatives use civilian infrastructure for cover and to conceal operations posts and arms caches; Hamas denies this.</p>

<p>Hamas operatives say they continue to carry out ambush attacks on Israeli troops and armoured vehicles with explosive devices, and are still able to launch limited rocket salvoes into Israel.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Islamic Jihad, a close Hamas ally, said it fired rockets into Israel in response to what it called Israeli "massacres of civilians".</p>

<p>The Israeli military said that over the past week Hamas had fired rockets from launchers embedded near two international humanitarian aid and distribution warehouses, including the U.N. Palestinian refugee agency UNRWA. Israeli forces struck those sites, it added.</p>

<p>Hamas-led operatives set off the Gaza war on Oct. 7 with a cross-border rampage into Israeli communities, killing 1,200 Israelis and foreigners and seizing some 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>In response, Israel has pursued a relentless assault on Gaza that has reduced much of the heavily populated coastal strip to ruins, killed more than 39,600 Palestinians and wounded over 91,500, according to Gaza health ministry figures.</p>

<p>The Hamas-led ministry does not distinguish between combatants and civilians in its death lists.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/skb2i3ko_gaza-strikes-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Hamas war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/son-of-norway-crown-princess-arrested-for-assault-woman-cops-6286023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Son Of Norway Crown Princess Arrested For Assault Woman: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/son-of-norway-crown-princess-arrested-for-assault-woman-cops-6286023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 20:14:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 27-year-old son of Norwegian Crown Princess Mette-Marit was arrested at the weekend on suspicion of assaulting a woman, police said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 27-year-old son of Norwegian Crown Princess Mette-Marit was arrested at the weekend on suspicion of assaulting a woman, police said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Mette-Marit's son Marius Borg Hoiby was born in 1997 from a relationship prior to her 2001 marriage to Crown Prince Haakon, the heir apparent to the Norwegian throne.</p>

<p>Police said they were called to an Oslo address early Sunday after an overnight altercation in an apartment.</p>

<p>A man in his 20s was arrested over the incident and released from custody the following day, police said in a statement.</p>

<p>"As it has been made known in several media that this (person) is Marius Borg Hoiby, the police confirm that it is Hoiby who is a suspect in the case."</p>

<p>Police said he was suspected of causing "bodily harm and damage". They did not identify the woman, saying only there was "relationship between the accused and the victim".</p>

<p>Police said they had "no information that the victim suffered serious injuries".</p>

<p>Crown Prince Haakon, currently in Paris for the Olympics, on Wednesday told Norwegian media in the French capital it was a "serious" matter.</p>

<p>"It's a serious matter when police are involved like this," TV2 quoted him as saying on its website.</p>

<p>"At the same time, it would not be right for me to comment on it at this time."</p>

<p>While Hoiby was raised by Mette-Marit and Haakon together with his step-siblings, 20-year-old Princess Ingrid Alexandra and 18-year-old Prince Sverre Magnus, unlike them he has no official public role.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g17n0o7g_marius-borg-hoiby_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Norwegian Crown Princess Mette-Marit with her son Marius Borg Hoiby (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drop-charges-against-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-party-leader-living-in-india-6285462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drop Charges Against Bangladesh Ex-PM  Party Leader Living In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drop-charges-against-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-party-leader-living-in-india-6285462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:01:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina ousted, all eyes in Bangladesh are on the main opposition party - the Bangladesh National party or BNP, whose top leader -- former Prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia  has been released from house arrest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina ousted, all eyes in Bangladesh are on the main opposition party - the Bangladesh National party or BNP, whose top leader -- former Prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia – has been released from house arrest.</p>

<p>Her son Tareue Rehman is returning to Bangladesh. Another top BNP leader who is expected to return is Salahuddin Ahmed, who has been living in India since 2015.</p>

<p>Ahmed has served a one-year jail term for illegally entering India, but even after being released has chosen to stay on. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The leader, who has been camping out in Shillong, has claimed that Khaleda Zia will need advanced medical treatment.</p>

<p>"BNP wants all charges against her to be dropped. She would need advanced treatment and has to go abroad for it," Salahuddin Ahmed said.Bangladesh President Khaleda Zia has already received her her renewed passport.</p>

<p>"People of Bangladesh strongly believe that Sheikh Hasina left after being forced. Others were not lucky enough to survive. Luckily I am still alive. I have been ready to return since the first day," Salahuddin said.</p>

<p>Salahuddin, who landed in Shillong in 2015, faced trial for illegal entry. He was&nbsp; acquitted in 2018 and has since been free to go.</p>

<p>The process, however, was delayed following an appeal by the authorities against his release. On February 28, a court in Shillong upheld the 2018 order of acquittal.</p>

<p>The BNP leader has claimed that Begum Khaleda Zia needs advanced medical treatment abroad thus BNP would demand all charges against her be dropped. The BNP will also call for a neutral general election.</p>

<p>"What happened to Hasina was her fate as she resorted to misrule for three consecutive terms with flawed elections and there was absence of rule of law. It was complete tyranny. The situation prevailing in Bangladesh is something like the mass revolution led by students," Salahuddin said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pgin4hf_khaleda-zia_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-climate-change-is-threatening-pearl-of-kazakhstan-lake-balkhash-6285454]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Climate Change Is Threatening "Pearl Of Kazakhstan" - Lake Balkhash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-climate-change-is-threatening-pearl-of-kazakhstan-lake-balkhash-6285454]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:00:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Seen from the sky, with its turquoise waters stretching out into the desert expanses in the shape of a crescent, you can see why they call Lake Balkhash the "pearl of Kazakhstan".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seen from the sky, with its turquoise waters stretching out into the desert expanses in the shape of a crescent, you can see why they call Lake Balkhash the "pearl of Kazakhstan".</p>

<p>But pollution, climate change and its overuse are threatening the existence of one of the most unique stretches of water in the world.</p>

<p>One side of the Balkhash -- the biggest lake in Central Asia after the Caspian Sea -- has salt water, but on the other it is fresh. In such a strange environment, rare species have abounded. Until now.</p>

<p>"All the miseries of the Balkhash are right under my eyes," fisherman Alexei Grebennikov told AFP from the deck of his boat on the northern shores, which sometimes has salty water, sometimes fresh.</p>

<p>"There are fewer and fewer fish, it's catastrophic, the lake is silting up," warned the 50-year-old.</p>

<p>A dredger to clear the little harbour lay anchored, rusting and unused, off the industrial town of Balkhack, itself seemingly stuck in a Soviet timewarp.</p>

<p>"We used to take tourists underwater fishing. Now the place has become a swamp," said Grebennikov.</p>

<p>In town, scientist Olga Sharipova was studying the changes.</p>

<p>"The Balkhash is the country's largest fishery. But the quantity of fish goes down when the water level drops, because the conditions for reproduction are disrupted," she told AFP.</p>

<p>And its level is now only a metre from the critical threshold where it could tilt towards disaster.</p>

<p>There was an unexpected respite this spring when unprecedented floods allowed the Kazakh authorities to divert 3.3 million cubic metres of water to the Balkhash.</p>

<p>The Caspian also got a six-billion-cubic-metre fill-up.</p>

<p><strong>China 'overusing' water</strong></p>

<p>But the few extra centimetres has not changed the longterm trend.</p>

<p>"The level of the Balkhash has been falling everywhere since 2019, mainly due to a decrease in the flow of the Ili River" from neighbouring China, said Sharipova.</p>

<p>All the great lakes of Central Asia, also known as enclosed seas, share a similar worrying fate.</p>

<p>The Aral Sea has almost disappeared, the situation is alarming for the Caspian Sea and Lake Issyk-Kul in neighbouring Kyrgyzstan.</p>

<p>Located on dry lands isolated from the ocean, they are particularly vulnerable to disturbances "exacerbated by global warming and human activities", according to leading scientific journal Nature.</p>

<p>Rising temperatures accelerate evaporation, as water resources dwindle due to the melting of surrounding glaciers.</p>

<p>These issues are compounded by the economic importance of the Balkhash, which is on the path of China's Belt and Road Initiative, a massive infrastructure project also known as the New Silk Road.</p>

<p>A 2021 study by Oxford University scientists published in the journal "Water" concluded the lake's decline resulted from China's overuse of the Ili River which feeds it for its agriculture, including cotton.</p>

<p>"If the hydro-climatic regime of the Ili for 2020-2060 remains unchanged compared to the past 50 years and agriculture continues to expand in China, future water supplies will become increasingly strained," the study said.</p>

<p>Beijing is a key economic partner for Kazakhstan but it is less keen to collaborate on water issues.</p>

<p>"The drafting and signing of an agreement with China on the sharing of water in transborder rivers is a key issue," the Kazakh Ministry of Water Resources told AFP.</p>

<p>"The main objective is to supply the volumes of water needed to preserve the Balkhash," it said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The water being syphoned away adds to &quot;pollution from heavy metals, pesticides and other harmful substances&quot;, authorities said" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nujn70ag_lake-balkhash-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The water being syphoned away adds to &quot;pollution from heavy metals, pesticides and other harmful substances&quot;, authorities said" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The level of the Balkhash has been falling everywhere since 2019, said Olga Sharipova, a scientist (File)<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p><strong>Heavy pollution</strong></p>

<p>The water being syphoned away adds to "pollution from heavy metals, pesticides and other harmful substances", authorities said, without citing culprits.</p>

<p>The town of Balkhash was founded around Kazakhstan's largest copper producer, Kazakhmys.</p>

<p>Holidaymakers bathing on Balkhash's municipal beach have a view of the smoking chimneys of its metal plant.</p>

<p>Lung cancer rates here are almost 10 times the regional average, which is already among the highest in the country, health authorities said.</p>

<p>Despite being sanctioned for breaking environmental standards, Kazakhmys denies it is the main polluter of the lake and has vowed to to reduce pollution by renewing its equipment.</p>

<p>"Kazakhmys is carrying out protective work to prevent environmental disasters in the Balkhash," Sherkhan Rustemov, the company's ecological engineer, told AFP.</p>

<p>In the meantime, the plant continues to discharge industrial waste into another huge body of water, right next to the lake.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/um1cnvbo_lake-balkhash-afp_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Balkhash is the biggest lake in Central Asia after the Caspian Sea]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-will-he-negotiate-gazans-concerned-over-hamass-new-chief-yahya-sinwar-6285381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["How Will He Negotiate?" Gazans Concerned Over Hamas's New Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-will-he-negotiate-gazans-concerned-over-hamass-new-chief-yahya-sinwar-6285381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:50:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[War-weary Gazans voiced concern on Wednesday after Hamas appointed Yahya Sinwar as its new supremo, fearing his past as the movement's military commander might hamper efforts for the ceasefire they yearn for.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>War-weary Gazans voiced concern on Wednesday after Hamas appointed <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/webstories/feature/who-is-yahya-sinwar-new-leader-of-hamas-21965">Yahya Sinwar</a> as its new supremo, fearing his past as the movement's military commander might hamper efforts for the ceasefire they yearn for.</p>

<p>"We don't know how Hamas is thinking or what led them to choose Yahya Sinwar as their chief, especially when his whereabouts are unknown", 29-year-old Mohammad al-Sharif told AFP in the central Gaza city of Deir el-Balah.</p>

<p>"He is a fighter. How will negotiations take place?", asked the displaced man originally from Gaza City, adding: "We want nothing but the end of the war".</p>

<p>Late on Tuesday, Hamas announced it had chosen Sinwar, 61, the man Israel says masterminded the October 7 attack that sparked the Gaza war, to replace Ismail Haniyeh, who was assassinated in Tehran on July 31.</p>

<p>Sinwar has not been seen since the attack on Israel, with many reports claiming he is operating from one of several underground tunnels in Gaza.</p>

<p>Ibrahim Abu Daqa, 35, echoed Sharif's disappointment over the choice of Sinwar to succeed Haniyeh, who was regarded by some as a pragmatist.</p>

<p>"In my opinion, appointing Yahya Sinwar as the head of Hamas was inappropriate at this critical stage", he told AFP.</p>

<p>Also displaced in Deir el-Balah, and originally from the southern Gaza city of Rafah, Abu Daqa said that the decision "may lead to negative results on multiple levels, including halting negotiations or failing to make progress in them, especially since Israel is seeking him for assassination".</p>

<p>"The occupation killed the negotiator Ismail Haniyeh. What will happen with the fighter Yahya Sinwar?" he asked.</p>

<p>A senior Hamas official told AFP that the selection of Sinwar sent a message that the operative group "continues its path of resistance".</p>

<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz has already called for Sinwar's killing.</p>

<p>Bashir Qarqaz voiced fears that Israel's determination to kill Sinwar would make his appointment an obstacle to peace.</p>

<p>"The war will not end in the near future because Israel rejects Sinwar," he said, adding that "they want a political figure to concede to them, and Sinwar is a stubborn man who may not concede".</p>

<p>Hani al-Qano was more hopeful. He underlined that unlike Haniyeh, who lived in self-exile in Qatar, Sinwar had lived in Gaza throughout the conflict and was more familiar with the daily reality of the war.</p>

<p>"He may have a positive impact on the negotiations and may be a challenge to Israel, given that Sinwar is living inside the Gaza Strip among the people under siege", he said.</p>

<p>"He is different from Haniyeh, who lived abroad."</p>

<h3 id="-enthusiasm-in-west-bank-"><strong>Enthusiasm in West Bank</strong></h3>

<p>Various Palestinian political factions in the occupied West Bank congratulated Hamas on its choice of Sinwar.</p>

<p>These included the leftist Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, which "wished Sinwar success" in a statement published by Hamas.</p>

<p>Palestinian residents of the Israeli-occupied West Bank, where Hamas has been more popular than the ruling Fatah movement since the October 7 attack, showed more enthusiasm for the new Hamas supremo.</p>

<p>"Choosing Sinwar to lead the Hamas movement was an excellent decision because Sinwar lives in the heart of the battle, and therefore he knows exactly what he is negotiating," said Farah Qassem, a coffee shop owner in Ramallah, the seat of the Fatah-led Palestinian Authority.</p>

<p>"His decisions will come from the suffering experienced by the people in Gaza", the 54-year-old added.</p>

<p>Emad Abu Fokheidah, a school administrator in a nearby village, echoed the sentiment.</p>

<p>"Choosing Sinwar was a wise decision and a message to the (Israeli) occupation that the political solution, which Israel rejected by assassinating Haniyeh, will only come from the barrel of a gun", Abu Fokheidah, 57, said.</p>

<p>"All wars end with negotiations, and today the negotiator will be the one leading the battle."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnlapn8o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar has not been seen since the attack on Israel (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-read-from-the-bible-and-told-his-3-sons-they-were-best-boys-ever-then-he-killed-them-6285027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Told His Sons They Were "The Best Boys Ever" Before Killing Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-read-from-the-bible-and-told-his-3-sons-they-were-best-boys-ever-then-he-killed-them-6285027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:07:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On Friday, he pleaded guilty and was sentenced to three consecutive life terms in prison.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Ohio father read from the Bible, told his children he loved them, and made a cryptic call to his own father-saying his eldest boy would be "the hardest one"-before brutally murdering his three young sons at their family home, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/chad-doerman-ohio-dad-murder-bible-b2591995.html"><em>Independent </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Chad Doerman, 33, shot and killed his sons Clayton, 7, Hunter, 4, and Chase, 3, in Monroe Township, about 75 miles west of Columbus, on June 15, 2023. On Friday, he pleaded guilty and was sentenced to three consecutive life terms in prison.</p>

<p>Disturbing new details have emerged about Doerman's actions leading up to the murders and the final hours of the three young boys' lives.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-lined-up-and-shot-3-sons-police-say-attack-planned-over-several-months-4129120">Also Read|&nbsp;US Man Lined Up And Shot 3 Sons, Police Say Attack Planned Over Several Months</a></p>

<p>In a press briefing on Monday, Clermont County Prosecuting Attorney Mark Tekulve revealed that on the day of the shooting spree, Doerman had lunch with his wife Laura and told her, "This will be my last good meal."</p>

<p>Despite this ominous statement, Laura did not feel the need to "do something to protect the family," and Doerman spent the afternoon doing yard work and playing with the children.</p>

<p>Around 3:30 to 3:45 p.m., Doerman began reading the Bible to Hunter, Tekulve said. "He was walking around the house with the Bible, mumbling 'Chad knows what's right. Chad knows what's right,'" he said.</p>

<p>Just before 4 p.m., Doerman asked his family to join him for a nap in the master bedroom. His wife and three sons entered the room with him while his 12-year-old stepdaughter watched television in another room.</p>

<p>When Doerman opened the gun safe, his wife grew alarmed and told him, "You're scaring me."</p>

<p>What followed were events so harrowing that they brought experienced officers to tears, Tekulve told reporters in a separate press briefing on Friday.</p>

<p>Doerman told his family he loved them and called his sons the "best boys ever." Then he jumped up from the bed, grabbed a .22 rifle from the safe, and his family initially worried for his safety rather than their own, fearing he would kill himself.</p>

<p>"Laura is screaming, the boys are screaming, Laura is frightened that he's about to kill himself," said Tekulve. "They're all trying to discourage him, telling him that they love him and begging him not to kill himself."</p>

<p>According to a press release from the Clermont County Sheriff's Office, the mother of the boys was also shot in the hand. She was sent to University Hospital in Cincinnati for non-life-threatening injuries after being discovered outside the house. The prosecutors added that she was trying to take the gun away from Mr Doerman and was shot during the same. She was sent to a hospital to be treated for her injuries. However, the age and the extent of the daughter's injuries are still unknown.</p>

<p>After the incident, the father was found sitting on a porch outside his residence and admitted to lining the boys up in the yard and firing at them during a subsequent interview with the authorities. He said that he had been planning the killings for several months.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3d7vqm_chad-doerman_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mother of the boys was also shot in the hand]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-to-take-oath-tomorrow-says-army-chief-6284991]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Interim Government Led By Nobel Winner To Take Oath Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-to-take-oath-tomorrow-says-army-chief-6284991]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 18:02:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The interim government in Bangladesh led by Nobel-laureate Muhammad Yunus will take oath today, the nation's army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman said today. General Waker told reporters the interim government is likely to take oath at 8 pm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The army chief said the advisory council to be led by Mr Yunus may have 15 members. Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin on Tuesday appointed Mr Yunus, 84, to head the interim government after the violent ouster of former pro-India Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</li>
	<li>Mr Yunus will lead Bangladesh through a "democratic process" when he arrives in the country to helm the interim government, General Waker said.</li>
	<li>"He is very eager to do this," the General said in a televised address to the nation. "I am certain that he will be able to take us through a beautiful democratic process and that we will benefit from this," he said.</li>
	<li>Mr Yunus also said today he was looking forward to helping the country overcome its current turbulence. "I'm looking forward to going back home, see what's happening and how we can organise ourselves to get out of the trouble we are in," he told reporters before boarding a flight at Paris' Charles de Gaulle airport bound for Dubai, where he will take a connecting plane for Dhaka.</li>
	<li>The Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer has asked for calm after weeks of violence in which at least 455 people were killed. "If we take the path of violence everything will be destroyed," he added.</li>
	<li>The appointment came quickly after student leaders called on Mr Yunus -- credited with lifting millions out of poverty in Bangladesh -- to lead. The decision was made in a meeting with President Mohammed Shahabuddin, the heads of the army, navy and air force, and student leaders.</li>
	<li>Mr Yunus will have the title of chief adviser, according to Nahid Islam, one of the leaders of Students Against Discrimination who participated in the meeting.</li>
	<li>A Bangladesh court today acquitted Mr Yunus of a labour conviction on appeal, his lawyer Khaja Tanvir Ahmed told news agency AFP. Mr Yunus had travelled abroad earlier this year after he was sentenced to six months in jail for the labour charge -- but was immediately bailed pending appeal. The case was criticised as politically motivated by rights watchdogs including Amnesty International.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina, 76, who had been in power since 2009, resigned on Monday as hundreds of thousands of people flooded the streets of Dhaka demanding she stand down. Monday's events were the culmination of more than a month of unrest, which began as protests against a plan for quotas in government jobs but morphed into an anti-Hasina movement.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina, who was accused of rigging January elections and widespread human rights abuses, deployed security forces to quash the protests. Hundreds of people were killed in the crackdown, but the military turned against Ms Hasina on the weekend and she was forced to flee in a helicopter to neighbouring India.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>With inputs from AFP</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/30bqu6s_muhammad-yunus-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh's interim government led by Muhammad Yunus will take oath tomorrow]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-nearly-40-000-and-counting-the-struggle-to-keep-track-of-gaza-deaths-6284569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 40,000 And Counting: The Struggle To Keep Track Of Gaza Deaths]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-nearly-40-000-and-counting-the-struggle-to-keep-track-of-gaza-deaths-6284569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 17:15:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With much of Gaza reduced to rubble by 10 months of war, counting the dead has become a challenge for the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, as the death toll nears 40,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With much of Gaza reduced to rubble by 10 months of war, counting the dead has become a challenge for the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, as the death count nears 40,000.</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly questioned the credibility of the daily figures put out by the ministry and US President Joe Biden did so too in the early stages of the war.</p>

<p>But several United Nations agencies that operate in Gaza have said the figures are credible and they are frequently cited by international organisations.</p>

<p><strong>Data collection</strong></p>

<p>Two AFP correspondents witnessed health facilities enter deaths in the ministry's database.</p>

<p>Gaza health officials first identify the bodies of the dead, by the visual recognition of a relative or friend, or by the recovery of personal items.</p>

<p>The dead person's information is then entered in the health ministry's digital database, usually including name, gender, birth date and ID number.</p>

<p>When bodies cannot be identified because they are unrecognisable or when no one claims them, staff record the death under a number, alongside all the information they were able to gather.</p>

<p>Any distinguishing marks that may help with later identification, whether personal items or a birthmark, are collected and photographed.</p>

<p><strong>Central registry</strong></p>

<p>Gaza's health ministry has issued several statements setting out its procedures for compiling the death count.</p>

<p>In public hospitals under the direct supervision of the territory's Hamas government, the "personal information and identity number" of every Palestinian killed during the war are entered in the hospital's database as soon as they are pronounced dead.</p>

<p>The data is then sent to the health ministry's central registry on a daily basis.</p>

<p>For those who die in private hospitals and clinics, their information is taken down on a form that must be sent to the ministry within 24 hours to be added to the central registry, a ministry statement said.</p>

<p>The ministry's "information centre" then verifies the data entries to "ensure they do not contain any duplicates or mistakes", before saving them in the database, the statement added.</p>

<p>Gaza residents are also encouraged by Palestinian authorities to report any deaths in their families on a designated government website. The data is used for the ministry's verifications.</p>

<p>The ministry is staffed with civil servants that answer to the West Bank-based Palestinian Authority as well as to the Hamas-led government in Gaza.</p>

<p><strong>'High correlation'</strong></p>

<p>An investigation conducted by Airwars, an NGO focused on the impact of war on civilians, analysed the data entries for 3,000 of the dead and found "a high correlation" between the ministry's data and what Palestinian civilians reported online, with 75 percent of publicly reported names also appearing on the ministry's list.</p>

<p>The study found that the ministry's figures had become "less accurate" as the war dragged on, a development it attributed to the heavy damage to health infrastructure resulting from the war.</p>

<p>For instance, at southern Gaza's Nasser Hospital, one of the few still at least partly functioning, only 50 out of 400 computers still work, its director Atef al-Hout told AFP.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities frequently criticise the ministry's figures for failing to distinguish between combatants and civilians. But neither the army nor Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu deny the scale of the overall count.</p>

<p>The press office of Gaza's Hamas government estimates that nearly 70 percent of the roughly 40,000 dead are women (about 11,000) or children (at least 16,300).</p>

<p>Several UN agencies, including the agency in charge of Palestinian refugees (UNRWA), have said the ministry's figures are credible.</p>

<p>"In the past -- the five, six cycles of conflict in the Gaza Strip -- these figures were considered as credible and no one ever really challenged these figures," the agency's chief Philippe Lazzarini said in October.</p>

<p>A study by British medical review The Lancet estimated that 186,000 deaths can be attributed to the war in Gaza, directly or indirectly as a result of the humanitarian crisis it has triggered.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza was triggered by the October 7 attack by Hamas, which resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rvmt6gc8_gaza-war_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-hotel-collapse-2-dead-several-injured-as-hotel-collapses-6284399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Dead, Several Feared Trapped After Hotel In Germany Collapses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-hotel-collapse-2-dead-several-injured-as-hotel-collapses-6284399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:55:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rescue teams were Wednesday working to free people trapped after part of a hotel collapsed in western Germany, killing two and injuring several others, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rescue teams were Wednesday working to free people trapped after part of a hotel collapsed in western Germany, killing two and injuring several others, authorities said.</p>

<p>A floor in the hotel in Kroev, a town some 110 kilometres (68 miles) west of Frankfurt, collapsed for unknown reasons around 11:00 pm (2100 GMT) on Tuesday, police said in a statement.</p>

<p>A woman and a man were killed in the accident, police spokesman Joerg Teusch told journalists on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Of the 14 people inside at the time, five managed to get out.</p>

<p>Emergency services rescued one man, a child and two women on Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>"We were able to make contact with the seven people buried and four of them were rescued with minor injuries, so it's a miracle," Teusch said.</p>

<p>Three people remain trapped under the rubble, he said, and are "probably seriously injured".</p>

<p>The rescue operation was difficult "as the building could only be entered... with the utmost caution", police said.</p>

<p>Thirty-one residents from the local neighbourhood were evacuated and some 250 search-and-rescue staff were working at the site.</p>

<p>Dutch media reported that a Dutch family of three was among those caught up in the incident.</p>

<p>The mother and child had been pulled out alive but the father was still trapped, Dutch national news agency ANP said.</p>

<p>The family were reportedly from Urk, a small fishing town in the north of the Netherlands.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0rmhtor8_germany-hotel-collapse-afp_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A woman and a man were killed in the accident, police spokesman said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-bangladesh-pm-khaleda-zia-released-from-prison-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-says-brave-children-made-impossible-possible-6284373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Brave Children Made Impossible Possible": Ex Bangladesh PM Amid Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-bangladesh-pm-khaleda-zia-released-from-prison-after-sheikh-hasina-ouster-says-brave-children-made-impossible-possible-6284373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:52:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ex Bangladesh PM Khaleda Zia, released from prison after Sheikh Hasina ouster, says "brave children made impossible possible"]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia congratulated the people today from her hospital bed, saying the country has been "liberated" through the efforts of "our valiant children". Released from prison after Sheikh Hasina resigned from Prime Minister post and skipped the country, Khaleda Zia also thanked the people "who prayed for my health and freedom".</p>

<p>"This victory has brought us to a new beginning.&nbsp; We have to build a new country, a prosperous Bangladesh, out of the long-standing wreckage of democracy and piled up corruption. The students, the youth, are our future. We will bring to life the dreams for which they gave their lifeblood," she said in a video message posted on social media. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"I would like to express my sincere thanks to our brave children who fought to the death to make the impossible possible. Pay respect to hundreds of martyrs," she added.</p>

<p>The release of Khaleda Zia, a two-time Prime Minister who heads the&nbsp; heads the Bangladesh Nationalist Party, was ordered by President Mohammed Shahabuddin hours after Sheikh Hasina's ouster.</p>

<p>Ms Zia was convicted for corruption in 2018 and jailed for 17 years. It left her ineligible to contest elections later that year. Because of ill health, she had been in hospital for most of this period.</p>

<p>The ouster of Sheikh Hasina has not stemmed the tide of violence that has been ravaging the neighbouring country over the past month. Twenty bodies of Awami League leaders have been found across Bangladesh since Sheikh Hasina left Dhaka on Monday.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate and the country's microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus, who will head the army-backed interim government, has called for calm.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina -- the daughter of Bangladesh's founding father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman -- had stepped down from the top post and and left the country after a 45-minute ultimatum from the army. She is currently in India.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said yesterday that the government is giving her time to "recover" before discussing her next plans.</p>

<p>"At a very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India. We simultaneously received a request for flight clearance from the Bangladesh authorities," Mr Jaishankar had told the Lok Sabha.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p8irsdfo_khaleda-zia_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-saudi-uae-agree-to-roll-over-paks-12-billion-debt-for-a-year-6284220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China, Saudi, UAE Agree To Roll Over Pak's $12 Billion Debt For A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-saudi-uae-agree-to-roll-over-paks-12-billion-debt-for-a-year-6284220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:36:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China, Saudi Arabia and the UAE have agreed to roll over cash-strapped Pakistan's $12 billion debt for one year, as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) is likely to approve its $7 billion bailout package later this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China, Saudi Arabia and the UAE have agreed to roll over cash-strapped Pakistan's $12 billion debt for one year, as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) is likely to approve its $7 billion bailout package later this month.</p>

<p>After a meeting of the Senate Standing Committee on Finance yesterday, Pakistan Finance Minister Muhammad Aurangzeb told reporters that there was no delay in the IMF Executive Board meeting, which is going to take place by the end of this month to approve the $7 billion Extended Fund Facility, the Express Tribune reported today.</p>

<p>The Executive Board is scheduled to meet on August 28 to approve the $7 billion package, the report said, quoting government officials.</p>

<p>The development marks an end to the uncertainty over the timing of the Executive Board meeting, which was contingent upon the rollover of debts by Pakistan's three traditional creditors, it said.</p>

<p>Aurangzeb said the $12 billion cash deposits by China, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates would be rolled over for one year, like last time. Earlier, he had said that the IMF had asked for the rollover for three to five years before the Executive Board meeting.</p>

<p>However, he clarified that the requirement was to secure the rollover for one year, but the government was trying to have these rollovers for three to five years. He added that the three bilateral creditors had agreed to roll the loans over on the existing terms and conditions.</p>

<p>The IMF announced a staff-level agreement for USD 7 billion last month, subject to the approval of the Executive Board and securing financing commitments from the bilateral and multilateral creditors.</p>

<p>The finance minister said there was no point in asking for an increase in the interest rates on these loans when the country's foreign exchange reserves had strengthened compared to a year ago. The IMF, he added, had identified only a USD 3-5 billion financing gap over the three-year programme period, which was quite manageable.</p>

<p>"Pakistan has also received an offer from a foreign commercial bank but we are waiting for the IMF Board approval to ask the lender to cut the offered interest rates," said Aurangzeb. The offer had come from a non-Gulf and non-Chinese commercial bank, he added, without disclosing the name.</p>

<p>A finance ministry official said that Standard Chartered Bank had offered a less than USD 400 million loan but it was asking for a double-digit interest rate that the government could not afford to pay. Aurangzeb said the government would wait for the IMF Board's approval to get the commercial bank to cut its offered interest rates.</p>

<p>The finance minister said two important developments had taken place in the last few days, which showed that Pakistan was well on its way to achieving macroeconomic stability. He described the Fitch rating agency's decision to improve Pakistan's credit rating by one notch and the central bank's decision to cut the interest rates by 1% as "very critical elements for achieving macroeconomic stability".</p>

<p>When asked as to why Standard and Poor's had not improved Pakistan's CCC+ rating, the minister stated that raising a CCC+ rating to a B negative one would have been a big jump.</p>

<p>He hoped that the three rating agencies would improve Pakistan's standing to B negative by the end of this year, a grade where it can venture into the international capital markets to float sovereign bonds at relatively lower rates than offered at the current CCC+ ratings.</p>

<p>The three international credit rating agencies have given below investment grade to Pakistani bonds due to their weak economic position and huge external financing requirements. However, Fitch last week improved the rating by one notch -- from CCC to CCC+ -- which was still below the investment grade.</p>

<p>The finance minister said the government was trying to issue the Panda bond in the Chinese markets and had engaged a Chinese financial adviser firm to complete the transaction either by the end of this calendar year or in early 2025.</p>

<p>Aurangzeb said the government was also contemplating hiring another Chinese financial adviser to secure the energy debt rollover. He said that Pakistan had requested up to a five-year extension in the energy debt, but it would take time before any agreement was reached.</p>

<p>He said that even the conversion of the Chinese power plants from imported to local coal would take at least two to three years.</p>

<p>The finance minister also said that to cut expenditures, the government had undertaken the privatisation programme and an exercise was ongoing to close ministries or merge them. "It is about time to right-size the federal government," Aurangzeb said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/4n0oo86_pakistan-economy-reuters_625x300_10_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[IMF is likely to approve a bailout package later this month, the Pakistan finance minister said. File]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-chopper-crash-four-chinese-passengers-pilot-killed-in-chopper-crash-6284194]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[4 Chinese Passengers, Pilot Killed In Helicopter Crash In Nepal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-chopper-crash-four-chinese-passengers-pilot-killed-in-chopper-crash-6284194]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 07 Aug 2024 16:33:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A helicopter crashed in central Nepal on Wednesday, killing all five people aboard including the pilot and four Chinese tourists.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A helicopter crashed in central Nepal on Wednesday, killing all five people aboard including the pilot and four Chinese tourists.</p>

<p>Nepal has a woeful track record on aviation safety and the Himalayan republic has seen a spate of deadly light plane and helicopter crashes over the decades.</p>

<p>The Air Dynasty chopper was heading to Syabrubesi, a starting point for many trekking routes popular with tourists, from the capital Kathmandu.</p>

<p>It lost contact about three minutes after taking off, a press release from the Civil Aviation Authority said, and crashed in Nuwakot district north of the capital.</p>

<p>Another helicopter was dispatched immediately to the accident site for rescue, it said.</p>

<p>"All five people aboard including the pilot are dead," police spokesman Dan Bahadur Karki told AFP.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="The helicopter lost contact about three minutes after taking off, authorities said" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v2ueroto_nepal-chopper-crash-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="The helicopter lost contact about three minutes after taking off, authorities said" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">The helicopter lost contact about three minutes after taking off, authorities said</p>
</div>

<p>Nuwakot district officer Ram Krishna Adhikari said five dead bodies have been retrieved from the accident site.</p>

<p>"It has crashed in a jungle area on the slope of a hill. We do not know the cause yet or how it happened," he said from the crash site.</p>

<p>Adhikari said that police and army personnel were dispatched after locals had alerted him about the crash and a fire at the site.</p>

<p>Nepal's air industry has boomed in recent years, carrying goods and people between hard-to-reach areas as well as foreign trekkers and climbers.</p>

<p>But it has been plagued by poor safety due to insufficient training and maintenance, issues compounded by mountainous Nepal's treacherous geography.</p>

<p>The Himalayan republic has some of the world's most remote and tricky runways, flanked by snow-capped peaks with approaches that pose a challenge even for accomplished pilots.</p>

<p>The European Union has banned all Nepali carriers from its airspace over safety concerns.</p>

<p>Wednesday's incident comes two weeks after a plane crash in Kathmandu killed all 18 aboard except the pilot.</p>

<p>Six people, including five members of a Mexican family, were killed when a helicopter crashed soon after take-off in the Everest region in 2023.</p>

<p>Nepal's tourism minister Rabindra Adhikari was among seven killed in a helicopter crash in 2019.</p>

<p>The country's last major incident involving a commercial flight was in January 2023 when a Yeti Airlines service crashed while landing at Pokhara, killing all 72 aboard.</p>

<p>That was Nepal's deadliest since 1992 when all 167 people aboard a Pakistan International Airlines plane were killed when it crashed on approach to Kathmandu airport.</p>

<p>A Thai Airways aircraft crashed near the same airport earlier that year, killing 113 people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e139tlig_nepal-chopper-crash-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This incident comes two weeks after a plane crash in Kathmandu killed 18 aboard. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>