<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 04:34:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-far-left-calls-for-president-emmanuel-macrons-resignation-after-no-confidence-vote-7174337]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Far-Left Calls For Macron's Resignation After No-Confidence Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-far-left-calls-for-president-emmanuel-macrons-resignation-after-no-confidence-vote-7174337]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 02:13:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[France's hard left on Wednesday urged President Emmanuel Macron to resign and hold early presidential elections after lawmakers voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's hard left on Wednesday urged President Emmanuel Macron to resign and hold early presidential elections after lawmakers voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier.</p>

<p>"We are now calling on Macron to go," Mathilde Panot, the head of the parliamentary faction of the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) party told reporters, urging "early presidential elections" to solve a deepening political crisis.a</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/2qf344e8_emmanuel-macron-reuters-650_625x300_26_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[France's hard-left also urged President Emmanuel Macron to hold early presidential elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/700-bangladeshi-terrorists-death-row-convicts-still-on-run-after-jailbreaks-7174244]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[700 Bangladeshi Terrorists, Death Row Convicts Still On Run After Jailbreak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/700-bangladeshi-terrorists-death-row-convicts-still-on-run-after-jailbreaks-7174244]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 01:50:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Around 700 Bangladeshi prison inmates were still on the run after mass jailbreaks over the summer during the student-led revolution that ousted autocratic ex-prime minister Sheikh Hasina, authorities said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Around 700 Bangladeshi prison inmates were still on the run after mass jailbreaks over the summer during the student-led revolution that ousted autocratic ex-prime minister Sheikh Hasina, authorities said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina fled in August to India, where she remains, as her government collapsed at the peak of a popular revolt.</p>

<p>In the weeks before her departure, revolts or sieges by protesters at five prisons around the Muslim-majority nation saw roughly 2,200 inmates break out of their cells.</p>

<p>Prisons chief Syed Mohammad Motaher Hossain told reporters that around 1,500 of that number had since been captured, with the remainder still at large.</p>

<p>Hossain said that at least 70 fugitives were either "terrorists" or "death row convicts".</p>

<p>Hundreds of people marched on a jail in the city of Narsingdi east of the capital Dhaka on July 19, setting the facility on fire and setting hundreds of inmates free.</p>

<p>Four more prisons were also attacked in the following weeks including a high security facility at Kashimpur, home to some of the country's most notorious criminals.</p>

<p>Police spokesman Imam Hossain Sagar said efforts to track the remaining escapees were ongoing.</p>

<p>"We have instructed all the police stations to stay alert and arrest the escaped prisoners," he said.</p>

<p>Sagar added that police were also closely monitoring several "top terrorists" granted bail by courts following Hasina's ouster.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fh1k7t2o_jail-generic-getty_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Around 700 Bangladeshi prison inmates are still on the run after mass jailbreaks. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-lawmakers-oust-pm-michel-barnier-in-no-confidence-vote-7174153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Lawmakers Oust PM Michel Barnier In No-Confidence Vote]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-lawmakers-oust-pm-michel-barnier-in-no-confidence-vote-7174153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 01:15:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French lawmakers on Wednesday voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier after just three months in office in a move which deepens a political crisis in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French lawmakers on Wednesday voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier after just three months in office, a historic move which plunged the country further into political chaos.</p>

<p>For the first time in over sixty years, the National Assembly lower house toppled the incumbent government, approving a no-confidence motion that had been proposed by the hard left but which crucially was backed by the far-right headed by Marine Le Pen.</p>

<p>Barnier's rapid ejection from office comes after snap parliamentary elections this summer which resulted in a hung parliament with no party having an overall majority and the far-right holding the key to the government's survival.</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron now has the unenviable choice of picking a viable successor with over two years of his presidential term left.</p>

<p>The National Assembly debated a motion brought by the hard left in a standoff over next year's austerity budget, after the prime minister on Monday forced through a social security financing bill without a vote.</p>

<p>With the support of the far-right, a majority of 331 MPs in the 577-member chamber voted to oust the government.</p>

<p>Speaker Yael Braun-Pivet confirmed Barnier would now have to "submit his resignation" to Macron and declared the session closed.</p>

<p>Macron flew back into Paris just ahead of the vote after wrapping up his three-day state visit to Saudi Arabia, an apparent world away from the domestic crisis.</p>

<p>He strolled earlier Wednesday through the desert sands of the Al-Ula oasis, an iconic tourist project of the kingdom, marvelling at ancient landmarks. After landing, he headed direct to the Elysee Palace.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, Macron accused Le Pen's far-right of "unbearable cynicism" in backing the motion.</p>

<p>No new elections can be called within a year of last summer's vote, narrowing Macron's options.</p>

<p>Laurent Wauquiez, the head of right-wing deputies in parliament, said the far-right and hard-left bore the responsibility for a no-confidence vote that will "plunge the country into instability".</p>

<p>- 'His failure' -</p>

<p>Some have suggested Macron himself should resign to break the impasse.</p>

<p>But Macron rejected those calls, saying such a scenario amounted to "political fiction".</p>

<p>"It's frankly not up to scratch to say these things," Macron said during his trip to Saudi.</p>

<p>Eric Coquerel, a hard-left MP, said the motion against Barnier sounded the "death knell of Emmanuel Macron's mandate".</p>

<p>With markets nervous and France bracing for public-sector strikes over the threat of cutbacks that will shut schools and hit air and rail traffic, there is a growing sense of crisis.</p>

<p>The unions have called for civil servants, including teachers and air traffic controllers, to strike on Thursday over separate cost-cutting measures proposed by their respective ministries this autumn.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Macron is due to host a major international event Saturday with the reopening of the Notre-Dame cathedral after the 2019 fire, with guests including Donald Trump on his first foreign trip since he was elected to be the next US president.</p>

<p>"His failure," was left-wing daily Liberation's front-page headline, with a picture of Macron, whose term runs until 2027.</p>

<p>- 'Shattered strategy' -</p>

<p>But in an editorial, Le Monde said Le Pen's move risked upsetting her own supporters, such as retirees and business leaders, by toppling the government.</p>

<p>"In the space of a few minutes, she shattered the strategy of normalisation she had consistently pursued," the daily said.</p>

<p>Some observers have suggested that Le Pen, 56, is seeking to bring down Macron before his term ends by ousting Barnier.</p>

<p>Le Pen is embroiled in a high-profile embezzlement trial. If found guilty in March, she could be blocked from participating in France's next presidential election.</p>

<p>But if Macron stepped down soon, an election would have to be called within a month, potentially ahead of the verdict in her trial.</p>

<p>Candidates for the post of premier are few and far between, but loyalist Defence Minister Sebastien Lecornu and Macron's centrist ally Francois Bayrou are possible contenders.</p>

<p>On the left, Macron could turn to former Socialist premier and interior minister Bernard Cazeneuve, a contender in September.</p>

<p>Macron is minded to appoint the new premier rapidly, several sources told AFP.</p>

<p>It was the first successful no-confidence vote since a defeat for Georges Pompidou's government in 1962, when Charles de Gaulle was president. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The lifespan of Barnier's government is also the shortest of any administration since the Fifth Republic began in 1958.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/p06fhas8_michel-barnier-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[French lawmakers on Wednesday voted to oust the government of Prime Minister Michel Barnier.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/martial-law-most-searched-word-on-google-in-south-korea-7174065]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Martial Law' Most-Searched Word On Google In South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/martial-law-most-searched-word-on-google-in-south-korea-7174065]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:48:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Korean term for "martial law" was the most-searched word on Google in South Korea on Wednesday, following President Yoon Suk Yeol's short-lived declaration of martial law.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Korean term for "martial law" was the most-searched word on Google in South Korea on Wednesday, following President Yoon Suk Yeol's short-lived declaration of martial law.</p>

<p>The word topped Google's trends chart with the search volume over the past 24 hours surpassing the 2 million mark, up more than a thousand percent from a day ago.</p>

<p>"Currency exchange rate" and "Kim Yong-hyun," the name of the South Korean defense minister who reportedly proposed declaring the martial law to the president, ranked second and third on the trends chart, respectively, reports Yonhap news agency.</p>

<p>Yoon declared martial law late on Tuesday night, accusing the opposition of paralyzing the government with "anti-state activities," but lifted it hours later after the National Assembly voted to call for its end.</p>

<p>With the nation in shock over the incident, the news page of South Korea's largest internet portal, Naver, saw all-time high traffic overnight, according to its operator.</p>

<p>The surge briefly disrupted some of its functions, but service was quickly normalised.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Yeol on Wednesday held a meeting with Prime Minister Han Duck-soo and leaders of the ruling People Power Party (PPP) to discuss follow-up measures after opposition parties submitted an impeachment motion in response to the short-lived martial law declaration.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Han, PPP leader Han Dong-hoon and floor leader Choo Kyung-ho convened at the presidential office just hours after the opposition submitted the motion, following the National Assembly's rejection of the martial law declaration earlier in the day.</p>

<p>"They seriously discussed the current situation, and there was no difference in opinions," a senior presidential official said, adding Yoon's potential departure from the party was not a topic of discussion during the meeting.</p>

<p>The main opposition Democratic Party and five other minor parties plan to report the motion to a parliamentary plenary session on Thursday and put it up for a vote as early as Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/hussm8bg_south-korea-police_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 'martial law' word topped Google's trends chart with the search volume over the past 24 hours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-one-of-the-wisest-persons-in-world-says-kuwait-foreign-minister-7174000]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi One Of The Wisest Persons In World, Says Kuwait Foreign Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-one-of-the-wisest-persons-in-world-says-kuwait-foreign-minister-7174000]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:27:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Calling India a "very important partner", Kuwait's Foreign Minister Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya on Wednesday heaped praise on Prime Minister Narendra Modi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling India a "very important partner", Kuwait's Foreign Minister Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya on Wednesday heaped praise on Prime Minister Narendra Modi, saying that the West Asian nation believes that the Indian leader is one of the wisest persons in the world.</p>

<p>"I would like to thank you for the invitation and also for the opportunity of meeting Prime Minister Modi, who we believe is one of the wisest persons worldwide. I am sure that the Prime Minister puts India on a better level, and I am sure that he will continue that... India is a very important partner and we count on our relationship," the visiting Foreign Minister said in his opening remarks at the delegation-level meeting with External Affairs Minister (EAM) S. Jaishankar in New Delhi on Wednesday evening.</p>

<p>Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya arrived in India late Tuesday night for an official visit that aims at further strengthening the multifaceted relationship between the two countries.</p>

<p>In the afternoon, he made a courtesy call on PM Modi at his Lok Kalyan Marg residence before holding a meeting with EAM Jaishankar at the Hyderabad House.</p>

<p>"Glad to receive Foreign Minister of Kuwait Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya. I thank the Kuwaiti leadership for the welfare of the Indian nationals. India is committed to advance our deep-rooted and historical ties for the benefit of our people and the region," PM Modi posted on X after the meeting.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Glad to receive Foreign Minister of Kuwait H.E. Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya. I thank the Kuwaiti leadership for the welfare of the Indian nationals. India is committed to advance our deep-rooted and historical ties for the benefit of our people and the region. <a href="https://t.co/hR5URxPyt5">pic.twitter.com/hR5URxPyt5</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1864309806439518358?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>India and Kuwait share a historically strong bilateral relationship that has stood the test of time. Rooted in centuries of trade and cultural exchange, the partnership predates Kuwait's independence in 1961, during which the Indian Rupee served as its legal tender.</p>

<p>"I think the Joint Committee will solve many issues between Kuwait and India. I think we can draw a roadmap between Kuwait and India and proceed as fast as we can," said Abdullah Ali Al-Yahya.</p>

<p>Kuwait's economy, before the discovery of oil, thrived on maritime activities, including shipbuilding, pearl diving, and trading goods like Arabian horses, dates, and pearls with India in exchange for wood, spices, and textiles.</p>

<p>This legacy of cooperation was commemorated during the 60th anniversary of diplomatic relations between the two countries in 2021-22.</p>

<p>The Indian community, estimated to be one million strong, forms the largest expatriate group in Kuwait. Known for their diverse contributions, Indians hold roles across various fields, from engineering, medicine, and IT to business and trade.</p>

<p>The robust Indian business community in Kuwait, comprising retailers, distributors, and professionals, has played a pivotal role in strengthening economic ties.</p>

<p>Prominent Indian brands like Lulu Hypermarket and Centre Point have become integral to the Kuwaiti market.</p>

<p>Cultural and social engagement also thrives through more than 200 Indian associations registered with the Indian Embassy in Kuwait. These groups actively organise programs to promote cultural exchange and community welfare, further solidifying the people-to-people connection between the nations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/6qgnjgcg_pm-modi-kuwait-foreign-minister_625x300_05_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["India is a very important partner," said Kuwait's Foreign Minister.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-palestine-hamas-threatens-to-neutralise-hostages-if-israel-conducts-rescue-operation-7173874]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Threatens To "Neutralise" Hostages If Israel Conducts Rescue Op]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-palestine-hamas-threatens-to-neutralise-hostages-if-israel-conducts-rescue-operation-7173874]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:52:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas said it had information that Israel intended to carry out a hostage rescue operation similar to one conducted in Gaza's Nuseirat camp in June and threatened to "neutralise" the captives if any such action took place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas said it had information that Israel intended to carry out a hostage rescue operation similar to one conducted in Gaza's Nuseirat camp in June and threatened to "neutralise" the captives if any such action took place, according to an internal statement seen by Reuters on Wednesday.</p>

<p>In the statement dated November 22, Hamas told its operatives not to consider what the repercussions of following the instructions might be and said it held Israel responsible for the fate of the hostages.</p>

<p>The statement, which a senior Hamas source told Reuters was circulated to its factions by the intelligence unit of the group's military wing Izz el-Deen al-Qassam Brigades, did not say when any Israeli operation was expected to take place.</p>

<p>There was no immediate Israeli response to the statement. On Wednesday, Israeli media cited Defence Minister Israel Katz as saying pressure on Hamas was increasing and this time "we will really be able to advance a hostage deal".</p>

<p>Israel's Nuseirat rescue operation on June 9 saw Israeli forces free four hostages, who had been held by Hamas since October 2023, in a raid Palestinian officials said killed more than 200 people, making it one of the bloodiest Israeli assaults of the war.</p>

<p>In the Hamas statement, the group told its operatives to "tighten" the living conditions of the captives and said this should be done in accordance with instructions issued after the Nuseirat operation.</p>

<p>In a section titled "recommendations", Hamas also instructed its operatives to "activate neutralisation orders ... as an immediate and swift response to any adventure by the enemy."</p>

<p>Israel launched its campaign in Gaza after Hamas-led fighters attacked Israeli communities across the border on October 7, 2023, killing 1,200 people and taking over 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign has since killed more than 44,500 Palestinians and injured many others, according to Palestinian figures. The offensive has reduced much of Gaza to rubble.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ffef62o_gaza_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's Nuseirat rescue operation on June 9 saw Israeli forces free four hostages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-tackles-child-abuse-images-after-founders-arrest-7173811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram Tackles Child Abuse Images After Founder's Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-tackles-child-abuse-images-after-founders-arrest-7173811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:42:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Messaging app Telegram will deploy new tools to prevent the spread of images of child sexual abuse after teaming up with the Internet Watch Foundation (IWF), the UK-based charity said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Messaging app Telegram will deploy new tools to prevent the spread of images of child sexual abuse after teaming up with the Internet Watch Foundation (IWF), the UK-based charity said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The social media platform, which claims to have more than 950 million active users per month, will use tools and data from the IWF "to detect, disrupt, remove and block child sexual abuse imagery," the charity said.</p>

<p>The move comes after Telegram's Russian-born founder and chief executive Pavel Durov was arrested in August at a Paris airport and later charged with several counts of failing to curb extremist and terrorist content on the app.</p>

<p>Prosecutors also claimed the platform had failed to take action against child sexual abuse imagery. Durov, who was released on a five-million-euro ($5.6 million) bail, later announced a crackdown on illegal content.</p>

<p>The IWF said previously it had found thousands of instances of child sexual abuse imagery on Telegram since 2022.</p>

<p>The charity is a global leader in tracking down and reporting images and videos of abuse, being one of the few non-law enforcement bodies worldwide with the legal power to search for such material.</p>

<p>It is hoped the new initiative will prevent the spread of illegal images on the public parts of Telegram's platform.</p>

<p>Derek Ray-Hill, interim CEO at the IWF, called the partnership "a transformational first step on a much longer journey".</p>

<p>"We look forward to seeing what further steps we can take together to create a world in which the spread of online sexual abuse material is virtually impossible," he added.</p>

<p>The app will now use the IWF's unique digital fingerprints of millions of known child sexual abuse images and videos to spot when criminal content is being shared.</p>

<p>IWF will also report directly to Telegram when child sexual abuse imagery is detected.</p>

<p>Remi Vaughn, head of Press and Media Relations at Telegram, said the datasets and tools "will strengthen the mechanisms Telegram has in place to protect its public platform".<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/67geepn8_telegram-ceo_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Telegram's Russian-born founder and CEO Pavel Durov was arrested in August (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-junk-food-including-cereals-muffins-burgers-7173782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Bans Daytime TV Ads For Junk Food, Including Cereals, Muffins, Burgers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-junk-food-including-cereals-muffins-burgers-7173782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:38:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK government is banning daytime TV adverts for sugary foods like granola and muffins in its battle against child obesity, branding such popular items as junk food.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK government is banning daytime TV adverts for sugary foods like granola and muffins in its battle against child obesity, branding such popular items as junk food.</p>

<p>Under measures unveiled on Tuesday, ads showing "less healthy" food and drinks will only be allowed to be aired after the 9:00 pm watershed from October next year.</p>

<p>According to the National Health Service, obesity is rising among British kids with one in 10 four-year-olds now considered to be obese. And one in five five-year-olds suffers from tooth decay from eating too much sugar.</p>

<p>Also included on the government's list -- which uses a scoring system based on each item's sugar, fat and salt content -- are pre-packaged popular sugary breakfast foods such as croissants, pancakes and waffles.</p>

<p>"Breakfast cereals including ready-to-eat cereals, granola, muesli, porridge oats and other oat-based cereals" are included, the government said.</p>

<p>Also on the banned list are products such as chickpea or lentil-based crisps, seaweed-based snacks and Bombay mix as well as energy drinks, hamburgers and chicken nuggets.</p>

<p>But the new restrictions will not apply to healthier options such as natural porridge oats and unsweetened yoghurt.</p>

<p>The government hopes the new measures could help prevent some 20,000 cases of childhood obesity a year.</p>

<p>"Obesity robs our kids of the best possible start in life, sets them up for a lifetime of health problems, and costs the NHS billions," Health Secretary Wes Streeting said.</p>

<p>"This government is taking action now to end the targeting of junk food ads at kids, across both TV and online."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-06/lamb-burger-generic_650x400_41465267882.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UK government is banning daytime TV adverts for junk food like burgers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-people-in-cuba-without-power-after-grid-collapse-7173773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millions Of People In Cuba Without Power After Grid Collapse]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-people-in-cuba-without-power-after-grid-collapse-7173773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:34:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cuba said it had begun restoring power after the island's electrical grid collapsed, the latest in a string of nationwide blackouts that underscore the increasingly frail state of the country's power generation system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cuba said it had begun restoring power after the island's electrical grid collapsed, the latest in a string of nationwide blackouts that underscore the increasingly frail state of the country's power generation system.</p>

<p>Cuba's energy minister Vicente de la O'Levy said the government had prioritized hospitals and water pumping facilities as it began restoring electricity to scattered circuits around the country.</p>

<p>But millions of Cubans across the island remained without power by midmorning, according to official reports, forcing the communist-run government to close schools and order non-official workers to stay home until electricity is restored.</p>

<p>The energy minister said he expected the system to be back online by Thursday, but said he would not rush the process.</p>

<p>"We have very capable specialists and they are all involved. We're going step by step," de la O'Levy said.</p>

<p>Cuba's grid has fallen into near-total disarray amid fuel shortages, natural disaster and economic crisis.</p>

<p>The island's oil-fired power plants, already obsolete and struggling to keep the lights on, reached a full crisis this year as oil imports from Venezuela, Russia and Mexico dwindled, contributing to multiple nationwide blackouts over two months.</p>

<p>Shortages of food, medicine, water and electricity have made life increasingly unbearable for many Cubans, who have fled the island in record-breaking numbers in the past three years.</p>

<p>Cuba blames U.S. sanctions, which complicate financial transactions and the purchase of fuel, for the crisis.</p>

<p>PLANT FAIL</p>

<p>The Wednesday morning blackout was triggered by a failure at the Antonio Guiteras power plant in Matanzas, the island's top electricity producer, which shut down at around 2 a.m. local time.</p>

<p>Several other major power plants were undergoing maintenance and were offline when the Matanzas plant failed, starving the grid of electricity and leading to the nationwide collapse, the energy minister said.</p>

<p>Millions of people across Cuba were already seeing hours-long rolling blackouts daily before Wednesday's collapse.</p>

<p>Havana hotel worker Danielis Mora woke up frustrated and confused on Wednesday, like many Havana residents, who now experience regular blackouts throughout the week.</p>

<p>"I didn't know it was a total blackout again," Mora said. "Where I am living ... there is no gas either, if there is no electricity there is no way to make food, it has to be with firewood, or charcoal."</p>

<p>Scattered protests have erupted over the past two months over the repeated power failures as well as water, gas and food shortages.</p>

<p>The system failure on Wednesday morning had left the capital Havana almost completely in the dark.</p>

<p>Officials said floating power plants, contracted from Turkey's Karpowership, were generating electricity from offshore of Havana, providing power by midmorning to hospitals and a small number of the city's 2 million residents.</p>

<p>Cuba's obsolete grid collapsed multiple times in October as fuel supplies dwindled and Hurricane Oscar struck the far eastern end of the island, then again in November with the passage of Hurricane Rafael.</p>

<p>Cuba's government last week issued a decree ordering state and private businesses to generate more of their own electricity from renewable resources. The regulations also require businesses to limit their use of air conditioning, among other measures, as the country wrestles with the increasingly dire energy crisis.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/vak2ds9o_cuba-power-outage_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cuba's grid has fallen into near-total disarray amid fuel shortages, natural disaster and economic crisis]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-settlers-raid-west-bank-towns-set-homes-buildings-on-fire-7173703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Settlers Raid West Bank Towns, Set Homes, Buildings On Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-settlers-raid-west-bank-towns-set-homes-buildings-on-fire-7173703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:21:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli settlers on Wednesday wounded a Palestinian and set buildings on fire while raiding two villages in the occupied West Bank after a nearby settlement outpost was evicted by Israeli forces, Palestinian and Israeli sources said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli settlers on Wednesday wounded a Palestinian and set buildings on fire while raiding two villages in the occupied West Bank after a nearby settlement outpost was evicted by Israeli forces, Palestinian and Israeli sources said.</p>

<p>"Israeli civilians entered the village of Beit Furik" east of the Palestinian city of Nablus, the Israeli army said, adding that they "set property on fire, and hurled stones".</p>

<p>Local authorities told AFP the attacks took place early on Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>The army said that the settlers reacted after Israeli forces "acted against illegal construction by Israeli civilians adjacent to the town of Beit Furik" on Tuesday night, triggering clashes during which the settlers injured two policemen with stones.</p>

<p>Nahi Hanani, deputy head of the Beit Furik council, told AFP that dozens of settlers attacked the village "setting fire to a truck in front of one house and another vehicle", early on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"They also set fire to a grocery shop in the village and another house was slightly damaged," he said.</p>

<p>The army said the Israelis also "set property on fire and threw stones" in Huwara, a town to the south of Nablus.</p>

<p>Rana Abu Hania, spokeswoman for Huwara's town hall, confirmed to AFP that one resident was injured when settlers attacked the town early on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"They burned two cars and the house of one citizen... The army also demolished a used car lot," said Abu Hania.</p>

<h2><strong>'THEY WOULD HAVE BURNED'</strong></h2>

<p>Yusef Awadi, a resident of Huwara, told AFP that settlers burned his brother's house Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>"They set fire to the Jeep and to the car outside... They entered the house, set it on fire, and then left," the 66-year-old said, adding that his brother Tayseer was hospitalised.</p>

<p>"He was hit on the head and... was transferred to Rafidia Hospital," Awadi told AFP, adding that had his brother's family not been awake, "they would have all burned with the house."</p>

<p>In a joint statement, the Israeli army and police said that eight suspects were arrested in the investigation into the Beit Furik and Huwara attacks, "for assaulting security forces, engaging in friction, and causing damage to property".</p>

<p>The army said that there were also clashes between the Israeli army and "about 20 Israelis" in Rujeib, a town closer to Nablus, on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The West Bank is home to some three million Palestinians as well as 490,000 Israelis who live in settlements that are considered illegal under international law.</p>

<p>Violence in the occupied Palestinian territory has soared since the war in Gaza erupted on October 7 last year after Hamas's attack on Israel.</p>

<p>Israeli troops or settlers have killed at least 788 Palestinians in the West Bank since the start of the Gaza war, according to the Ramallah-based health ministry.</p>

<p>Palestinian attacks on Israelis have also killed at least 24 people in the West Bank in the same period, according to Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel has occupied the West Bank since 1967.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/1gthe4rc_west-bank-properties-burned-afp_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Palestinian man inspects his burnt and damaged house following an attack on Wednesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-chief-sam-altman-says-elon-musk-wont-abuse-government-power-7173668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Chief Sam Altman Says Elon Musk Won't Abuse Government Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-chief-sam-altman-says-elon-musk-wont-abuse-government-power-7173668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:17:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI CEO Sam Altman expressed confidence Wednesday that Elon Musk would not use his proximity to Donald Trump to harm business rivals, calling such actions "profoundly un-American."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman expressed confidence Wednesday that Elon Musk would not use his proximity to Donald Trump to harm business rivals, calling such actions "profoundly un-American."</p>

<p>Speaking at the New York Times DealBook conference, Altman addressed concerns about Musk's announced role heading a new Department of Government Efficiency in the incoming Trump administration, and whether he might use it to favor his own companies.</p>

<p>"I may turn out to be wrong, but I believe pretty strongly that Elon will do the right thing," Altman said. "It would be profoundly un-American to use political power to hurt your competitors and advantage your own businesses."</p>

<p>Even if there are "lots of things not to like about him... it would go so deeply against the values I believe he holds very dear to himself that I'm not that worried about it."</p>

<p>Musk, an OpenAI co-founder who later departed the company, is currently suing OpenAI and Microsoft, claiming they shifted from the project's original nonprofit mission.</p>

<p>He has since launched xAI, reportedly valued at $50 billion, according to the Wall Street Journal, making it one of the world's most valuable startups.</p>

<p>Altman said that the court battle was "tremendously sad" and that he once saw Musk as "a mega hero."</p>

<p>Musk became a close ally of Trump during his campaign, spending over $100 million to boost his presidential bid and joining him at rallies.</p>

<p>Musk has been a frequent presence in the Trump transition and was reportedly on the line when Google CEO Sundar Pichai called the president-elect to congratulate him on winning the election.</p>

<p>The tycoon's businesses have deep connections with US and foreign governments, and his new position has raised concerns about conflict of interest.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/brgta8s8_elon-musk-sam-altman_625x300_07_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Musk, an OpenAI co-founder who later departed the company, is currently suing OpenAI (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-frees-nobel-winner-narges-mohammadi-for-3-weeks-on-medical-grounds-7173603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Frees Nobel Winner Narges Mohammadi For 3 Weeks On Medical Grounds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-frees-nobel-winner-narges-mohammadi-for-3-weeks-on-medical-grounds-7173603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:09:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranian authorities on Wednesday freed Nobel peace prize winner Narges Mohammadi from prison for three weeks on medical grounds, a move supporters decried as "too little too late" with the Nobel committee urging a permanent release.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranian authorities on Wednesday freed Nobel peace prize winner Narges Mohammadi from prison for three weeks on medical grounds, a move supporters decried as "too little too late" with the Nobel committee urging a permanent release.</p>

<p>Addressing reporters in Paris, Mohammadi's 18-year-old son, Ali Rahmani, said he had been able to speak by phone to his mother for the first time in two years.</p>

<p>Her lawyer Mostafa Nili earlier announced on X that her jail sentence had been "suspended" for three weeks and she had been released.</p>

<p>Her supporters said: "A 21-day suspension of Narges Mohammadi's sentence is inadequate."</p>

<p>"We demand Narges Mohammadi's immediate and unconditional release or at least an extension of her leave to three months," they said in a statement, describing the measure as "too little, too late".</p>

<p>In a sign of her defiance, her husband Taghi Rahmani told reporters in Paris that Mohammadi shouted "Woman Life Freedom" after her release, the slogan of the 2022-2023 protest movement thatNarges Mohammadi rocked the Islamic authorities.</p>

<p>"She came out chanting the slogan Woman Life Freedom," he said.</p>

<p>"She came out in a good state of mind, a combative state despite her very fragile state of health."</p>

<p>Mohammadi's son Rahmani told reporters that their phone exchange was brief but intense.</p>

<p>"She was able to tell me that she loves me," he said.</p>

<p>"The first thing she told me was that she'd left Evin prison without the compulsory veil," he added.</p>

<p>"What touched me the most was that she will continue to fight relentlessly against the Islamic Republic of Iran to have gender apartheid recognised as a universal crime throughout the world, and that she will also continue to fight against the death penalty."</p>

<p>Mohammadi has been jailed since November 2021 over several past convictions relating to her advocacy against the obligatory hijab for women and capital punishment in Iran.</p>

<p>She has not seen her husband and twin children for several years and has spent much of the last decade in and out of prison.</p>

<p><strong>'Denial of medical care'</strong></p>

<p>Supporters said her release did not even amount to a medical furlough and was merely a suspension, meaning Mohammadi would have to serve "an additional 21 days" on her return to Tehran's Evin prison.</p>

<p>The head of the Norwegian Nobel Committee, Jorgen Watne Frydnes, told reporters: "We call upon the Iranian authorities to permanently end her imprisonment and ensure that she will get adequate medical treatment for her illnesses."</p>

<p>Mohammadi, who won last year's Nobel Peace Prize for her work campaigning for human rights in Iran, had last month undergone bone surgery, including a bone graft, for a non-malignant growth.</p>

<p>"The denial of proper medical care and sufficient recovery time post-surgery has led to the rapid development of bedsores and intensified pain in her back and legs," her supporters and family said.</p>

<p>"After over a decade of imprisonment, Narges requires specialised medical care in a safe, sanitary environment -- a basic human right," they added.</p>

<p>Lawyer Nili said the prosecutor allowed the release based on medical advice due to "her physical condition after the removal of a tumour and a bone graft three weeks ago."</p>

<p>"The tumour was benign but she needs check-ups every three months," he added.</p>

<p>Behind bars and deprived of the right to speak to her family in France, Mohammadi had refused to give up campaigning, staging protests in the yard of Evin prison and going on hunger strikes.</p>

<p>In a letter from prison in September, she condemned the "devastating oppression" of women in Iran.</p>

<p>Mohammadi was a strong supporter of the 2022-2023 protests, calling for the ousting of the Islamic authorities under Ayatollah Ali Khamenei.</p>

<p>In June, she was sentenced to an additional year behind bars for "propaganda against the state".</p>

<p>She refused to appear in court for the trial after her request for it to be held in public was rejected.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/13c0nn4c_jailed-iranian-womens-rights-activist-narges-mohammadi_625x300_31_October_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narges Mohammadi has been jailed since November 2021 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-names-billionaire-private-astronaut-jared-isaacman-as-next-nasa-chief-7173527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Names Billionaire Private Astronaut Jared Isaacman As Next NASA Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-names-billionaire-private-astronaut-jared-isaacman-as-next-nasa-chief-7173527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 22:57:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump on Wednesday nominated Jared Isaacman, the online payments billionaire and the first private astronaut to ever perform a spacewalk, as the next head of NASA.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Wednesday nominated Jared Isaacman, the online payments billionaire and the first private astronaut to ever perform a spacewalk, as the next head of NASA.</p>

<p>The nod could spark questions about potential conflicts of interest, given Isaacman's extensive financial ties to Elon Musk, who is set to co-chair a government efficiency commission and is one of Trump's closest advisors.</p>

<p>Isaacman, 41, the founder and CEO of Shift4 Payments, has emerged as a leading figure in commercial spaceflight through his high-profile collaborations with Musk's SpaceX.</p>

<p>His achievements include stepping out of a Crew Dragon to gaze at Earth from the void of space, while clutching the spacecraft's exterior, back in September.</p>

<p>"I am delighted to nominate Jared Isaacman, an accomplished business leader, philanthropist, pilot and astronaut, as Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)," Trump wrote on Truth Social.</p>

<p>"Jared will drive NASA's mission of discovery and inspiration, paving the way for groundbreaking achievements in Space science, technology, and exploration."</p>

<p>The historic spacewalk took place under the Polaris program, a collaboration between Isaacman and SpaceX that is set to include three missions in total.</p>

<p>Financial terms of the partnership remain under wraps but Isaacman reportedly poured $200 million of his own money into leading the 2021 all-civilian SpaceX Inspiration4 orbital mission, his first foray into space.</p>

<p>He is also a vocal supporter of SpaceX and Musk, frequently praising the company and its vision on the platform X.</p>

<p>"There will inevitably be a thriving space economy -- one that will create opportunities for countless people to live and work in space," Isaacman said in a post after Trump's announcement.</p>

<p>"At NASA, we will passionately pursue these possibilities."</p>

<p>Isaacman, a Pennsylvania native, founded the business that became Shift4 Payments from his family's basement at just 16.</p>

<p>A skilled aviator, he is qualified to fly military aircraft, has performed in airshows, and set a world record for an around-the-world flight.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/tirtt4m8_jared-isaacman-afp_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jared Isaacman, 41, is the founder and CEO of Shift4 Payments]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-sinks-in-chaos-as-police-raid-opposition-offices-7173428]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgia Sinks In Chaos As Police Raid Opposition Offices]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-sinks-in-chaos-as-police-raid-opposition-offices-7173428]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 22:40:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The protests have turned violent, with around 300 people detained and dozens injured in clashes between protesters and police, outside the parliament building in Tbilisi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Georgia's political crisis deepened on Wednesday as police raided opposition party offices, sparking widespread condemnation.</p>

<p>The raids came after Prime Minister Irakli Kobakhidze vowed to crack down on pro-EU protests, which have rocked the capital city of Tbilisi since the disputed October 26 parliamentary election.</p>

<p>"It is clear to everyone that these violent actions are entirely coordinated by the radical opposition... No one will escape accountability, including the politicians hiding in their offices," Prime Minister Kobakhidze said, adding that "radical" political forces are responsible for the protests.</p>

<p>Soon after, the Georgian police beat and arrested the leader of Akhali liberal opposition party and also conducted a raid on the offices of the Droa party.</p>

<p>Droa leader Elene Khoshtaria posted on X: "They are now in our party office, searching. Likely hoping to find something to charge some of our members with trumped-up charges."</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of protesters have taken to the streets, alleging election fraud and denouncing the government's decision to suspend EU membership talks until 2028.</p>

<p>The protests have turned violent, with around 300 people detained and dozens injured in clashes between protesters and police, outside the parliament building in Tbilisi.</p>

<p>The government's actions have been widely criticised, with opposition leaders accusing the authorities of using "torture" against detained protesters and launching "all-out terror and repressions" against opponents. The US and EU have also condemned the government's actions, with several ambassadors and a deputy foreign minister resigning in protest.</p>

<p>The crisis has exposed deep divisions within Georgian society, with the ruling Georgian Dream party accused of moving closer to Moscow despite strong anti-Russian sentiment. The party has advanced Russia-style legislation targeting civil society and independent media outlets, as well as curbing LGBTQ rights.</p>

<p>Although Russia and Georgia do not have formal diplomatic relations, since both of the countries fought in 2008, foreign ministry spokesperson Maria Zakharova said Wednesday that Moscow was open to developing closer ties with Tbilisi.</p>

<p>As the situation continues to escalate, there are fears that the government's actions could have long-term consequences for Georgia's democracy and its relations with the EU.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/b4fhcdq8_georgia-protest-afp_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of protesters have taken to the streets, alleging election fraud]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-joins-chinas-belt-and-road-initiative-raises-concerns-for-new-delhi-7173147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepal Joins China's Belt And Road Initiative, Raises Concerns For New Delhi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-joins-chinas-belt-and-road-initiative-raises-concerns-for-new-delhi-7173147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 22:03:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A significant agreement was signed in Beijing today paving the way for China to make major inroads in Nepal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A significant agreement was signed in Beijing today paving the way for China to make major inroads in Nepal. Seven years after an initial understanding for Kathmandu to be part of Beijing's Belt and Road Initiative or BRI, today's agreement lays the framework of how projects will be executed.</p>

<p>Breaking tradition of making New Delhi a Nepalese prime minister's first port of call after election results, KP Sharma Oli chose to visit Beijing instead. He has been in China since Monday to work closely with Xi Jinping and finalise the deal.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/4bccifok_nepal-china-bilateral-talks_625x300_04_December_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>China and Nepal have "signed the framework for Belt and Road Cooperation today," Nepal's foreign office said in a post on X today, but shared no further details.</p>

<p>Sources familiar with the agreement have said that today's deal means both countries will not plan and coordinate the details of each project. It also paves the way for China to fund these projects and how exactly each project would be financed by Beijing.</p>

<blockquote align="center" class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Government of Nepal and the Government of the People's Republic of China signed the Framework for Belt and Road Cooperation today. <a href="https://t.co/6oTlDvTzIe">pic.twitter.com/6oTlDvTzIe</a></p>
— MOFA of Nepal ?? (@MofaNepal) <a href="https://twitter.com/MofaNepal/status/1864210839940812810?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>In 2017, Nepal had agreed in-principle to be part of China's mega Belt and Road project - a massive network of roads, transport corridors, airports, and rail lines connecting China with the rest of Asia, Europe and beyond. However, no progress was made in the last seven years because of the lack of a proper framework of executing them. Kathmandu also struggled to find political consensus on the issue. That now seems to have been addressed with today's pact.</p>

<p>China's Belt and Road Initiative, though ambitious, has been a red flag for many countries due to Beijing's suspicious dealings and ulterior motives. Several countries have fallen in a debt trap, often called China's "debt diplomacy" wherein China builds a mega project on credit in a smaller country in terms of economy, and when the country cannot pay back the loan or interest, Beijing either takes over the project for a lifetime or cuts a deal to forward its expansionist agenda.</p>

<p>China's Belt and Road Initiative has also had a history of ignoring the national security concerns and violating the sovereignty of other nations.</p>

<p>Several leaders in Nepal's government and opposition are concerned over debt concerns mounting in an already-stretched economy. Even within Prime Minister Oli's government, there is fierce debate over the potential risks in mega projects executed by China. Nepal Congress, which is a key ally of PM Oli's party, has vehemently opposed any projects funded by Chinese loans.</p>

<p>China had funded the airport project in Pokhra - Nepal's second-largest city - by loaning more than $200 million. Nepal went ahead with the project despite India raising serious concerns and opened the airport last year.</p>

<p>But the airport has had to deal with losses due to lack of international flights. This can partially be due to a slender demand for airlines, but also due to India's refusal to planes using its airspace to do so.</p>

<p>Pokhra, located around 120 kilometers from Kathmandu, is less than 20 minutes from the India border by commercial flight. India had to shut its airspace out of a national security compulsion because Kathmandu ignored New Delhi's concerns that China may use the airport to station its military aircraft and helicopters - a massive national security threat for New Delhi.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/3avksduc_nepal-pm-kp-sharma-oli-meets-xi-jinping-twitter_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nepal's Prime Minister KP Sharma Oli met Chinese President Xi Jinping in Beijing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/108-metre-chunri-offered-to-temple-as-nepal-city-celebrates-ram-sita-wedding-7173084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[108 Metre "Chunri" Offered To Temple As Nepal City Celebrates Ram-Sita Wedding]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/108-metre-chunri-offered-to-temple-as-nepal-city-celebrates-ram-sita-wedding-7173084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:54:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to the Janaki Temple of Nepal by a trust from Surat (Gujarat, India) on the occasion of 'Bibah Panchami', marking the wedding of Lord Ram with Goddess Sita.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to the Janaki Temple of Nepal by a trust from Surat (Gujarat, India) on the occasion of 'Bibah Panchami', marking the wedding of Lord Ram with Goddess Sita.</p>

<p>The event set for Friday is the first 'Bibah Panchami' to be held in the city after the Pran Pratishtha at Ram Temple in Ayodhya, Uttar Pradesh.</p>

<p>Stretching far and wide the red-coloured Chunri which was sent by Jin Mata Trust has toured the ancient historic city of Janakpur.</p>

<p>"Today for the first time from Surat (Gujarat, India) Jin Mata Trust has sent 108 meters long Chunri (shawl) to Janakpur. It is the first time that it has been brought to Janakpur, the People of Janakpur are elated that it can't be explained in words and they extended their full support. People took part in the Shobha Yatra and we want to see this continued further with devotees sending it to Janaki Temple and we offer it to the goddess," Manoj Rungata, Chairman of Sitaram Gaushala who facilitated in bringing the Chunri to Janakpur told ANI.</p>

<p>Janakpur, the paternal home of Hindu Goddess Sita is filled with festivity and grandeur ahead of the 'Bibah Panchami' event scheduled for Friday, this week.</p>

<p>This will be the first Bibah Panchami celebrations to be held after the Pranpratistha of Ram Mandir in Ayodhya earlier this year. Every year, on the fifth day of the Margashirsha month, devotees celebrate Bibah Panchami, the day of the divine wedding.</p>

<p>"On the occasion of Bibah Panchami 2081 (2024), a Chunri measuring 108 meters has been offered to Mata Janaki after a de-tour of the Janakpur city. Jin Mata (Trust) has till now offered Chunri in over 475 Bhagwati temples. Today the 476th Chunri that came via the Sitaram Gaushala has been offered to Mata Janaki on the occasion of Bibah Panchami after touring around the city," Nirmal Chaudhary, Chairman of Marwadi Sewa Samiti told ANI.</p>

<p>On Tuesday the Barat of Lord Ram arrived in Janakpur with great pomp and show. Around 500 devotees from Ayodhya, who have come from various corners of India, arrived at Janakpur Dham as baratis at the wedding of Lord Ram.</p>

<p>Forty Vedic Brahmins from Tirupati will be performing the marriage of Sita-Ram in Janakpur Dham. These Vedic Brahmins will directly reach Janakpur to conduct the marriage rituals.</p>

<p>According to the scriptures, Lord Ram, son of King Dasharath of Ayodhya married Goddess Sita, daughter of King Janak of Janakpurdham during the Treta epoch. The marriage was solemnized in Janakpurdham.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/85liros8_janaki-temple-nepal_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Janakpur is the paternal home of Hindu Goddess Sita (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/up-man-given-death-penalty-in-saudi-arabia-on-drug-charges-family-pleads-for-mercy-7172972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UP Man Given Death Penalty In Saudi On Drug Charges, Family Pleads For Mercy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/up-man-given-death-penalty-in-saudi-arabia-on-drug-charges-family-pleads-for-mercy-7172972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:39:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Saudi Arabia has sentenced a man from Meerut in Uttar Pradesh to death on charges of drug trafficking, triggering panic and despair among his family members who have pleaded for clemency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>A court in Saudi Arabia has sentenced a man from Meerut in Uttar Pradesh to death on charges of drug trafficking, triggering panic and despair among his family members who have pleaded for clemency.</p>

<p>Meerut Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP) Vipin Tada on Wednesday confirmed receiving a letter in this regard from the Indian consulate in Saudi Arabia via the district administration.</p>

<p>"The letter said Zaid Junaid, a resident of Rachauti village under the Mundali police station area, has been sentenced to death by a court in Mecca for drug smuggling. His family members have been informed about the option of filing a mercy plea," the SSP said.</p>

<p>A notice was also pasted at the entrance of the family house to ensure they were aware of the situation.</p>

<p>Zaid's father Zubair, a farmer, and mother Rehana became inconsolable on hearing the news.</p>

<p>His elder brother Suhail said, "My father has already requested the Indian government to file a mercy plea with the Saudi authorities. The application was submitted on Tuesday." Aged around 35 and the second of seven brothers, Zaid moved to Saudi Arabia in 2018 to work as a driver for a company.</p>

<p>Initially employed by one firm, he later joined Al-Zafar Company, his family members said.</p>

<p>His troubles began when his vehicle was stolen, and was recovered by Saudi police three days later. Subsequently, the vehicle got damaged in a road accident, leading his employer to file a lawsuit to recover the costs.</p>

<p>Unable to bear the financial burden, Zaid left the company and began working as the personal driver for a Saudi police officer, the family said.</p>

<p>However, three months into his new job, Zaid was allegedly implicated in a drug smuggling case after police claimed to have found 700 gm of narcotics from the vehicle he was driving, the family said.</p>

<p>He was arrested on January 15, 2023, and has been imprisoned at the Jeddah Central Jail since then.</p>

<p>"My brother has been framed. He was just doing his job as a driver. We hope the Indian government intervenes and saves his life," Suhail said.</p>

<p>Zaid's father Zubair said, "We've never faced such trouble before. All we want now is Zaid to return alive." Another elder brother of Zaid, Naeem Khan Faisal, who also works as a driver in Saudi Arabia, is in touch with the family to the coordinate efforts for his release.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jqjk6bh_jail-generic_625x300_21_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zaid Junaid's father Zubair said, "We've never faced such trouble before. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-new-york-gunman-at-large-7172850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[United Healthcare CEO Brian Thompson Shot Dead In New York, Gunman At Large]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-healthcare-ceo-brian-thompson-shot-dead-in-new-york-gunman-at-large-7172850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:22:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, 50, was shot in Manhattan just before 7 am at a hotel. The shooter fled the scene of the crime after the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brian Thompson, the CEO of one of the largest health insurance companies, UnitedHealthcare, was fatally shot in the chest in New York on Wednesday according to US media reports.</p>

<p>According to the New York Times, Thompson, 50, was shot in Manhattan just before 7 am at a hotel. The shooter fled the scene of the crime after the attack. Thompson was rushed to the hospital in an unconscious and unresponsive state but was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the New York Hilton Midtown said, "We are deeply saddened by this morning's events in the area and our thoughts are with all affected by the tragedy. Additional questions should be directed to the New York Police Department."</p>

<p>The company was scheduled to hold its investor day but cancelled it after reports of the shooting emerged.</p>

<p>"I'm afraid that we - some of you may know we're dealing with a very serious medical situation with one of our team members," UnitedHealth Group staff said. "And as a result, I'm afraid we're going to have to bring to a close the event today, which I'm sure you'll understand."</p>

<p>As per a report in CNBC, the suspect was a white male, wearing black hoodie, black pants and black sneakers with a white trim and a gray backpack. The suspect is also described as possessing a firearm with a silencer.</p>

<p>The investigation is ongoing and no arrests have been made.</p>

<p>The UnitedHealth Group ranks 5th on Fortune 500 and this news has left many in the healthcare and business communities shocked.</p>

<p>Brian Thompson had been the CEO of UnitedHealthcare since April 2021. Before this he led their government programs including Medicare &amp; Retirement and Community &amp; State divisions.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/49kchst_brian-thompson-reuters_625x300_04_December_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brian Thompson, the CEO of UnitedHealthcare, was fatally shot in the chest in New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-involved-in-genocide-sheikh-hasina-in-1st-public-address-7172709]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Muhammad Yunus Involved In Genocide": Sheikh Hasina In 1st Public Address]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-involved-in-genocide-sheikh-hasina-in-1st-public-address-7172709]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 21:03:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has mounted a stinging attack on the country's interim leader Muhammad Yunus over alleged persecution of minorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has mounted a stinging attack on the country's interim leader Muhammad Yunus over alleged persecution of minorities.</p>

<p>In a virtual address at an event in New York, Sheikh Hasina accused Muhammad Yunus of perpetrating "genocide" and failing to protect minorities including Hindus. She also claimed that there were plans to assassinate her and her sister Sheikh Rehana just like their father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.</p>

<p>Mujibur Rahman was assassinated in 1975.</p>

<p>It was Sheikh Hasina's first public address after taking shelter in India following her resignation in August in the face of massive anti-government protests, though she had commented on the overall situation in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"The armed protestors were directed towards Ganabhaban. If the security guards opened fire, many lives would have been lost. It was a matter of 25-30 minutes, and I was forced to leave. I told them [guards] not to fire no matter what happened," she said referring to the storming of her official residence in Dhaka on August 5.</p>

<p>"Today, I am being accused of genocide. In reality, Yunus has been involved in genocide in a meticulously designed manner. The masterminds -- the student coordinators and Yunus -- are behind this genocide," she said at the event on Sunday.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina said the current ruling dispensation in Dhaka failed to protect the minorities.</p>

<p>"Hindus, Buddhists, Christians -- no one has been spared. Eleven churches have been razed, temples and Buddhist shrines have been broken. When the Hindus protested, the Iskcon leader was arrested," she said in an oblique reference to the arrest of Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das.</p>

<p>"What is this persecution of minorities for? Why are they being ruthlessly persecuted and attacked?" she said.</p>

<p>"People no longer have the right to justice... I never even got the time to resign," she said speaking in Bengali.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina said she left Bangladesh in August with an aim to stop the violence, but that did not happen.</p>

<p>The relations between India and Bangladesh came under strain after the interim government headed by Muhammad Yunus came to power. India has been expressing concerns over attacks on minorities, especially Hindus, in that country.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina has been staying in India since she left Bangladesh following massive anti-government protests in July and August.</p>

<p>In her speech at the event hosted to mark Bangladesh's 'Vijay Diwas', the Awami League leader also alleged that there was a plot to assassinate her.</p>

<p>"When people were dying indiscriminately, I decided I should leave," she said.</p>

<p>There has been a spate of attacks on minorities including on the Hindu community in Bangladesh in the last few months.</p>

<p>India last week said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus.</p>

<p>New Delhi also hoped that the case relating to Das, arrested on a charge of sedition, would be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>"Our position on the matter is very clear -- the interim government must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities," MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing on Friday.</p>

<p>"We are concerned at the surge of extremist rhetoric, increasing incidents of violence and provocation. These developments cannot be dismissed only as media exaggeration. We once again call upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pp02ivl_sheikh-hasina-ians_625x300_28_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It was Sheikh Hasina's first public address after taking shelter in India (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-trapped-in-thai-well-for-three-days-as-villagers-mistake-his-cries-for-ghost-sounds-7172638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Trapped In Well For 3 Days As Villagers Mistake Cries For Ghost Sounds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-man-trapped-in-thai-well-for-three-days-as-villagers-mistake-his-cries-for-ghost-sounds-7172638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:53:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It wasn't until police dispatched rescue personnel to the forest that they heard a voice responding to their calls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a bizarre incident near the Thailand-Myanmar border, a Chinese man was trapped in an abandoned well for three days. Villagers had heard strange cries coming from a nearby forest, but mistook them for ghostly sounds, according to Thai media reports. It wasn't until police dispatched rescue personnel to the forest that they heard a voice responding to their calls. The crew located the source of the voice and found 22-year-old Liu Chuanyi at the bottom of a 12-metre-deep well, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/china/thailand-chinese-tourist-abandoned-well-rescue-b2658630.html">Independent</a></em> reported.&nbsp;The rescue operation lasted 30 minutes.</p>

<p>Mr Chuanyi was found in a weakened state and had sustained serious injuries, including a fractured wrist, cerebral concussion, and bruises, after being trapped without food or water for three days and nights. He was rescued and taken to the hospital for medical attention.</p>

<p>According to Mr Chuanyi, he strategically shouted for help once every hour, conserving his energy during his three-day ordeal. Meanwhile, nearby villagers reported hearing strange cries, which they attributed to paranormal activity. As a result, they avoided venturing outside after dark and didn't investigate the noise further.</p>

<p>Authorities believe that Mr. Liu accidentally fell into the well while attempting to navigate his way out of the forest. The circumstances surrounding Mr Liu's presence at the Thailand-Myanmar border remain a mystery, and authorities have reached out to the immigration department to investigate how he ended up in the area. In the meantime, local authorities are taking proactive measures to prevent similar incidents by sealing the well with a cover, ensuring the area is safer for everyone.</p>

<p>The incident has sparked widespread attention on Chinese social media, with many users sharing and discussing the harrowing story.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One user wrote, "A Chinese man shouting for help in the middle of nowhere? Of course, the locals can't understand the language and might think it was a wizard uttering spells."</p>

<p>Another commented, "Kudos to his strength and stamina. Struggling for three days and nights but still yelling; this guy is truly impressive."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-12/jjjd28lg_well_625x300_04_December_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was rescued and taken to the hospital for medical attention.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>