<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:39:48 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaign-for-georgia-intensifies-ahead-of-us-polls-6441590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Vs Trump: Campaign For Georgia Intensifies Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaign-for-georgia-intensifies-ahead-of-us-polls-6441590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:39:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris campaigned across southern Georgia by bus Wednesday as Democrats try to harness a surge of enthusiasm and put the swing state back in play in November's election against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris campaigned across southern Georgia by bus on Wednesday as Democrats try to harness a surge of enthusiasm and put the swing state back in play in November's election against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden had been on course to lose the southern state he flipped from Republican Trump in 2020, but since Harris replaced Biden as the candidate five weeks ago, the party has begun to hope it could win it again.</p>

<p>Both Harris and Trump are now ramping up their campaigns in seven key battleground states as an extraordinary -- and now super-short -- White House race enters its final 10-week sprint.</p>

<p>"We're seizing on the energy and putting in the work to win again in 2024," Harris's campaign said.</p>

<p>Riding a wave of enthusiasm from the Democratic National Convention last week, Harris and running mate Tim Walz are travelling through southern parts of Georgia on a two-day bus tour.</p>

<p>The blitz is focused on Black and working-class voters who the campaign believes are crucial to a Harris victory in the state in November.</p>

<p>She and Walz began their tour in Savannah, where they met students from a historically Black university, before heading by bus through rural communities where some onlookers waved Trump flags, and then stopping at Liberty County High School in Hinesville.</p>

<p>"We wanted to come by just to let you know that our country is counting on you," Harris told student marching band members there.</p>

<p>Back in Savannah the candidates ducked into Sandfly Bar-B-Q, a small restaurant where they chatted with diners and staff and posed for photographs.</p>

<p>"You have to stay in it," Harris encouraged a patron about the upcoming election.</p>

<h3><strong>'Dangerously liberal'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The bus tour culminates with a rally Thursday in Savannah, where the 59-year-old also faces a critical test on the same day: her first sit-down interview since starting her campaign, in a joint appearance on CNN with Walz.</p>

<p>Republicans have criticized her for not facing media scrutiny sooner, and Trump spokesman Jason Miller accused her on Wednesday of using Walz as a "human shield."</p>

<p>But Harris has been content to let her campaign do the talking in the frenetic weeks since the 81-year-old Biden stunned the country by bowing out.</p>

<p>She has reinvigorated the Democratic Party, raised more than half a billion dollars and wiped out Trump's lead in the polls.</p>

<p>Harris insists, however, she remains the underdog, and that the election will be won or lost in the battleground states.</p>

<p>In the last days of Biden's campaign, increasingly poor polls showed his only real remaining hope of victory was through winning the three "Rust Belt" states of Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Harris is now also targeting the four "Sun Belt" states of Georgia, Arizona, Nevada and North Carolina as a way to give her multiple ways to win the overall Electoral College vote.</p>

<p>The Peach State is a particularly tough target. Biden won it by a razor-thin margin of less than 12,000 votes in 2020, a result that Trump bitterly contested.</p>

<p>The Republican now faces criminal charges in Georgia related to his alleged plot to overturn that vote.</p>

<p>On Wednesday in an uplift for her campaign, the latest Fox News poll shows Harris edging Trump in Georgia, 50 percent to 48 percent.</p>

<p>But Trump is also stepping up his swing state campaign as he seeks to recover his poise after being wrong-footed by new flag bearer Harris.</p>

<p>The vice president is not only two decades younger than Trump and of Black and South Asian heritage, but vying to be the first female US president.</p>

<p>Trump will be attacking Harris's "dangerously liberal policies" Thursday in Michigan and Wisconsin, before traveling to Pennsylvania on Friday, the campaign said.</p>

<p>But his team was embroiled in controversy Wednesday after a report that Trump's entourage shoved and verbally abused staff during a politicized visit to the United States' most hallowed resting place for its war dead.</p>

<p>National Public Radio reported that the incident happened when an Arlington National Cemetery official tried to prevent Trump aides from taking images in a section for those killed in recent wars, where filming and staging of political events is banned.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both Kamala Harris and Donald Trump are now ramping up their campaigns in seven key battleground states.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/why-is-worlds-most-important-stock-nvidia-falling-expert-explains-6441549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Is 'World's Most Important Stock' Nvidia Falling, Expert Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/why-is-worlds-most-important-stock-nvidia-falling-expert-explains-6441549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:23:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence behemoth Nvidia on Wednesday said quarterly sales reached a higher-than-expected $30 billion in the last quarter, though that growth was slower than the furious pace seen in previous quarters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence behemoth Nvidia on Wednesday said quarterly sales reached a higher-than-expected $30 billion in the last quarter, though that growth was slower than the furious pace seen in previous quarters.</p>

<p>Declared by Wall Street to be the world's most important stock, the California-based AI chip-maker led by CEO Jensen Huang saw its share price fall by about four percent in after hours trading.</p>

<p>Even though sales and profit, which hit $16.5 billion in the period, more than doubled from a year earlier, investors showed nervousness that Nvidia's extraordinary growth, spurred by the AI frenzy, may be showing signs of normalization.</p>

<p>The world's biggest tech companies have invested tens of billions of dollars, quarter after quarter, into Nvidia's powerful AI chips and software in order to get their ChatGPT-style AI models up and running.</p>

<p>Microsoft, Google, Meta, Tesla and Amazon all depend on Nvidia technology to train generative AI models and execute the heavy computing workloads needed to deploy the new technology.</p>

<p>Ahead of the latest earnings, Nvidia's share price was up about 160 per cent year-to-date and has accounted for a third of the broad-based S&amp;P 500 index's gains this year.</p>

<p>Nvidia stock wavered in July, as investor sentiment hesitated over whether generative AI would be a money-making enterprise anytime soon.</p>

<p>But in recent weeks Nvidia's share price has been back on its historic tear, nearing the heights of a few months ago when the firm was very briefly the world's most valuable company when measured by stock valuation.</p>

<p>The market had expected the company to post sales at about $28 billion, more than double from a year ago.</p>

<p>"Nvidia once again delivered spectacular results, beating expectations with margins that rival its previous blockbuster quarters, despite growing economic uncertainties and AI bubble concerns," said Emarketer technology analyst Jacob Bourne.</p>

<p>Nvidia's financial postings have become must-see events on Wall Street after the company has repeatedly crushed expectations, many times tripling its revenue and profit.</p>

<h3><strong>'Disappointed a touch'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>But some analysts worried that Nvidia was slowly coming down to earth with its latest earnings, as stellar as they might be.</p>

<p>"It's less about just beating estimates now -- markets expect them to be shattered, and it's the scale of the beat today that looks to have disappointed a touch," said Matt Britzman, senior equity analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown.</p>

<p>Traders also focused on Nvidia's forecast that next quarter's revenue will be about $32.5 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though this was better than the average of analyst predictions, it left some observers disappointed that the days of triple-digit growth were over.</p>

<p>Investors were also laser focused on any potential delays to Nvidia's new generation Blackwell line of technology, the successor to the best-selling Hopper line of AI chips that thrust the company onto the world stage.</p>

<p>CEO Huang said the new product line would ship at scale to clients in the coming months, with its previous generation of AI chips expected to maintain very strong sales.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aqaknihg_nvidia_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The world's biggest tech companies have invested billions of dollars into Nvidia's AI chips (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/condom-use-among-european-teens-worryingly-declining-who-6441394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Condom Use Among European Teens "Worryingly" Declining: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/condom-use-among-european-teens-worryingly-declining-who-6441394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:38:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Condom use among sexually active teens has declined significantly in Europe over the past decade, with rates of unprotected sex "worryingly high", the World Health Organization said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Condom use among sexually active teens has declined significantly in Europe over the past decade, with rates of unprotected sex "worryingly high", the World Health Organization said Thursday.</p>

<p>"This is putting young people at significant risk of sexually transmitted infections (STIs) and unplanned pregnancies," WHO Europe said in a statement.</p>

<p>Data from a survey of more than 242,000 15-year-olds across 42 of the 53 countries that make up the WHO European region, which includes Central Asia, showed that the proportion of sexually active teenage boys who used a condom the last time they had sex fell from 70 percent in 2014 to 61 percent in 2022.</p>

<p>The figure for girls who said a condom had been used the last time they had sex fell from 63 to 57 percent.</p>

<p>Almost a third of adolescents said they used neither a condom nor a contraceptive pill the last time they had intercourse, largely unchanged from 2018.</p>

<p>Use of contraceptive pills also remained relatively stable between 2014 and 2022, with 26 percent of 15-year-olds reporting that they or their partner had used it the last time they had sex.</p>

<p>The report also showed that teens from low-income families were more likely to not use a condom or a pill, with 33 percent reporting using neither during their last intercourse, compared to 25 percent from more affluent families.</p>

<p>"Age-appropriate comprehensive sexuality education remains neglected in many countries, and where it is available, it has increasingly come under attack in recent years on the false premise that it encourages sexual behaviour," WHO Europe director Hans Kluge said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The truth is that equipping young persons with the right knowledge at the right time leads to optimal health outcomes linked to responsible behaviour and choices," he said.</p>

<p>The WHO said that in addition to higher rates of STIs and unplanned pregnancies, inadequate sexuality education also leads to increased healthcare costs and disrupted education and career paths for young people.</p>

<p>"We are reaping the bitter fruit of these reactionary efforts, with worse to come unless governments, health authorities, the education sector and other essential stakeholders truly recognise the root causes of the current situation and take steps to rectify it," it said.</p>

<p>The agency urged policymakers, educators and healthcare providers to invest in comprehensive sexuality education, improve access to sexual health services, promote dialogue and better train educators.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-01/dipedhl_condoms-istock-650_625x300_17_January_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The report also showed that teens from low-income families were more likely to not use a condom.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-threatens-to-suspend-elon-musks-x-in-country-within-24-hours-6441356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Threatens To Suspend Elon Musk's X In Country Within 24 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-threatens-to-suspend-elon-musks-x-in-country-within-24-hours-6441356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:20:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered Elon Musk on Wednesday to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country, a court decision showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered billionaire Elon Musk on Wednesday to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country, a court decision showed.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, X announced it would close its operations and fire its staff in Brazil due to what it called "censorship orders" from Moraes, while adding the firm's service would remain available for users in Brazil.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court posted a screenshot of Wednesday's court decision on its X account, tagging Musk's and X's Global Government Affairs accounts.</p>

<p>X did not immediately respond to a request for comment sent outside normal working hours.</p>

<p>In the decision, Moraes says that under the country's law regulating internet issues, companies that do not respect Brazilian legislation or the confidentiality of private information could have their activities temporarily suspended.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/puugc1eg_elon-musk_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier this month, X announced it would close its operations and fire its staff in Brazi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-reveals-gunman-viewed-donald-trump-rally-as-target-of-opportunity-report-6441328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Reveals Gunman Viewed Trump Rally As "Target Of Opportunity": Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-reveals-gunman-viewed-donald-trump-rally-as-target-of-opportunity-report-6441328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:11:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The FBI on Wednesday revealed that the gunman who attempted to kill former President Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania campaign rally last month viewed the event as a "target of opportunity," Al-Jazeera reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI on Wednesday revealed that the gunman who attempted to kill former President Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania campaign rally last month viewed the event as a "target of opportunity," Al-Jazeera reported.</p>

<p>Crooks of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, fired shots, one of which grazed Trump in the ear at an outdoor rally in Butler. Thomas Matthew Crooks was planted on the roof of a manufacturing plant located over 130 yards away from the stage at Butler Farm Show grounds, the New York Post had reported, citing sources.</p>

<p>According to FBI officials, 20-year-old Thomas Crooks had mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July.</p>

<p>FBI officials said Thomas Crooks searched more than 60 times for details about Trump and his then-rival, Democratic President Joe Biden, before registering for the Trump rally.</p>

<p>"We saw ... a sustained, detailed effort to plan an attack on some events, meaning he looked at any number of events or targets," Kevin Rojek, the FBI's top official in western Pennsylvania, said in a telephone briefing to reporters on Wednesday, according to Al-Jazeera.</p>

<p>Rojek further said that Crooks became "hyper-focused" on the Trump rally when it was announced "and looked at it as a target of opportunity."</p>

<p>Notably, after the assassination attempt, the US Secret Service snipers had shot Crooks and an AR-style rifle was later recovered. Bethel Park is a village 40 miles south of where Trump's rally was held in Butler.</p>

<p>Donald Trump was on stage at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania's Butler before gunshots rang out and Secret Service agents stormed the stage, The Hill had reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks fired shots, one of which grazed Trump in the ear at an outdoor rally in Butler.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-mysterious-and-controversial-telegram-founder-6441269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pavel Durov: Mysterious And Controversial Telegram Founder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-mysterious-and-controversial-telegram-founder-6441269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 05:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian-born tech entrepreneur Pavel Durov has founded wildly popular social networks, cryptocurrencies, amassed a multi-billion-dollar fortune and locked horns with authorities, in Russia and around the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian-born tech entrepreneur Pavel Durov has founded wildly popular social networks, cryptocurrencies, amassed a multi-billion-dollar fortune and locked horns with authorities, in Russia and around the world.</p>

<p>Still a few months shy of his 40th birthday, the man once dubbed the "Russian Zuckerberg" after Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg now presides over the Telegram app which boasts more than 900 million users worldwide.</p>

<p>But Durov, 39, who preaches the virtues of ice baths for health and has fathered 100 children through sperm donations, is a controversial as well as enigmatic figure, accused of not doing enough to halt the spread of extremist content on his network.</p>

<p>His sensational arrest at a Paris airport last weekend could prove a turning point, with Durov charged by the French judiciary on Wednesday and banned from leaving the country.</p>

<p>A self-avowed libertarian, Durov has championed confidentiality on the internet and freedom of speech, defiantly refusing to allow the moderation of messages on Telegram.</p>

<p>Despite boasting a fortune estimated by Forbes magazine at $15.5 billion, Durov says his goal in life was never to become rich but "free".</p>

<p>"And to the extent that it is possible my mission in life was to allow other people to also become free... and using the platforms that we created my hope was that could express their freedoms," he told US talk show host Tucker Carlson in a rare interview in April.</p>

<p>"This is the mission of Telegram."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Thanks for all the fish' -</strong></p>

<p>Born in Soviet times into a family of academics in Leningrad, now known as Saint Petersburg, Durov spent his childhood in Italy before his family returned as the USSR crumbled.</p>

<p>While still in his 20s, he founded the VKontakte (VK) social network which catered to the needs of Russian-language users and outgunned Facebook throughout the former USSR.</p>

<p>In a stunt typical of his unpredictable behaviour, Durov in 2012 showered high-denomination notes on pedestrians from VK's headquarters on top of a historic bookstore on Saint Petersburg's Nevsky Prospekt.</p>

<p>After disputes with the Russian authorities and ownership battles, he sold out of VKontakte and founded Telegram along with his brother Nikolai, whom he credits as the mathematical brain behind its success.</p>

<p>Durov resigned from VK with a typical flourish, posting a picture of dolphins and the slogan "So Long and Thanks for All the Fish", a title in the famous "Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy" science fiction series.</p>

<p><strong>- '100 percent owned by myself' -</strong></p>

<p>He stopped living in Russia in 2014, leading a nomadic life that saw him pick up citizenship of the Caribbean nation of Saint Kitts and Nevis.</p>

<p>But his departure from Russia was reportedly not an abrupt exile: according to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing leaked border data, he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021.</p>

<p>Durov settled in Dubai, deciding it offered the best business climate to build up Telegram, also gaining UAE citizenship.</p>

<p>He boasted to Carlson that Telegram has just 30 core staff and spent "zero" on marketing, in stark contrast to its rivals. He made clear "Telegram is 100 percent owned by myself".</p>

<p>In August 2021, he also won French nationality following a low-profile procedure about which Paris remains highly discreet.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal reported that in 2018 President Emmanuel Macron hosted Durov for lunch in Paris and suggested Telegram be based in the French capital.</p>

<p>But Durov declined, said the newspaper, which also reported that France and the UAE had waged a joint operation to hack his phone over concerns Telegram was providing a platform for Islamist extremists.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Civic duty' -</strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Telegram enjoyed stratospheric success, presenting itself as a champion of individual freedoms, refusing "censorship" and protecting the confidentiality of its users.</p>

<p>This rankled with authorities, especially in his home country, and in 2018 a Moscow court ordered the blocking of the application.</p>

<p>But the imposition of the measure was shambolic and Russia has abandoned its efforts to block Telegram which is now used by both the Russian government and the opposition, with some channels boasting several hundred thousand subscribers.</p>

<p>Telegram also plays a key role in Russia's war against Ukraine, documented by bloggers from both sides who post their analyses and videos of the fighting.</p>

<p>Durov has also found time to set up cryptocurrencies, Toncoin and Notcoin which emerged from a viral Telegram game.</p>

<p>Dressed almost always in black and possibly trying to ape the look of Keanu Reeves in "The Matrix", Durov readily cultivates a mystical image.</p>

<p>In July, he boasted in a Telegram post of being the biological father of more than 100 children thanks to his sperm donations in a dozen countries, describing this as a "civic duty", an attitude to parenting that echoes fellow tech mogul, the X and Tesla chief Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Durov told Carlson he was delighted by Musk's acquisition of Twitter. "Twitter or X, that is seemingly becoming more pro-freedom of speech, it's a great development."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/03h9ob6g_pavel-durov_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Born in Soviet times, Pavel Durov is a controversial as well as enigmatic figure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-makes-landfall-on-japanese-island-of-kyushu-weather-office-6441168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Typhoon Makes Landfall On Japanese Island Of Kyushu: Weather Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-makes-landfall-on-japanese-island-of-kyushu-weather-office-6441168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 05:20:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major typhoon made landfall on Japan's main southern island of Kyushu on Thursday morning, the weather office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Typhoon Shanshan slammed into Japan's main southern island of Kyushu early Thursday, with authorities advising thousands of people to evacuate and issuing the highest warning level for wind and storm surges.</p>

<p>The weather office said that Japan's most powerful typhoon this year made landfall at around 8:00 am (2300 GMT Wednesday) packing gusts of up to 252 kilometres (157 miles) per hour.</p>

<p>Kyushu's utility operator said that 254,610 houses were already without power.</p>

<p>"Special warnings of violent storms, high waves and high tides are being issued to the Kagoshima region (of Kyuhsu)," the Japan Meteorological Office said.</p>

<p>"Please exercise maximum vigilance against violent storms, high waves and high tides in Kagoshima, as well as landslides, flooding in low-lying areas and overflowing rivers in southern Kyushu," it said.</p>

<p>"Please also be advised that the risk of a disaster due to heavy rain can rapidly escalate in western Japan as Friday approaches."</p>

<p>Heavy rain brought by Shanshan has been lashing large parts of Japan since Tuesday.</p>

<p>Three members of a family died after a landslide buried a house in Gamagori, a city in central Aichi prefecture, Japan's Kyodo news agency reported early Thursday, citing local government officials.</p>

<p>The deceased included a couple in their 70s as well as a son in his 30s, while two adult daughters in their 40s survived with injuries, Kyodo reported.</p>

<p>For southern Kyushu, the JMA predicted an enormous 1,100 millimetres (43 inches) of precipitation in the 48 hours to Friday morning.</p>

<p>Video on public broadcaster NHK TV showed roof tiles being blown off houses, broken windows and felled trees.</p>

<p>"Our carport roof was blown away in its entirety. I wasn't at home when it happened, but my kids say they felt the shaking so strong they thought an earthquake happened," a local resident in Miyazaki told NHK.</p>

<p>"I was surprised. It was completely beyond our imagination," she said.</p>

<p>Auto giant Toyota has suspended production at all 14 of its factories in Japan.</p>

<p>Japan Airlines cancelled 172 domestic flights and six international flights scheduled for Wednesday and Thursday, while ANA nixed 219 domestic flights and four international ones on Wednesday, Thursday and Friday.</p>

<p>The cancellations affected around 25,000 people.</p>

<p>Kyushu Railway said it would suspend some Shinkansen bullet train services between Kumamoto and Kagoshima Chuo from Wednesday night and warned of further possible disruption.</p>

<p>Trains between Tokyo and Fukuoka, the most populous city on Kyushu, may also be cancelled depending on weather conditions this week, other operators said.</p>

<p>Shanshan comes in the wake of Typhoon Ampil, which disrupted hundreds of flights and trains this month.</p>

<p>Despite dumping heavy rain, it caused only minor injuries and damage.</p>

<p>Ampil came days after Tropical Storm Maria brought record rains to northern areas.</p>

<p>Typhoons in the region have been forming closer to coastlines, intensifying more rapidly and lasting longer over land due to climate change, according to a study released last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/avmjs4jc_typhoon-generic_625x300_03_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A major typhoon made landfall on Japan's main southern island of Kyushu on Thursday morning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-appoints-1st-female-government-spokesperson-6441092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Appoints 1st Female Government Spokesperson]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-appoints-1st-female-government-spokesperson-6441092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 04:56:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In another first, a woman will be the public face of the new Iranian government with Fatemeh Mohajerani being appointed the government spokesperson of Masoud Pezeshkian regime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In another first, a woman will be the public face of the new Iranian government with Fatemeh Mohajerani being appointed the government spokesperson of Masoud Pezeshkian regime.</p>

<p>The appointment was made by President Pezeshkian in a cabinet meeting on Wednesday, Iranian media reported.</p>

<p>Mohajerani, 54, is a Doctor of Business Administration from Edinburgh and has earlier served as the head of the Technical and Vocational Training University of Shariati (for women) in the 11th government.</p>

<p>Mohajerani was named the head of the Center for Brilliant Talents by then-Education Minister Seyyed Mohammad Bat'hai in 2017 and has held other positions in the Education Ministry too.</p>

<p>This is the latest appointment of a woman to a senior position. President Pezeshkian had, last week, appointed Shina Ansari as Iran's Deputy President and Head of the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>Ansari, whose LinkedIn profile describes her as an experienced environmental specialist with a demonstrated history of working in environmental services and skilled in waste, RCRA, sustainable development, and environmental compliance, replaces Ali Salajegheh as head of the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>A PhD in Environmental Management from the Science &amp; Research University, she was presently the Advisor at the Air Quality Control Centre at Tehran Municipality and previously had been Head of Environment and Sustainable Development at the Municipality and General Director of the Bureau of Comprehensive Environmental Pollution Monitoring in the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian's cabinet also has (post-1979 Islamic Revolution) Iran's second woman minister with Farzaneh Sadeq Malvajard being approved as the Roads and Urban Development Minister. The Deputy Minister of Urban Planning and Architecture from January 2019 to July 2023, she got 230 out of 285-odd lawmakers present and voting despite some opposition when her name was read out in Parliament when the ministerial choices were submitted earlier this month.</p>

<p>Sadeq, 48, follows Marzieh Vahid Dastjerdi who was Health and Medical Education Minister in populist President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad's second government (2009-13).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mdc6hr5o_fatemeh-mohajerani_625x300_29_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fatemeh Mohajerani, 54, is a Doctor of Business Administration from Edinburgh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-nations-vehicle-in-gaza-hit-by-israeli-gunfire-6440981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[United Nations Vehicle In Gaza Hit By Israeli Gunfire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-nations-vehicle-in-gaza-hit-by-israeli-gunfire-6440981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 04:13:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza, marked with the organisation's insignia, was fired upon 10 times by Israeli forces, including shots targeting its front windows.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The United Nations has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza, marked with the organisation's insignia, was fired upon 10 times by Israeli forces, including shots targeting its front windows, while it was part of a convoy fully coordinated with the Israeli army.</p>

<p>UN spokesperson Stephane Dujarric stated on Wednesday that the two staff members in the vehicle were unharmed. He referred to comments made by a senior UN official, who requested anonymity, two days ago to journalists about the need for armoured vehicles in Gaza.</p>

<p>The incident underscored the importance of this, as the armoured vehicle saved the lives of the staff members and revealed that current coordination mechanisms are ineffective.</p>

<p>Dujarric assured that the UN would continue to work with the Israeli army to ensure that such incidents do not recur.</p>

<p>The international spokesperson stressed the necessity for all parties to respect international humanitarian law at all times, which includes the protection of civilians and the provision of their basic needs, such as food, water, shelter, and health care, wherever they are in Gaza.</p>

<p>He clarified that this applies to those under evacuation orders, whether they have moved or not, indicating that those who leave must be given sufficient time to depart, safe routes, and safe areas to which they can go.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/iq5k0vlg_-gaza-strip_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza hit by Israeli gunfire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-charges-telegram-chief-pavel-durov-prosecutor-6440551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram Chief Pavel Durov Charged, Banned From Leaving France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-charges-telegram-chief-pavel-durov-prosecutor-6440551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 01:59:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The chief of Telegram Pavel Durov on Wednesday was charged by the French judiciary with a litany of violations related to the messaging app but allowed to go free while being banned from leaving the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France on Wednesday charged Pavel Durov, the founder and chief of Telegram, with a litany of violations related to the messaging app and banned him from leaving the country while allowing the billionaire to walk free after four days under arrest.</p>

<p>Durov, 39, was charged on several counts of failing to curb extremist and illegal content on the popular messaging app following a hearing with investigating magistrates in Paris.</p>

<p>Russian-born Durov was arrested at Le Bourget airport outside Paris late Saturday and questioned in subsequent days under arrest by investigators.</p>

<p>He was granted conditional release against a bail of five million euros and on the condition he must report to a police station twice a week as well as remaining in France, Paris prosecutor Laure Beccuau said in a statement.</p>

<p>The charges concern alleged crimes involving an organised group including "complicity in the administration of an online platform to enable an illicit transaction".</p>

<p>Durov has also been charged with refusing to share documents demanded by authorities as well as "dissemination in an organised group of images of minors in child pornography" as well as drug trafficking, fraud and money laundering.</p>

<p>His lawyer David-Olivier Kaminski said it was "absurd" to suggest Durov could be implicated in any crime committed on the app, adding: "Telegram complies in all respects with European rules concerning digital technology."</p>

<p>Separately, Durov is also being investigated on suspicion of "serious acts of violence" towards one of his children while he and an ex-partner, the boy's mother, were in Paris, a source said. She also filed another complaint against Durov in Switzerland last year.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Not political' -</strong></p>

<p>The tech mogul founded Telegram as he was in the process of quitting his native Russia a decade ago. Its growth has been exponential, with the app now reporting more than 900 million users.</p>

<p>An enigmatic figure who rarely speaks in public, Durov is a citizen of Russia, France and the United Arab Emirates, where Telegram is based.</p>

<p>Forbes magazine estimates his current fortune at $15.5 billion, though he proudly promotes the virtues of an ascetic life that includes ice baths and not drinking alcohol or coffee.</p>

<p>Numerous questions have been raised about the timing and circumstances of Durov's detention, with supporters seeing him as a freedom of speech champion and detractors as a menace who wilfully allowed Telegram to get out of control.</p>

<p>Le Monde newspaper reported Wednesday that Durov had met President Emmanuel Macron on several occasions prior to receiving French nationality in 2021, via a special procedure reserved for those deemed to have made a special contribution to France.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal added that at one lunch in 2018, Macron -- who along with his team was in the past an avid user of Telegram -- had suggested it should be headquartered in Paris, but Durov refused.</p>

<p>According to a source close to the case, confirming a story first published on the Politico news site, both Pavel Durov and his elder brother Nikolai, a lower-profile figure seen as the mathematical brain behind Telegram, have been wanted by France since March this year.</p>

<p>In a post on X to address what he called "false information" concerning the case, Macron said Durov's arrest was "in no way a political decision" and it was "up to the judges to rule".</p>

<p>In Moscow, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the charges were very serious and thus needed "no less serious evidence".</p>

<p>Among those voicing support for Durov is fellow tech tycoon and chief executive of X, Elon Musk, who has posted comments under the hashtag #FreePavel.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Near total absence' -</strong></p>

<p>Durov left Russia a decade ago as he was setting up Telegram amid an ownership squabble concerning his first project, the Russian social network VKontakte.</p>

<p>But his departure from Russia was reportedly not an abrupt exile: according to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing leaked border data, he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021.</p>

<p>Telegram has positioned itself as a "neutral" alternative to US-owned platforms, which have been criticised for their commercial exploitation of users' personal data.</p>

<p>It has also played a key role since Russia's invasion of Ukraine, used actively by politicians and commentators on both sides of the war.</p>

<p>The Paris prosecutor said the French judicial authorities had been made aware of the "near total absence of a response" from Telegram to requests from the authorities and had first opened an investigation in February 2024.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5b78286g_pavel-durov_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The chief of Telegram Pavel Durov on Wednesday was charged by the French judiciary.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-spent-months-seeking-a-target-then-settled-on-donald-trump-fbi-6440260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunman Spent Months Seeking A Target, Then Settled On Donald Trump: FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-spent-months-seeking-a-target-then-settled-on-donald-trump-fbi-6440260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:26:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who tried to kill Donald Trump mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July, FBI officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who tried to kill Donald Trump mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July, FBI officials said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>FBI officials said Thomas Crooks, 20, searched more than 60 times for information about the Republican presidential candidate and his then-rival, Democratic President Joe Biden, before registering for the Trump rally in early July.</p>

<p>"We saw ... a sustained, detailed effort to plan an attack on some events, meaning he looked at any number of events or targets," Kevin Rojek, the FBI's top official in western Pennsylvania, said in a telephone briefing to reporters.</p>

<p>Rojek said Crooks became "hyper focused" on the Trump rally when it was announced in early July "and looked at it as a target of opportunity."</p>

<p>Rojek said the FBI has not yet been able to determine what motivated Crooks to try to assassinate Trump at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, on July 13.</p>

<p>Crooks' computer activity showed he was interested in a mix of ideologies, but did not show definitively that he was motivated by a particular left-leaning or right-leaning point of view, Rojek said.</p>

<p>FBI officials said they had not found any evidence indicated that Crooks had worked with other people, or had been directed by a foreign power.</p>

<p>There were no traces of illicit drugs or alcohol in his system.</p>

<p>The assassination attempt prompted questions about how Crooks was able to climb a nearby building and fire eight shots at the former president before being killed by a Secret Service sharpshooter. Several congressional and government probes are examining the event's security measures.</p>

<p>The FBI, meanwhile, is investigating Crooks himself. Officials said they had gained some understanding of his mindset, even if they still did not know what motivated him.</p>

<p>Crooks searched for Trump's campaign events as early as September 2023, FBI officials said, and began searching in April for campaign events for both candidates near where he lived in western Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He also searched for the dates of both the Republican and Democratic presidential conventions, they said.</p>

<p>In the days leading up to the July 13 rally, he searched for information about the site, including where Trump would speak and details of the company that owned a nearby building where he would later fire the eight shots, one of which grazed Trump's ear. Video evidence shows Crooks was only on the building's roof for about six minutes.</p>

<p>Crooks, who left several explosive devices in his car, had searched for information about bomb components as early as 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were no traces of illicit drugs or alcohol in the gunman's system. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-military-says-failed-to-stop-west-bank-attack-that-killed-1-6440141]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Failed To Stop West Bank Attack That Killed 1 Palestinian]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-military-says-failed-to-stop-west-bank-attack-that-killed-1-6440141]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 23:57:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said on Wednesday it had "failed" in its response to a settler attack in the occupied West Bank earlier this month that Palestinian officials said killed one man.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said on Wednesday it had "failed" in its response to a settler attack in the occupied West Bank earlier this month that Palestinian officials said killed one man.</p>

<p>The August 15 raid on the northern West Bank village of Jit came amid soaring violence in the Palestinian territory during the Gaza war and growing international concern over an uptick in attacks by Jewish settlers.</p>

<p>Major General Avi Bluth, head of the military's Central Command which operates in the West Bank, was quoted in a statement as saying the attack was "a very serious terror incident in which Israelis set out to deliberately harm the residents of the town of Jit, and we failed by not succeeding to arrive earlier to protect them".</p>

<p>Jit residents have said about 100 settlers armed with knives and firearms set fire to cars and homes in the village.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The military, releasing on Wednesday a summary of its investigation, said the group wore masks, threw rocks and Molotov cocktails and set three vehicles and two buildings on fire.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry said a 23-year-old Palestinian man, Rashid Sada, was shot dead in the attack.</p>

<p>Last week, Israeli police and the Shin Bet internal security service said they had arrested four suspects for "terrorist" acts in connection with the incident.</p>

<p>The military's investigation found that the first troops at the scene "did not manage to fully gauge the situation" and "needed to act more decisively", the statement said.</p>

<p>"Several members of the rapid response team from a nearby (settlement) community, who were not in active reserve duty, arrived at the scene without authorisation, dressed in uniform, and acted contrary to the authority defined for the members of the rapid response team," it added without elaborating.</p>

<p>Two members of the team "were dismissed, and their weapons were confiscated", it said.</p>

<p>The statement said the shooting that killed Sada and wounded another Palestinian occurred before more Israeli forces managed to disperse the assailants.</p>

<p>"The troops acted assertively, risking their lives, containing the rioters, and pushing them out of the town using crowd dispersal means and firing into the air," the statement said.</p>

<p>"Half an hour after the incident began, all Israelis were removed from the town."</p>

<p>Bluth was quoted as saying the case "will not be closed until we bring the perpetrators to justice".</p>

<h3><strong>Rising violence</strong></h3>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog "firmly" condemned the attack on Jit when it occurred.</p>

<p>Since Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza, violence has flared in the West Bank, a Palestinian territory occupied by Israel since 1967 and separated geographically from Gaza by Israeli territory.</p>

<p>Israeli settlements in the West Bank, where some 490,000 people live, are illegal under international law. The United Nations considers them an obstacle to Israeli-Palestinian peace.</p>

<p>On Wednesday Washington announced new sanctions on Israeli settlers in the West Bank over violence against Palestinians, urging Israel to bring greater accountability.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said on Wednesday that he viewed the sanctions "with utmost severity" and that they were the subject of "pointed discussion" with the US.</p>

<p>Since October 7, at least 660 Palestinians have been killed in the West Bank by Israeli troops or settlers, according to an AFP count based on Palestinian official figures.</p>

<p>During the same period, at least 19 Israelis, including soldiers, have been killed in Palestinian attacks, according to Israeli official figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ef87ehd_israel-military_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli military's investigation found the troops "needed to act more decisively". (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-sees-us-sanctions-on-west-bank-settlers-with-utmost-severity-6439991]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel PM Sees US Sanctions On West Bank Settlers With "Utmost Severity"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-sees-us-sanctions-on-west-bank-settlers-with-utmost-severity-6439991]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 23:26:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday he views "with utmost severity" new sanctions imposed by Washington on Israeli setters in the West Bank over violence against Palestinians.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday he views "with utmost severity" new sanctions imposed by Washington on Israeli setters in the West Bank over violence against Palestinians.</p>

<p>"Israel views with utmost severity the imposition of sanctions on citizens of Israel. The issue is in a pointed discussion with the US," Netanyahu's office said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/r3m1cb98_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US has imposed new sanctions on Israeli settlers in West Bank over violence against Palestinians. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-spains-iconic-tomatina-festival-in-full-glory-6439915]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Spain's Iconic Tomatina Festival In Full Glory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-spains-iconic-tomatina-festival-in-full-glory-6439915]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 23:16:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The streets of a town in eastern Spain were awash in red on Wednesday as revellers flung overripe tomatoes at each other in a high-spirited battle royale during the traditional Tomatina festival.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The streets of a town in eastern Spain were awash in red on Wednesday as revellers flung overripe tomatoes at each other in a high-spirited battle royale during the traditional Tomatina festival.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Participants attend the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol, near Valencia, Spain" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0605irto_tomatina-festival_625x300_28_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Participants attend the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol, near Valencia, Spain" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Participants attend the annual food fight festival 'La Tomatina' in Bunol, near Valencia, Spain.&nbsp;<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>
</div>

<p>Some 22,000 participants wearing white clothes bespattered with tomato pulp engaged in the frenzy that grips Bunol - located 40 km (25 miles) to the west of Valencia - every year in the last week of August.</p>

<p>Seven trucks distributed 150 tons of ripe pear tomatoes to eager roisterers, many of them visiting from abroad. Non-residents pay a fee of 15 euros ($16.70), while Bunol locals enjoy it for free.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="A participant covered in tomato pulp looks on, as people attend the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol, near Valencia, Spain" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9vjfpsio_tomatina-festival_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="A participant covered in tomato pulp looks on, as people attend the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol, near Valencia, Spain" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">A participant covered in tomato pulp looks on, as people attend the annual food fight festival 'La Tomatina' in Bunol.&nbsp;<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>"We love tomatoes! That's why we decided to come and we had a fab time," said Taylor, who came from Australia, adding that she and her friends would "make some spaghetti to have with the sauce".</p>

<p>The start of the hour-long fight was signalled by firecrackers ignited once one of the contenders managed to climb up a slippery pole lathered in soap to snatch a leg of ham hanging from the top.</p>

<p>Senam, from Kenya, described the event as "beautiful, wonderful, creative, mind-blowing".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Participants pose, while in tomato pulp, during the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mot328uo_tomatina-festival_625x300_28_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Participants pose, while in tomato pulp, during the annual food fight festival La Tomatina in Bunol" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Participants pose, while in tomato pulp, during the annual food fight festival.&nbsp;<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>After the friendly fight ended, a cleaning crew armed with water hoses was dispatched to remove the refuse from the town's streets, which were left gleaming thanks to the tomatoes' natural acidity.</p>

<p>The fruits, grown specifically for the festival, are considered too sour for human consumption.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Participants pose for a photo as they enjoy the traditional festival." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jsnf3hko_tomatina-festival_625x300_28_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Participants pose for a photo as they enjoy the traditional festival." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Participants pose for a photo as they enjoy the traditional festival.&nbsp;<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>According to the Tomatina's official website, the festival originated during a brawl that ensued in 1945 when youngsters attempting to get a closer view of a parade knocked over one of the participants. Several people plucked tomatoes from a nearby stand as makeshift projectiles until police restored order.</p>

<p>The following year, youths recreated the altercation, with some even bringing their own tomatoes. The event was briefly outlawed in the 1950s under General Francisco Franco's fascist dictatorship, but resumed in 1959 with certain rules.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/52m4ghjo_tomatina-festival_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fruits, grown specifically for the festival, are considered too sour for human consumption.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffetts-berkshire-hathaway-tops-1-trillion-in-market-value-6439753]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Warren Buffett's Berkshire Hathaway Tops $1 Trillion In Market Value]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffetts-berkshire-hathaway-tops-1-trillion-in-market-value-6439753]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 22:43:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Berkshire Hathaway Inc. became the first US company outside of the tech sector to surpass $1 trillion in market value.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Berkshire Hathaway Inc. became the first US company outside of the tech sector to surpass $1 trillion in market value.</p>

<p>Shares of Warren Buffett's conglomerate rose as much as 0.8% on Wednesday to push its market capitalization above the trillion-dollar mark for the first time. The stock has rallied this year on strong insurance results and economic optimism. The Omaha, Nebraska-based company joins the ranks of a small group to crack the milestone, dominated by technology giants like Alphabet Inc., Meta Platforms Inc. and Nvidia Corp. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Berkshire has done it the slower, but more sure, way," said Steve Check, the founder and chief investment officer of Check Capital Management. His firm has about $2 billion in assets under management, with Berkshire as their largest holding. "It's harder to make money the old-fashioned way."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4p3km724_berkshire-tops-usd-1-trillion-bloomberg_625x300_28_August_24.png" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Add image caption here</p>
</div>

<p>Berkshire's rally this year has outpaced the S&amp;P 500's gains, with the company off to one of its best annual starts in a decade. It's gained 30% in 2024, while the market benchmark is up 18%. The company isn't that far behind the so-called Magnificent Seven: a gauge of the biggest tech stocks is up 35% this year.</p>

<p>Buffett has spent the bulk of his life turning Berkshire Hathaway from a struggling textile maker into a sprawling business empire. He shaped the company alongside longtime business partner Charlie Munger, who died in November at age 99.</p>

<p>Berkshire's market value climbed by roughly 20% a year from 1965 through last year - nearly double the S&amp;P 500's annual return in that time. That's turned Buffett into one of the richest people in the world, and perhaps the most prolific investor ever.</p>

<p>The conglomerate's strength comes as optimism for the economy builds, with the Federal Reserve expected to cut interest rates at its September meeting. Consumer confidence rose to a six-month high in August. Berkshire's businesses span from truck stop operator Pilot Travel Centers LLC to ice cream chain Dairy Queen and battery brand Duracell.</p>

<p>The stock has added more than $200 billion in market capitalization this year alone - a record for the firm, but a sharp contrast to Nvidia's nearly $2 trillion increase. Berkshire's rally has pushed it into overbought territory, based on the relative strength index, and prompted a bit of reticence from analysts.</p>

<p>The fundamental outlook for Berkshire's core businesses isn't necessarily that much brighter ahead, according to Bloomberg Intelligence analyst Matthew Palazola, but the firm boasts an "all-weather" portfolio.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, lower interest rates could impact returns on the record cash pile Berkshire amassed while slashing its Apple Inc. stake and paring its Bank of America Corp. holdings. Buffett's cash heap stood at about $276.9 billion in second-quarter results reported in early August. The sheer size of the Apple stake had become a worry, Check said, and the move to reduce that exposure was prudent. "It's taken a lot of that risk off the table," Check said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-04/warren-buffett-washington-post_650x400_61493353846.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Berkshire's market value climbed by roughly 20% a year from 1965 through last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-launches-deadly-west-bank-operation-as-gaza-war-drags-on-6439372]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Launches Deadly West Bank Operation As Gaza War Drags On]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-launches-deadly-west-bank-operation-as-gaza-war-drags-on-6439372]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 21:47:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel launched a large-scale military operation today in the West Bank, where the army said it killed nine Palestinian fighters, while the nearly 11-month Gaza war showed no signs of abating.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel launched a large-scale military operation today in the West Bank, where the army said it killed nine Palestinian fighters, while the nearly 11-month Gaza war showed no signs of abating.</p>

<p>Violence has surged in the West Bank during the Gaza war sparked by Palestinian Islamist group Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attacks on Israel.</p>

<p>The war has killed more than 40,000 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. It has also caused widespread destruction, displaced nearly all of Gaza's 2.4 million people at least once and triggered a humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>In the West Bank in the early hours of Wednesday, the Israeli military launched a series of coordinated raids across four cities -- Jenin, Nablus, Tubas and Tulkarem.</p>

<p>Columns of Israeli armoured vehicles entered two refugee camps, in Tulkarem and Tubas, as well as Jenin.</p>

<p>By midday, they were blocking entrances to the towns and camps, AFP photographers said, with soldiers firing at the camps from which gunfire and explosions were heard.</p>

<p>Israeli bulldozers dug up asphalt from the streets, with the army saying it was looking for roadside bombs.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Red Crescent said Israeli forces killed nine people and wounded 15 others in the raids, revising its previous toll of 10 dead.</p>

<p>Palestinian president Mahmud Abbas cut short a visit to Saudi Arabia and headed home to "follow up on the latest developments in light of the Israeli aggression on the northern West Bank", Palestinian official media said.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said it had killed nine Palestinian "terrorists", with no casualties so far on its side.</p>

<p>Soldiers encountered explosives and were exchanging fire with militants, said army spokesman Nadav Shoshani. He declined to say how many were involved or how long the operation would last.</p>

<p>The operation, he added, was not "extremely different (from usual army activity in the area) or special".</p>

<p><strong>'This Is War'</strong></p>

<p>Foreign Minster Israel Katz had a different take, however, saying the military was "operating in full force since last night" in a bid to "dismantle Iranian-Islamic terror infrastructure".</p>

<p>In a post on X, he accused Iran, Israel's main foe in the region, of seeking to "establish an eastern front against Israel" based on the "model" for Gaza and Lebanon, where it backs Hamas and Hezbollah, respectively.</p>

<p>"We must address this threat with the same determination used against terror infrastructures in Gaza, including temporary evacuation of residents and any necessary measures," Katz said.</p>

<p>"This is a war, and we must win it."</p>

<p>Since Hamas's October 7 attack, Israeli troops or settlers have killed more than 650 Palestinians in the West Bank, according to an AFP tally based on Palestinian health ministry figures.</p>

<p>During the same period, at least 19 Israelis have been killed in Palestinian attacks, according to Israeli officials.</p>

<p>While Israeli military operations have become a daily occurrence in the West Bank, occupied by Israel since 1967, it is rare for these to happen in multiple cities simultaneously.</p>

<p>In recent weeks, Israel's West Bank operations have focused on the territory's north, where armed groups are particularly active.</p>

<p><strong>Patients Flee Hospital</strong></p>

<p>Last week, the army announced it had killed a senior Palestinian militant in Lebanon, accusing him of "directing attacks and smuggling weapons" to the West Bank and collaborating with Iranian forces.</p>

<p>Islamic Jihad, a Palestinian Islamist movement allied with Hamas which has a strong presence in the northern West Bank, issued a statement early Wednesday denouncing an "open war" by Israel.</p>

<p>"With this aggression, which aims to transfer the weight of the conflict to the occupied West Bank, the occupier wants to impose a new state of affairs on the ground to annex the West Bank," the statement said.</p>

<p>Hamas, whose popularity has soared in the West Bank since the Gaza war began, late Tuesday reiterated its call for Palestinians in the territory to "rise up".</p>

<p>Its statement came in response to comments by far-right Israeli National Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir, who said this week he would build a synagogue at Jerusalem's flashpoint Al-Aqsa mosque compound if he could.</p>

<p>Ben Gvir, a settler himself, has openly called for the annexation of the West Bank.</p>

<p>In Gaza, families in distress continued to move according to the Israeli army's evacuation orders.</p>

<p>One of the latest targeted the area around Al-Aqsa Martyrs' Hospital in Deir el-Balah in central Gaza, from which "nearly 650 patients have fled", Doctors Without Borders (MSF) said.</p>

<p>The medical charity's website says it has "quickly opened a field hospital and started receiving patients amid a severe lack of supplies and resources".</p>

<p>MSF said field hospitals are not a solution, "but a last resort in response to Israel's dismantling of the healthcare system".</p>

<p>Gaza's civil defence agency reported at least 12 dead, including at least one child and a woman, in new Israeli strikes.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,199 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 40,534 people in Gaza, according to the territory's health ministry. The UN rights office says most of the dead are women and children.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nijdjiig_israel-strikes-in-west-bank-afp_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel launched a large-scale military operation today in the West Bank.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/92-us-citizens-banned-from-entering-russia-report-6439348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[92 US Citizens Banned From Entering Russia: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/92-us-citizens-banned-from-entering-russia-report-6439348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 21:41:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia said Wednesday it had banned another 92 US citizens from entering its territory, listing names of reporters from the Wall Street Journal, New York Times and Washington Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia said Wednesday it had banned another 92 US citizens from entering its territory, listing names of reporters from the Wall Street Journal, New York Times and Washington Post.</p>

<p>The foreign ministry said in a statement it was responding to sanctions against Russian figures in the United States. It was not possible to immediately verify whether all those listed held US nationality.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7jdhr158_russia_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Names of reporters were also included in the list. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-mission-featuring-first-ever-private-spacewalk-postponed-by-spacex-6438680]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Historic Mission Featuring First-Ever Private Spacewalk Postponed By SpaceX]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/historic-mission-featuring-first-ever-private-spacewalk-postponed-by-spacex-6438680]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 20:11:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX postponed once more its attempt at launching a daring orbital expedition featuring an all-civilian crew that is aiming to carry out the first-ever spacewalk by private citizens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX postponed once more its attempt at launching a daring orbital expedition featuring an all-civilian crew that is aiming to carry out the first-ever spacewalk by private citizens.</p>

<p>The Polaris Dawn mission, organized by billionaire entrepreneur Jared Isaacman, had been set to lift off from NASA's Kennedy Space Center in Florida during a four-hour window early Wednesday.</p>

<p>But SpaceX announced late Tuesday it was pushing back the launch plans "due to unfavorable weather forecasted in Dragon's splashdown areas off the coast of Florida," in a message on X.</p>

<p>Isaacman later added on X that, because the spaceship won't rendezvous with the International Space Station and has limited consumables on board, it was particularly constrained by the forecast during the splashdown window.</p>

<p>"As of now, conditions are not favorable tonight or tomorrow, so we'll assess day by day," he said.</p>

<p>The timing of the next launch could be further complicated by the fact the first stage booster of another SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket that had sent a batch of Starlink satellites into orbit tipped over and exploded during a landing attempt on a waiting droneship.</p>

<p>Although landing the booster is a secondary consideration, the reusability of the entire rocket system is core to SpaceX's business model, and the loss snapped a three-year-streak of successful first stage landings.</p>

<p>SpaceX announced it was standing down from launching the next set of Starlink satellites while it reviewed the data.</p>

<p>An earlier attempt to launch Polaris Dawn on Tuesday was scrapped due to a helium leak on a line connecting the tower to the rocket.</p>

<p><strong>High radiation zone</strong></p>

<p>Riding atop a Falcon 9 rocket, the SpaceX Dragon capsule is set to reach a peak altitude of 870 miles (1,400 kilometers) -- higher than any crewed mission in more than half a century, since the Apollo era.</p>

<p>Mission commander Isaacman will guide his four-member team through the mission's centerpiece: the first-ever spacewalk carried out by non-professional astronauts, equipped with sleek, newly developed SpaceX extravehicular activity (EVA) suits.</p>

<p>Rounding out the team are mission pilot Scott Poteet, a retired US Air Force lieutenant colonel; mission specialist Sarah Gillis, a lead space operations engineer at SpaceX; and mission specialist and medical officer Anna Menon, also a lead space operations engineer at SpaceX.</p>

<p>The quartet underwent more than two years of training in preparation for the landmark mission, logging hundreds of hours on simulators as well as skydiving, centrifuge training, scuba diving, and summiting an Ecuadorian volcano.</p>

<p>Polaris Dawn is set to be the first of three missions under the Polaris program, a collaboration between Isaacman, the founder of tech company Shift4 Payments, and SpaceX.</p>

<p>Isaacman declined to reveal his total investment in the project, though reports suggest he paid around $200 million for the SpaceX Inspiration4 mission in September 2021, the first all-civilian orbital mission.</p>

<p>Polaris Dawn will reach its highest altitude on its first day, venturing briefly into the Van Allen radiation belt, a region teeming with high-energy charged particles that can pose health risks to humans over extended periods.</p>

<p>On day three, the crew will don their state-of-the-art EVA spacesuits -- outfitted with heads-up displays, helmet cameras, and advanced joint mobility systems -- and take turns to venture outside their spacecraft in twos.</p>

<p>Each will spend 15 to 20 minutes in space, 435 miles above Earth's surface.</p>

<p>Also on their to-do list are testing laser-based satellite communication between the spacecraft and Starlink, SpaceX's more than 6,000-strong constellation of internet satellites, in a bid to boost space communication speeds, and conducting nearly 40 scientific experiments.</p>

<p>After six days in space, the mission will conclude with the splashdown off the coast of Florida.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pmp4tlko_spacex-falcon-9_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polaris Dawn is set to be the first of three missions under the Polaris program. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boy-accidentally-shatters-3-500-year-old-rare-jar-at-israel-museum-6438540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boy Shatters 3,500-Year-Old Bronze Age Jar At Israel Museum]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boy-accidentally-shatters-3-500-year-old-rare-jar-at-israel-museum-6438540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 19:51:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A four year old boy accidentally shattered a rare bronze age jar that was on display at an archaeological museum in Haifa, Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A four year old boy accidentally shattered a rare bronze age jar that was on display at an archaeological museum in Haifa, Israel.</p>

<p>The 3,500-year-old ancient artefact had been on display near the entrance of the Hecht Museum without a glass case.</p>

<p><br />
The child's father told the BBC his son "pulled the jar slightly" because he was "curious about what was inside". The man added that he was "in shock" to see his son beside the broken pieces and thought "it wasn't my child that did it".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Despite the rare incident" the museum said it intends to continue displaying items "without barriers or glass walls" as it believes there is a "special charm" in showing archaeological finds "without obstructions".</p>

<p><br />
"There are instances where display items are intentionally damaged, and such cases are treated with great severity, including involving the police," Lihi Laszlo from the museum told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckg2j2y20epo" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">the BBC</a>.</p>

<p>"In this case, however, this was not the situation. The jar was accidentally damaged by a young child visiting the museum, and the response will be accordingly."</p>

<p>The jar, which the museum believes dates between 2200 and 1500 BC, was most likely intended to be used to carry local supplies such as wine and olive oil. It was discovered during excavations in Samaria, in central Israel, and has been in the museum for 35 years.</p>

<p>The museum said the artefact was "an impressive find" because similar archaeological items unearthed during excavations are usually broken or incomplete.</p>

<p>An expert has been appointed to restore the jar and it will be displayed again "in a short time", the museum said.</p>

<p>The boy's father said they feel "relieved" to know the jar will be restored but they were apologetic as "it will no longer be the same item".</p>

<p>However, the museum's head Inbal Rivlin told Israeli news outlet Ynet that the boy and his mother have been invited back to the museum for a private tour.</p>

<p>"The museum is not a mausoleum but a living place, open to families (and) accessible. We are appealing to parents: Don't be afraid. Things like this happen. We will fix (the jar) and put it back," the museum head told Ynet.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dsd2u9ag_jar-museum-_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The jar was most likely intended to be used to carry local supplies such as wine and olive oil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-to-appear-in-paris-court-report-6438143]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram CEO Pavel Durov To Appear In Paris Court: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-to-appear-in-paris-court-report-6438143]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 28 Aug 2024 19:09:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Telegram founder and chief Pavel Durov was headed to court in Paris Wednesday where he could be formally charged, after his initial arrest period for questioning came to an end, a source familiar with the case told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telegram founder and chief Pavel Durov was headed to court in Paris Wednesday where he could be formally charged, after his initial arrest period for questioning came to an end, a source familiar with the case told AFP.</p>

<p>The Russian-born 39-year-old was arrested at the French capital's Le Bourget airport late Saturday on suspicion of failing to act against illicit content on 900-million-user social network Telegram, allegations the company itself has denied.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5b78286g_pavel-durov_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Telegram has denied the allegations against its CEO Pavel Durov. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>