<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:40:09 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemen-floods-news-over-560-000-affected-by-unprecedented-yemen-floods-un-6498883]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 560,000 Affected By "Unprecedented" Yemen Floods: UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemen-floods-news-over-560-000-affected-by-unprecedented-yemen-floods-un-6498883]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:22:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Severe flooding and violent windstorms have affected 562,000 people across Yemen in recent weeks, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) said Thursday, appealing for $13.3 million in donations amid a funding shortfall.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Severe flooding and violent windstorms have affected 562,000 people across Yemen in recent weeks, the International Organization for Migration (IOM) said Thursday, appealing for $13.3 million in donations amid a funding shortfall.</p>

<p>The "unprecedented weather events" have compounded suffering in the Arabian Peninsula's poorest country, which is already grappling with one of the world's worst humanitarian crises, said the IOM.</p>

<p>"The scale of the destruction is staggering, and we urgently need additional funding to ensure that the most vulnerable are not left behind," said Matt Huber, the IOM's acting Yemen mission chief.</p>

<p>Since late July, torrential rains and flooding have destroyed homes, displaced thousands of families and severely damaged critical infrastructure, including health centres, schools and roads, according to the UN agency.</p>

<p>Late last month, torrential rains caused flash floods in Yemen's Mahawit governorate, leaving around 40 people either missing or dead, according to the UN's humanitarian agency OCHA.</p>

<p>Dozens of houses were damaged or destroyed, forcing 215 families into displacement, it said.</p>

<p>Another 60 people were killed and hundreds more were injured in earlier flash floods across Yemen since late July, according to UN figures.</p>

<p>"These rains have not only led to tragic loss of life but have also wiped out entire communities' belongings and means of survival," the IOM said.</p>

<p>"Immediate funding is necessary to address the most pressing needs on the ground," the IOM said, warning that severe weather conditions are expected to continue in the coming weeks.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r7tb2lbg_yemen-floods_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dozens of houses have either been damaged or destroyed. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pleads-not-guilty-to-revised-2020-election-charges-6498804]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Pleads Not Guilty To Revised 2020 Election Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-pleads-not-guilty-to-revised-2020-election-charges-6498804]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:12:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump pleaded not guilty on Thursday to criminal charges in a revised federal indictment accusing the former U.S. president of attempting to overturn his defeat in the 2020 election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump pleaded not guilty on Thursday to criminal charges in a revised federal indictment accusing the former U.S. president of attempting to overturn his defeat in the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers entered the plea on his behalf at the start of a court hearing in Washington focused on how the case should proceed after the U.S. Supreme Court ruled that former presidents have broad immunity from criminal prosecution.</p>

<p>Trump, the Republican candidate in the Nov. 5 presidential election, is not attending the hearing.</p>

<p>The new indictment, brought in August, included the same four charges as the one obtained last year by Special Counsel Jack Smith, but dropped allegations the Supreme Court found could not remain part of the case.</p>

<p>U.S. District Judge Tanya Chutkan is expected to consider dueling proposals from Smith, who is seeking to press the case forward, and Trump, who is pushing to delay action until after the election. The Supreme Court directed Chutkan to decide whether any other portions of the case must be tossed out.</p>

<p>Trump faces four criminal charges that accuse him of using false claims of voter fraud to undermine the election results and thwart certification of his defeat to Democratic President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The case had been delayed for months while Trump pursued his immunity claim and is virtually certain not to go to trial before Trump faces Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris in the election.</p>

<p>Trump has argued that the prosecution as well as other legal cases against him are politically motivated attempts to undermine his presidential campaign.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court ruled in a 6-3 decision in July that former presidents are presumed to be immune from criminal prosecution for actions taken as part of their official responsibilities as president.</p>

<p>Smith has argued that all the remaining allegations are not covered by the immunity ruling and can proceed to trial.</p>

<p>Prosecutors have said that they are prepared to file court papers laying out their argument "at any time the court deems appropriate."</p>

<p>Trump's lawyers, meanwhile, have suggested that Chutkan should not begin weighing the impact of the immunity ruling until December, after the election.</p>

<p>If Trump wins the election, he is expected to direct the Justice Department to drop the charges.</p>

<p>Trump has proposed that his lawyers first move to dismiss the case based on an argument that Smith was unlawfully appointed as special counsel under the U.S. Constitution.</p>

<p>Trump used the same argument to convince a federal judge in Florida who was appointed by Trump to throw out a second criminal case, also brought by Smith, accusing him of illegally holding onto classified documents after leaving office. Smith's office is appealing that decision.</p>

<p>The federal appeals court in Washington has previously upheld the authority of special counsels to handle certain sensitive investigations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tif74i68_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If Donald Trump wins the election, he is expected to direct Justice Department to drop charges. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-news-first-batch-of-mpox-vaccine-doses-arrives-in-congo-epicentre-of-outbreak-6498500]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First Batch Of Mpox Vaccine Doses Arrives In Congo, Epicentre Of Outbreak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-news-first-batch-of-mpox-vaccine-doses-arrives-in-congo-epicentre-of-outbreak-6498500]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:33:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic Republic of Congo received its first batch of mpox vaccines on Thursday, which health authorities hope will help curb an outbreak that has prompted the U.N. to declare a global public health emergency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic Republic of Congo received its first batch of mpox vaccines on Thursday, which health authorities hope will help curb an outbreak that has prompted the U.N. to declare a global public health emergency.</p>

<p>Congo is the epicentre of the outbreak, which has spread to neighbouring countries and elsewhere, but a lack of vaccines in Africa has hampered efforts to stop the spread of the sometimes deadly disease.</p>

<p>A plane carrying doses manufactured by Bavarian Nordic and donated by the European Union touched down in the capital Kinshasa around 13:00 local time (12:00 GMT), Reuters reporters at the airport said.</p>

<p>Congo's health minister, Samuel Roger Kamba Mulamba, told reporters the newly arrived vaccine had already proved its worth in the United States and would be rolled out to adults in Congo.</p>

<p>"We know which provinces are heavily affected, notably Equateur and South Kivu... The idea is to contain the virus as quickly as possible," he added.</p>

<p>This first delivery amounts to 99,000 doses and a further delivery on Saturday will take the total to 200,000 doses, said Laurent Muschel, the head of the EU Health Emergency Preparedness and Response Authority (HERA).</p>

<p>Overall, Europe aims to deliver 566,000 doses to wherever needs are greatest in the region, Muschel told Reuters. "Based on the number of cases, the next country (for deliveries) should be Burundi, but the country's medical agency must authorise it."</p>

<p>The arrival of the vaccine in Congo should start to address a huge inequity that has left African countries with no access to the two shots used in a 2022 global mpox outbreak, while they were widely available in Europe and the United States.</p>

<p>Congo has said it will launch its vaccination campaign on Oct. 8 to allow time for a thorough awareness-raising campaign to overcome mistrust in some communities.</p>

<p>Mpox typically causes flu-like symptoms and pus-filled lesions, and can kill. There were 19,710 suspected cases of mpox reported in Congo in the first eight months of this year, according to the health ministry. Of those, 5,041 were confirmed and 655 were fatal.</p>

<p>It spreads through close contact, including sexual contact.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8966ron_mpox-vaccine_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This first delivery amounts to 99,000 doses. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-woman-says-uncovering-of-mass-rape-trauma-saved-her-life-6498421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Woman Says Uncovering Of Mass Rape Trauma "Saved Her Life"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-woman-says-uncovering-of-mass-rape-trauma-saved-her-life-6498421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:22:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A French woman whose husband is accused of enlisting dozens of strangers to rape her while she was drugged told his trial on Thursday that police had saved her by uncovering the crimes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A French woman whose husband has admitted to enlisting dozens of strangers to rape her while she was drugged told his trial on Thursday that police had saved her by uncovering the crimes.</p>

<p>"The police saved my life by investigating Mister P.'s computer," Gisele P. told the court in the southern city of Avignon, referring to her husband -- one of 51 of her alleged abusers on trial -- by only his last name.</p>

<p>Gisele P., now 71, revealed her emotion in almost 90 minutes of testimony, recounting the moment in November 2020 when investigators first showed her the images of a decade of sexual abuse orchestrated and filmed by her husband, Dominique P.</p>

<p>"My world is falling apart. For me, everything is falling apart. Everything I have built up over 50 years," Gisele P. said, pausing at times only to sip from a glass of water.</p>

<p>She had told police her husband was a "super guy" when she was first invited to speak with them, she recounted as her daughter and two sons watched the testimony.</p>

<p>At that meeting, Gisele P. was shown "barbaric" pictures where "I'm lying motionless on the bed, being raped", she remembered as her husband listened with his head bowed.</p>

<p>"They treat me like a rag doll," she told a panel of five judges, adding that she had only plucked up the courage to watch the video footage in May 2024.</p>

<p>Lawyers for some of the defendants had questioned on Wednesday whether the couple had had a libertine relationship, or whether it was credible that Gisele P. had noticed nothing for the entire decade of the abuse.</p>

<p>"Don't talk to me about sex scenes. These are rape scenes," she said on Thursday, emphasising that she had never practised swinging or any other form of libertine sex.</p>

<p><strong>'NEVER COMPLICIT'</strong></p>

<p>She reiterated that she was "never complicit" and had never "pretended to be asleep" when asked by lead judge Roger Arata.</p>

<p>Gisele P. has insisted that the trial take place in public so the full facts of the case can emerge.</p>

<p>"I'm speaking for every woman who's been drugged without knowing it, in the name of every woman who may never know... so that no woman has to suffer" the same thing in future, she said.</p>

<p>Gisele P. is in the process of divorcing her husband, who admitted on Tuesday to drugging her with sleeping pills and then recruiting dozens of strangers to rape her.</p>

<p>He was exposed by chance when he was caught filming up women's skirts in a local supermarket.</p>

<p>The husband "will again explain the reasons why he did this. He will explain himself and justify himself, if there can be a justification for this, because it's unpardonable," his lawyer Beatrice Zavarro told AFPTV.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old father of three documented his actions with meticulous precision on a hard drive with a folder labelled "abuse", lead investigator Jeremie Bosse Platiere told the court on Wednesday.</p>

<p>That enabled French police to track down more than 50 men suspected of raping Gisele P. while she was drugged.</p>

<p>A third of them were identified using facial recognition software, Bosse Platiere said.</p>

<p>He said he had hand-picked investigators "who had the stomach" to face the videos and images of abuse.</p>

<p>Police drew up a list of 72 individuals suspected of abusing Gisele P.</p>

<p>The investigators counted around 200 instances of rape, most of them by Dominique P., and over 90 by strangers enlisted through an adult website.</p>

<p><strong>'I FEEL DISGUSTED'</strong></p>

<p>Gisele P. said she had recognised only one of her alleged rapists, a man who had come to discuss cycling with her husband at their home.</p>

<p>"I saw him now and then in the bakery, I would say hello, I never thought he'd come and raped me," she said.</p>

<p>"I feel disgusted," she added, telling the accused to "for once in your lives at least, take responsibility for your actions".</p>

<p>The men received "strict instructions, there was clear and transparent information" about what was happening, the husband's lawyer Zavarro said.</p>

<p>"If these man came (to the couple's home), they were coming in the knowledge of what they were doing. That is what Mr P. will say."</p>

<p>The assaults took place between July 2011 and October 2020, mainly in the couple's home in Mazan, a village of 6,000 people in the southern region of Provence.</p>

<p>Most of the suspects face up to 20 years in jail for aggravated rape if convicted.</p>

<p>Eighteen of the 51 accused are in custody, including Dominique P. Thirty-two other defendants are attending the trial as free men.</p>

<p>The last suspect, still at large, will be tried in absentia, with hearings expected to last four months until December 20.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0lc5jh0o_gisele-p-french-woman-drugged-by-husband-raped-by-strangers-afp_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gisele P. attends the trial of her husband accused of drugging her and inviting strangers to rape her.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-sitting-too-long-is-impacting-your-health-the-surge-of-dead-butt-syndrome-6498067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Sitting Long Is Impacting Your Health: The Surge Of Dead Butt Syndrome]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/how-sitting-too-long-is-impacting-your-health-the-surge-of-dead-butt-syndrome-6498067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:36:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[To combat dead butt syndrome, experts recommend incorporating regular physical activity, stretching, and strengthening exercises targeting the gluteal muscles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new medical ailment that is becoming more prevalent is concerning medical specialists and drawing attention to the risks associated with a more sedentary lifestyle. Gluteus medius tendinosis, commonly known as "dead butt syndrome," is a disorder marked by a weak or inactive gluteus medius muscle. It is frequently brought on by extended sitting, driving, or excessive screen time.</p>

<p>Experts caution that this health condition may result in a variety of issues, such as injuries to the knee, hip pain, and lower back pain. Dead butt syndrome is becoming increasingly common as more individuals spend their days slumped over computers or in front of screens.</p>

<p>"The name sounds silly, but the side effects are serious," said Jane Konidis, a specialist in physical medicine and rehabilitation at the Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minnisota told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/04/well/move/dead-butt-syndrome-gluteal-amnesia.html"><em>The New York Times. </em></a>"The gluteus maximus is one of the strongest muscles in the body and biggest shock absorbers," she said. "If it's not working properly, it can cause a domino chain of issues, from hamstring tears and sciatica to shin splints and arthritis in the knees."</p>

<p>Gluteal amnesia happens when the muscles in your rear become so weak from inactivity they seem to forget how to function, meaning they fail or become slow to activate. This is different than a leg or arm "falling asleep" because of a compressed nerve; you won't feel pins and needles. Some people may feel a dull ache while sitting, but most people don't feel any pain until they go for a jog or hike, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/04/well/move/dead-butt-syndrome-gluteal-amnesia.html"><em>The NYT.</em></a></p>

<p>Sluggish glutes can result in other muscles and joints, especially in the lower back and knees, picking up the slack, Dr Konidis said.</p>

<p>To combat this issue, healthcare providers recommend incorporating regular physical activity, stretching, and strengthening exercises that target the gluteal muscles. By prioritising overall health and well-being, individuals can help prevent dead butt syndrome and its associated complications.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ifdqtubg_back-pain_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This condition can lead to various health issues, including knee, hip, and back pain.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-twin-elephants-born-in-myanmar-timber-camp-6497799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare Twin Elephants Born In Myanmar Timber Camp]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-twin-elephants-born-in-myanmar-timber-camp-6497799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:00:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Baby elephant twins born last week on a timber camp in Myanmar are thriving after a wobbly first few days in the world, officials told AFP on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baby elephant twins born last week on a timber camp in Myanmar are thriving after a wobbly first few days in the world, officials told AFP on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pearl Sint was born a few minutes before her brother Kyaw Pearl last week at the 60-acre Wingabaw elephant camp in the Bago region operated by state-run Myanmar Timber Enterprise.</p>

<p>At about two feet and six inches tall, the pint-sized twins were around four inches shorter than the average calf, said Myo Min Aung, the camp's assistant manager.</p>

<p>This meant they were not tall enough to reach their mother's teat and feed.</p>

<p>"We helped them by putting small wooden blocks under their front legs and bringing their heads up to their mother's breast," he said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/sdel82e_twin-elephants-afp_625x300_05_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>On the third day, they were able to feed themselves and quickly showed their personalities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The little male likes to wander around and play with humans rather than stay with his mother," said Myo Min Aung.</p>

<p>"He is not feeding as much as the female little one does."</p>

<p>Another official at the camp, who did not want to give his name, said he hoped the twins would not take after their father, a bull elephant named Aye Htike.</p>

<p>"He was badly behaved. He used to attack the other elephants and people," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Pearl Sandar, the twins' mother, "has a kind heart", the official said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n65htpvg_twin-elephants-afp_625x300_05_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>"She doesn't attack others... we are training the twins to be well-behaved, not like their father."</p>

<p>The arrival of the twins takes the population of the elephant camp up to nine, the official said.</p>

<p>Previously around 3,000 elephants were used for labour at state timber enterprises in Myanmar, the majority dragging freshly cut trees through the dense jungle to transport hubs and mills.</p>

<p>But now those at the Wingabaw camp, like many others, carry humans instead of logs and earn their keep as a tourist attraction.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fewer than 50,000 Asian elephants remain in the wild, and fewer than 2,000 of them are found in Myanmar, according 2018 figures from environmental group WWF.</p>

<p>"This is my first time personally experiencing an elephant twin birth," said Myo Min Aung.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I am happy to take care of the little twin elephants, but it is also a big responsibility."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qhhgprjo_twin-elephants-afp_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The twins were around 4 inches shorter than the average calf, a camp official said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/second-phase-of-polio-vaccination-campaign-begins-in-gaza-amid-raging-war-6497621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Second Phase Of Polio Vaccination Campaign Begins In Gaza Amid Raging War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/second-phase-of-polio-vaccination-campaign-begins-in-gaza-amid-raging-war-6497621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:39:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Crowds of Palestinians gathered at medical centers in the south of the embattled Gaza Strip on Thursday to have their children vaccinated against polio, the start of the second stage of a campaign that has so far seen 187,000 youngsters inoculated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crowds of Palestinians gathered at medical centers in the south of the embattled Gaza Strip on Thursday to have their children vaccinated against polio, the start of the second stage of a campaign that has so far seen 187,000 youngsters inoculated.</p>

<p>The U.N. Palestinian refugee agency UNRWA said the campaign, facilitated by Hamas and Israel agreeing on limited pauses in their fighting, was so far successful but complex.</p>

<p>But the war continued elsewhere in the enclave, with Gaza health authorities reporting several people killed in Israeli airstrikes, including a hit on a hospital in central Gaza.</p>

<p>And despite the success of the polio campaign, diplomatic efforts to secure a permanent ceasefire in the war, the release of hostages held in Gaza, and the return of Palestinians jailed by Israel have faltered.</p>

<p>On Thursday, vaccinations began in Rafah and Khan Younis in the south of Gaza, both areas that have been battered by the war and have hosted tens of thousands of people who have fled other parts.</p>

<p>"The #polio vaccination campaign has moved to #Gaza southern areas today. @UNRWA teams are in Khan Younis this morning, working with partners to provide the vaccine to children," UNRWA said in a statement.</p>

<p>"At this critical time, area pauses must be respected to protect families and humanitarian workers," it said.</p>

<p>Most of the activity will be conducted in Khan Younis and will include residents who had been forced by the Israeli military to leave Rafah, near the border with Egypt, where Israeli forces have been operating since May.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it has killed hundreds of Palestinian gunmen in Rafah and located dozens of tunnels and military infrastructure in that time.</p>

<p>Health officials aim to reach 640,000 Gaza children for vaccinations against polio in a campaign launched after the discovery of a case in which a one-year-old baby was partially paralyzed.</p>

<p>This was the first known case of the disease in Gaza - one of the world's most densely populated places - in 25 years. It re-emerged as Gaza's health system has virtually collapsed and many hospitals have been knocked out of action due to the war.</p>

<p>Footage circulated by the Gaza Health Ministry showed large crowds of Palestinians arriving at medical facilities in Khan Younis to get their children vaccinated.</p>

<p>UNRWA said on Wednesday good progress was being made in rolling out the vaccine to children in Gaza but a permanent ceasefire in the 11-month-old war is needed to ease humanitarian suffering.</p>

<p><strong>DEADLOCK AND FIGHTING</strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Israeli forces pressed on with operations in several areas across the Palestinian enclave, battling fighters from Hamas and the Islamic Jihad group.</p>

<p>Gaza health officials said an Israeli airstrike killed five Palestinians at the Al-Aqsa Hospital in Deir Al-Balah in the central Gaza Strip on Thursday.</p>

<p>The victims were in a tent encampment inside the hospital compound where displaced people had sought shelter, they said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the airstrike hit a command center there used by Hamas and the Islamic Jihad to plan and direct attacks against Israeli forces.</p>

<p>On the diplomatic front, the United States was trying to put forward a new proposal for a ceasefire and the release of hostages held by Hamas in the coming days, two U.S. officials, two Egyptian security sources, and an official with knowledge of the matter told Reuters.</p>

<p>The proposal aims to work out the major sticking points behind a months-long impasse in talks mediated by the United States, Qatar, and Egypt, the U.S. officials said.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says the war can only end when Hamas is eradicated. Hamas wants any agreement ending the war to include a withdrawal of all Israeli forces from Gaza.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza was triggered by Hamas' Oct. 7 attack on southern Israel, when its fighters killed 1,200 people and captured more than 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Since then, more than 40,800 Palestinians have been killed in Gaza, according to the enclave's health ministry.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a198uf7g_gaza-polio_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 40,800 Palestinians have been killed in Gaza, says Gaza health ministry]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/suffering-from-constipation-this-simple-breath-test-could-change-everything-6497420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Suffering From Constipation? This Breath Test Could Change Everything]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/suffering-from-constipation-this-simple-breath-test-could-change-everything-6497420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:14:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Using a simple breath test to measure methane, patients with intestinal methanogen overgrowth (IMO) may benefit from antibiotics and specialized diets, offering hope beyond conventional laxatives.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Constipation is more common in those whose guts contain larger concentrations of archaea, a kind of methane-producing microbe, according to a study published in the journal <em>Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology. </em>This finding may result in more focused therapies for this prevalent gastrointestinal problem. After analysing data from more than 1,500 people, researchers at Cedars-Sinai Medical Centre discovered that people with intestinal methanogen overgrowth (IMO) were more likely to have symptoms like bloating, stomach pain, and trouble passing gas.</p>

<p>"<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cghjournal.org/article/S1542-3565(24)00716-X/abstract">Our study</a> found that patients with IMO are more likely to have constipation, particularly severe constipation, and less likely to have unyielding diarrhoea," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cedars-sinai.org/newsroom/gut-microorganism-may-play-a-role-in-constipation/">said the study's corresponding author,</a> Ali Rezaie, MD, medical director of the Cedars-Sinai GI Motility Program and director of Bioinformatics at the Medically Associated Science and Technology (MAST) program at Cedars-Sinai. "Patients, however, also reported several other gut-related symptoms, including bloating, diarrhoea, abdominal pain, and flatulence."</p>

<p>As per a release by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cedars-sinai.org/newsroom/gut-microorganism-may-play-a-role-in-constipation/"><em>Cedars-Sinai Medical Centre,</em></a> constipation is one of the most common gut-related issues in the United States. About 16% of adults experience bloating, abdominal pain, and difficulty having bowel movements; the numbers nearly double for people over 60. While many things, like medication side effects or lack of dietary fibre, can cause constipation, historically, there has been a shortage of research on the gut microbiome's role in constipation and other digestive issues.</p>

<p>A simple breath test can be used to diagnose IMO. Patients with excessive methane levels in their breath may benefit from a combination of antibiotics and a specialised diet to suppress the growth of archaea in the gut.</p>

<p>"When there is an excessive amount of archaea in your gut, they produce more methane, and some of that methane makes its way to your bloodstream, then to your lungs, and you breathe it out, where it can be measured as a diagnostic test," Rezaie said. "Essentially, people who have excessive amounts of methane have a lot of GI symptoms, including constipation, flatulence, bloating, and diarrhoea."</p>

<p>This research offers hope for people struggling with constipation and paves the way for research exploring the connection between the gut microbiome and digestive health.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/av8fbc6o_constipation_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study suggests that a personalised approach could address the root causes of digestive issues.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-year-old-arrested-for-murder-of-80-year-old-indian-origin-man-in-uk-6497406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[14-Year-Old Arrested For Murder Of 80-Year-Old Indian-Origin Man In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-year-old-arrested-for-murder-of-80-year-old-indian-origin-man-in-uk-6497406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:12:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 14-year-old boy arrested following the fatal assault on 80-year-old Bhim Kohli while he was out walking his dog in a park near the eastern England city of Leicester appeared in court on Thursday charged with his murder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 14-year-old boy arrested following the fatal assault on 80-year-old Bhim Kohli while he was out walking his dog in a park near the eastern England city of Leicester appeared in court on Thursday charged with his murder.</p>

<p>The boy, who cannot be named for legal reasons as he is a minor, appeared at Leicester Youth Court sitting at Leicester Magistrates' Court. He was among five children aged between 12 and 14 years to be arrested following the death of Mr Kohli in hospital on Monday night by Leicestershire Police, with the other four released earlier with no further action.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kohli's family released a statement via the police to say they were heartbroken and struggling to cope with the loss of a loving and caring person.</p>

<p>"Bhim was a loving husband, dad and granddad. He was also a son, brother and uncle. He adored his grandkids with all his heart and loved spending time with them. He really was such a loving, caring person whose life was centred around his family," the statement said.</p>

<p>"He has always been a very hardworking man and even at the age of 80 he was still very active. One of his great passions was his allotment, he would go everyday to tend to his plots and was so proud of them. He also enjoyed walking the family dog Rocky in the park many times a day," the statement said.</p>

<p>The family shared how Kohli "loved to laugh" and was always very happy and talkative, the "joker of the family" who always loved to outsmart us with a smile.</p>

<p>"Our family has lived in the same house in Braunstone for 40 years, so he was very well known in the community - we have been overwhelmed by the messages and support from many who knew him. Our hearts have been completely broken. We are now pulling together as a family to try and support each other through the most difficult time imaginable and would ask for privacy while we do this," the statement concludes.</p>

<p>A post-mortem examination carried out following the attack at Franklin Park in Braunstone Town on Sunday evening confirmed the cause of death as a neck injury, while further tests will be carried out.</p>

<p>"The circumstances surrounding Mr Kohli's death are extremely tragic and upsetting not only for his family and friends but also the wider community," Detective Inspector Emma Matts, Senior Investigating Officer at Leicestershire Police, said earlier this week.</p>

<p>"We continue to offer support to the family through our family liaison officers and the local policing teams are in the area to provide reassurance and discuss any issues or concerns," she added.</p>

<p>Now that a suspect has been charged in the case, further details will be restricted to prevent any interventions that may prejudice a murder trial.</p>

<p>Earlier, Leicestershire Police had admitted "prior police contact with the victim", which initially led to a voluntary referral to the Independent Office of Police Conduct (IOPC) before being escalated to a mandatory referral after further contact with the watchdog.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A post-mortem examination confirmed the cause of death as a neck injury. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-macron-names-former-brexit-negotiator-michel-barnier-as-new-french-pm-6497318]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French President Macron Names Ex-Brexit Negotiator As New French PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-macron-names-former-brexit-negotiator-michel-barnier-as-new-french-pm-6497318]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 17:01:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron appointed Michel Barnier, the European Union's former Brexit negotiator, as his new prime minister on Thursday, after weeks of drawn out talks following an inconclusive snap election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron appointed Michel Barnier, the European Union's former Brexit negotiator, as his new prime minister on Thursday, after weeks of drawn out talks following an inconclusive snap election.</p>

<p>Michel Barnier, aged 73, led the EU's talks with Britain over its exit from the bloc from 2016-2021. Prior to that, the conservative politician held roles in various French governments and was also EU Commissioner.</p>

<p>Macron had considered a string of potential prime ministers in recent weeks, none of which mustered enough support to guarantee a stable government, and there is no guarantee Barnier's government will manage to get reforms adopted by a hung parliament.</p>

<p>But at least the far-right National Rally (RN), whose party is one of the biggest in parliament after the early July election, signalled earlier on Thursday it would not immediately reject Barnier, if he met certain conditions.</p>

<p>Barnier is a staunch pro-European and a moderate career politician, but he toughened his discourse considerably during his failed 2021 bid to get his conservative party's ticket for the presidential election, saying immigration was out of control - a view shared by the RN.</p>

<p>Macron's gamble to call the snap parliamentary election in June backfired, with his centrist coalition losing dozens of seats and no party winning an absolute majority.</p>

<p>The left's New Popular Front alliance came first but Macron ruled out asking them to form a government after other parties said they would immediately vote it down.</p>

<p>Instead, he waited weeks to make his choice.</p>

<p>Even if the political paralysis were to continue despite the appointment of a new government, Macron could not call a new snap election until July next year.</p>

<p>RN lawmaker Sebastien Chenu told BFM TV that the far-right party would wait to see what Barnier has to say on immigration, and on changing France's voting system.</p>

<p>Lawmaker Laurent Jacobelli, also from the RN, said a condition was that parliament be dissolved as soon as possible - which would be early July.</p>

<p>"The RN wants a prime minister who is committed to dissolving as soon as possible and establishing proportional representation (for parliamentary elections)," Jacobelli told TF1.</p>

<p>Still, the RN was not particularly enthusiastic about Barnier.</p>

<p>"They are taking out of mothballs those who have governed France for 40 years," Jacobelli said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0fipnmig_michel-barnier_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Emmanuel Macron had considered a string of potential prime ministers in recent weeks. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-couple-on-trial-over-locking-foster-daughter-10-in-electrified-cage-6496996]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dutch Couple On Trial Over Locking Foster Daughter, 10, In Electrified Cage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-couple-on-trial-over-locking-foster-daughter-10-in-electrified-cage-6496996]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A couple went on trial on Thursday accused of locking their 10-year-old foster daughter in an electrified cage and throwing her downstairs, in a harrowing case that has shocked the Netherlands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A couple went on trial on Thursday accused of locking their 10-year-old foster daughter in an electrified cage and throwing her downstairs, in a harrowing case that has shocked the Netherlands.</p>

<p>The girl was taken to hospital in May, unconscious, in a filthy state, with several broken bones and badly malnourished, reportedly weighing just 22 kilogrammes (50 pounds).</p>

<p>She emerged from her coma in July but is unable to sit up independently or communicate, prosecutors said as the trial opened in Rotterdam.</p>

<p>They said she would probably need intensive medical care for the rest of her life.</p>

<p>The couple, named only as Daisy and John, both 37, stand charged of attempted manslaughter for throwing or pushing her down the stairs, among other charges.</p>

<p>They held their foster daughter captive in the house and abused her for months, prosecutors alleged.</p>

<p>"They locked her in her room, handcuffed her arms and legs and covered her mouth with tape. They placed her in a homemade cage with electrical wires attached to it," the public prosecutor told the court.</p>

<p>Neither suspect was present in court to hear the accusations.</p>

<p>A lawyer for the couple said they denied pushing her down the stairs, arguing that she jumped down the stairs herself.</p>

<p>The case of the "Foster Girl From Vlaardingen", the harbour town just outside Rotterdam where she lived, has been headline news in the Netherlands, with question over how authorities could have missed the alleged abuse.</p>

<p>Dutch media said the girl had reported the alleged abuse several times.</p>

<p>She was forcibly removed from her biological parents after suffering abuse at their hands.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qpr783oo_cage-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dutch media said the girl had reported the alleged abuse several times. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-10-points-on-israels-response-to-munich-massacre-6496964]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wrath of God": 10 Points On Israel's Response To Munich Massacre]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wrath-of-god-10-points-on-israels-response-to-munich-massacre-6496964]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:21:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Today marks the anniversary of the 1972 Munich massacre, where eight members of Black September took 11 Israeli athletes hostage at the Olympics. Two were killed initially, and a failed rescue led to the deaths of all hostages, a German officer.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>After the horrific 1972 Munich Olympics massacre that shook the whole world, Israel implemented a program of sending covert agents abroad to kill enemies, an approach that is still active today.</li>
	<li>The national intelligence agency of Israel Mossad launched Operation "Wrath of God" to hunt down Black September members, targeting the group's leadership with covert assassinations overseas.</li>
	<li>Ehud Barak, former Israeli prime minister, who at the time served as a commando leading an elite military unit, recalls the Munich massacre as a shock that ignited public outrage and a drive for revenge.</li>
	<li>Under Prime Minister Golda Meir, Israel devised a strategy to "smash the head of the serpent" by targeting Black September's leadership in Europe and the Middle East.</li>
	<li>In 1973, Israeli operatives, disguised as women, assassinated three senior Palestinian leaders in Beirut in a daring mission involving speedboats and military deception.</li>
	<li>Ehud Barak himself, disguised as a woman during the Beirut mission, led the team that killed Mohammed Youssef al-Najjar, Kamal Adwan, and Kamal Nasser.</li>
	<li>Mossad's overconfidence led to a failure in Norway, where agents mistakenly killed a Moroccan waiter, Ahmed Bouchikhi, instead of Black September leader Ali Hassan Salameh.</li>
	<li>After years of tracking Salameh, Mossad finally assassinated him in 1979 in Beirut, using a car bomb, after infiltrating his social circle.</li>
	<li>Israel continued targeted assassinations against its enemies, including Palestinian militants during the Intifada, and later expanded operations to Iranian targets.</li>
	<li>Mossad's assassination of Iranian nuclear scientist Mohsen Fakhrizadeh highlights the ongoing "shadow war" with Iran, aimed at preventing its nuclear capability development.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kg1h1nno_israeli-olympians_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Images of the Israeli Olympians who were murdered by the attackers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/putin-says-constantly-in-touch-with-india-over-ukraine-conflict-report-6496923]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Putin Says Constantly In Touch With India Over Ukraine Conflict: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/putin-says-constantly-in-touch-with-india-over-ukraine-conflict-report-6496923]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:19:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin on Thursday named India among the three countries he is constantly in touch over the Ukraine conflict and said they are sincerely making efforts to resolve it, state-owned TASS news agency reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin on Thursday named India among the three countries he is constantly in touch with over the Ukraine conflict and said they are sincerely making efforts to resolve it, state-owned TASS news agency reported.</p>

<p>Reporting on his remarks at the plenary session of the Eastern Economic Forum (EEF) in Vladivostok, US media outlet Politico reported him as also saying, "If there is a desire of Ukraine to carry on with the negotiations, I can do that." Putin's remarks came within two weeks after Prime Minister Narendra Modi's historic visit to Ukraine where he held talks with President President Volodymyr Zelenskyy.</p>

<p>"We respect our friends and partners, who, I believe, sincerely seek to resolve all issues surrounding this conflict, primarily China, Brazil and India. I constantly keep in touch with our colleagues on this issue," Putin was quoted as saying by the Russian news agency.</p>

<p>Separately, Russian Presidential Spokesman Dmitry Peskov told the Izvestia daily that India could help in establishing a dialogue on Ukraine.</p>

<p>Underlining the existing "highly constructive, even friendly relations" between PM Modi and Putin, he said the Indian Prime Minister can "lead the line on getting first-hand information from the participants in this conflict," as he "freely communicates with Putin, with Zelenskyy, and with the Americans." "This gives a great opportunity for India to throw its weight in world affairs, to use its influence that would drive the Americans and Ukrainians towards using a greater political will and entering the peaceful settlement track," Peskov said.</p>

<p>He, however, said there are "no specific plans" on PM Modi mediating on the issue.</p>

<p>"At this time they can hardly exist, as we do not see any preconditions for talks for now," the Kremlin spokesman said.</p>

<p>PM Modi on August 23 visited Ukraine where he conveyed to President Zelenskyy that both Ukraine and Russia should sit together without wasting time to end the ongoing war and that India was ready to play an "active role" to restore peace in the region.</p>

<p>His nearly nine-hour visit to Ukraine, the first by an Indian prime minister since its independence in 1991, came six weeks after he held summit talks with President Putin that triggered anguish in some Western countries.</p>

<p>In his talks with Zelenskyy in Kyiv, PM Modi said India was on the side of peace since the beginning of the conflict and he would even like to contribute personally for a peaceful resolution of the crisis.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p59m2dh8_putin-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We respect our friends and partners," said Vladimir Putin. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/elon-musk-x-grok-ai-musks-x-bows-to-eu-data-protection-demands-on-grok-ai-scraping-6496907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musks X Bows To EU Data Protection Demands On Grok AI Scraping]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/elon-musk-x-grok-ai-musks-x-bows-to-eu-data-protection-demands-on-grok-ai-scraping-6496907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:15:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following the notification, X agreed to temporarily suspend the use of the data to train Grok - a commitment that became permanent on Wednesday]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X Corp. agreed to stop processing the personal information of European users to train its artificial intelligence chatbot Grok, bowing to demands from European Union regulators.</p>

<p>Ireland's Data Protection Commission on Wednesday announced the company's commitment to delete EU users' personal data contained in public posts on its X social-media platform that were collected between May 7 and Aug. 1, 2024.</p>

<p>The spat began in August, when the DPC filed a request with Ireland's High Court to stop X from processing the data for use in the company's AI model, citing EU data protection restrictions and alleging that X's action risked jeopardizing users' rights.</p>

<p>Ireland's data protection office serves as the chief EU regulator for X, which has its European headquarters in the country. The DPC said it was the first time a lead EU agency has taken such an action against an online platform.</p>

<p>Following the DPC's original notification, X agreed to temporarily suspend the use of the data to train Grok - a commitment that became permanent Wednesday, leading the DPC to conclude the court proceedings.</p>

<p>The DPC also asked the EU-level European Data Protection Board to kick-start a discussion on the interplay between data protection and AI model training - an issue that has in recent months given rise to disputes between data watchdogs and tech companies, including X and Meta Platforms, Inc.</p>

<p>"The DPC hopes that the resulting opinion will enable proactive, effective and consistent Europe-wide regulation of this area more broadly," DPC commissioner Dale Sunderland said in a news release. "It will also support the handling of a number of complaints that have been lodged with/transmitted to the DPC" about this matter.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fhr2e05_grokai_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X has faced recent setbacks, including a ban of the platform in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-kanye-west-telegraphically-told-her-to-steal-car-with-child-inside-6496822]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Claims Kanye West 'Telegraphically' Told Her To Steal Car, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-kanye-west-telegraphically-told-her-to-steal-car-with-child-inside-6496822]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:07:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman, identified by police as 28-year-old Ricki Smith was arrested following reports of a disturbance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman from Louisville was arrested in Evansville, Indiana, after attempting to steal cars outside a business, claiming that musician Kanye West had instructed her through 'telepathy' to commit the theft. The incident occurred on Friday and caused a stir when the woman tried to enter several vehicles, one of which had a child inside, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbc4i.com/news/u-s-world/woman-claims-kanye-west-telegraphically-told-her-to-steal-car-with-child-inside/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The woman, identified by police as 28-year-old Ricki Smith was arrested following reports of a disturbance. Witnesses at the scene reported seeing Smith attempting to open random car doors in a nearby parking lot.</p>

<p>According to an eyewitness, Smith managed to find an unlocked vehicle and sat in the driver's seat. Bystanders asked her to leave, but she refused. Moments later, she entered another car, which belonged to a woman who had stepped away briefly, leaving her car unlocked with her child in the back seat.</p>

<p>The situation escalated when the car owner returned to find Smith inside her vehicle. Fearing for her child's safety, the woman reportedly grabbed Smith by the hair and forcibly removed her from the car. Local reports confirmed that the woman plans to press charges.</p>

<p>Smith, however, gave a different version of events to the police, claiming she had been travelling from Louisville to Evansville when her car broke down. She said she hitchhiked to Evansville and, in a bizarre twist, claimed that she was instructed to steal a vehicle because "Kanye West speaks to me telegraphically." She likely meant to say telepathically.</p>

<p>Further investigation revealed that Smith had crashed her vehicle into a tree line off Highway 64 before abandoning it, which led to her alleged attempts to steal another car. She was subsequently arrested and is currently being held at the Vanderburgh County Jail.</p>

<p>Kanye West, also known as Ye, is a controversial rapper and music producer in the US, widely known for his provocative statements.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/7n58ucd8_kanye-west-afp-650_625x300_27_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kanye West, also known as Ye, is a controversial rapper]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacecraft-flies-closer-to-mercury-than-planned-after-thruster-problems-6496809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Spacecraft Flies Closer To Mercury Than Planned After Thruster Problems]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacecraft-flies-closer-to-mercury-than-planned-after-thruster-problems-6496809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 16:04:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A spacecraft carrying European and Japanese probes passed closer to Mercury than originally planned overnight after thruster problems delayed the mission to study the little-known, Sun-scorched planet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A spacecraft carrying European and Japanese probes passed closer to Mercury than originally planned overnight after thruster problems delayed the mission to study the little-known, Sun-scorched planet.</p>

<p>The BepiColombo mission launched in 2018 on a winding path that had been intended to enter the orbit of the planet closest to the Sun in December 2025.</p>

<p>But in April, a glitch with the spacecraft's thrusters sapped some of its power supply, forcing teams on the ground to change its trajectory and delaying its arrival until November 2026.</p>

<p>The new path meant the spacecraft needed to fly 35 kilometres (22 miles) closer to the planet than initially planned -- passing just 165 kilometres above the surface -- during its latest flyby.</p>

<p>The European Space Agency's operations team confirmed that "all went well" with the flyby overnight, the mission's account on X said on Thursday.</p>

<p>It also posted a new image taken by the probe of the planet, whose pockmarked surface resembles the Moon.</p>

<p>It was the fourth of six planned flybys of Mercury on the mission's nine-billion-kilometre journey before it can finally settle into the planet's orbit.</p>

<p>Most of the time Mercury is closer to Earth than Mars -- but the red planet can be reached by missions from Earth in just seven months.</p>

<p>Mercury is "the most difficult" planet for probes to reach, explained Paris Observatory astronomer Alain Doressoundiram.</p>

<p>The planet's relatively tiny mass -- it is only slightly bigger than the Moon -- means its gravitational pull is extremely weak compared to the Sun, making it tricky for satellites to stay in its orbit.</p>

<p>"It takes much more energy to brake and stop at Mercury than to go to Mars," Doressoundiram told AFP.</p>

<p>This is where delicate manoeuvres called gravitational assists come in. These slingshots around celestial bodies allow spacecraft to speed up, slow down, or change trajectory.</p>

<p>The glitch with the electric thrusters means the spacecraft is now operating with only 90 percent of its planned power supply.</p>

<p>After months spent investigating the problem, the thrusters will "remain operating below the minimum thrust required for an insertion into orbit around Mercury in December 2025," mission manager Santa Martinez said in a statement earlier this week.</p>

<p>The new slower path means BepiColombo is now planned to enter orbit in November 2026.</p>

<p>- Space 'oddities' -</p>

<p>Mercury is by far the least studied of the four rocky, innermost planets in our solar system, which also include Venus, Earth and Mars.</p>

<p>NASA's Mariner 10 was the first probe to capture a close picture of its lunar-looking surface in 1974.</p>

<p>No spacecraft had orbited the planet until the MESSENGER probe arrived in 2011.</p>

<p>The NASA mission confirmed "some rather bizarre things," said Doressoundiram, a specialist on the surfaces of planets.</p>

<p>One of these "oddities" is that Mercury is the only rocky planet other than Earth to have a magnetic field, Doressoundiram said. Exactly how it has such a magnetic field so close to the Sun is not fully understood.</p>

<p>Another "oddity" is that Mercury's iron core composes 60 percent of its mass -- compared to only a third for Earth.</p>

<p>Mercury's surface is also marked by "hollows," which could suggest relatively recent geologic activity.</p>

<p>Also unclear is the composition of minerals on covering the planet's surface, which is blasted with intense radiation from the Sun.</p>

<p>These are just some of the mysteries that the BepiColombo mission hopes to shed light on when it finally orbits Mercury for at least a year and a half.</p>

<p>The spacecraft carries two separate satellites, one from the ESA and another from Japan's JAXA space agency, which have a total of 16 scientific instruments.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/908lteu_mercury-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mercury is "the most difficult" planet for probes to reach, says Alain Doressoundiram. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-shot-dead-near-nazi-era-exhibit-israel-consulate-in-germany-6496670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunman Shot Dead Near Nazi-Era Exhibit, Israel Consulate In Germany]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-shot-dead-near-nazi-era-exhibit-israel-consulate-in-germany-6496670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:46:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A gunman opened fire at German police before he was shot dead dead by officers Thursday near Munich's Nazi-era documentation centre and the Israeli consulate, the Bavarian state interior minister said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A gunman opened fire at German police before he was shot dead dead by officers Thursday near Munich's Nazi-era documentation centre and the Israeli consulate, the Bavarian state interior minister said.</p>

<p>"Police responded with armed force against the perpetrator, who was carrying a rifle and had fired a number of shots," said the minister, Joachim Herrmann, adding that the gunman had died of his wounds.</p>

<p>Joachim Herrmann said it was "obvious that the crime scene" near the documentation centre and the Israeli diplomatic mission "could provide further clues" about the gunman's motive.</p>

<p>The minister also pointed out that Thursday marks "the 52nd anniversary of the terrible attack on the Israeli team during the Olympic Games" of 1972 at the hands of a Palestinian group.</p>

<p>Munich police wrote on social media platform X that, after the shooting, there were "no indications of any other suspects" and that no one else was wounded.</p>

<p>The Munich Documentation Center for the History of National Socialism is located on the site of the former Nazi party headquarters and close to Israel's consulate in the southern German city.</p>

<p>A police helicopter was in the sky above the area and the sound of police sirens blared through the streets.</p>

<p>The Bild daily showed pictures of armed police wearing helmets and body armour in the downtown area.</p>

<p>Police advised the public that a large number of police were "on their way to the site of operations in the area of the NS Documentation Centre".</p>

<p>"To ensure that they can work without hindrance, we ask that you avoid this area as much as possible."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/d4q8cs38_germany-police-generic_625x300_05_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["No indications of any other suspects," Say Munich police]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-is-finally-reversing-its-semiconductor-misfortune-6496509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Is Finally Reversing Its Semiconductor Misfortune]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-is-finally-reversing-its-semiconductor-misfortune-6496509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 15:22:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Modi government has recognised the fact that if India needs to be a big geopolitical player, it needs to be the leading light in the semiconductor arena.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cefisvro_semiconductor_625x300_05_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em>(This is the second article in a two-part series on the US-China semiconductor battle, and where India stands in it. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/china-is-eating-away-at-uss-tech-reign-chip-by-chip-6481939">Here is the first part</a>)</em></p>

<p>When Chandrayaan 3 landed on the moon on August 23 last year, there was one place in Mohali that was particularly jubilant: the government-run Semiconductor Laboratory (SCL). It was a personal win for SCL's engineers, the unsung heroes who for months worked on producing a wide variety of semiconductors critical for controlling and commanding the mission. The spacecraft used chips to enable communication with Earth and navigate its way to the landing destination, using sensors and cameras to transmit data and messages.</p>

<p>Mohali's SCL is India's only well-known chip-making foundry. It began production in 1984, three years before the world's biggest semiconductor manufacturing company, the Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC), was founded.</p>

<p>Today, however, while TSMC produces 90% of the world's most sophisticated and advanced semiconductors or microchips, churning out the most valued 5-nanometer (nm) chips in size, SCL can make only legacy chips of 100 nm and above, which are obviously many generations old. TSMC's annual turnover exceeded $70 billion last year, far more than the SCL's meagre $5 million. And while TSMC's clients are some of the world's leading tech firms, such as Apple, AMD and Nvidia, among SCL's top clients is just ISRO (Indian Space Research Organisation). TSMC's factories are state-of-the-art; SCL is in dire need of modernisation and upgradation.</p>

<h2><strong>India's Tough Luck</strong></h2>

<p>SCL could have been TSMC's largest rival if it were not for one very unfortunate incident, which pushed India back to the semiconductor dark ages. On February 27, 1989, a mysterious fire broke out in the plant, destroying most of the facilities. To date, no one knows if it was an act of sabotage or an accident. The factory later rose from the ashes, but by then, it was left far behind in the race.</p>

<p>Dan Hutcheson of Canada's TechInsights company, one of the industry's global voices, surprised me when he said he had been monitoring the Indian chip industry since the 1970s. "I have seen India strive for this industry my entire career. There have been only failures. It is important for India to be successful now." Dan is not wrong, as India's semiconductor history is made up of a series of broken dreams and unfulfilled promises. Several multinational companies tried their luck in setting up chip production projects, but they did not materialise for various reasons.</p>

<h2><strong>Micron Project, A Sign Of Good Things To Come</strong></h2>

<p>It took India over three decades after the 1989 tragedy to see a positive development in its semiconductor journey. In August last year, a groundbreaking ceremony was held in Sanand, Gujarat, for Micron Technology's state-of-the-art semiconductor assembly, testing, and packaging facility. Its bosses claim the facility will be operational early next year. The plant will be completed in two phases at a cost of $2.75 billion  $825 million being invested by Micron, and the rest by the Centre and the Gujarat government.</p>

<p>The Micron project appears to be the beginning of the country's bright chip future. Since the groundbreaking ceremony&nbsp;last year, four new projects have been announced, the latest on Monday when the government said it&nbsp;cleared a proposal of Kaynes Semicon to set up a semiconductor unit in Sanand. All the new units, except Tata Electronics' fab unit in Dholera in Gujarat are testing and packaging&nbsp;units. Taiwain's Powerchip Semiconductor Manufacturing Corporation (PSMC) and Tata Electronics announced in&nbsp;February this year that they will set up a fabrication unit in Dholera. I am sure the government will be more keen to see the progress of this project because it's India's first fab unit in the private sector. Neither company in their press statements have&nbsp;given a completion date or the costs involved but according to media&nbsp;reports, the total project will cost Rs 91,000 crore.</p>

<p>India have witnessed several false dawns in the last few decades, but now things appear to be changing, and at a fast speed. There was a time when India could not even dream of producing sophisticated smartphones. That was a domain exclusively captured by China. Today, India is a manufacturing hub for iPhones and other smartphone brands. Citing this success story, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said last year, We have successfully made India a manufacturing hub for mobile phones over the last decade. Now, our next goal is to position the country as a leader in semiconductor manufacturing.</p>

<h2><strong>India Is Established In Just One Segment&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>A semiconductor manufacturing ecosystem requires infrastructure for designing, fabrication, research, testing, and packaging. Besides, it needs sophisticated tools, minerals, and gases to make chips. While India severely lacks large-scale semiconductor fabrication facilities, it has built a robust ecosystem for chip design and related services. Major global semiconductor companies such as Intel, Qualcomm, Texas Instruments, NVIDIA, AMD and Broadcom have established significant design and R&amp;D centres in India. Indian engineers contribute to the design of the most complex chips used in cutting-edge technologies, from artificial intelligence to 5G networks. Companies like Wipro, Tata Elxsi, and HCL Technologies also provide outsourced semiconductor design services, catering to global clients.</p>

<h2><strong>"Learn To Walk Before You Can Run"</strong></h2>

<p>Now, the Modi government wants India to become a fabrication, R&amp;D, testing, and packaging hub. A tall order indeed, considering India is only at the beginning of the chip race  but not an impossible one. I have spoken to several industry experts worldwide over the last two years, and they believe India can become a semiconductor hub and a global player in 10-20 years if it stays as focused, patient, and committed as the Modi government appears to be today.</p>

<p>To put India's efforts in perspective, we ought to remember that it took semiconductor superpowers Taiwan and South Korea decades to reach where they are in the race today. "Realistically, it'll take 10 to 20 years, assuming it is well-executed. You have to learn to walk before you can run. That's the important thing  to make sure the Micron project is successful," says Hutcheson, who calls the Micron packaging project "a great baby step. To be sure, South Korea, Taiwan, and China all started with packaging units.</p>

<h2><strong>India's Challenges</strong></h2>

<p>Chip fabrication, which allows for the production of 5 nm or even 2 nm microchips, is widely believed to be the key to the success of a semiconductor mission. A host of things are needed before manufacturing can start 10-15 years later. This is not a simple industry; it requires a lot of work and high-end equipment and materials.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>1. Investment</strong></h2>

<p>According to the Semiconductor Industry Association estimates, a state-of-the-art manufacturing factory takes a minimum of 10 years to produce chips. The initial capital investment and operating costs can run up to anywhere between $10 billion and $40 billion. If India dreams of being a chi hub, it will have to invest hugely in the sector in the next 10-15 years. China has been doing just that, pouring billions of dollars into becoming self-reliant in semiconductor manufacturing. The US has pumped in over $100 billion in its own industry since 2022. Against these stark figures, India has managed to inject just about $15 billion into its semiconductor project.&nbsp;</p>

<p>What India badly needs is private investors and global players.</p>

<h2><strong>2. Gases and Mineral Shortages</strong></h2>

<p>Semiconductor chip manufacturing essentially uses more than 150 types of chemicals and over 30 types of gases and minerals. At present, all these are available only in a few countries. The challenge for India is to be self-reliant in this sector.</p>

<h2><strong>3. Supporting Industries</strong></h2>

<p>Some experts believe that the main task for India is to create supporting industries for the chip industry to emerge. The issue relates to some basic things, like having a stable power grid and consistent water availability, which make it possible to build the semiconductor industry.</p>

<h2><strong>4. Political Will</strong></h2>

<p>The chip industry is capital-intensive and time-consuming, which requires deep commitment from the government and private players alike. It requires the willpower of successive governments to stay in the game. PM Modi wants India to be a developed economy by 2047. A long-term semiconductor strategy will be needed if India really is to become a developed country by 2047.</p>

<h2><strong>5. Skilled Manpower</strong></h2>

<p>India has manpower in abundance, but it has a shortage of the kind of skilled manpower needed in the semiconductor industry.</p>

<h2><strong>6. Brain Drain</strong></h2>

<p>India could achieve its goal of becoming a semiconductor hub in around five to six years rather than the conventional 10-20 year timeframe if we manage to bring big Indian talent, serving global companies, back home. Can we entice them with equivalent salary packages and perks? Can nation-building be a motivator? Can we improve our work culture to make it more professional and productive?</p>

<p>Taiwan's success story owes a lot to the Taiwanese-origin executives who obtained their semiconductor expertise and experiences in the US. The Taiwanese government in the 1980s decided to bring its talented people back to kickstart the semiconductor industry. It paid them salaries on a par with Western companies. These expat Taiwanese played a huge role in making Taiwan a truly global chip hub.</p>

<p>South Korea's chip revolution also started after the government enticed many Korean experts working in Japanese companies to come back and work in Korea.</p>

<p>There is no dearth of Indians who are doing well in the semiconductor business in the US and elsewhere. Around a dozen leaders of the world's leading chip-making companies are either Indian or of Indian origin. I have met a couple. They all love India. But India needs to create the right conditions to bring them back, and also stop the brain drain of young engineering graduates who are in high demand abroad.</p>

<h2><strong>A New Dawn</strong></h2>

<p>India is on the cusp of sealing deals with several multinational companies to launch new projects. The Modi government has recognised the fact that if India needs to be a big geopolitical player, it needs to be the leading light in the semiconductor arena. What follows after the Micron factory will determine the future of India's semiconductor industry.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/kdi4q9t8_semiconductor_625x300_05_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/goldman-sachs-says-kamala-harris-victory-better-for-us-economy-6496270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs Says Kamala Harris' Victory Better For US Economy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/goldman-sachs-says-kamala-harris-victory-better-for-us-economy-6496270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:51:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The investment bank stated the US economic growth would likely witness the biggest boost in the coming two years from a Democratic government, headed by Kamala Harris.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wall Street giant Goldman Sachs has predicted the potential economic implications of a Republican or Democratic victory in the November 5 presidential elections in the US. It claimed the country's GDP may face a hit if Donald Trump secures a second term in the White House, reported Reuters.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In a note on Tuesday, economists at the investment bank stated that the economic growth of the US would likely witness the biggest boost in the coming two years from a Democratic government, headed by Kamala Harris, Reuters reported.<br />
<br />
The economic output would take a hit next year, majorly from the increased tariffs on imports as well as tighter immigration policies, if the Republican Party comes to power, even with a divided government led by the former US president, they said.<br />
<br />
As per Goldman Sachs, there will be more job growth in the US under a Democrat government than the Republicans.<br />
<br />
If Trump sweeps the polls or even manages to form a divided government, in that case, "the hit to growth from tariffs and tighter immigration policy would outweigh the positive fiscal impulse, resulting in a peak hit to GDP growth of -0.5pp in 2025H2 that abates in 2026," it said.<br />
<br />
If Democrats get another term then the new spending and expanded middle-income tax credits will slightly be more than the "offset lower investment due to higher corporate tax rates", the Wall Street behemoth believes.<br />
<br />
This will result in a "very slight boost to GDP investment due to higher corporate tax rates." Ultimately, this will give a little boost to GDP growth on average over 2025-2026.<br />
<br />
"If Democrats sweep, new spending and expanded middle-income tax credits would slightly more than offset lower investment due to higher corporate tax rates, resulting in a very slight boost to GDP investment due to higher corporate tax rates, resulting in a very slight boost to GDP growth on average over 2025-2026," the news agency quoted the note from the company.<br />
<br />
If Harris wins, the job growth will be 10,000 a month higher compared with Trump's win with a divided government, and it will be 30,000 higher in comparison with a sweep by the Republicans, as per Goldman estimates.<br />
<br />
The US' core inflation is likely to rise as a Trump win may lead to increased tariffs on auto imports from China, Mexico and the European Union, it added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qlnqj9dg_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-says-attacks-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-not-communal-6496138]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Attacks On Hindus In Bangladesh Not Communal: Muhammad Yunus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-says-attacks-on-hindus-in-bangladesh-not-communal-6496138]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 Sep 2024 14:43:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chief Adviser to Bangladesh's interim government, Muhammad Yunus, has said the issue of attacks on minority Hindus in his country is "exaggerated" and questioned the manner in which India projected it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chief Adviser to Bangladesh's interim government, Muhammad Yunus, has said the issue of attacks on minority Hindus in his country is exaggerated and questioned the manner in which India projected it.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI at his official residence here, Yunus said the attacks on minorities in Bangladesh are more political than communal.</p>

<p>He suggested that the attacks were not communal, but a fallout of a political upheaval as there is a perception that most Hindus supported the now-deposed Awami League regime.</p>

<p>I have said this to (Prime Minister Narendra) Modi also that this is exaggerated. This issue has several dimensions. When the country went through an upheaval following the atrocities by (Sheikh) Hasina and the Awami League, those who were with them also faced attacks, the Nobel laureate told PTI.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/muhammad-yunus-advice-to-sheikh-hasina-stay-silent-in-india-till-6494885"><strong>Read: "Stay Silent In India Till...": Muhammad Yunus' Advice To Sheikh Hasina</strong></a></p>

<p>The minority Hindu population faced vandalism of their businesses and properties, as well as the destruction of Hindu temples, during the student-led violence that erupted following the ouster of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>After unprecedented anti-government protests that peaked on August 5, Hasina resigned as prime minister and fled to India.</p>

<p>Now, while beating up Awami League cadres, they had beaten up Hindus as there is a perception that Hindus in Bangladesh mean Awami League supporters. I am not saying that what has happened is right, but some people are using it as an excuse to seize property. So, there is no clear distinction between Awami League supporters and Hindus, he said.</p>

<p>In his first direct contact with New Delhi last month, shortly after becoming the head of Bangladesh's interim government, Yunus conveyed to Prime Minister Modi that Dhaka would prioritise the protection and safety of Hindus and all other minority groups.</p>

<p>During the conversation, Modi reaffirmed India's support for a democratic, stable, peaceful, and progressive Bangladesh and emphasised the importance of ensuring the safety of Hindus and other minority communities in the violence-hit country.</p>

<p>Hindus, who made up 22 per cent of Bangladesh's population at the time of the 1971 Liberation War, now constitute about 8 per cent of 170 million and have predominantly supported the Awami League, known for its secular stance.</p>

<p>Describing the attacks as more political than communal, Yunus questioned the manner in which India is propagating them.</p>

<p>These attacks are political in nature and not communal. And India is propagating these incidents in a big way. We have not said that we can't do anything; we have said that we are doing everything, the Chief Adviser said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi, in his Independence Day address from the Red Fort on August 15, expressed hope that the situation in violence-hit Bangladesh would return to normal soon and said 1.4 billion Indians are concerned about the safety of Hindus and minorities in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>Discussing the future of India-Bangladesh relations, Yunus expressed a desire for good ties with India but insisted that New Delhi must abandon the narrative that Bangladesh will turn into another Afghanistan without Sheikh Hasina at the helm.</p>

<p>The way forward is for India to come out of the narrative. The narrative is that everybody is Islamist, BNP is Islamist, and everyone else is Islamist and will make this country into Afghanistan. And Bangladesh is in safe hands with Sheikh Hasina at the helm only.</p>

<p>India is captivated by this narrative. India needs to come out of this narrative. Bangladesh, like any other nation, is just another neighbour, he said.</p>

<p>The noted economist added, The issue of trying to portray the conditions of minorities in such a big way is just an excuse. Yunus said that when he met leaders of the minority community, he urged them to protest as citizens of the country with equal rights and not merely as Hindus.</p>

<p>Even when I met members of the Hindu community, I had requested them: please don't identify yourselves as Hindus; rather, you should say you are citizens of this country and you have equal rights. If someone tries to snatch your legal rights as citizens, then there are remedies, he said.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Hindu Buddhist Christian Unity Council (BHBCUC), a prominent Hindu minority group in Bangladesh, had also reported attacks on minorities, especially Hindus, following the fall of Sheikh Hasina's government on August 5.</p>

<p>Thousands of Hindus staged protest rallies in Bangladesh's capital and the northeastern port city of Chattogram on August 10-11, demanding protection amid nationwide vandalism that saw attacks on temples and their homes and businesses.</p>

<p>Earlier in August, the Bangladesh National Hindu Grand Alliance said that the minority Hindu community faced attacks and threats in 278 locations across 48 districts since the fall of the Hasina-led government and termed it as an assault on the Hindu religion.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/56nalei8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus  suggested that the attacks were not communal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>