<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 09:02:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-jabaliya-3-israeli-soldiers-killed-as-forces-step-up-ground-ops-in-northern-gaza-6764321]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Israeli Soldiers Killed As Forces Step Up Ground Ops In Northern Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-jabaliya-3-israeli-soldiers-killed-as-forces-step-up-ground-ops-in-northern-gaza-6764321]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 09:02:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three Israeli soldiers were killed on Wednesday in the northern Gaza strip, even as the Israel Defence Forces stepped up air and ground operations in Jabaliya.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three Israeli soldiers were killed on Wednesday in the northern Gaza Strip, even as the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) stepped up air and ground operations in Jabaliya.</p>

<p>The deceased soldiers were identified as&nbsp;37-year-old Major Nathaniel Hershkowitz, 32-year-old&nbsp;Major Zvi Mattiyo Marantz and 32-year-old&nbsp;Major Uri Moshe Bornstein. Their funeral will be held at the&nbsp;Mount Herzl Military Cemetery in Jerusalem on Friday.</p>

<p>The Israeli military amplified its offensive in Gaza's north, with troops encircling the key city of Jabaliya and some surrounding areas since Sunday with the goal to&nbsp;destroy the operational capabilities Hamas is trying to rebuild there.</p>

<p>Residents have been asked to evacuate, as the IDF aims to impose a&nbsp;total siege on Jabaliya until Hamas fighters surrender, according to news agency AFP. Further,&nbsp;Israeli army spokesman Avichay Adraee urged residents of the northern towns of Beit Hanoun, Jabaliya, Beit Lahia and other neighbourhoods to evacuate to southern Gaza.</p>

<p>The military said it has killed at least "20 terrorists".</p>

<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said the north has been pounded with air strikes in recent days, with dozens killed. Meanwhile,&nbsp;Hamas has said its fighters are targeting Israeli soldiers and tanks.</p>

<p>As the exchange of fire continues, Gaza's health ministry issued an appeal to the international community to bring in fuel to enable hospitals to continue providing services.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hle4bpbg_israel-soldiers_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[(Clockwise from top - Nathaniel Hershkowitz, Zvi Mathiahu Marentz, Uri Moshe Bornstein)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terrifying-video-shows-tree-falling-on-moving-car-as-hurricane-milton-approaches-6764275]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Captures Life-Or-Death Moment As Hurricane Milton Unleashes Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terrifying-video-shows-tree-falling-on-moving-car-as-hurricane-milton-approaches-6764275]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:44:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton: The storm made landfall on Florida's west coast on Wednesday night as a Category 3 hurricane on the Saffir-Simpson scale, bringing maximum sustained winds of 120 mph (205 kph).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A terrifying video has surfaced showing the moment a tree fell on a moving car in Florida, just before Hurricane Milton made landfall. The driver survived the incident, which took place in DeLand as 120-mph winds from the hurricane pummeled Florida's west coast. As of Thursday, the fatalities from the hurricane rose to at least 15, according to CNN. The powerful tropical storm has left over 3 million residents without power and has caused widespread devastation across the state.</p>

<p>The storm made landfall on Florida's west coast on Wednesday night as a Category 3 hurricane on the Saffir-Simpson scale, bringing maximum sustained winds of 120 mph (205 kph).</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA8zJ5KKTFm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA8zJ5KKTFm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA8zJ5KKTFm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DA8zJ5KKTFm/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by New York Post (@nypost)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Urban Search and Rescue Teams, along with the Florida National Guard, have been working around the clock to assist those affected. According to Governor Ron DeSantis, nearly 1,000 people have been rescued so far. There are 23 rescue teams, comprising over 1,600 personnel, currently deployed across Florida, with additional support expected from other states.</p>

<p>In St Lucie County, one of the hardest-hit areas, residents recalled the terrifying moments when tornadoes ripped through the region ahead of the storm's landfall. Susan Carlos, a resident of Sunnier Palms Park, described the experience as "the most frightening thing I've ever lived through," noting that the damage from the tornadoes was unlike anything she had ever seen since moving to Florida in 1989.</p>

<p>"I've lived in Florida since 1989. Never have I experienced damage or the amount of tornadoes that came through this area. It was the most frightening thing I've ever lived through," Carlos told CNN.</p>

<p>As recovery efforts continue, the Biden administration is closely monitoring the situation, with officials focusing on coordinating national efforts to ensure a smooth recovery process for the storm-ravaged state.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/quu3s3c8_the-damaged-car-in-florida_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton's impact: The incident took place in DeLand.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-india-is-biggest-tariff-charger-and-he-will-reciprocate-if-elected-to-power-6764073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Biggest Tariff Charger", Will Reciprocate If Elected To Power: Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-india-is-biggest-tariff-charger-and-he-will-reciprocate-if-elected-to-power-6764073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:35:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vowing to introduce a reciprocal tax if elected to power, former US president Donald Trump on Thursday alleged that India, among all major countries, imposes the highest tariffs on foreign products.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vowing to introduce a reciprocal tax if elected to power, former US president Donald Trump on Thursday alleged that India, among all major countries, imposes the highest tariffs on foreign products.</p>

<p>“Perhaps the most important element of my plan to make America extraordinarily wealthy again&nbsp;is reciprocity. It's a word that's very important in my plan because we generally don't charge tariffs. I started that process, it was so great, with the vans and the small trucks, etc. We really don't charge. China will charge us a 200 per cent tariff. Brazil is a big charger. The biggest charger of all is India,” Trump said in a major economic policy speech in Detroit.</p>

<p>“India is a very big charger. We have a great relationship with India. I did. And especially the leader, Modi. He's a great leader. Great man. Really is a great man. He's brought it together. He's done a great job. But they probably charge as much,” he said.</p>

<p>“I mean, I think they probably charge more than, in many ways, China. But they do it with a smile. They do it... Sort of a nicer charge. They said, thank you so much for purchasing from India. Harley Davidson came to the White House a long time ago during my third year or second year. I met with them. They were based in Wisconsin. I said, how's business? Good, good. What are the bad countries? Well, India is very tough. And they gave me some others. Why? Tariffs. I said, what are they? And they said like 150 per cent, some massive amount,” Trump told the members of the Detroit Economic Club.</p>

<p>“I said so do you sell many motorcycles because you think people want to buy a Harley. No, we sell very few in India, but they want us to go there. They said, if you go there and build your plant there, we're not going to charge you anything. I mean, you can do whatever you want. I said I don't like that. And I see they went, they built the plant, and now they do their business with India. They probably do it outside of India too. They built a very big plant in many countries, they do that. Then all of a sudden, you hear that they're leaving Milwaukee or they're leaving wherever they may be located,” he said.</p>

<p>Thursday's remarks by Trump come following his <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-praises-pm-modi-says-hes-the-nicest-6754565">praise for Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> earlier this week.</p>

<p>Trump described Modi as “the nicest human being”, saying the Indian leader is “a friend of mine”.</p>

<p>“Modi, India. He's a friend of mine. He's great. Before him, they were replacing them every year. It's very unstable. He came over. He's a friend of mine. But on the outside, he looks like he's your father. He's the nicest, but he's a total killer,” he said.</p>

<p>Trump recalled Modi's visit to Houston in 2019 to attend the ‘Howdy Modi' event during his tenure and said: “It was beautiful. It's like 80,000 people going crazy. We were walking around.” The Republican candidate said he shared a “very good relationship” with Modi.</p>

<p>Recalling that there were a couple of occasions where somebody was threatening India, Trump said: "I told Modi, let me help as I am very good with those people. To which he aggressively responded, ‘I will do it. I will do it. And I would do anything necessary. We have defeated them for hundreds of years.' I said 'Whoa, what just happened there',” he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hl6ceebk_donald-trump-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump said India imposes the highest tariffs on foreign products.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-is-the-nobel-peace-prize-decided-6764236]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Is The Nobel Peace Prize Decided?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-is-the-nobel-peace-prize-decided-6764236]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:33:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to the will of Swedish industrialist Alfred Nobel, the inventor of dynamite, the prize should go to the person "who has done the most or best to advance fellowship among nations, the abolition or reduction of standing armies, and the establ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The winner of the 2024 Nobel Peace Prize will be announced on Friday in Oslo. Here is a look at how the award works:</p>

<p><strong>Who can win?</strong></p>

<p>According to the will of Swedish industrialist Alfred Nobel, the inventor of dynamite, the prize should go to the person "who has done the most or best to advance fellowship among nations, the abolition or reduction of standing armies, and the establishment and promotion of peace congresses".</p>

<p>Thousands of people can propose names: members of governments and parliaments; current heads of state; university professors of history, social sciences, law and philosophy; and former Nobel Peace Prize laureates, among others.</p>

<p>This year there are 286 nominees, although the full list will be locked in a vault for 50 years.</p>

<p>Among the oddsmakers' favourites this year is late Russian dissident Alexei Navalny, who died in detention in February. But that is not possible as he cannot receive the prize posthumously.</p>

<p>Another favourite at the bookmakers is Ukraine's Volodymyr Zelenskiy, but he is also unlikely because he is a wartime leader.</p>

<p><strong>Who decides?</strong></p>

<p>The Norwegian Nobel Committee, which consists of five individuals appointed by the Norwegian parliament, is the arbiter. Members are often retired politicians, but not always. The current committee is led by the head of the Norwegian branch of PEN International, a group defending freedom of expression.</p>

<p>They are all put forward by Norwegian political parties and their appointments reflect the balance of power in Norway's parliament.</p>

<p><strong>How do they decide?</strong></p>

<p>Nominations close on Jan. 31. Members of the committee can make their own nominations no later than at the first meeting of the committee in February.</p>

<p>They discuss all the nominations, then establish a shortlist. Each nominee is then assessed and examined by a group of permanent advisers and other experts.</p>

<p>The committee meets roughly once a month to discuss the nominations. They usually make their decision at the final committee meeting, which tends to be at the beginning of October.</p>

<p>The committee seeks a consensus on its selection. If it cannot, the decision is reached by majority vote.</p>

<p>The last time a member quit in protest was in 1994, when Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat shared the prize with Israel's Shimon Peres and Yitzhak Rabin.</p>

<p><strong>Who is nominated?</strong></p>

<p>While the full list of nominations is kept secret, nominators are free to disclose them.</p>

<p>Among the names that have been disclosed this year are the United Nations refugee agency, UNHCR, Pope Francis and British naturalist David Attenborough.</p>

<p>Experts who follow the award say this year's prize may highlight the U.N. Palestinian refugee agency (UNRWA), the International Court of Justice and U.N. chief Antonio Guterres.</p>

<p><strong>What does the laureate get?</strong></p>

<p>A medal, a diploma, 11 million Swedish crowns ($1.1 million) and immediate global attention.</p>

<p>South African Archbishop Desmond Tutu, the 1984 winner, said becoming a Nobel laureate was a double-edged sword. "One day no one was listening. The next, I was an oracle," he is quoted as saying in his authorised biography.</p>

<p><strong>When are the announcement and the ceremony?</strong></p>

<p>The announcement will be made at 1100 CET (0900 GMT) on Friday, Oct. 11 at the Norwegian Nobel Institute in Oslo by the chair of the Norwegian Nobel Committee, Joergen Watne Frydnes.</p>

<p>The ceremony will take place at the Oslo City Hall on Dec. 10, the anniversary of Alfred Nobel's death.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/o5a880n8_nobel-prize-generic_625x300_10_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The winner of the 2024 Nobel Peace Prize will be announced on Friday in Oslo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/has-donald-trump-ever-changed-a-diaper-barack-obama-at-kamala-harris-rally-6764162]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Has Trump Ever Changed A Diaper": Barack Obama At Kamala Harris Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/has-donald-trump-ever-changed-a-diaper-barack-obama-at-kamala-harris-rally-6764162]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:14:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Barack Obama lashed out at "crazy" Donald Trump Thursday and urged voters to back Kamala Harris as he brought his star power to the 2024 election campaign trail for the first time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Barack Obama lashed out at "crazy" Donald Trump Thursday and urged voters to back Kamala Harris as he brought his star power to the 2024 election campaign trail for the first time.</p>

<p>As he hit the stump in the must-win state of Pennsylvania, Obama also chided Black male voters for hesitancy in supporting Democrat Harris because they "just aren't feeling the idea of having a woman as president."</p>

<p>Obama trained his fire on Trump during a pumped-up rally in Pittsburgh, comparing the Republican's long speeches to late Cuban communist leader Fidel Castro's and calling the billionaire out of touch with ordinary people.</p>

<p>America's first Black president admitted that "this election's going to be tight" as many voters were still struggling with high prices.</p>

<p>But he told the crowd that "what I cannot understand is why anybody would think that Donald Trump will shake things up", adding: "You think Donald Trump ever changed a diaper?'</p>

<p>The popular Democrat called Trump's schemes to sell bibles as "crazy" and used the same word to describe the 78-year-old former president's embrace of conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>As the crowd booed Trump, his successor in the White House, Obama added: "Don't boo -- vote."</p>

<p>"Kamala is as prepared for the job as any nominee for president has ever been," he added.</p>

<p><strong>'Got a problem'</strong></p>

<p>Vice president Harris's campaign said Obama's appearance, the first in a series in battleground states before the November 5 election, was designed to get people out to vote in crucial Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Obama took aim at male voters who might be attracted by the Republican's appeals towards machismo.</p>

<p>"I'm sorry gentlemen, I've noticed this, especially with some men who seem to think Trump's behavior, the bullying and the putting people down, is a sign of strength," he said.</p>

<p>"And I am here to tell you that is not what real strength is."</p>

<p>Earlier, in a surprise stop before the rally at a campaign field office in Pittsburgh, Obama made an unusually direct appeal to Black men, whose support polls show Harris has struggled to mobilize.</p>

<p>Saying he had some "truths" that he wanted the Black community to hear, Obama said that "you're coming up with all kinds of reasons and excuses, I've got a problem with that."</p>

<p>"Because part of it makes me think -- and I'm speaking to men directly -- part of it makes me think that, well, you just aren't feeling the idea of having a woman as president.”</p>

<p>Harris was in battleground Nevada for a town hall hosted by the Spanish language network Univision Thursday before heading to Arizona for a rally to reach out to Latino voters.</p>

<p>When a woman asked Harris at the town hall to name three of Trump's virtues, she replied: "I think Donald Trump loves his family, and I think that's very important.... But I don't really know him, to be honest with you. I don't have much more to offer you."</p>

<p>The White House said Harris had also taken part in a virtual briefing on deadly Hurricane Milton hitting Florida, which has sparked a political storm between Republicans and Democrats.</p>

<p><strong>'Dumber than hell'</strong></p>

<p>Trump was in the hotly contested state of Michigan on Thursday, unveiling new details of his protectionist plans for the US auto industry, including sweeping tariffs on vehicles not made in America.</p>

<p>Trump also ramped up his personal attacks on Harris, branding her "dumber than hell," and assailed the auto industry capital Detroit itself as run down as he was speaking to the city's economic club.</p>

<p>"Our whole country will end up being like Detroit if she's your president," he said.</p>

<p>Harris meanwhile said she had accepted an offer for a CNN town hall on October 23 in Pennsylvania, after Trump turned down a final televised debate with her.</p>

<p>Democrats are hoping Obama could give Harris a boost in a race that has been locked with Trump for weeks, after her initial boost in the polls after she took over from President Joe Biden as the party's nominee in July.</p>

<p>Obama and former first lady Michelle Obama delivered rapturously received speeches backing Harris at the Democratic National Convention in August.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4rp6oapg_barack-obama_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-tank-fires-at-un-mission-in-lebanon-nations-condemn-attack-10-points-6764037]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Tank Hits UN 'Blue Helmet' Base In Lebanon, Nations Condemn Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-tank-fires-at-un-mission-in-lebanon-nations-condemn-attack-10-points-6764037]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 07:36:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two UN peacekeepers were injured in a strike by the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) on their headquarters in south Lebanon on Thursday. The attack led to wide international condemnation, especially by the European members of the 'Blue Helmet' mission.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel admitted its forces opened fire in the area, saying Hezbollah militants operated near UN posts. Italy, a major contributor of troops to the UN peacekeeping force, said the acts "could constitute war crimes" while the US said it was "deeply concerned."</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The peacekeeping mission last week rejected Israel's demands to "relocate" from some of its positions in south Lebanon, where the IDF has been hitting what it claimed were Hezbollah targets.&nbsp;The United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon, or UNIFIL, has some 10,000 peacekeepers deployed in south Lebanon. It has been calling for a ceasefire since fighting escalated between the IDF and the militant group Hezbollah on September 23.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The UN mission confirmed two peacekeepers were injured after an IDF Merkava tank fired a shell towards an observation tower at the UNIFIL headquarters in south Lebanon's Naqura, directly hitting it.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The peacekeepers did not suffer serious injuries, "but they remain in hospital," it said. They are Indonesian nationals, a UNIFIL spokesperson said. Indonesia is also a major contributor of troops to the UNIFIL.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Indonesia's UN ambassador Hari Prabowo said the incident "clearly demonstrates how Israel positioned itself above international law, above impunity and above our shared values of peace."&nbsp;Israel claimed its military "opened fire in the area" of the UNIFIL base after telling UN forces to seek shelter.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Italy's Defence Minister Guido Crosetto said the attack and other incidents that the UNIFIL blames on Israel "could constitute war crimes", and asked for an explanation because "it was not a mistake". The Defence Minister described the shooting as intolerable, and filed protests with his Israeli counterpart and the country's ambassador to Italy.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The White House said it was "deeply concerned". "We understand Israel is conducting targeted operations near the Blue Line to destroy Hezbollah infrastructure... it is critical that they not threaten UN peacekeepers' safety and security," the White House said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Spain's foreign ministry said it "strongly condemns the Israeli firing that hit UNIFIL headquarters" which it called a "grave violation of international law".&nbsp;Irish Prime Minister Simon Harris, whose country has about 370 troops in the mission, said "any firing in the vicinity of UNIFIL troops or facilities is reckless and must stop".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">UNIFIL headquarters and nearby positions "have been repeatedly hit," the mission said. On Wednesday, "IDF soldiers deliberately fired at and disabled" perimetre-monitoring cameras around a position, UNIFIL added.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The head of UN peacekeeping Jean-Pierre Lacroix said peacekeepers were at "serious risk" and that by Sunday 300 Blue Helmets were temporarily relocated to larger bases "with the movement of another 200 planned." UNIFIL's footprint in the most affected positions would be slashed by 25 percent, he said. "The safety and security of peacekeepers is now increasingly in jeopardy," Mr Lacroix told the UN Security Council oln Thursday.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mbcnrbu8_lebanon-afp_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/return-of-a-monet-painting-nazis-stole-it-during-world-war-2-now-its-back-6764033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How FBI Tracked Down Rare Monet Painting Stolen By Nazis 80 Years Ago]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/return-of-a-monet-painting-nazis-stole-it-during-world-war-2-now-its-back-6764033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 07:30:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[FBI Art Crime Team, the New York and New Orleans Field Offices, and the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Eastern District of Louisiana Wednesday announced the repatriation of a Claude Monet pastel on paper, "Bord de Mer."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“The emotions tied to reclaiming something taken so brutally can't be measured in dollars—it's priceless,” said James Dennehy, assistant director in charge of the FBI in New York City, after the organisation helped bring back Nazi-looted Monet painting after 80 years.</p>

<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation's (FBI) Art Crime Team, the New York and New Orleans Field Offices, and the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Eastern District of Louisiana Wednesday announced the repatriation of a Claude Monet pastel on paper, “Bord de Mer.”</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“The emotions tied to reclaiming something taken so brutally can't be measured in dollars—it's priceless.”<br />
<br />
Discover how the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FBI?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FBI</a> helped return a Nazi-Looted Monet, missing for over 80 years, to the heirs of original owners: <a href="https://t.co/wL66ULxImd">https://t.co/wL66ULxImd</a> <a href="https://t.co/zZIzOtHcWq">pic.twitter.com/zZIzOtHcWq</a></p>
— FBI (@FBI) <a href="https://twitter.com/FBI/status/1844106065043972584?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The painting, created around 1865, was purchased by the Parlagi family at an Austrian art auction in 1936. A few years later, in 1940, during World War II, the pastel was seized by Gestapo, the Nazis' secret police force.</p>

<p>Eventually, the Monet was purchased at an auction by a Nazi art dealer and disappeared in 1941.</p>

<p>The Parlagi family has spent decades looking for the painting.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read:&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-mona-lisa-climate-protesters-throw-soup-at-monet-painting-5035355">After Mona Lisa, Climate Protesters Throw Soup at Monet Painting</a></p>

<p>In 2023, the FBI got a lead when the artwork was listed for sale at a Houston art gallery. The team contacted Dr. and Mrs. Kevin Schlamp, the owners of the artwork, and explained its looted history. Schlamps voluntarily surrendered the piece.</p>

<p>Following this, with the help of the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Eastern District of Louisiana, a consent judgment was secured in May 2024. The judgment awarded full ownership of the Monet to the Parlagi heirs.</p>

<p>“We are honored to have played a role in returning this stolen artwork to its rightful owners,” said James Dennehy. “While this Monet is undoubtedly valuable, its true worth lies in what it represents to the Parlagi family. It's a connection to their history, their loved ones, and a legacy that was nearly erased,” he added.</p>

<p>The FBI's work on this case is ongoing. Several other pieces of artwork were stolen from the Parlagi family in 1940 and the search is on.</p>

<p><strong>Video: </strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-environment-activists-smear-paint-on-monet-artwork-in-stockholm-4121806">Environment Activists Smear Paint On Monet Artwork In Stockholm</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lesp9o5o_monet-painting_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Claude Monet, pastel on paper, "Bord de Mer," about 1865.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/internet-archive-hit-by-catastrophic-attack-31-million-passwords-stolen-6763970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Internet Archive Hit By "Catastrophic" Attack, 31 Million Passwords Stolen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/internet-archive-hit-by-catastrophic-attack-31-million-passwords-stolen-6763970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 07:10:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A pro-Palestinian hacktivist has claimed responsibility for a major cyberattack on the Internet Archive, exposing the personal data of 31 million users.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A pro-Palestinian hacktivist has claimed responsibility for a major cyberattack on the Internet Archive, exposing the personal data of 31 million users. The attack compromised email addresses, screen names, and encrypted passwords, prompting cybersecurity experts to urge users to change their passwords immediately. The breach has raised concerns about data privacy and the security of the popular digital library, best known for its Wayback Machine.</p>

<p>The attack, which surfaced on October 9, revealed the details of millions of users after a JavaScript (JS) library on the Internet Archive's website was exploited. A pop-up message on the site alerted visitors, stating: "Have you ever felt like the Internet Archive runs on sticks and is constantly on the verge of suffering a catastrophic security breach? It just happened. See 31 million of you on HIBP!"&nbsp;</p>

<p>This message referred to the service <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://haveibeenpwned.com/" rel="nofollow,noindex">Have I Been Pwned?</a> (HIBP), which helps users determine if their data has been compromised in a breach.</p>

<p>The database, which has been shared with cybersecurity experts, contained email addresses, screen names, passwords, and other internal data for 31 million unique email addresses. Troy Hunt, founder of Have I Been Pwned?, confirmed receiving a 6.4 GB database file from the attackers. Mr Hunt also noted that over half of the email addresses had already appeared in previous data breaches.</p>

<h3><strong>Internet Archive's Response</strong></h3>

<p>Brewster Kahle, the founder of the Internet Archive, acknowledged the breach and the ongoing Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks affecting the platform. In a post on X (formerly Twitter), Mr Kahle wrote: "What we know: DDOS attack fended off for now; defacement of our website via JS library; breach of usernames/email/salted-encrypted passwords. What we've done: Disabled the JS library, scrubbing systems, upgrading security. Will share more as we know it."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">What we know: DDOS attack–fended off for now; defacement of our website via JS library; breach of usernames/email/salted-encrypted passwords.<br />
<br />
What we've done: Disabled the JS library, scrubbing systems, upgrading security.<br />
<br />
Will share more as we know it.</p>
— Brewster Kahle (@brewster_kahle) <a href="https://twitter.com/brewster_kahle/status/1844183111514603812?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Despite the initial efforts to fend off the attack, the Internet Archive's website, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://archive.org/" rel="nofollow,noindex">archive.org</a>, and its Wayback Machine have been intermittently inaccessible. The organisation has been scrubbing its systems and upgrading security as a response to the breach.</p>

<h3><strong>Behind The Breach</strong></h3>

<p>The account "SN_BlackMeta" claimed responsibility for both the data breach and the DDoS attacks, which have taken the Internet Archive offline multiple times. The group stated that their campaign lasted five hours and that they were launching "highly successful attacks."</p>

<p>SN_BlackMeta has been previously linked to attacks on Middle Eastern financial institutions and is associated with pro-Palestinian hacktivist movements.</p>

<p>In an X post, the group mentioned, "The Internet Archive has and is suffering from a devastating attack. We have been launching several highly successful attacks for five long hours and, to this moment, all their systems are completely down."</p>

<p>A community note attached to this post added context, stating: "This group claims they took down the Internet Archive because it 'belongs to the USA ... who support Israel,' which is not true. The Archive is not the US government; it is a nonprofit that includes many resources about Palestine, which we can't now access because of this attack."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bl94eit_internet-archive-_625x300_11_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brewster Kahle, the founder of the Internet Archive, acknowledged the breach.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-de-escalation-needed-in-middle-east-6763738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Says De-Escalation Needed In Middle East Amid Israeli Offensive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-says-de-escalation-needed-in-middle-east-6763738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 06:00:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris said on Thursday that de-escalation was needed in the Middle East, a region on edge for months amid Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris said on Thursday that de-escalation was needed in the Middle East, a region on edge for months amid Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>WHY IT'S IMPORTANT</strong></p>

<p>A ceasefire remains elusive in Gaza and Lebanon and the region is bracing for an Israeli response to an Iranian missile attack last week carried out in retaliation for Israel's military action in Lebanon. No one in Israel was killed in Iran's attack, and Washington called it ineffective.</p>

<p>For Gaza, President Joe Biden put forward a three-phase ceasefire plan on May 31, which has run into obstacles for months over Israeli demands of keeping presence in a corridor on Gaza's border with Egypt and over differences in exchanges of Israeli hostages and Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, Washington and Paris put forward a 21-day ceasefire proposal in late September that Israel rejected.</p>

<p><strong>KEY QUOTES</strong></p>

<p>"We have got to reach a ceasefire," Harris told reporters as she departed Las Vegas, while commenting on the situations in Gaza and Lebanon. "We've got to de-escalate."</p>

<p>Washington's occasional condemnation of Israel over the war's civilian death toll has mostly been verbal with no substantive change in policy.</p>

<p><strong>CONTEXT</strong></p>

<p>The latest bloodshed in the decades-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict was triggered on Oct. 7, 2023, when Palestinian Hamas militants attacked Israel, killing 1,200 people and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>Israel's subsequent military assault on Gaza has killed almost 42,000 Palestinians, according to local health officials, and displaced nearly the entire population, while causing a hunger crisis and leading to genocide allegations at the World Court that Israel denies.</p>

<p>Israel's recent operations in Lebanon have killed hundreds, wounded thousands and displaced over a million. Israel says it is targeting Lebanese Iran-backed Hezbollah militants.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris said on Thursday that de-escalation was needed in the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crown-of-goddess-kali-gifted-by-pm-modi-stolen-from-bangladesh-temple-6762998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Crown of Goddess Kali, Gifted by PM Modi, Stolen from Bangladesh Temple]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crown-of-goddess-kali-gifted-by-pm-modi-stolen-from-bangladesh-temple-6762998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 01:30:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[According to Hindu mythology, the Jeshoreshwari Temple is one of the 51 Shakti Peeths scattered across India and neighboring countries. The name "Jeshoreshwari" means "Goddess of Jeshore."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;A crown of goddess Kali has been stolen from the Jeshoreshwari temple in Satkhira's Shyamnagar. This crown was gifted by Prime Minister Narendra Modi during his visit to the temple in March, 2021, as reported by The Daily Star.</p>

<p>The theft occurred on Thursday between 2.00 pm and 2.30 pm, after Temple Priest Dilip Mukherjee left following the day's worship. The cleaning staff later found that the crown was missing from the deity's head, as reported by The Daily Star.</p>

<p>"We are reviewing the temple's CCTV footage to identify the thief," said Inspector Taizul Islam of Shyamnagar Police Station.</p>

<p>The stolen crown, made of silver and gold-plated, holds significant cultural and religious importance.</p>

<p>According to Hindu mythology, the Jeshoreshwari Temple is one of the 51 Shakti Peeths scattered across India and neighboring countries. The name "Jeshoreshwari" means "Goddess of Jeshore."</p>

<p>PM Modi visited the Jeshoreshwari Temple on March 27, 2021, during his trip to Bangladesh.</p>

<p>On that day, he placed the crown on the head of the deity as a symbolic gesture.</p>

<p>PM Modi also shared a video of his visit to the temple, which was his first visit to any country after the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>Jeshoreshwari Kali Temple a famous Hindu temple dedicated to the Goddess Kali, the temple is located in Ishwaripur--a village in Shyam Nagar, Upazila of Satkhira.</p>

<p>It is believed that the temple was built by a Brahman named Anari in the latter part of the 12th century.</p>

<p>He created a 100-door temple for the Jashoreshwari Peeth (shrine) and later it was renovated by Lakshman Sen in the 13th century and finally, Raja Pratapaditya rebuilt the temple in the 16th century.</p>

<p>According to Hindu mythology, of the 51 Peeths, the temple at Ishwaripur is the place where the palms and soles of the feet of Goddess Sati fell and the goddess resides there in the form of Devi Jashoreshwari and Lord Shiva appears as Chanda.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ccesnd2k_pm-modi-at-jeshoreshwari-temple_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi visited the Jeshoreshwari Temple on March 27, 2021, during his trip to Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-central-beirut-killing-18-hezbollah-figure-targeted-6762937]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Strikes Beirut, Killing 22, Injuring 117, Hezbollah Figure Targeted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strikes-central-beirut-killing-18-hezbollah-figure-targeted-6762937]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 01:13:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel pounded central Beirut with a deadly air strike on Thursday while its ground troops in Lebanon were accused of firing on the UN's peacekeeping headquarters, injuring two of them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel pounded central Beirut with a deadly air strike on Thursday while its ground troops in Lebanon were accused of firing on the UN's peacekeeping headquarters, injuring two of them.</p>

<p>The air raid on Beirut, where an AFP journalist heard several loud explosions, was the third such attack on the centre of the Lebanese capital since Israel escalated its campaign last month.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy's attacks on the capital Beirut this evening resulted in an updated toll of 22 people killed and 117 others injured," Lebanon's health ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security source, without giving further details, said a "Hezbollah figure" was targeted, after a series of killings of top officials in the Iran-backed movement.</p>

<p>AFP live TV footage showed two plumes of smoke billowing in between densely-packed buildings, while there was no immediate comment from Israeli authorities about the nature of the target.</p>

<p>Most Israeli strikes have targeted the south Beirut area, not the centre.</p>

<p>The attack came on the same day as the UN's peacekeeping force in Lebanon accused Israeli soldiers of "repeatedly" firing on its positions, including with a tank, leaving two Indonesian Blue Helmets with injuries.</p>

<p>Italian Defence Minister Guido Crosetto, whose country is a major contributor to the force, condemned the "hostile acts" which he said "could constitute war crimes", while Spain called it a "grave violation of international law".</p>

<p>Washington said that while Israel targets Hezbollah facilities "it is critical that they not threaten UN peacekeepers' safety and security."</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it had been operating against Hezbollah militants near UNIFIL headquarters and had "instructed the UN forces in the area to remain in protected spaces."</p>

<p>Israel has been pounding Hezbollah in Lebanon since September 23 in an escalated campaign that has killed more than 1,200 people and displaced more than a million others, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures.</p>

<p>Its ground forces crossed into Lebanon on September 30 with the aim of stopping Hezbollah's cross-border fire in support of Palestinian militant group Hamas, which attacked Israel on October 7.</p>

<p>Hezbollah missile and artillery fire has forced tens of thousands of Israelis to flee their homes near the border over the past year, and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has promised to fight until they can return.</p>

<h2><strong>HUMANITARIAN LAW</strong></h2>

<p>The Lebanon operation is a second front for Israel's stretched armed forces which are continuing their campaign against Hamas Palestinian militants in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israeli forces launched a major operation in the north of the territory at the weekend around the Jabalia refugee camp, where about 400,000 people are trapped, according to Philippe Lazzarini, head of the UN agency for Palestinian refugees, UNRWA.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters on Wednesday about the humanitarian situation, US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said that Washington was "incredibly concerned" as Israel tightens its siege.</p>

<p>"We have been making clear to the government of Israel that they have an obligation under international humanitarian law to allow food and water and other needed humanitarian assistance to make it into all parts of Gaza," he said.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike on a school building in Deir el-Balah in central Gaza on Thursday left at least 28 people dead and 54 injured, according to the Palestine Red Crescent.</p>

<p>It is the latest of numerous such incidents.</p>

<p>The Israeli army said in a statement the strike targeted Palestinian combatants operating from a command-and-control centre "embedded inside a compound that previously served as the (Rafida) School".</p>

<p>The Israeli military accuses Hamas of hiding in school buildings where thousands of Gazans have sought shelter -- a charge denied by the militant group.</p>

<p>UN investigators on Thursday also accused Israel of deliberately targeting health facilities and killing and torturing medical personnel in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel is "committing war crimes and the crime against humanity of extermination with relentless and deliberate attacks on medical personnel and facilities", the UN Independent International Commission of Inquiry said in a statement.</p>

<h3><strong>DEADLY, PRECISE</strong></h3>

<p>Ahead of Yom Kippur this Friday and Saturday, the holiest day in the Jewish calendar, Israelis are also braced for the country's reaction to a missile attack last week from Iran, which backs both Hamas and Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Iran fired about 200 missiles in what it said was retaliation for the assassination of two of its closest allies, Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh, along with an Iranian general.</p>

<p>Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said Wednesday that "our attack on Iran will be deadly, precise and surprising. They will not understand what happened and how it happened."</p>

<p>Biden has cautioned Israel against attempting to target Iran's nuclear facilities and opposes striking oil installations.</p>

<p>"I don't think we are currently in a situation that the two countries are seeking an all-out direct war," Hamid, a 29-year-old university student in Tehran, told AFP on Thursday.</p>

<p>"It will have severe economic and military consequences" on both countries, he added.</p>

<p>The Gaza war began on October 7 last year, when Hamas militants stormed across the border and carried out the worst attack in Israeli history.</p>

<p>The militants took 251 people hostage in an attack that resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>According to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, 42,065 people have been killed in Gaza since the start of the war, a majority civilians, figures the UN has described as reliable.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o4dvpfv_israeli-air-strike-central-beirut-reuters_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke and fire rise over Beirut after an Israeli air strikes targeting a Hezbollah figure. 22 have died.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-killed-48-injured-in-israeli-strikes-in-lebanon-6762863]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11 Killed, 48 Injured In Israeli Strikes In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-killed-48-injured-in-israeli-strikes-in-lebanon-6762863]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:51:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's health ministry said Thursday at least 11 people had been killed in Israeli strikes on Beirut -- the third such attack on the capital since Israel escalated its air campaign last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's health ministry said Thursday at least 11 people had been killed in Israeli strikes on Beirut -- the third such attack on the capital since Israel escalated its air campaign last month.</p>

<p>Israel has repeatedly pounded southern Beirut suburbs, the bastion of Lebanon's Hezbollah movement, for more than two weeks but strikes have rarely targeted the city centre.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy's attacks on the capital Beirut this evening killed, according to a preliminary toll, 11 people and injured 48 others," the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>Lebanon's National News Agency (NNA) said the strikes hit the densely populated neighbourhoods of Nweiri and Basta.</p>

<p>"The first strike in Beirut targeted the third floor of an eight-storey building" in the Nweiri area, and a second strike hit "a four-storey building... in al-Basta al-Fouqa, which completely collapsed," the NNA.</p>

<p>An AFP photographer at the site of the strike in the Basta area said two old buildings had collapsed, while the windows of surrounding homes had been blown out with the force of the explosion.</p>

<p>Civil defence members and local residents were attempting to pull survivors out of the mountain of rubble, with some of them carried away on stretchers.</p>

<p>Firefighters were working to put out a blaze in a "residential building" hit in the Nweiri area, with residents being evacuated from the upper floors using a ladder, NNA reported.</p>

<p>Immediately after the raids, AFP live footage showed two plumes of smoke billowing in between densely-packed buildings.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Israel carried out a deadly air raid in Beirut, hitting an emergency services rescue facility run by Hezbollah, killing seven workers, the service said.</p>

<p>On September 30, an Israeli drone strike on a building in Beirut's busy Cola district killed three members of the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP), the leftist armed group said.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah movement and its foe Israel have been exchanging near-daily cross-border fire for nearly a year in fallout from the Gaza war.</p>

<p>But since September 23, Israel has escalated its air strikes on targets in Lebanon, killing more than 1,200 people and forced more than one million to flee their homes, according to official figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mbcnrbu8_lebanon-afp_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 1200 people have been killed since Israel launched attacks against Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-asean-india-summit-pm-narendra-modi-proposes-10-point-plan-to-strengthen-group-6762790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At ASEAN-India Summit, PM Modi Proposes 10-Point Plan To Strengthen Group]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-asean-india-summit-pm-narendra-modi-proposes-10-point-plan-to-strengthen-group-6762790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:34:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi today attended the 21st ASEAN-India Summit in Laos. At the summit, PM Modi also announced a 10-point plan to strengthen ASEAN-India comprehensive partnership and asserted that ties with the regional grouping were critical for Asia's future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Celebrating the year 2025 as ASEAN-India Year of Tourism for which India will make available USD 5 million towards joint activities.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">To celebrate a decade of the Act East Policy through several people centric activities, including a youth summit, a start-up festival, a hackathon, a music festival, building on an ASEAN-India netrowk of think tanks and the Delhi Dialogue.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">To organise an ASEAN-India women scientists conclave under the ASEAN-India Science and Technology Development Fund.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Doubling the number of scholarships at the Nalanda University and a provision of new scholarships for ASEAN students at the Agricultural Universities in India.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Review of the ASEAN-India Trade and Goods Agreement by 2025.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Enhancing disaster resilience for which India would contribute an additional USD 5 million.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Initiate a new health ministers' track towards building health resilience.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Initiate a regular mechanism of ASEAN-India cyber policy dialogue towards strengthening digital and cyber resilience.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Organising a workshop on green hydrogen.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Invite all ASEAN leaders to join the 'Plant a Tree for Mother' campaign towards building climate resilience.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3pt6vrm_narendra-modi-asean-india-summit-2024-pti_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi attended the 21st ASEAN-India Summit in Laos today. He proposed a 10-point plan at the meet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-among-worlds-harshest-users-of-death-penalty-report-6762707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Among World's Harshest Users Of Death Penalty: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-among-worlds-harshest-users-of-death-penalty-report-6762707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:11:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's use of the death penalty is among the harshest in the world, accounting for 26 per cent of the global death row population, according to data released by a non-profit group on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's use of the death penalty is among the harshest in the world, accounting for 26 per cent of the global death row population, according to data released by a non-profit group on Thursday.</p>

<p>A total of 6,161 prisoners were on death row in 2024, up from the 6,039 reported in 2023, legal action group Justice Project Pakistan (JPP) said in its annual report. The number contrasted with the earlier trends when the death row population stood at 3,226 in 2022.</p>

<p>The Lahore-based NGO issued the third edition of its annual report called Death Penalty in Pakistan: Data Mapping Capital Punishment, commemorating the 22nd World Day Against the Death Penalty.</p>

<p>The highest number of such prisoners was in the Punjab province at 2,505, followed by the Khyber Pakhtunkhwa province at 2,311. The JPP data also showed that Pakistan's use of the death penalty is among the harshest in the world, accounting for 26 per cent of the world's death row population, 13 per cent of global executions, and 14 per cent of worldwide death sentences.</p>

<p>Since 2004, Pakistan has handed out at least 4,500 death sentences, an average of one per day. Every seventh person sentenced to death globally and every eighth person executed in the world is a Pakistani, according to the JPP.</p>

<p>Pakistan was ranked as "one of the highest users of the death penalty globally" which is a "sobering statistic", highlighting "the urgent need for reform", the report said.</p>

<p>It said that Pakistan has not carried out capital punishment since December 2019, but "remains one of the most prolific users of capital punishment, with over 31 crimes punishable by death." The NGO invited policymakers, advocates, and the general public to engage with the data as part of a broader dialogue on justice reform.</p>

<p>"The report not only presents a statistical overview of death row prisoners but also delves into the underlying issues within Pakistan's criminal justice system that perpetuate the use of capital punishment," the JPP said.</p>

<p>It said the NGO seeks to "magnify the individual stories behind these statistics, highlighting the often overlooked human toll of state-sanctioned executions."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fh1k7t2o_jail-generic-getty_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since 2004, Pakistan has handed out at least 4,500 death sentences. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ethel-kennedy-wife-of-assassinated-us-politician-robert-kennedy-dies-at-96-6762704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ethel Kennedy, Wife Of Assassinated US Politician Robert Kennedy, Dies At 96]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ethel-kennedy-wife-of-assassinated-us-politician-robert-kennedy-dies-at-96-6762704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:10:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ethel Kennedy, the widow of assassinated US politician Robert F. Kennedy, died Thursday at the age of 96, her family said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ethel Kennedy, the widow of assassinated US politician Robert F. Kennedy, died Thursday at the age of 96, her family said.</p>

<p>"It is with our hearts full of love that we announce the passing of our amazing grandmother," former congressman Joe Kennedy III said on social media.</p>

<p>Ethel Kennedy, who died of complications from a stroke, was a key figure in a family that counted former president John F. Kennedy -- also assassinated -- and senator Ted Kennedy among its ranks.</p>

<p>She was also the mother of Robert F. Kennedy Jr, a vaccine conspiracy theorist whose failed third-party presidential bid and endorsement of Donald Trump cast a shadow over the family's dynastic status in American politics and the Democratic Party.</p>

<p>Born Ethel Skakel in Chicago in 1928, she met her future husband at the age of 17.</p>

<p>Robert Kennedy -- known as Bobby or RFK -- would go on to serve as US attorney general in his brother John's administration, serving from 1961 to 1964. He was later a senator representing New York.</p>

<p>Five years after JFK's assassination, Robert Kennedy was himself shot dead while running for president in 1968.</p>

<p>Six months after his death, Ethel Kennedy gave birth to the couple's 11th child.</p>

<p>She went on to found Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights, an advocacy organization notable for its work on freedom of expression around the world.</p>

<p>In 2014, then-president Barack Obama honored her with the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian distinction in the United States.</p>

<p>Praising her "lifetime's work in social justice and human rights," Joe Kennedy III said, "we are comforted in knowing she is reunited with the love of her life, our father, Robert F. Kennedy."</p>

<p>She is survived by nine children, 34 grandchildren and 24 great-grandchildren, the former congressman said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/thrkcqdg_ethel-skakel-afp_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Born Ethel Skakel in Chicago in 1928, she met her future husband at the age of 17.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-to-dodge-requirements-of-eu-tech-rules-report-6762668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X To Dodge Requirements Of EU Tech Rules: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-to-dodge-requirements-of-eu-tech-rules-report-6762668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:02:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X will not be designated as a gatekeeper under landmark EU tech rules known as the Digital Markets Act which would have subjected it to an onerous list of obligations, people with direct knowledge of the matter said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's X will not be designated as a gatekeeper under landmark EU tech rules known as the Digital Markets Act which would have subjected it to an onerous list of obligations, people with direct knowledge of the matter said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The European Commission, which opened an investigation into online social media platform X in May, will announce its decision next week, the people said.</p>

<p>The EU competition enforcer declined to comment.</p>

<p>X, formerly known as Twitter, had previously told the Commission that even though it met the criterion regarding the number of users to be classified as a gatekeeper, it does not qualify for the other criterion as an important gateway between businesses and consumers.</p>

<p>Its response prompted the Commission's investigation in May to look further into the issue.</p>

<p>Alphabet, Amazon, Apple, Meta, Microsoft, TikTok owner ByteDance and Booking.com have been designated as gatekeepers, among others.</p>

<p>The DMA requires gatekeepers to make their messaging apps interact with rivals, let users decide which apps to pre-install on their devices and are not allowed to favour their own services over rivals or risk fines as much as 10% of their annual global turnover.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1hc9c9e_x-eu-generic_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The EU competition enforcer declined to comment. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-israel-from-bombing-irans-oil-sites-gulf-states-urge-us-6762624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stop Israel From Bombing Iran's Oil Sites, Gulf States Urge US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-israel-from-bombing-irans-oil-sites-gulf-states-urge-us-6762624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:52:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gulf states are lobbying Washington to stop Israel from attacking Iran's oil sites because they are concerned their own oil facilities could come under fire from Tehran's proxies if the conflict escalates, three Gulf sources told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gulf states are lobbying Washington to stop Israel from attacking Iran's oil sites because they are concerned their own oil facilities could come under fire from Tehran's proxies if the conflict escalates, three Gulf sources told Reuters.</p>

<p>As part of their attempts to avoid being caught in the crossfire, Gulf states including Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates and Qatar are also refusing to let Israel fly over their airspace for any attack on Iran and have conveyed this to Washington, the three sources close to government circles said.</p>

<p>Israel has promised Iran will pay for its missile attack last week while Tehran has said any retaliation would be met with vast destruction, raising fears of a wider war in the region that could suck in the United States.</p>

<p>The moves by the Gulf states come after a diplomatic push by non-Arab Shi'ite Iran to persuade its Sunni Gulf neighbours to use their influence with Washington amid rising concerns Israel could target Iran's oil production facilities.</p>

<p>During meetings this week, Iran warned Saudi Arabia it could not guarantee the safety of the Gulf kingdom's oil facilities if Israel were given any assistance in carrying out an attack, a senior Iranian official and an Iranian diplomat told Reuters.</p>

<p>Ali Shihabi, a Saudi analyst close to the Saudi royal court, said: "The Iranians have stated: 'If the Gulf states open up their airspace to Israel, that would be an act of war'. But (Saudi Arabia) won't allow anybody to use their airspace."</p>

<p>The diplomat said Tehran had sent a clear message to Riyadh that its allies in countries such as Iraq or Yemen might respond if there was any regional support for Israel against Iran.</p>

<p>A potential Israeli strike was the focus of talks on Wednesday between Saudi de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, and Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araqchi, who was on a Gulf tour to rally support, Gulf and Iranian sources said.</p>

<p>The Iranian minister's visit, along with Saudi-American communications at defence ministry level, are part of a coordinated effort to address the crisis, a Gulf source close to government circles told Reuters.</p>

<p>A person in Washington familiar with the discussions confirmed that Gulf officials had been in touch with US counterparts to express concern about the potential scope of Israel's expected retaliation.</p>

<p>The White House declined comment when asked whether Gulf governments had asked Washington to ensure Israel's response was measured. US President Joe Biden and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu spoke on Wednesday about the Israeli retaliation in a call both sides described as positive.</p>

<p>Jonathan Panikoff, former deputy US national intelligence officer on the Middle East and now at the Atlantic Council think-tank in Washington said: "Gulf states' anxiety is likely to be a key talking point with Israeli counterparts in trying to convince Israel to undertake a carefully calibrated response."</p>

<p><strong>OIL AT RISK?</strong></p>

<p>The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries, OPEC, which is de-facto led by Saudi Arabia, has enough spare oil capacity to make up for any loss of Iranian supply if an Israeli retaliation knocked out some of the country's facilities.</p>

<p>But much of that spare capacity is in the Gulf region so if oil facilities in Saudi Arabia or the UAE, for example, were targeted too, the world could face an oil supply problem.</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia has been wary of an Iranian strike on its oil plants since a 2019 attack on its Aramco oilfield shut down over 5% of global oil supply. Iran denied involvement.</p>

<p>Riyadh has had a rapprochement with Tehran in recent years, but trust remains an issue. Bahrain, Kuwait, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the UAE all host US military facilities or troops.</p>

<p>Concerns over oil facilities and the potential for a wider regional conflict were also central to talks between Emirati officials and their US counterparts, said another Gulf source.</p>

<p>In 2022, the Iran-aligned Houthis in Yemen fired missiles and drones at oil refuelling trucks near an oil refinery owned by UAE's state oil firm ADNOC and claimed the attack.</p>

<p>"The Gulf states aren't letting Israel use their airspace. They won't allow Israeli missiles to pass through, and there's also a hope that they won't strike the oil facilities," the Gulf source said.</p>

<p>The three Gulf sources emphasized that Israel could route strikes through Jordan or Iraq, but using Saudi, UAE, or Qatari airspace was off the table and strategically unnecessary.</p>

<p>Analysts also pointed out that Israel has other options, including mid-air refuelling capabilities that would enable its jets to fly down the Red Sea into the Indian Ocean, proceed to the Gulf and then fly back.</p>

<p><strong>'MIDDLE OF A MISSILE WAR'</strong></p>

<p>According to two senior Israeli officials, Israel is going to calibrate its response and, as of Wednesday, it had not yet decided whether it would strike Iran's oilfields.</p>

<p>The option was one of a number presented by the defence establishment to Israeli leaders, according to the officials.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Wednesday: "Our strike will be lethal, precise, and above all - surprising. They will not understand what happened and how it happened. They will see the results."</p>

<p>The three Gulf sources stated that Saudi Arabia, as a leading oil exporter along with oil-producing neighbours - the UAE, Qatar, Kuwait, Oman and Bahrain - had keen a interest in de-escalating the situation.</p>

<p>"We will be in the middle of a missile war. There is serious concern, especially if the Israeli strike targets Iran's oil installations," a second Gulf source said.</p>

<p>The three Gulf sources said an Israeli strike on Iran's oil infrastructure would have a global impact, particularly for China - Iran's top oil customer - as well as for Kamala Harris ahead of the Nov. 5 presidential election in which she is running against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"If oil prices surge to $120 per barrel, it would harm both the US economy and Harris' chances in the election. So they (Americans) won't allow the oil war to expand," the first Gulf source said.</p>

<p>Gulf sources said safeguarding all oil installations remained a challenge, despite having advanced missile and Patriot defence systems, so the primary approach remained diplomatic: signalling to Iran that Gulf states pose no threat.</p>

<p>Bernard Haykel, professor of Near East Studies at Princeton University, noted that Riyadh was vulnerable "because the Iranians can swarm those installations given the short distance from the mainland".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v08b2vag_iran-generic-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has promised Iran will pay for its missile attack last week]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/28-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-gaza-school-6762589]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[28 Killed In Israeli Strike On Gaza School]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/28-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-gaza-school-6762589]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:47:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli airstrike on a school sheltering displaced people in central Gaza killed at least 28 people including women and children on Thursday, while three hospitals in the north were told to evacuate, putting patients' lives at risk, medics said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli airstrike on a school sheltering displaced people in central Gaza killed at least 28 people including women and children on Thursday, while three hospitals in the north were told to evacuate, putting patients' lives at risk, medics said.</p>

<p>The strike, in which many more were wounded, occurred in the city of Deir Al-Balah where a million people have taken shelter after fleeing fighting elsewhere after more than a year of war.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said on Thursday it had carried out a "precise strike on terrorists" who had a command and control centre embedded in a school.</p>

<p>"This is a further example of the Hamas terrorist organisation's systematic abuse of civilian infrastructure in violation of international law," a military statement said.</p>

<p>The Palestinian group denies such accusations. Medics said 54 other people were injured at the school.</p>

<p>In Gaza's north, the Israeli military was pursuing an offensive begun six days ago when it sent its troops into Jabalia, the largest of Gaza's eight historic refugee camps, and the nearby towns of Beit Hanoun and Beit Lahiya.</p>

<p>On Thursday, the military said it had killed at least 12 militants from Hamas and the Iranian-backed Islamic Jihad who it said were operating from a command and control centre in what was previously a medical compound in Jabalia. It said large quantities of weapons and ammunition were stored at the site.</p>

<p>Palestinian health officials say at least 130 people have been killed so far in the operation, which Israel says is aimed at preventing Hamas from regrouping.</p>

<p>The military has told residents to evacuate an area in which the UN estimates more than 400,000 people are trapped.</p>

<p>The health officials said the Israeli military on Wednesday gave patients and medics 24 hours to leave the Indonesian, Al-Awda and Kamal Adwan hospitals or risk being stormed as happened earlier in the war at Al Shifa Hospital in Gaza City.</p>

<p>Israel, which has not yet commented on evacuation orders for medical facilities, has said Hamas has command facilities concealed within the hospitals, which it denies.</p>

<p>Hussam Abu Safiya, director of Kamal Adwan Hospital, said eight patients, mostly children with critical shrapnel wounds, were at risk inside intensive-care units should the army force their evacuation, and the hospital was also running out of fuel.</p>

<p><strong>APPEAL FOR HELP</strong></p>

<p>Abu Safiya called for international pressure on Israel to allow medical staffers in north Gaza's three hospitals to continue to operate, saying: "Our message is a message of peace for the sake of those children."</p>

<p>Ramesh Rajasingham, director of the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, said an OCHA-World Health Organization team could not reach Kamal Adwan Hospital despite having secured a green light from the Israeli military.</p>

<p>"The team was forced to wait at the holding point for hours, and, ultimately, the mission had to be aborted. And that's not an unusual practice," Rajasingham told a UN meeting. "In September, less than 10% of coordinated missions to the north (of Gaza) were facilitated by the Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>"The essential conditions for effective aid operations are severely lacking or entirely absent," he added.</p>

<p>Israeli bombardment near Kamal Adwan Hospital has already caused some damage to the facility, medics said. They said they know of many dead bodies lying on the roads outside the hospital because of Israeli fire.</p>

<p>The Israeli military told residents of Jabalia and nearby areas to head to humanitarian-designated zones in southern Gaza, but Palestinian and UN officials say there are no safe places to flee to in the densely populated enclave.</p>

<p>Philippe Lazzarini, the head of the UN Palestinian refugee agency UNRWA, told the UN Security Council: "Hundreds of thousands of people are again being pushed to move to the south, where living conditions are intolerable."</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli forces had encircled Jabalia and ordered them to leave through one corridor. They said troops were interrogating those leaving and making arrests, while anyone trying to leave via a different route gets fired at.</p>

<p>Hamas and ally Islamic Jihad said they continued to fight Israeli forces with anti-tank rockets and mortar bombs.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it killed dozens more militants, seized arms and dismantled militant infrastructure in the north.</p>

<p>Israel began its offensive after Hamas-led militants carried out a cross-border attack on southern Israeli communities on Oct. 7, 2023, killing about 1,200 people and taking about 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>More than 42,000 Palestinians have been killed in the Israeli offensive, the Gaza health ministry says. Most of Gaza's 2.3 million people have been displaced and much of the enclave has been laid to waste.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mp90bg4o_gaza_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike occurred in the city of Deir Al-Balah]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-milton-leaves-10-dead-millions-without-power-in-florida-6762576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton Leaves 10 Dead, Millions Without Power In Florida]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-milton-leaves-10-dead-millions-without-power-in-florida-6762576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:41:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton plowed into the Atlantic Ocean on Thursday after cutting a destructive path across Florida that spawned tornados, killed at least 10 people and left millions without power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Milton plowed into the Atlantic Ocean on Thursday after cutting a destructive path across Florida that spawned tornados, killed at least 10 people and left millions without power, but the storm did not trigger the catastrophic surge of seawater that was feared.</p>

<p>Governor Ron DeSantis said the state had avoided the "worst-case scenario," though he cautioned the damage was still significant. The Tampa Bay area appeared to sidestep the storm surge that had prompted the most dire warnings.</p>

<p>US Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas said at a White House briefing the government had reports of at least 10 deaths from Milton, adding it appeared they were caused by tornados.</p>

<p>In St. Lucie County on Florida's east coast, a spate of tornados killed five people, including at least two in the senior-living Spanish Lakes Communities, county spokesperson Erick Gill said. Search-and-rescue teams there are combing through hard-hit areas, including a mobile-home park.</p>

<p>There were 19 confirmed tornados in Florida as of 8 pm Wednesday, about the time Milton made landfall, DeSantis said. Some 45 tornados were reported throughout the day, mostly in the central and eastern parts of the state, the National Weather Service said.</p>

<p>More than 3 million homes and businesses in Florida were without power on Thursday morning, according to PowerOutage.us. At least some had already been waiting days for power to be restored after Hurricane Helene hit the area two weeks ago.</p>

<p>Milton shredded the fabric roof of Tropicana Field, the stadium of the Tampa Bay Rays baseball team in St. Petersburg, but there were no reported injuries. The ballpark was a staging area for responders, with thousands of cots set up on the field.</p>

<p>In the Tampa area, the storm toppled trees, threw debris across roadways and downed power lines, video footage from local news showed. Some neighborhoods were flooded, but the extent of the damage will not be known until crews can assess the destruction, Tampa Mayor Jane Castor said at a morning news conference.</p>

<p>Steven Cole Smith, 71, an automotive writer and editor who lives in Tampa about seven miles (11 km) from the Gulf Coast, rode out the storm with his wife. He said the wind shook the windows so hard he thought they would shatter.</p>

<p>"We really didn't have anywhere else to go," Smith said of their decision not to follow evacuation orders. He has a house in central Florida, but said the forecast for that area looked as bad as where he was staying.</p>

<p>"I spent yesterday scavenging for supplies, fuel for the generator, everything we'd need," he said. "I have a chainsaw too."</p>

<p>Luckily, he said, Tampa was spared a direct hit.</p>

<p>Ken Wood, 58, a state ferryboat operator in Pinellas County, fled his Dunedin home on Florida's Gulf Coast with his 16-year-old cat Andy, after making the "harrowing" mistake of riding out Hurricane Helene two weeks ago in his mobile home.</p>

<p>They heeded evacuation orders and headed north but only made it as far as a hotel about an hour's drive away when he decided it wasn't safe to stay on the roads.</p>

<p>"It was pretty loud, but Andy slept through it all," he told Reuters by telephone.</p>

<p>He is worried about his home but was awaiting official word that roads are clear before returning. Helene destroyed about a third of his neighborhood, and the streets were still piled with rubble that could have become wind-driven projectiles.</p>

<p><strong>'INSTANTANEOUS'</strong></p>

<p>Emergency crews responded overnight to dozens of calls for help, including one in which 15 people were rescued after a tree fell on top of a house, Tampa Police Chief Lee Bercaw said.</p>

<p>The winds toppled a large construction crane in St. Petersburg, sending it crashing onto a deserted street.</p>

<p>The state was still in danger of river flooding after up to 18 inches (457 mm) of rain fell. Authorities were waiting for rivers to crest, but so far levels were at or below those after Hurricane Helene two weeks ago, Castor said on Thursday morning.</p>

<p>Most of the severe damage reported so far stemmed from the tornados, according to Federal Emergency Management Agency head Deanne Criswell, who was in Tallahassee on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The evacuation orders saved lives," she said, noting that more than 90,000 residents went to shelters.</p>

<p>In Fort Myers on the southwest coast, resident Connor Ferin surveyed the wreckage of his home, which had lost its roof and was full of debris and rainwater after a tornado hit.</p>

<p>"All this happened instantaneous, like these windows blew out," he said. "I grabbed the two dogs and run under my bed and that was it. Probably one minute total."</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, who postponed an overseas trip to monitor Milton, spoke to local leaders in Florida on Thursday and pledged the federal government's full support.</p>

<p>The storm hit Florida's west coast on Wednesday night as a Category 3 hurricane on the five-step Saffir-Simpson scale, with top sustained winds of 120 mph (205 kph). While still a dangerous storm, Milton had weakened from the rare Category 5 status as it trekked over the Gulf of Mexico toward Florida.</p>

<p>Milton tailed off further over land, dropping to a Category 1 hurricane with top sustained winds of 85 mph (145 kph) as it reached the peninsula's east coast, the National Hurricane Center said. By Thursday morning, the storm was moving away from the Florida Atlantic coast after lashing communities on the eastern shoreline.</p>

<p>The eye of the storm made landfall in Siesta Key, a barrier island town of some 5,400 people off Sarasota about 60 miles (100 km) south of Tampa Bay.</p>

<p>In a state already battered by Hurricane Helene, as many as 2 million people had been ordered to evacuate ahead of Milton's arrival, and millions more live in the storm's path. Both storms are expected to cause billions of dollars in damage.</p>

<p>Florida airports remained closed on Thursday, including Tampa, Palm Beach and St. Pete-Clearwater, with exceptions for emergency aircraft, according to the Federal Aviation Administration.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/556ep25o_hurricane-milton-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 3 million homes and businesses in Florida were reportedly without power on Thursday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bbc-forecasts-20-000-kph-winds-for-london-apologises-6762512]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BBC Forecasts 20,000 KPH Winds For London, Apologises]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bbc-forecasts-20-000-kph-winds-for-london-apologises-6762512]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 10 Oct 2024 23:30:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The BBC on Thursday apologised after a graphic incorrectly forecast winds of more than 13,000 miles (20,000 kilometres) per hour in London, as Hurricane Milton battered the US state of Florida.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The BBC on Thursday apologised after a graphic incorrectly forecast winds of more than 13,000 miles (20,000 kilometres) per hour in London, as Hurricane Milton battered the US state of Florida.</p>

<p>"Don't be alarmed folks -- Hurricane Milton hasn't made it to us here in the UK!" one of the broadcaster's meteorologists, Matt Taylor, assured the public on X.</p>

<p>"There's been a data glitch between our suppliers and the app/online. Folk are working to solve the issue," he said, adding: "No need to panic buy plywood and candles."</p>

<p>The technical gremlins on the BBC's weather app and website also resulted in overnight temperatures of 404 degrees Celsius (759 degrees Fahrenheit) being predicted for the central English city of Nottingham.</p>

<p>A BBC Weather statement apologised for "some data issues on our app and website. We are working hard to fix it quickly.</p>

<p>"Sorry -- please bear with us," it added.</p>

<p>The real forecast for Thursday was colder, clearer air moving in with rain and drizzle in the south and blustery showers near the east coast.</p>

<p>The blunder has echoes of a 1987 forecast that went down in broadcasting folklore and turned the meteorologist involved into a national celebrity.</p>

<p>Michael Fish famously told viewers during a broadcast on October 15, 1987 that "apparently a woman rang the BBC and said she heard there was a hurricane on the way.</p>

<p>"Well, if you're watching, don't worry, there isn't!"</p>

<p>A few hours later a storm dubbed the "Great Storm of 1987" -- the worst to hit southeast England for three centuries -- hit the region.</p>

<p>The BBC's meteorological mishap came as Milton smashed into Florida leaving at least four people dead and millions without power.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/v1i8eja_bbc-weather-app_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The BBC's meteorological mishap came as Milton smashed into Florida]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>