<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 07:49:41 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fireworks-from-yacht-spark-forest-fire-on-greek-island-13-arrested-5949668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fireworks From Yacht Spark Forest Fire On Greek Island, 13 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fireworks-from-yacht-spark-forest-fire-on-greek-island-13-arrested-5949668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 07:38:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident has caused widespread outrage in Greece, which is already grappling with multiple wildfires amidst its first heatwave of the year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thirteen people have been arrested following a forest fire on the Greek island of Hydra, which authorities believe was started by fireworks launched from a yacht. The fire, which started on Friday, devastated the island's sole pine forest. Although now under control, the fire presented significant challenges for firefighters who had to access the area by sea and use helicopters to drop water due to the lack of roads leading to the beach.</p>

<section id="main" role="main" tabindex="-1">
<section>
<article>
<p>Hydra, southwest of Athens in the Saronic Gulf, is popular among foreign visitors and those travelling on yachts.</p>
</article>
</section>
</section>

<p>The latest blaze was ''caused by fireworks launched from a boat and burned the only pine forest on the island in a place that is difficult to access and has no road'', Hydra's firefighting team said on Facebook.</p>

<p>In a statement on Saturday, Greek authorities confirmed the arrest of 13 Greek citizens who are scheduled to appear before prosecutors on Sunday. An&nbsp;official said the people were arrested at an Athens area marina.</p>

<p>The incident has caused widespread outrage in Greece, which is already grappling with multiple wildfires amidst its first heatwave of the year. The country has been on high alert for wildfires due to dry conditions, strong winds, and high temperatures, which are expected to persist throughout the summer. Officials say 64 forest and brush fires have broken out in Greece over the past 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hydra's mayor, Giorgos Koukoudakis, expressed anger over the reckless actions that led to the fire.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are indignant that some people so irresponsibly throw fireworks into a pine forest," Hydra's mayor, Giorgos Koukoudakis, told Greek broadcaster ERT.</p>

<p>In a related incident, a 55-year-old volunteer firefighter succumbed to injuries sustained while combating a fire in the Ilia region of the Peloponnese peninsula.</p>

<p>Scientists have warned that fossil fuel emissions caused by humans are worsening the length and intensity of heat waves around the world.</p>

<p>Additionally, arson remains a significant problem, with 79 people arrested for arson last August. To combat this, Greece increased penalties for both deliberate and negligent arson last year, introducing fines of up to 200,000 Euro and jail sentences of up to 20 years​</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/uv3rfu5g_forest-fire_625x300_23_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hydra is popular among foreign visitors and those travelling on yachts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-war-games-to-mimic-combat-as-closely-as-possible-5949478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid China Threat, Taiwan War Games To Mimic Combat As Closely As Possible]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-war-games-to-mimic-combat-as-closely-as-possible-5949478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 06:38:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan's annual war games this year will be as close as possible to actual combat, no longer just putting on a show to score points but aiming to simulate real fighting given a rapidly rising "enemy threat" from China, a senior official said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's annual war games this year will be as close as possible to actual combat, no longer just putting on a show to score points but aiming to simulate real fighting given a rapidly rising "enemy threat" from China, a senior official said.</p>

<p>China, which views democratically governed Taiwan as its territory, has been staging regular exercises around the island for four years to pressure Taipei to accept Beijing's claim of sovereignty, despite Taiwan's strong objections.</p>

<p>Taiwan starts its five-day Han Kuang exercises on July 22.</p>

<p>A senior Taiwan defence official, speaking on condition of anonymity to be able to speak more freely, said there was an urgent need to rethink how the drills were conducted.</p>

<p>"In recent years, the enemy threat has changed rapidly," the official said. "Our defence combat plan must also be continuously revised on a rolling basis, and the urgency of comprehensive combat training is becoming more and more important."</p>

<p>Elements that were mostly for show, like rehearsal drills, have been cancelled, while this year there will be nighttime exercises and, unusually, the capital Taipei will be included too, the official said.</p>

<p>"It's not about scoring points," the official said. "We want the soldiers to wonder whether this is for real."</p>

<p>Things may go wrong, like vehicle breakdowns, and that is fine, the official added. "These are problems that may be faced in actual combat."</p>

<p>The exercises will be a continuous experience, the official said. "War does not distinguish between night and day."</p>

<p>China's defence ministry did not answer calls seeking comment about the exercises outside of office hours at the weekend. It has previously said it is futile for Taiwan to think it can use arms to prevent "reunification".</p>

<p>Announcing the drills in April, Taiwan's defence ministry said the war games would practice "kill" zones at sea to break a blockade and simulate a scenario where China suddenly turns one of its regular drills around the island into an attack.</p>

<p>"Only with real-time, on-the-ground verification can we truly understand the capabilities and limitations of our troops," the official said.</p>

<p>China held two days of its own war games around the island shortly after President Lai Ching-te took office last month, saying it was "punishment" for his inauguration speech, which Beijing denounced as being full of separatist content.</p>

<p>But China has also been using grey zone warfare against Taiwan, wielding irregular tactics to exhaust a foe by keeping them continually on alert without resorting to open combat. This includes sending balloons over the island and almost daily air force missions into the skies near Taiwan.</p>

<p>China has never renounced the use of force to bring Taiwan under its control. Lai, who says only the Taiwanese people can decide their future, has repeatedly offered talks but been rebuffed.</p>

<p>The official declined to comment on which parts of the war games Lai would attend, as is customary for the president as commander-in-chief, or whether there would be U.S. observers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/1hkhdv6c_taiwan-war-games_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-island-capri-lifts-tourist-ban-after-water-shortage-resolved-5949338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italy Island Capri Lifts Tourist Ban After Water Shortage Resolved]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-island-capri-lifts-tourist-ban-after-water-shortage-resolved-5949338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 05:44:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Italian island of Capri lifted a ban on tourists Saturday after problems with the water supply to the holiday hotspot were resolved.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Italian island of Capri lifted a ban on tourists Saturday after problems with the water supply to the holiday hotspot were resolved.</p>

<p>Capri's mayor, Paolo Falco, said the ban was "revoked" after a technical issue preventing the arrival of water from the mainland was fixed.</p>

<p>The ban was announced early Saturday, forcing several morning ferries on their way to the island from Naples and Sorrento in southern Italy to return to port.</p>

<p>In justifying the ban, Falco warned of "a real emergency" and said that while there was still water on most of the island on Friday, local tanks early Saturday were "running out".</p>

<p>"The emergency would be worsened by the arrival of the thousands of tourists who arrive on Capri daily," he said.</p>

<p>Locals, not targeted by the ban, were permitted to collect up to 25 litres (6.6 gallons) of drinking water per household from a supply tanker.</p>

<p>Capri, in the Bay of Naples, is famed for its white villas, cove-studded coastline and upscale hotels. It has around 13,000 permanent residents but attracts huge numbers of day-trippers in summer months.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/elg1q4qo_capri-tourists_625x300_22_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Capri is famed for its white villas, cove-studded coastline and upscale hotels]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-7-injured-in-shooting-outside-nightclub-in-us-kentucky-report-5949334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Killed, 7 Injured In Shooting Outside Nightclub In US' Kentucky: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-7-injured-in-shooting-outside-nightclub-in-us-kentucky-report-5949334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 05:43:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One person was killed and seven others were injured in a shooting outside a nightclub in Louisville, Kentucky, on Saturday (local time), CNN reported, citing police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One person was killed and seven others were injured in a shooting outside a nightclub in Louisville, Kentucky, on Saturday (local time), CNN reported, citing police.</p>

<p>First responders found two people injured with gunshot wounds when they reached the spot outside H20 Lounge at 12:47 am (local time), according to the Louisville Police Metro Department's statement. Later, one of the victims, a man, was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>The police said the second person was taken to hospital with critical, life-threatening injuries. Later, medical staff reported that another six victims, all adults, reached area hospitals for treatment after the shooting.</p>

<p>According to Aaron Ellis, a public information officer with the police department, all six people were shot. The police said, "Those injuries are believed to be non-life threatening."</p>

<p>The police did not mention any information about the suspect and it's unclear how many people opened fire or what caused the shooting.</p>

<p>Police said, "The relationship of the victims, if any, is not known at this time," adding that the shooting remains under investigation.</p>

<p>In a separate incident, three people were killed and ten others were injured in a shooting incident at a grocery store in Fordyce, Arkansas on Friday (local time), authorities said in a news conference, CNN reported.</p>

<p>The Arkansas State Police reported that the incident occurred at the Mad Butcher grocery store around 11:30 am local time, CNN reported.</p>

<p>Mike Hagar, Secretary of Public Safety and Director of Arkansas State Police, said that law enforcement swiftly responded to the scene and engaged in a confrontation with the "lone suspect" exchanging gunfire. Both officers and the suspect sustained injuries, but none are believed to be life-threatening.</p>

<p>In the past few weeks, the US has witnessed several shooting incidents, with at least 21 other mass shootings recorded by the Gun Violence Archive since last Friday. According to CNN report, the Gun Violence Archive, regards mass shootings as ones in which four or more people are shot, excluding the shooter.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/6835sp0g_us-police-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police did not mention any information about the suspect (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-british-coalition-conducts-4-strikes-on-yemens-hodeidah-in-red-sea-report-5949166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US-British Coalition Conducts 4 Strikes On Yemen's Hodeidah In Red Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-british-coalition-conducts-4-strikes-on-yemens-hodeidah-in-red-sea-report-5949166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 04:48:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US-British coalition conducted four airstrikes on Yemen's Hodeidah province, the Houthi-run al-Masirah TV reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US-British coalition conducted four airstrikes on Yemen's Hodeidah province, the Houthi-run al-Masirah TV reported.</p>

<p>The strikes hit the Red Sea coastal district of Alluhayah, northwest of the province, al-Masirah TV reported on Saturday, without providing further information.</p>

<p>The US-British coalition has not commented on the airstrikes yet, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, the UK Maritime Trade Operations agency said it received a report of an incident 126 nautical miles east of Yemen's Aden.</p>

<p>"The master of a merchant vessel reports explosions in the vicinity of the vessel. The crew are reported safe and the vessel is proceeding to its next port of call," the agency said on its account on social media platform X, without providing further details.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">UKMTO DAILY SUMMARY 1600UTC 21 JUNE 24 to 1600UTC 22 JUNE 24<a href="https://t.co/lBGHDotJOT">https://t.co/lBGHDotJOT</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MaritimeSecurity?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MaritimeSecurity</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MarSec?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MarSec</a> <a href="https://t.co/msQzfZWS2V">pic.twitter.com/msQzfZWS2V</a></p>
— United Kingdom Maritime Trade Operations (UKMTO) (@UK_MTO) <a href="https://twitter.com/UK_MTO/status/1804547212388499856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>On Friday, the US-British coalition said its forces had destroyed four drone boats and two drone aircraft launched by the Houthis to the Red Sea.</p>

<p>The Houthi group, which controls much of northern Yemen, began in November last year to launch anti-ship ballistic missiles and drones targeting what they said were Israeli-linked ships transiting the Red Sea, to show solidarity with Palestinians in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>In response, the US-British naval coalition stationed in the region has since January conducted air raids and missile strikes against Houthi targets to deter the group, prompting an expansion of Houthi attacks to include US and British commercial vessels and naval ships.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/qi24jrlg_houthis-reuters-_625x300_20_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US-British coalition has not commented on the airstrikes yet (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-you-vote-we-cannot-lose-donald-trump-tells-evangelical-christians-us-elections-2024-5949132]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If You Vote, We Cannot Lose": Donald Trump Tells Evangelical Christians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-you-vote-we-cannot-lose-donald-trump-tells-evangelical-christians-us-elections-2024-5949132]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 04:34:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US president Donald Trump urged evangelical Christians Saturday to vote en masse for him in November, vowing to "aggressively" protect their religious freedom if he is elected.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US president Donald Trump urged evangelical Christians Saturday to vote en masse for him in November, vowing to "aggressively" protect their religious freedom if he is elected.</p>

<p>The ex-leader, who rarely appears in church himself, has built a crucial base among the religious right, promising -- and delivering -- on some of their biggest priorities, including by appointing Supreme Court justices who helped overturn the federal right to abortion.</p>

<p>"The evangelicals and the Christians, they don't vote as much as they should," Trump told hundreds of supporters at a Washington conference put on by the Faith and Freedom Coalition, a conservative advocacy group.</p>

<p>"They go to church every Sunday, but they don't vote," he said, adding in a half-joke that "in four years, you don't have to vote. Okay? In four years, don't vote. I don't care."</p>

<p>Trump would be ineligible to run for president in 2028 because of term limits.</p>

<p>Evangelical voters were crucial for Trump's 2016 victory and again in his failed 2020 campaign, when 84 percent of white evangelical Protestants voted for him, according to the Pew Research Center.</p>

<p>Trump promised to protect their interests Saturday, as he vowed to "aggressively defend religious freedom."</p>

<p>"We will protect Christians in our schools, in our military, in our government, in our workplaces, in our hospitals and in our public square," he told supporters.</p>

<p>He additionally promised to create "a new federal task force on fighting anti-Christian bias" that would investigate supposed "illegal discrimination, harassment, persecution" of US Christians.</p>

<p>Almost half (49 percent) of Americans believe that religion's influence is declining in the United States and that this is a bad thing, according to a Pew Research survey published last month.</p>

<p>The number of Americans identifying as Christian has dropped from nearly 90 percent in the 1990s to less than two-thirds of the population in 2022, mostly due to rising numbers of people who are not religiously affiliated.</p>

<p>For many white evangelical Christians -- a conservative denomination that makes up about 14 percent of US voters -- it is crucial that religion stays relevant in public life.</p>

<p>Trump told the crowd that the political left wanted to "silence you, demoralize you, and they want to keep you out of politics."</p>

<p>"They don't want you to vote, that's why you have to vote," he said, adding "If you vote, no, we cannot lose."</p>

<p>Trump will face his Democratic rival, President Joe Biden, in the first 2024 presidential debate on Thursday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3irh8p6g_trump_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump would be ineligible to run for president in 2028 because of term limits (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-uk-minister-compares-election-betting-scandal-to-partygate-report-5949103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Senior UK Minister Compares Election Betting Scandal To Partygate: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/senior-uk-minister-compares-election-betting-scandal-to-partygate-report-5949103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 04:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior British minister compared the latest scandal involving Tory candidates accused of betting on the election date to Partygate, a series of Covid-era parties that brought down Boris Johnson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior British minister compared the latest scandal involving Tory candidates accused of betting on the election date to Partygate, a series of Covid-era parties that brought down Boris Johnson.</p>

<p>Housing minister Michael Gove compared the betting allegations to the Partygate scandal in an interview with the Times newspaper on Saturday.</p>

<p>"It looks like one rule for them and one rule for us... That's the most potentially damaging thing," said Gove, who is standing down this election after 14 years as an MP.</p>

<p>"That was damaging at the time of Partygate and is damaging here", he added.</p>

<p>Prime minister Johnson was forced from office in 2022 following public anger at the revelations of parties held in Downing Street when the rest of the country was under lockdown during the pandemic.</p>

<p>Now another senior Conservative Party figure has been caught up in the latest scandal.</p>

<p>The party's chief data officer, Nick Mason, has taken a leave of absence, following claims he placed bets on the timing of the election, the PA news agency reported Saturday.</p>

<p>Mason is being investigated by betting regulators, accused of placing dozens of bets on the election date according to the Times. He is the fourth Tory figure to be implicated in the affair.</p>

<h3><strong>'Incredibly damaging'</strong></h3>

<p>The party's campaign director stepped aside following reports on Thursday that he and his wife, a Tory candidate in the July 4 election, were under investigation by the Gambling Commission.</p>

<p>The scandal broke a week earlier, when Tory candidate and Sunak's ministerial aide Craig Williams said he was being probed for staking a bet on the snap election date before it was called.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, London police said one of Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's security detail had been arrested for allegedly placing a bet on the date.</p>

<p>Sunak has said he is "incredibly angry" over the revelations.</p>

<p>"If anyone is found to have broken the rules, not only should they face the full consequences of the law, I will make sure that they are booted out of the Conservative Party," he said earlier this week.</p>

<p>Political bets are allowed in the UK, including on the date of elections, but using insider knowledge to do so is against the law.</p>

<p>The inquiries heap further misery on Sunak, whose party has trailed Labour by about 20 points in the polls for nearly two years, making it odds-on to be dumped out of office after 14 years.</p>

<p>Gove said that those involved in the betting scandal were "sucking the oxygen out of the campaign".</p>

<p>Comparing it to Partygate again, he added: "A few individuals end up creating an incredibly damaging atmosphere for the party.</p>

<p>"So it's both bad in itself, but also destructive to the efforts of all of those good people who are currently fighting hard for the Conservative vote."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/munp5db_michael-gove_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Political bets are allowed in the UK but using insider knowledge to do so is against the law]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/piles-of-bodies-blood-everywhere-red-cross-chief-in-rafah-recounts-shelling-horror-5949077]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Piles Of Bodies Everywhere": Red Cross Chief In Rafah Recounts Horror]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/piles-of-bodies-blood-everywhere-red-cross-chief-in-rafah-recounts-shelling-horror-5949077]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 04:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Red Cross official in Gaza on Saturday told reporters of the horrific scenes after an Israeli strike in the Gaza Strip.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Red Cross official in Gaza on Saturday told reporters of the horrific scenes after an Israeli strike in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>It was around 3:30 pm when three explosions rocked the walls of the Red Cross compound in Gaza on Friday, William Schomburg, the local chief for the ICRC told reporters in Geneva via video link.</p>

<p>Then came the "flood of wounded people" seeking help, said the international charity's chief in Rafah.</p>

<p>"There were piles of dead bodies, blood everywhere," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Twenty-two people were killed in shelling that lightly damaged the outside walls of the compound where the Red Cross has been operating.</p>

<p>It is located just south of a humanitarian zone identified by the Israeli army in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>"All of our buildings are very well known to all parties to the conflict," Schomburg said.</p>

<p>Refusing to speculate on the source of the shelling, he said: "We're not here to lay blame.</p>

<p>"But of course, this incident is one of several near misses that we have had... and we as the ICRC cannot operate like this."</p>

<h3><strong>'Pools of blood'</strong></h3>

<p>Many of the wounded were taken by ambulance to a nearby Red Cross field hospital for operations. Some did not survive.</p>

<p>No Red Cross employees were killed, Schomburg said, but two children of staff members required treatment for injuries sustained in the blasts.</p>

<p>It is not the first time Red Cross facilities have been damaged during the more than eight months of fighting between Israel and Hamas militants who control the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Schomburg said that recovering from the trauma of Friday's strike would not be easy.</p>

<p>"Around the compound on the street, there were pools of blood, there were bodies strewn across the ground," he said.</p>

<p>"We literally found body parts scattered in different areas, including within the compound.</p>

<p>"Frankly, it's like nothing I've ever seen before. The scale of the suffering in such a short period of time was really very shocking for the team."</p>

<h3><strong>'Overwhelming' fear</strong></h3>

<p>The shelling came as Israel has stepped up its strikes in the Gaza Strip since war broke out after the October 7 attack by Hamas, which resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 41 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,551 people, also mostly civilians, Gaza's health ministry said on Saturday.</p>

<p>An Israel Defense Forces statement on Saturday said an initial inquiry found "there was no direct attack carried out by the IDF against a Red Cross facility".</p>

<p>But the incident was still under review and "findings will be presented to our international partners".</p>

<p>The Red Cross office is surrounded by a camp where several families of ICRC staff members live in tents. Schomburg said it was a "miracle" that none were severely injured.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nonetheless "there was an overwhelming sense of fear amongst people that were clearly panicked and very desperate with nowhere to go", he added.</p>

<p>Thousands of displaced Palestinians have been sheltering in tents in the coastal Al-Mawasi area since the outbreak of the fighting, prompting the recognition of the humanitarian zone by Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>"Our office here in Rafah, like all of our buildings and facilities, are all marked with the Red Cross emblem and are known by all parties," Schomburg said.</p>

<p>"So how to explain the strikes we experienced yesterday? I think you will have to ask the parties involved in this conflict, and not us."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tf0057tg_rafah_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many of the wounded were taken by ambulance to a nearby Red Cross field hospital]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-attack-on-4-ships-at-israel-port-for-violating-ban-5949019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthis Claim Attack On 4 Ships At Israel Port For "Violating Ban"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-attack-on-4-ships-at-israel-port-for-violating-ban-5949019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 03:59:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis said early on Sunday that they had conducted a joint military operation with the Islamic Resistance in Iraq militant group, targeting four ships at Israel's northern Haifa port.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthis said early on Sunday that they had conducted a joint military operation with the Islamic Resistance in Iraq militant group, targeting four ships at Israel's northern Haifa port.</p>

<p>The Houthi military spokesperson, Yahya Saree, said in a televised statement that the two groups launched a drone attack on two cement tankers and two cargo ships at the Haifa port on Saturday.</p>

<p>He said the ships belonged to companies that "violated the ban on entering the ports of occupied Palestine".</p>

<p>The Israeli military did not immediately comment, though it had previously denied a similar claim by the Houthis early this month.</p>

<p>Saree also said the Houthis had attacked the Shorthorn Express in the Mediterranean using drones as part of the group's campaign to disrupt shipping in key waterways, which they say is an act of solidarity with Palestinians in the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"The two operations successfully achieved their objectives, and the strikes were precise and direct," Saree said.</p>

<p>There was no independent confirmation of strikes, and Reuters could not verify the claims.</p>

<p>The Iran-aligned Houthis first launched drone and missile strikes in shipping lanes in November. In dozens of attacks, they have sunk two vessels, seized another and killed at least three seafarers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/pr4n5o3c_houthi-rebels_625x300_26_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iran-aligned Houthis first launched drone and missile strikes in November]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-official-from-uk-pm-rishi-sunaks-party-probed-over-election-bets-report-5948987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Another Official From Sunak's Party Probed Over Election Bets: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-official-from-uk-pm-rishi-sunaks-party-probed-over-election-bets-report-5948987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 03:44:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An official from Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party is being investigated by Britain's gambling regulator over allegations he placed bets on the date of the general election before it was announced, the Sunday Times reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An official from Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's Conservative Party is being investigated by Britain's gambling regulator over allegations he placed bets on the date of the general election before it was announced, the Sunday Times reported.</p>

<p>Britain's Gambling Commission has already been reported to be investigating two Conservative election candidates and the party's director of campaigning over bets on the date of the July 4 election.</p>

<p>The widening scandal has further damaged Sunak's attempts to catch the opposition Labour Party, which is far ahead in opinion polls in the run-up to the election.</p>

<p>The official was named by the paper as Nick Mason, chief data officer at the Conservative Party. Mason did not immediately respond to a request for comment. The newspaper cited a spokesperson for Mason as saying he denied any wrongdoing.</p>

<p>The Sunday Times cited a statement from the Conservative Party as saying Mason had taken a leave of absence. The party did not confirm this when contacted by Reuters.</p>

<p>"As instructed by the Gambling Commission, we are not permitted to discuss any matters related to any investigation with the subject or any other persons," a Conservative Party spokesman said.</p>

<p>The Gambling Commission has not confirmed the names of those under investigation. In a response to a request for comment on the Sunday Times report, a commission spokesperson said it would not provide details of its probe, including the identity of any individuals it is investigating.</p>

<p>Sunak said on Thursday he was "incredibly angry" to hear about the allegations against his party colleagues, calling them a "really serious matter."</p>

<p>One of the Conservative candidates named in the scandal, Craig Williams, has already apologised for an error of judgment, and the party's director of campaigning Tony Lee has taken a leave of absence.</p>

<p>A police officer working in a special protection unit has also been arrested over alleged bets on the election date.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/c8u6i1l8_rishi-sunak_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak said on Thursday he was "incredibly angry" to hear about the allegations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-launch-ballistic-missiles-at-us-aircraft-carrier-eisenhower-in-red-sea-5948983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthis Launch Ballistic Missiles At US Aircraft Carrier In Red Sea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-launch-ballistic-missiles-at-us-aircraft-carrier-eisenhower-in-red-sea-5948983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 03:42:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's armed Houthi group has said in a statement that it had launched ballistic missiles at the US aircraft carrier Eisenhower in northern Red Sea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's armed Houthi group has said in a statement that it had launched ballistic missiles at the US aircraft carrier Eisenhower in northern Red Sea.</p>

<p>"The missile force in our armed forces carried out an operation targeting the American aircraft carrier Eisenhower in the northern Red Sea with several ballistic and cruise missiles, and the operation achieved its goals successfully," Houthi military spokesman Yahya Sarea said on Saturday in a statement aired by Houthi-run al-Masirah TV.</p>

<p>However, there is currently no evidence to confirm that the aircraft carrier was indeed attacked, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>This is the second claimed attack by Houthis targeting the US aircraft carrier Eisenhower in the Red Sea in less than a month. The first attack against the nuclear-powered aircraft carrier was on May 31, in which the US military didn't comment.</p>

<p>Sarea said that the militant group also attacked the merchant vessel TRANSWORLD NAVIGATOR in the Arabian Sea with ballistic missiles, as a response to what Houthis called the vessel owner's violation of their entry ban to Israeli ports.</p>

<p>The statement threatened more such strikes "until the (Israeli) aggression stops and the siege on the Palestinian people in the Gaza Strip is lifted".</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, fighter jets of the US-British coalition conducted four airstrikes against Houthi targets northwest of Yemen's Red Sea port city of Hodeidah, according to the Houthi al-Masirah television.</p>

<p>Hours before the coalition airstrikes, the UK Maritime Trade Operations reported explosions in the vicinity of a merchant vessel 126 nautical miles east of Yemen's southern port city of Aden. There were no reports of casualties or damage.</p>

<p>The Houthi group, which controls much of northern Yemen, began in November last year to launch anti-ship ballistic missiles and drones targeting what they said were Israeli-linked ships transiting the Red Sea, to show solidarity with Palestinians in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>In response, the US-British naval coalition stationed in the waters has since January conducted air raids and missile strikes against Houthi targets to deter the group, but this only led to an expansion of Houthi attacks to include US and British commercial vessels and naval ships.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/1cnmnbco_houthis_625x300_03_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is the second claimed attack by Houthis targeting the US aircraft carrier (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/policeman-among-3-killed-8-injured-in-colombia-car-bombing-5948861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Policeman Among 3 Killed, 8 Injured In Colombia Car Bombing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/policeman-among-3-killed-8-injured-in-colombia-car-bombing-5948861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 03:06:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three people died, including a policeman, and eight others were wounded in a car bombing in a region of Colombia where a leftist rebel group remains active, officials said Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people died, including a policeman, and eight others were wounded in a car bombing in a region of Colombia where a leftist rebel group remains active, officials said Saturday.</p>

<p>"An explosive charge placed in a private vehicle was detonated, causing the death of police officer Santiago Moreno Rios along with a shopkeeper and a man," the country's defense ministry said on social network X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="es">El atentado terrorista en Taminango, Nariño, fue perpetrado por el frente ‘Franco Benavides', bajo el mando de alias ‘Mata', del autodenominado Estado Mayor Central.<br />
<br />
Se ofrece una recompensa de hasta 50 millones de pesos por información que dé con la captura de los responsables… <a href="https://t.co/OmrUZGkI9y">pic.twitter.com/OmrUZGkI9y</a></p>
— Mindefensa (@mindefensa) <a href="https://twitter.com/mindefensa/status/1804582006287954270?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It said two other officers and six civilians were wounded in the Friday explosion in the southwestern Narino department.</p>

<p>The incident occurred in a region where a FARC dissident group called Estado Mayor Central (EMC) operates, according to authorities.</p>

<p>The EMC and Segunda Marquetalia are two splinter groups that refused to disarm when the FARC -- the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, once the most powerful guerrilla organization on the continent -- signed a peace deal in 2016.</p>

<p>Friday's attack came the same day rebels in the Cesar department killed one policeman and wounded another.</p>

<p>President Gustavo Petro expressed solidarity with the families of victims of both attacks and said "those who choose the path of war over peace will continue to face the full weight of the law."</p>

<p>The attacks come ahead of negotiations on Monday in Caracas between the Colombian government and representatives of Segunda Marquetalia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/si0hlih8_colombia-police-generic_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occurred in a region where a FARC dissident group operates (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-touches-briefly-on-abortion-in-address-to-christian-group-says-5948755]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Believe In Exception": Trump Touches Briefly On Abortion At Faith Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-touches-briefly-on-abortion-in-address-to-christian-group-says-5948755]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 02:24:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump called on religious supporters to go the polls in a speech to conservative Christian activists on Saturday, but mentioned only briefly the politically sensitive issue of abortion, a topic of central importance to the group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump called on religious supporters to go the polls in a speech to conservative Christian activists on Saturday, but mentioned only briefly the politically sensitive issue of abortion, a topic of central importance to the group.</p>

<p>Speaking at an event organized by the Faith &amp; Freedom Coalition in Washington, the former president reiterated his position that abortion restrictions should be decided by voters on a state-by-state basis.</p>

<p>That stance contradicts the view of most conservative Christians, and Trump's reticence to push for or even discuss additional federal regulations speaks to how sensitive the issue has become for Republicans.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly said Republicans risk electoral defeat if they take too stringent a line on abortion rights. The party's underwhelming performance in the 2022 congressional midterm elections has been widely attributed to the Supreme Court's Dobbs ruling that year, which removed most constitutional protections for the procedure.</p>

<p>"We've gotten abortion out of the federal government and back to the states. The people will decide, and that's the way it should be," Trump said.</p>

<p>"Like Ronald Reagan, I believe in exceptions for the life of the mother - rape and incest ... You have to go with your heart. You have to also remember you have to get elected," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump's comments on abortion appeared to receive a lukewarm reception. Some in the crowd broke out in chants of "No dead babies!" as he discussed the topic.</p>

<p>But there was no indication the heavily pro-Trump audience would support another candidate as the Nov. 5 general election rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden approaches.</p>

<p>Trump received heavy applause when he discussed several other proposals, including eliminating the Department of Education, a measure favored by many conservative Christians who accuse the federal government of attacking faith-based teaching methods.</p>

<p>At multiple points during his speech, Trump called on Christians to show up to the polls in November, prompting chants of "Vote!" from the crowd.</p>

<p>Trump has claimed credit for appointing three conservative justices to the Supreme Court who helped overturn the Roe v. Wade decision two years ago this Monday, eliminating a nationwide right to abortion in a moment of triumph for conservatives.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly said he would not support a federal ban on abortion, however, preferring to leave the issue to individual states.</p>

<p>Ralph Reed, the founder and chairman of the Faith &amp; Freedom Coalition and a key Trump ally, has previously said his group would continue to work towards restrictions at both the state and federal levels.</p>

<h3><strong>On To Philadelphia</strong></h3>

<p>Later on Saturday, Trump will hold a campaign rally at Temple University in a historically Black area of Philadelphia, long a stronghold for Democrats. Trump won just 5% of the vote in precincts within a half-mile radius of Temple's main campus, according to the Philadelphia Inquirer.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign has made courting Black and Hispanic voters, who make up more than half of Philadelphia's population, a priority this cycle, encouraged by some opinion polls that indicate he may be gaining ground with these voters.</p>

<p>Trump has little chance of winning the city, as President Joe Biden, a Democrat, won 81.4% of the votes in Philadelphia County in 2020. But Trump could boost his chances by narrowing the margin in Philadelphia and surrounding counties so critical to the overall tally in Pennsylvania, a battleground state that is hotly contested because it can swing either to Republicans or Democrats.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign said he will use his Philadelphia speech to talk about Biden's handling of inflation, the southern border and crime, all key tenets of the Republican's campaign for a second term.</p>

<p>William Rosenberg, a political science professor at Drexel University, said he believed Trump's main goal was projecting his outreach to Black voters nationally, similar to the rally he held in the Bronx borough of New York City last month.</p>

<p>"It's a play to get on national TV to say you are in Philadelphia, to make the case that this is a Black community," Rosenberg said. "Then perhaps you convince some swing voters that Donald Trump is not so bad."</p>

<p>Democrats have set up posters, billboards and kiosks in Philadelphia and on the Temple campus to promote Biden's policies, including his efforts to forgive student debt, as well as to criticize Trump's record with the Black community.</p>

<p>State lawmaker Malcolm Kenyatta, a Democrat, said Black voters remember Trump's history promoting the bigoted conspiracy theory that questioned whether Barack Obama, the country's first African American president, was born in the United States, and policies that he pursued that hurt the Black working class.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is in a Black place, but Donald Trump does not give a damn about Black people," Kenyatta said at a press event at a Biden campaign office in Philadelphia, adding that Trump would "get the type of welcome he deserves" from the city.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3irh8p6g_trump_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has repeatedly said he would not support a federal ban on abortion]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explosives-found-in-jordan-residential-apartment-near-military-airport-used-by-us-planes-5948729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explosives Found In Jordan Apartment Near Airport Used By US Planes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explosives-found-in-jordan-residential-apartment-near-military-airport-used-by-us-planes-5948729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 02:17:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police in Jordan said on Saturday they had discovered and detonated explosives stored in a crowded residential area of the capital close to a military airport used by U.S. army planes, and that they were investigating the incident.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police in Jordan said on Saturday they had discovered and detonated explosives stored in a crowded residential area of the capital close to a military airport used by U.S. army planes, and that they were investigating the incident.</p>

<p>The explosives in a home in the Marka neighbourhood northeast of the capital were detonated at the site after the area was evacuated, according to a statement from the public security directorate.</p>

<p>The statement did not say if police suspected the stash was terrorism related, whether arrests were made, and did not detail the quantity of explosives. It added more details would be published once the investigation was complete.</p>

<p>Witnesses said the flat was nearly one kilometre (0.6 miles) from the Marka military airport used by U.S. planes stationed in the kingdom, and by other coalition partners.</p>

<p>The explosives were discovered after civil defence authorities arrived at the flat following an explosion that was initially believed to have been caused by a gas leak, but may have been a botched attempt to manufacture explosives, former officials and security experts said.</p>

<p>"The indications all point it's a terrorist case and an incident related to radical groups that target the kingdom on the pretext of its stance on Gaza," said Saud Al Sharafat, a former brigadier general in Jordanian intelligence.</p>

<p>U.S. ally Jordan has over 3,500 American troops stationed in several bases and, since the war between Israel and Palestinian groups in Gaza erupted in October, it has been increasingly targeted by Iranian-backed groups operating in neighbouring Syria and Iraq.</p>

<p>Over the past year, Jordan has said it has foiled many attempts to smuggle weapons by parties linked to pro-Iranian militias in Syria.</p>

<p>Iran has denied being behind such attempts.</p>

<p>Many of the arms are bound for the neighbouring Israeli-occupied West Bank, Jordanian officials say, adding they have arrested several Jordanians linked to Palestinian fighters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/jbslfmjo_jordan-generic_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The statement did not say if police suspected the stash was terrorism related (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crime-minister-thousands-wave-flags-protest-against-netanyahu-in-israel-5948654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Crime Minister: Thousands Wave Flags, Protest Against Netanyahu In Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crime-minister-thousands-wave-flags-protest-against-netanyahu-in-israel-5948654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 01:55:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tens of thousands of protesters waving Israeli flags and chanting slogans against Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government rallied in Tel Aviv Saturday, demanding new elections and the return of hostages held in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tens of thousands of protesters waving Israeli flags and chanting slogans against Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government rallied in Tel Aviv Saturday, demanding new elections and the return of hostages held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Large protests have occurred in the Israeli city on a weekly basis over Netanyahu's handling of the nearly nine-month-old war in Gaza started by Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>Many protesters held signs reading "Crime Minister" and "Stop the War" as people poured into the biggest Israeli city's main thoroughfare.</p>

<p>"I am here because I am afraid of the future of my grandchild. There will be no future for them if we don't go out and get rid of the horrible government," said 66-year-old contractor Shai Erel.</p>

<p>"All of the rats in the Knesset... I wouldn't let any one of them be a guard of a kindergarten."</p>

<p>Anti-government protest organisation Hofshi Israel estimated more than 150,000 people attended the rally, calling it the biggest since the Gaza war began.</p>

<p>Some demonstrators lay on the ground covered in red paint in the city's Democracy Square to protest what they say is the death of the country's democracy under Netanyahu.</p>

<p>In an address to the crowd, a former head of Israel's domestic Shin Bet security agency, Yuval Diskin, condemned Netanyahu as Israel's "worst prime minister".</p>

<p>Many are frustrated with the country's right-wing coalition, which includes Security Minister Itamar Ben Gvir and other far-right ultra-nationalists, accusing it of prolonging the war in Gaza and putting the country's security and hostages at risk.</p>

<p>Yoram, a 50-year-old tour guide who declined to give his last name, said he was attending every weekly protest as Israel needed elections "yesterday" because of Netanyahu.</p>

<p>"I really hope that the government collapses," he said. "If we go to the original date of elections in 2026, it is not going to be a democratic election."</p>

<p>Hamas seized 251 hostages on October 7, of whom Israel believes 116 remain in Gaza, including 41 who the army says are dead.</p>

<p>A separate Tel Aviv rally on Saturday night drew thousands of relatives and supporters of the hostages.</p>

<p>The attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,194 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 37,551 people, also mostly civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-ruled territory.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/cflm000g_tel-aviv-protest_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many are frustrated with the country's right-wing coalition]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-strap-wounded-palestinian-tie-him-on-top-of-vehicle-and-drive-off-5948624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Forces Strap Wounded Man, Tie Him On Top Of Vehicle And Drive Off]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-forces-strap-wounded-palestinian-tie-him-on-top-of-vehicle-and-drive-off-5948624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 01:44:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli army forces strapped a wounded Palestinian man to the hood of the military jeep during an arrest raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli army forces strapped a wounded Palestinian man to the hood of the military jeep during an arrest raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin on Saturday.</p>

<p>A video circulating on social media and verified by Reuters showed a Palestinian resident of Jenin, Mujahed Azmi, on the jeep that passes through two ambulances.</p>

<p>The Israeli military in a statement said Israeli forces were fired at and exchanged fire, wounding a suspect and arresting him.</p>

<p>Soldiers then violated military protocol, the statement said. "The suspect was taken by the forces while tied on top of a vehicle," it said.</p>

<p>The military said the "conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values" of the Israeli military and that the incident will be investigated and dealt with.</p>

<p>The individual was transferred to medics for treatment, the military said.</p>

<p>Reuters was able to match the location from corroborating and verified footage shared on social media that shows a vehicle transporting an individual tied on top of a vehicle in Jenin. The date was confirmed by an eyewitness interviewed by Reuters.</p>

<p>According to the family of Azmi, there was an arrest raid, and he was injured during the raid, and when the family asked for an ambulance, the army took Mujahed, strapped him on the hood and drove off.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, already on the rise before the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza, has escalated since then with frequent army raids on terror groups, rampages by Jewish settlers in Palestinian villages, and deadly Palestinian street attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ggsc7m78_israel_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The individual was transferred to medics for treatment, the military said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-42-killed-in-fresh-israeli-strikes-in-gaza-5948440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Least 42 Killed In Fresh Israeli Strikes In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-42-killed-in-fresh-israeli-strikes-in-gaza-5948440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:47:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 42 people were killed in Israeli attacks on districts of Gaza City in the north of the Palestinian enclave on Saturday, the director of the Hamas-run government media office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 42 people were killed in Israeli attacks on districts of Gaza City in the north of the Palestinian enclave on Saturday, the director of the Hamas-run government media office said.</p>

<p>One Israeli strike on houses in Al-Shati, one of the Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps, killed 24 people, Ismail Al-Thawabta told Reuters. Another 18 Palestinians were killed in a strike on houses in the Al-Tuffah neighborhood.</p>

<p>The Israeli military released a brief statement saying: "A short while ago, IDF fighter jets struck two Hamas military infrastructure sites in the area of Gaza City."</p>

<p>It said more details would be released soon.</p>

<p>Hamas did not comment on the Israeli claim to have hit its military infrastructure. It said in a statement the attacks targeted the civilian population and vowed in a statement "the occupation and its Nazi leaders will pay the price for their violations against our people."</p>

<p>Footage obtained by Reuters showed dozens of Palestinians rushing out to search for victims amid the destroyed houses. The footage showed wrecked homes, blasted walls, and debris and dust filling the street in Shati refugee camp.</p>

<p>Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza was triggered when Hamas stormed into southern Israel on Oct. 7, killing around 1,200 people and seizing more than 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The offensive has left Gaza in ruins, killed more than 37,400 people, of whom 101 were killed in the past 24 hours, according to Palestinian health authorities, and left nearly the entire population homeless and destitute.</p>

<p>More than eight months into the war, Israel's advance is now focused on the two last areas its forces had yet to seize: Rafah on Gaza's southern edge and the area surrounding Deir al-Balah in the centre.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli tanks deepened their incursion into western and northern Rafah areas in recent days. On Saturday Israeli forces bombed several areas from air and the ground, forcing many families living in areas described as humanitarian-designated zones to leave northwards.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said forces continued "precise, intelligence-based" targeted operations in Rafah, killing many Palestinian gunmen and dismantling military infrastructure.</p>

<p>On Friday, the Gaza health ministry said at least 25 Palestinians were killed in Mawasi in western Rafah and 50 wounded. Palestinians said a tank shell hit a tent housing displaced families.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said that the incident was under review. "An initial inquiry conducted suggests that there is no indication that a strike was carried out by the IDF (Israel Defence Forces) in the Humanitarian Area in Al-Mawasi," it said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tviol0p_gaza_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The offensive has left Gaza in ruins and killed more than 37,400 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-evening-prince-william-celebrates-birthday-at-taylor-swifts-london-concert-5948394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On His Birthday, Prince William Dances To Taylor's "Shake It Off" In London]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-evening-prince-william-celebrates-birthday-at-taylor-swifts-london-concert-5948394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:32:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taylor Swift got the London-leg of her Eras tour off to a good start, with the UK's Prince William posting a backstage picture of them posted on social media Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taylor Swift got the London-leg of her Eras tour off to a good start, with the UK's Prince William posting a backstage picture of them posted on social media Saturday.</p>

<p>After celebrating his 42nd birthday at Swift's Wembley Stadium concert with his children, Prince George and Princess Charlotte, William posted their backstage selfie.</p>

<p>The US pop sensation seemed equally enamoured, posting a photo with the three royals and her boyfriend Travis Kelce.</p>

<p>"Happy Bday M8! London shows are off to a splendid start," she wrote on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Happy Bday M8! London shows are off to a splendid start ????? <a href="https://twitter.com/KensingtonRoyal?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KensingtonRoyal</a> <a href="https://t.co/VlD6V0PiEL">pic.twitter.com/VlD6V0PiEL</a></p>
— Taylor Swift (@taylorswift13) <a href="https://twitter.com/taylorswift13/status/1804489925246529747?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Reposting Taylor's post, the official X handle of Kensington Palace, wrote, "Thank you @taylorswift13 for a great evening! #LondonTSTheErastour" (sic)</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/taylorswift13?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@taylorswift13</a> for a great evening! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LondonTSTheErastour?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LondonTSTheErastour</a> <a href="https://t.co/NFSi8hAl1o">pic.twitter.com/NFSi8hAl1o</a></p>
— The Prince and Princess of Wales (@KensingtonRoyal) <a href="https://twitter.com/KensingtonRoyal/status/1804489979294364005?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A widely shared video on social media appeared to show William, who is the heir to the throne, dancing energetically to Swift's hit single "Shake it off".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?| Prince William vibing and dancing along to "Shake It Off" at Night 1 of Taylor Swift's 'The Eras Tour' in London! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/LondonTSTheErasTour?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#LondonTSTheErasTour</a><br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/WYr5rG8DaL">pic.twitter.com/WYr5rG8DaL</a></p>
— The Eras Tour (@tswifterastour) <a href="https://twitter.com/tswifterastour/status/1804456967613931742?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Also among the nearly 90,000 fans packed into the stadium was Labour party leader Keir Starmer, who with his wife.</p>

<p>Starmer, who after next month's election could be Britain's next prime minister, said on Saturday that Swift "was fantastic. Absolutely fantastic".</p>

<p>"I know I will be asked what is my favourite song and I am not going to pretend I have got every album and know every song," he told reporters on the campaign trail.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Although 'Change' is the one for obvious reasons," he added, referring to the word which is also his election campaign slogan.</p>

<p>Swift is currently touring the UK as part of the Europe-leg of her Era's tour. She is performing two more shows in London on Saturday and Sunday before returning to the British capital again in August.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She has already played shows in Edinburgh, Liverpool and Cardiff and will be heading to Dublin next.</p>

<p>The London Mayor's office announced on Thursday that the eight Era's tour performances in London would general &amp;#163;300 million ($380m) for the city's economy.</p>

<p>In the lead-up to Friday's show, the mayor unveiled several murals dedicated to Swift as well as a special Tube map with stations named after songs to mark the tour.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tbhtmvno_william-and-swift_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US pop sensation seemed equally enamoured, posting a photo with the three royals]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-court-overturns-popular-rapper-toomaj-salehis-death-sentence-says-lawyer-5948154]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Supreme Court Overturns Popular Rapper's Death Sentence, Says Lawyer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-supreme-court-overturns-popular-rapper-toomaj-salehis-death-sentence-says-lawyer-5948154]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 22 Jun 2024 23:39:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme court has overturned a death sentence against popular rapper Toomaj Salehi who was jailed for backing nationwide protests sparked by Mahsa Amini's death, his lawyer said Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's supreme court has overturned a death sentence against popular rapper Toomaj Salehi who was jailed for backing nationwide protests sparked by Mahsa Amini's death, his lawyer said Saturday.</p>

<p>"Salehi's death sentence was overturned," the rapper's lawyer Amir Raisian said in a post on X, adding that the Islamic republic's top court had ordered a retrial.</p>

<p>In April, an Iranian court sentenced Salehi to death for the capital offence of "corruption on earth", Raisian said at the time.</p>

<p>The rapper was also found guilty of "assistance in sedition, assembly and collusion, propaganda against the state and calling for riots", the lawyer said.</p>

<p>Salehi, 33, was arrested in October 2022 after publicly backing demonstrations which had erupted a month earlier, triggered by Amini's death in police custody.</p>

<p>Amini, a 22-year-old Iranian Kurd, was detained by the morality police in Tehran over an alleged breach of the Islamic republic's strict dress rules for women.</p>

<p>"The Supreme Court prevented an irreparable judicial error," Raisian said, adding that the court also ruled that Salehi's "previous sentence (6 years and three months) was also without compliance with the rules of a multiplicity of crimes."</p>

<p>The months-long protests sparked by Amini's death saw hundreds of people killed, including dozens of security personnel.</p>

<p>Thousands were arrested as authorities moved to quell what they branded foreign-instigated "riots".</p>

<p>In January, another singer, Mehdi Yarrahi who criticised the headscarf requirement for women was sentenced to a total of two years and eight months in prison on multiple charges, which would have been served concurrently.</p>

<p>The court later changed Yarrahi's sentence to home confinement due to his health issues.</p>

<p>Nine men have been executed in protest-related cases involving killings and other violence against security forces.</p>

<p>Covering the neck and head has been compulsory for women in Iran since 1983, following the 1979 Islamic Revolution.</p>

<p>Since the protests, women have been increasingly flouting the strict dress code but Iranian police have in recent months toughened controls on women who ignore the rules.</p>

<p>Iranian media has in recent weeks reported that police in the capital have launched a campaign codenamed "Noor", the Persian word for light, in their efforts to double down on those who break the dress code.</p>

<p>In an effort to tackle those breaking hijab laws, the authorities have also shut down cafes and restaurants where the wearing of the hijab was not respected.</p>

<p>The country's parliament has also approved a draft "Chastity and Hijab" law that seeks to toughen penalties on women not adhering to the dress rules.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/ut2742co_toomaj-salehi_625x300_24_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Toomaj Salehi was sentenced to death for the capital offence of "corruption on earth" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-banned-from-italys-capri-over-water-shortage-5947468]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tourists Banned From Italy's Capri Over Water Shortage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tourists-banned-from-italys-capri-over-water-shortage-5947468]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 22 Jun 2024 21:33:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Italian island of Capri banned tourists from disembarking Saturday after problems with the water supply from the mainland threatened to leave the holiday hotspot parched.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Italian island of Capri banned tourists from disembarking Saturday after problems with the water supply from the mainland threatened to leave the holiday hotspot parched.</p>

<p>The ban by Capri mayor Paolo Falco forced several ferries on their way to the island from Naples and Sorrento in southern Italy to turn back.</p>

<p>The company charged with supplying the island with water said there had been a technical problem on the mainland on Thursday, and while that had since been fixed problems with the supply to Capri remained.</p>

<p>Falco warned of "a real emergency" and said that while there was still water on most of the island on Friday, local tanks were "running out".</p>

<p>"The emergency would be worsened by the arrival of the thousands of tourists which arrive on Capri daily", he said.</p>

<p>Locals could collect up to 25 litres of drinking water per household from a supply tanker, he said.</p>

<p>The ban, which does not apply to residents, will be in place until further notice.</p>

<p>Capri, in the Bay of Naples, is famed for its white villas, cove-studded coastline and upscale hotels. There are some 13,000 permanent residents but huge numbers of day-trippers in summer months.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/elg1q4qo_capri-tourists_625x300_22_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ban, which does not apply to residents, will be in place until further notice.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>