<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:43:53 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/now-is-the-time-to-end-gaza-war-says-us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-6854535]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now Is The Time" To End Gaza War, Says US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/now-is-the-time-to-end-gaza-war-says-us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-6854535]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:31:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Wednesday "now is the time" to end the conflict in Gaza, and urged Israel to avoid further escalation with Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Wednesday "now is the time" to end the conflict in Gaza, and urged Israel to avoid further escalation with Iran.</p>

<p>Israel is fighting Iran-backed Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, and has pledged to hit back against Iran's October 1 missile strike.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, state media reported an Israeli drone strike on Tyre, after the military warned residents of parts of the coastal city to flee ahead of operations targeting Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The warning sparked a new exodus from the once vibrant city, which is perched on the Mediterranean coast, and AFPTV footage showed a plume of thick black smoke rising from the city after the strike.</p>

<p>"The situation is very bad, we're evacuating people," said Mortada Mhanna, who heads Tyre's disaster management unit.</p>

<p>"You could say that the entire city of Tyre is being evacuated," said Bilal Kashmar, the unit's media officer.</p>

<p>Blinken's visit to the region is his 11th since the start of the war in Gaza and his first since Israel-Hezbollah violence escalated to all-out war late last month.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began with Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed 42,718 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>"Since October 7 a year ago, Israel has achieved most of its strategic objectives when it comes to Gaza... Now is the time to turn those successes into enduring, strategic success," Blinken said as he left Israel, following meetings with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and other top officials.</p>

<p>On aid to Gaza, Blinken said he saw "progress being made, which is good, but more progress needs to be made and, most critically, it needs to be sustained".</p>

<p>Of Israel's pledge to retaliate for Iran's October 1 missile attack, the US top diplomat said: "It's also very important that Israel respond in ways that do not create greater escalation."</p>

<p>After Israel, Blinken will visit Saudi Arabia, which has put on hold talks towards a normalisation deal with Israel until a Palestinian state is created.</p>

<p>The US diplomat urged Israel to seize what he described as an "incredible opportunity" to move towards a deal with Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Previous US efforts to end the Gaza war and contain the regional fallout have failed, as did a bid spearheaded by President Joe Biden and his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron to secure a temporary ceasefire in Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>Hostages still in Gaza</strong></p>

<p>In his meeting with Netanyahu on Tuesday, Blinken urged his ally to seize on the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar in Gaza to work towards a ceasefire.</p>

<p>Sinwar was the architect of the October 7, 2023 attack that triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hailing his killing, Netanyahu said it did not mean the war was over, though he added that it could be the beginning of the end.</p>

<p>The militants also took 251 hostages back into Gaza. Ninety-seven are still being held there, including 34 the Israeli military has said are dead.</p>

<p>During his meeting with the Israeli premier in Jerusalem, Blinken "underscored the need to capitalise" on the death of Sinwar, US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said.</p>

<p>This would be done by "securing the release of all hostages and ending the conflict in Gaza in a way that provides lasting security for Israelis and Palestinians alike", he added.</p>

<p>Netanyahu told Blinken that Sinwar's death "could have a positive impact on the return of the hostages", according to a statement from the prime minister's office.</p>

<p>Blinken also pressed for more aid to be allowed into besieged Gaza as concerns rise for tens of thousands of civilians trapped by fighting in the hard-to-reach north.</p>

<p>Israel launched a major air and ground assault in northern Gaza this month, vowing to stop Hamas militants from regrouping in the area.</p>

<p>The only medical facility still partially functioning in the targeted area has "no medicine or medical supplies", warned Kamal Adwan Hospital director Hossam Abu Safia.</p>

<p>"People are being killed in the streets, and we can't help them. Bodies are lying on the streets."</p>

<p><strong>Hezbollah heir</strong></p>

<p>After nearly a year of war with Hamas in Gaza, Israel shifted its focus to Lebanon in late September, vowing to secure its northern border under fire from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel ramped up its air strikes on Hezbollah strongholds around the country and sent in ground troops late last month, in a war that has killed at least 1,552 people since September 23, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p>

<p>Hezbollah kept up its attacks on Israel Wednesday, saying it had fired rockets at an Israeli military intelligence base in the suburbs of commercial hub Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the Israeli army said it had killed the Hezbollah cleric tipped to succeed the group's slain leader Hassan Nasrallah in an air strike three weeks ago.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has not issued a statement confirming Hashem Safieddine's death, but a high-level source close to the group had said that the militant leader had been out of contact since the strikes.</p>

<p>"We have reached Nasrallah, his replacement and most of Hezbollah's senior leadership", Israeli army chief Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said in a statement.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the Israeli military again struck the southern suburbs of Beirut, a once densely populated bastion of Hezbollah, after issuing new calls for residents to evacuate the area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rngv1mh8_israel-hamas-war_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel is fighting Iran-backed Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/sikh-woman-employee-found-dead-inside-walk-in-oven-in-canada-walmart-6854421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sikh Woman Employee Found Dead Inside Walk-In Oven In Canada Walmart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/sikh-woman-employee-found-dead-inside-walk-in-oven-in-canada-walmart-6854421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:31:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 19-year-old Sikh woman was found dead inside a walk-in oven of the Walmart store's bakery department in Canada's Halifax city, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 19-year-old Sikh woman was found dead inside a walk-in oven of the Walmart store's bakery department in Canada's Halifax city, according to media reports.</p>

<p>Halifax Regional Police (HRP) said they were called to a sudden death at the Walmart at 6990 Mumford Road around 9:30 pm on Saturday.</p>

<p>According to police, the woman, who has not been identified, was employed at the store.</p>

<p>Her body was found in a walk-in oven, police said.</p>

<p>The Maritime Sikh Society confirmed to CTV News that she was a member of their community.</p>

<p>“It's very sad for us, for her family as well, because she came for a better future and she lost her life,” said Anmolpreet Singh, with the Maritime Sikh Society.</p>

<p>She had recently moved to Canada from India, The Globe and Mail newspaper said.</p>

<p>The store has remained closed since Saturday night while the investigation is ongoing.</p>

<p>HRP Constable Martin Cromwell said police were aware of online speculation about the woman's cause of death.</p>

<p>“The investigation is complex,” said Cromwell.</p>

<p>“We understand the public is involved, and we just wanted to encourage the public to be patient with our investigation and be mindful that there are family members and coworkers involved.” Cromwell said Halifax police were coordinating with the appropriate agencies to help with the investigation.</p>

<p>“We urge the public to be mindful of sharing speculative information on social media,” HRP said in a statement on Tuesday.</p>

<p>A spokeswoman for the province's labour department said a stop-work order has been issued for the bakery and “one piece of equipment” at the Walmart store.</p>

<p>“It is important to note that the investigation has not yet reached a point where the cause and manner of death have been confirmed,” HRP said.</p>

<p>Nova Scotia's medical examiner is working to determine the cause of death, and the province's Department of Health and Safety is taking part in the investigation.</p>

<p>Walk-in ovens, also referred to as cabinet or batch ovens, allow for curing, drying or baking in batches using wheeled racks or carts. They are often found in large-volume bakeries in places such as supermarkets.</p>

<p>In a statement, Walmart Canada said the company is heartbroken and their thoughts are with the woman's family.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/90a6u5v_walmart_625x300_05_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to police, the woman, who has not been identified, was employed at the store.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-west-master-of-espionage-must-shun-its-double-standards-6854501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: With CIA And Mossad, West Shouldn't Lecture Others On Espionage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-west-master-of-espionage-must-shun-its-double-standards-6854501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:29:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From the CIA's colossal resources and Mossad's precision strikes to MI6s legacy of colonial espionage and RAW's rising influence, these agencies navigate the murky waters of international politics anddiplomacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hrlt7l28_spy_625x300_23_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On a blustery, cold January day in 2011 in Lahore, a CIA contractor and former US Special Forces operative was driving through a busy street when two motorcyclists who allegedly attempted to rob him—or that is what he claimed—were shot and killed by him. In the ensuing chaos, he hit another car, got caught and was promptly charged with murder. You might think this was a minor incident, but Washington didn't.</p>

<p>Davis was hardly a big fish in the CIA pond, yet the Obama administration threw a diplomatic tantrum generally typical of a superpower. Diplomatic relations and the $2 billion in annual aid to Pakistan were frozen. The US falsely claimed Davis was a diplomat, deserving immunity. Pakistan's investigation showed he was a Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) operative and therefore wasn't covered by diplomatic immunity. Initially, it refused to back down despite the political heat.</p>

<p>In the end, after a 50-day standoff, Davis was whisked back to the US, but not before $2.34 million of blood money exchanged hands, reportedly compensating the victims' families. He later wrote about this cloak-and-dagger saga in his 2016 book&nbsp;<i>The Contractor: How I Landed in Pakistan's Deadliest Jail and Then Escaped</i>, revealing how the CIA operates when things get messy.</p>

<h2><strong>CIA's Long Arms</strong></h2>

<p>The Raymond Davis affair revealed how deeply the CIA was operating in Pakistan's backyard, raising public anger about America's covert meddling in a country it called an "ally" in the war on terror. The Pakistanis felt betrayed by their trusted ally.</p>

<p>This brings us to the present: the CIA, the agency behind countless covert operations all around the world, lectures India on cooperating with Canada over Hardeep Singh Nijjar's assassination. It's as if the US forgot it's been running around the world in the shadows since the CIA's inception in 1947, toppling governments, orchestrating coups, and assassinating foreign leaders—all in the name of national interest. But let's not dwell on the hypocrisy or "double standards", as India's foreign minister S. Jaishankar put it in a recent interview with&nbsp;<i>NDTV</i>. He didn't hold back in calling out Canada's double standards and pointed out how it is quick to gather intel through its diplomats on foreign soil but becomes very protective when it comes to limiting similar activities by diplomats from other nations on its own turf.</p>

<p>Indeed, while Canada plays the victim, it conveniently turns a blind eye to the unchecked privileges its own diplomats enjoy in India. Jaishankar, ever direct, put it plainly: "Double standards is a very mild word for it." His pointed remark wasn't just a dig at Canada's hypocrisy but also an indictment of the wider Western duplicity.</p>

<p>Take the recent case of the US charging former Indian intelligence agent Vikas Yadav with being involved in a plot to assassinate Sikh separatist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun in New York. Now, imagine if the tables were turned. Would the US sit quietly? Absolutely not. By now, Washington would have launched a full-scale diplomatic offensive to bring its man home, just like it did in the above-mentioned case of Davis. And if this led to a potential diplomatic row, so be it. The hypocrisy is so obvious.</p>

<h2><strong>West's Unquestioned Hypocrisy</strong></h2>

<p>In the murky realm of espionage, agencies like the CIA, Mossad and MI6 have always played by their own rules, causing diplomatic rifts, regime changes and the occasional assassinations. But when the tables turn, if at all, well, it's all about the rule of law and international cooperation. I do not suggest the Indian spy agency RAW is doing what the likes of CIA, Mossad and MI6 have been doing for decades without being questioned by anyone. The US, for instance, never lectured Israel for Mossad's countless extraterritorial activities overseas. India is cooperating with the US in the Vikas Yadav case. It wants to cooperate with Canada in its investigation of Hardeep Singh Nijjar's murder upon receipt of credible evidence.</p>

<p>Jaishankar's view isn't just an Indian perspective—countries across the Global South, and even some in the West, are getting increasingly fed up with the blatant foreign policy double standards.</p>

<h2><strong>'Ajax' To 'Condor', CIA's Myriad Assassination Plots</strong></h2>

<p>The US government's own report on assassination plots involving foreign leaders reveals some shocking truths about the CIA's covert operations overseas. The report&nbsp;<i>Alleged Assassination Plots Involving Foreign Leaders</i>&nbsp;wasn't fully declassified and released until July 23, 2002. The report, also known as the Church Committee report, investigated alleged CIA assassination plots against foreign leaders, including Cuba's Fidel Castro and Congo's Patrice Lumumba. The report also mentions other foreign leaders who were targeted for assassination, although their names were not disclosed.</p>

<p>Despite the White House's efforts to bury the report, the Church Committee conducted a thorough investigation into the CIA's assassination plots. It confirmed the CIA's involvement in these plots and recommended legislation to prohibit assassinations. The reports also raised important questions about the ethics and legality of targeted killings, which remain relevant today. And yet, the CIA often disregards its rule books and ethical standards.</p>

<p>Some of its notable plots were&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Operation Ajax (1953)</strong>: Successfully overthrew Iranian Prime Minister Mohammad Mosaddegh, consolidating Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi's power. This was a joint operation between the CIA and Britain's MI6.&nbsp;</li>
	<li><strong>Bay of Pigs Invasion (1961): </strong>Failed to overthrow Cuban leader Fidel Castro, resulting in embarrassment to the US and loss of life.</li>
	<li><strong>Operation Condor (1970s-1980s):</strong> Supported Latin American dictatorships in eliminating leftist opposition, leading to human rights abuses.</li>
</ul>

<p>In more recent times, the CIA's extraterritorial actions in the Middle East, especially during the ‘War on Terror', have had long-term destabilising effects. US drone strikes, covert actions in Pakistan, Yemen and Somalia and operations in Iraq and Afghanistan have sometimes led to increased radicalisation. While these operations are aimed at counterterrorism, the resulting instability often fuels new cycles of violence and anti-American sentiment.</p>

<h2><strong>Mossad's Misdemeanours</strong></h2>

<p>Many experts in the West are bracing for a fiery Israeli strike on Iran in response to Tehran's October 1 missile attack. But here's the catch—it may not come from the skies at all. Instead of sending jets and missiles, Israel could very well stick to its trusted playbook: cyberattacks or political assassinations. After all, these methods have proven highly effective in the past, often executed with the help of local assets within Iran. So, while everyone waits for a military show of force, Israel might be quietly sharpening its digital knives or preparing for another covert strike that leaves no fingerprints but sends a very loud message.</p>

<p>It is widely believed, and not disputed by Israel, that Mossad has been actively involved in covert operations inside Iran for years, particularly targeting Iran's nuclear programme. One might recall the cyberattack using the Stuxnet virus, which disrupted uranium enrichment in 2010. In 2018, Mossad is believed to have stolen 55,000 pages of documents and 183 CDs from Iran's nuclear archives, revealing the country's nuclear programme details.</p>

<p>However, Mossad's most high-profile and controversial actions have been the assassinations of Iranian nuclear scientists. These operations are believed to be part of a broader Israeli strategy to delay or dismantle Iran's nuclear capabilities, which Israel sees as an existential threat. Between 2010 and 2012, at least five Iranian nuclear scientists were assassinated in Tehran in a series of precision attacks that many attributed to Mossad. Israel has not commented on them. The most notable method involved motorcyclists attaching magnetic bombs to the victims' cars during busy commutes. The victims included Majid Shahriari, a key figure in Iran's nuclear research, and Mostafa Ahmadi Roshan, a prominent scientist at Iran's Natanz nuclear facility. These killings sent shockwaves through Iran's scientific community, severely damaging its nuclear programme and provoking outrage from Tehran, which accused Israel and the West of orchestrating the murders.</p>

<h2><strong>The Strikes On Iran's Nuclear Ambitions</strong></h2>

<p>The most striking assassination occurred in 2020 when Mohsen Fakhrizadeh, considered the father of Iran's nuclear weapons programme, was killed in a highly sophisticated operation. Reports suggested the use of a satellite-controlled machine gun to eliminate Fakhrizadeh near Tehran. This assassination was a major blow to Iran's nuclear ambitions. Mossad's operations inside Iran demonstrate the agency's deep penetration into the country and its relentless efforts to undermine Iran's nuclear ambitions.</p>

<p>Iranian secret agents have also been active against Israel, with the Israeli government successfully foiling Iranian plots to assassinate Israelis in Israel, Cyprus and elsewhere.</p>

<h2><strong>MI6 And Its Legacy Spy Network</strong></h2>

<p>The United Kingdom, as the original colonial power, practically wrote the book on covert operations. MI6, founded in 1909 as the Empire's main Secret Intelligence Service, was tasked with protecting British interests worldwide—sometimes by any means necessary. One of its most infamous escapades was its role in the 1953 coup against Iran's Prime Minister Mohammad Mossadegh, a man who dared to nationalise Iran's oil, threatening Britain's golden pipeline. As mentioned above, the MI6 teamed up with the CIA for Operation Ajax, toppling Mossadegh and reinstalling the Shah, whose authoritarian reign would last until the 1979 revolution.</p>

<p>In more recent times, especially during the early 2000s, MI6 found itself embroiled in another scandal, this time involving Libya. Partnering again with the CIA, MI6 was accused of helping to render Libyan dissidents back to Gaddafi's regime, where they were tortured. The most prominent case was that of Abdel Hakim Belhaj, an opposition leader kidnapped and sent to Libya allegedly with MI6's help. After years of legal battles, Belhaj won an apology from Prime Minister Theresa May in 2018.</p>

<h2><strong>India's RAW Power</strong></h2>

<p>India's Research and Analysis Wing (RAW) was established in 1968 as the nation's primary external intelligence agency. While RAW has gained significant prominence within the global intelligence community, its capabilities still trail behind those of the CIA, Mossad, and MI6. With a reported budget of around $700 million, RAW operates on a fraction of the resources available to the CIA, whose budget hovers between $18-20 billion. Its main mandate is national security, with a sharp focus on counterterrorism—disrupting terror outfits, cutting off funding to extremists, and monitoring state enemies abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Contrary to popular belief, RAW does not operate with unchecked power. Its operations are governed by strict directives from the Indian government and, at least on paper, must adhere to Indian laws. While RAW plays a crucial role in safeguarding the nation, it is by no means a rogue agency; it works within the limits of its mandate, with each mission requiring government approval.</p>

<p>From the CIA's colossal resources and Mossad's precision strikes to MI6's legacy of colonial espionage and RAW's rising influence, these agencies navigate the murky waters of international politics and&nbsp;diplomacy.&nbsp;Yet, they remain indispensable tools of statecraft in an increasingly complex world.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gtq0m7hg_spy_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/american-billionaires-cliffside-mansion-is-up-for-sale-for-108-million-6853683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Billionaire's Cliffside Mansion Is Up For Sale For  $108 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/american-billionaires-cliffside-mansion-is-up-for-sale-for-108-million-6853683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:57:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Darwin Deason's estate spans nearly 13,000 square feet and features stone columns, balconies and a private elevated beach. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American businessman Darwin Deason's La Jolla estate, ‘The Sandcastle', has been listed for $108 million, a potential record-breaking price for San Diego County real estate. If sold at the asking price, it would surpass the current record of $44 million, held by billionaire Egon Durban, who bought a Del Mar oceanfront property earlier this year.<br />
<br />
Mr Deason's estate spans nearly 13,000 square feet and features stone columns, balconies and a private elevated beach. The interior is inspired by old-world Europe, with gold accents, marble floors and mosaics. The guest house is modelled after Versailles's Le Petit Trianon. The billionaire, who founded Affiliated Computer Services and sold it to Xerox for over $6 billion in 2009, purchased the estate and a neighbouring parcel for $26 million that same year. He has since invested an estimated $60 million into its construction.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ltr1845g_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Mr Deason enlisted renowned designer Timothy Corrigan, who has designed for Hollywood elites and royalty, to craft the interiors. Designed with French elegance and inspired by the Hotel du Cap-Eden-Roc in Antibes, the estate features custom-made furnishings, a dining room that seats 16 and a nautically themed bar. The grounds include a pool, fitness centre and a beachfront boathouse with slate roof tiles imported from China.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k05eqvog_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Mr Deason also brought in $40,000 of imported sand to match Augusta National Golf Club's signature white shade. “Everyone who watches the golf tournament knows it is a spectacular shade of white,” he told <a href="https://www.wsj.com/real-estate/luxury-homes/a-billionaire-built-a-cliffside-version-of-versailles-now-its-asking-108-million-848fbaaa?mod=real-estate_lead_story" rel="nofollow,noindex">The Wall Street Journal</a>, which first reported the listing. The property also includes two natural caves at its base.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/njgk5jf8_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Despite the lavish design, Mr Deason, a Dallas-based businessman, says he doesn't use the property as much as his other homes. “In the history of La Jolla, there has never been and will never be another property built on the waterfront like The Sandcastle due to the present oceanfront construction standards established by the State of California,” agents Brett Dickinson and Ross Clark from Compass said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/50k3etlo_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The home features old-world European-inspired interiors.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-ex-lawyer-asked-to-hand-over-valuables-manhattan-apartment-6853688]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Ex Lawyer Asked To Hand Over Valuables, Manhattan Apartment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-ex-lawyer-asked-to-hand-over-valuables-manhattan-apartment-6853688]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:33:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A judge instructed Rudy Giuliani, Donald Trump's former personal lawyer, to turn over valuables and his luxury Manhattan apartment on Tuesday to two election workers he was found to have defamed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A judge instructed Rudy Giuliani, Donald Trump's former personal lawyer, to turn over valuables and his luxury Manhattan apartment on Tuesday to two election workers he was found to have defamed.</p>

<p>In December 2023, a federal jury in Washington ordered him to pay $148 million to Ruby Freeman and her daughter Wandrea "Shaye" Moss for repeatedly making false claims that they engaged in 2020 election fraud.</p>

<p>Mr Giuliani was found liable in 2023 by US District Judge Beryl Howell of defaming Freeman and Moss, both Fulton County poll workers, with his 2020 election lies on behalf of former president Trump.</p>

<p>An eight-person federal jury awarded Freeman and Moss more than $16 million each for defamation, $20 million each for emotional distress and $75 million in punitive damages.</p>

<p>Mr Giuliani filed for bankruptcy in December 2023 over the order.</p>

<p>"Defendant is ordered... to transfer all personal property specified in the list below... including cash accounts, jewelry and valuables, a legal claim for unpaid attorneys' fees, and his interest in his Madison Avenue co-op apartment," according to a Manhattan court filing.</p>

<p>Mr Giuliani has seven days to make the transfer to a receivership under the control of Freeman and Moss, it said.</p>

<p>The former mayor of New York, who led Trump's legal efforts to overturn the results of the election, posted a video of Freeman and Moss that falsely accused them of engaging in fraud during ballot counting and made numerous other baseless claims about them.</p>

<p>Freeman and Moss, who are Black, told the jury during the defamation trial that Mr Giuliani's false accusations had upended their lives and made them the target of racist threats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lsv4qh5g_rudy-giuliani-afp_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-china-lac-pact-will-beijings-words-match-its-actions-6853622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: LAC Pact: Will China's Words Match Its Actions?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-china-lac-pact-will-beijings-words-match-its-actions-6853622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:27:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For Indians at large, the question still remains whether China indeed wants to move towards a lasting solution to the boundary dispute, or whether this is another tactical attempt at buying time as both China and India continue their ascent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fe70pjro_china_625x300_23_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>India and China have decided to bury the hatchet, almost and for now. As a result, there will be a bilateral meeting between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping today on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Kazan, Russia. In a major breakthrough that can potentially end the over four-year-long military standoff, the two neighbours have reached an agreement on patrolling along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh "leading to disengagement."</p>

<p>While the militaries of the two nations had already pulled back from four of six friction points in eastern Ladakh, including the Galwan Valley, the site of a violent clash in June 2020, the latest pact pertains to patrolling in Depsang and Demchok areas. With this, External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar confirmed that the agreement on border patrols signalled that "the disengagement process with China has been completed".</p>

<h2><strong>A Long-Drawn Conflict</strong></h2>

<p>The two formidable military forces have been locked in an eyeball-to-eyeball confrontation since May 2020, with New Delhi making it clear that there cannot be any normalcy in the bilateral relationship till the situation is not restored to pre-2020 status at the Line of Actual Control (LAC). The Galwan incident of June 15, 2020, which was the most serious military conflict between the two sides in decades and the deadliest since the 1962 war, resulted in India losing 20 soldiers and the PLA losing as many as 40 personnel, even though China has acknowledged only four casualties.</p>

<p>This has been a major inflexion point in Indian policy towards China as well as the wider geopolitical churn shaping the Indo-Pacific. New Delhi dramatically recalibrated its ties with Beijing across a full range of sectors and mobilised at a national level to take the China challenge head-on. From foreign policy to economy, from infrastructure to people-to-people engagement, a re-appraisal was undertaken and a recalibration was the result. China's belligerence was met with an unprecedented Indian resoluteness as a whole-of-government approach exemplified a newfound willingness in New Delhi to not shy away from taking difficult decisions.</p>

<h2><strong>India Is More Prepared Now</strong></h2>

<p>And it is this resolve by New Delhi that seems to have paid off with the agreement on disengagement. There are lots of issues that remain shrouded in secrecy and will only reveal themselves once the details of the new pact are out. As India looks for a return to status quo ante, the massive infrastructure that China has created along the border with India is unlikely to disappear any time soon. What has happened, as a result, however, is that India has managed to get its act together on the infrastructure front as well. So, unlike the pre-May 2020 period, Indian logistical presence along the border is much stronger, and, hopefully, there won't be any let up in its building up of its own infrastructure on its side of the border.</p>

<p>The other issue is related to how China is perceived in India now. Whatever the diplomatese, the reality remains that trust in Beijing, which was already low, seems to have completely disappeared not only in the Indian political establishment but also in the society at large. It is for China now to rebuild that trust, not through its words but by its actions. Repeated violations of agreements have now led to a new reality where any new pact with China will struggle to regain legitimacy in the eyes of ordinary Indians, making the job of Indian diplomats even harder. After all, there was an attempt to create a 'Wuhan spirit' after the Doklam debacle, only to lead to Galwan!</p>

<h2><strong>Can China Accept India As A Peer?</strong></h2>

<p>Moreover, while the latest agreement can be the starting point for rebuilding confidence between the two neighbours, the border problem is a manifestation of a wider issue facing Sino-Indian relations. The two rising powers are now structural rivals, and the inability of China to accept India as a peer or to be sensitive to New Delhi's core security concerns has been at the heart of deteriorating ties between the two Asian giants. This latest agreement does nothing to alter that reality.</p>

<p>For Indians at large, the question still remains whether China indeed wants to move towards a lasting solution to the boundary dispute, or whether this is another tactical attempt at buying time as both China and India continue their ascent in the global interstate hierarchy. Nonetheless, what is clear is that New Delhi's resolve in frontally challenging China's expansionism has paid off. Even as India would be engaging with China after the latest agreement, it would be worth remembering that there is no substitute for building inherent capacity and leveraging external partnerships to effectively manage a potentially malevolent China.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V. Pant is Vice President – Studies and Foreign Policy, at Observer Research Foundation, and Professor of International Relations at King's College London.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dh5bnqko_china_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-ukraine-trade-europes-jitters-ahead-of-us-elections-2024-6853592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO, Ukraine, Trade: Europe's Jitters Ahead Of US Elections 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-ukraine-trade-europes-jitters-ahead-of-us-elections-2024-6853592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:21:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has threatened to upend NATO, cut a quick deal with Russia over Ukraine and impose trade tariffs if he wins November's presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>European nations are nervously eyeing the nail-biting US election that will bring the radically different approach of either Donald Trump or Kamala Harris to the White House.</p>

<p>Trump has threatened to upend NATO, cut a quick deal with Russia over Ukraine and impose trade tariffs if he wins November's presidential election.</p>

<p>Harris has stressed the importance of NATO and decried Trump's tariffs as a hidden sales tax.</p>

<p>It is no secret that most European officials would prefer the more predictable Democratic vice president rather than the volatile Republican take the reins at such a perilous moment.</p>

<p>Ahead of the ballot, here are some of the biggest worries for Europe:</p>

<p><strong>NATO</strong></p>

<p>Trump unleashed a firestorm on the campaign trail by saying he would encourage Russia to do "whatever the hell" it wants with NATO members not spending enough on defence.</p>

<p>The broadside was the latest from the ex-reality TV star to rattle the alliance that has underpinned Europe's security for 75 years.</p>

<p>Having already weathered four years of Trump in charge, NATO diplomats insist the nightmare prospect of Washington pulling out remains distant.</p>

<p>To head off his criticism, European nations have played up their increased defence spending since Moscow's 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>This year 23 of NATO's 32 members are set to hit the target of 2 percent of GDP -- up from three a decade ago.</p>

<p>"It's a Trumpian way of doing business, it's the way he says it, but it's a totally reasonable message on the necessity for Europe to do more," said one European diplomat.</p>

<p>If Harris wins, the tone towards NATO is set to be notably warmer. She has echoed President Joe Biden's pledge to stand strong with US allies.</p>

<p>But even under Harris, European countries expect major pressure to keep increasing defence spending.</p>

<p>And as the United States increasingly focuses on its rivalry with China, there is a sense that either way Europe will have to take more responsibility for its security in the long run.</p>

<p><strong>Ukraine</strong></p>

<p>While European officials are hopeful they could talk Trump down from undermining NATO, there are more questions swirling over US backing for Ukraine.</p>

<p>The United States and EU nations have given the bulk of support for Kyiv in a fight many in Europe see as an existential struggle for the continent's security.</p>

<p>While European countries combined have provided some $130 billion, Washington alone has come up with $90 billion, according to a tracker from the Kiel Institute.</p>

<p>Former president Trump has cast doubt on US help for Ukraine and insists he could do a deal with Russian leader Vladimir Putin to end the war in one day.</p>

<p>European officials say that should Trump pull the plug they would try to keep Ukraine afloat, but that would likely only keep Kyiv going until it was forced to accept a deal.</p>

<p>"But I'm not sure Trump will withdraw. He could call Putin, not get the deal he wants and decide to fully support Ukraine, said one diplomat. "You never know with him."</p>

<p>Like Biden, Harris has pledged to maintain Washington's firm backing for Kyiv.</p>

<p>But European diplomats say that she likely will not be as personally invested as Biden, and as the war drags on into a third year calls to end it somehow will grow.</p>

<p><strong>Trade</strong></p>

<p>The EU believes this time it will be battle-ready if Trump wins and follows through on threats to impose tariffs on imports to the United States.</p>

<p>The European Commission, the EU's executive arm in charge of trade policy, has set up a team to ready plans for a Harris or Trump win.</p>

<p>"The EU is much better prepared for another Trump administration," an EU diplomat said.</p>

<p>The team is however preparing for different scenarios and "unlike last time, we have various trade tools", the diplomat said.</p>

<p>There has been much talk of a "list" of US products the EU could slap tariffs on, but European officials and diplomats insist this would be a last-resort measure.</p>

<p>The first test for the EU and the United States under any new administration will be in March, when a truce relating to US steel and aluminium tariffs expires.</p>

<p>Trump in 2018 slapped high duties on steel and aluminium coming from many countries, sweeping up EU exports in the process. When Biden came to power, he kept the tariffs in place but granted suspensions for EU exporters.</p>

<p>Brussels fears Trump will impose higher tariffs while Harris, although unlikely to be soft, would maintain "dialogue in good faith", the EU diplomat said.</p>

<p>"There'll be a continued focus on trying to find those areas of cooperation, trying to avoid unnecessary conflict under a Harris administration," said Greta Peisch, a former General Counsel for the US Trade Representative.</p>

<p>Peisch, now a partner at US law firm Wiley, told AFP Harris would represent a "continuation" of Biden's administration, noting that under Trump, it could be more complicated.</p>

<p>"I think that there were areas of cooperation, but in the Trump administration, there was also more of a willingness to be confrontational on trade issues."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/njs5i84o_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_08_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[European nations are nervously eyeing the nail-biting US election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/300-million-year-old-fossils-reveal-what-worlds-biggest-arthropod-looked-like-6853387]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[300-Million-Year-Old Fossils Reveal What World's Biggest Arthropod Looked Like]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/300-million-year-old-fossils-reveal-what-worlds-biggest-arthropod-looked-like-6853387]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:18:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The giant arthropod 'Arthropleura', which roamed the Earth over 300 million years ago, combined traits of millipedes and centipedes, new fossils have revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The giant arthropod ‘Arthropleura', which roamed the Earth over 300 million years ago, combined traits of millipedes and centipedes, new fossils have revealed. These fossils, from juvenile specimens, were found in France and have finally solved a nearly 200-year-old mystery about the creature's head structure. It also offers fresh insights into its lifestyle and evolutionary relationships.</p>

<p>Arthropods, a diverse group of invertebrates, are known for their segmented bodies, jointed legs and exoskeletons. This group includes insects, crustaceans, and arachnids, but Arthropleura holds a particularly important place in history as the largest arthropod ever to live on Earth.</p>

<p>First discovered in Great Britain in 1854, fossils of Arthropleura showed that adults could reach a massive 8.5 feet in length. However, until now, no fossils with preserved heads were found, making it difficult to determine whether Arthropleura was a predator like centipedes or a detritivore like modern millipedes.</p>

<p>This recent discovery, detailed in the journal <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.adp6362 " rel="nofollow,noindex">Science Advances</a>&nbsp;on October 9, is considered a breakthrough. Using advanced scanning techniques such as micro-computed tomography and synchrotron imagery, researchers analysed the fossils encased in stone without damaging them. The scans revealed intricate details, including antennae, mandibles, eyes and feeding structures.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to Dr Greg Edgecombe, a palaeontologist at London's Natural History Museum, “Millipedes and centipedes are actually each other's closest relative,” a point illustrated by the features found in the Arthropleura fossils.</p>

<p>The findings suggest that Arthropleura likely wasn't a predator. With no venom fangs or specialised predatory legs, the creature probably lived a lifestyle similar to modern detritus-eating millipedes. “They were probably more like the detritus-eating millipedes alive today,” Mr Edgecombe added.</p>

<p>The creature's stalked eyes – more commonly seen in aquatic arthropods like crabs – raise the possibility that it may have lived a partially amphibious life. “Today, stalked eyes are a typical feature of aquatic arthropods like crabs or shrimps,” explained Mickael Lheritier, lead author of the study. Future discoveries, particularly of its respiratory system, could further shed light on Arthropleura's connection to water, he said.</p>

<p>James C. Lamsdell, a geology professor at West Virginia University, praised the discovery, noting that these “remarkable findings” offer a new understanding of this long-extinct giant.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/02o5mkrg_arthropleura-istock_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The arthropod Arthropleura is the largest known arthropod ever to inhabit the Earth.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-11-000-artists-issue-unlicensed-use-of-artificial-intelligence-warning-6853225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Major, Unjust Threat": 11,000 Artists On "Unlicensed Use" Of AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-11-000-artists-issue-unlicensed-use-of-artificial-intelligence-warning-6853225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 11:35:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of artists have signed a statement warning about the unlicensed use of artificial intelligence. The statement was organized by British composer and former AI executive Ed Newton-Rex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Thousands of artists including ABBA singer Bjorn Ulvaeus, Hollywood actress Julianne Moore and Nobel laureate Kazuo Ishiguro have signed a statement warning about the unlicensed use of artificial intelligence.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Some 11,500 stars of music, literature, screen and stage had put their names to the&nbsp;statement by Tuesday, as fears mount over tech companies using existing creative works to train up AI models without permission from their original creators.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"The unlicensed use of creative works for training generative AI is a major, unjust threat to the livelihoods of the people behind those works, and must not be permitted," says the brief statement.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">In Hollywood, studios have been experimenting with AI in recent years, from bringing late movie stars back using realistic "digital replicas," to using computer-generated background figures to reduce the number of actors needed for battle scenes.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Similar fears have gripped other creative industries.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">The statement was organized by British composer and former AI executive Ed Newton-Rex, the Guardian reported.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Newton-Rex told the newspaper that generative AI companies including his former employer Stability AI were using copyrighted contented to train their models without paying the original creators.&nbsp;</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">"When AI companies call this 'training data,' they dehumanize it. What we're talking about is people's work -- their writing, their art, their music," he said.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Last year, authors including John Grisham, Jodi Picoult and George RR Martin sued OpenAI for "systematic theft on a mass scale."</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Hollywood stars including Pedro Pascal, Jane Fonda and Mark Hamill last month backed a sweeping AI safety bill in California that was ultimately vetoed by Governor Gavin Newsom.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Other artists have chosen to collaborate with AI.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Facebook owner Meta last week announced that Hollywood actor Casey Affleck and horror studio Blumhouse were partnering to test its AI movie generating software by making a series of short films.</p>

<p data-olk-copy-source="MessageBody">Among other famous signatories to Monday's statement were Radiohead singer Thom Yorke, author James Patterson and actor Kevin Bacon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3928vl9_artificial-intelligence-_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fears mount over tech companies using existing creative works to train up AI models without permission]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/despite-donald-trumps-hate-for-taylor-swift-ivanka-trump-attends-her-concert-6852975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Despite Donald Trump's "Hate" For Taylor Swift, Ivanka Attends Her Concert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/despite-donald-trumps-hate-for-taylor-swift-ivanka-trump-attends-her-concert-6852975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 11:26:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ivanka Trump took her 13-year-old daughter, Arabella, along with her friends to the Taylor Swift concert in Miami, despite her father, Donald Trump, once publicly declaring he hated the 14-time Grammy Award-winner.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ivanka Trump took her 13-year-old daughter, Arabella, along with her friends to the Taylor Swift concert in Miami, despite her father, Donald Trump, once publicly declaring he hated the 14-time Grammy Award-winner.</p>

<p>The singer's Eras Tour was in Miami at the Hard Rock Stadium over the weekend. Among the famous names in the crowd was Ivanka “to see one of her daughter's favourite artists,” sources told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://pagesix.com/2024/10/22/entertainment/ivanka-trump-takes-daughter-to-taylor-swifts-eras-tour-in-miami/" rel="nofollow,noindex">Page Six</a>.</p>

<p>Their outing comes weeks after Swift endorsed US Vice President and Democratic candidate Kamala Harris for the November 5 US presidential election, prompting Donald Trump to issue a statement on social media that read, “I HATE TAYLOR SWIFT!”</p>

<p>Arabella, who celebrates her birthday in July, earlier showed her love for Swift through a theme-based birthday cake decorated with lyrics from the 2014 single Blank Space -- 'Boys only want love if it's torture.'</p>

<p>Earlier, Ivanka shared a few photographs from her daughter's birthday party on Instagram. In one of the images, she wrote, "Best cake for my favourite Swiftie”.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9iWeoohSA2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9iWeoohSA2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9iWeoohSA2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C9iWeoohSA2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Ivanka Trump (@ivankatrump)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>On September 11, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shell-pay-for-it-says-donald-trump-after-taylor-swift-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6542169">Swift extended support to Harris</a> in a lengthy post on Instagram. "I will be casting my vote for Kamala Harris and Tim Walz in the 2024 Presidential Election. I'm voting for @kamalaharris because she fights for the rights and causes I believe need a warrior to champion them," she wrote, adding that Harris is "steady-handed, gifted leader and I believe we can accomplish so much more in this country if we are led by calm and not chaos."</p>

<p>In her viral post, she also called out the fake AI image of herself endorsing Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"Recently I was made aware that AI of ‘me' falsely endorsing Donald Trump's presidential run was posted to his site. It really conjured up my fears around AI and the dangers of spreading misinformation," she said.</p>

<p>Swift signed off her post as “Childless cat lady”, taking a dig at Trump's running mate JD Vance. Her endorsement post came after Trump and Harris' presidential debate last month.</p>

<p>Responding to Swift's support for Harris, Trump said in an interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/trump-says-taylor-swift-endorsing-harris-just-question-time" rel="nofollow,noindex">Fox &amp; Friends</a>, "I was not a Taylor Swift fan... It was just a question of time... But she's a very liberal person. She seems to always endorse a Democrat. And she'll probably pay a price for it in the marketplace."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ugnlka3o_ivanka-trump-daughter-arabella-instagram_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ivanka Trump took her daughter Arabella to Taylor Swift's concert. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/injecting-diamond-dust-into-atmosphere-could-cool-the-planet-study-6852779]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Injecting Diamond Dust Into Atmosphere May Cool Down The Planet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/injecting-diamond-dust-into-atmosphere-could-cool-the-planet-study-6852779]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 11:13:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the climate crisis deepens, scientists have been pondering ways to cool the planet]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the climate crisis deepens, scientists have been pondering ways to cool the planet. A new study proposes to spray millions of tonnes of diamond dust in the Earth's upper atmosphere every year to cool it down. The study, published in <a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2024GL110575" rel="nofollow,noindex">Geophysical Research Letters</a> journal, was conducted by a multi-institutional team of climatologists, meteorologists and Earth scientists. The team found evidence based on 3D climate models that compared aerosols that may be utilised to cool the planet.</p>

<p>Prior studies suggested that Earth was at or nearing its tipping point, causing significant changes to global weather patterns. With time, the planet will continue to grow warmer.</p>

<p>Experts, therefore, have argued the only solution to this issue is cooling the planet. Among other suggestions, scientists have also advised deploying millions of devices to pull carbon from the air that could later be sequestered.</p>

<p>However, a problem with this idea is that if the Earth has already reached its tipping point, simply removing carbon from the air won't help. Scientists will have to look out for ways to not just put a brake on warming but also to actively cool down the planet, Phys.org reported.</p>

<p>The latest proposed solution is injecting aerosols into the atmosphere. It will reflect heat and sunlight into the space.</p>

<p>To find a solution, the team of researchers in their latest study tried to look for material that could best serve as the best medium to cool the planet.</p>

<p>For this, they came up with the idea of building a 3D climate model, showing the impact of spreading aerosols into the atmosphere. This also included effects of different aerosols such as light and heat reflection, meaning how it would eventually settle to the ground and whether these aerosols would clump together in the atmosphere, thereby retaining more heat.</p>

<p>In their study, the team modeled the impact on the Earth of injections of calcite, silicon carbide, diamond, aluminum, anatase, rutile and sulfur dioxide.</p>

<p>Ultimately, they concluded that diamond dust was the best option because its particles go on to reflect the most light and heat, besides staying aloft for a longer duration. Another positive side of it is that since they are chemically inert, they may not react to form acid rain.</p>

<p>In their study, the researchers found that the Earth could be cooled down by at least 1.6 degree Celsius in 45 years if 5 million tons of synthetic diamond dust is injected into the atmosphere. A downside, though, is that it will cost approximately $200 trillion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-09/o1q6dpco_diamonds_625x300_19_September_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A downside, though, is that it will cost approximately $200 trillion.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-absolutely-ready-for-first-woman-president-kamala-harris-6853027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US "Absolutely" Ready For First Woman President: Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-absolutely-ready-for-first-woman-president-kamala-harris-6853027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 11:06:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris said Tuesday that America is "absolutely" ready to elect its first woman president but downplayed her historic bid, saying she simply wants to turn the page for a nation "exhausted" by Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris said Tuesday that America is "absolutely" ready to elect its first woman president but downplayed her historic bid, saying she simply wants to turn the page for a nation "exhausted" by Donald Trump.</p>

<p>With two weeks to Election Day, Harris and Trump are saturating swing states with rallies and taking to the airwaves and podcasts on the hunt for an advantage in a race that polls suggest is effectively tied.</p>

<p>Speaking on the national NBC network, Harris responded "absolutely" when asked if America was ready to elect its first woman -- but also noted her candidacy was about "turning the page."</p>

<p>"People are exhausted with Donald Trump and his approach, because it's all about himself," she said.</p>

<p>Trump, speaking to supporters in North Carolina, pitched a very different message.</p>

<p>"This election is a choice between whether we will have four more years of incompetence, failure and disaster, or whether we'll begin the four greatest years in the history of our country," he said to cheers.</p>

<p>He repeatedly called Harris and her running mate Tim Walz stupid during the rally.</p>

<p><strong>'Lock him up'</strong></p>

<p>The race is overshadowed by extraordinary tensions and fears of violence or a refusal by Trump to recognize the results if he loses, as he continues to do over his 2020 loss to Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Harris told NBC that her campaign was "of course" ready for a scenario where Trump prematurely claims victory during a vote-counting process that could take days to complete.</p>

<p>Biden, who has been an infrequent presence in Harris's campaign, took a shot at Trump Tuesday by re-wording the ex-president's notorious anti-Hillary Clinton chant of "Lock her up".</p>

<p>On a visit to New Hampshire, Biden told a small crowd that "we got to lock" Trump up –- adding quickly, "politically lock him up."</p>

<p>With Trump facing multiple pending criminal charges as he competes against Harris to succeed Biden, the White House has been very careful not to weigh in on the Republican's legal problems.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign responded that Biden and Harris had a "plan all along... to politically persecute their opponent."</p>

<p>About 18 million Americans have already voted by mail or in person -- representing more than 10 percent of the total in 2020.</p>

<p>Some polls appear to be giving the Republican, who at 78 is the oldest nominee from a major party in US history, a slight edge recently -- but all within the margin of error.</p>

<p>Whatever the result, US voters will make history on November 5: they will either elect the country's first woman president, or they will put the first convicted felon into the White House.</p>

<p><strong>Early voters</strong></p>

<p>Harris, 60, is also deploying two of her party's most popular emissaries onto the campaign trail: Barack and Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>The former president, speaking at a rally in Madison on Tuesday, rolled back the years with fiery attacks on Trump.</p>

<p>"Don't boo, vote!" he implored people after his jibes.</p>

<p>Laster in the day, Rapper Eminem upped the star factor when he introduced Obama at a major Harris campaign event in Detroit, drawing a rapped reply from the ex-president.</p>

<p>"I don't usually get nervous, but I was feeling some kinda way following Eminem," Obama said before launching into a recitation of the lyrics to the rapper's hit "Lose Yourself".</p>

<p>At the same time, Trump has increasingly repeated conspiracy theories on the campaign trail, often taking aim at migrants and his political opponents.</p>

<p>While speaking to Latino leaders Tuesday in Florida he said: "As president, you have tremendous — it's called extreme power. You have extreme power."</p>

<p>"You can, just by the fact, you say, 'Close the border,' and the border's closed," he added.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign has begun to hammer at his mental and physical fitness to occupy the Oval Office while trying to woo moderate Republican voters.</p>

<p>One of Trump's top aides as president, former Marine general John Kelly, confirmed Tuesday to The New York Times previous reports that he considered the Republican to be a fascist.</p>

<p>"Certainly the former president is in the far-right area, he's certainly an authoritarian, admires people who are dictators -- he has said that. So he certainly falls into the general definition of fascist, for sure."</p>

<p>Joe Rogan, host of one of the most listened to podcasts in America, said his interview with Trump is due out Friday.</p>

<p>Non-traditional media, including podcasts, have played a key role in the campaign in targeting specific audiences like young women and Black men.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mtruabig_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/al-jassasiya-the-qatars-largest-rock-art-site-which-has-900-ancient-carvings-6853007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Al Jassasiya: Qatar's Largest Rock Art Site Which Has 900 Ancient Carvings]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/al-jassasiya-the-qatars-largest-rock-art-site-which-has-900-ancient-carvings-6853007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 11:00:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The carvings, mostly enigmatic cup marks arranged in various patterns, also feature sailing ships, symbols and signs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">In the northeastern corner of Qatar, lies Al Jassasiya, the country's largest and most significant rock art site. This barren desert landscape is home to approximately 900 ancient rock carvings, or petroglyphs, created centuries ago.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The carvings, mostly enigmatic cup marks arranged in various patterns, also feature sailing ships, symbols and signs. “Some of the carvings in Al Jassasiya are unique and cannot be found anywhere else,” Ferhan Sakal, head of excavation and site management at Qatar Museums told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/article/qatar-al-jassasiya-petroglyphs-cmd/index.html " rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>. He highlighted the petroglyphs of ships seen from a bird's-eye view, demonstrating “a high degree of creativity and observation skills” by the artists.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Some researchers suggest these marks may have been used for playing the board game Mancala, while others cite their use in rituals or for sorting pearls.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“It is very difficult to answer,” Mr Sakal acknowledged regarding the purpose of the cup marks. “We have no direct clues about the motifs used in Al Jassasiya,” he said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The age of the carvings remains uncertain, with estimates ranging from Neolithic to late Islamic times. Mr Sakal said, “Petroglyphs – and rock art, in general – are very challenging to date.”&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">A previous study found no evidence of the carvings being more than a few hundred years old, but further research is needed.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The ship carvings at Al Jassasiya provide important insights into Qatar's fishing and pearling industries. These vessels typically feature pointed stern and detailed designs, with some anchors indicating traditional maritime practices.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Experts speculate on the significance of the high concentration of ship carvings at Al Jassasiya, with references to ancient beliefs surrounding boats as symbols of transition to the afterlife.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Visitors to Al Jassasiya are advised to take water and wear sun protection, as the site lacks shaded areas. The best times to visit are at sunrise and sunset, and the site is located near Azerbaijani Beach.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fh5ht4co_al-jassasiya_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The age of the carvings remains uncertain (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prime-minister-modi-to-meet-chinas-xi-in-russia-6852959]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Prime Minister Modi To Meet China's Xi In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prime-minister-modi-to-meet-chinas-xi-in-russia-6852959]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:54:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping will hold their first bilateral meeting in five years Wednesday, Indian officials said, days after their countries reached a deal on their contested border.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping will hold their first bilateral meeting in five years Wednesday, Indian officials said, days after their countries reached a deal on their contested border.</p>

<p>The meeting will take place on the sidelines of the three-day BRICS gathering hosted by President Vladimir Putin in the Russian city of Kazan, a sign of a potential thaw between the neighbours since clashes between their troops in 2020.</p>

<p>"There will be a bilateral meeting held between Prime Minister Modi and President Xi Jinping... on the sidelines of the BRICS summit," senior Indian foreign ministry official Vikram Misri said late Tuesday.</p>

<p>The leaders of the world's two most populous nations last held face-to-face formal talks when Xi visited PM Modi in the Indian city of Mahabalipuram in October of 2019.</p>

<p>Months later, in 2020, relations plunged after a skirmish along their contested frontier in the high-altitude Himalayan region of Ladakh, in which at least 20 Indian and four Chinese soldiers were killed.</p>

<p>China and India are intense rivals and have accused each other of trying to seize territory along their unofficial divide, known as the Line of Actual Control.</p>

<p>Since then, both sides pulled back tens of thousands of troops and agreed not to send patrols into a narrow dividing strip.</p>

<p>But India on Monday said that "agreement has been arrived at on patrolling arrangements" with China, easing the military standoff.</p>

<p>PM Modi and Xi met briefly in Bali in Indonesia on the sidelines of the G20 leaders' meeting in 2022, and in Johannesburg in South Africa in 2023.</p>

<p>India, however, maintained that ties could not return to normal unless the pre-clash status quo at their Ladakh frontier was restored.</p>

<p>In the last four years, New Delhi made it harder for many Chinese companies to invest in critical Indian sectors, and banned hundreds of Chinese gaming and e-commerce apps, including TikTok.</p>

<p>New Delhi also forged deeper ties with the so-called Quad, a US-led group that includes India, Australia and Japan, and hopes to counter China's influence in the Asia-Pacific region.</p>

<p>India eased laws for Western companies to invest and co-produce military hardware in the country.</p>

<p>Beijing is now expected to push New Delhi to restore economic ties and access for its companies in the fast-growing Indian market.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/agbij83_modi-and-xi-jinping_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China and India are intense rivals and have accused each other of trying to seize territory along LAC.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-enters-worlds-500-richest-list-for-first-time-in-11-weeks-6852948]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Enters World's 500 Richest List For First Time In 11 Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-enters-worlds-500-richest-list-for-first-time-in-11-weeks-6852948]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:51:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has rejoined the Bloomberg Billionaires Index for the first time since Aug. 6 as his media startup's stock surges alongside his odds in political betting markets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has rejoined the Bloomberg Billionaires Index for the first time since Aug. 6 as his media startup's stock surges alongside his odds in political betting markets.</p>

<p>The former president's fortune rose to $6.5 billion Tuesday, ranking him 481st on the list of the world's 500 richest people. Trump Media &amp; Technology Group Corp., which owns Truth Social, has nearly tripled in value since late September, boosting his paper wealth.</p>

<p>Trump Media has been trading as a proxy for betting on the likelihood that Trump will be the next US president. The odds that Trump will win the Nov. 5 election have spiked in recent weeks on betting sites Polymarket and PredictIt.</p>

<p>Trump's net worth is the highest it's been since July 22, the day after President Joe Biden dropped out of the race, which led to Vice President Kamala Harris becoming the Democratic nominee.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f41du9is_donald-trump-afp_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-abercrombie-ceo-mike-jeffries-partner-accused-of-sex-trafficking-involving-make-models-6852889]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Abercrombie CEO, Partner Accused Of Sex-Trafficking Involving Make Models]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-abercrombie-ceo-mike-jeffries-partner-accused-of-sex-trafficking-involving-make-models-6852889]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:43:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Abercrombie & Fitch Chief Executive Officer Mike Jeffries was charged by the US with running a sex-trafficking ring that coerced young men to engage in sexual acts with him in hopes of a career in modeling.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Abercrombie &amp; Fitch Chief Executive Officer Mike Jeffries was charged by the US with running a sex-trafficking ring that coerced young men to engage in sexual acts with him in hopes of a career in modeling.</p>

<p>Jeffries, 80, was arrested along with his romantic partner and another man, accused of one count of sex trafficking and 15 counts of interstate prostitution, according to an indictment unsealed in federal court on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Aspiring fashion models knew that a place on one of Abercrombie's iconic ads could be the ticket to success," Breon Peace, the US attorney in Brooklyn, said at a news conference announcing the case. "While Jeffries was the CEO of one of the most recognizable clothing retailers in the world, he was using his power, his wealth and his influence to traffic men for his own sexual pleasure and that of his romantic partner, Matthew Smith."</p>

<p>If convicted of the sex-trafficking charge, the most serious, the defendants face a maximum sentence of life in prison and a minimum of 15 years behind bars.</p>

<p>Brian Bieber, a lawyer for Jeffries, said in a statement: "We will respond in detail to the allegations after the indictment is unsealed, and when appropriate, but plan to do so in the courthouse - not the media." A lawyer for Smith didn't immediately return voicemails and emails seeking comment. Jeremy Schneider, who represents the third defendant, James Jacobson, declined to comment.</p>

<p>A representative of Abercrombie, which wasn't charged, also declined to comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The company's shares closed down 3.2% at $154.82.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Sex 'Tryouts'</strong></p>

<p>From at least late 2008 to early 2015, Jeffries and Smith spent millions of dollars to operate a "massive" sex-trafficking ring to victimize the men and "prolific amounts of money for staff to run the sex events," the US alleged.</p>

<p>They paid hundreds of thousands of dollars for the men to travel to their homes in the Hamptons on Long Island as well as to hotels in England, France, Italy, Morocco and the Caribbean for "sex events," according to Peace. Meanwhile, Jacobson, who worked for the couple, operated sex "tryouts" and recruited men as candidates, the US said.</p>

<p>The defendants allegedly used alcohol, muscle relaxants known as poppers and "force, fraud and coercion" to operate the illicit business while Jeffries and Smith relied upon their "vast financial resources" and Jeffries' position as the CEO to prey on the men. The men were required to sign nondisclosure agreements and threatened with reprisals if they complained, according to the government.</p>

<p>At least 15 men were lured with the promise of modeling opportunities for the fashion brand, Peace said. He said the actual number of victims may be in the "dozens and dozens" and asked any victims to come forward as the investigation continues. The FBI has also set up a hotline.</p>

<p>Jeffries and Smith appeared before a magistrate in federal court in West Palm Beach, Florida, on Tuesday. Jeffries was released on a $10 million bond. Smith, who is a UK citizen, was ordered held without bail. Jacobson appeared in federal court in St. Paul, Minnesota, and was released on a $500,000 bond, Peace spokesman John Marzulli said.</p>

<p><strong>'All-American Look'</strong></p>

<p>Jeffries was hired in 1992 by Leslie Wexner, founder of the company's former parent, Limited Brands (now L Brands), which also owned Victoria's Secret. He used racy marketing to sell an aspirational image of the "cool kid," one who plays rugby barechested and sports an "all-American" look.</p>

<p>Jeffries has also been sued over allegations he forced models to take drugs and engage in sex acts with him and others in exchange for the chance to be featured in the company's provocative fashion catalogs. One lawsuit against him and Abercrombie, in federal court in Manhattan, alleges that he used his position to recruit men and invite them to casting sessions at his homes in New York, the Hamptons and elsewhere.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the suit, filed by former Abercrombie model David Bradberry, the ex-CEO used his role "to prey upon attractive young men who believed that Jeffries was going to hire them as an Abercrombie model - the pinnacle of the modeling industry for men during the relevant time period."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bradberry claims Abercrombie "knew that it was providing the financial lifeblood for a sex-trafficking organization led by its CEO from at least 1992 through 2014," and that there could be more than 100 victims.</p>

<p>Lawyers for Jeffries and Abercrombie defended themselves in a filing this month, seeking the suit's dismissal.</p>

<p><strong>Prosecutor's Warning</strong></p>

<p>Brad Edwards, a lawyer for Bradberry who also represents victims of Jeffrey Epstein, said the criminal charges have brought his client "an overwhelming sense of validation." He said "it took a tremendous amount of courage for each of these men to come forward and speak out."</p>

<p>New Albany, Ohio-based Abercrombie, once known for its perfumed stores and shirtless models, has made a comeback among Gen Z and millennial adults, reinventing its brand by embracing more inclusive sizing and expanding its denim offerings. Jeffries left the company in 2014 after the Abercrombie and Hollister clothing lines lost their cachet with teenage shoppers.</p>

<p>"This case should serve as a warning" Peace said at the press conference. "Sexually exploiting vulnerable human beings is a crime."</p>

<p>The case is US v. Jeffries, 24-cr-00423, US District Court, Eastern District of New York (Central Islip).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ov8ndi1o_mike-jeffries-reuters_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Jeffries was charged by the US with running a sex-trafficking ring.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marriage-apps-in-pakistan-claiming-to-be-halal-rival-rishta-aunties-6852877]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rise Of Marriage Apps In Pak, Claiming To Be 'Halal', With Chaperone Options]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/marriage-apps-in-pakistan-claiming-to-be-halal-rival-rishta-aunties-6852877]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:40:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Marriage apps describe themselves as "halal", or permissible in Islam, offering options to blur profile pictures for privacy and making clear the purpose is to reach a proposal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's traditional matchmakers play a revered role in moulding daughters into potential brides, but marriage apps marketing themselves as halal are offering women a new route to finding a husband.</p>

<p>"When I saw my colleague happy after being married to someone she met online... I thought, since we have tried rishta aunties for four or five years, let's try this too," Ezza Nawaz, a textile designer in Lahore, told AFP.</p>

<p>Rishta aunties -- or traditional matchmakers -- polish up women and present them to the families of potential suitors, in a country where dating is considered dishonourable.</p>

<p>But in the last few years, marriage apps for Muslims have emerged in Pakistan promising so-called "love matches".</p>

<p>Some offer a "chaperone" option -- which provides a weekly transcript of sent and received messages to a chosen relative, satisfying families wary of their son or daughter connecting with strangers.</p>

<p>For Ezza, it was a success: just three months after meeting Waseem Akhtar on Muzz, she was married.</p>

<p>"We went on a couple of dates before we got our family involved. We took our time," she said.</p>

<p>More than 80 percent of Pakistanis have arranged marriages, according to a survey by Gallup and Gilani Pakistan, where families decide the union, sometimes settling an engagement without the bride and the groom even meeting.</p>

<p>Parents enlist the help of professional rishta aunties to help find a suitable family, with the first impression often based on how the young woman looks as she pours tea for her potential in-laws.</p>

<p>The app, however, says 1.2 million Pakistanis have signed up since it launched last year with an advertising campaign in major cities, and 15,000 people have already married.</p>

<p>Marriage apps describe themselves as "halal", or permissible in Islam, offering options to blur profile pictures for privacy and making clear the purpose is to reach a proposal.</p>

<p>But they continue to battle a stigma linking them to casual dating apps such as Tinder, which has been banned in Pakistan for being "immoral".</p>

<p>"I do not tell people how I met my wife until I am sure that the person would not judge us," said Waseem.</p>

<h3><strong>Tradition dates modernity</strong></h3>

<p>Marriage is viewed as a coming together of two families in Pakistan, where many live in multigenerational households.</p>

<p>Choosing your husband or wife yourself can be seen as a challenge to the deeply ingrained reverence towards elders and a threat to the traditional family structure.</p>

<p>Rishta aunties are therefore relied upon to find suitors from acceptable families -- a process that young women, who are widely expected to marry by the age of 25, can sometimes find demeaning.</p>

<p>"I was asked not to tell the guy's family that my hobbies are hiking or photography, but are cooking and cleaning... it made me angry," said Rida Fatima.</p>

<p>"They had the audacity to talk about how I looked, what I did, how much I earned, who my family is, how many brothers I have, what are my future aspirations. So every little thing is judged."</p>

<p>Fatima was presented with several potential matches through a rishta auntie appointed by her parents, but was asked to pay around $700 for an introductory meeting with a guy.</p>

<p>The rate fluctuates depending on whether the match has a foreign passport, she added.</p>

<p>Eventually, she ditched the process, becoming part of the 18 percent of Pakistanis who have a "love marriage" after meeting her husband by chance.</p>

<p>"No matter how the guy looks, even if he is bald or has a big belly, he wants a wife who looks like a model," said Muskan Ali, the managing director at a marriage consultancy in Karachi.</p>

<h3><strong>Waste of time</strong></h3>

<p>Rishta aunties do not feel threatened yet.</p>

<p>Their offices buzz with parents and their children crafting profiles on computers, as matchmakers strive to digitise their businesses with sleek websites and WhatsApp groups for client communication.</p>

<p>Consultants teach young women how to walk, talk and dress to best correspond to the wishes of their future in-laws.</p>

<p>Many traditional matchmakers like Fauzia Aazam, the head of a community of rishta aunties in Rawalpindi, reject marriage apps altogether.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"People waste time on these apps," she said.</p>

<p>"Chatting together all through the night, I just don't like it."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Fauzia Aazam (C), the head of a community of rishta aunties, with other matchmakers during an annual meeting in Rawalpindi" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8on79mlo_pak-dating-apps_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Fauzia Aazam (C), the head of a community of rishta aunties, with other matchmakers during an annual meeting in Rawalpindi" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Fauzia Aazam (C), the head of a community of rishta aunties, with other matchmakers during an annual meeting in Rawalpindi<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p>For Aisha Sarwari, a feminist author, the matchmaking process is about exercising "control" over daughters-in-law.</p>

<p>"I would say that we need to find a good middle ground, where the respect is equal on both sides and there is no sense of demeaning a human being just because they look a certain way or they are from a particular race," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Aneela, a digital media artist, whose name has been changed, tried her best to avoid being poured over by a matchmaker and turned to a marriage app, but found a new set of concerns.</p>

<p>"It is hard being on an app... men lie," she said, swiping through her profile at a cafe in Islamabad.</p>

<p>She later admitted to using a fake name and pictures on her profile so that men cannot identify her.</p>

<p>"The only option left is to go for an arranged marriage instead."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oe3vea8_pak-marriage-apps-_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ezza Nawaz (R), a textile designer who got married through Muzz app, with her husband Waseem Akhtar]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-scurvy-making-a-comeback-what-is-it-all-you-need-to-know-6852738]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is Scurvy Making A Comeback? What Is It? All You Need To Know]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-scurvy-making-a-comeback-what-is-it-all-you-need-to-know-6852738]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:15:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scurvy is a disease caused by a severe deficiency of vitamin C (ascorbic acid), which is essential for the production of collagen. This protein helps maintain the health of skin, blood vessels, bones and connective tissue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scurvy is often considered a historical ailment, conjuring images of sailors on long sea voyages suffering from a lack of fresh fruit and vegetables.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Yet doctors in developed countries have recently reported treating cases of scurvy, including Australian doctors who <a href="https://casereports.bmj.com/lookup/doi/10.1136//bcr-2024-261082">reported their findings</a> today in the journal <a href="https://casereports.bmj.com/">BMJ Case Reports</a>.</p>

<h2><strong>What is scurvy?</strong></h2>

<p>Scurvy is a disease caused by a severe deficiency of vitamin C (ascorbic acid), which is essential for the production of collagen. This protein helps maintain the health of skin, blood vessels, bones and connective tissue.</p>

<p>Without enough vitamin C, the body cannot properly repair tissues, heal wounds, or fight infections. This can lead to a range of <a href="https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.1515/9781400884544/html">symptoms</a> including:</p>

<ul>
	<li>fatigue and weakness</li>
	<li>swollen, bleeding gums or loose teeth</li>
	<li>joint and muscle pain and tenderness</li>
	<li>bruising easily</li>
	<li>dry, rough or discoloured skin (reddish or purple spots due to bleeding under the skin)</li>
	<li>cuts and sores take longer to heal</li>
	<li>anaemia (a shortage of red blood cells, leading to further fatigue and weakness)</li>
	<li>increased susceptibility to infections.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>It historically affected sailors</strong></h2>

<p>Scurvy was <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23183299/">common</a> from the 15th to 18th centuries, when naval sailors and other explorers lived on rations or went without fresh food for long periods. You might have heard some of these milestones in the history of the disease:</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong>in 1497-1499</strong>, Vasco da Gama's crew <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(03)13131-5/fulltext#:%7E:text=After%205%20weeks%20at%20sea,lemons%2C%20clearing%20up%20the%20condition">suffered severely from scurvy</a> during their expedition to India, with a large portion of the crew dying from it</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>from the 16th to 18th centuries</strong>, scurvy was rampant among European navies and explorers, affecting notable figures such as <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/26305889">Ferdinand Magellan and Sir Francis Drake</a>. It was considered one of the greatest threats to sailors' health during long voyages</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>in 1747</strong>, British naval surgeon <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3536506/">James Lind</a> is thought to have conducted one of the first clinical trials, demonstrating that citrus fruit could prevent and cure scurvy. However, it took several decades for his findings to be widely implemented</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>in 1795</strong>, the British Royal Navy officially adopted the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/003591572601902602">practice of providing lemon or lime juice to sailors</a>, dramatically reducing the number of scurvy cases.</p>
	</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Evidence of scurvy re-emerging</strong></h2>

<p>In the new case report, doctors in Western Australia <a href="https://casereports.bmj.com/lookup/doi/10.1136//bcr-2024-261082">reported</a> treating a middle-aged man with the condition. In a separate case report, doctors in Canada <a href="https://www.cmaj.ca/content/196/33/E1144">reported</a> treating a 65-year old woman.</p>

<figure class="align-right "><img alt="Tangarines" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=237&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1005&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1005&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627463/original/file-20241022-19-2qug5n.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1005&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">There's an abundance of vitamin C in our food supply, but some people still aren't getting enough.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/pile-of-tangerines-16181546/">Rebecca Kate/Pexels</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Both patients presented with leg weakness and compromised skin, yet the doctors didn't initially consider scurvy. This was based on the <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/12/7/1963">premise</a> that there is abundant vitamin C in our modern food supply, so deficiency should not occur.</p>

<p>On both occasions, treatment with high doses of vitamin C (1,000mg per day for at least seven days) resulted in improvements in symptoms and eventually a full recovery.</p>

<p>The authors of both case reports are concerned that if scurvy is left untreated, it could lead to inflamed blood vessels (<a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/vasculitis/symptoms-causes/syc-20363435">vasculitis</a>) and potentially <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211419X11001625">cause fatal bleeding</a>.</p>

<p>Last year, a major New South Wales hospital undertook a <a href="https://www.mja.com.au/journal/2023/219/10/serum-vitamin-c-status-people-new-south-wales-retrospective-analysis-findings">chart review</a>, where patient records are reviewed to answer research questions.</p>

<p>This found vitamin C deficiency was common. More than 50% of patients who had their vitamin C levels tested had either a modest deficiency (29.9%) or significant deficiency (24.5%). Deficiencies were more common among patients from rural and lower socioeconomic areas.</p>

<p>Now clinicians are <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.5694/mja2.52146">urged to</a> consider vitamin C deficiency and scurvy as a potential diagnosis and involve the support of a dietitian.</p>

<h2><strong>Why might scurvy be re-emerging?</strong></h2>

<p>Sourcing and consuming nutritious foods with sufficient vitamin C is unfortunately <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10260575/">still an issue</a> for some people. Factors that increase the risk of vitamin C deficiency include:</p>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong>poor diet</strong>. People with restricted diets – due to poverty, food insecurity or dietary choices – <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10296835/">may not get enough</a> vitamin C. This includes those who rely heavily on processed, nutrient-poor foods rather than fresh produce</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>food deserts</strong>. In areas where access to fresh, affordable fruits and vegetables is limited (often referred to as food deserts), people may <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9587807/">unintentionally suffer from a vitamin C deficiency</a>. In some parts of developing countries such as India, lack of access to fresh food is <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10296835/">recognised as a risk</a> for scurvy</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>the cost-of-living crisis</strong>. With greater numbers of people <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10935407/">unable to pay for fresh produce</a>, people who limit their intake of fruits and vegetables may develop nutrient deficiencies, including scurvy</p>
	</li>
</ul>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="Couple buy capsicums at the supermarket" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/627464/original/file-20241022-15-1oyczo.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Capsicums are a good source of vitamin C but they're not cheap.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/couple-buying-groceries-at-a-supermarket-4198970/">Pexels/Jack Sparrow</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<ul>
	<li>
	<p><strong>weight loss procedures and medications</strong>. Restricted dietary intake due to weight loss surgery or weight loss medications may <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/oby.24067">lead to nutrient deficiencies</a>, such as in this <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3320124/">case report of scurvy</a> from Denmark</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>mental illness and eating disorders</strong>. Conditions such as depression and anorexia nervosa can lead to severely restricted diets, increasing the risk of scurvy, such as in this <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32291151/">case report</a> from 2020 in Canada</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>isolation</strong>. Older adults, especially those who live alone or in nursing homes, may have <a href="https://doi.org/10.1136//bcr-2024-261082">difficulty</a> preparing balanced meals with sufficient vitamin C</p>
	</li>
	<li>
	<p><strong>certain medical conditions</strong>. People with digestive disorders, malabsorption issues, or those on restrictive medical diets (due to severe allergies or intolerances) can develop scurvy if they are <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8248877/">unable to absorb or consume enough vitamin C</a>.</p>
	</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>How much vitamin C do we need?</strong></h2>

<p>Australia's dietary guidelines <a href="https://www.eatforhealth.gov.au/nutrient-reference-values/nutrients/vitamin-c">recommend</a> adults consume 45mg of vitamin C (higher if pregnant or breastfeeding) each day. This is roughly the amount found in half an orange or half a cup of strawberries.</p>

<p>When more vitamin C is <a href="https://www.abs.gov.au/statistics/health/health-conditions-and-risks/australian-health-survey-usual-nutrient-intakes/latest-release">consumed</a> than required, excess amounts leave the body through urine.</p>

<p>Signs of scurvy can appear as early as a month after a daily intake of less than 10 mg of vitamin C.</p>

<p>Eating vitamin C-rich foods – such as oranges, strawberries, kiwifruit, plums, pineapple, mango, capsicum, broccoli and Brussels sprouts – can resolve symptoms within a few weeks.</p>

<p>Vitamin C is also readily available as a supplement if there are reasons why intake through food may be compromised. Typically, the supplements contain 1,000mg per tablet, and the <a href="https://www.eatforhealth.gov.au/nutrient-reference-values/nutrients/vitamin-c">recommended upper limit</a> for daily Vitamin C intake is 2,000mg.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/241894/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/lauren-ball-14718">Lauren Ball</a>, Professor of Community Health and Wellbeing, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/the-university-of-queensland-805">The University of Queensland</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/scurvy-is-largely-a-historical-disease-but-there-are-signs-its-making-a-comeback-241894">original article</a>.)</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-01/srer67jg_vitamin-c_625x300_18_January_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-satellite-breakup-adds-to-more-than-4-300-tonnes-of-space-junk-6852669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Another Satellite Breakup Adds To More Than 4,300 Tonnes Of Space Junk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-satellite-breakup-adds-to-more-than-4-300-tonnes-of-space-junk-6852669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:05:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The European Space Agency estimates there are more than 40,000 pieces larger than 10cm in orbit, and more than 130,000,000 smaller than 1cm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A large communications satellite has <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/satellite-orbiting-earth-broken-intelsat-lost-1972438">broken up in orbit</a>, affecting users in Europe, Central Africa, the Middle East, Asia and Australia, and adding to the growing swarm of space junk clouding our planet's neighbourhood.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.satcat.com/sats/41748">Intelsat 33e satellite</a> provided broadband communication from a point some 35,000km above the Indian Ocean, in a geostationary orbit around the equator.</p>

<p>Initial reports on October 20 said Intelsat 33e had experienced a sudden power loss. Hours later, <a href="https://www.space-track.org/">US Space Forces-Space</a> confirmed the satellite appears to have broken up into at least 20 pieces.</p>

<p>So what happened? And is this a sign of things to come as more and more satellites head into orbit?</p>

<h2><strong>A space whodunnit</strong></h2>

<p>There are no confirmed reports about what caused the breakup of Intelsat 33e. However, it is not the first event of its kind.</p>

<p>In the past we've seen <a href="https://www.space.com/3415-china-anti-satellite-test-worrisome-debris-cloud-circles-earth.html">deliberate satellite destructions</a>, <a href="https://scienceandglobalsecurity.org/archive/2010/06/analysis_of_debris_from_the_co.html">accidental collisions</a>, and loss of satellites due to <a href="https://svs.gsfc.nasa.gov/5193/">increased solar activity</a>.</p>

<p>What we do know is that Intelsat 33e has a history of issues while in orbit. Designed and manufactured by <a href="https://www.boeing.com/content/dam/boeing/boeingdotcom/space/boeing_satellites/pdf/Bkgd_SatFam_Intelsat.pdf">Boeing</a>, the satellite was launched in August 2016.</p>

<p>In 2017, the satellite reached its desired orbit three months later than anticipated, due to a <a href="https://spaceflightnow.com/2017/01/30/intelsat-satellite-in-service-after-overcoming-engine-trouble/">reported issue</a> with its primary thruster, which controls its altitude and acceleration.</p>

<p>More propulsion troubles emerged when the satellite performed something called a station keeping activity, which keeps it at the right altitude. It was <a href="https://spacenews.com/intelsat-33e-propulsion-problems-to-cut-service-life-by-3-5-years/">burning more fuel than expected</a>, which meant its mission would end around 3.5 years early, in 2027. Intelsat lodged a US$78 million insurance claim as a result of these problems.</p>

<p>However, at the time of its breakup, the satellite was reportedly <a href="https://spacenews.com/intelsat-33e-loses-power-in-geostationary-orbit/">not insured</a>.</p>

<p>Intelsat is <a href="https://www.intelsat.com/newsroom/intelsat-reports-is-33e-satellite-loss/">investigating</a> what went wrong, but we may never know exactly what caused the satellite to fragment. We do know another Intelsat <a href="https://www.spaceintelreport.com/sudden-failure-of-intelsat-is-33-satellite-forces-fresh-look-at-companys-five-remaining-boeing-702-mp-models/">satellite of the same model</a>, a Boeing-built EpicNG 702 MP, failed in 2019.</p>

<p>More importantly, we can learn from the aftermath of the breakup: space junk.</p>

<h2><strong>30 blue whales of space junk</strong></h2>

<p>The amount of debris in orbit around Earth is increasing rapidly. The European Space Agency (ESA) <a href="https://www.esa.int/Space_Safety/Space_Debris">estimates</a> there are more than 40,000 pieces larger than 10cm in orbit, and more than 130,000,000 smaller than 1cm.</p>

<p>The total mass of human-made space objects in Earth orbit is some <a href="https://sdup.esoc.esa.int/discosweb/statistics/">13,000 tonnes</a>. That's about the same mass as 90 adult male blue whales. About one third of this mass is debris (4,300 tonnes), mostly in the form of leftover rocket bodies.</p>

<p>Tracking and identifying space debris is a challenging task. At higher altitudes, such as Intelsat 33e's orbit around 35,000km up, we can only see objects above a certain size.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="260" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6zoQmV3PGNc?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="440"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Visualisation of debris around the Earth.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>One of the most concerning things about the loss of Intelsat 33e is that the breakup likely produced debris that is too small for us to see from ground level with current facilities.</p>

<p>The past few months have seen a string of <a href="https://orbitaldebris.jsc.nasa.gov/quarterly-news/pdfs/ODQNv28i4.pdf">uncontrolled breakups</a> of decommissioned and abandoned objects in orbit.</p>

<p>In June, the <a href="https://spacenews.com/low-intensity-explosion-caused-russian-satellite-to-spew-debris/">RESURS-P1 satellite</a> fractured in low Earth orbit (an altitude of around 470km), creating more than 100 trackable pieces of debris. This event also likely created many more pieces of debris too small to be tracked.</p>

<p>In July, another decommissioned satellite – the <a href="https://space.skyrocket.de/doc_sdat/dmsp-5d2.htm">Defense Meteorological Satellite Program (DMSP) 5D-2 F8 spacecraft</a> – broke up. In August, the upper stage of a <a href="https://spacenews.com/chinese-rocket-stage-breaks-up-into-cloud-of-more-than-700-pieces-of-space-debris/">Long March 6A (CZ-6A) rocket fragmented</a>, creating at least 283 pieces of trackable debris, and potentially hundreds of thousands of untrackable fragments.</p>

<p>It is not yet known whether this most recent event will affect other objects in orbit. This is where continuous monitoring of the sky becomes vital, to understand these complex space debris environments.</p>

<h2><strong>Who is responsible?</strong></h2>

<p>When space debris is created, who is responsible for cleaning it up or monitoring it?</p>

<p>In principle, the country that launched the object into space has the burden of responsibility where fault can be proved. This was explored in the 1972 <a href="https://www.unoosa.org/oosa/en/ourwork/spacelaw/treaties/introliability-convention.html">Convention of International Liability for Damage Caused by Space Objects</a>.</p>

<p>In practice, there is often little accountability. The <a href="https://theconversation.com/space-is-getting-crowded-with-satellites-and-space-junk-how-do-we-avoid-collisions-215545">first fine over space debris</a> was issued in 2023 by the US Federal Communications Commission.</p>

<p>It's not clear whether a similar fine will be issued in the case of Intelsat 33e.</p>

<h2><strong>Looking ahead</strong></h2>

<p>As the human use of space accelerates, Earth orbit is growing increasingly crowded. To manage the hazards of orbital debris, we will need continuous monitoring and improved tracking technology alongside deliberate efforts to minimise the amount of debris.</p>

<p>Most satellites are much closer to Earth than Intelsat 33e. Often these low Earth orbit satellites can be safely brought down from orbit (or “de-orbited”) at the end of their missions without creating space debris, especially with a bit of forward planning.</p>

<p>In September, ESA's <a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Cluster/Goodnight_Cluster_brilliant_end_to_trailblazing_mission">Cluster 2 “Salsa” satellite</a> was de-orbited with a targeted re-entry into Earth's atmosphere, burning up safely.</p>

<p>Of course, the bigger the space object, the more debris it can produce. NASA's Orbital Debris Program Office <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/iss-deorbit-analysis-summary.pdf">calculated</a> the International Space Station would produce more than 220 million debris fragments if it broke up in orbit, for example.</p>

<p>Accordingly, planning for de-orbiting of the station (ISS) at the end of its operational life in 2030 is now well underway, with the <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-selects-international-space-station-us-deorbit-vehicle/">contract awarded</a> to SpaceX.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/241790/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors</strong>:&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/sara-webb-984920">Sara Webb</a>, Lecturer, Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/swinburne-university-of-technology-767">Swinburne University of Technology</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/christopher-fluke-1480163">Christopher Fluke</a>, Professor, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/swinburne-university-of-technology-767">Swinburne University of Technology</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/tallulah-waterson-2240348">Tallulah Waterson</a>, PhD Student at the Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/swinburne-university-of-technology-767">Swinburne University of Technology</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/4-300-tonnes-of-space-junk-and-rising-another-satellite-breakup-adds-to-orbital-debris-woes-241790">original article</a>.)</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/63cfcaa8_space-generic-560_625x300_29_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The amount of debris in orbit around Earth is increasing rapidly (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/e-coli-outbreak-whats-is-mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-causes-and-symptoms-6852562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What's Is E. Coli Outbreak That's Being Linked To McDonald's Burgers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/e-coli-outbreak-whats-is-mcdonalds-e-coli-outbreak-causes-and-symptoms-6852562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 09:57:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A person died and 49 others fell ill following an E. coli outbreak linked to McDonald's Quarter Pounder hamburgers, according to a report from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A person died and 49 others fell ill following an E. coli outbreak linked to McDonald's Quarter Pounder hamburgers, according to a report from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/ecoli/outbreaks/e-coli-O157.html " rel="nofollow,noindex">CDC</a>). The outbreak has primarily affected residents in the US states of Colorado and Nebraska. The slivered onions used in the burgers are suspected to be the source of contamination.</p>

<p><strong>What is E. coli?</strong></p>

<p>Escherichia coli (E. coli) is a type of bacteria commonly found in the intestines of humans and animals. While most strains of E. coli are harmless and help maintain gut health, some can cause serious foodborne illness.</p>

<p><strong>E. coli outbreak at McDonald's: What's happening?</strong></p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/ecoli/outbreaks/where-people-got-sick-e-coli-o157-2024.html " rel="nofollow,noindex">CDC</a>, along with the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), identified onions as a "likely source," leading <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-responds-to-e-coli-bacterial-outbreak-linked-to-its-quarter-pounder-hamburgers-in-us-6852564">McDonald's</a> to suspend sales of Quarter Pounders in 12 states, including Colorado, Nebraska, Kansas and Utah. The fast-food chain has also stopped using the onions in question, although investigations are underway to determine whether the hamburger patties themselves could also be contributing to the outbreak. The outbreak was tied to E. coli O157.&nbsp;</p>

<p>So far, 10 people, including a child with a complicating illness, have been hospitalised, while a Colorado resident has died. The CDC's investigation suggests the actual number of sick people may be higher than reported, as many individuals recover without seeking medical attention. They warned it was a "fast-moving outbreak," with infections primarily occurring between customers who ate the burgers between late September and mid-October.</p>

<p><strong>E. coli: Symptoms</strong></p>

<p>Common symptoms include:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Severe stomach cramps</li>
	<li>Diarrhoea, often bloody</li>
	<li>Vomiting</li>
	<li>Fever, though not always present and usually mild if it occurs</li>
</ul>

<p>Symptoms usually appear three to four days after exposure to the bacteria, but can sometimes start as early as a day or as late as 10. Most people recover within 5 to 7 days. In severe cases, E. coli can lead to a serious complication called hemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS), which affects the kidneys and may require hospitalisation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The CDC advises to seek medical help if you experience:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Diarrhoea that lasts more than 3 days</li>
	<li>High fever (over 102 degree F)</li>
	<li>Bloody diarrhoea</li>
	<li>Severe vomiting that prevents keeping liquids down</li>
	<li>Signs of dehydration, such as dry mouth, dizziness or reduced urination</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/1ininp3k_uk-hospital-generic_625x300_02_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[E. Coli Outbreak: It has primarily affected residents in US states of Colorado and Nebraska.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>