<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:46:59 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddys-legal-team-files-appeal-after-bail-denied-twice-6689169]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Rapper Sean Diddy's Legal Team Files Appeal After Bail Denied Second Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-rapper-sean-diddys-legal-team-files-appeal-after-bail-denied-twice-6689169]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 09:04:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sean 'Diddy' Combs' attorney plans to file an appeal to get him released from prison, according to court documents obtained by 'People' on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sean 'Diddy' Combs' attorney plans to file an appeal to get him released from prison, according to court documents obtained by 'People' on Monday.</p>

<p>Combs' lawyer, Alexandra Shapiro, filed a notice on Monday stating their intent to appeal after Combs was denied bail twice. A source close to Combs told 'People' that the official appeal brief will be submitted soon.</p>

<p>The music mogul was arrested at a Manhattan hotel on September 16 at 8:25 pm. The next day, a 14-page indictment was unsealed, revealing the charges against him. He is accused of allegedly organizing several "freak offs," which prosecutors described as "elaborate and produced sex performances." He also allegedly drugged and sexually assaulted his victims.</p>

<p>On September 18, Combs was denied bail for the second time and is currently being held at Brooklyn's Metropolitan Detention Center.</p>

<p>Judge Robyn F. Tarnofsky, who denied his bail on September 17, cited concerns about his alleged "substance abuse and what seems like anger issues. I don't know that you can trust yourself" not to harm others," she said.</p>

<p>According to PEOPLE, Combs is reportedly no longer on suicide watch.</p>

<p>"He is focused and very strong. He is concentrating on his defence and preparing for his trial," a lawyer for Combs told PEOPLE.</p>

<p>Combs' next court appearance is scheduled for early October.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/amruf0fg_sean-diddy-combs_625x300_17_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sean 'Diddy' Combs' was arrested at a Manhattan hotel on September 16 (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-school-teacher-36-sentenced-for-sexual-battery-and-rape-of-a-minor-6689081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US School Teacher, 36, Sentenced For Sexual Battery And Rape Of A Minor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-school-teacher-36-sentenced-for-sexual-battery-and-rape-of-a-minor-6689081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 08:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawson was arrested in St. Anthony, Idaho, in November 2023 when police stopped a car driven by a teenage boy with Lawson in the passenger seat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Idaho high school teacher has been sentenced to a minimum of two years and up to 20 years in prison after pleading guilty to sexual battery of a minor. Jessica Lawson, 36, admitted to two counts of sexual battery as part of a plea agreement, according to court records. As part of the deal, additional charges for providing alcohol to a minor and delivering a controlled substance were dismissed, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/30/us-news/idaho-teacher-sentenced-for-sexual-battery-rape-of-teen-adopted-by-a-local-family-days-prior/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lawson was arrested in St. Anthony, Idaho, in November 2023 when police stopped a car driven by a teenage boy with Lawson in the passenger seat. According to reports from the Idaho State Journal, East Idaho News, and Local News 8, police said Lawson had instructed the boy to drive because she was too "drunk".</p>

<p>The car was initially pulled over for a broken taillight, and the boy reportedly confessed to possessing marijuana. The boy's parents later informed police that Lawson had picked him up the previous night, and he admitted to receiving alcohol and marijuana from her before they engaged in sexual activity.</p>

<p>Lawson, a former teacher at South Fremont High School, will serve at least two years in prison. She was also issued a 20-year no-contact order with the victim, according to East Idaho News.</p>

<p>"It takes a village to raise a young man, especially a young man that has been in and out of foster care, that has never known what it's like to have a mom and a dad," the father told the court, according to East Idaho News.</p>

<p>"My son is going to take a long time to heal and he doesn't even know the wounds that he has yet. He's not going to understand those wounds until he's a parent and he's sending his daughter or son ... to the house of a parent that he trusts."</p>

<p>The teen's mother said that struggles to differentiate between safe and unsafe situations because of his time in the foster home.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We brought [my son] in because he needed somebody, and he didn't have anybody ... It was pretty quick that we realized this is a really great kid, and he's wonderful and he should be in our family," the mother told the court.</p>

<p>"He's got a lot of problems because he didn't have a mom and dad that taught him how to recognize safe people. And you took advantage of that ... she knew she could get something from him."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7c6q6nio_jessica-lawson_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jessica Lawson, 36, admitted to two counts of sexual battery as part of a plea agreement]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-urges-ceasefire-amid-escalating-israel-hezbollah-conflict-in-lebanon-6688999]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Urges Ceasefire Amid Escalating Israel-Hezbollah Conflict In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-urges-ceasefire-amid-escalating-israel-hezbollah-conflict-in-lebanon-6688999]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 08:24:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite US calls to avert a ground offensive in Lebanon, Israel has begun "targeted" raids on the country -- more proof that Washington has been unable to rein in its ally, amid fears of a wider Middle East conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite US calls to avert a ground offensive in Lebanon, Israel has begun "targeted" raids on the country -- more proof that Washington has been unable to rein in its ally, amid fears of a wider Middle East conflict.</p>

<p>The US president indicated Monday that he was opposed to Israeli ground operations in Lebanon, calling for a ceasefire as tensions spiralled after the assassination of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>"I'm more aware than you might know and I'm comfortable with them stopping. We should have a ceasefire now," Biden told reporters when asked if he was aware of Israeli plans for a limited operation on Lebanese soil.</p>

<p>A few hours later, State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said Israel had informed Washington that it was currently conducting "limited operations targeting Hezbollah infrastructure near the border."</p>

<p>And the Israeli military confirmed early Tuesday that it had indeed launched "ground raids" on villages in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>It felt like deja vu all over again.</p>

<p>Every time the United States calls for a negotiated solution or a ceasefire, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu seems to respond by ramping up his military offensive.</p>

<p>Last week, with the ink barely dry on a joint US-French statement on the sidelines of a top-level UN summit for a three-week ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah, Netanyahu announced fresh air strikes against the Iran-backed militant group the very next day.</p>

<p>"The Biden administration has largely been a bystander to these events -- one that has supplied Israel with the military means to conduct these operations but has been repeatedly caught by surprise by its actions," wrote Brian Katulis, a senior fellow for US foreign policy at the Middle East Institute.</p>

<p>On Friday at the United Nations, the contrast was jarring: as Netanyahu authorized a strike against Nasrallah, risking a broader regional conflict, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken again called for all sides to choose diplomacy.</p>

<p>"The question is not, does Israel have a right to deal with existential threats to its security and enemies across its borders with the avowed intent to destroy Israel? Of course, it does.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But the question is what is the best way to achieve its objectives," Blinken said, echoing the US position expressed shortly after Hamas attacked Israel on October 7 last year.</p>

<h3><strong>Israel seeks to capitalize</strong></h3>

<p>Of course, there are no tears in Washington over Nasrallah's demise. Blinken called him a "brutal terrorist" on Monday.</p>

<p>But the United States has been at pains to say it was neither consulted nor aware of Israel's plans to target him ahead of time.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It made a similar statement after Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was killed in Iran in late July in an attack blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>Now, Israel clearly appears to be seeking to capitalize on its position, having done significant damage to Hezbollah in a series of attacks, and sending Hamas reeling in Gaza, diplomats say.</p>

<p>Washington meanwhile is still hoping that diplomacy will prevail, both in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>Diplomacy remains "the best and only path to achieving greater stability in the Middle East," and Washington is "committed to urgently driving these efforts forward," Blinken said Monday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Blinken spoke Sunday with his French counterpart Jean-Noel Barrot, who called on Israel to avoid any ground operation -- a call that apparently went unheeded.</p>

<p>The US secretary of state also talked to Britain's David Lammy on Monday and held talks with counterparts from Arab states on the sidelines of a ministerial meeting in Washington of the international coalition battling the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>Aides to Blinken have long insisted that Washington respects Israel's sovereignty, and tacitly acknowledge that US influence on Netanyahu is limited.</p>

<p>Events on the ground appear to be unfolding at a more rapid pace, and the United States is effectively unable to intercede, meaning Israel's top military and diplomatic ally is on the back foot, merely reacting to the crisis.</p>

<p>Until now, Biden has refused to play the military aid card to force Netanyahu's hand, other than the suspension of one delivery of bombs in May.</p>

<p>The US election calendar has complicated matters, as Vice President Kamala Harris, Biden's heir apparent, is battling for the White House with Republican former president Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Biden administration hopes to see a Middle East peace deal reached before the election, but few observers believe it is ready to change its strategy so close to Election Day on November 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o30es1hg_joe-biden-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden indicated Monday that he was opposed to Israeli ground operations in Lebanon (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-15-injured-in-china-supermarket-stabbing-incident-6688922]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Dead, 15 Injured, In China Supermarket Stabbing Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-dead-15-injured-in-china-supermarket-stabbing-incident-6688922]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 08:02:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man killed three people and wounded 15 in a knife attack at a supermarket in the Chinese megacity of Shanghai, police said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man killed three people and wounded 15 in a knife attack at a supermarket in the Chinese megacity of Shanghai, police said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The suspected attacker, a 37-year-old man surnamed Lin, was arrested at the supermarket shortly after the incident on Monday night, local police said in a statement.</p>

<p>Police said the man went on the rampage in anger caused by a "personal financial dispute".</p>

<p>Eighteen wounded people were taken to hospital for treatment, where three died, they added.</p>

<p>The other 15 did not sustain life-threatening wounds.</p>

<p>Violent knife crime is not uncommon in China, where firearms are strictly controlled, with a number of similar attacks at schools in recent years.</p>

<p>A Japanese schoolboy in September was stabbed in the southern city of Shenzhen and died of his injuries, prompting outrage from Tokyo.</p>

<p>And in May, a man killed eight people and wounded one more with a knife in the city of Xiaogan in central Hubei province.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/65ce303_china-police-generic_625x300_23_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[18 wounded people were taken to hospital for treatment, where 3 died, said police (Representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-in-netanyahus-message-warning-to-irans-leaders-assurance-to-its-people-6688881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Netanyahu's Message, Warning To Iran's Leaders, Assurance To Its People]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-in-netanyahus-message-warning-to-irans-leaders-assurance-to-its-people-6688881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:53:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a direct address to the people of Iran, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sent a clear and forceful message on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a direct address to the people of Iran, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu sent a clear and forceful message on Monday. The Israeli leader's speech, delivered in English and subtitled in Persian, conveyed both a warning to the Iranian regime and an assurance to its citizens. The message comes amidst Israel's escalating actions against Iranian-backed groups in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Netanyahu condemned Iran's leadership for allegedly prioritising regional conflicts over its own people's welfare. "Every day, you see a regime that subjugates you make fiery speeches about defending Lebanon, defending Gaza," Netanyahu said, adding that the Iranian government was "plunging the region deeper into darkness and deeper into war."</p>

<p>Referring to Iran's support for Hezbollah and Hamas, groups that have been engaged in violent conflicts with Israel, Netanyahu said that Iran's proxies were being systematically targeted. "Iran's puppets are being eliminated," he said. adding that there was "nowhere we will not go to protect our people."</p>

<p>"With every passing moment, the regime is bringing you - the noble Persian people - closer to the abyss," he said. "The vast majority of Iranians know their regime doesn't care a whit about them. If it did care, if it cared about you, it would stop wasting billions of dollars on futile wars across the Middle East. It would start improving your lives.</p>

<p>"Imagine if all the vast money the regime wasted on nuclear weapons and foreign wars were invested in your children's education, in improving your health care, in building your nation's infrastructure, water, sewage, all the other things that you need. Imagine that."</p>

<p>Netanyahu predicted a future where Iran is free from theocratic rule, envisioning a new era of peace between Israel and Iran. He expressed confidence that change would come "a lot sooner than people think." According to Netanyahu, a post-regime Iran would enjoy prosperity through global investments, tourism, and technological advancements.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"When Iran is finally free - and that moment will come a lot sooner than people think - everything will be different," he said. "Our two ancient peoples, the Jewish people and the Persian people, will finally be at peace. Our two countries, Israel and Iran, will be at peace.</p>

<p>"When that day comes, the terror network that the regime built in five continents will be bankrupt, dismantled. Iran will thrive as never before: Global investment; massive tourism; brilliant technological innovation based on the tremendous talents that exist inside Iran. Doesn't that sound better than endless poverty, repression and war?"</p>

<p>This direct message comes in the wake of Israel's intensified operations against Iranian proxies. Days before Netanyahu's statement, the Israel Defense Forces (IDF) executed a major airstrike that killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah at the group's headquarters in Beirut. The strike also reportedly took the life of a senior Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) official. Nasrallah's death has been met with celebration by anti-regime Iranians worldwide.</p>

<p>"You deserve better. Your children deserve better. The entire world deserves better. I know you don't support the rapists and murderers of Hamas and Hezbollah, but your leaders do. You deserve more. The people of Iran should know - Israel stands with you. May we together know a future of prosperity and peace," Netanyahu added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following Nasrallah's assassination, reports surfaced that Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, was moved to a secure location amid fears of further Israeli action.</p>

<p>The tension between Israel and Iran reached new heights earlier this year when Iran launched over 300 missiles and drones at Israel in retaliation for an alleged Israeli strike in Syria that killed several high-ranking IRGC officers. The vast majority of those missiles were intercepted by Israeli defence systems, with the support of a US-led coalition. Israel responded to Iran's actions with a limited drone strike targeting a nuclear research centre in Isfahan.</p>

<p>Nasrallah's assassination also came amid Israel's campaign against Hezbollah in Lebanon, which has seen frequent cross-border attacks against Israel, allegedly in solidarity with Hamas during its ongoing war with Israel in Gaza. Israel has steadily escalated its strikes on Hezbollah targets, leading to significant losses within the group's leadership. Earlier in the month, mysterious explosions attributed to Israel destroyed Hezbollah's communication devices, injuring thousands and intensifying the ongoing conflict.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5hltaio_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu said that Iran's proxies were being systematically targeted.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-imports-genetic-material-to-create-enormous-hybrid-sheep-arrested-6688770]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Imports Genetic Material To Create "Enormous" Hybrid Sheep, Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-imports-genetic-material-to-create-enormous-hybrid-sheep-arrested-6688770]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:20:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man who tried to breed enormous hybrid sheep using genetic material from endangered animals so he could sell them to trophy hunting ranches has been sentenced to six months in prison, the US Department of Justice said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man who tried to breed enormous hybrid sheep using genetic material from endangered animals so he could sell them to trophy hunting ranches has been sentenced to six months in prison, the US Department of Justice said Monday.</p>

<p>Arthur Schubarth, 81, illegally imported parts of the world's largest species of sheep from Kyrgyzstan, which he used to create cloned embryos in the United States.</p>

<p>The resulting embryos were then implanted in ewes on his Montana ranch, resulting in the birth of a genetically pure Marco Polo argali, an endangered species that can weigh more than 300 pounds (135 kilograms) and has horns more than five feet (1.5 meters) wide.</p>

<p>Schubarth then used semen from this specimen to impregnate various species of sheep in an effort to create never-before-seen hybrids, with the goal of breeding even larger sheep.</p>

<p>He hoped to sell the resulting animals to "canned" hunting ranches, facilities where customers pay to shoot captive animals, and where bigger animals can command higher prices.</p>

<p>"Schubarth's criminal conduct is not how Montanans treat our wildlife population," said US Attorney Jesse Laslovich.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Indeed, his actions threatened Montana's native wildlife species for no other reason than he and his co-conspirators wanted to make more money.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Schubarth's greed drove their conspiracy to bring to Montana parts of the largest sheep in the world from Kyrgyzstan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Such actions to create hybrid animals are as unnatural as they are illegal."</p>

<p>Schubarth, whose ranch breeds and sells mountain sheep, mountain goats and other ungulates primarily for game ranches, admitted one count of conspiracy to violate the Lacey Act, and one of substantively violating the Lacey Act at an earlier hearing.</p>

<p>The Lacey Act prohibits interstate trade in certain wildlife and is used by authorities to combat wildlife trafficking.</p>

<p>In addition to his prison sentence, Schubarth was ordered to pay a $20,000 fine to the Lacey Act Reward Fund, a $4,000 payment to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation and a $200 special assessment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ekobrb7g_arthur-schubarth_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The result was an endangered species that can weigh over 135 kg and has horns more than 5 feet wide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-begins-group-op-in-lebanon-after-hezbollah-chiefs-death-10-points-6688681]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Op 'Northern Arrows' Will Continue": Israeli Ground Raids Begin In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-begins-group-op-in-lebanon-after-hezbollah-chiefs-death-10-points-6688681]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 06:58:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have begun "limited, localized, and targeted" ground raids in Lebanon two days after it killed the group's chief Hassan Nasrallah in an airstrike, threatening to worsen the Middle East crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">The ground raids target Hezbollah infrastructure in villages in south Lebanon, close to the border, which pose&nbsp;an immediate threat to Israeli communities in northern Israel, said the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF), asserting that&nbsp;Operation "Northern Arrows"&nbsp;will continue in parallel to the fighting in Gaza and in other arenas.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel conducted at least six strikes on south Beirut after ordering the residents to evacuate, according to a Lebanese official. A Palestinian camp in south Lebanon was among those hit by the airstrikes, said an official.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hezbollah's deputy leader Naim Qassem, in his first televised speech since Nasrallah's death, said they were ready if Israel "decides to enter by land". The group has said in a statement they "targeted" Israeli troops in orchards near the Lebanese border.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">World leaders, including the United Nations Secretary-General and US President Joe Biden, had opposed a ground invasion into Lebanon and called for a ceasefire.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel and Hezbollah, which runs Lebanon, have been defiant and ignoring global calls for a ceasefire. Israel has been pounding Beirut with airstrikes, killing hundreds of people over the past week and forcing thousands to flee, according to Lebanese officials.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israeli army ordered people in southern Beirut to evacuate last evening. "You are located near interests and facilities belonging to the terrorist Hezbollah group. For your safety and the safety of your family members, you must evacuate the buildings immediately and stay away from them," said the group's military spokesman Avichay Adraee.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hassan Nasrallah, who was the chief of Hezbollah, was killed in a massive&nbsp;airstrike on Beirut on Friday. But Israel had vowed the battle was still on. The killing of Nasrallah was "an important step, but not the final one," their defence minister had said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant had also warned they will use "all the means that may be required" to fight the battle in northern Israel, which shares border with Lebanon - "from the air, from the sea, and on land".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Meanwhile, three civilians have been killed in Israeli airstrikes on Damascus, according to the state media. The official SANA agency said Israeli warplanes and drones launched attacks from the direction of the Syrian Golan, targeting several points in Damascus.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel's war with Hezbollah marks a shift in focus from Gaza, where Hamas operatives have been fighting an Israeli ground operation for months. Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon supports the Palestinian Hamas group.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vjsmbq1g_lebanon-airstrikes-afp_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-has-begun-ground-raids-against-hezbollah-in-south-lebanon-6688414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says It Has Begun "Ground Raids" Against Hezbollah In South Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-says-it-has-begun-ground-raids-against-hezbollah-in-south-lebanon-6688414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 05:34:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said Tuesday troops have started "targeted ground raids" in villages of southern Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said Tuesday that troops have started "ground raids" in villages in southern Lebanon, after militant group Hezbollah said it had targeted "enemy soldiers" at the countries' border.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security official said Israel had also conducted at least six strikes on south Beirut after Israel's army ordered residents in the Hezbollah stronghold to evacuate.</p>

<p>Despite international calls for de-escalation, Israel earlier vowed to keep fighting Hezbollah and sealed part of the border after killing the Iran-backed group's leader.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned the battle was not over even after the massive strike on Beirut that killed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah on Friday, dealing the group a seismic blow.</p>

<p>The military said troops backed by airstrikes and artillery launched ground raids "a few hours ago" targeting militant group Hezbollah "in villages close to the border".</p>

<p>Israel informed its main weapons supplier Washington of the incursions, US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told journalists.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden earlier on Monday indicated he opposed an Israeli ground operation.</p>

<p>"We should have a ceasefire now," he said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters were "ready if Israel decides to enter by land", the group's deputy leader Naim Qassem said in a first televised address since Nasrallah's death.</p>

<p>In a statement, Hezbollah said it "targeted" Israeli troops carrying out "movements" in orchards near the border, with a source close to the group saying the soldiers were "right on the border".</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Hezbollah following the Israeli army's announcement of the ground raids, but the group's al-Manar television reported the Israeli statement announcing the raids on its Telegram channel.</p>

<p>Lebanon's national army, dwarfed by Hezbollah's military power, was "repositioning" troops farther from the border, a military official told AFP.</p>

<p>World leaders have urged de-escalation, with United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres's spokesman Stephane Dujarric saying: "We do not want any sort of ground invasion."</p>

<p><strong>- Hezbollah 'targets' troops -</strong></p>

<p>Earlier this month, Israel launched a wave of deadly air strikes aimed at Hezbollah across Lebanon, the latest of which killed 95 people on Monday, according to Lebanon's health ministry.</p>

<p>On Monday evening, the Israeli military called on people in three districts of southern Beirut to evacuate.</p>

<p>"You are located near interests and facilities belonging to the terrorist Hezbollah group," Israeli military spokesman Avichay Adraee said.</p>

<p>"For your safety and the safety of your family members, you must evacuate the buildings immediately and stay away from them."</p>

<p>AFP correspondents in the capital heard explosions and saw a flash around ground level.</p>

<p>As Israel announced its ground raids, Syria's official news agency SANA said the country's air defence systems were intercepting "hostile targets" in the Damascus area.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from the Israeli military, which has carried out hundreds of strikes on Syria in recent years.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Everyone is afraid' -</strong></p>

<p>He said the killing of Nasrallah was "an important step, but it is not the final one".</p>

<p>Hezbollah began low-intensity strikes on Israeli troops a day after its Palestinian ally Hamas staged its unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7, which triggered Israel's devastating assault on the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The border clashes rapidly escalated this month.</p>

<p>On Monday, the Israeli army declared an area of the border strip a "closed military zone".</p>

<p>Israel's strikes on Lebanon have killed hundreds of people over the past week and forced up to a million to flee their homes, according to Lebanese officials.</p>

<p>Hezbollah and other groups launched rockets, drones and some missiles at Israel over the same period, causing some injuries but no deaths.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu accused Iran, which backs Hamas, Hezbollah and other armed groups, of plunging "our region deeper... into war".</p>

<p>"There is nowhere in the Middle East Israel cannot reach," Netanyahu warned.</p>

<p>Iran has said Nasrallah's killing would bring about Israel's "destruction", though the foreign ministry said Monday that Tehran would not deploy any fighters to confront Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati called for a ceasefire based on a recent US-French proposal, urging "an end to the Israeli aggression against Lebanon".</p>

<p>Earlier on Monday, an Israeli strike hit a building in central Beirut, with an armed Palestinian group saying it had killed three of its members.</p>

<p>The strike, the first in the city centre in years, sparked panic.</p>

<p>Central Beirut resident Kahier Bannout, 42, said it was "supposed to be a safe area -- not a war zone".</p>

<p><strong>"Everyone is afraid."</strong></p>

<p>Lebanon's Health Minister Firass Abiad said more than 1,000 people have been killed since September 17.</p>

<p>UN refugee agency chief Filippo Grandi said: "Well over 200,000 people are displaced inside Lebanon", while more than 100,000 have fled to neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>- 'Little time' -</p>

<p>France on Monday evening said it was deploying a naval ship to Lebanon as a "precaution" in case it decided to evacuate French citizens.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot, the first high-level diplomat to visit Beirut since the Israeli strikes intensified, said "there is still hope" for a ceasefire, "but there is little time".</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said diplomacy was the best path forward for the region.</p>

<p>Washington "will continue to work... to advance a diplomatic resolution" for the Israel-Lebanon border, and for a Gaza ceasefire and hostage-release deal, he said.</p>

<p>The United States, Qatar and Egypt tried for months to broker such a deal, which Netanyahu's domestic critics accused him of obstructing.</p>

<p>In Gaza, AFP journalists said the number of Israeli air strikes has dropped significantly in recent days.</p>

<p>A UN Satellite Centre assessment issued Monday said "two-thirds of the total structures in the Gaza Strip have sustained damage" in nearly a year of war.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,615 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pa11ulu_israel-invasion-of-lebanon_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel said that it is targeting Hezbollah "in villages close to the border" with its border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-targeted-israeli-troops-at-lebanon-border-6688162]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Says It "Targeted" Israeli Troops At Lebanon Border]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-targeted-israeli-troops-at-lebanon-border-6688162]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 04:03:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah said it "targeted" Israeli troops carrying out "movements" near the Lebanese border Tuesday, with a source close to the group saying the soldiers were "right on the border" as fears of an incursion grow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said it "targeted" Israeli troops carrying out "movements" near the Lebanese border Tuesday, with a source close to the group saying the soldiers were "right on the border" as fears of an incursion grow.</p>

<p>The militant group said it targeted "enemy soldiers' movements in the orchards opposite Adaisseh and Kfarkila" near the border.</p>

<p>The US State Department had earlier said Israel was conducting limited operations targeting Hezbollah inside Lebanon.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security official reported "Israeli army movements on the southern Lebanese border".</p>

<p>Israeli troops are "launching artillery shells from areas that it declared as closed military zones" earlier on Monday," the official said, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>Fears of an incursion also prompted Lebanon's army to move troops away from its southern border, a Lebanese military official told AFP Monday.</p>

<p>The Lebanese army is "repositioning and regrouping forces" from the southern border, the official said, requesting anonymity to discuss sensitive matters.</p>

<p>Lebanon's national army is dwarfed by the military power of the Iran-backed Hezbollah movement.</p>

<p>On Monday evening, Hezbollah's Al-Manar television channel reported "Zionist artillery shelling" near the border areas of Wazzani, the Khiam valley, Alma Al-Shaab and Naqura.</p>

<p>Wazzani and Khiam are right across from Metula in the north of Israel, where the military on Monday declared a closed military zone in Metula, Misgav Am, and Kfar Giladi.</p>

<p>Lebanon's state-run National News Agency reported "continued artillery shelling" on border areas including Wazzani and the nearby Marjayoun plain and Khiam.</p>

<p>Last Friday, the Israeli army killed Hezbollah's powerful leader Hassan Nasrallah in a strike on the group's southern Beirut bastion.</p>

<p>For the past week, Israel has launched an intense bombing campaign on the country's east, south and southern Beirut suburbs, killing hundreds of people and displacing up to one million, according to Lebanese officials.</p>

<p>The war follows nearly one year of cross-border exchanges of fire between Israel and Hezbollah that the Lebanese group said were in support of Palestinian ally Hamas, whose October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/d7vq94ps_lebanon-_625x300_01_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Lebanese security official reported "Israeli army movements on the southern Lebanese border".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-hits-beiruts-southern-suburbs-security-source-6687912]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strike Hits Beirut's Southern Suburbs: Security Source]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strike-hits-beiruts-southern-suburbs-security-source-6687912]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 02:34:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Israeli strike hit Beirut's southern suburbs late on Monday, a security source said, with a Reuters reporter seeing a flash of light and hearing a loud blast.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Israeli strike hit Beirut's southern suburbs late on Monday, a security source said, with a Reuters reporter seeing a flash of light and hearing a loud blast.</p>

<p>The Israeli military had warned it would strike specific buildings in the neighbourhood, a densely populated district south of the Lebanese capital, as fears grow of a looming ground invasion.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mcd9ec9o_lebanon_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An Israeli strike hit Beirut's southern suburbs late on Monday, a security source said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-hezbollah-commander-eid-hassan-nashar-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-6687655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Another Hezbollah Commander Killed In Israeli Airstrike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/another-hezbollah-commander-eid-hassan-nashar-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-6687655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 01:17:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a targeted airstrike on Saturday, the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) struck Beirut, resulting in the death of Eid Hassan Nashar, a high-ranking commander of Hezbollah's Medium-Range Rocket Unit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a targeted airstrike on Saturday, the Israeli Defence Forces (IDF) struck Beirut, resulting in the death of Eid Hassan Nashar, a high-ranking commander of Hezbollah's Medium-Range Rocket Unit.</p>

<p>Sharing a post on X, the IDF wrote, "Dismantled: Hezbollah's Missiles and Rockets Force. IAF fighter jets struck and eliminated commanders and infrastructure over the last week." It added, "During an airstrike in Beirut on Saturday, Eid Hassan Nashar, the Commander of Hezbollah's Medium-Range Rocket Unit, was eliminated."</p>

<p>According to the IDF, Eid Hassan Nashar held key leadership roles within Hezbollah. He served as the Commander of the Surface-to-Surface Rocket Unit, overseeing the organisation's day-to-day operations. The IDF stated, "Eid was a veteran commander in Hezbollah and played a significant role in the unit's day-to-day operations. In the past, he served as the Commander of the Surface-to-Surface Rocket Unit and Deputy Commander of the Badr Unit."</p>

<p>"Additionally, the commander, deputy commander and other commanders of Hezbollah's Precision Missile Unit were eliminated. Just last week, this unit was responsible for firing towards central Israel," the IDF added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in a precision strike, the IDF dismantled a Hezbollah surface-to-air missile launcher storage facility, located approximately 1.5 kilometres from Beirut's international airport.</p>

<p>In a post on X, the IDF said, "A surface-to-air missile launcher storage facility that Hezbollah had positioned approximately 1.5 km from Beirut's international airport was dismantled in a precise IDF strike."</p>

<p>The IDF further asserted that the facility posed a threat to Lebanese and international airspace. "This infrastructure poses a threat to both Lebanese and international airspace. The IDF will continue to degrade Hezbollah's military capabilities in Lebanon," the IDF stated.</p>

<p>A day earlier, the IDF had announced the deaths of the head of the Lebanon branch of the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine (PFLP), Nidal Abdel-Aal, and the head of the PFLP's military office in Lebanon, Imad Odeh, in an intelligence-based strike.</p>

<p>The IDF also reported that Hamas' Lebanon branch chief, Fateh Sherif, was killed in an airstrike. According to the IDF, Nidal Abdel-Aal took part in planning and executing terror attacks against Israel and directed terror activities in Judea and Samaria. He was responsible for the bus bombing attack in Beitar Illit and the shooting attack from a passing vehicle at the Huwara Junction in 2023.</p>

<p>In a post on X, the IDF stated, "Head of the Lebanon Branch of the PFLP terrorist organisation, Nidal Abdel-Aal, and Head of the PFLP's Military Office in Lebanon, Imad Odeh, were eliminated in a joint IDF and ISA intelligence-based strike. Abdel-Aal took part in planning and carrying out terror attacks against Israel and directed terror activities in Judea and Samaria, operating to establish terror infrastructure for attacks on Israeli civilians. Abdel-Aal directed the bus bombing attack in Beitar Illit on March 9, 2023, and the shooting attack from a passing vehicle at the Huwara Junction on March 25, 2023, during which two IDF soldiers were injured."</p>

<p>According to the IDF, Sherif was responsible for coordinating Hamas' terror activities in Lebanon with Hezbollah operatives, as well as Hamas' efforts in Lebanon to recruit operatives and acquire weapons.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3qap7rg_lebanon-strike_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The IDF further asserted that the facility posed a threat to Lebanese and international airspace]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-informed-us-of-limited-ground-operations-in-lebanon-says-state-department-6687301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Informs US Of 'Limited Ground Op' Against Hezbollah In Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-informed-us-of-limited-ground-operations-in-lebanon-says-state-department-6687301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:47:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has told the United States it is conducting limited ground operations focused on Hezbollah infrastructure in Lebanon near the border with Israel, the State Department said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has told the United States it is conducting limited ground operations focused on Hezbollah infrastructure in Lebanon near the border with Israel, the State Department said on Monday.</p>

<p>"This is what they have informed us that they are currently conducting, which are limited operations targeting Hezbollah infrastructure near the border," State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>Asked to confirm they were limited ground operations, he said: "That is our understanding."</p>

<p>Indications grew on Monday that Israel was on the verge of sending ground troops into Lebanon, two weeks into an assault on the Iranian-backed Hezbollah militia that culminated in the assassination of its leader, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>A U.S. official who spoke on condition of anonymity told Reuters the positioning of Israeli troops suggested a ground incursion could be imminent.</p>

<p>After two weeks of intensive airstrikes and a string of assassinations of Hezbollah commanders, Israel has suggested ever more strongly that a land invasion is looming.</p>

<p>The Israeli attacks on militant targets in Lebanon are part of a conflict stretching from the Palestinian territories of Gaza and the occupied West Bank to Iranian-backed groups in Yemen and Iraq. The escalation has raised fears that the United States and Iran will be sucked into the conflict.</p>

<p>Miller said that the United States continues to support a ceasefire between Israel and Hezbollah but added that military pressure can at times enable diplomacy. He cautioned that military pressure can also lead to miscalculation and unintended consequences.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8a6ntim8_israel-army-reuters_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli attacks on militant targets in Lebanon are part of a conflict stretching from Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-calls-for-ceasefire-in-lebanon-but-israeli-incursion-seems-imminent-6687175]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Calls For Ceasefire In Lebanon But Israeli Incursion Seems Imminent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-calls-for-ceasefire-in-lebanon-but-israeli-incursion-seems-imminent-6687175]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:22:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden called for a ceasefire in Lebanon on Monday but a US official said Israeli troop deployments suggested a ground incursion against Hezbollah militants could be imminent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden called for a ceasefire in Lebanon on Monday but a US official said Israeli troop deployments suggested a ground incursion against Hezbollah militants could be imminent.</p>

<p>Asked about reports that Israeli ground troops were preparing to move into southern Lebanon, Biden told reporters that he was "comfortable with them (Israel) stopping."</p>

<p>Several top aides reinforced Biden's call for a ceasefire by urging a diplomatic resolution to the violence to allow tens of thousands of displaced Israelis and Lebanese to return to their homes along the border.</p>

<p>Washington "will continue to work with our partners in the region and around the world to advance a diplomatic resolution," Secretary of State Antony Blinken told a State Department conference.</p>

<p>But a U.S. official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said that the positioning of Israeli troops as observed by the United States suggested a ground incursion into Lebanon could be imminent.</p>

<p>The official declined to comment further or to provide details on the posture of Israeli forces.</p>

<p>The US call for de-escalation follows two weeks of Israeli airstrikes and assassinations of Hezbollah commanders, including the Iran-backed group's leader, Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah, on Friday.</p>

<p>Israeli officials say they will do what is necessary to return some 70,000 citizens evacuated from northern Israeli communities after Hezbollah on Oct. 8 began rocket strikes in support of a Hamas assault on Israel from Gaza the previous day.</p>

<p>Speaking to troops deployed along Israel's northern border, Defence Minister Yoav Gallant hinted at a looming ground incursion.</p>

<p>"We will use all the means that may be required - your forces, other forces, from the air, from the sea, and on land. Good luck," Gallant said.</p>

<p>The Biden administration fears the killing of Nasrallah and further Israeli military action could ignite a wider regional conflict.</p>

<p>The U.S. envoy to the United Nations urged continued diplomacy to halt the violence in Lebanon and Gaza.</p>

<p>"We want to find a path to peace, so that Palestinians and Israelis have safety and Lebanese and Israelis living on the northern border find security and safety as well," U.S. Ambassador to the U.N. Linda Thomas-Greenfield told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jvv72ca_israel-attack-on-beirut_625x300_30_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US call for de-escalation follows two weeks of Israeli airstrikes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-important-dates-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6687136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A List Of Important Dates In 2024 US Presidential Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-important-dates-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6687136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:16:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the November 5 US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat, will face each other in the Nov. 5 U.S. presidential election. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Here is a timeline of events related to the election between now and Inauguration Day next January.</p>

<p>- <strong>Oct. 1</strong>: Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance and Democratic rival Tim Walz will take part in a debate hosted by CBS News.</p>

<p>-<strong> Nov. 5: Election Day</strong></p>

<p>- Later in November: It could take days for the election result to be known, especially if it is close and mail-in ballots are a factor.</p>

<p>- <strong>Nov. 26</strong>: Trump, the first sitting or former U.S. president to be convicted of a crime, is due to be sentenced in the Manhattan hush money case where he was found guilty of falsifying documents to cover up a payment to silence a porn star. Trump has denied wrongdoing and sentencing was originally due to take place on Sept. 18.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- <strong>Dec. 17</strong>: Electors, who together form the Electoral College, meet in their respective states or the District of Columbia to select the president and vice president.</p>

<p>- <strong>Dec. 25</strong>: The electoral votes must be received by the president of the Senate - a role held by the vice president, currently Harris - and the archivist by this date.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>2025</strong></p>

<p>- <strong>Jan. 6</strong>: The vice president presides over the Electoral College vote count at a joint session of Congress, announces the results and declares who has been elected.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ahead of the count on Jan. 6, 2021, Trump lambasted his vice president, Mike Pence, for refusing to try to prevent Congress from certifying Biden's win. On that day, the U.S. Capitol was attacked by Trump supporters trying to stop the count. Biden's win was certified early the next day.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Congress has since passed the Electoral Count Reform and Presidential Transition Improvement Act of 2022, which requires approval of one-fifth of the House and Senate to consider a challenge to a state's results - a much higher bar than existed before, when any single lawmaker from each chamber could trigger a challenge.</p>

<p>- <strong>Jan. 20:</strong> The inauguration of the election winner and their vice president takes place. At this ceremony, the victor and the vice president are officially sworn into office.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/tiie9gi4_us-elections-reuters_625x300_08_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The voting will take place on November 5.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-explain-mount-everests-more-than-expected-growth-6686986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Explain Mount Everest's 'More Than Expected' Growth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-explain-mount-everests-more-than-expected-growth-6686986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:51:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mount Everest is Earth's tallest mountain - towering 5.5 miles (8.85 km) above sea level - and is still growing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mount Everest is Earth's tallest mountain - towering 5.5 miles (8.85 km) above sea level - and is still growing.</p>

<p>While it and the rest of the Himalayas are continuing an inexorable uplift that dates back to their birth roughly 50 million years ago when the Indian subcontinent collided with Eurasia, Everest is growing more than expected from this alone. Scientists now think they know the reason why, and it has to do with the monumental merger of two nearby river systems.</p>

<p>Everest has gained roughly 49-164 feet (15-50 meters) in height due to this change in the regional river system, with the Kosi river merging with the Arun river approximately 89,000 years ago, the researchers estimated. That translates to an uplift rate of roughly 0.01-0.02 inches (0.2-0.5 millimetres) per year.</p>

<p>The geological process at work, they said, is called isostatic rebound. It involves the rise of land masses on Earth's crust when the weight of the surface diminishes. The crust, Earth's outermost layer, essentially floats atop a mantle layer made of hot, semi-liquid rock.</p>

<p>In this case, the merger of the rivers - more like a hostile takeover, with the Kosi subjugating the Arun as the rivers changed course over time - resulted in accelerated erosion that has carried off huge amounts of rock and soil, reducing the weight of the region near Everest.</p>

<p>"Isostatic rebound can be likened to a floating object adjusting its position when weight is removed," said geoscientist Jin-Gen Dai of China University of Geosciences in Beijing, one of the leaders of the study published on Monday in the journal Nature Geoscience.</p>

<p>"When a heavy load, such as ice or eroded rock, is removed from the Earth's crust, the land beneath slowly rises in response, much like a boat rising in water when cargo is unloaded," Dai added.</p>

<p>The main gorge of the merged river system is located approximately 28 miles (45 km) east of Everest.</p>

<p>The researchers, who used numerical models to simulate the evolution of the river system, estimated that isostatic rebound accounts for about 10% of Everest's annual uplift rate.</p>

<p>This geological process is not unique to the Himalayas.</p>

<p>"A classic example is in Scandinavia, where the land is still rising in response to the melting of thick ice sheets that covered the region during the last Ice Age. This process continues today, affecting coastlines and landscapes, thousands of years after the ice retreated," Dai said.</p>

<p>Study co-author Adam Smith, a University College London doctoral student in Earth sciences, said GPS measurements reveal the continued rising of Everest and the rest of the Himalayas.</p>

<p>This uplift outpaces the continued surface erosion caused by factors such as wind, rain and river flow. As this erosion continues, Everest's uplift rate from isostatic rebound may increase, Smith said.</p>

<p>Neighbouring peaks including Lhotse, the world's fourth highest, and Makalu, the fifth highest, also get a boost from the same process. Lhotse is experiencing an uplift rate similar to Everest. Makalu, situated closer to the Arun, has a slightly higher uplift rate.</p>

<p>"This research underscores our planet's dynamic nature. Even a seemingly immutable feature like Mount Everest is subject to ongoing geological processes, reminding us that Earth is constantly changing, often in ways imperceptible in our daily lives," Dai said.</p>

<p>Earth's rigid outer part is divided into colossal plates that move gradually over time in a process called plate tectonics, with the Himalayas rising following a collision between two plates.</p>

<p>Everest, also called Sagarmatha in Nepali and Chomolungma in Tibetan, is situated on the border between Nepal and the Tibet Autonomous Region of China. It was named for George Everest, a 19th-century British surveyor in India.</p>

<p>"Mount Everest occupies a unique place in human consciousness," Dai said.</p>

<p>"Physically, it represents Earth's highest point, giving it immense significance simply by virtue of its stature," Dai added. "Culturally, Everest is sacred to local Sherpa and Tibetan communities. Globally, it symbolizes the ultimate challenge, embodying human endurance and our drive to surpass perceived limits."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/q82v1fjo_mount-everest_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The geological process at work, they said, is called isostatic rebound.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nowhere-in-middle-east-israel-cannot-reach-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-iran-6686791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Nowhere In Middle East Israel Cannot Reach": Netanyahu Warns Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nowhere-in-middle-east-israel-cannot-reach-benjamin-netanyahu-warns-iran-6686791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:28:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu issued a fresh warning to Iran Monday, saying there was no place in the Middle East beyond Israel's reach amid a flurry of strikes against Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu issued a fresh warning to Iran Monday, saying there was no place in the Middle East beyond Israel's reach amid a flurry of strikes against Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>In a video statement made in English, Netanyahu addressed the people of Iran and warned that their government was bringing them "closer to the abyss".</p>

<p>"With every passing moment, the regime is bringing you -- the noble Persian people -- closer to the abyss," said Netanyahu.</p>

<p>"There is nowhere in the Middle East Israel cannot reach," the prime minister added, warning the people of Iran that their "regime plunges our region deeper into darkness and deeper into war".</p>

<p>"Don't let a small group of theocrats crush your hopes and your dreams," Netanyahu said.</p>

<p>Israel has in recent days been mounting heavy air strikes in Lebanon against the "Axis of Resistance", a network of Iran-aligned militant groups in the region, including in Syria, Yemen and Iraq.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike in Beirut Friday killed Hassan Nasrallah, the head of the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah which has been armed and financed by the Islamic Republic for years.</p>

<p>Iran has also vowed to avenge the killing of Abbas Nilforoushan, a top commander of the Quds Force, the foreign operations arm of Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps, who died alongside the Hezbollah leader on Friday.</p>

<p>In his video statement, Netanyahu expressed hope for a future "when Iran is finally free", saying it would "come a lot sooner than people think".</p>

<p>"Everything will be different," he said. "Our two countries, Israel and Iran, will be at peace. Iran will thrive as never before."</p>

<p>Netanyahu's comments came hours after Iran's foreign ministry spokesman said the country had no plans to send its fighters to directly confront Israel.</p>

<p>"There is no need to send extra or volunteer forces of the Islamic Republic of Iran," said foreign ministry spokesman Nasser Kanani, adding that Lebanon and fighters in the Palestinian territories "have the capability and strength to defend themselves against the aggression".</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian visited Hezbollah's office in Tehran "to pay tribute" to Nasrallah, according to the government's website.</p>

<p>Supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei -- who has the final say in all matters of the state in Iran -- has vowed that Nasrallah's death "will not be in vain".</p>

<p>Khamenei said Israel was "too weak to cause significant damage to the solid construction of Hezbollah in Lebanon" and called on the "Axis of Resistance" to stand with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>"Lebanon will make the aggressor and the evil enemy regretful," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/3b6ofdcg_netanyahu_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu expressed hope for a future "when Iran is finally free". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-vows-to-keep-fighting-israel-after-nasrallahs-killing-in-strikes-6686787]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Vows To Keep Fighting Israel After Nasrallah's Killing In Strikes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-vows-to-keep-fighting-israel-after-nasrallahs-killing-in-strikes-6686787]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:27:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah vowed on Monday to keep fighting Israel and said it was ready to face any ground operation into Lebanon, after its leader was killed in an air strike that dealt the group a seismic blow.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah vowed on Monday to keep fighting Israel and said it was ready to face any ground operation into Lebanon after its leader was killed in an air strike that dealt the group a seismic blow.</p>

<p>In a televised address, the Iran-backed group's deputy chief Naim Qassem said a new leader to replace Hassan Nasrallah, who enjoyed cult status among his supporters, would be selected "at the earliest opportunity".</p>

<p>He also said the group was ready for any Israeli ground offensive, even though Israel's bombardment of its strongholds has in the past week killed a large number of its top commanders and officials.</p>

<p>Hezbollah began low-intensity cross-border strikes on Israeli troops a day after its Palestinian ally Hamas staged its unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7, triggering war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Israel said earlier this month that it was shifting its focus from Gaza to securing its northern border with Lebanon, in order to allow Israelis displaced since October to return to their homes.</p>

<p>It has also not ruled out a ground offensive in order to achieve its goals.</p>

<p>Israel's strikes on Lebanon have killed hundreds and forced hundreds of thousands more to flee their homes, and left people across the region fearful of more violence to come.</p>

<p>Qassem said Hezbollah would continue "confronting the Israeli enemy in support of Gaza and Palestine, in defence of Lebanon and its people, and in response to the assassinations and the killing of civilians".</p>

<p>Warning that any battle with Israel would be long, he said: "We will face any scenario and we are ready if Israel decides to enter by land, the resistance forces are ready for any ground confrontation."</p>

<p>On the other side of the border, Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told troops: "The elimination of Nasrallah is an important step, but it is not the final one."</p>

<p>"In order to ensure the return of Israel's northern communities, we will employ all of our capabilities, and this includes you," he said.</p>

<p><strong>- Beirut strike -</strong></p>

<p>Most of Israel's strikes have targeted Hezbollah strongholds in eastern and southern Lebanon and the southern suburbs of Beirut, the group's main bastion.</p>

<p>On Monday, a drone strike hit a building in the Cola district in central Beirut, with an armed Palestinian group saying it had killed three of its members.</p>

<p>The strike, the first in the centre of the city in years, sparked panic, with 41-year-old resident Mohammed al-Hoss saying "the kids were in shock" after his house was damaged.</p>

<p>"We are with Gaza and support the Palestinian cause, but our country cannot cope with us going to war," he said.</p>

<p>"Our country is in a wretched state. They (Israel) finished with Gaza and they have come to Lebanon."</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry also reported the strike, saying it had killed four people and wounded four others. Israel has yet to comment.</p>

<p>Palestinian Islamist group Hamas later announced that its leader in Lebanon, Fatah Sharif Abu al-Amine, had been killed along with his wife and two children in another strike on Al-Bass refugee camp in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Israeli military confirmed it had "eliminated" Sharif in a strike.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said six rescuers affiliated with Hezbollah were killed in an Israeli strike Monday.</p>

<p>Around Lebanon, Israeli strikes killed more than 100 people on Sunday, including 45 near the southern city of Sidon, according to the ministry.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Health Minister Firass Abiad said Saturday that 1,030 people including 87 children had been killed since September 16.</p>

<p>UN refugee agency chief Filippo Grandi said "well over 200,000 people are displaced inside Lebanon", while more than 100,000 have fled to neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Najib Mikati said up to one million people may have been uprooted, in potentially the "largest displacement movement" in Lebanon's history.</p>

<p><strong>- Yemen strikes -</strong></p>

<p>The violence in Lebanon has raised fears of a much wider conflagration in the region.</p>

<p>On Monday, the Israeli army said it "successfully intercepted a suspicious aerial target that crossed from Lebanon into Israeli territory".</p>

<p>Israel said it also carried out strikes on Sunday targeting Iran-backed Huthis in Yemen that the rebels said killed four people and wounded 33.</p>

<p>The raids in Yemen came a day after the Huthis said they launched a missile at Israel's Ben Gurion airport, trying to hit it as Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was returning from New York.</p>

<p>Iran has said Nasrallah's killing would bring about Israel's "destruction", though the foreign ministry said Monday it would not deploy any fighters to confront Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanon began a three-day national mourning period for Nasrallah on Monday, with flags flying at half-mast.</p>

<p>In Israel, some had mixed feelings about the Hezbollah chief's killing.</p>

<p>"Nasrallah was responsible for the deaths of many Israelis, so it is good news," said Matan Sofer, 24, in the northern town of Rosh Pina.</p>

<p>"But do we risk it getting worse, who knows?"</p>

<p><strong>- Calls for halt -</strong></p>

<p>World leaders have called for a de-escalation.</p>

<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot met with the Lebanese premier in Beirut Monday, and said his government sought "an immediate halt" in the strikes.</p>

<p>He is the first high-level foreign diplomat to visit since the Israeli strikes intensified.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, whose government is Israel's top arms supplier, said Sunday a wider war "really has to be avoided".</p>

<p>In Gaza, AFP journalists said the number of air strikes across the territory has dropped significantly in recent days.</p>

<p>Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,615 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/edmrg2ao_israelhezbollah-conflict_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[srael said earlier this month that it was shifting its focus from Gaza to Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-issues-helpline-numbers-for-citizens-stranded-in-nepal-floods-6686776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Issues Helpline Numbers For Citizens Stranded In Nepal Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-issues-helpline-numbers-for-citizens-stranded-in-nepal-floods-6686776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 22:25:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Monday issued helpline numbers for its citizens stranded in Nepal due to floods and landslides during the past few days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Monday issued helpline numbers for its citizens stranded in Nepal due to floods and landslides during the past few days.</p>

<p>The advisory follows severe flooding and landslides triggered by record rainfall over the weekend, which caused widespread damage across Nepal.</p>

<p>In a post on social media platform X, the Indian Embassy in Nepal expressed concern at the current situation, stating, "There has been widespread damage due to floods and landslides on account of record rainfall over the weekend. Our thoughts are with everyone affected."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">3/3 Indian citizens in Nepal who require assistance may contact the following emergency numbers (with WhatsApp):<br />
<br />
+977-9851316807 - [Emergency Helpline]<br />
<br />
+977-9851107021- [Attache (Consular)]<br />
<br />
+977-9749833292 - [ASO (Consular)]</p>
 IndiaInNepal (@IndiaInNepal) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiaInNepal/status/1840680229406453998?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Embassy acknowledged that it has received reports of Indian citizens being stranded due to the natural disaster and is coordinating with Nepali authorities to ensure the safe evacuation and return of these individuals.</p>

<p>"The Embassy is in touch with some of these groups and arranging for their safe return," the advisory stated.</p>

<p>To assist stranded citizens, the Embassy issued three helpline numbers for those in need of help.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the death count from the devastating floods and landslides in Nepal neared 200 by Monday afternoon, with 30 people reported missing and 194 others injured, according to Nepal's Home Ministry.</p>

<p>Rescue operations have saved over 4,500 people, with security forces continuing efforts to clear blocked highways and reach affected areas.</p>

<p>Government data also revealed that 1,327 houses were destroyed, and 19 major highways across Nepal suffered damage, further complicating rescue and recovery efforts.</p>

<p>Security forces remain mobilised to clear blocked roads and assist in ongoing rescue missions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f2ibqhho_nepal-floods-ians_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian Embassy in Nepal issued three helpline numbers for those in need of help. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-patriotic-choice-new-york-times-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6686382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Only Patriotic Choice": NYT Endorses Kamala Harris For President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/only-patriotic-choice-new-york-times-endorses-kamala-harris-for-president-6686382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 21:30:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The New York Times editorial board on Monday endorsed Kamala Harris, calling the Democrat "the only patriotic choice for president" in the race against Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times editorial board on Monday endorsed Kamala Harris, calling the Democrat "the only patriotic choice for president" in the race against Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>But the paper did not even mention the vice president's name until the fourth paragraph of its written endorsement -- instead focusing attention on Trump's unworthiness for the presidency, calling him morally and temperamentally "unfit."</p>

<p>"This unequivocal, dispiriting truth -- Donald Trump is not fit to be president -- should be enough for any voter who cares about the health of our country and the stability of our democracy to deny him re-election."</p>

<p>It's an "anyone but Trump" approach that The New Yorker took one day prior, with editors at the magazine saying the Republican represents the "ongoing assault on the stability, the nerves, and the nature of the United States."</p>

<p>In its lengthy endorsement, the Times acknowledged Harris "may not be the perfect candidate for every voter, especially those who are frustrated and angry about our government's failures to fix what's broken."</p>

<p>"Yet we urge Americans to contrast Ms. Harris's record with her opponent's," the paper said. "Ms. Harris is more than a necessary alternative."</p>

<p>The Times editorial board has not thrown its weight behind a Republican for president since 1956 when it backed Dwight Eisenhower.</p>

<p>But the paper emphasized that this election is "about something more foundational" than "competing politics and principles" in a two-party system.</p>

<p>"Unless American voters stand up to him, Mr Trump will have the power to do profound and lasting harm to our democracy," the paper wrote.</p>

<p>The Times said voters are right to ask more from Harris when it comes to policy specifics: "Given the stakes of this election, Ms. Harris may think that she is running a campaign designed to minimize the risks of an unforced error... under the belief that being the only viable alternative to Mr. Trump may be enough to bring her to victory."</p>

<p>"That strategy may ultimately prove winning, but it's a disservice to the American people and to her own record."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, it called the Republican Party "little more than an instrument" of Trump's "quest to regain power" and claimed a second Trump term "would be much more damaging and divisive than the first."</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris is the only choice," the editorial board said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hvdvasi_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Times said voters are right to ask more from Harris when it comes to policy specifics.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-to-pay-22-6-million-to-settle-women-trainees-sex-bias-lawsuit-6686042]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI To Pay $22.6 Million To Settle Women Trainees' Sex Bias Lawsuit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-to-pay-22-6-million-to-settle-women-trainees-sex-bias-lawsuit-6686042]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 30 Sep 2024 20:43:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Justice has agreed to pay $22.6 million to settle a lawsuit by 34 women who claim they were wrongly dismissed from the FBI's agent training academy because of their sex.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Department of Justice has agreed to pay $22.6 million to settle a lawsuit by 34 women who claim they were wrongly dismissed from the FBI's agent training academy because of their sex, according to a court filing on Monday.</p>

<p>The settlement, which must be approved by a federal judge in Washington, D.C., would resolve a 2019 class action claiming the FBI, which is part of the Justice Department, had a widespread practice of forcing out female trainees.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/laabhvko_fbi-generic_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It claimed FBI had a widespread practice of forcing out female trainees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>