<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:30:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-where-will-sheikh-hasina-go-bangladesh-ex-pms-options-after-dhaka-exit-6290306]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Where Will Sheikh Hasina Go? Bangladesh Ex-PM's Options After Dhaka Exit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-where-will-sheikh-hasina-go-bangladesh-ex-pms-options-after-dhaka-exit-6290306]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 12:18:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two days back, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh Prime Minister, fled capital Dhaka amid violent protests demanding her ouster and landed near Delhi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two days back, Sheikh Hasina resigned as Bangladesh Prime Minister, fled capital Dhaka amid violent protests demanding her ouster and landed near Delhi. Since then, there has been speculation on where she is headed next. Right after her escape from Dhaka, some reports had claimed that the 76-year-old leader plans to seek asylum in the UK. But with London hesitating, the Awami League leader, it is learnt, is looking at other options.</p>

<p><strong>What Sheikh Hasina's Son Said</strong></p>

<p>In an interview to NDTV, Sheikh Hasina's son and Awami League leader Sajeeb Wazed Joy said reports claiming that his mother sought asylum in the UK are incorrect. "She has not requested asylum anywhere, so the question of the UK or US not responding yet is not true. My mother was planning to retire after this term anyway. She is done with politics in Bangladesh."</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's daughter Saima Wazed is WHO's Regional Director for South-East Asia and lives in Delhi. But a Twitter post she put up suggests that she has not met Sheikh Hasina after her escape from Dhaka. "Heartbroken with the loss of life in my country that I love. So heartbroken that I cannot see and hug my mother during this difficult time. I remain committed to my role as RD @WHOSEARO@WHO#HealthForAll#OneWHO," she posted on X.</p>

<p><strong>What Has UK Said</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's sister Sheikh Rehana is a UK citizen, and Rehana's daughter Tulip Siddiq is a Labour Party politician and a minister in the Keir Starmer government. Also, the UK has a record of giving refuge to several prominent figures of the subcontinent, including former Pakistan president Pervez Musharraf and former Pakistan Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif. So soon after she fled Dhaka, multiple reports predicted that she is headed to the UK.</p>

<p>But the UK Home Office told NDTV that British immigration rules do not allow individuals to travel to that country to seek asylum or temporary refuge. A spokesperson also said individuals seeking asylum must do so "in the first safe country they reach".</p>

<p>"The UK has a proud record of providing protection for people who need it. However, there is no provision for someone to be allowed to travel to the UK to seek asylum or temporary refuge," the Home office said.</p>

<p><strong>Is US An Option?</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina's son Joy is based in the US, but the chances of her moving there are slim after Washington DC and Dhaka's ties nosedived during her tenure. In fact, earlier this year, when Awami League stormed to victory in the Bangladesh election, the US State Department had said, "The United States remains concerned by the arrests of thousands of political opposition members and by reports of irregularities on elections day. The United States shares the view with other observers that these elections were not free or fair and we regret that not all parties participated."</p>

<p>While some reports say the US has cancelled Sheikh Hasina's visa after she resigned as Prime Minister, there has been no official confirmation and authorities have said visa records are confidential.</p>

<p>Earlier, after Sheikh Hasina fled the country, the US had said it stands with the people of Bangladesh. "We welcome the announcement of an interim government and urge any transition be conducted in accordance with Bangladesh's laws," State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller had said, flagging reports of human rights abuses, casualties, and injuries during the violent protests against the Awami League government.</p>

<p><strong>What About India?</strong></p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina has been in India since she landed here Monday. Addressing the Parliament on the Bangladesh situation, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said Sheikh Hasina had sought approval to come to India on a very short notice.</p>

<p>The government, according to reports, has told an all-party meeting that they have given time to the veteran politician to decide on her next move. Sheikh Hasina is in a state of shock and the government is giving her time to recover before it discusses these issues, sources have said.</p>

<p>New Delhi also faces a diplomatic dilemma here. It does not want to be seen as overtly backing the ousted leader because that may complicate its relationship with the new dispensation in Bangladesh,a a strategic partner geopolitically. At the same time, the history of Sheikh Hasina's relationship with India must also be kept in mind. Long before she became Prime Minister, the Indira Gandhi government had given her refuge after her whole family, including father Mujibur Rahaman, was assassinated during the 1975 unrest in Bangladesh. So abandoning her at this point will also not be an easy decision, considering her equations with Delhi.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina was forced to resign as Bangladesh PM amid violent protests demanding her exit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-vice-president-doesnt-answer-questions-jd-vance-slams-kamala-harris-6290102]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Vice President Doesn't Answer Questions": JD Vance Slams Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-vice-president-doesnt-answer-questions-jd-vance-slams-kamala-harris-6290102]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:45:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican vice-presidential candidate and Ohio Senator JD Vance tried to confront Vice President Kamala Harris on the tarmac as their planes arrived at about the same time in Wisconsin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican vice-presidential candidate and Ohio Senator JD Vance tried to confront Vice President Kamala Harris on the tarmac as their planes arrived at about the same time in Wisconsin.</p>

<p>The video captured by Reuters shows Vance approaching a press gaggle at the airport and said to have a closer look at Air Force Two. He said that Kamala Harris does not respond to reporters.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters, he said, "I figured I'd come by and just get a good look at the plane because hopefully, it's going to be my plane in a few months."</p>

<p>"But I also thought you guys might get lonely because the Vice President doesn't answer questions from reporters and hasn't for 17 days," he added. "Have they given you guys an explanation for why she won't take questions from reporters? No. Nobody? Okay, great," he asked the reporters.</p>

<p>He said that Kamala Harris should change her mind, as it would be good for the Americans.</p>

<p>Vance said, "Well, I hope that she changes her mind, because it'd be good for the American people, and I think it'd be good for you all.She actually ran a real campaign instead of one from a basement with a teleprompter."&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I thought the reporters traveling with Kamala might be a little lonely given that she never answers questions from them, so I figured I'd come say hello and check out my new plane while I was at it. <a href="https://t.co/OPEh0UKBDc">https://t.co/OPEh0UKBDc</a></p>
— JD Vance (@JDVance) <a href="https://twitter.com/JDVance/status/1821252923919364126?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mentioning the encounter on X, Vance stated, "I thought the reporters travelling with Kamala might be a little lonely given that she never answers questions from them, so I figured I'd come say hello and check out my new plane while I was at it."</p>

<p>Kamala Harris and her running mate, Tim Walz, posed for pictures with Girl Scouts Troop #3307 on the tarmac shortly before Vance spoke to reporters. The two leaders appeared to have left seconds before their rival walked over, the New York Post reported.</p>

<p>Harris' campaign tried to make fun of Vance by sharing a video of his plane landing at Eau Claire airport with the TikTok-style oral caption, "all of a sudden, I hear this agitating, grating voice."</p>

<p>In response to their post, Donald Trump-Vance campaign spokesman Steven Cheung stated, "Make sure AF2 is deep cleaned because Lord only knows what @KamalaHarris and her team have done on there."</p>

<p>"The smell alone on that plane must be crazy," he added.</p>

<p>Vance's statement comes after he accused Walz of "stolen valour" and criticized Harris' performance as US President Joe Biden's designated point person on reducing illegal immigration at a Michigan event earlier in the day, the New York Post reported.</p>

<p>He called it "insulting" to Americans that Harris has not been giving interviews. He said, "I'd love her to just answer what she wants to do and also explain why every single position she has has changed."</p>

<p>Criticising Harris for her decisions regarding the US border, Vance said, "She pretends to be a tough-on-crime prosecutor and yet here she is wanting to defund the police. She's the border czar, yet she's opened up the American southern border."</p>

<p>Vance also slammed Walz after the Minnesota governor mocked him at his first rally as Harris' running mate in Philadelphia on Tuesday, according to a New York Post report.</p>

<p>"What bothers me about Tim Waltz is the stolen valour garbage," Vance said of Walz, who left the National Guard in 2005 shortly after his battalion was ordered to deploy to the Iraq War.</p>

<p>Vance asked Walz not to pretend to be something that he is not. JD Vance, who did serve in the Iraq War, said: "Do not pretend to be something that you're not. And if he wants to criticize me for getting an Ivy League education, I'm proud of the fact that my mamaw supported me, and that I was able to make something of myself. I'd be ashamed if I was him and I lied about my military service.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e9fu8kmo_jd-vance-kamala-harris_625x300_26_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance said that Kamala Harris should change her mind, as it would be good for the Americans (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/july-2024-sees-2-warmest-days-ever-becomes-second-hottest-month-on-record-6289981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[July 2024 Sees 2 Warmest Days Ever Becomes Second Hottest Month On Record]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/july-2024-sees-2-warmest-days-ever-becomes-second-hottest-month-on-record-6289981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:27:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Last month was the second hottest July for the planet on record, breaking a 13-month period when each month was warmest, which had been in part fuelled by the warming El Nino weather pattern.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month was the second hottest July for the planet on record, breaking a 13-month period when each month was warmest, which had been in part fuelled by the warming El Nino weather pattern, the European Union's Copernicus Climate Change Service said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The month was 1.48 degrees Celsius (2.7 degrees Fahrenheit) above the pre-industrial reference of 1850-1990, Copernicus said in a monthly report, while the last 12 months were 1.64 C above the pre-industrial average due to climate change.</p>

<p>July also recorded the two hottest days on record.</p>

<p>Copernicus attributes the high temperatures largely to greenhouse gas emissions from fossil fuel-based industries and noted that oceans not normally impacted by El Nino saw an unusual rise in temperatures.</p>

<p>"This El Nino has ended but this magnitude of global temperature rises, the big picture is quite similar to where we were a year ago," Julien Nicolas, a climate researcher with Copernicus, told Reuters.</p>

<p>"We are not done with temperature records causing heatwaves ... We know this long-term warming trend can be with a very high level of confidence related to the human impact on climate."</p>

<p>Above-average temperatures were recorded in southern and eastern Europe, the western United States, western Canada, most of Africa, the Middle East, Asia and eastern Antarctica.</p>

<p>Near or below-average temperatures were seen in northwestern Europe, western Antarctica, parts of the United States, South America and Australia.</p>

<p>July 2024 was also wetter than average in northern Europe and southeastern Turkey while drought warnings persisted in southern and eastern Europe.</p>

<p>Arctic sea ice was down more than in 2022 and 2023 at 7% below average though not as severe as the record 14% drop in 2020. Antarctic sea ice was the second lowest extent for July at 11% below average compared with 15% below in July last year.</p>

<p>Global sea temperatures remain at near record highs with this July only 0.1 C below July last year, ending a 15-month consecutive new record streak.</p>

<p>"What we saw was surprising in terms of how much warmer it has been. That raises the question of what is happening to the ocean outside this natural climate pattern like El Nino or La Nina events. Are there shifts in the ocean currents?" Nicolas said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/tlk67lj8_europe-hot-summer_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[July 2024 was also wetter than average in northern Europe and South Eastern Turkey]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-carolina-anticipates-deluge-as-hurricane-debby-makes-landfall-6289975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Carolina Anticipates Deluge As Hurricane Debby Makes Landfall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-carolina-anticipates-deluge-as-hurricane-debby-makes-landfall-6289975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:23:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tropical Storm Debby is forecast to make landfall early Thursday and dump even more rain on the South Carolina coast, prompting fears of flash flooding in areas already soaked by the slow-moving weather system.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tropical Storm Debby is forecast to make landfall early Thursday and dump even more rain on the South Carolina coast, prompting fears of flash flooding in areas already soaked by the slow-moving weather system.</p>

<p>The storm could dump another 9 inches (23 cm) of rain in parts of eastern South Carolina on Thursday, forecasters said, with total accumulative rainfall in some spots hitting more than 25 inches since Debby started lashing the southeastern United States on Monday.</p>

<p>While Debby produced less rain on Wednesday than the previous days, Rich Bann, a meteorologist with the National Weather Service warned that Thursday would be different.</p>

<p>"Moisture has pulsed back into Debby," Bann said, noting that the storm picked up water as it spent the last day parked over the Atlantic Ocean off the coast of Georgia and South Carolina. "As Debby makes its way inland ... the threat of heavy rains will lead to flooding concerns."</p>

<p>Bann said that by Friday Debby would be dumping up to 4 inches of rain on Virginia up into Pennsylvania, where ground in some patches was already soaked from other storms this week, heightening flooding concerns there. By the weekend, the storm could also produce rain of up to 4 inches in central New York state and into northern Vermont.</p>

<p>At least six people have died in Florida and Georgia in the wake of the storm, which made landfall on Florida's Gulf Coast on Monday as a Category 1 hurricane and headed northeast.</p>

<p>Governors in the Carolinas, Florida and Georgia have declared states of emergency. The storm has already left neighbourhoods and communities underwater, washing out streets and inundating homes across the region.</p>

<p>Emergency management officials were keeping a close watch as the rainwater drained into the numerous river systems that snake through the Carolinas. The National Water Prediction Service forecast that seven waterways would reach major flood levels before the weather event runs its course.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ibe9etoo_storm-debby_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 6 people have died in Florida and Georgia in the wake of the Category 1 hurricane. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-may-use-spacexs-dragon-capsule-to-bring-sunita-williams-back-to-earth-6289919]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Went To Space For 8 Days, But Could Be Stuck Till Feb 2025]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-may-use-spacexs-dragon-capsule-to-bring-sunita-williams-back-to-earth-6289919]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 11:19:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What was meant to be a 10-day mission to the International Space Station (ISS) for the first NASA astronauts - Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams - to fly with Boeing could extend to eight months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What was meant to be a weeklong mission to the International Space Station (ISS) for the first NASA astronauts - Butch Wilmore and Sunita Williams - to fly with Boeing could extend to eight months.</p>

<p>NASA said on Wednesday that the two astronauts sent to International Space Station by Boeing's Starliner on a 10-day mission could return on SpaceX's Crew Dragon in February 2025 if Starliner is still deemed unsafe to return to Earth.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore took off aboard the Boeing Starliner in June and have been at the ISS since the sixth of that month. The Starliner has faced glitches in the propulsion system following a series of helium leaks and the astronauts</p>

<p>NASA is working on several return options including using SpaceX Dragon Crew. The Crew Dragon capsule would then be able to return to Earth with Starliner's crew of Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams in February 2025</p>

<p>Starliner spacecraft launched in June carrying two astronauts to the ISS in a high-stakes test mission required before NASA can certify the spacecraft for routine astronaut flights.</p>

<p>But the mission, initially expected to last about eight days, has been drawn out far longer by an array of problems with the craft's propulsion system that Boeing and NASA have been scrambling to fix.</p>

<p>The US space agency said Ms Williams, who is a veteran and is on her third space mission, investigated using fluid physics, such as surface tension, to overcome the lack of gravity when watering and nourishing plants being grown in space.</p>

<p>This is akin to gardening in space and is a very vital step towards understanding how plants grow and respond to microgravity conditions. The research will be crucial when humanity looks to establish various bases in the solar system and beyond.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/720ksnho_sunita-williams_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NASA is working on several return options including using SpaceX Dragon Crew.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-woman-arrested-for-singing-in-public-without-hijab-whereabouts-unknown-6289770]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Woman Jailed For Singing In Public Without Hijab, Whereabouts Unknown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-woman-arrested-for-singing-in-public-without-hijab-whereabouts-unknown-6289770]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 10:50:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This arrest is the latest example of Iran's strict enforcement of the mandatory hijab laws, which human rights activists have widely criticised.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zara Esmaeili, a young Iranian woman, was arrested and jailed for singing Amy Winehouse's song 'Back to Black' in public without wearing a hijab.&nbsp;<span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">According to a report in <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/07/iranian-woman-jailed-street-performance-amy-winehouse-without-hijab-21376746/?ico=mosaic_world">Metro</a></em>, she was taken into custody after her video went viral on social media</span>.&nbsp;A source close to the situation confirmed that ''Zara's family has been unable to locate her''.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="nl">Zara Esmaeili, een getalenteerde jonge zangeres uit Teheran, is gearresteerd vanwege haar moedige optredens zonder de verplichte hijab. Dit krachtige beeld van haar en een dansend meisje illustreert hoe de jonge generatie in Iran zich verzet tegen onderdrukking. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Iran?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Iran</a> <a href="https://t.co/DMc2soS1Gf">pic.twitter.com/DMc2soS1Gf</a></p>
— Shermin Amiri (@SherminAmiri) <a href="https://twitter.com/SherminAmiri/status/1819792987913666905?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Ms Esmaeli is known for performing without the mandatory hijab in public spaces like the metro and parks. Her performances on the streets of Tehran have been a form of protest against the Islamic Republic's oppressive laws, which restrict women's freedom and self-expression.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="de">? Islamische Republik Iran<br />
SÄNGERIN FESTGENOMMEN<br />
<br />
„Laut den uns vorliegenden Nachrichten wurde Zara Esmaeili, eine Künstlerin, die wegen ihres kraftvollen und warmen Gesangs in Straßen, Zügen, U-Bahnen und anderen Orten in den sozialen Medien Aufmerksamkeit erregt hat,… <a href="https://t.co/bsE5VBUDNZ">https://t.co/bsE5VBUDNZ</a> <a href="https://t.co/1cImupU177">pic.twitter.com/1cImupU177</a></p>
— In Lak‘ech ❤️☀️? (@inlakech77) <a href="https://twitter.com/inlakech77/status/1819491886937039132?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Faravaz Farvardin, Iranian singer and the founder of the Berlin-based Right to Sing Campaign condemned the arrest.</p>

<p>She wrote in a statement on X, ''Zara, an Iranian female singer, is imprisoned in the Tehran Central Detention Center (Fashafoueh) for the crime of singing in public. She is under the pressure of the interrogators to admit connection with activists and musicians outside Iran. This claim is a lie and made by the think tank of the Islamic Republic.''</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Zara,is currently imprisoned in the central detention center of Tehran.<br />
She is under the pressure of the interrogators to admit his connection with activists and musicians outside Iran.<br />
This allegation is a lie made by the Islamic Republic's think-tank.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/freexara?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#freexara</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ZaraEsmaeili?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ZaraEsmaeili</a> <a href="https://t.co/YMVMQgtQx4">pic.twitter.com/YMVMQgtQx4</a></p>
— faravaz (@faravaz1) <a href="https://twitter.com/faravaz1/status/1819784333017731256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
This arrest is the latest example of Iran's strict enforcement of the mandatory hijab laws, which human rights activists have widely criticized. This escalation is rooted in the decades-long rhetoric of Ayatollah Khomeini, Iran's supreme leader, who has denounced "Westoxication" - the perceived corruption of Iranian society by Western influences - since before and after the 1979 revolution. Her arrest also coincides with the authorities' introduction of a new initiative aimed at restricting women's autonomy, amidst the ongoing "Woman, Life, Freedom" movement.</p>

<p>Earlier, other Iranian artists have also faced persecution and arrest for expressing themselves freely.</p>

<p>While rapper Toomaj Salehi was arrested for his lyrics criticising the government and social issues, singer Shervin Hajipour was imprisoned for his song <em>'Baraye,'</em> which became an anthem for the "Woman, Life, Freedom" movement.</p>

<p>This movement gained momentum following the tragic death of Mahsa Amini in 2022, sparking widespread protests and demands for change.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/tqraanm_iranian-woman-jailed_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran prohibits women from singing or dancing in public]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-are-there-anti-racism-protests-riots-in-the-uk-6289614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Anti-Racism Protests And Riots Are Sweeping Across The UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-why-are-there-anti-racism-protests-riots-in-the-uk-6289614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 10:28:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A wave of riots, sparked by a deadly attack at a children's dance event and further fueled by a torrent of misinformation, has gripped parts of the United Kingdom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A wave of riots, sparked by a deadly attack at a children's dance event and further fueled by a torrent of misinformation, has gripped parts of the United Kingdom. What began as a community's grief over the tragic loss of three young girls has spiralled into nationwide chaos, with far-right groups using the moment to incite anti-immigration and anti-Muslim violence.</p>

<p><strong>What triggered the protests</strong></p>

<p>On July 29, three young girls, aged six to nine, were killed during a Taylor Swift-themed dance event in Southport, northern England. Eight other children and two adults also suffered stab wounds and were transferred to the hospital. The attacker, 17-year-old Axel Rudakubana, was arrested and charged with three counts of murder, 10 counts of attempted murder and one of possession of a blade.</p>

<p>Axel Rudakubana was born and raised in Cardiff, Wales. However, false information that he was an Islamist migrant quickly spread on social media. This misinformation incited violent anti-Muslim protests in Southport the following day, including an attempted attack on the local mosque.</p>

<p><strong>Spread of the riots</strong></p>

<p>On Wednesday evening, a sea of angry demonstrators descended upon Prime Minister Keir Starmer's Downing Street office, voicing their outrage over immigration and demanding action from the government. The crowd's chants of "Save our kids" and "We want our country back" filled the air as protesters clashed with police, hurling flares and smoke canisters towards the prime minister's residence.</p>

<p>The Metropolitan police reported 111 arrests and five injured officers, following a night of violent disorder. This comes after Tuesday's initial protests in Southport, where over 50 police officers were hurt and police vans were set ablaze.</p>

<p>Since then, riots have erupted in over 20 locations, including Sunderland, Manchester, Plymouth and Belfast, across Britain. These protests have involved hundreds of participants targeting migrants or Muslims, vandalising shops, and clashing with police.</p>

<p><strong>Who is behind the riots?</strong></p>

<p>Keir Starmer blames the recent violence on "far-right thuggery". Prominent anti-Muslim and anti-immigration activists, like Stephen Yaxley-Lennon, are accused of spreading false information to inflame tensions. Social media platforms have been criticised for not preventing the spread of disinformation, which has played a significant role in amplifying these false narratives.</p>

<p>According to police, the majority of those involved in the clashes were far-right agitators from outside the local areas. However, some individuals with local grievances or young people seeking excitement also joined the fray, police said. Meanwhile, counter-protesters and anti-fascist groups have gathered to oppose them.</p>

<p><strong>The motivation behind the riots</strong></p>

<p>Many rioters, describing themselves as "patriots", claimed that high immigration levels were undermining British society. They argued that immigration fueled violence and crime and that politicians favoured migrants. However, rights groups and anti-racist organisations rejected these claims as baseless, suggesting the true motive was extremism masked as patriotism.</p>

<p><strong>Government's response</strong></p>

<p>The Starmer-led government has taken swift action in response to the recent riots, making nearly 600 additional prison places available and deploying specialist officers to prevent the situation from spiralling. A 58-year-old British man has also been jailed for three years for violent disorder.</p>

<p>The government is also targeting those using social media to spread trouble, with one man charged for using threatening language to stir up racial hatred on Facebook. Science Minister Peter Kyle has met with representatives from major tech companies, like TikTok, Meta, Google and X, to prevent incitement and the spread of false information online.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c973pnao_anti-racism-protests-uk-x-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-unstable-situation-indian-visa-centres-in-bangladesh-closed-indefinitely-6289306]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unstable Situation": Indian Visa Centres In Bangladesh Closed Indefinitely]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bangladesh-violence-sheikh-hasina-unstable-situation-indian-visa-centres-in-bangladesh-closed-indefinitely-6289306]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 09:33:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[All Indian visa application centres in Bangladesh will remain closed until further notice after unrest in the neighbouring country forced Sheikh Hasina to resign as Prime Minister and flee the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All Indian visa application centres in Bangladesh will remain closed until further notice after unrest in the neighbouring country forced Sheikh Hasina to resign as Prime Minister and flee the country. The online portal to apply for Indian visa now has a message, "All IVACs will remain closed till further notice, due to unstable situation. Next application date will be informed through SMS &amp; It is requested to pick up the passport on the next working day."</p>

<p>This comes a day after New Delhi evacuated non-essential staff and their families from its High Commission and consulates in Bangladesh amid the volatile situation in the country. Indian diplomats, however, remain in the country and the missions are functional, sources in the government have said.</p>

<p>India has a high commission in Bangladesh capital Dhaka and consulates in Chittagong, Rajshahi, Khulna and Sylhet.</p>

<p>Massive protests against the Sheikh Hasina-led Awami League government in Bangladesh have forced the 76-year-old leader to resign as Prime Minister and flee to India.</p>

<p>An interim government backed by the Army is in the process of being formed. Nobel peace prize winner and Grameen Bank founder Muhammad Yunus will lead the caretaker government.</p>

<p>Addressing the Parliament on the neighbourhood situation, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has said that there are nearly 19,000 Indian nationals in Bangladesh of which 9,000 are students. Many of the students, he said, returned to India after the protests broke out. He has said the government is in close contact with the Indian community there. He has also said the government is monitoring the situation regarding minorities living in Bangladesh.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m70ochj_bangladesh-protests_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina has been forced to resign and flee Bangladesh amid violent protests]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/actor-shanto-khan-his-father-lynched-during-unrest-in-bangladesh-had-played-role-of-sheikh-mujibur-rahman-6289259]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Actor Shanto Khan, His Father Lynched During Unrest In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/actor-shanto-khan-his-father-lynched-during-unrest-in-bangladesh-had-played-role-of-sheikh-mujibur-rahman-6289259]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 09:24:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Actor Shanto Khan was lynched at Chandpur along with his father Selim Khan, owner of a renowned Bangladeshi production house.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Members of the Kolkata film industry on Wednesday expressed shock over the killing of Bangladeshi actor Shanto Khan along with his father, producer Selim Khan, during the unrest in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>The Kolkata-based actors, several of whom have worked with Shanto Khan in Bangladeshi film projects, however, did not want to comment on the reasons for the killing, saying those were internal matters of another country.</p>

<p>"I was stunned after hearing the news that he and his father were killed. We don't know the circumstances leading to their deaths. It saddens my heart to learn they were killed. Artists like us who thrive on art and creativity always yearn for peace, amity and brotherhood," said popular actor Rajatabha Dutta.</p>

<p>Dutta, who had worked with Shanto in the 2022 Bangladeshi film 'Bikkhov' (Resentment), told PTI that the young actor was cooperative and respectful on the sets.</p>

<p>"During our shoot in Chandpur (in Bangladesh) for the movie, he personally took care of my needs. He was attentive to my needs even at the hotel. I do not know how or why he had to die at such a young age when his career was looking up," he said.</p>

<p>The critically acclaimed actor said he does not wish to comment on the situation in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Shanto debuted with 'Prem Chor' in 2019 and later worked in 'Piya Re' in 2021, 'Bubujaan' in 2023 and 'Anto Nagar' in 2024.</p>

<p>Actor Kaushani Mukhopadhyay, who starred opposite Shanto in 'Piya Re', said, "I got the deeply disturbing news late Monday night and have remained distressed ever since." She recalled that Shanto had extended all hospitality to her and other actors from India during the shoot at Chandpur and Dhaka for the film and not for once did she feel like an outsider in a foreign land.</p>

<p>"Since I was senior in the industry, Shanto was very respectful towards me and shared his ambition of making a significant impact in the industry," Mukhopadhyay said.</p>

<p>"I believe in the triumph of humanity and hope the situation will soon turn normal there," she said.</p>

<p>Shanto, who also dabbled in modelling, had essayed the role of young Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman in the film 'Tungiparar Miya Bhai' in 2021.</p>

<p>Filmmaker Raj Chakraborty said, "Any death, be it of a protesting student, a policeman, an actor, a producer or a political activist, is shocking. All of us have fond memories of working in Bangladesh. I am not merely saying this as a stakeholder of the film industry, but also as a human being and a citizen of India.</p>

<p>Actor-director Parambrata Chatterjee, who had worked on several projects in Bangladesh, was also appalled at the killings in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>He denounced vandalizing statues of iconic figures during the turmoil there.</p>

<p>According to media reports, Shanto was lynched at Chandpur on Monday night along with his father Selim Khan, owner of a renowned Bangladeshi production house, who had financed films 'Tungi Parar Miya Bhai', 'Commando' and others.</p>

<p>Selim Khan was an expelled leader of the Awami League, the supporters of which have been facing attacks for the past several days.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina who was heading the Awami League government in the country resigned on Monday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v3njs4gg_shanto-khan_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shanto Khan debuted with 'Prem Chor' in 2019]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-resignation-heartbroken-that-i-cant-see-hug-her-sheikh-hasinas-daughter-6289024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Heartbroken That I Can't See, Hug Her": Sheikh Hasina's Daughter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-resignation-heartbroken-that-i-cant-see-hug-her-sheikh-hasinas-daughter-6289024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 08:30:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's daughter today said she was "heartbroken" that she could not "see and hug her mother" after her ouster.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's daughter today said she was "heartbroken" that she could not "see and hug her mother" after her ouster amid massive turmoil in her home country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Heartbroken with the loss of life in my country Bangladesh that I love. So heartbroken that I cannot see and hug my mother during this difficult time. I remain committed to my role as RD," Saima Wazed wrote in a post on X - earlier known as Twitter.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Heartbroken with the loss of life in my country ?? that I love. So heartbroken that I cannot see and hug my mother during this difficult time. I remain committed to my role as RD <a href="https://twitter.com/WHOSEARO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WHOSEARO</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/WHO?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WHO</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HealthForAll?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HealthForAll</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/OneWHO?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#OneWHO</a></p>
— Saima Wazed (@drSaimaWazed) <a href="https://twitter.com/drSaimaWazed/status/1821348386886324579?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>Saima Wazed is the Regional Director for South-East Asia at the World Health Organisation (WHO).</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, 76, was forced to resign as Prime Minister Monday evening after weeks-long protests over a jobs quota killed over 400 people. She fled Dhaka reportedly after the Bangladesh Army gave her a 45-minute ultimatum.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina left state capital Dhaka in a military aircraft for India after resigning. Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said the government is giving time to Sheikh Hasina to "recover" and let them know about her next move. "At very short notice, she requested approval to come for the moment to India. We simultaneously received a request for flight clearance from the Bangladesh authorities," he said.</p>

<p>Sources had earlier said wanted to go to London to claim sanctuary, but her son Sajeeb Wazed has dismissed the speculation.</p>

<p>Asked about multiple reports about UK's "silence" her request for asylum and revocation of her visa by the US, Mr Wazed said, "The reports about her requesting asylum are incorrect. She has not requested asylum anywhere. So the question of UK or US not responding yet is not true".</p>

<p>Sajeeb Wazed also expressed concern over the attacks on his mother's party leaders and minorities in the country amid massive political turmoil.</p>

<p>On being asked, what the future of Bangladesh looks like, Sajeeb Wazed Joy said Bangladesh runs the risk of becoming like Syria. "I wanted to say Pakistan, but It looks more like Bangladesh is becoming like Syria."</p>

<p>"They (people of Bangladesh) have made their future. They will have to live with it. It's going to be bleak, economic growth is going to stop, militancy will continue," he said.</p>

<p>Bangladesh's Nobel-winning microfinance pioneer Muhammad Yunus has been named the head of the military-backed interim government after the ouster of Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>The army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman sa the advisory council to be led by Mr Yunus may have 15 members.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6i75hnp8_sheikh-hasina-daughter-saima-wazed-twitter_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, 76, was forced to resign as Prime Minister Monday evening]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-set-to-get-interim-government-led-by-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-today-after-sheikh-hasinas-exit-due-to-students-protests-6288788]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Set To Get Interim Government Led By Nobel Winner Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-set-to-get-interim-government-led-by-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-today-after-sheikh-hasinas-exit-due-to-students-protests-6288788]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 07:27:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh is set to get an interim government headed by Nobel Peace Prize-winning economist Muhammad Yunus today, days after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was forced to resign amid violent student protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-to-lead-bangladesh-after-shunning-politics-6280701" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus</a>, Bangladesh's only Nobel laureate, is likely to be sworn in as chief adviser along with a team of advisers today.</li>
	<li>Mr Yunus, a harsh critic of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-security-meet-and-a-phone-call-the-hours-before-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6274604" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>, is due to arrive in Dhaka from Paris today, where he had been receiving medical treatment.</li>
	<li>Speaking to reporters before boarding a flight on Wednesday evening, he said, "I'm looking forward to going back home and see what's happening there and how we can organise ourselves to get out of the trouble that we're in."</li>
	<li>The 84-year-old, who has mostly stayed away from politics, is known as the 'banker to the poor' and was awarded the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize for founding a bank that pioneered fighting poverty with small loans to needy borrowers.</li>
	<li>He was chosen to lead the interim government during a meeting of Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin, military leaders, and the heads of the Students Against Discrimination group.</li>
	<li>On Wednesday, a court overturned Mr Yunus' conviction in a labour case in which he was handed a six-month jail sentence in January.</li>
	<li>The announcement of the new interim government was made shortly after Ms Hasina's dramatic exit on Monday from the country she ruled for five terms.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina, 76, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasinas-fall-leads-to-slump-in-india-bangladesh-border-trade-6280867" target="_blank">fled to India</a> and is currently taking shelter at an air base near Delhi.</li>
	<li>Student protests against controversial quotas for government jobs spiralled in July and more than 250 people were killed and thousands injured as protesters clashed with security forces and supporters of Ms Hasina's Awami League party.</li>
	<li>The protests were fuelled by tough economic conditions and political repression as well.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/56nalei8_muhammad-yunus_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh violence update: Mohammad Yunus is a harsh critic of Sheikh Hasina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-racism-protesters-take-to-streets-in-uk-after-days-of-unrest-6288569]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Anti-Racism Protests Erupt In UK Amid Unrest After Far-Right Demonstrations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-racism-protesters-take-to-streets-in-uk-after-days-of-unrest-6288569]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 06:16:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of anti-racism protesters have taken to the streets in many cities and towns of the UK to counter far-right demonstrations after days of unrest following Southport stabbing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of anti-racism protesters have taken to the streets in many cities and towns of the UK to counter far-right demonstrations after days of unrest following Southport stabbing.</p>

<p>By 11 pm on Wednesday, most of the planned far-right demonstrations, numbering more than 100, didn't materialize after the British government deployed heavy police force to maintain order and large numbers of anti-racist protesters swarmed streets in cities and towns like London, Bristol, Brighton, Birmingham, Liverpool, Hastings and Walthamstow, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Anti-racism protesters held placards with words such as "Smash fascism &amp; racism", "Refugees welcome. Stop the far-right" and "Love, not hate". In Brighton, only a small number of far-right protesters turned up and were outnumbered by huge anti-racism crowds.</p>

<p>This came as a relief for the UK after days of far-right protests, targeting Muslims and the immigrant population in general, gripped the country, resulting in police officers being injured, stores being looted, and hotels housing asylum-seekers being stormed.</p>

<p>The unrest was sparked by online disinformation that wrongly claimed the suspect who killed three children in Southport, northwest England, at the end of July was a Muslim immigrant. It was a 17-year-old boy named Axel Rudakubana born in Cardiff to Rwandan parents that was later charged with murder.</p>

<p>More than 100 rioters have been charged following the disorder and their cases have been swiftly processed in the court system. On Wednesday, three men were jailed, with one being given three years of prison time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c973pnao_anti-racism-protests-uk-x-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thousands of anti-racism protesters held placards with words such as smash fascism & racism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-new-interim-pm-muhammad-yunus-heads-home-to-be-sworn-in-today-6288483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh New Interim PM Muhammad Yunus Heads Home, To Be Sworn In Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-new-interim-pm-muhammad-yunus-heads-home-to-be-sworn-in-today-6288483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 05:50:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate economist Muhammad Yunus is expected to return to Bangladesh on Thursday, Bangladesh-based Dhaka Tribune reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Nobel Laureate economist Muhammad Yunus is expected to return to Bangladesh on Thursday, Bangladesh-based Dhaka Tribune reported.</p>

<p>Yunus will arrive at Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport in Dhaka on an Emirates flight from Dubai at 2.10 pm, subject to the flight being on time, Dhaka Tribune reported, quoting a statement from Yunus Centre.</p>

<p>Yunus' return comes as he is set to take on a significant role as head of the interim government, following a meeting with President Mohammed Shahabuddin.</p>

<p>Nahid Islam, a coordinator of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement, said that the oath-taking ceremony for Yunus, proposed as head of the interim government during a meeting with President Mohammed Shahabuddin, will take place the following day, Dhaka Tribune reported.</p>

<p>In a statement issued on Wednesday, Yunus Centre congratulated the students who played a key role in achieving the Second Victory Day and urged the public to avoid violence.</p>

<p>"I congratulate the brave students who took the lead in making our Second Victory Day possible and to the people for giving your total support to them. Let us make the best use of our new victory. Let us not let this slip away because of our mistakes. I fervently appeal to everybody to stay calm. Please refrain from all kinds of violence. I appeal to all students, members of all political parties and non-political people to stay calm," the statement read.</p>

<p>The statement highlighted the country's potential and urged the population to focus on building a better future. "This is our beautiful country with lots of exciting possibilities. We must protect and make it a wonderful country for us and for our future generations," Yunus Centre added in its statement.</p>

<p>Yunus Centre further said that violence is their enemy.</p>

<p>"Our youth is ready to give this leadership in creating a new world. Let us not miss the chance by going into any senseless violence. Violence is our enemy. Please don't create more enemies. Be calm and get ready to build the country. If we take the path of violence everything will be destroyed. Please stay calm. Help those around you to stay calm," it added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/udobbb28_muhammad-yunus_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus will arrive in Dhaka on an Emirates flight from Dubai at 2.10 pm today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tunisian-president-sacks-prime-minister-ahmed-hachani-without-any-explanation-6288421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tunisian President Sacks Prime Minister Without Any Explanation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tunisian-president-sacks-prime-minister-ahmed-hachani-without-any-explanation-6288421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 05:28:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tunisian President Kais Saied sacked his Prime Minister Ahmed Hachani without explanation on Wednesday and replaced him with social affairs minister Kamel Madouri, his office said in a statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tunisian President Kais Saied sacked his Prime Minister Ahmed Hachani without explanation on Wednesday and replaced him with social affairs minister Kamel Madouri, his office said in a statement.</p>

<p>Hachani had taken office on August 1 last year, replacing Najla Bouden, who was also dismissed without an official reason by Saied.</p>

<p>The president was democratically elected in 2019 but orchestrated a sweeping power grab in 2021 and is now seeking another term in office in elections on October 6.</p>

<p>The constitution was rewritten in 2022 to create a presidential regime whose parliament has extremely limited powers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hachani had earlier on Wednesday published a statement about government meetings to address difficulties affecting public transport.</p>

<p>Madouri had only taken on the social affairs portfolio in May.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/13k87f2_tunisia-president_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tunisian President Kais Saied sacked his Prime Minister Ahmed Hachani on Wednesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-israel-to-probe-video-of-prison-sex-abuse-6288391]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Urges Israel To Probe Video Of Prison Sex Abuse]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-urges-israel-to-probe-video-of-prison-sex-abuse-6288391]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 05:12:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Wednesday urged Israel to investigate and implement accountability after a video appeared to show soldiers sexually abusing a Palestinian prisoner.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Wednesday urged Israel to investigate and implement accountability after a video appeared to show soldiers sexually abusing a Palestinian prisoner.</p>

<p>A leaked surveillance video, broadcast on Israel's Channel 12, appeared to show soldiers picking out a prisoner at the Sde Teiman base, where Israel has been holding Palestinians detained during the Gaza war.</p>

<p>The Israeli soldiers seem to be performing sexual acts on the prisoner behind shields, with at least one of the troops with his hand on his own groin.</p>

<p>"We have seen the video and reports of sexual abuse of detainees are horrific," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>Freed Palestinian prisoners have made regular allegations of torture, rape and other abuses in custody that Israeli authorities have denied.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This week, UN experts warned of the "escalating use of torture" by Israel against Palestinian prisoners since the war in Gaza began and called for efforts to prevent crimes against humanity.</p>

<p>"Prisoners' human rights need to be respected in all cases, and when there are alleged violations, the government of Israel needs to take steps to investigate those who are alleged to have committed abuses and, if appropriate, hold them accountable," Miller said.</p>

<p>An Israeli military spokesperson contacted by AFP said the army was looking into the reports.</p>

<p>Miller said that the Israeli military investigation "ought to proceed swiftly."</p>

<p>The military late last month said it was opening an investigation into "suspected abuse" of a detainee at Sde Teiman after accounts by international media, United Nations agencies and human rights groups.</p>

<p>Nine soldiers were taken in for questioning, prompting far-right Israeli activists, some close to the government, to rush to Sde Teiman to show support for the accused, with several managing to break into the facility.</p>

<p>The United States has been a critical ally of Israel in the war but has repeatedly voiced alarm over the toll on civilians.</p>

<p>Hamas launched the deadliest-ever attack on Israel on October 7, leading to the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Hamas also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 who the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory response has killed 39,677 people in Gaza, according to Gaza's health ministry, which does not provide details on civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>The campaign has also reduced much of the Palestinian territory to rubble, including residential areas, schools and other critical infrastructure.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/fh1k7t2o_jail-generic-getty_625x300_20_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A leaked surveillance video appeared to show soldiers picking out a prisoner at the Sde Teiman base.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/islamic-bloc-says-israel-fully-responsible-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-death-6288338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Islamic Bloc Says Israel "Fully Responsible" For Hamas Chief's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/islamic-bloc-says-israel-fully-responsible-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-death-6288338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:56:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Top Muslim diplomats on Wednesday said Israel was "fully responsible" for the "heinous" killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran and warned it could destabilise the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Top Muslim diplomats on Wednesday said Israel was "fully responsible" for the "heinous" killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran and warned it could destabilise the region.</p>

<p>The declaration came at the end of an extraordinary meeting of the Saudi-based Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) called in part by Iran, which has vowed to retaliate for the attack on Haniyeh, setting the Middle East on edge.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on the death of Haniyeh, who lived in Qatar and was a major player in talks to end the war in the Gaza Strip.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After foreign ministers gathered at the OIC's headquarters in the Saudi coastal city of Jeddah, the bloc issued a statement saying it "holds Israel, the illegal occupying power, fully responsible for this heinous attack", which it described as "a serious infringement" of Iran's sovereignty.</p>

<p>The deputy foreign minister for Saudi Arabia, which until Wednesday had not commented on the attack, described it in similar terms, according to a Saudi government statement.</p>

<p>During the opening ceremony, Mamadou Tangara, foreign minister for current OIC chair The Gambia, said Haniyeh's death risked deepening and widening the ongoing bloodshed in the Middle East.</p>

<p>"This heinous act serves only to escalate the existing tensions potentially leading to a wider conflict that could involve the entire region," Tangara said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's killing "will not quell the Palestinian cause but rather it amplifies it, underscoring the urgency for justice and human rights for the Palestinian people," he said.</p>

<p>"The sovereignty and territorial integrity of nation states are fundamental principles underpinning the international order.</p>

<p>"Respecting these principles has profound implications and their violation equally carries significant consequences."</p>

<p><strong>- Escalation fears -</strong><br />
Iran's acting foreign minister, Ali Bagheri, reiterated Tehran's view that it needs to respond.</p>

<p>"Currently, in the absence of any appropriate action by the (United Nations) Security Council against the aggressions and violations of the Israeli regime, the Islamic Republic of Iran has no choice but to use its inherent right to legitimate defence against the aggressions of this regime," he said.</p>

<p>US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller voiced hope on Wednesday that "all parties that have a relationship with Iran impress upon Iran, the same way we've been impressing upon the government of Israel, that they shouldn't take any steps to escalate the conflict".</p>

<p>Miller said the United States had been in touch with a number of nations attending the OIC meeting and believed there was a "broad consensus" that "escalation would only exacerbate the problems facing the region".</p>

<p>Hamas's Lebanese ally Hezbollah has also pledged to retaliate for Haniyeh's killing and that of its military commander Fuad Shukr in an Israeli strike in Beirut hours earlier.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>- 'Condemnation and denunciation' -&nbsp;</strong><br />
Wednesday's meeting was far from the first time the bloc has weighed in on the war, which began with Hamas's October 7 attacks on southern Israel.</p>

<p>That operation resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,677 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>In addition to issuing regular statements condemning civilian deaths in Gaza, OIC leaders gathered with their counterparts from the Arab League in November for a summit that condemned Israeli forces' "barbaric" actions in Gaza.</p>

<p>The strong statement masked divisions within the assembled group, as some countries proposed threatening to disrupt oil supplies to Israel and its allies as well as severing any economic and diplomatic ties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Diplomats said at the time that countries that have formal diplomatic ties with Israel, including the United Arab Emirates and Bahrain, came out against the idea.</p>

<p>Saudi political analyst Mohammed bin Saleh al-Harbi told AFP that, for Wednesday's OIC meeting, "we cannot expect more than condemnation and denunciation."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh was assassinated last month in July in Iran's capital Tehran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ready-to-work-with-bangladesh-interim-government-6288190]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ready To Work With Bangladesh Interim Government, Says US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-ready-to-work-with-bangladesh-interim-government-6288190]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 04:02:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States Wednesday said it is ready to work with the interim government of Bangladesh as the country charts a democratic future for its people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States Wednesday said it is ready to work with the interim government of Bangladesh as the country charts a democratic future for its people.</p>

<p>"We continue to monitor developments in Bangladesh, and we obviously have seen the appointment of Muhammad Yunus as the leader of an interim government," State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters at his daily news conference.</p>

<p>"We think the interim government will play a vital role in establishing long-term peace and political stability in Bangladesh," Miller said responding to questions on the fast-moving development in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>A State Department spokesperson, meanwhile, told PTI, "All decisions regarding the interim government should respect democratic principles, rule of law, and the will of the Bangladeshi people." "We understand Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus has agreed to lead Bangladesh's interim government. We stand ready to work with the interim government, as it charts a democratic future for the people of Bangladesh," the spokesperson said in response to a question.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Mohammad Yunus is set to take oath as the head of Bangladesh's interim government on Thursday, as he made a fervent appeal to everyone to stay calm and "refrain from all kinds of violence" to make the best use of "our new victory".</p>

<p>As authorities scrambled to bring the law and order situation under control, Army chief Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman on Wednesday announced that the interim government will take oath around 8 pm on Thursday. He said the advisory council may have 15 members.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/i0j7i4ug_matthew-miller_625x300_07_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US official said that all decisions regarding the interim government should respect democratic rules.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swifts-vienna-shows-cancelled-after-alleged-terror-attack-threat-6288136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift's Vienna Shows Cancelled After Alleged Terror Attack Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taylor-swifts-vienna-shows-cancelled-after-alleged-terror-attack-threat-6288136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 03:43:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Vienna leg of a tour by American mega-star Taylor Swift has been cancelled after Austria arrested a man in connection with an Islamist attack plot, the organisers said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Vienna leg of a tour by American mega-star Taylor Swift has been cancelled after Austria arrested a man in connection with an Islamist attack plot, the organisers said Wednesday.</p>

<p>Authorities had earlier confirmed the arrest of a 19-year-old Islamic State (IS) group sympathiser for allegedly planning an Islamist attack in the Vienna region, warning he had a "focus" on Swift's three upcoming shows.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"With confirmation from government officials of a planned terrorist attack at Ernst Happel Stadium, we have no choice but to cancel the three scheduled shows for everyone's safety," Barracuda Music said on Instagram.</p>

<p>The organisers added that all would-be concert-goers would have their tickets refunded. About 65,000 spectators were expected at each show scheduled for Thursday, Friday and Saturday.</p>

<p>The man, who had pledged his allegiance to IS "in recent weeks", was detained in Lower Austria about an hour from the capital early on Wednesday, Austria's top security chief Franz Ruf told a press conference.</p>

<p>"We have established corresponding preparatory acts and also that there is a focus of the 19-year-old perpetrator on the Taylor Swift concerts in Vienna," Ruf said.</p>

<p>He said that chemical substances had been seized at the suspect's home.</p>

<p>A second person believed to have been in contact with the suspect was arrested in Vienna.</p>

<p>According to initial investigation findings, both suspects radicalised themselves on the internet.</p>

<p>In November 2020, a convicted IS sympathiser went on a shooting rampage in downtown Vienna, killing four and wounding 23 others before police shot him dead.</p>

<p>It marked the Alpine nation's first deadly jihadist attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7kupi45g_taylor-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift's three concerts in Vienna have been cancelled over suspect terror attacks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-raises-concerns-over-peaceful-transfer-of-power-after-november-elections-6288048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If Trump Loses...": Biden Raises Concerns Over Peaceful Transfer Of Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-raises-concerns-over-peaceful-transfer-of-power-after-november-elections-6288048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 03:16:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said an interview with CBS he is "not confident at all" there will be a peaceful transfer of power to Kamala Harris if Donald Trump loses November's election, according to an extract broadcast Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said an interview with CBS he is "not confident at all" there will be a peaceful transfer of power to Kamala Harris if Donald Trump loses November's election, according to an extract broadcast Wednesday.</p>

<p>"If Trump loses, I'm not confident at all," Biden told the US network in the interview, which was due to air fully on Sunday. "He means what he says. We don't take him seriously. He means it -- all the stuff about 'if we lose there'll be a bloodbath.'"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/uj0lr04_joe-biden_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden expressed his concern over the peaceful transfer of power after November election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-could-return-on-another-craft-in-february-if-needed-nasa-6287423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sunita Williams Could Return On Another Craft In February If Needed: NASA]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-butch-wilmore-could-return-on-another-craft-in-february-if-needed-nasa-6287423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:18:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA said on Wednesday that astronauts delivered to the International Space Station by Boeing's Starliner could return on SpaceX's Crew Dragon in February 2025 if Starliner is still deemed unsafe to return to Earth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA said on Wednesday that astronauts delivered to the International Space Station by Boeing's Starliner could return on SpaceX's Crew Dragon in February 2025 if Starliner is still deemed unsafe to return to Earth.</p>

<p>Starliner spacecraft launched in June carrying two astronauts to the ISS in a high-stakes test mission required before NASA can certify the spacecraft for routine astronaut flights.</p>

<p>But the mission, initially expected to last about eight days, has been drawn out far longer by an array of problems with the craft's propulsion system that Boeing and NASA have been scrambling to fix.</p>

<p>Those problems have called into question Starliner's ability to safely return to Earth its crew, veteran NASA astronauts Butch Wilmore and Suni Williams. NASA has been examining whether a Crew Dragon capsule will have to bring them home instead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bl93e5h_sunita-williams-from-space_625x300_10_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Starliner spacecraft launched in June carrying Sunita Williams, Butch Wilmore (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>