<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:18:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andre-beadle-1stockf30-influencer-and-youtuber-famous-for-drag-racing-videos-dies-in-high-speed-bmw-car-crash-6970721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[YouTuber Famous For Drag Racing Videos Dies In High-Speed BMW Car Crash]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/andre-beadle-1stockf30-influencer-and-youtuber-famous-for-drag-racing-videos-dies-in-high-speed-bmw-car-crash-6970721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:03:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 25-year-old influencer and YouTuber, famous for his drag-racing videos, died in a car crash early Wednesday morning on the Nassau Expressway in Queens, New York.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 25-year-old influencer and YouTuber, famous for his drag-racing videos, died in a car crash early Wednesday morning on the Nassau Expressway in Queens, New York. Andre Beadle, known online as 1Stockf30, was reportedly driving eastbound “at a high rate of speed” in a 2023 BMW when he lost control of the vehicle, New York police confirmed.<br />
<br />
Police shared he “veered to the right,” going off the right side of the road and into the shoulder, where his vehicle collided with a metal pole, authorities told <a href="https://people.com/youtube-star-andre-beadle-dies-25-crashing-bmw-8741322 ">People magazine</a>. Emergency responders arrived at the scene around 1:12 am, and Beadle was transported to Jamaica Hospital Medical Centre, where he was pronounced dead. The Highway District's Collision Investigation Squad is continuing to investigate the incident.<br />
<br />
Mr Beadle, who had 59,500 YouTube subscribers and nearly 250,000 followers on Instagram, frequently shared content on street racing and his experiences with high-performance cars. In a video titled “I'm bringing the M240 back to the streets + Trackhawk vs 1Stock Corvette $10,000 race,” he took his BMW to get it serviced in preparation for an upcoming race.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eHYU-mJALiA?si=-vU4KWTf2SUd3iDD" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Some of Mr Beadle's videos, filmed alongside other popular street racers, included disclaimers urging viewers to “follow the road code and drive with care.”<br />
<br />
In June, Mr Beadle revealed in a video that he previously crashed his BMW at “170 mph.”<br />
<br />
Fans and supporters have been invited to gather at Haffen Park on Friday, November 8, at 4:30 pm for a balloon release in his honour.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCDYDSsp7WZ/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by 1Stock ???? (@1stockf30)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>“Bring some balloons and come celebrate life with the young legend and trendsetter,” read a post shared to Mr Beadle's Instagram on Wednesday. The tribute described him as “driven by passion” and “fueled by the thrill,” adding, “May you find the ultimate track among the stars.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bunqqt5o_andre-beadle-instagram_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andre Beadle frequently shared content on street racing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rahul-gandhi-writes-to-kamala-harris-after-donald-trump-wins-2024-us-elections-6970900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Your Unifying Message Of Hope...": Rahul Gandhi Writes To Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rahul-gandhi-writes-to-kamala-harris-after-donald-trump-wins-2024-us-elections-6970900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:54:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's message to Kamala Harris came after she lost to Donald Trump in the hotly-contested US presidential polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leader of Opposition in the Lok Sabha Rahul Gandhi has written to outgoing US Vice President Kamala Harris congratulating her on her spirited presidential campaign and said her unifying message of hope will continue to inspire many.</p>

<p>Ms Harris lost to Donald Trump in the hotly-contested US presidential polls.</p>

<p>"I would like to congratulate you on your spirited Presidential campaign. Your unifying message of hope will continue to inspire many," Mr Gandhi said in his letter to Harris.</p>

<p>Under the Biden administration, India and the United States have deepened cooperation on issues of global importance, the former Congress chief said.</p>

<p>"Our shared commitment to democratic values will continue to guide our friendship. As the Vice-President, your determination to bring people together and find common ground will be remembered," Mr Gandhi said in his letter dated November 7.</p>

<p>"I wish you the very best in your future endeavours," he added.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gc81into_kamala-harris-rahul-gandhi_625x300_08_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelenskiy-putin-vie-for-edge-with-trump-ahead-of-ukraine-pivot-6970707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelenskiy, Putin Vie For Edge With Trump Ahead Of Ukraine Pivot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelenskiy-putin-vie-for-edge-with-trump-ahead-of-ukraine-pivot-6970707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:27:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The leaders of Ukraine and Russia began jockeying for influence with President-elect Donald Trump in the immediate aftermath of the US election, seeking to gain an advantage in his promised push for a resolution to their years-long conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The leaders of Ukraine and Russia began jockeying for influence with President-elect Donald Trump in the immediate aftermath of the US election, seeking through public statements Thursday to gain an advantage in his promised push for a resolution to their years-long conflict.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy on Thursday called for “a fair ending to the war” and warned that a swift end to hostilities could force his country into a defeat.</p>

<p>“A quick ending would be a loss,” Zelenskiy told reporters at a summit in Budapest hosted by Viktor Orban, the European Union's biggest critic of aid for Kyiv.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin congratulated Trump on his victory and said the Republican, who on the campaign trail pledged to broker a peace deal between the two countries and suggested he wanted to scale back or end US aid to Kyiv, had ideas worth exploring.</p>

<p>“It seems to me, it deserves attention what was said about the desire to restore relations with Russia, to help end the Ukrainian crisis,” Putin said late Thursday at the annual meeting of the Valdai Club in the Black Sea city of Sochi, in his first comments on Trump's reelection. “I have always said that we will work with any head of state who has the trust of the American people.”</p>

<p>The dueling remarks underscored the extent to which Trump's election has jumbled the international politics around the war, which until now has seen the US and European leaders provide billions of dollars in arms and assistance to Ukraine as it has sought to repel Russia's invasion.</p>

<p>Trump, who had predicted he could end the conflict the day after his election, gave little indication of how he planned to approach that challenge in an interview with NBC News on Thursday.</p>

<p>Trump said that he had already spoken with Zelenskiy but that Putin wasn't among the “probably” 70 phone conversations he has held with world leaders since winning the election. But, Trump said, he still planned a conversation with the Russian leader.</p>

<p>“I think we'll speak,” Trump said.</p>

<p><strong>‘Open Question'</strong></p>

<p>But Orban, one of Trump's closest allies on the world stage, said that US and European aid to Ukraine to the tune of €50 billion ($54 billion) that's already been agreed is now an “open question.”</p>

<p>US and European nations were tiring of putting up money and the package is insufficient to continue to finance Ukraine, Orban said after the summit.</p>

<p>Zelenskiy had hoped to shore up that support from his European allies in the aftermath of Trump's election victory. But German Chancellor Olaf Scholz was late for the meeting after his coalition government collapsed overnight, in part due to a dispute over aid for Ukraine.</p>

<p>Western officials have been saying privately for months that Zelenskiy's goal of pushing Russia out of Ukrainian territory looks beyond reach in the foreseeable future and signaled their hopes for an end to the fighting.</p>

<p>“Some of you present here were strongly advocating for Ukraine to make concessions,” Zelenskiy told leaders earlier during the summit meeting. “It's unacceptable for Ukraine and suicidal for all of Europe.”</p>

<p>As Zelenskiy was speaking with European leaders, Russian forces hit the city of Zaporizhzhia in southern Ukraine with five glide bombs on Thursday, killing four and injuring at least 18 civilians, the regional government said on Telegram. The country was also targeted with a barrage of more than 100 explosive-laden drones overnight.</p>

<p>Putin gave no indication that Russia is ready to make concessions to secure an end to the war he started in February 2022. He's repeatedly said he's willing to hold talks, while insisting that any negotiations take account of the realities on the ground since his forces invaded Ukraine and occupied swathes of the country's south and east.</p>

<p>Russian officials have veered between ill-disguised joy and apprehension at the prospect of a new four-year term for Trump. Despite his comments on the Ukraine conflict and attempts to curry favor with Putin during his first administration, Trump also imposed punishing new sanctions, including on aluminum producer Rusal and the Nord Stream 2 pipeline project, and expelled scores of Russian diplomats.</p>

<p>“Many people close to power in Moscow who understand US policy are afraid of Trump's victory,” said Tatiana Stanovaya, founder of the consultancy R.Politik and a senior fellow at the Carnegie Russia Eurasia Center. “You can drink a bottle of wine, dance with happiness and then get an awful hangover.”</p>

<p>Ukraine's staunchest supporters in eastern Europe have been arguing that giving Zelenskiy the weapons and the money to defeat Putin isn't just the right thing to do, it's also the most effective solution. If Putin succeeds in Ukraine, he'll pose a bigger threat to Europe and that will require much greater investment in defense.</p>

<p>“The European value-based and rule-based system will also somewhat be decided in the conflict,” Estonian Prime Minister Kristen Michal said in an interview with Bloomberg Television on the eve of the talks. “That probably also will be a mark that will be left on Europe.”</p>

<p>Yet on the sidelines of the summit discussions, some European leaders were holding their first phone conversations with Trump since the election.</p>

<p>Zelenskiy said that he had not discussed the possibility of a quick end to the fighting when he spoke to Trump Wednesday in the aftermath of the election result. “This is ahead,” he told reporters. “It is clear for me that he wants to end it.”</p>

<p>Zelenskiy said previously that he wanted US help to force Russia to negotiate on Ukrainian terms and avoid a frozen conflict that would give Moscow time to rearm and attack again.</p>

<p><strong>European Allies</strong></p>

<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer was engaged in a series of bilateral meetings with other leaders, according to another senior official. Starmer is discussing with his European allies how to deepen defense coordination and ramp up help for Ukraine, especially if Trump dials back support after he takes office in January, the official said.</p>

<p>The UK is considering joint procurement with European nations and participating in military exercises, the official added.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden has so far declined to provide what Kyiv says it needs to achieve a just peace. That plan includes an invitation to join NATO and permission to use western-made weapons to strike military targets deep inside Russia.</p>

<p>US thinking is unlikely to change in the months Biden has left in office, according to western diplomats. Most allies don't want to risk getting dragged into war with Russia while a symbolic invitation would have limited bargaining power, they added, asking not to be identified.</p>

<p>White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said Thursday that Biden's focus was pushing forward with the foreign policy he had made, and making sure Ukraine had what it needed for its defense.</p>

<p>The diplomats also said that even if Kyiv was given permission for long-range strikes inside Russia, it doesn't have many missiles and there aren't enough targets within its reach to substantively change the balance on the ground.</p>

<p>Kyiv on the other hand believes that move would curb Russia's ability to continue hammering Ukraine's infrastructure and cities.</p>

<p>Critics have argued that Biden's Ukraine strategy points to continued stalemate as it's premised on cautious incrementalism and fear of escalation. Any peace talks in the near future would happen with Russia occupying parts of its neighbor and Putin unwilling to let that land go.</p>

<p>In the longer term, Ukraine's best bet to guarantee its security is to develop its own defense industry and capabilities with allied help, and mobilize a stronger and younger army, some of the diplomats said.</p>

<p>Speaking in Budapest, Zelenskiy also took an indirect dig at the host of the meeting, Orban, who has cultivated ties with Putin and visited him in Moscow in July.</p>

<p>“Hugs with Putin won't help,” Zelenskiy said. “Some of you have been hugging him for 20 years, and things are only getting worse.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/48pu789o_zelenskiy-putin-trump_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I'm not going to start wars, I'm going to stop wars," Donald Trump said in his victory speech.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-believes-his-decision-to-drop-out-of-presidential-race-was-correct-white-house-6969503]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Believes His Decision To Drop Out Of Presidential Race Was "Correct": White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-believes-his-decision-to-drop-out-of-presidential-race-was-correct-white-house-6969503]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:22:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Blaming the US President's incumbent status for Vice President Kamala Harris' electoral defeat, the White House has said that Joe Biden felt it was the "correct" decision he made to not run for the presidential race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blaming the US President's incumbent status for Vice President Kamala Harris' electoral defeat, the White House has said that Joe Biden felt it was the "correct" decision he made to not run for the presidential race.</p>

<p>"The President is very proud of what he was able to accomplish," White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said during a White House briefing on Thursday -- the first since President-elect Donald Trump's victory was declared.</p>

<p>"He was very proud, and when he made that decision to hand over the torch, pass the torch to the Vice President, he believed it was the right decision to make at that time," she said.</p>

<p>"He (Biden) believed that she (Kamala Harris) was ready."</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre's answers were ambiguously phrased, either speaking in the past tense or alluding to Biden's feelings in July, when he made his decision, rather than how he feels at the moment.</p>

<p>She did not directly answer whether Biden regrets not dropping from the US presidential race sooner than he did.</p>

<p>Jean-Pierre sought to herald Biden's accomplishments during his term as President, while subtly blaming his and Harris' status as incumbents for Democrats' loss.</p>

<p>"Despite all of the accomplishments that we were able to get done, there were global headwinds, that, because of the Covid-19 pandemic, obviously, Covid-19 led to disruptions with the supply chain, and it had a political toll on many incumbents."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cdsiem5o_joe-biden-afp_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-artwork-by-humanoid-robot-sells-for-1-3-million-6970600]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First Artwork By Humanoid Robot Sells For $1.3 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-artwork-by-humanoid-robot-sells-for-1-3-million-6970600]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 11:11:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A portrait of English mathematician Alan Turing became the first artwork by a humanoid robot to be sold at auction, fetching $1,320,000 on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A portrait of English mathematician Alan Turing became the first artwork by a humanoid robot to be sold at auction, fetching $1,320,000 on Thursday.</p>

<p>The 2.2 metre (7.5 feet) portrait "A.I. God" by "Ai-Da", the world's first ultra-realistic robot artist, smashed pre-sale expectations of $180,000 when it went under the hammer at London auction house Sotheby's Digital Art Sale.</p>

<p>"Today's record-breaking sale price for the first artwork by a humanoid robot artist to go up for auction marks a moment in the history of modern and contemporary art and reflects the growing intersection between A.I. technology and the global art market," said the auction house.</p>

<p>Ai-Da Robot, which uses AI to speak, said: "The key value of my work is its capacity to serve as a catalyst for dialogue about emerging technologies."</p>

<p>Ai-Da added that a "portrait of pioneer Alan Turing invites viewers to reflect on the god-like nature of AI and computing while considering the ethical and societal implications of these advancements."</p>

<p>The ultra-realistic robot, one of the most advanced in the world, is designed to resemble a human woman with a face, large eyes and a brown wig.</p>

<p>Ai-Da is named after Ada Lovelace, the world's first computer programmer and was devised by Aidan Meller, a specialist in modern and contemporary art.</p>

<p>"The greatest artists in history grappled with their period of time, and both celebrated and questioned society's shifts," said Meller.</p>

<p>"Ai-Da Robot as technology, is the perfect artist today to discuss the current developments with technology and its unfolding legacy," he added.</p>

<p>Ai-Da generates ideas through conversations with members of the studio, and suggested creating an image of Turing during a discussion about "A.I. for good".</p>

<p>The robot was then asked what style, colour, content, tone and texture to use, before using cameras in its eyes to look at a picture of Turing and create the painting.</p>

<p>Meller led the team that created Ai-Da with artificial intelligence specialists at the universities of Oxford and Birmingham in England.</p>

<p>Meller said Turing, who made his name as a World War II codebreaker, mathematician and early computer scientist, had raised concerns about the use of AI in the 1950s.</p>

<p>The artwork's "muted tones and broken facial planes" seemingly suggested "the struggles Turing warned we will face when it comes to managing AI", he said.</p>

<p>Ai-Da's works were "ethereal and haunting" and "continue to question where the power of AI will take us, and the global race to harness its power", he added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/20kg4ki8_alan-turing-portrait-by-ai_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Portrait "A.I. God" by "Ai-Da", the world's first ultra-realistic robot artist.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fired-us-worker-shoots-ex-boss-in-new-york-city-flees-through-subway-tunnels-6970174]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fired Worker Shoots Ex-Boss In New York City. Flees Through Subway Tunnels]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fired-us-worker-shoots-ex-boss-in-new-york-city-flees-through-subway-tunnels-6970174]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:18:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recently dismissed employee of a computer repair store shot his former boss in New York City's Upper West Side area on Wednesday and fled into the subway system to evade the police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recently dismissed employee of a computer repair store shot his former boss in New York City's Upper West Side area on Wednesday and fled into the subway system to evade the police. According to authorities, the incident unfolded at West 69th Street and Columbus Avenue at around 9:20 am.</p>

<p>The attacker, reportedly a remote worker at Lincoln Business Machines Incorporated, was recently let go from his position, according to a report in The <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/07/us-news/man-shot-in-broad-daylight-in-nyc-suspect-at-large-cops/" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Post</a>. Witnesses claim the former employee, a man in his 40s, confronted his ex-employer on the street near the store, firing twice --&nbsp;once in his shoulder and then in his leg. The victim, a 47-year-old man, was immediately transported to St. Luke's Hospital, where he remains in stable condition, said the report.</p>

<p>After the shooting, the suspect ran into the nearby 72nd Street subway station and hid under a stationary train. “It was all about the situation with work,” a resident told The New York Post, adding the attacker's grievances reportedly involved financial disagreements with his former employer. “It was something about money and something about being cheated or wronged … It was terrifying.”</p>

<p>"I heard like 15 loud bangs," a resident told <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/nyc-shooting-upper-west-side/" rel="nofollow,noindex">CBS News</a>. Another witness recalled, "I was actually half asleep and I heard 10 gunshots." A stray bullet struck the door of a nearby apartment building. "We just moved into this building a month and a half ago, thinking it was a really safe area," said a resident of the building.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the search, subway passengers experienced significant disruptions, with one train being evacuated. A video shared on social media captured commuters crouched on the floor and exiting through darkened tunnels. A passenger posted on X (formerly Twitter), “My super pleasant subway ride to work this morning!! Love the C train!!! Nothing like an active gunman on the train to wake you up for the day!”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">my super pleasant subway ride to work this morning!! love the C train !!! nothing like an active gunman on the train to wake you up for the day! <a href="https://t.co/C173IdfxOB">pic.twitter.com/C173IdfxOB</a></p>
— joyceepoo (@joyceepoo1) <a href="https://twitter.com/joyceepoo1/status/1854589976933023985?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to the Metropolitan Transportation Authority, C trains were temporarily suspended in both directions, while A and D trains faced severe delays. Other lines, including the B and E, were also impacted.</p>

<p>The gunman, still at large, was last seen wearing a black hoodie, green jacket, tan pants, and carrying a black firearm, according to The New York Post report.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aek4ib5o_us-police-generic_625x300_07_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the search, subway passengers experienced significant disruptions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-replies-to-we-need-your-help-removing-trudeau-post-6970273]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Replies To 'We Need Your Help Removing Trudeau' Post]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-replies-to-we-need-your-help-removing-trudeau-post-6970273]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:18:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has predicted the downfall of Canada's Prime Minister Justin Trudeau in the upcoming Canadian federal election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has predicted the downfall of Canada's Prime Minister Justin Trudeau in the upcoming Canadian federal election, scheduled to take place on or before October 2025. “He will be gone in the upcoming election,” posted Musk on X, while responding to a user's request to help Canada get rid of Trudeau.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">He will be gone in the upcoming election</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1854560717866668425?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The exchange on social media started when a Swedish journalist shared an update on the German government and wrote, “The German Socialist government has COLLAPSED and there are now talks about a snap election.”</p>

<p>To this, Musk, Chief executive officer (CEO) of electric automobile maker Tesla and the private space company SpaceX, called German Chancellor Olaf Scholz a “fool” after the collapse of his three-party coalition.</p>

<p>He responded in German: “Olaf ist ein Narr.” The sentence translates to: “Olaf is a fool.”</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="de">Olaf ist ein Narr <a href="https://t.co/Yye3DIeA17">https://t.co/Yye3DIeA17</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1854558548732121169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>To this, a user said, “Elon Musk we need your help in Canada getting rid of Trudeau”.</p>

<p>This is not the first time Musk has bashed Mr Trudeau. Musk had earlier slammed the Justin Trudeau government in Canada for “crushing free speech” in the country.</p>

<p>Last year, the Canadian government made it compulsory for online streaming services to formally register with the government for 'regulatory controls'. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-justin-trudeau-crushing-free-speech-online-streaming-services-podcasts-registration-compulsory-with-government-4441582">Musk called it “shameful”</a> and wrote, “Trudeau is trying to crush free speech in Canada.”</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Trudeau is trying to crush free speech in Canada. Shameful. <a href="https://t.co/oHFFvyBGxu">https://t.co/oHFFvyBGxu</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1708583842905211225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2023</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Before this, in February 2022, when Mr Trudeau invoked emergency powers - for the first time in the country's history - to arm his government with more power to respond to truckers protesting the vaccine mandates at that time, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-compares-canadas-justin-trudeau-to-hitler-to-support-freedom-convoy-protesters-deletes-tweet-2774806">Musk compared him to Adolf Hitler</a>.</p>

<p>Responding to a social media post describing how Trudeau's government had ordered banks to help cut funding to the protesters, Musk posted a meme of a photo of Hitler, with "Stop comparing me to Justin Trudeau" written above his head and "I had a budget" below it.</p>

<p>Later the post was deleted.</p>

<p>The war of words continues.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/j9i6f3e_elon-musk-justin-trudeau_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk has predicted the future of the Canadian government.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-why-more-young-men-voted-for-donald-trump-6970224]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why More Young Men Voted For Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-why-more-young-men-voted-for-donald-trump-6970224]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 10:04:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among younger voters aged 18-29, 49 percent of men voted for Donald Trump -- shattering previous images of young people generally leaning left.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Putting abortion rights front and center in her campaign, Kamala Harris thought she found a winning formula in courting women voters.</p>

<p>But it was Donald Trump who found victory, running up the margins on American men -- particularly young men.</p>

<p>That young people as a whole tend to be more liberal was no deterrent to a US presidential campaign that capitalized on youth masculinity -- tapping into interests such as fighting sports and cryptocurrency, as well as making appearances on male-dominated podcasts.</p>

<p>"If you are a man in this country and you don't vote for Donald Trump, you're not a man," said Charlie Kirk, a conservative activist long focused on the youth vote.</p>

<p>Donald Trump won the presidency with 54 percent of men voting for the Republican, up slightly from the 51 percent that supported him in 2020, according to exit polling by NBC.</p>

<p>But what raised eyebrows was among younger voters aged 18-29, where 49 percent of men voted Trump -- shattering previous images of young people generally leaning left.</p>

<p>As Elon Musk -- tech bro, wealthy businessman and major Trump backer -- put it on Election Day: "the cavalry has arrived."</p>

<p>Trump's gains come as a gender divide makes itself felt among young people at-large: women under 29 had a massive 61-37 Harris-Trump split.</p>

<p>"There is a lot of latent sexism in the US electorate, male and female members alike," Tammy Vigil, an associate professor of media science at the University of Boston, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Trump's campaign gave people permission to indulge their worst impulses and embrace divisiveness of many sorts."</p>

<p><strong>'Tough' Trump seen as a 'leader'</strong></p>

<p>Spencer Thomas, who voted for Harris, said the economy was on the mind of many of his peers who voted for Trump.</p>

<p>"They focused more on the economic policies and different things of that nature, rather than abortion rights," said the student at Howard University, a historically Black college in Washington.</p>

<p>The macho energy of the Trump presidential run -- eschewing political correctness, "wokeness" or other forms of liberal handwringing -- won over plenty of Black men, despite the campaign's outright racism at times.</p>

<p>Among Black men under 45, about three out of 10 voted for Trump -- double the rate of the 2020 vote and blowing yet another hole in the Democrats' traditional base.</p>

<p>As Democrats embark on their postmortem, trying to figure out what went wrong, there won't be one simple explanation.</p>

<p>But "Black and Latino men could possibly overlook the racism of the Trump campaign because Trump appealed to their sense of machismo," Vigil offered.</p>

<p>Trump going on the "Joe Rogan Experience" podcast, where listeners overwhelmingly skew young and male, "was about trying to motivate young men to turn out," said Kathleen Dolan, a political scientist at the University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee.</p>

<p>"The rest of his performance of masculinity was to appeal to his base, women and men, who like him because they think he is 'tough' and a 'leader' and clearly aren't offended by the things he says," she told AFP.</p>

<p>Whatever Trump's x-factor was, it scratched an itch.</p>

<p>According to exit polling from Edison Research, some 54 percent of Latino men voted for Trump on Tuesday -- a whopping 18 percentage point gain for Republicans compared to 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/r40m422o_us-voters_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/meet-anita-verma-lallian-indian-origin-woman-who-bought-matthew-perry-s-home-6970124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Anita Verma-Lallian, Indian-Origin Woman Who Bought Matthew Perry's Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/meet-anita-verma-lallian-indian-origin-woman-who-bought-matthew-perry-s-home-6970124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:51:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian-origin real estate developer and film producer has purchased 'Friends' star Matthew Perry's Los Angeles home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin real estate developer and film producer has purchased 'Friends' star Matthew Perry's Los Angeles home. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indian-origin-woman-buys-house-where-matthew-perry-was-found-dead-performs-puja-6962680">Anita Verma-Lallian</a> acquired the Pacific Palisades property for $8.55 million. Before moving in, Ms Verma-Lallian and her family performed a traditional 'puja' ceremony to bless the space and honour the late actor's spirit. Mr Perry was found dead in the same house last year.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who is Anita Verma-Lallian?</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Anita Lallian is a real estate developer and film producer. She founded Camelback Productions, a film production company focused on increasing South Asian representation in the film industry.</li>
	<li>Her journey into real estate was inspired by her parents, Kuldip Verma, an engineer, and Binu Verma, a physician, who emigrated from India and established <a href="https://vermaland.com/family-business-and-a-love-of-learning-and-culture/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">Vermaland</a>, one of Arizona's largest land banking companies. Following their entrepreneurial footsteps, Verma-Lallian launched her venture, Arizona Land Consulting. Today, she is a recognised commercial real estate consultant in Arizona, leading her successful company. She is also Vermaland's Marketing Director.</li>
	<li>Ms Verma-Lallian earned her MBA from the University of Southern California (USC) in 2007 and a Bachelor of Science in Business Administration from the University of Arizona in 2004.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Alongside her sister, Jennifer, Ms Verma-Lallian co-founded the Verma Charitable Foundation. Established with real estate donations valued at $1.2 million from the Verma Legacy Trust (a Vermaland subsidiary), the foundation aims to support underprivileged students in India. Through this Foundation, she and her family hope to provide scholarships for 100 students in India and establish a cultural centre in Phoenix to promote Indian heritage and teachings in the local community.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Anita Verma-Lallian was named a "Dynamic Woman" by Modern Luxury in 2021 and awarded "Global Real Estate Leader of the Year" by the Global Chamber of Phoenix in 2018 and 2019. She has also been recognised among the "Most Influential Women in Commercial Real Estate" by AZ Business Magazine and featured as one of the "Women Who Move the Valley" by Arizona Foothills Magazine.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mastnt0g_anita-lallian_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anita Lallian is a real estate developer and film producer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-strikes-down-joe-bidens-immigration-policy-for-undocumented-spouses-6970159]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Judge Strikes Down Joe Biden's Immigration Policy For Undocumented Spouses]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/judge-strikes-down-joe-bidens-immigration-policy-for-undocumented-spouses-6970159]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:51:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The "Keeping Families Together" policy, allowed certain undocumented immigrants married to US nationals to apply for permanent residency without leaving the country, as was previously required.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A federal judge on Thursday struck down a policy aimed at helping undocumented spouses of US citizens obtain legal status, dealing a blow to outgoing President Joe Biden and an estimated half a million people eligible under the program.</p>

<p>The ruling comes just days after Donald Trump swept to victory in the presidential election on promises of cracking down on illegal immigration and launching a massive deportation effort.</p>

<p>The "Keeping Families Together" policy, which had been previously suspended amid a court challenge, allowed certain undocumented immigrants married to US nationals to apply for permanent residency without leaving the country, as was previously required.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/undocumented-immigrants-in-us-terrified-frustrated-as-trump-returns-6968785">Undocumented Immigrants In US "Terrified", "Frustrated" As Trump Returns</a></p>

<p>Judge J. Campbell Barker, of the Eastern District of Texas, who was nominated by Trump during his first White House term, ruled that federal agencies "lack statutory authority" for the program.</p>

<p>Biden announced "Keeping Families Together" in June at the height of his reelection bid, before dropping out of the race the next month.</p>

<p>On the campaign trail, Trump hammered Biden and his Democratic replacement, Vice President Kamala Harris, over a record spike in illegal border crossings in the past year.</p>

<p>A coalition of Republican-led states including Texas filed suit to block the program, arguing it would cost them millions of dollars in public services -- including healthcare, education and law enforcement.</p>

<p>The program would apply to immigrants who have been in the country for at least 10 years and were married to a US citizen before June 17, 2024, and also apply to an estimated 50,000 stepchildren of US citizens.</p>

<p>Judge Barker temporarily halted the program in August, and then again after an appeals court lifted the stay.</p>

<p>Biden officials could appeal Barker's ruling, but it is doubtful the incoming Trump administration would continue to defend it.</p>

<p>"Today's decision is a deeply disappointing and unjust setback for the families who live every day under the weight of uncertainty," said Harold A. Solis, co-legal director of Make The Road New York, an NGO supporting immigrants.</p>

<p>"'Keeping Families Together' and everything it represents -- family unity, opportunity and stability -- is our immigration system at its best. We must and will continue to support family unity despite today's dangerous decision."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trumps-7-priorities-in-2-0-administration-immigration-ukraine-war-6963936">Donald Trump's 7 Priorities In 2.0 Administration: End Immigration, Wars</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-04/j8u2trc8_immigration-generic-afp-650_625x300_22_April_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-proud-of-strengthening-ties-with-india-official-6969330]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Administration "Proud Of" Strengthening Ties With India: Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-administration-proud-of-strengthening-ties-with-india-official-6969330]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:15:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Biden Administration is incredibly proud of strengthening ties with India, a senior administration official said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Biden Administration is incredibly proud of strengthening ties with India, a senior administration official said on Thursday.</p>

<p>“I will say that the strengthening of our ties with India is something that this administration is incredibly proud of, both through our increased alliances through the Quad, and through our work on a number of shared priorities,” State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters at his daily news conference.</p>

<p>“It's something that we focused on from day one and something that we see as a great success as we prepare to leave office,” Miller said.</p>

<p>Miller was responding to a question on India-US relationship under the Biden Administration.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/0m441f8_joe-biden-pm-modi_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Matthew Miller said ties with India is something that they focused on from day one.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-discusses-ties-with-singapores-deputy-prime-minister-gan-kim-yong-6969670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Foreign Minister S Jaishankar Discusses Ties With Singapore's Deputy PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/external-affairs-minister-s-jaishankar-discusses-ties-with-singapores-deputy-prime-minister-gan-kim-yong-6969670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 09:13:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Friday met Singapore's Deputy Prime Minister Gan Kim Yong and discussed with him ways to take forward contemporary bilateral partnership.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Friday met Singapore's Deputy Prime Minister Gan Kim Yong and discussed with him ways to take forward contemporary bilateral partnership, with a focus on areas like industrial parks, innovation and semiconductors.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar is here on the second leg of his two-nation tour which also took him to Australia.</p>

<p>"Started my visit to Singapore by meeting DPM &amp; Minister for Trade and Industry Gan Kim Yong. Discussed taking forward contemporary partnership, with a focus on industrial parks, green energy, skilling, innovation and semiconductors," Mr Jaishankar posted on X.</p>

<p>During his day-long visit here, Mr Jaishankar will address the 8th Roundtable of ASEAN– India Network of Think Tanks.</p>

<p>He will also meet the leadership of Singapore to review the close partnership between the two countries and explore avenues to further enhance the bilateral relationship.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n89c2ih8_s-jaishankar-gan-kim-yong-twiter_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar met Singapore's Deputy Prime Minister Gan Kim Yong.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-did-kamala-harris-lose-because-democrats-guilt-tripped-americans-6969672]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Did Kamala Harris Lose? Because Democrats Guilt-Tripped Americans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-did-kamala-harris-lose-because-democrats-guilt-tripped-americans-6969672]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:05:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harriss campaign raised and spent more money than Donald Trump, but what was the substance? The political messaging barely managed to escape the rhetoric of Save America from Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4sb4k218_kamala-harris_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>It's not misogyny that defeated Kamala Harris. There is a certain insincerity lurking behind this explanation for the decisive victory of the Republican Party, which has led to the installation of Donald Trump, once again, in the White House.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is the same insincerity with which the Harris-Walz campaign was carried out for months. In the face of an ‘unexpected' debacle, the Democrats in the US, along with other politicians across the world, will do well to introspect. What, indeed, was the problem?</p>

<p>It is easy to employ feminism to explain away Trump's triumph over two women in less than a decade. What is being forgotten easily here is the fact that she was recruited in a huff to replace Joe Biden, who was sure to have lost to Trump. An afterthought. The Democrats were desperate to fight anti-incumbency but addressed it from the wrong end.</p>

<h2><strong>A Guilt Bait</strong></h2>

<p>Harris was used by her party as guilt-inducing bait in the 2024 presidential election, and her defeat has important lessons for everyone. First and most obviously, you cannot guilt-trip voters into supporting you unconditionally. The Harris-Walz campaign doubled down on making the undecided voter feel guilt-ridden for even considering a change. There was a complete lack of self-awareness on the part of campaign designers and ideological Democrat voters that their policies may have anything to do with people's dissatisfaction. Or they knew and smugly brushed it off, armed with weapons of collective guilt. This smugness caused a swing.</p>

<p>The most palpable example of this is the Democrats' tone-deafness around the war in West Asia. In a year marked by relentless anti-war campaigns and demonstrations, Democrats believed Dick Cheney to be their trump card. Cheney's hawkish attitude as George W. Bush's vice-president left a legacy of violence and human rights violations in the US and everywhere else the country intervened militarily. Harris's claims to usher in peace fell flat in the face of such crude irony. Depending on how disappointed or angry they were, anti-war Democrats sat the election out, cross-voted for Trump, or voted for the third alternative to mark their dissent.</p>

<h2><strong>Thick Cosmopolitanism</strong></h2>

<p>Democrats' adaptation of what political scientists call the theory of ‘thick cosmopolitanism' in the domestic domain of immigration did not work in securing them a consecutive second term. The theory argues that when people realise their ingroup's culpability in causing harm to people living in distant nations, they adopt a cosmopolitan helping demeanour. The inherent limitation of the theory, as demonstrated by Nicholas Faulkner, and the revelation of Democrats' hypocrisy ensured that voters rejected their guilt-tripping political campaign. This may partially explain why a substantial diaspora cohort swung towards Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Democrats were counting on brow-beating dissent with guilt. Unfortunately for them, this strategy backfired. Scholars Gunn and Wilson propose that collective guilt, an important political tool, is often undercut by defensiveness. The Democratic Party forgot that just as an attack on personal identity makes an individual defensive, people are wont to react with defensiveness when their social identities are threatened. Calling voters racist and sexist before, during, and after the polls, Democrats inspired a surge of defensiveness across multiple demographic groups.</p>

<h2><strong>Nobody Knew What Kamala Was About</strong></h2>

<p>Kamala Harris's campaign raised and spent more money than Donald Trump, but what was the substance? The political messaging barely managed to escape the rhetoric of ‘Save America from Trump'. Reeling under high inflation rates, American voters felt invisible when no concrete policy measures were offered for this ‘Save America' operation. The Republicans are guilty of running the same banal campaign, but they had anti-incumbency on their side. Memories of Trump's previous presidency were fading, and that helped him. Trump's campaign counted on the fickleness of public memory and put its bets on people's ability to forget the past when they are obsessing about ongoing concerns.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Team Harris, on the other hand, weaponised memories of the fractured American past to make this election about correcting historical wrongs. Psychologists warn that people do not necessarily react well when confronted with problematic actions of their own. Political scientist Eunbin Chung proposed in the context of East Asia that national identity affirmation can be employed “as a way of disarming the defensiveness that is prompted from recognising guilt of one's country, allowing more prosocial responses to emerge”. Democrats, however, fell short in offering a positive spin to the American identity in a bid to counter its chequered racial history.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Competitive Defensiveness</strong></h2>

<p>Add to this the Biden administration's no-limits support to Israel despite the growing anti-war chime even within the rank and file of the Democratic Party, and we got a game of competitive defensiveness all around. The leadership and the voters stopped listening to each other.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To peg this defeat as only a misogynistic mistake, therefore, is oversimplifying the matters. This is how Democrats wish to continue to play the guilting game without a shred of introspection.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4sb4k218_kamala-harris_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fed-cuts-interest-rates-a-quarter-point-after-trump-victory-6969576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Fed Cuts Interest Rates A Quarter Point After Trump Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-fed-cuts-interest-rates-a-quarter-point-after-trump-victory-6969576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:37:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Federal Reserve shrugged off concerns about the impact of Donald Trump's election victory on interest rates and moved ahead with a quarter point cut Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Federal Reserve shrugged off concerns about the impact of Donald Trump's election victory on interest rates and moved ahead with a quarter point cut Thursday.</p>

<p>The Fed sits just a short walk from the White House, where Democratic President Joe Biden will in January hand back the keys to Trump following the Republican's election win.</p>

<p>But as expected, policymakers ignored the political drama playing out up the road, voting unanimously to reduce interest rates by 25 basis points to between 4.50 and 4.75 percent, the Fed said in a statement.</p>

<p>"In the near term, the election will have no effects on our policy decisions," Fed Chair Jerome Powell told reporters, noting there was still uncertainty about what President-elect Trump's actual economic agenda would be.</p>

<p>"We don't guess, we don't speculate, and we don't assume," he said.</p>

<p>Powell also said he would not resign if asked to leave early by the president-elect, adding that firing any of the Fed's seven governors was "not permitted under the law."</p>

<p>The US central bank's rate decision should help ease the costs of mortgages and other loans -- welcome news for consumers, who had widely cited the cost of living as a top concern ahead of Tuesday's vote.</p>

<p>But the cost of borrowing will also depend on how financial markets think a Trump victory will impact the economy over the longer term, and where the Fed's interest rates will need to settle to ensure inflation remains now.</p>

<p>'Economy looks quite resilient'</p>

<p>Experts have pointed to the post-pandemic surge in US inflation -- which saw consumer prices rise more than 20 percent -- as playing a major factor in Trump's victory.</p>

<p>Thursday's decision adds to a previous rate cut in September, when the Fed kicked off its easing cycle with a larger half point decrease, and penciled in additional rate reductions this year.</p>

<p>The Fed's favored inflation gauge has since eased to 2.1 percent in September, while economic growth has remained robust.</p>

<p>The labor market has also stayed strong overall, despite a sharp hiring slowdown last month attributed in large part to adverse weather conditions and a labor strike.</p>

<p>"Generally speaking, the US economy looks quite resilient, and the labor market still looks very good," Jim Bullard, the long-serving former St Louis Fed president, told AFP ahead of Election Day.</p>

<p>Bullard, now dean of the Daniels School of Business at Purdue University, predicted a 25 basis point cut this week, and another cut of a similar size in December.</p>

<p>Futures traders place a probability of around 65 percent that the Fed will cut by a quarter of a percentage-point next month, according to data from CME Group.</p>

<p>But analysts remain split over what the Fed will do next month.</p>

<p>Fiscal discipline 'broken down'</p>

<p>With a Trump victory assured, a lot still depends on whether Republicans can hold onto the House of Representatives, as they appear on track to do -- giving them a "Red Sweep" of both houses of Congress along with the White House.</p>

<p>"Markets tend to like divided government as a way to control spending and keep deficits down," said Bullard.</p>

<p>"What's distressing to an economist like me is that, really, fiscal discipline has broken down for both political parties," he said.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly accused Powell -- whom he first appointed to run the US central bank -- of working to favor the Democrats, and has suggested he would look to replace him once his term expires in 2026.</p>

<p>The president-elect has also said he would like "at least" a say over setting the Fed's interest rate -- something that runs against the Fed's current mandate to act independently of Congress and the White House to tackle inflation and unemployment.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/os662ulg_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/susie-wiles-donald-trumps-aid-and-1st-woman-white-house-chief-of-staff-6969540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["First-Ever In US History": Trump Picks A Woman White House Chief Of Staff]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/susie-wiles-donald-trumps-aid-and-1st-woman-white-house-chief-of-staff-6969540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:23:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Susie Wiles, who is credited for Donald Trump's successful presidential bid, is the daughter of Pat Summerall, a prominent football player and sportscaster.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump on Thursday announced that his campaign manager, Susie Wiles, will be his White House chief of staff. Wiles, 67, will become the first woman to hold the position in the US history.</p>

<p>"Susie Wiles just helped me achieve one of the greatest political victories in American history, and was an integral part of both my 2016 and 2020 successful campaigns," Trump said two days after his decisive US election win over Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>She is "tough, smart, innovative, and is universally admired and respected", the 78-year-old Republican said.</p>

<p>"It is a well-deserved honour to have Susie as the first-ever female Chief of Staff in United States history," he added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President Donald J. Trump Announces Susan Summerall Wiles as White House Chief of Staff <a href="https://t.co/rzU3Zj6d0j">pic.twitter.com/rzU3Zj6d0j</a></p>
— Team Trump (Text TRUMP to 88022) (@TeamTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/TeamTrump/status/1854655827350581726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Wiles, along with fellow campaign manager Chris LaCivita, are credited for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-2-0-jd-vance-elon-musk-a-galaxy-of-contrarian-characters-set-for-white-house-stints-6961648" target="_blank">Trump's successful presidential bid</a>.</p>

<p>Trump also gave a shout-out to Wiles during his victory speech on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"We call her the 'ice baby'... Susie likes to stay in the background," he said.</p>

<p>US Vice President-elect JD Vance called it a "great news" and said Susie was a "huge asset" to Trump on the campaign.</p>

<p>"She will be a huge asset in the White House. She's also just a really good person," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Susie Wiles</strong></h3>

<p>Born on May 14, 1957, Susie Wiles is the daughter of Pat Summerall, who was a prominent football player and sportscaster.</p>

<p>A long-time Florida-based political strategist, she has previously worked on Ronald Reagan's 1980 presidential campaign and helped Florida's Republican Governor Ron DeSantis win the election in 2018.</p>

<p>Early in her career, she also worked for Republican US representatives Jack Kemp and Tillie Fowler.</p>

<p>Wiles also served briefly as the manager of former Utah Governor Jon Huntsman Jr's 2012 presidential campaign.</p>

<p>She served as a senior adviser on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-age-family-net-worth-political-career-and-more-6558144" target="_blank">Trump's 2016 and 2020 bids</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eqh3l0to_susie-wiles_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Susie Wiles served as a senior adviser on Trump's 2016 and 2020 bids.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-dont-see-my-future-in-us-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-after-trumps-win-6969535]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Don't See Future In US": Musk's Transgender Daughter After Trump's Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-dont-see-my-future-in-us-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-after-trumps-win-6969535]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 07:20:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following Donald Trump's US election win, Elon Musk's estranged trans daughter, Vivian Wilson, announced her intention to leave the US, saying she doesn't see a future in the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Donald Trump's US election win, Elon Musk's estranged trans daughter, Vivian Wilson, announced her intention to leave the US, saying she doesn't see a future in the country. Vivian, who Musk once claimed was "killed by the woke mind virus", is transgender and has been estranged from her father since 2022. On Wednesday, she took to Meta's Threads to share her thoughts. "I've thought this for a while, but yesterday confirmed it for me. I don't see my future being in the United States," she wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Even if he's only in office for 4 years, even if the anti-trans regulations magically don't happen, the people who willingly voted this in are not going anywhere anytime soon," she said after Donald Trump's win.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the post below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;">
<div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"></div>

<div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"><strong><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"><svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewbox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"></svg><strong> </strong><path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z"></path></a></strong></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCDViBCy_w6" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank">View on Threads</a></div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>

<p>After Vivian announced her plans to leave America, Musk responded to the news on X. "The woke mind killed my son," he reiterated in a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1854576310699348325">tweet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vivian shared a screenshot of her father's post on Threads and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCFUOgETs7l">wrote</a>, "So, you're still going with the sob-story about how "woe is me, my child was infected by something-or-other and that's totally the only reason why they hate me. Just don't... please don't look into it, god forbid I'm anything but the victim in every scenario imaginable."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Did anyone ever actually believe this? It's just tired, it's overdone, it's clich&amp;#233;. I'm just bored honestly, like is this really the best you could come up with?" she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-in-trump-familys-election-victory-photo-but-melania-is-missing-6963915">Elon Musk In Trump Family's Election Victory Photo, But Melania Is Missing</a></strong></p>

<p>In the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/DCFUO7hTEIb">following Thread</a>, Vivian stated that the only reason this news got to her father is because he is mad that he doesn't have power over someone. "You're upset because at the end of the day everyone around you knows you as a delusional and grubby little control freak who hasn't matured as a person for 38 years. However, last time I checked that's not my fucking problem," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-disowned-by-transgender-daughter-hes-desperate-for-attention-6193039">Vivian Wilson </a>is one of six kids Musk shares with his first wife, Justine Wilson. She legally changed her name in 2022 and sought gender-affirming care. Her billionaire father has repeatedly blamed the "woke mind virus" for her decision and said that she is "dead" to him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Vivian, on the other hand, described her father as "cold" and "cruel". She claimed that the billionaire harassed her as a young child over her effeminate traits. "He is uncaring and narcissistic," she said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jeedva6o_elon-musk-daughter_625x300_13_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivian Wilson is one of six kids Musk shares with his first wife, Justine Wilson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-capitol-rioters-supporters-of-donald-trump-await-pardons-6969400]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Capitol Rioters, Supporters Of Donald Trump, Await Pardons]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-capitol-rioters-supporters-of-donald-trump-await-pardons-6969400]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:49:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump supporters who were charged with storming the US Capitol are now expecting pardons from the incoming American president, who has lauded them as "patriots" and "political prisoners."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump supporters who were charged with storming the US Capitol are now expecting pardons from the incoming American president, who has lauded them as "patriots" and "political prisoners."</p>

<p>More than 1,500 people have been charged in connection with the January 6, 2021 assault on Congress which sought to disrupt certification of Democrat Joe Biden's 2020 election victory.</p>

<p>"I am inclined to pardon many of them," Trump, whose first term as president ended under the cloud of the attack, said at a CNN town hall, one of a number of times he made the pledge during his 2024 bid to retake the White House.</p>

<p>"I can't say for every single one because a couple of them, probably, they got out of control," he said.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly played down the violence of January 6, even going so far as to describe it recently as a "day of love."</p>

<p>More than 140 police officers were injured in hours of clashes with rioters wielding flagpoles, baseball bats, hockey sticks and other makeshift weapons along with Tasers and canisters of bear spray.</p>

<p>The assault on the Capitol followed a fiery speech by then-president Trump to tens of thousands of his supporters near the White House in which he repeated his false claims that he won the 2020 race.</p>

<p>Several Capitol riot defendants have already seized upon Trump's election victory over Vice President Kamala Harris to ask that their trials or sentencing be put on hold.</p>

<p>Christopher Carnell, a 21-year-old from North Carolina, asked that a status hearing in his disorderly conduct case be delayed in light of Trump's "multiple clemency promises."</p>

<p>Carnell, his lawyer said, "is expecting to be relieved of the criminal prosecution that he is currently facing when the new administration takes office."</p>

<p>Judge Beryl Howell denied the request.</p>

<p><strong>'Never face consequences'</strong></p>

<p>Another defendant, Jaimee Avery, asked that her sentencing on Friday for trespassing convictions be rescheduled to a date after January 20, 2025 -- the day Trump will be sworn in as the 47th US president.</p>

<p>"President-elect Trump, who played an integral role in the events of January 6, 2021, has repeatedly publicly stated that he will pardon January 6 protestors should he win the presidency," her lawyer said in a court filing.</p>

<p>"It would create a gross disparity for Ms Avery to spend even a day in jail when the man who played a pivotal role in organizing and instigating the events of January 6 will now never face consequences for it."</p>

<p>Judge Christopher Cooper denied Avery's request to delay her sentencing.</p>

<p>Trump was charged by special counsel Jack Smith with conspiring to overturn the results of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>But the case never made it to trial, and is now being wound down under the Justice Department's policy of not prosecuting a sitting president.</p>

<p>Trump has not ruled out giving pardons to members of the far-right Proud Boys and Oath Keepers militant groups, who were convicted of seditious conspiracy and received the stiffest prison sentences.</p>

<p>Enrique Tarrio, the former Proud Boys leader, is serving a 22-year prison sentence for directing a military-style assault on the Capitol, while Oath Keepers founder Stewart Rhodes was sentenced to 18 years in prison.</p>

<p>According to the latest figures from the US Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia, 1,532 people have been charged in connection with the Capitol siege, including 571 accused of assaulting, resisting or impeding law enforcement officers.</p>

<p>More than 940 defendants have pleaded guilty to various offenses while another 195 were convicted at trial.</p>

<p>Trump pardoned a number of his close political allies of federal charges before he left office in January 2021, including his 2016 presidential campaign chiefs Paul Manafort and Steve Bannon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/gqsn3b4_capitol-hill-reuters_625x300_08_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 1,500 people have been charged in connection with the January 6, 2021 assault on Congress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/f-15-fighter-jets-arrive-in-middle-east-us-military-6969368]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[F-15 Fighter Jets Arrive In Middle East: US Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/f-15-fighter-jets-arrive-in-middle-east-us-military-6969368]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:37:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American F-15 fighter planes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, after Washington announced the deployment of additional assets to the region in a warning to Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American F-15 fighter planes arrived in the Middle East on Thursday, the US military said, after Washington announced the deployment of additional assets to the region in a warning to Iran.</p>

<p>"Today, US Air Force F-15E Strike Eagles from the 492nd Fighter Squadron, RAF Lakenheath, England, arrive in the US Central Command area of responsibility," the military command responsible for the Middle East said on social media.</p>

<p>The United States announced on November 1 that it was sending bombers, fighter and tanker aircraft and ballistic missile defense destroyers to the Middle East.</p>

<p>"Should Iran, its partners, or its proxies use this moment to target American personnel or interests in the region, the United States will take every measure necessary to defend our people," Pentagon spokesman Major General Pat Ryder said in a statement on the deployment.</p>

<p>Israel launched strikes against Iran on October 26, hitting military infrastructure while steering clear of critical nuclear and oil sites, and the country's supreme leader has vowed that Tehran will retaliate for Israeli attacks.</p>

<p>Iran has carried out two major attacks against Israel in 2024 -- one in April after a strike on its consulate in Damascus that was blamed on Israel, and another in October that Tehran said was in response to the assassination of leaders of armed groups it backs in the Middle East.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/b5dh9oeo_f15-fighter-jet_625x300_10_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US announced on November 1 that it was sending fighter aircrafts to the Middle East (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/throughout-history-jews-found-refuge-in-india-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-6969361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Throughout History, Jews Found Refuge In India: Israeli Envoy Reuven Azar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/throughout-history-jews-found-refuge-in-india-israeli-envoy-reuven-azar-6969361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:30:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India never harboured a sense of anti-semitism, which encouraged Jews to come here for refuge, said Israeli ambassador to India, Reuven Azar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli ambassador to India, Reuven Azar, who was a guest at the event at the Austrian Ambassador to India, Katharina Wieser's house, who hosted Vinay Gupta, the author of the book, 'A Rescue in Vienna' at her residence, said that he admired the effort by Gupta's family in rescuing the Jews.</p>

<p>Mr Azar, while speaking with ANI said that Indians and Jews have been oppressed historically, but now as they are free, they have the opportunity to flourish together.</p>

<p>Mr Azar said that India never harboured a sense of anti-semitism, which encouraged Jews to come here for refuge.</p>

<p>"Well, people-to-people contact at the end of the day is the true diplomacy. You know, the bond between countries is not just a bond between leaders, but also a bond between people. India has extraordinary people, people who have been always welcoming of the Jewish people. There has never been in India any sign of anti-semitism. So people who came here throughout history to escape from persecution found refuge here and this is something worth mentioning and something that is continuing today when we are not being persecuted anymore when we have our state. Both the Indian people and the Jewish people have been oppressed for many centuries but today we are free and we have huge opportunities to develop relations to prosper and flourish together," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Azar said that he was in all praise for Gupta's book and his family who helped in rescuing the five Jewish families.</p>

<p>"I was delighted to come here today to the Austrian Ambassador's residence, and I congratulate the Ambassador for actually hosting Vinay Gupta, who has written the amazing story of his family, and rescued five Jewish families from Vienna in the 30s, after the Anschluss, after the Nazis took over Austria. The Jewish community was a formidable community with businesspeople, academicians, and doctors who unfortunately were exterminated by the Nazis. Some of them managed to escape and each one of these stories is worth telling. I heard with admiration the amazing story of Gupta's family," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Azar said that he would send the book to Yad Vashem, Israel's official memorial to the victims of the Holocaust, for research purposes.</p>

<p>"Gupta Sr was not only an entrepreneur but was a person with a huge heart. Thanks to his goodwill, many souls were saved during the Holocaust. So it's a story that is worth to be told. And I promise Gupta that I'm going to send his book to Yad Vashem, to Jerusalem, for the researchers of the Holocaust in Jerusalem to read it and to follow it up and I'm really thankful for this opportunity to be here today," he said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pbaru998_reuven-azar_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reuven Azar, Israeli ambassador to India]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centenarians-increased-by-30-in-italy-over-the-past-decade-6969334]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Centenarians Increased By 30% In Italy While Birth Rate Continues To Decline]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centenarians-increased-by-30-in-italy-over-the-past-decade-6969334]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 08 Nov 2024 06:29:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The number of people aged over 100 in Italy has increased by 30% over the past 10 years, while birth rates have continued to decline.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The number of people aged over 100 in Italy has increased by 30% over the past 10 years, while birth rates have continued to decline.</p>

<p>There were more than 22,000 Italians in the age bracket between 100 and 104 in 2024, up from just over 17,000 in 2014, according to a report by national statistics bureau ISTAT on Thursday. The vast majority of them - 81% - are women.</p>

<p>There were 21 super-centenarians - individuals aged 110 years and older - still alive in 2024, of whom only one is a man. This is more than double the number in 2009, when there were only 10.</p>

<p>The gradual aging of the population is causing problems for Italy, where the birth rate is among the lowest in Europe, with a heavy impact on public accounts because of huge spending on pensions and health care.</p>

<p>The oldest person in Italy is a 114-year-old woman; among men, the oldest is 110, said ISTAT.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7scksqm_centenarians-in-italy_625x300_08_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The oldest person in Italy is a 114-year-old woman]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>