<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 23:15:41 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-teen-youngest-to-scale-14-tallest-peaks-says-sherpas-deserve-better-6811003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepal Teen, Youngest To Scale 14 Tallest Peaks, Says Sherpas Deserve Better]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-teen-youngest-to-scale-14-tallest-peaks-says-sherpas-deserve-better-6811003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 23:02:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Nepali teenager, the youngest person ever to scale all 14 of the world's tallest peaks, says he wants to use his skills to benefit the Himalayan nation's Sherpa community and turn out world-class athletes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Nepali teenager, the youngest person ever to scale all 14 of the world's tallest peaks, says he wants to use his skills to benefit the Himalayan nation's Sherpa community and turn out world-class athletes.</p>

<p>Sherpas, an ethnic group living mainly in the vicinity of the world's highest peak, Mount Everest, are known for climbing skills that make them the backbone of mountain expeditions.</p>

<p>They fix ropes, ladders, carry loads, cook and guide foreign climbers, earning from a single expedition amounts that range from $2,500 to $16,500 or more, depending on experience.</p>

<p>"I want to see Sherpas as global athletes, not just guides," said Nima Rinji Sherpa, 18, who last week climbed Shishapangma, the world's 14th highest peak at 8,027 m (26,335 ft), in Tibet.</p>

<p>"We deserve the same privilege as Western climbers," added the 12th grader, who began climbing at the age of 16, and scaled all 14 peaks exceeding 8,000 ft (2,438 m) in the last two years.</p>

<p>He said he planned to exploit his climbing skills to build contacts with donor agencies, mobilising funds and support for schools, hospitals and activities to benefit the mountain community.</p>

<p>"I want to be a medium between the community and donor agencies," Nima said on Wednesday, the lower portion of his face still black from burns caused by the sun's reflections off the snow during his climb.</p>

<p>The son of a veteran Everest climber who now runs his own company organising expeditions, Nima bested the record of Mingma Gyalu Sherpa of Nepal, who was 30 when he achieved the feat in 2019.</p>

<p>His most demanding effort was the 8,034-m (26,358-ft) climb of Pakistan's Gasherbrum II last year directly after having scaled Gasherbrum I, the world's 11th highest peak at 8,080 m (26,510 ft), in 25 hours without proper rest and food, he said.</p>

<p>Nima said muscle cramps were his biggest physical challenge as his "fragile" teenage body had not finished growing, adding, "I am not as strong as I should be."</p>

<p>He was caught in a small avalanche on Nepal's Annapurna I peak this year after a fall of about 5 m to 10 m (16 ft to 32 feet) on Pakistan's Nanga Parbat last year, but luckily escaped serious injury both times.</p>

<p>"I never push myself beyond my bounds," he said. "There is (the need for) good judgment. There is (the need for) safety."</p>

<p>This winter, Nima aims for an alpine-style climb of Nepal's Mount Manaslu, the world's eighth highest peak at 8,163 m (26,781 ft).</p>

<p>An 8,000-m mountain has never been climbed in winter in alpine style, he said, referring to the technique in which climbers tackle the summit in one go, without oxygen and relying chiefly on themselves, with minimum support.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rcq9bgs_nima-rinji-sherpa-afp_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nima Rinji Sherpa, a Nepali teenager, is youngest ever to scale all 14 of the world's tallest peaks]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-finding-on-fruit-flies-could-be-key-to-human-longevity-study-6813465]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Big Finding On Fruit Flies Could be Key to Human Longevity: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/big-finding-on-fruit-flies-could-be-key-to-human-longevity-study-6813465]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 22:51:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gut could be key to understanding longevity, according to a study that found a gut hormone in fruit flies could control lifespan, a result important to humans as both species have many similar genes and hormones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gut could be key to understanding longevity, according to a study that found a gut hormone in fruit flies could control lifespan, a result important to humans as both species have many similar genes and hormones.</p>

<p>Researchers at Brown University in the US have found that suppressing the insulin-regulating 'neuropeptide F' hormone in the gut of fruit flies extended longevity.</p>

<p>The findings are important for humans too, especially as new diabetes and obesity drugs developed from gut hormones in the same insect family are becoming widespread, the researchers said.</p>

<p>Understanding ageing mechanisms in flies may thus help explain what's happening in humans as well, they said.</p>

<p>The findings are published in the journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.</p>

<p>Reducing insulin and targeting related processes have been found to slow ageing and extend lifespan in animals in previous studies.</p>

<p>In this study, the researchers manipulated gene activity in the intestines of fruit flies such that they produced lower levels of the neuropeptide F hormone, and thereby lower levels of insulin.</p>

<p>The team then compared the hormone production in the gut to what was happening in the fruit flies' brains and connected all the results with the diet that the insects were consuming.</p>

<p>The researchers found that suppressing the gut activity of the neuropeptide F hormone extended longevity in the flies, as did blocking the activity of related proteins in their brains. These proteins control the production of 'juvenile' hormones, which are known to regulate physiology.</p>

<p>The researchers said that neuropeptide F hormone in the gut impacted ageing in flies by integrating these factors -- nutrient sensing, insulin processes and juvenile hormone production.</p>

<p>"Gut neuropeptide F modulates (fruit fly) ageing through the integration of nutrient sensing, insulin signalling, and juvenile hormone," the authors wrote.</p>

<p>"Based on (our) research, we suspect that over-production of gut neuropeptide F in flies will have a negative effect on ageing and decrease lifespan," study author Marc Tatar, a professor of biology at Brown University.</p>

<p>The researchers explained that humans do not produce either of the neuropeptide F or juvenile hormones. Instead, gut hormones are involved in regulating insulin in humans.</p>

<p>Given how diabetes and obesity drugs, which are known to target hormones involved in controlling insulin, and the findings on the relationship between insulin and ageing in flies, it may be time to consider how the drugs could impact human ageing, the authors said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/ci99s078_fruit-flies_625x300_09_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Findings are published in the journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-killed-says-israeli-minister-news-agency-afp-6813248]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Chief And "Mass Murderer" Yahya Sinwar Eliminated: Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-killed-says-israeli-minister-news-agency-afp-6813248]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 22:20:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel said Thursday its forces killed Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar in a Gaza operation, dealing a massive blow to the group it has been fighting since the October 7, 2023 attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel said Thursday its forces killed Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar in a Gaza operation, dealing a massive blow to the group it has been fighting since the October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>"The mass murderer Yahya Sinwar, responsible for the massacre and atrocities of October 7, was eliminated... by IDF (Israeli military) soldiers," Foreign Minister Israel Katz said in a statement.</p>

<p>The military later confirmed that "after a year-long pursuit", soldiers "eliminated Yahya Sinwar, the leader of the Hamas terrorist organisation, in an operation in the southern Gaza Strip" on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Hamas has not confirmed his death.</p>

<p>Israel accuses Sinwar of masterminding the October 7 attack, the deadliest in Israeli history, and had been hunting him down since the start of the Gaza war.</p>

<p>He rose through the ranks of the Palestinian group to become first its leader in Gaza, then its overall head after the killing in July of political chief Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>Israel's announcement on Sinwar comes weeks after it assassinated Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah in a massive strike in Lebanon, where the Israeli military has been at war since late September.</p>

<p>A slew of other Iran-backed operative commanders have also been killed in recent months.</p>

<p>Israel said earlier this year that it had killed Mohammed Deif, Hamas's military chief, though the Palestinian group has not confirmed it.</p>

<p>Deif stood accused of planning, with Sinwar, the October 7 attack.</p>

<p>With Hamas massively weakened more than a year into the Gaza war, Sinwar's death could deal a seismic blow to the organisation.</p>

<p>Before the Israeli foreign minister confirmed Sinwar's death, the military said in a brief statement that during "operations in the Gaza Strip, three terrorists were eliminated", with the Hamas leader possibly one of them.</p>

<p>An Israeli security official told AFP that the military was conducting a DNA test on a operative's body to confirm whether it was Sinwar's.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Israel's Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said the country would "reach every terrorist and eliminate them".</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden was briefed aboard Air Force One while heading to Germany and was being kept informed of developments, a US official said Thursday.</p>

<p><strong>War on many fronts</strong></p>

<p>Israel has been at war with Hamas since the October 7 attack, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign in Gaza has killed 42,438 people, the majority civilians, according to data from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>Following the attack, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed to crush Hamas and bring home all 251 hostages seized by operatives in their cross-border onslaught. Ninety-seven remain in Gaza, including 34 Israeli officials say are dead.</p>

<p>Israel has since expanded the scope of its operations to Lebanon, where Hamas ally Hezbollah opened a front against Israel by launching low-intensity cross-border strikes that forced tens of thousands of Israelis to flee their homes.</p>

<p>Israel on Thursday launched strikes on the south Lebanese city of Tyre, where the group and its allies hold sway.</p>

<p>Israel also issued evacuation warnings for civilians in parts of Lebanon's eastern Bekaa Valley, a Hezbollah stronghold.</p>

<p>It had earlier struck a Hezbollah target in Syria, according to a war monitor, while Israel's main ally the United States used heavy bombers to hit rebel targets in Yemen.</p>

<p>Syria, the Huthi rebels in Yemen, Hezbollah in Lebanon and Hamas in Gaza all belong to the "axis of resistance" of groups aligned with Iran.</p>

<p>Tehran on October 1 conducted a missile strike on Israel, over which Israel has vowed to retaliate, sparking concern around the world that what is already a war on multiple fronts could morph into an all-out regional conflict.</p>

<p><strong>Iran warning</strong></p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards chief Hossein Salami on Thursday warned Tehran would hit Israel "painfully" if it attacks Iranian targets.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a Britain-based monitor, said the Israeli raid on the Syrian city of Latakia targeted a "weapons depot belonging to Hezbollah".</p>

<p>The Israeli military did not comment on the strike when contacted by AFP.</p>

<p>In Huthi-controlled areas of Yemen, the United States conducted multiple B-2 bomber strikes on weapons storage facilities, according to the US military and defence department.</p>

<p>The Huthis' political bureau said "the American aggression will not pass without a response", and vowed to continue the group's "support and assistance to Gaza and Lebanon".</p>

<p>The war in Lebanon since last month has left at least 1,373 people dead, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures, though the real toll is likely higher.</p>

<p>Israeli troops and Hezbollah fighters have been clashing near Lebanon's southern border, where Hezbollah on Thursday said it hit four Israeli tanks with guided missiles.</p>

<p>Rescue workers affiliated with the Amal party, a Hezbollah ally, in the southern city of Qana were digging through the rubble of several buildings destroyed in strikes this week.</p>

<p>"More than 15 buildings have been completely destroyed, total destruction in a neighbourhood in Qana," said Mohammed Nasrallah Ibrahim, one of the rescuers.</p>

<p>Israel has faced criticism over its strikes in Lebanon, including from its tops arms supplier the US.</p>

<p><strong>Hunger in Gaza</strong></p>

<p>In northern Gaza's Jabalia, two hospitals said Israeli air strikes on a school sheltering displaced people killed at least 14 people.</p>

<p>The military reported that it had hit operatives.</p>

<p>Some 345,000 Gazans face "catastrophic" levels of hunger this winter after aid deliveries fell, a UN-backed assessment said Thursday, warning of the persistent risk of famine.</p>

<p>Nearly 100 percent of Gaza's population now lives in poverty, with a "staggering" unemployment rate of nearly 80 percent, the UN's International Labour Organization said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The impact of the war on Gaza "will be felt for generations to come," said the ILO's Ruba Jaradat.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0as4rdso_yahya-sinwar_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has accused Yahya Sinwar of masterminding the group's attack on October 7 last year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/africa-reports-1-100-mpox-death-warns-outbreak-is-out-of-control-6812758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Africa Reports 1,100 Mpox Deaths, Warns Outbreak Is "Out Of Control"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/africa-reports-1-100-mpox-death-warns-outbreak-is-out-of-control-6812758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 21:08:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some 1,100 people across Africa have died from mpox, the African Union's health agency said Thursday, warning that the epidemic was "going out of control" without further action.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some 1,100 people across Africa have died from mpox, the African Union's health agency said Thursday, warning that the epidemic was "going out of control" without further action.</p>

<p>In all, 42,000 cases have been recorded in Africa since January, the Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) said, with cases reported for the first time in Zambia and Zimbabwe.</p>

<p>This brings to 18 the number of African countries where mpox has been officially detected this year, it said.</p>

<p>"Mpox is going out of control if we don't act," Africa CDC head Jean Kaseya told an online media briefing.</p>

<p>"I'm so sad to say we now have more than 1,000 deaths due to mpox, as you can see this week, week 40, we have 1,100 deaths reported in total."</p>

<p>The majority of deaths have been in the Democratic Republic of Congo, the epicentre of the outbreak, which launched a vaccination drive earlier this month.</p>

<p>But Kaseya said that across the continent there were still "more new cases week after week".</p>

<p>"Eighteen countries is too much, we cannot continue like that," he said.</p>

<p>Kaseya once again urged international partners to step up and called for them to immediately release funds pledged to combat mpox.</p>

<p>"We want now to see concrete action on the ground to stop this outbreak," he said.</p>

<p>Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.</p>

<p>It causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions, and can be deadly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b9dvemb_mpox_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mpox is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-scrambled-typhoon-jet-to-intercept-london-bound-air-india-flight-after-bomb-threat-6812625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Scrambled Typhoon Jet To Intercept Air India Flight After Bomb Threat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-scrambled-typhoon-jet-to-intercept-london-bound-air-india-flight-after-bomb-threat-6812625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:51:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Royal Air Force on Thursday scrambled a Typhoon fighter jet to intercept an Air India aircraft that received a bomb threat and the plane later landed safely in London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Royal Air Force on Thursday scrambled a Typhoon fighter jet to intercept an Air India aircraft that received a bomb threat and the plane later landed safely in London.</p>

<p>The bomb threat was received for the Air India plane from Mumbai to London, an airline official said.</p>

<p>"We can confirm that RAF Quick Reaction Alert Typhoon fighter aircraft from RAF Coningsby were launched this afternoon, to investigate a civilian aircraft," a Royal Air Force spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Following an uneventful interception the aircraft was released to continue to its original destination under the direction of civilian air traffic control, the spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Further, the spokesperson said the incident is now being handled under the control of civilian authorities.</p>

<p>The airline official said the flight landed safely at London Heathrow Airport.</p>

<p>A loud sonic boom was heard in the East Anglia region of England as the jets were scrambled, authorised to transit at supersonic speed for operational reasons.</p>

<p>"Police can confirm a loud noise heard by residents in the county was a sonic boom caused by RAF aircraft this afternoon (17 October) and was not an explosion," Norfolk Police said in a statement.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/3e42nik8_eurofighter-typhoon_625x300_04_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A loud sonic boom was heard in East Anglia region on England. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-deploy-10-000-north-korean-troops-in-kyiv-claims-ukraine-president-6812459]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia To Deploy 10,000 North Korean Troops Against Ukraine, Claims Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-to-deploy-10-000-north-korean-troops-in-kyiv-claims-ukraine-president-6812459]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:26:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia is preparing to deploy 10,000 North Korean soldiers in the fight against Kyiv, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Thursday, citing intelligence information.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia is preparing to deploy 10,000 North Korean soldiers in the fight against Kyiv, Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said Thursday, citing intelligence information.</p>

<p>Zelensky has previously accused North Korea of sending troops to Russia's army but this was the first time he gave an exact figure.</p>

<p>An unspecified number of North Korean soldiers were already on "occupied Ukrainian territory from the side of Russian enemies", Zelensky said, based on "information from our intelligence".</p>

<p>"We know (of) about 10,000 soldiers of North Korea that they are preparing to send fight against us," he added, speaking to reporters in Brussels after talks with EU leaders.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader was attending both an EU leaders' summit and a meeting of NATO defence ministers in Brussels as he presses for support for his "victory plan" to end the war against Russia.</p>

<p>Zelensky said the North Korean troops included "land forces" and "other tactical personnel".</p>

<p>"This is the first step to a world war," he warned, noting that Iran was also backing Russia with "drones and missiles", a claim that Tehran has repeatedly denied.</p>

<p>He said Russian President Vladimir Putin was "counting" on the North Korean soldiers because he was "afraid of mobilisation".</p>

<p>Zelensky conducted a whirlwind tour of Western capitals earlier this month including Washington, Paris, Berlin, Rome and London to promote his initiative.</p>

<p>Experts have long said North Korean missiles are being deployed in Ukraine by Russian forces, which both Moscow and Pyongyang have denied.</p>

<p>Putin made a rare visit to Pyongyang in June, where he signed a mutual defence agreement with leader Kim Jong Un.</p>

<p>Moscow and Pyongyang have been allies since North Korea's founding after World War II and have drawn closer since Russia's 2022 invasion of Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6fdrip3s_volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelensky said North Korean troops included "land forces" and "other tactical personnel". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-paynes-death-hotel-employee-called-police-warning-about-his-safety-6812221]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Before Liam Payne's Death, Call To Cops From Hotel Warned Of "Life At Risk"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-paynes-death-hotel-employee-called-police-warning-about-his-safety-6812221]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:50:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pop star Liam Payne, who shot to global fame with boy band One Direction, died at the age of 31 after falling from a third-floor hotel room balcony in Buenos Aires, Argentina, triggering an outpouring of tributes from fans around the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop star Liam Payne, who shot to global fame with boy band One Direction, died at the age of 31 after falling from a third-floor hotel room balcony in Buenos Aires, Argentina, triggering an outpouring of tributes from fans around the world.</p>

<p>Before the fall, a hotel employee at the CasaSur hotel in the leafy neighborhood of Palermo called emergency services, asking for help with a guest who he said was trashing his room and appeared to be under the influence of drugs or alcohol, an audio obtained from the Buenos Aires security ministry showed.</p>

<p>Here is the full transcript of that call, translated by Reuters from the original Spanish. The Buenos Aires security ministry confirmed to Reuters that the call related to Liam Payne.</p>

<h2><strong>911 CALL TEXT</strong></h2>

<p>- Good afternoon, an emergency.</p>

<p>- Hello, good morning. I just called, I got disconnected. I'm calling from CasaSur Palermo hotel, Costa Rica 6032.</p>

<p>- What's going on at the hotel, sir?</p>

<p>- Well, we have a guest who is intoxicated by drugs and alcohol. And, well, he's ... When he's conscious, he breaks, he's breaking the whole room. And, well, we need you to send someone, please.</p>

<p>- Under the influence of alcohol and drugs, right, sir?</p>

<p>- Yes, that's correct.</p>

<p>- You told me Costa Rica, what number, sir? Excuse me.</p>

<p>- Costa Rica 6032.</p>

<p>- This is in the Capital (Buenos Aires), right? Between Arevalo and Cramer.</p>

<p>- Yes.</p>

<p>- Where is the hotel? What's the name of the hotel?</p>

<p>- CasaSur Palermo. And we need you to send someone urgently because, well, I don't know if the guest's life is at risk. He is in a room with a balcony. And, well, we are a little afraid that he will do something that will put his life at risk.</p>

<p>- How long has he been there or is it a residential hotel?</p>

<p>- No, no, he has been here for two or three days.</p>

<p>- I understand. There is no information because they cannot enter any more?</p>

<p>- No.</p>

<p>- Should we notify the SAME (Sistema de Atencion Médica de Emergencia) staff as well?</p>

<p>- Yes, what I ask you is that someone comes urgently because, well...</p>

<p>- In the call they've been notified (the SAME). Any more information to give to us? Who are you? The person in charge?</p>

<p>- I am the head of reception.</p>

<p>- Would you be the person in charge of the place, right?</p>

<p>- Yes, yes.</p>

<p>- It has already been noted. What is your name, sir?</p>

<p>- Esteban.</p>

<p>- It has been notified. Please wait for the police.</p>

<p>- Ok.</p>

<p>- Thank you for contacting us. You can release the line.</p>

<p>- Do they send the police too or not?</p>

<p>- The police of the commune, yes, give me a second to ... Commune 14 and SAME?</p>

<p>- No, no, no. Only SAME. Only SAME.</p>

<p>- I understand. Don't worry, that was notified anyway.</p>

<p>- Ok, perfect. Well, thank you very much.</p>

<p>- Since you tell me that he is under the influence of alcohol and drugs, SAME won't come in alone.</p>

<p>- Doesn't SAME come in alone?</p>

<p>- No.</p>

<p>- Ok.</p>

<p>- It is still notified. When the police arrives, you explain to them and if it's required the SAME presence, they will call them.</p>

<p>- Good, ok. Perfect.</p>

<p>- It has already been notified anyway. Have a nice day, sir.</p>

<p>- Good, thank you. Likewise.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m2vmgrlo_liam-payne_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liam Payne  died at the age of 31. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-leader-sinwar-unrepentant-amid-ongoing-israeli-assault-on-gaza-6812183]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About Yahya Sinwar: Hamas Chief Who Was Committed To Eradicating Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-leader-sinwar-unrepentant-amid-ongoing-israeli-assault-on-gaza-6812183]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:47:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar remains unrepentant about the October 7 attacks a year ago, people in contact with him have said, despite unleashing an Israeli invasion that has killed tens of thousands of Palestinians, laid waste to his Gaza homeland and]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar remains unrepentant about the October 7 attacks a year ago, people in contact with him have said, despite unleashing an Israeli invasion that has killed tens of thousands of Palestinians, laid waste to his Gaza homeland and rained destruction on ally Hezbollah.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Israel said it had killed Sinwar, 62, the architect of the Hamas cross-border raids that became the deadliest day in Israel's history.</p>

<p>For Sinwar, armed struggle remained the only way to force the creation of a Palestinian nation, four Palestinian officials and two sources from governments in the Middle East said, speaking in weeks leading up to the October 7 anniversary.</p>

<p>The October 7 attacks killed 1,200 people, mainly civilians, and captured 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies, in the deadliest day for Jews since the Holocaust.</p>

<p>Israel responded by launching a massive offensive, killing 42,400 people and displacing 1.9 million, according to Palestinian health authorities and UN figures.</p>

<p>Now the conflict has spread to Lebanon, with Israel heavily degrading the Iranian-backed operator group Hezbollah, including killing most of its leadership. Hamas patron Tehran is at risk of being pulled into open war with Israel.</p>

<p>Sinwar has drawn Iran and its entire "Axis of Resistance" - comprising Hezbollah, Yemen's Houthis and Iraqi militias - into conflict with Israel, said Hassan Hassan, an author and researcher on Islamic groups.</p>

<p>"We're seeing now the ripple effects of October 7. Sinwar's gamble didn't work," Hassan said, suggesting that the Axis of Resistance may never recover.</p>

<p>"What Israel did to Hezbollah in two weeks is almost equal to a whole year of degrading Hamas in Gaza. With Hezbollah, three layers of leadership have been eliminated, its military command has been decimated, and its important leader Hassan Nasrallah has been assassinated," added Hassan.</p>

<p>However, Sinwar's grip on the Hamas remains unwavering, despite some signs of dissent among Gazans.</p>

<p>He was chosen as the Islamist movement's overall leader after his predecessor Ismail Haniyeh was killed in July by a suspected Israeli strike during a visit to Tehran. Israel has not confirmed its involvement in the strike.</p>

<p>Operating from the shadows of a network of labyrinthine tunnels under Gaza, two Israeli sources said Sinwar and his brother, also a top commander, had appeared to have survived Israeli airstrikes, which have reportedly killed his deputy Mohammed Deif and other senior leaders.</p>

<p>Dubbed "The Face of Evil" by Israel, Sinwar operates in secrecy, moving constantly and using trusted messengers for non-digital communication, according to three Hamas officials and one regional official. He has not been seen in public since October 7, 2023.</p>

<p>Over months of failed ceasefire talks, led by Qatar and Egypt, that focused on swapping prisoners for hostages, Sinwar was the sole decision-maker, three Hamas sources said. Negotiators would wait for days for responses filtered through a secretive chain of messengers.</p>

<p>Hamas and Israel did not respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>Sinwar's high tolerance for suffering, both for himself and for the Palestinian people, in the name of a cause, was apparent when he helped negotiate the 2011 exchange of 1,027 prisoners, himself included, for one kidnapped Israeli soldier held in Gaza. The kidnapping by Hamas had led to an Israeli assault on the coastal enclave and thousands of Palestinian deaths.</p>

<p>Half a dozen people who know Sinwar told Reuters his resolve was shaped by an impoverished childhood in Gaza's refugee camps and a brutal 22 years in Israeli custody, including a period in Ashkelon, the town his parents called home before fleeing after the 1948 Arab-Israeli war.</p>

<p>The question of hostages and prisoner swaps is deeply personal for Sinwar, said all the sources, who requested anonymity to speak freely about sensitive matters. He has vowed to free all Palestinian prisoners held in Israel.</p>

<p>Sinwar became a member of Hamas soon after its founding in the 1980s, adopting the group's radical Islamist ideology, which seeks to establish an Islamic state in historic Palestine and opposes Israel's existence.</p>

<p>The ideology views Israel not only as a political rival but as an occupying force on Muslim land. Seen in this light, hardships and suffering are often interpreted by him and his followers as part of a larger Islamic belief of sacrifice, experts on Islamic movements say.</p>

<p>"What lies behind his resolve is tenacity of ideology, tenacity of goal. He's ascetic and satisfied with little," said one senior Hamas official who requested anonymity.</p>

<p><strong>FROM SACKCLOTH TO LEADER</strong></p>

<p>Before the war, Sinwar, would sometimes tell of his early life in Gaza during decades of Israeli occupation, once saying his mother made clothes from empty UN food-aid sacks, according to Gaza resident Wissam Ibrahim, who has met him.</p>

<p>In a semi-autobiographical novel written in prison, Sinwar described scenes of troops bulldozing Palestinian houses, "like a monster crushing its prey's bones," before Israel withdrew from Gaza in 2005.</p>

<p>A ruthless enforcer tasked with punishing Palestinians suspected of informing for Israel, Sinwar then made his name as a prison leader, emerging as a street hero from a 22-year Israeli sentence for masterminding the abduction and murder of two Israeli soldiers and four Palestinians. He then quickly rose to the top of the Hamas ranks.</p>

<p>His understanding of the everyday hardships and brutal realities in Gaza was well-received by Gazans and made people feel at ease, four journalists and three Hamas officials said, despite his fearsome reputation and explosive anger.</p>

<p>Sinwar is regarded by Arab and Palestinian officials as the architect of Hamas' strategy and military capabilities, bolstered through his strong ties with Iran, which he visited in 2012.</p>

<p>Before orchestrating the October 7 raids Sinwar made no secret of his desire to strike his enemy hard.</p>

<p>In a speech the year before, he vowed to send a flood of fighters and rockets to Israel, hinting at a war that would either unite the world to establish a Palestinian state on land Israel occupied in 1967, or leave the Jewish nation isolated on the global stage.</p>

<p>By the time of the speech, Sinwar and Deif had already hatched secret plans for the assault. They were even running training drills in public that simulated such an attack.</p>

<p>His goals have not been fulfilled. While the issue is once again at the top of the global agenda, the prospect of a Palestinian nation is as distant as ever.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has categorically rejected a post-war plan for Gaza that would include a firm timeline for the establishment of a Palestinian state.</p>

<p><strong>'HEAD HARDER THAN A ROCK'</strong></p>

<p>Sinwar was arrested in 1988 and sentenced to four life sentences, accused of orchestrating the abduction and murder of two Israeli soldiers and four suspected Palestinian informants.</p>

<p>Nabih Awadah, a former Lebanese Communist operator who was imprisoned with Sinwar in Ashkelon between 1991-95, said the Hamas leader viewed the 1993 Oslo peace accords between Israel and the Palestinian Authority as "disastrous" and a ruse by Israel, which he said would only relinquish Palestinian land "by force, not by negotiations."</p>

<p>Calling him "willful and dogmatic", Awadah said Sinwar would light up with joy whenever he heard of attacks against Israelis by Hamas or Lebanon's Hezbollah group. For him, military confrontation was the only path "to liberating Palestine" from Israeli occupation.</p>

<p>Awadah said Sinwar was an "influential model to all prisoners, even those who were not Islamists or religious."</p>

<p>Michael Koubi, a former official with Israel's Shin Bet security agency who interrogated Sinwar for 180 hours in prison, said Sinwar clearly stood out for his ability to intimidate and command.</p>

<p>Koubi once asked the operator, then aged 28 or 29, why he was not already married. "He told me Hamas is my wife, Hamas is my child. Hamas for me is everything." Sinwar married after his release from prison in 2011 and has three children.</p>

<p>In jail, he continued to pursue Palestinian spies, Awadah said, echoing reports from Shin Bet interrogators.</p>

<p>His sharp instincts and caution allowed him to identify and expose Shin Bet informants infiltrated in the prison, Awadah said.</p>

<p>He said Sinwar's leadership was pivotal during a hunger strike in 1992, in which he led over 1,000 prisoners to survive solely on water and salt. Sinwar negotiated with prison authorities and refused to settle for partial concessions.</p>

<p>He also used his time in prison to learn fluent Hebrew.</p>

<p>Awadah said Sinwar frequently recalled that Ashkelon, where they were imprisoned together, was his family's ancestral hometown.</p>

<p>When playing table tennis in the courtyard of Ashkelon jail, in present day Israel, Sinwar would often play barefoot, saying he wanted his feet to touch the land of Palestine.</p>

<p>"Sinwar often told us: 'I'm not in prison; I'm on my land. I am free here, in my country.'"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnlapn8o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For Yahya Sinwar, armed struggle remained the only way to force the creation of a Palestinian nation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-killed-in-gaza-strike-checking-says-israel-army-6811921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Leader Yahya Sinwar Likely Killed In Gaza Strike, Claims Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-killed-in-gaza-strike-checking-says-israel-army-6811921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 19:13:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli ministers have been informed that Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar has very likely been killed by Israeli troops who were conducting an operation in southern Gaza, two officials with knowledge of the situation said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli ministers have been informed that Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar has very likely been killed by Israeli troops who were conducting an operation in southern Gaza, two officials with knowledge of the situation said.</p>

<p>Israeli broadcasters quoted unnamed officials as saying Sinwar, the architect of the devastating attack on Israel last October that set off the Gaza war, was dead.</p>

<p>There was no immediate confirmation from the military, which earlier said it was checking the possibility that Sinwar, Israel's most wanted enemy, was among three operatives killed during an operation in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>"At this stage, the identity of the terrorists cannot be confirmed," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>It said there were no signs that Israeli hostages had been present in the building where the three operatives were killed.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Hamas. Al-Majd, a Hamas-linked website that usually publishes about security issues, urged Palestinians to wait for information about Sinwar from the group itself and not Israeli media outlets, which it said aimed to break their spirit.</p>

<p>Israeli media reported that the operation was a routine raid that caught Sinwar by chance.</p>

<p>If confirmed, his death would represent a major boost to the Israeli military and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu after a string of high-profile assassinations of prominent leaders of its enemies in recent months.</p>

<p>Families of the 101 Israeli and foreign hostages still held in Gaza welcomed the news about Sinwar but repeated their call for a deal to bring the hostages home.</p>

<p>"We call on the Israeli government, world leaders, and mediating countries to leverage the military achievement into a diplomatic one by pursuing an immediate agreement for the release of all 101 hostages," the group said.</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant posted a message on social media platform X with a biblical quotation.</p>

<p>"'You will pursue your enemies and they will fall before you by the sword.' - Leviticus 26 Our enemies cannot hide. We will pursue and eliminate them."</p>

<p>The post contained pictures of former Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, who was assassinated in Beirut last month and former Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif, who was killed in August, with a blank space for a third picture between them. All three were crossed out in red.</p>

<p><strong>SUCCESSION QUESTIONS</strong></p>

<p>Sinwar, the chief architect of the on Israel that triggered the Gaza war, has been at the top of Israel's wanted list ever since Hamas-led gunmen attacked Israel on Oct 7, 2023 killing some 1,200 people and taking more than 250 hostages into Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel's campaign in response has killed more than 42,000 people, turned much of Gaza into rubble and displaced most of its population. But Sinwar had so far eluded detection, possibly hiding in the warren of tunnels Hamas has built under Gaza over the past two decades.</p>

<p>His death would be the heaviest blow Hamas has suffered in more than a year of war, with more serious consequences for its remaining forces in Gaza than the assassination of former political leader Ismail Haniyeh, who had less connection with the day-to-day running of the conflict.</p>

<p>Previously leader of Hamas in the Gaza Strip, Sinwar was named as its overall leader following the assassination of former political chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in July.</p>

<p>It remains unclear who may succeed Sinwar, an uncompromising enemy of Israel with a reputation as a ruthless enforcer within the organisation. None of his potential successors has the same standing.</p>

<p>The group's mastermind and political and strategic leader, Sinwar had unrivalled influence within Hamas and his death could potentially open the way to renewed efforts to reach a ceasefire deal to end the fighting.</p>

<p>Israel estimates it has destroyed Hamas as an organized military force and killed more than 18,000 Hamas fighters. But it is still engaged in fierce battles with small groups of fighters operating in the rubble of Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0as4rdso_yahya-sinwar_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If confirmed, the death of Yahya Sinwar would represent a major boost to the Israeli military. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-hit-record-low-all-you-need-to-know-about-justin-trudeau-6811687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India-Canada Ties Hit Record Low, All You Need To Know About Justin Trudeau]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-hit-record-low-all-you-need-to-know-about-justin-trudeau-6811687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:36:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This diplomatic row stems from Justin Trudeau's earlier accusations linking Indian agents to the 2023 murder of Khalistani leader Hardeep Singh Nijjar]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau is in the eye of a storm after he targeted India on Wednesday, saying the country made "a horrific mistake" by interfering as aggressively as it allegedly did in Canada's sovereignty. The statement -- Mr Trudeau's strongest in what's been a year of diplomatic tensions between the two nations -- came days after India and Canada expelled six of each other's diplomats.</p>

<p>India's Ministry of External Affairs has hit back at Justin Trudeau, saying Canada presented no evidence to support "serious allegations that it has chosen to level against India and Indian diplomats."</p>

<p><strong>Who is Justin Trudeau?</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau, Canada's 23rd Prime Minister, has steered the country through significant challenges. From climate change and economic uncertainty to diplomatic tensions and national security concerns, Mr Trudeau has shown strong leadership.</p>

<p><strong>Early Life And Education</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau was born on December 25, 1971, in Ottawa, Ontario, into political royalty. He is the son of former Canadian Prime Minister Pierre Trudeau and Margaret Trudeau.</p>

<p>Justin Trudeau studied literature at McGill University, earning a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1994. He then completed the education programme at the University of British Columbia and spent several years teaching French and maths in Vancouver.</p>

<p>Before entering politics, he engaged in community service as the Chair of Katimavik, a national youth volunteer organisation established by his father. He was also on the board of the Canadian Avalanche Foundation. Justin Trudeau also worked at a Montreal radio station, covering the 2004 Olympic Games in Athens, and had a role in the television miniseries, The Great War.</p>

<p><strong>Political innings</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau's entry into politics was marked by his election to the House of Commons in 2008, representing the district of Papineau. He served as the Liberal Party's Official Opposition critic for youth and multiculturalism, citizenship and immigration and secondary education and sport. He was re-elected in 2011, 2015, 2019 and 2021.</p>

<p>Justin Trudeau became the Leader of the Liberal Party in April 2013, focusing on job creation, economic growth and environmental protection. His win with 80 per cent of the votes set him up for the 2015 general election fight, where he faced Conservative Prime Minister Stephen Harper.</p>

<p>He was sworn in as Prime Minister on November 4, 2015, just over two weeks after he led the Liberal Party to victory on October 19.</p>

<p>As Prime Minister, Justin Trudeau continued to make waves in Canadian politics. In 2016, he established the Canada Child Benefit, legalised medical assistance for dying and introduced the federal carbon tax. He also legalised recreational marijuana through the Cannabis Act in 2018. In addition, he attempted Senate appointment reform by establishing the Independent Advisory Board for Senate Appointments and introduced the federal carbon tax.</p>

<p>He also appointed Canada's first gender-balanced Cabinet.</p>

<p><strong>Personal Life</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau got married to Sophie Gregoire in 2005, in Montreal. They have three children - Xavier (2007), Ella-Grace (2009) and Hadrien (2014).</p>

<p>In June 2013, after Mr Trudeau became the Liberal Party leader, they sold their Montreal home and rented a place in Ottawa. In 2014, an intruder broke in while Ms Gregoire and the children were asleep, and left a threatening note. Justin Trudeau was away at the time. After winning the 2015 election, he moved to Rideau Cottage.</p>

<p><strong>Foreign Policy Achievements</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau's government negotiated trade deals such as the Canada-United States-Mexico Agreement (CUSMA) and the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership. He also signed the Paris Agreement on climate change, demonstrating Canada's commitment to reducing greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau's government also signed the Paris Agreement on climate change in 2016.</p>

<p><strong>Election Wins</strong></p>

<p>Justin Trudeau led the Liberal Party to two consecutive minority government victories in Canada's federal elections. In the 2019 federal election, Mr Trudeau's Liberal Party won 157 seats but lost their previous majority, needing support from other parties to govern. The campaign centred on economic security and climate action, building on successes from his 2015 victory when he implemented tax cuts and child benefits.</p>

<p>In the 2021 federal election, Justin Trudeau once again led the Liberals to another minority government. This repeated outcome also stressed the need for ongoing coalition-building.</p>

<p><strong>Initiatives</strong></p>

<p>During the COVID-19 pandemic, Justin Trudeau's government responded with various measures, including an "assault-style" weapons ban in 2020, and launching a national $10-a-day childcare programme in 2021. More recently, Justin Trudeau launched a national school food programme and entered into a confidence and supply agreement with the New Democratic Party (NDP) on March 22, 2022. This agreement resulted in the Canadian Dental Care Plan and a framework for national pharmacare, both introduced in 2022.</p>

<p><strong>India-Canada Relations Under Trudeau's Regime</strong></p>

<p>India-Canada diplomatic tensions have escalated significantly under the Justin Trudeau government. The crisis began with the death of Hardeep Singh Nijjar, a Canadian citizen and Khalistani leader, in June 2023. Mr Trudeau's government claimed that agents of the Indian government were involved in the killing. India vehemently denies these claims.</p>

<p>The diplomatic fallout was swift, with Canada expelling six Indian diplomats and India responding in the same manner. India also withdrew its High Commissioner and other targeted officials from Canada. Justin Trudeau claimed that Indian agents were involved not only in Nijjar's killing but also in other violent activities in Canada. India rejected these claims, labelling them "preposterous" and criticising Mr Trudeau's government for "vote bank politics."</p>

<p><strong>Controversies</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Aga Khan row</strong>: In 2016, Justin Trudeau and his family took a vacation on the Aga Khan's private island in the Bahamas. The Aga Khan, a spiritual leader, also heads a development network that receives Canadian government funding. This raised concerns about conflict of interest and ethics. An investigation by the Conflict of Interest and Ethics Commissioner found Mr Trudeau in violation of four sections of the Conflict of Interest Act.</li>
	<li><strong>SNC-Lavalin issue</strong>: SNC-Lavalin, a Canadian engineering firm, faced corruption and fraud charges related to its Libyan business dealings. The company lobbied the government for intervention. Justin Trudeau and his office were accused of putting pressure on Justice Minister Jody Wilson-Raybould to grant SNC-Lavalin a deferred prosecution agreement. Mr Wilson-Raybould refused and was later shuffled out of her cabinet position.</li>
	<li><strong>Freedom Convoy</strong>: The Canada convoy protest, known as the Freedom Convoy, started in January 2022 against COVID-19 vaccine mandates for truckers. These truckers from across Canada gathered in Ottawa, expressing broader anti-government grievances against Prime Minister Justin Trudeau. As protests escalated, Mr Trudeau relocated for safety and called the demonstrations an "insult to the truth." On February 14, he invoked the Emergencies Act, which faced legal challenges. The declaration was revoked on February 23 after police intervention ended the protests.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6mhhs5m8_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau studied literature at McGill University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/gods-problem-now-us-mans-hilarious-obituary-for-his-father-goes-viral-6811324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["God's Problem Now": US Man's Hilarious Obituary For His Father Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/gods-problem-now-us-mans-hilarious-obituary-for-his-father-goes-viral-6811324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:55:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An obituary for a 74-year-old US man who died after falling and hitting his head has gone viral, with his son letting the public know that he is "God's problem now".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An obituary for a 74-year-old US man who died after falling and hitting his head has gone viral, with his son letting the public know that he is "God's problem now". Robert Boehm died on October 6 and his son, Charles Boehm, recalled the life of his father in the most unconventional and hilarious ways. He candidly told the public who his father really was. But he clarified that it was not out of disrespect. Instead, it was a more honest tribute to the man who raised him, and a chance for his small town of Clarendon, Texas, to laugh once more with the beloved fellow resident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Robert Adolph Boehm, in accordance with his lifelong dedication to his own personal brand of decorum, muttered his last unintelligible and likely unnecessary curse on October 6, 2024, shortly before tripping backward over 'some stupid mother****ing thing' and hitting his head on the floor," the obituary read, per Robertson Funeral Directors' Facebook post.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="539" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FRobertsonfuneraldirectors%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0yKNZQcQd26sD84KyQMHepcaBZkAXYbutCYVTq4DfmDUVTboUVddptsk6JjZTUiirl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>In the obituary, Mr Charles recapped his father's life from start to finish. He wrote that his father's 1950 birth "God immediately and thankfully broke the mold and attempted to cover up the evidence". He also joked that his Catholic father managed to get his mother pregnant three times in five years, allowing him to avoid getting drafted to fight in the Vietnam War. &nbsp;</p>

<p>"Raised Catholic, Robert managed to get his wife Dianne pregnant (three times) fast enough to just barely miss getting drafted into the Vietnam War by fathering Michelle, John, and Charlotte between 1967 and 1972. Much later, with Robert possibly concerned about the brewing conflict in Grenada, Charles was born in 1983," the obituary read.</p>

<p>"This lack of military service was probably for the best, as when taking up shooting as a hobby in his later years, he managed to blow not one, but two holes in the dash of his own car on two separate occasions, which unfortunately did not even startle, let alone surprise, his dear wife Dianne, who was much accustomed to such happenings in his presence and may have actually been safer in the jungles of Vietnam the entire time," it continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Charles also recalled that his father who worked as a "semi-professional truck driver" had a penchant for collecting antique weaponry, as well as harmonicas. The latter caused "his beloved dogs to howl continuously at odd hours of the night to entertain his many neighbours, and occasionally to give to his many, many, many grandchildren and great-grandchildren to play loudly during long road trips with their parents," the son lamented.</p>

<p>Mr Charles also noted that his mother and Robert's wife, Dianne, had passed away in February. The loss was jokingly framed as "God finally showed mercy upon" her so that she could get "the heck out of there for some well-earned peace and quiet," their son wrote.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/x-user-advising-people-to-invest-in-sips-instead-of-buying-car-sparks-debate-6804790">&nbsp;X User Advising People To Invest In SIPs Instead Of Buying Car Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>"Without Dianne to gleefully entertain, Robert shifted his creative focus to the entertainment of you, the fine townspeople of Clarendon, Texas. Over the last eight months, if you have not met Robert or seen his road show yet, you probably would have soon. We have all done our best to enjoy/weather Robert's antics up to this point, but he is God's problem now," the obituary concluded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This humour-filled obituary has gone viral on social media. Reacting to this, one user wrote, "Best obituary I've ever read! Thanks for your *almost* service Sir!" "His legacy is his children that understood him enough to write the best obituary EVER!" expressed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I truly wish more obituaries were written like this, telling the story of someone's life with making it truly a reflection of them," commented a third user. "I can only hope that mine is half as good. I felt like I both missed out on knowing him, and yet also knew him personally by how amazing this was written. What an honor! My condolences to the family," said one user.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pagpk1r_robert-adolph-boehm_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In the obituary, Mr Charles recapped his father's life from start to finish.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-mumbai-london-flight-gets-bomb-threat-an-hour-before-landing-6811272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Air India Mumbai-London Flight Gets Bomb Threat An Hour Before Landing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/air-india-mumbai-london-flight-gets-bomb-threat-an-hour-before-landing-6811272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:49:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Air India flight from Mumbai to London declared an emergency onboard after receiving a bomb threat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Air India flight from Mumbai to London declared an emergency onboard after receiving a bomb threat. Today, six Air India Express flights, five Air India, two Vistara and two IndiGo flights received bomb threats, adding to a list of threat calls airlines have received this week.</p>

<p>The aircraft was 'squawking 7700' - a code used by pilots of an aircraft to declare a general emergency. Online Flight tracking website, FlightRadar24, showed the Boeing 777, operated by Air India, taking off at 7:05 am (IST) from Mumbai circling over East England and declaring an emergency.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AI129?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AI129</a> from Mumbai to London is squawking 7700, indicating a general emergency. Reason currently unknown. <a href="https://t.co/vxipNBzfSO">https://t.co/vxipNBzfSO</a><br />
<br />
More info on 'squawking 7700' here. <a href="https://t.co/CRoOOMhDKB">https://t.co/CRoOOMhDKB</a> <a href="https://t.co/uadlHmvSEG">pic.twitter.com/uadlHmvSEG</a></p>
— Flightradar24 (@flightradar24) <a href="https://twitter.com/flightradar24/status/1846875391752855901?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The AI129 flight declared an emergency an hour before landing. It was scheduled to land at Heathrow Airport in London at 12:05 pm (UK time).</p>

<p>As per the latest information from FlightRadar24, the aircraft is no longer 'squawking 7700' and landed at Heathrow Airport. 'Squawking 7700' notifies the nearby Air Traffic Controllers of the situation onboard the aircraft.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/5-year-flight-ban-for-hoax-callers-say-sources-amid-bomb-threat-to-airlines-6803649">The pattern of airlines receiving bomb threats</a> continued for the fourth consecutive day, with at least 34 aircraft getting threats in four days.</p>

<p>Confirming the threats, an Air India official said, "Five Air India flights received security threats on social media today. Regulatory bodies have been informed and all laid-down procedures have been strictly followed. All five flights have landed safely. Air India is committed to the safety of its passengers and crew and accords it the highest priority."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/mumbai-news/2-mumbai-bound-international-flights-receive-bomb-threats-forced-to-land-6809729">A Mumbai-bound Vistara flight</a> with 147 persons on board was immediately taken to security checks on its arrival from Frankfurt following the Boeing 787 aircraft receiving a bomb threat, according to the airline.</p>

<p>"Vistara flight UK 028 operating from Frankfurt to Mumbai on 16 October 2024 was subject to a security threat received on social media. As per protocol, all relevant authorities were immediately informed. The aircraft safely landed at the Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj International Airport, Mumbai and was taken to the isolation bay where all customers were disembarked. We are fully cooperating with the security agencies to complete the mandatory security checks. At Vistara, the safety and security of our customers, crew and aircraft are of utmost importance to us," a Vistara spokesperson said.</p>

<p>At the same time, an IndiGo flight operating from Istanbul to Turkiye for Mumbai also received a bomb threat and was taken to an isolation bay here for the security agencies to carry out a comprehensive security check.</p>

<p>IndiGo in a statement said, "Flight 6E 18, operating from Istanbul to Mumbai, received a security-related alert. Upon landing, the aircraft was isolated, and all passengers were safely disembarked." The airline worked closely with the relevant authorities, and standard operating procedures were followed, it said.</p>

<p>IndiGo, however, did not share other details.</p>

<p><strong>Action Plan</strong></p>

<p>Sources told NDTV earlier that the Centre and civil authorities are working together to handle the crisis. The Home Ministry asked the Civil Aviation Ministry to send a detailed report on the incidents. Airlines have been asked by the aviation ministry to provide inputs on the bomb scare incidents, based on which, the Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) will prepare a report.</p>

<p>A Parliamentary Standing Committee met over the issue yesterday. This was preceded by a meeting called by Civil Aviation Minister Ram Mohan Naidu with the Civil Aviation Ministry and DGCA officials.</p>

<p>"<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/closely-monitoring-situation-of-bomb-threats-to-airlines-says-aviation-minister-6805334">We are closely monitoring</a> the situation and ensuring that We are committed to maintaining the highest security standards and passenger safety remains our topmost priority," Civil Aviation Minister K Rammohan Naidu said in a statement.</p>

<p>Sources said several steps will be taken to deal with such situations: Those who post bomb threats will be added to the 'Unruly Passengers' list. The airlines have suggested that they should be banned from flying for five years.</p>

<p>Sources said that airlines suggested that losses borne by them due to fake bomb threats should be recovered from the accused.</p>

<p>The names of those responsible for hoax calls will be shared with the airline and security agencies. The Civil Aviation Ministry is expected to share the guidelines soon. The ministry will also share a detailed report on the bomb scare investigation in two days.</p>

<p>The Ministry of Home Affairs has ordered the Central Industrial Security Force (CISF) to stay alert at the airports.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/f1pka8d8_air-india-boeing-777_625x300_27_January_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The AI129 flight declared an emergency an hour before landing.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-28-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-school-says-gaza-ministry-6811048]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[28 Killed After Israeli Strike Hits School, Says Gaza Ministry]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-28-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-school-says-gaza-ministry-6811048]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:21:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 19 Palestinians including children were killed on Thursday after an Israeli strike hit a school in Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip that is sheltering displaced people, a Gaza health ministry official told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 28 Palestinians including children were killed on Thursday in an Israeli strike on a shelter in the northern Gaza Strip, a Gaza health ministry official said, while Israel said the attack targeted tens of operators at the site.</p>

<p>Dozens were also injured in the strike, said the official, Medhat Abbas, adding: "There is no water to extinguish the fire. There is nothing. This is a massacre."</p>

<p>"Civilians and children are being killed, burned under fire," said Abbas.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement the strike targeted operators from Hamas and Islamic Jihad groups, who operated from within the Abu Hussein School in Jabalia that had been serving as a shelter for displaced people.</p>

<p>It said dozens of operators were present inside the compound when the strike took place, and provided the names of at least 12 of them, which Reuters could not immediately verify.</p>

<p>The military said it took precautions to mitigate harm to civilians and accused Hamas of using them as human shields - a practice Hamas denies.</p>

<p>Hamas said in a statement that allegations there were fighters at the school were "nothing but lies", adding this was "a systematic policy of the enemy to justify its crime."</p>

<p>The Hamas-run Gaza government media office put the number of dead at the school at 28. It said 160 people were wounded in the attack.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, Palestinian health officials said at least 11 Palestinians were killed in two separate Israeli strikes in Gaza City, while several others were killed in central and southern Gaza areas.</p>

<p>Footage circulated by Palestinian media of the Abu Hussein School and which Reuters couldn't immediately verify, showed smoke coming from tents that caught fire, as many displaced people evacuated casualties including children to ambulances.</p>

<p>Residents of Jabalia, in northern Gaza, said Israeli forces blew up clusters of houses firing from the air, from tanks and by placing bombs in buildings then detonating them remotely.</p>

<p>The area has been a focus for the Israeli military for the past two weeks, which says it is trying to stop Hamas fighters from regrouping for more attacks.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli forces had effectively isolated Beit Hanoun, Jabalia, and Beit Lahiya in the far north of the enclave from Gaza City, blocking movement except for those families heeding evacuation orders and leaving the three towns.</p>

<p>"We have written our death notes, and we are not leaving Jabalia," one resident told Reuters via a chat app.</p>

<p>"The occupation (Israel) is punishing us for not leaving our houses in the early days of the war, and we are not going now either. They are blowing up houses, and roads, and are starving us but we die once and we don't lose our pride," the father of four said, refusing to give his name, fearing Israeli reprisal.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said on Thursday that it seized many weapons in the area, some of which were stashed in a school, and that its forces have killed dozens of operators in airstrikes and combat at close quarters, as troops try to root out Hamas forces operating in the rubble.</p>

<p>Northern Gaza, which had been home to well over half the territory's 2.3 million people, was bombed to rubble in the first phase of Israel's assault on the territory a year ago, after the October 7 attacks on southern Israel by Hamas-led fighters, who killed 1,200 people and captured 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>More than 42,000 Palestinians have been killed in the Israel's offensive so far, according to Gaza's health authorities.</p>

<p>The United States has told Israel that it must take steps to improve the humanitarian situation in northern Gaza in 30 days or face potential restrictions on military aid.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu convened an emergency meeting on Wednesday to discuss expanding humanitarian aid to Gaza, officials said, with aid likely to increase soon.</p>

<p>ACCESS FOR AID</p>

<p>The UN has long complained of obstacles to getting aid into Gaza and distributing it throughout the war zone, blaming impediments on Israel and lawlessness. The UN said no food aid entered northern Gaza between October 2 and October 15.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the Israeli military unit that oversees aid and commercial shipments said 50 trucks entered northern Gaza.</p>

<p>Ismail Al-Thawabta, the director of the Hamas-run Gaza government media office, said Israeli comments about allowing aid into the enclave were misleading.</p>

<p>He said the Israeli military has maintained a comprehensive siege on the far north of Gaza for 170 consecutive days, closing all humanitarian access points. He said 342 people had been killed in the Israeli assault over the last 10 days.</p>

<p>Israel says that its evacuation orders have been issued to ensure people's safety and separate them from operators and denies they are part of a systematic clearance plan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ok538n0g_gaza_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dozens were also injured in the strike, said an official (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/cc1-man-named-in-us-indictment-in-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-case-no-longer-government-employee-india-6810995]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Named In Terrorist Pannun Case No Longer Government Employee: India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/cc1-man-named-in-us-indictment-in-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-case-no-longer-government-employee-india-6810995]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:15:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has confirmed the US' assertion that a person identified as 'CC1' in a US Department of Justice indictment on an alleged assassination plot of Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun is no longer employed by the Indian government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has confirmed the United States' assertion that a person identified as 'CC1' in a US Department of Justice indictment on an alleged assassination plot of Khalistani terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun is no longer employed by the Indian government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US State Department had said it had been informed about this by Indian officials who are members of an inquiry committee.</p>

<p>"We've received an update from them on the investigation that they have been conducting. It was a productive meeting. They did inform us that the individual who was named in the Justice Department indictment is no longer an employee of the Indian government... We are satisfied with the cooperation," State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters.</p>

<p>At a press conference on Thursday, Ministry of External Affairs Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal confirmed that the person named in the indictment is no longer an employee of the government of India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To a follow-up question on who the Indian official is and who are the people who have gone to the United States, Mr Jaiswal said, "I have confirmed that this gentleman is not part of the Government of India setup, he's not an employee, beyond that I don't have anything to share with you. Regarding the people who have gone to the United States, these are members of the high-level inquiry committee that had been set up in November 2023 to look into the inputs that were shared by the US."</p>

<p>"We have taken these inputs very seriously and we remain engaged with the US side on this matter. Two members of the high-level committee have travelled there and held meetings with the US side," he added.</p>

<p>In November last year, UK newspaper Financial Times had reported that the US had foiled a plot to kill Pannun, who heads the radical outfit, Sikhs for Justice, and holds dual citizenship of the US and Canada. Officials in the Joe Biden administration had later confirmed this.</p>

<p>Both the US and India have said that the allegations and the indictment will not affect the upward trajectory of the ties between the two countries. &nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/d10hkbbo_pannun3_625x300_18_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Ministry of External Affairs said that the inputs shared by the US have been taken very seriously.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-halts-key-commercial-food-imports-to-gaza-report-6810976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Halts Key Commercial Food Imports To Gaza: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-halts-key-commercial-food-imports-to-gaza-report-6810976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 17:11:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has stopped processing requests from traders to import food to Gaza, according to 12 people involved in the trade, choking off a track that for the past six months supplied more than half of the besieged Palestinian territory's provisions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has stopped processing requests from traders to import food to Gaza, according to 12 people involved in the trade, choking off a track that for the past six months supplied more than half of the besieged Palestinian territory's provisions.</p>

<p>Since October 11, Gaza-based traders who were importing food from Israel and the Israeli-occupied West Bank have lost access to a system introduced in spring by Cogat, the Israeli government body that oversees aid and commercial shipments, and have received no reply to attempts to contact the agency, the sources said.</p>

<p>The shift has driven the flow of goods arriving in Gaza to its lowest level since the start of the war, a Reuters analysis of official Israeli data shows. The details of the halt in commercial goods into Gaza have not been previously reported.</p>

<p>Cogat did not respond to Reuters' questions about commercial food imports and aid to Gaza. The agency says it does all it can to ensure that enough aid enters the coastal enclave, and that Israel does not prevent the entry of humanitarian aid. It rejects allegations Israel has blocked supplies.</p>

<p>Between October 1 and October 16, the overall flow of shipments to Gaza - including both aid and commercial goods - fell to a daily average of 29 trucks, according to Cogat statistics.</p>

<p>That compares with a daily average of 175 trucks between May and September, the data shows. Commercial shipments -- goods bought by local traders, trucked in after direct approval by Cogat, and then sold in marketplaces in Gaza -- accounted for about 55% of the total during that period.</p>

<p>Two sources involved in food supply said the reason for halting commercial shipments was because Israel worried that the Hamas operator group was receiving revenues from the imports.</p>

<p>A Hamas spokesperson denied that the group had stolen food or used it for revenue and said it was trying to ensure the distribution of aid in Gaza.</p>

<p>The commercial system's apparent closure came as Israel launched a new military operation against Hamas in northern Gaza, a parallel development that has obstructed humanitarian aid deliveries. The U.N.'s World Food Programme said in a statement on Sunday the operation cut off all aid deliveries through crossings in the north for at least two weeks this month.</p>

<p>Plummeting volumes of aid into Gaza have prompted the United States to threaten to withhold military support to Israel.</p>

<p>Following international criticism, Cogat said in statements this week that Israel had allowed scores of trucks of aid into Gaza, including dozens via crossings in the north. It did not provide full details or respond to Reuters' requests for information for this story.</p>

<p>A series of measures by Israeli government departments and the military were already reducing food deliveries to Gaza. In August, Israeli authorities introduced a new customs rule on one aid channel, and began scaling down the separate track of commercial goods.</p>

<p>Getting enough food to Gaza's 2.3 million people, almost all of whom have been displaced, has been one of the most fraught issues of the war. Aid agencies have renewed their warnings of widening malnutrition and the danger of famine.</p>

<p>James Elder, a spokesman for UN child agency UNICEF, said aid supply had improved earlier this year after warnings of famine prompted a push to open new supply routes and access points to Gaza.</p>

<p>"We've seen an absolute reversal of that," he told reporters this week. "We see now what is probably the worst restrictions we've seen on humanitarian aid" to Gaza during the war.</p>

<p>Before the war, some 500 trucks per day entered Gaza carrying a mix of aid and commercial imports, such as food, building materials and agricultural supplies.</p>

<p>Reuters spoke to five Gaza-based importers, two businessmen sending goods from the West Bank, a Gaza-based business official and three people involved in aid delivery.</p>

<p>"The situation is getting desperate," said Ibrahim Baraka, a resident of southern Gaza. "We have some non-perishable aid but there's virtually no fresh produce anymore. A kilo of onions is $15 in southern Gaza."</p>

<p>His account was corroborated by five other residents, seven traders and five humanitarian workers.</p>

<p><strong>COMMERCIAL IMPORTS DOWN TO A TRICKLE</strong></p>

<p>Israel largely blocked commercial imports at the beginning of the war, but allowed them to resume from Israeli-controlled territory in May, in a move first reported by Reuters. Gaza-based businessmen could submit import requests to Cogat and have food delivered via the main goods crossing in southern Gaza.</p>

<p>The arrival of commercial goods augmented the supply of fresh, nutritious products not contained in aid shipments, UN officials and residents said.</p>

<p>After Israel invaded the southern town of Rafah in May, hampering the main UN aid route, the commercial one grew to account for a significant proportion of food supplies.</p>

<p>Cogat lists these private sector goods as making up some 98 of the 175 daily trucks that entered Gaza on average from May to September.</p>

<p>But this route was fraught with problems from early on, according to eight Palestinian businessmen who spoke to Reuters.</p>

<p>Convoys carrying goods are often looted by armed gangs or desperate Gazans, according to all those interviewed for this story. Importers hiked prices to pay for high transport costs and protection for their shipments.</p>

<p>As a result, commercially imported goods were too expensive for many Gazans, the businessmen said.</p>

<p>A group of around 20 traders was given priority, the businessmen and the three aid sources said; their import requests were approved ahead of others'.</p>

<p>Some of those priority traders resold their import permission to smaller businesses, charging them thousands of dollars to get trucks in, a dozen sources in the Gaza and West Bank business communities, as well as international aid groups, told Reuters.</p>

<p>Cogat also changed the method for submitting requests several times, the traders said - switching from an online form to a WhatsApp number, and back to an online form, but one that required a password that only the trusted traders knew.</p>

<p>A new rule introduced in September required traders to show bank records proving their business had a turnover of at least 15 million shekels ($4 million) per year, according to a message sent by Cogat to traders, seen by Reuters.</p>

<p>All the traders said the latest online form had stopped working for any importers. They said messages sent to up to five different Cogat WhatsApp numbers had gone unanswered.</p>

<p>Cogat did not respond to questions about these issues.</p>

<p>Data from the agency shows the private sector trucks getting through have slowed to a trickle. On October 1, 54 trucks of "private sector" deliveries were sent, the last significant shipment of commercial goods. Between October 8-10 another 17 were recorded, bringing October's average to 5 trucks a day.</p>

<p><strong>ISRAEL-UN COMPROMISE</strong></p>

<p>During the war, aid to Gaza has been delivered via several different routes that came in and out of use, according to UN and Israeli officials.</p>

<p>The main source of food for Gazans who cannot afford to buy from local markets remains international humanitarian aid organized by the UN, which is subject to security approval by Cogat for each consignment.</p>

<p>Before the war, the chief route was into southern Gaza via Egypt, after a detour for Israeli scans.</p>

<p>After Israel's military assault on Rafah in May, UN aid deliveries on that route have slumped because insecurity made them increasingly difficult to organize, UN relief agencies have said.</p>

<p>The UN then relied heavily on a route bringing supplies via Jordan through Israel to a crossing at Gaza's northern tip. But shipments halted after Israel introduced a customs rule on some of the aid, a move reported by Reuters this month.</p>

<p>Israel and the UN have reached a compromise on the main sticking point of that new rule, according to two people with knowledge of the matter.</p>

<p>But deliveries from Jordan remain lower after renewed fighting in the north of Gaza, interviews with five people involved in getting aid into Gaza and Cogat data show.</p>

<p>According to Cogat's online database, an average of two trucks per day carried aid from Jordan to Gaza over the first two weeks of October, down from around 18 a day in previous months.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2qpp57k_gaza_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel largely blocked commercial imports at the beginning of the war. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-100-of-gaza-now-lives-in-poverty-un-sounds-alarm-over-unemployment-6810647]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nearly 100% Of Gaza Now Lives In Poverty, UN Sounds Alarm Over Unemployment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nearly-100-of-gaza-now-lives-in-poverty-un-sounds-alarm-over-unemployment-6810647]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:35:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than a year into Israel's war against Hamas, "nearly 100 per cent" of Gaza's population has been plunged into poverty with a ruined economy and "staggering" unemployment, the UN said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than a year into Israel's war against Hamas, "nearly 100 per cent" of Gaza's population has been plunged into poverty with a ruined economy and "staggering" unemployment, the UN said today.</p>

<p>In the occupied West Bank, where violence has also surged since Hamas's October-7 attack last year that sparked the war in Gaza, the situation "has been equally concerning", the UN's International Labour Organisation said.</p>

<p>"The impact of the war in the Gaza Strip has taken a toll far beyond loss of life, desperate humanitarian conditions and physical destruction," Ruba Jaradat, ILO's regional director for Arab States, said in a statement.</p>

<p>"It has fundamentally altered the socioeconomic landscape of Gaza," she warned. "The impact will be felt for generations to come."</p>

<p>In the Gaza Strip, "nearly 100 percent of the population now lives in poverty", ILO said.</p>

<p>It warned that "the significant economic contraction in the West Bank is estimated to have more than doubled the short-term poverty rate, rising from 12 percent in 2023 to 28 percent by mid-2024".</p>

<p>Unemployment in the West Bank surged to nearly 35 percent since last October, "while in Gaza it averaged a staggering 79.7 percent", ILO said.</p>

<p>The agency said the wider economic toll had also been "unprecedented" across the occupied Palestinian territories.</p>

<p>The West Bank saw gross domestic product contract by 21.7 percent year-on-year, while GDP in the Gaza Strip nosedived 84.7 percent, it said.</p>

<p>Israel launched its military campaign in Gaza after lasy year's October attack by Hamas, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of official Israeli figures, including hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliation has killed at least 42,409 people, the majority civilians, according to figures from the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>These figures also "reflect the shutdown of most economic activities in Gaza due to the destruction of homes and infrastructure, and the recurring displacement of workers and employers", ILO said.</p>

<p>"This has led either to complete termination of work or to a predominance of informal and irregular work."</p>

<h2><strong>SOARING PRICES</strong></h2>

<p>ILO said Gazans were also grappling with soaring prices, with year-on-year inflation reaching a whopping 248 percent in August.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the United Nations again warned of the risk of a full-blown famine in the besieged territory.</p>

<p>The situation is also increasingly dire in the West Bank.</p>

<p>"Israeli barriers to movement of persons and goods, coupled with broader trade restrictions and supply chain disruptions, have severely impacted the economy", ILO said.</p>

<p>"The closure of the Israeli labour market to Palestinian workers has further strained livelihoods," it added.</p>

<p>Israeli troops or settlers have killed more than 738 Palestinians there in the past year, according to the Ramallah-based health ministry.</p>

<p>At least 24 Israelis, civilians or members of the security forces, have meanwhile been killed in attacks carried out by Palestinian militants or in Israeli military operations in the West Bank over the same period, Israeli officials say.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0nl0v2vo_gaza-war-afp_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[United Nations says there is 'staggering' unemployment in Gaza a year after war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-canada-to-extradite-bishnoi-gang-members-india-on-diplomatic-row-6810487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wanted Canada To Extradite Bishnoi Gang Members": India On Diplomatic Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-canada-to-extradite-bishnoi-gang-members-india-on-diplomatic-row-6810487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:17:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the backdrop of ongoing diplomatic tensions between India and Canada, India has raised concerns over Canada's handling of criminals linked to organised crime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the backdrop of ongoing diplomatic tensions between <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798">India and Canada</a>, India has raised concerns over Canada's handling of criminals linked to organised crime. Ministry of External Affairs spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal today alleged Canada's reluctance to extradite individuals associated with the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, a notorious criminal organisation based in India, involved in crimes in Canada.</p>

<p>"We find it really strange that people we asked to be deported, Canada cops are now claiming that these people are committing crimes in Canada, for which India is being blamed," Mr Jaiswal stated.&nbsp;On India's extradition requests, Mr Jaiswal said "26 are pending for a decade or more. Several probational requests are pending too."</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-justin-trudeau-admits-canada-has-only-intel-no-evidence-in-nijjar-killing-6807798">Justin Trudeau's Big Admission Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Showdown</a></p>

<p>Since September 2023, diplomatic ties between India and Canada have worsened, largely triggered by the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar in Canada. Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau publicly accused India of being involved in the killing, a claim which India has categorically rejected. Mr Jaiswal reaffirmed India's position during a recent press briefing, stating that despite multiple allegations from Canada, there remains "no shred of evidence" linking the Indian government to Nijjar's murder.</p>

<p>"We have made our position very clear through various press releases. Since September 2023, there has been no evidence provided, and just last night, we issued another press release reiterating our stance," Mr Jaiswal said. "So far Canada has not given any evidence to back their allegations. &nbsp;Their allegations are politically motivated. &nbsp;Clear pattern to smear India for reasons best known to them."</p>

<p>In addition to rejecting the accusations, India recently withdrew its diplomats from Canada, citing safety concerns, after which Canada expelled several Indian officials, further straining the relationship.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-pak-match-soon-cricket-comes-up-in-s-jaishankars-islamabad-visit-6809377">"Inaccurate Reports": Centre On Cricket Coming Up In S Jaishankar's Pakistan Visit</a></p>

<p>"We value our strong trade ties with Canada and our people-to-people links, especially given the large number of Indian students in Canada. But the current situation has been precipitated entirely by the Trudeau government," Mr Jaiswal explained, adding that Canada benefits from these relations, and India has shown restraint despite the provocative steps taken by Ottawa.</p>

<h3><strong>Ex-Raw Officer 'No Longer Employed'</strong></h3>

<p>On a related note, the United States Department of Justice (DOJ) today named a former Research and Analysis Wing (RAW) officer, referred to as 'CC1,' in its indictment over a failed plot to assassinate another Khalistani terrorist, Gurpatwant Singh Pannun. The United States confirmed that this individual is "no longer employed by the Indian government."</p>

<p>Mr Jaiswal today corroborated the US claim by confirming that the individual is no longer an Indian government employee.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-we-had-said-no-evidence-whatsoever-india-on-justin-trudeaus-deposition-6806506">"As We Had Said, No Evidence Whatsoever": India On Justin Trudeau's Deposition</a></p>

<p>US State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller, during a press briefing, confirmed that both India and the US are conducting separate but coordinated investigations into the plot. Miller said that a "productive meeting" had taken place between the Indian inquiry committee and US officials.</p>

<h3><strong>Justin Trudeau's Admission&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In a startling admission during a public inquiry, Prime Minister Trudeau admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Nijjar last year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking during a public inquiry into alleged foreign interference in Canada's federal electoral processes and democratic institutions, Mr Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence rather than conclusive evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>

<p>Nijjar, a designated terrorist by India's National Investigation Agency in 2020, was shot dead outside a gurdwara in Surrey, British Columbia, in June 2023. The Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP) later stated that six Indian diplomats were allegedly part of a plot to murder Nijjar. The Canadian Police also suggested that the Bishnoi gang was connected to Indian government agents.</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau explained that Canada had the option to go public with the allegations during the G20 summit held in New Delhi in September 2023 but chose not to.</p>

<p>"Our response was, well, it's within your security agencies," Mr Trudeau said, recounting Canada's exchanges with India. "At that point, it was primarily intelligence, not hard evidentiary proof. So we said, let's work together and look into your security services."</p>

<p>Mr Trudeau added that he confronted Prime Minister Narendra Modi during the G20 summit, claiming that Canada was aware of India's alleged involvement. According to Mr Trudeau, PM Modi's response was to express concern about individuals in Canada critical of the Indian government, requesting that they be arrested.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e1e9ifjo_trudeau-bishnoi_650x400_15_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In addition to rejecting the accusations, India recently withdrew its diplomats from Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fires-24-employees-for-misusing-25-meal-credits-on-toothpaste-detergent-6810327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Fires Employees For Using $25 Meal Credits On Toothpaste, Detergent]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fires-24-employees-for-misusing-25-meal-credits-on-toothpaste-detergent-6810327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 16:00:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The misuse of these benefits, which included sending meals home when employees weren't in the office, resulted in a formal HR investigation and subsequent firings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms, Inc, an American multinational technology conglomerate that owns and operates Facebook, Instagram, Threads, and WhatsApp, reportedly fired 24 employees at its Los Angeles offices for using their $25 meal credits to purchase items such as toothpaste, laundry detergent, and wine glasses, according to <em>The Guardian.</em></p>

<p>The company, which employs over 70,000 people, fired employees last week after an inquiry showed that they were misusing the system, including sending meals home when they were not in the office, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2024/oct/17/meta-fires-staff-free-meal-vouchers-buy-household-goods"><em>the news site.</em></a> One unnamed worker on a $400,000 (308,070 pounds) salary claimed to have spent their meal credits on household goods and groceries like toothpaste and tea.</p>

<p>"On days where I would not be eating at the office, like if my husband was cooking or if I was grabbing dinner with friends, I figured I ought not to waste the dinner credit," the employee wrote on Blind, an anonymous messaging platform.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ft.com/content/7d1a2738-2518-4ddb-811b-8abf9a745590"><em>Financial Times,</em></a> which first reported the story, the worker admitted the breach when approached as part of a human resources investigation into the practice and was later fired. "It was almost surreal that this was happening," the person wrote.</p>

<p>Free food has always been one of the benefits of working for a huge IT company. Meta is placed 91st on <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/companies/meta-platforms/?list=powerful-brands">Forbes</a>' list of the world's greatest employers (2024).</p>

<p>The company was founded by Mark Elliot Zuckerberg, Dustin Moskovitz, Chris R Hughes, Andrew McCollum, and Eduardo P. Saverin on February 4, 2004 and is headquartered in Menlo Park, CA.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c99ca29o_meta-generic_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta employees allegedly spent their $25 credits on non-food items.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-makes-it-illegal-to-seek-surrogacy-abroad-6810138]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Italy Makes It Illegal To Seek Surrogacy Abroad]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italy-makes-it-illegal-to-seek-surrogacy-abroad-6810138]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:34:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Italy's parliament made it illegal on Wednesday for couples to go abroad to have a baby via surrogacy -- a pet project of Prime Minister's Giorgia Meloni party which activists say is meant to target same-sex partners.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Italy's parliament made it illegal on Wednesday for couples to go abroad to have a baby via surrogacy -- a pet project of Prime Minister's Giorgia Meloni party which activists say is meant to target same-sex partners.</p>

<p>Since taking office in 2022 Meloni has pursued a highly conservative social agenda, looking to promote what she sees as traditional family values, making it progressively harder for LGBTQ couples to become legal parents.</p>

<p>The upper house Senate voted into law a bill proposed by Meloni's Brothers of Italy party by 84 votes to 58. The bill was already approved by the lower house last year.</p>

<p>The legislation extends a surrogacy ban already in place in Italy since 2004 to those who go to countries such as the United States or Canada, where it is legal, imposing jail terms of up to two years and fines of up to 1 million euros ($1.09 million).</p>

<p>"Motherhood is absolutely unique, it absolutely cannot be surrogated, and it is the foundation of our civilisation," Brothers of Italy senator Lavinia Mennuni said during the parliamentary debate.</p>

<p>"We want to uproot the phenomenon of surrogacy tourism."</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Meloni called surrogacy an 'inhuman' practice that treated children as supermarket products, echoing a position expressed by the Catholic Church.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, demonstrators gathered near the Senate voicing their outrage at the bill, saying the government was lashing out at LGBTQ people and damaging those who wanted to have children despite the fact Italy has a sharply declining birth rate.</p>

<p>"If someone has a baby, they should be given a medal. Here instead you are sent to jail... if you don't have children in the traditional way," Franco Grillini, a long-time activist for LGBTQ rights in Italy, told Reuters at the demonstration.</p>

<p>Rainbow Families President Alessia Crocini said 90% of Italians who choose surrogacy are heterosexual couples but they mostly do so in secret, meaning the new ban would de facto affect only gay couples who cannot hide it.</p>

<p>The clampdown on surrogacy comes against the backdrop of falling birthrates, with national statistics institute ISTAT saying in March that births had dropped to a record low in 2023 -- the 15th consecutive annual decline.</p>

<p>"This is a monstrous law. No country in the world has such a thing," said Grillini, referring to the government's move to prevent Italians from taking advantage of practices that are perfectly legal in some countries.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rgjlpjm8_italy-surrogacy-ban-protests_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The legislation extends a surrogacy ban already in place in Italy since 2004]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-door-spotted-in-antarctica-sparks-theories-what-scientists-say-6810088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Massive Door" Spotted In Antarctica Sparks Theories. What Scientists Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-door-spotted-in-antarctica-sparks-theories-what-scientists-say-6810088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 17 Oct 2024 15:31:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eagle-eyed users on Reddit first spotted the mysterious structure on Google Maps at the coordinates 69°00’50″S 39°36’22″E.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An unusual ice formation near Japan's Showa Station in East Antarctica has sparked wild theories across the internet. This rectangular shape, resembling a massive doorway, has led some to speculate about its origins, with suggestions ranging from a secret Nazi base to Bigfoot's vacation home.</p>

<p>Eagle-eyed users on Reddit first spotted the mysterious structure on Google Maps at the coordinates 69°00'50″S 39°36'22″E. One user asked, “Massive door in Antarctica?” Another suggested, “Just a blown-off Boeing door,” referencing a recent midair incident, while yet another joked, “Wonder if they get door dash there.”</p>

<blockquote class="reddit-embed-bq" data-embed-height="740" style="height:500px"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/conspiracy/comments/1bjxevc/massive_door_in_antarctica_32024/">Massive door in Antarctica? 3/20/24</a><br />
by<a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/realg00n/">u/realg00n</a> in<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/conspiracy/">conspiracy</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="https://embed.reddit.com/widgets.js" charset="UTF-8"></script>

<p>Scientists have since weighed in with a more grounded explanation. Bethan Davies, a professor of glaciology at the University of Newcastle, examined the coordinates using Google Earth Pro and historical imagery. She clarified, “This is an iceberg that became grounded and is now stuck and melting out [in place]. You can see many other icebergs in the area,” as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/15/science/mysterious-doorway-discovered-in-antarctic-ice-via-google-maps-and-conspiracy-theorists-have-wild-ideas/">NY Post</a>.</p>

<p>Adding to this, Professor Martin Siegert, co-director of the Imperial College London's Grantham Institute on Climate Change and the Environment, said, “This is simply ice flow around a solid subglacial obstacle, influenced also by melting and refreezing of ice and by katabatic winds.” He emphasised that the ice in the region is quite thin, allowing for a strong influence of the bedrock on ice flow.</p>

<p>Glaciologist Richard Smellie pointed out that the formation likely resulted from a rocky ridge being exposed due to a lowering of the ice, contributing to the “doorway” appearance. He noted, “There are two prominent parallel snow tails forming the sides of the ‘doorway,'” indicating the predominant wind direction.</p>

<p>Mr Smellie added that with a good imagination, there is a weak and totally false door-like appearance overall. "I am pretty sure it's just a natural phenomenon and nothing to get excited about."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vji48rcg_mysterious-antarctica-door_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to experts, this is just a "natural phenomenon"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>