<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 14:39:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-33-pleads-guilty-to-killing-10-year-old-daughter-in-uk-6459156]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian, 33, Pleads Guilty To Killing 10-Year-Old Daughter In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-33-pleads-guilty-to-killing-10-year-old-daughter-in-uk-6459156]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 14:39:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Indian-origin woman in the UK has pleaded guilty to murdering her 10-year-old daughter who was found dead with stab wounds earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-origin woman in the UK has pleaded guilty to murdering her 10-year-old daughter who was found dead with stab wounds earlier this year. Jaskirat Kaur, 33, pleaded guilty to the manslaughter of her daughter at the Wolverhampton Crown Court today.</p>

<p>10-year-old Shay Kang was found dead at home on March 4 with stab wounds in her chest.</p>

<p>Jaskirat Kaur, also known as Jasmine Kang, was arrested by West Midlands Police shortly after the body was discovered at approximately 12.10 pm. At the time of her arrest, Kaur denied the murder charge.</p>

<p>Kaur though admitted to the lesser charge of manslaughter during the court session. Judge Michael Chambers has set her sentencing on that charge for October 25, when she is expected to attend the court in person.</p>

<p>Prosecution counsel Sally Howes KC informed the court that the guilty plea to manslaughter was acceptable to the Crown, and there was no dispute over the facts of the case.</p>

<p>Brickhouse Primary School, where Shay was a pupil, issued a statement at the time to say the school was deeply saddened by the tragic death.</p>

<p>“Shay was a bright, happy, fun-loving child who was well-liked by all, and she will be very sadly missed by everyone,” read the statement.</p>

<p>Tributes including toys, cards, and balloons poured in and some parents of children who attended the same school had set up an online GoFundMe fundraiser to collect money for Shay's funeral.</p>

<p>The fundraiser read: "As you may be aware she had no family except her mum. The purpose of this is to come together as a community to help raise funds for her funeral and to also help with flowers, head stone etc. She didn't deserve this at all and the best we can do is make sure she flys (sic) high in the most beautiful way."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hpe1mjdk_shay-kang_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[10-year-old Shay Kang was found dead at home on March 4 with stab wounds.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greek-port-city-declares-state-of-emergency-over-flood-of-dead-fish-6459124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Greek Port City Declares State Of Emergency Over Flood Of Dead Fish]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/greek-port-city-declares-state-of-emergency-over-flood-of-dead-fish-6459124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 14:30:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The port city of Volos in central Greece declared a state emergency following an inundation of dead fish that local residents say could threaten their livelihoods, the state news agency announced Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The port city of Volos in central Greece declared a state emergency following an inundation of dead fish that local residents say could threaten their livelihoods, the state news agency announced Saturday.</p>

<p>The month-long emergency declaration issued by the climate ministry's secretary general of civil protection, Vassilis Papageorgiou, will inject funding and resources to speed up the cleaning of the Pagasetic Gulf port where tons of dead fish have piled up along the coast and in rivers, according to Athens News Agency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It is the second environmental catastrophe to hit the port of Volos, a three-and-a-half-hour drive north of Athens after catastrophic floods hit the Thessaly region last year.</p>

<p>Those floods refilled a nearby lake that had been drained in 1962 in a bid to fight malaria, swelling it to three times its normal size.</p>

<p>"After the storms, Daniel and Elias last autumn, around 20,000 hectares (50,000 acres) of plains in Thessaly were flooded, and various freshwater fish were carried by rivers" to the sea, Dimitris Klaudatos, a professor of agriculture and environment at the University of Thessaly had said.</p>

<p>Since then the lake waters have receded drastically, forcing the freshwater fish toward the Volos port that empties into the Pagasetic Gulf and the Aegean Sea, where they cannot survive.</p>

<p>On Tuesday alone, authorities had removed 57 tons of the dead fish washed up on beaches near Volos.</p>

<p>Most of the thousands of dead fish that flooded the Pagasetic have been recovered, while two boats are completing the process Saturday, Ertnews channel reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Special nets have been placed at the mouth of the Xiria River to contain the large volume of dead fish.</p>

<p>Tourist traffic to the area has already plunged by nearly 80 per cent since last year's flooding, according to the local association of restaurants and bars.</p>

<p>"The situation with this dead fish will be the death of us," said Stefanos Stefanou, the president of the association earlier this week. "What visitor will come to our city after this?"</p>

<p>The environmental crisis has prompted an investigation by the public prosecutor.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mo525om8_dead-fish-flood-greece-_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities removed 57 tons of the dead fish that have washed up on beaches near Volos on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-alexandre-de-moraes-the-judge-who-blocked-elon-musks-x-in-brazil-6458807]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Alexandre de Moraes, The Judge Who Blocked Elon Musk's X In Brazil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-alexandre-de-moraes-the-judge-who-blocked-elon-musks-x-in-brazil-6458807]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 13:32:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With his stern gaze and shiny-bald head, Supreme Court judge Alexandre de Moraes has emerged as one of the most powerful and polarizing people in Brazil by probing far-right ex-president Jair Bolsonaro's alleged attacks on democracy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With his stern gaze and shiny-bald head, Supreme Court judge Alexandre de Moraes has emerged as one of the most powerful and polarizing people in Brazil by probing far-right ex-president Jair Bolsonaro's alleged attacks on democracy.</p>

<p>The latest target in his disinformation crackdown: Elon Musk.</p>

<p>The billionaire X owner, who calls himself a "free-speech absolutist," in recent months went on the attack against Moraes, labelling him a dictator and threatening to defy the judge's rulings blocking users found to be spreading disinformation -- largely Bolsonaro supporters.</p>

<p>Moraes on Friday ordered the suspension of X, formerly known as Twitter, following a months-long standoff with the tech titan over disinformation in South America's largest nation.</p>

<p>Musk, who also owns Tesla and SpaceX, reacted with fury to the judge's order, branding Moraes an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>Known by his nickname, "Xandao," Moraes, 55, looms large over the fissures of a deeply divided Brazil.</p>

<p>The immensely powerful judge, who also heads the Superior Electoral Tribunal (TSE), is hated by the far right, which accuses him of censorship and abuse of office.</p>

<p>To others, he is a hero using the bench to save Brazil's young democracy.</p>

<h3><strong>'Political animal'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>There was little in Moraes's background to hint he would become a conservative nemesis.</p>

<p>The constitutional law expert worked as a Sao Paulo state prosecutor, then went on to become state security secretary. Known as a hardliner, he drew criticism from left-wing activists, who accused him of repressing social movements.</p>

<p>He served as justice minister under centre-right ex-president Michel Temer, who named him to the Supreme Court in 2017.</p>

<p>"Legal expertise has played a part in his meteoric rise, but what put him on the Supreme Court, and 99 per cent of his career, is politics. He's a political animal," constitutional law expert Antonio Carlos de Freitas told AFP.</p>

<p>Despite his severe demeanour, Moraes is known for a sense of humour behind the scenes.</p>

<p>Supreme Court insiders call him a pragmatist with a gift for engaging in dialogue with various players, including the military.</p>

<p>But he soon found himself on a collision course with Bolsonaro.</p>

<p>During Bolsonaro's administration (2019-2022), Moraes ordered investigations of several of the president's allies. Bolsonaro called him "scum" and vowed to stop following his rulings.</p>

<p>Moraes has presided over a slew of cases targeting the politician dubbed the "Tropical Trump," who has been barred from running for office until 2030 over his attempts to discredit the electoral system -- a decision delivered by the TSE, the electoral court Moraes heads.</p>

<p>Moraes's current docket includes what may be the most damaging case against Bolsonaro: the investigation into charges the ex-president and his inner circle plotted a coup to stay in power despite losing the 2022 elections to veteran leftist Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva.</p>

<p>"Bolsonaro's camp has found a favorite enemy in Moraes, who has dealt them their biggest defeats at the Supreme Court and blocked the spread of fake news," Freitas said.</p>

<p>Police investigating Bolsonaro's alleged coup plot say it included a presidential decree that would have declared a state of emergency, called new elections and ordered Moraes's arrest.</p>

<h3><strong>Disinformation war&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Moraes was an omnipresent figure during the polarizing 2022 campaign, aggressively using his rulings to fight election disinformation on social media.</p>

<p>That included blocking some prominent right-wing figures' accounts, leading to his standoff with Musk, who has been accused of turning his social media platform into a megaphone for right-wing conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>Moraes gives few interviews, and rarely posts on his own X account, "@Alexandre," where he nevertheless has a million followers.</p>

<p>"Freedom of expression doesn't mean freedom of aggression," he has said.</p>

<p>"It doesn't mean the freedom to defend tyranny."</p>

<p>Still two decades away from the mandatory retirement age for judges in Brazil -- 75 -- Moraes has political ambitions, including being president someday, a source close to him told AFP.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Musk will want to watch out if he challenges Moraes to a cage fight, as he did with fellow tech titan Mark Zuckerberg -- and as some internet wags have been hoping: Moraes has studied "muay thai," the martial art known as Thai boxing.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s5ibj3ao_elon-musk-brazil_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk reacted with fury to the order, branding Alexandre de Moraes an evil dictator.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-us-issues-new-guidelines-for-international-stem-students-6458666]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: New US Guidelines For International STEM Students]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-us-issues-new-guidelines-for-international-stem-students-6458666]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 13:08:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) has announced the updated policy guidelines for international students' eligibility for Optional Practical Training (OPT) in the Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) fields.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) has announced the updated policy guidelines for international students' eligibility for Optional Practical Training (OPT) in the Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) fields.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The revised guidelines, effective from August 27, offer clarity on rules concerning online study, school transfers, grace periods, and study abroad programmes. These will apply to all pending and future requests.</p>

<h3><strong>OPT duration extended for STEM students</strong></h3>

<p>As per USCIS, international students in STEM will now enjoy up to three years of OPT, compared to one year for the students of non-STEM fields. This will allow students to gain more work experience in the country.</p>

<h3><strong>Online Study Allowances</strong></h3>

<p>Eligible students will now be able to count one class or up to three credits per academic session towards their full course of study, without violating the F1 visa terms. It must be noted that the class is taken online or via distance learning, meaning that it does not require any physical attendance.</p>

<h3><strong>School Transfers</strong></h3>

<p>The new policy now grants permission to eligible students to transfer between Student and Exchange Visitor Program (SEVP) schools, certified by the US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), at the same educational level or even a switch between different educational levels.</p>

<h3><strong>Post-Completion OPT&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The new guidelines mention that students who have completed their associate, bachelor's, master's, or doctoral degree programmes are now eligible for the post-completion OPT.</p>

<h3><strong>OPT extensions</strong></h3>

<p>Students will now be able to apply for STEM OPT extension up to 90 days before the expiry of their current employment authorisation.</p>

<p>To be eligible for the 24-month STEM OPT extension, they will require a valid post-completion OPT period; a qualifying STEM degree from an accredited institution; and work with an employer enrolled in E-Verify.</p>

<h3><strong>60-Day Grace Period</strong></h3>

<p>Once they complete their OPT, students will have a 60-day grace period. During this time, they remain eligible to change their educational level, consider transferring to another SEVP-certified school, or apply for changing to a different nonimmigrant or immigrant status.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During this period, the employers can also sponsor the student's H-1B visa.</p>

<h3><strong>Clarification on the application period</strong></h3>

<p>The revised manual corrects the timeline during which the students can apply for the STEM OPT extensions, besides other technical adjustments. This ensures that the students can submit their applications.</p>

<h3><strong>Guidelines for the Study Abroad Programme</strong></h3>

<p>Students, who are enrolled in SEVP-certified schools, will be able to maintain active status in the Student and Exchange Visitor Information System (SEVIS) during the study abroad programmes if its duration is less than five months. For longer programmes, they will require a new Form I-20.</p>

<p>Students, who receive a STEM OPT extension, will be required to report any changes in their legal name, address, or employment details to the DSO within 10 days. Even in case there are no changes, still they will have to confirm their information every six months.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-01/h1b_650x400_61515001868.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Eligible students will now be able to count 1 class per academic session without violating F1 visa terms]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-york-based-real-estate-mogul-died-with-34-million-in-debt-had-just-8-000-in-bank-6458440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Millionaire, Who Died By Suicide, Owed $34 Million With $8,000 In Bank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-new-york-based-real-estate-mogul-died-with-34-million-in-debt-had-just-8-000-in-bank-6458440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:27:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On his wife's now-defunct lifestyle blog 'Mama + Tata,' Brandon Miller often showcased a fairy-tale lifestyle, portraying himself as a lucky head of an idyllic upper-crust family.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A high-profile New York real estate developer, who died by suicide last month, was almost $34 million in debt and had just $8,000 in his bank account. Despite being in secret debt, Brandon Miller and his influencer wife, Candace, were known for flaunting his high-profile lifestyle on social media.<br />
<br />
A report in The Real Deal highlighted that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/us-real-estate-mogul-dies-suddenly-aged-43-6067767">Brandon Miller</a>, 43, was in more dire financial straits than was initially thought at the time of his death on July 3.<br />
<br />
On his wife's now-defunct lifestyle blog 'Mama + Tata,' Miller often showcased a fairy-tale lifestyle, portraying himself as a lucky head of an idyllic upper-crust family, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/30/us-news/hamptons-real-estate-mogul-brandon-miller-died-34m-in-debt-with-just-8k-in-the-bank-report/">The New York Post</a> reported.<br />
<br />
However, new facts reveal the family was living way beyond their means in reality and was in massive debt.<br />
<br />
According to a bond petition filed by Candice in a surrogate's court, around $11.5 million of Miller's debt was from mortgages on his Hamptons estate.<br />
<br />
The property at 25 Cobb Isle Road in the Water Mill was put on the market at an asking price of $15.5 million earlier this month.<br />
<br />
The family had four outstanding loans on the property. This includes $800,000 from lender Titan Capital, who earlier sued Candice Miller over missed mortgage payments. Besides this, he owed the company another $2 million on the property, besides having loans from UBS and Stevens Financial Group, The Real Deal reported.<br />
<br />
The real estate developer's largest outstanding debt was an unsecured $11.3 million loan from a Chicago-based bank. He owned an additional $6.1 million on an unsecured loan from Donald Jaffe.<br />
<br />
Jaffe funded Miller as well as his father, Michael Miller, on multiple projects. In 2019, he sued Brandon Miller over the unpaid balance on the loan and has yet to receive his money.<br />
<br />
That's not all. Miller even had unpaid debts of more than $300,000 to American Express and $266,000 to the Funding Club, a cash advance lender based in Brooklyn.<br />
<br />
A few weeks ago, he was found unresponsive in his car inside the garage of his 4,300-square-foot Hamptons home. Soon, he was taken to the Stony Brook Southampton Hospital, where he passed away a few days later.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dod1c2vg_brandon-miller-_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brandon Miller was found unresponsive in his car last month]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-faces-rising-risk-of-waterborne-diseases-as-floods-recede-6458367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Faces Rising Risk Of Waterborne Diseases As Floods Recede]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-faces-rising-risk-of-waterborne-diseases-as-floods-recede-6458367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 12:16:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities in Bangladesh are bracing for the spread of waterborne diseases and racing to get drinking water to people after devastating floods last week that left at least 54 people dead and millions stranded.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Authorities in Bangladesh are bracing for the spread of waterborne diseases and racing to get drinking water to people after devastating floods last week that left at least 54 people dead and millions stranded.</p>

<p>As floodwaters recede slowly, many people remain stranded and in urgent need of food, clean water, medicine and dry clothes, especially in remote areas where blocked roads have hindered rescue and relief efforts.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Meteorological Department said that flood conditions could persist if the monsoon rains continued, as water levels were receding very slowly.</p>

<p>Around 470,000 people have taken refuge in 3,300 shelters across 11 flood-hit districts, where around 600 medical teams are helping provide treatment, with the army, air force, navy, and the border guard assisting in rescue operations, authorities said.</p>

<p>A disaster management ministry official warned that as floodwaters recede, there is a risk of an epidemic, adding that the outbreak of waterborne diseases is likely if clean water is not provided soon.</p>

<p>"Our top priority is to ensure the availability of safe drinking water," the official said.</p>

<p>In the past 24 hours, around 3,000 people have been hospitalized due to waterborne diseases in flood-hit areas, according to the Directorate General of Health Services. Many areas remained submerged, preventing stranded people from accessing healthcare facilities.</p>

<p>"Water is everywhere but there is no clean water to drink. People are getting sick," said Farid Ahmed, a resident of one of the worst-hit districts, Lakshmipur.</p>

<p>Vast areas of land are submerged, posing a significant threat to crops, agriculture ministry officials said.</p>

<p>The U.N. children's agency has warned that two million children were at risk as the worst floods in three decades sweep through eastern Bangladesh. The organization is urgently appealing for $35 million to provide life-saving supplies.</p>

<p>"The devastating floods in eastern Bangladesh are a tragic reminder of the relentless impact of extreme weather events and the climate crisis on children," said Emma Brigham, Deputy Representative of UNICEF Bangladesh.</p>

<p>An analysis in 2015 by the World Bank Institute estimated that 3.5 million people in Bangladesh, one of the world's most climate-vulnerable countries, were at risk of annual river flooding. Scientists attribute the exacerbation of such catastrophic events to climate change.</p>

<p>Farah Kabir, director of ActionAid Bangladesh, said that countries like Bangladesh, which contribute minimally to global emissions, urgently need funding to recover from climate-related losses and build resilience for future impacts while pursuing green development pathways.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/sqcvqu3_bangladesh-flood-reuters_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As floodwaters recede slowly, many people remain stranded and in urgent need of basic amenities like food]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-steers-clear-of-mentioning-race-or-gender-in-historic-bid-6458265]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Steers Clear Of Mentioning Race Or Gender In Historic Bid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-steers-clear-of-mentioning-race-or-gender-in-historic-bid-6458265]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 11:53:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is aiming to make history as America's first Black and South Asian woman president -- but she has not leaned into the prospect.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris is aiming to make history as America's first Black and South Asian woman president -- but she has not leaned into the prospect.</p>

<p>Instead, Harris has steered well clear of mentioning race and gender during speeches, rallies and the first press conference of her lightning campaign.</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Democrat has also refused to engage with Republican rival Donald Trump and his allies when they have tried to bait her by questioning her racial identity and making sexist attacks.</p>

<p>Rather, Harris seems to be focusing on the broader excitement over her replacing President Joe Biden as candidate, and on issues like the cost of living that she believes voters care more about.</p>

<p>Her reluctance to rely on her trailblazing status as a selling point was on full display when she and her running mate Tim Walz gave their first interview to CNN on Thursday.</p>

<p>Harris was asked about a photo circulating of her grand-niece watching her Democratic National Convention speech in Chicago, which went viral as a symbol of the breaking of racial and gender barriers in America.</p>

<p>But Harris was not biting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I am running because I believe that I am the best person to do this job at this moment for all Americans, regardless of race and gender," Harris told CNN.</p>

<p>Harris was equally dismissive when asked about Trump's inflammatory accusation that she leaned into her Black identity for political gain. "Same old, tired playbook. Next question, please," she said with a laugh.</p>

<h3><strong>'Precious time'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>One reason for her approach is that Trump's attacks are so far merely drawing attention to her history-making status, rather than damaging her, said Jesse J. Holland, an assistant professor of media and public affairs at George Washington University.</p>

<p>"Why spend your precious time talking about things when your opponent's doing it for you -- and perhaps not successfully?" Holland told AFP.</p>

<p>Harris is also helped by the fact that she is already a known quantity as the first-ever Black, female and South Asian vice president, even if voters are still getting used to her as a presidential candidate.</p>

<p>She has not shied away from talking about her background as the daughter of a Jamaican-born father and an Indian-born mother.</p>

<p>She began her convention speech with a heartfelt tribute to her mother, a "brilliant, five-foot-tall brown woman who taught her children to 'never complain about injustice, but do something about it.'"</p>

<p>But going further and explicitly ramming home a message on race and gender is not necessarily a vote winner across the board.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her candidacy has fired up many young, female and Black voters, but there are equally voters who would be turned off by a female or Black president, said Holland.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Democrats believe issues like the economy and migration are likely to play a bigger role in what is set to be another nail-biting election.</p>

<p>Nancy Pelosi -- the influential Democratic former House speaker who was critical in pushing Biden out of the race -- backed Harris's strategy of staying low-key on her race and gender.</p>

<p>A female president would be "icing on the cake. But it ain't the cake," Pelosi told a podcast with Barack Obama's one-time strategist David Axelrod, adding that "kitchen table" issues were more important.</p>

<h3><strong>'Resisting labels'</strong></h3>

<p>Democrats have also been stung by what happened in 2016 to Hillary Clinton.</p>

<p>Clinton made being a potential first female president a core part of her campaign with the slogan "I'm With Her" -- but then lost to Trump in a shocking result.</p>

<p>"Kamala Harris is right not to make her race and gender a rallying cry," Zeeshan Aleem said in an opinion piece on MSNBC.</p>

<p>Aleem said Clinton's slogan "got it backwards: the president is supposed to be with us, not the way around."</p>

<p>There's also a personal element to it for Harris, who has avoided attempts to be categorized throughout a career as a prosecutor, California attorney general and senator.</p>

<p>In her media interactions, Harris often comes across as guarded, giving deliberative answers that can be hard to pin down.</p>

<p>But that same instinct could be politically valuable as she seeks to prevent Republicans from defining her in an aggressive election cycle with less than 10 weeks to decision day.</p>

<p>"At this very second, she may be resisting labels, maybe resisting being boxed in," said Holland.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/425dmocs_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has steered well clear of mentioning race and gender during speeches. (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-faces-conservative-backlash-over-shifting-stance-on-abortion-rights-6458113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Faces Conservative Backlash Over Shifting Stance On Abortion Rights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-faces-conservative-backlash-over-shifting-stance-on-abortion-rights-6458113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 11:25:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican White House nominee Donald Trump sought Friday to contain the blast radius of a fierce backlash over his remarks publicly backing away from right-wing positions on reproductive rights.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican White House nominee Donald Trump sought Friday to contain the blast radius of a fierce backlash over his remarks publicly backing away from right-wing positions on reproductive rights.</p>

<p>The ex-president has been under fire from conservatives over an announcement that in a second term, he would ensure free in vitro fertilization (IVF) -- an expensive fertility procedure that many in the anti-abortion movement want to see curbed.</p>

<p>The rift widened as he hit out at his home state Florida's six-week abortion ban, calling it too restrictive and suggesting he planned to vote for an upcoming ballot measure that would make the procedure legal until a fetus becomes viable.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, walked back the comment ahead of a rally in the battleground state of Pennsylvania on Friday, telling Fox News that "I will be voting no."</p>

<p>But conservatives had already begun criticizing Trump's ever-shifting positions on abortion, with a new Republican policy platform dropping calls for a national ban and the tycoon's recent claim that his government would be "great" for reproductive rights.</p>

<p>The pushback from anti-abortion groups on his latest remarks was swift, with activists warning that he risks alienating his base.</p>

<p>Evangelical theologian Albert Mohler said Trump's positions appeared "almost calculated to alienate pro-life voters" while conservative commentator Erick Erickson posted that Trump's abortion stance "will be a bridge too far for too many."</p>

<p>Trump's rally, in Johnstown, was notable for the absence of any remarks on reproductive rights, despite Thursday's big IVF announcement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The campaign of Democratic candidate Kamala Harris was happy to weigh in on the issue, smelling blood in the water.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The majority of Americans support abortion access, they support IVF, they support contraception," Mini Timmaraju, of the Reproductive Freedom for All lobby group, told reporters in a campaign call.</p>

<p>"(Trump) has finally figured it out, and he'll do anything to distract from his abysmal, horrifying record on this issue."</p>

<h3><strong>'He is pro-life'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Trump has been all over the map on abortion in the last 15 years, initially describing himself as "pro-choice" before calling for "some form of punishment" for women seeking the procedure.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He boasts about appointing Supreme Court justices who ended federal protections for abortion access in 2022 but has more recently begun to worry that Republicans are out of step with the majority of voters on reproductive rights.</p>

<p>His IVF pledge appeared calculated to appeal to moderates but will upset conservatives who for years opposed Barack Obama's Affordable Care Act because they were against the redistributive economics of taxpayer-funded health insurance. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Almost every Senate Republican voted against assuring IVF access in a vote in June -- including Trump's running mate JD Vance -- and more than half of the House Republican lawmakers have sponsored legislation that threatens its legality.</p>

<p>Republicans are divided on fertility treatments such as IVF, with many hailing them as a boost to American families.</p>

<p>Others, with strong beliefs that life begins at conception, oppose IVF because the procedure can produce multiple embryos, not all of which get used.</p>

<p>Abortion rights activists worry that the Supreme Court decision threatens IVF and were given cause by a February ruling in Alabama that frozen embryos could be considered people, causing several clinics to briefly pause treatments.</p>

<p>Yet if the abortion and IVF rows threatened to alienate Trump's most loyal supporters, rally-goers in Johnstown weren't showing it.</p>

<p>"It's not enough to make me not vote for him, no way, because he is pro-life," said Lisa Davis, a 54-year-old retired office manager from the nearby town of Somerset.</p>

<p>"I know he wants to give some exceptions -- and I think there should be."</p>

<p>"Why should I pay with my tax dollars for a baby getting killed?" added retired nurse Rosemary Drzal, 69.</p>

<p>A fireside chat-style appearance at the conservative pressure group Moms for Liberty later Friday did not touch on the issue.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6tjcj0g_donald-trump-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Conservatives had already begun criticizing Donald Trump's ever-shifting positions on abortion (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-shoots-dead-nepal-student-21-while-robbing-flat-in-us-6457945]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Man Shoots Dead Nepal Student, 21, While Robbing Flat In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-man-shoots-dead-nepal-student-21-while-robbing-flat-in-us-6457945]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 10:58:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 21-year-old student from Nepal was shot dead allegedly by an Indian-origin man at her apartment in US during a robbery, police said on Saturday. The man, who has been identified as 52-year-old Bobby Sinh Shah, has been arrested.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 21-year-old student from Nepal was shot dead allegedly by an Indian-origin man at her apartment in US during a robbery, police said on Saturday. The man, who has been identified as 52-year-old Bobby Sinh Shah, has been arrested.</p>

<p>Muna Pandey, a community college student, was found with multiple gunshot wounds inside her Houston apartment around 5.30 pm on Monday, police said. Staff at her apartment complex told police that they received an anonymous call about a body inside the apartment. When the police reached the scene, she was declared dead.</p>

<p>Two days later, police released a photo of Shah who was caught on CCTV leaving her apartment on Saturday. Police said Shah was arrested later that day at a traffic stop and charged with murder.</p>

<p>According to a GoFundMe page, Ms Pandey had moved to study at the Houston Community College from Nepal in 2021. Her mother had been trying to reach her for days before her body was found inside her apartment, a member of Nepalese Association of Houston told the New York Post.</p>

<p>"What her Mom said is her phone was always online. After Saturday night, phone was offline. She had three gunshots and she was laying down on the bed, with head down. Hopefully, the investigation will come up with some idea of how this happened," he said, adding that Ms Pandey was an only child.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The association is working with the Nepal Consulate to help make travel arrangements for Ms Pandey's mother to fly to Houston.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are reaching out to you, our community, to help bring Anita to the United States so she can say goodbye to her only child and give Muna the farewell she deserves. The funds raised will be used to cover the costs of Muna's funeral and to bring her mother to Houston to be with her daughter's body for the final rituals," reads the GoFundMe page that has raised nearly $30,000.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/05tq474s_muna-pandey-bobby-shah_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-block-on-elon-musks-x-comes-into-effect-6457801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Block On Elon Musk's X Comes Into Effect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-block-on-elon-musks-x-comes-into-effect-6457801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 10:29:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A block on Elon Musk's X social network in Brazil started to take effect early Saturday after a Supreme Court judge ordered its suspension, according to AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A block on Elon Musk's X social network in Brazil started to take effect early Saturday after a Supreme Court judge ordered its suspension, according to AFP.</p>

<p>Access to the platform, formerly known as Twitter, was no longer possible for some users in the South American country, who were presented with a message asking them to reload the browser without being able to log in successfully.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mafbd1e4_x-twitter_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[X Users In Brazil were presented with a message asking them to reload the browser (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-block-on-elon-musks-x-comes-into-effect-6457794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Block On Elon Musk's X Comes Into Effect]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-block-on-elon-musks-x-comes-into-effect-6457794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 10:27:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A block on Elon Musk's X social network in Brazil started to take effect early Saturday after a Supreme Court judge ordered its suspension, according to AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A block on Elon Musk's X social network in Brazil started to take effect early Saturday after a Supreme Court judge ordered its suspension, according to AFP.</p>

<p>Brazilian Supreme Court judge Alexandre de Moraes on Friday ordered the suspension of the platform following a months-long standoff with the tech billionaire over disinformation in South America's largest nation.</p>

<p>Moraes handed down the ruling after Musk failed to comply with an order to name a new legal representative for the company.</p>

<p>Early Saturday access to X, formerly known as Twitter, was no longer possible for some users in the South American country, who were presented with a message asking them to reload the browser without being able to log in successfully.</p>

<p>Musk, who also owns Tesla and SpaceX, reacted with fury to the judge's order, branding Moraes an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge" and accusing him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>"Free speech is the bedrock of democracy and an unelected pseudo-judge in Brazil is destroying it for political purposes," the billionaire, who has become increasingly aligned with right-wing politics, wrote on X.</p>

<p>The two have been locked in an ongoing, high-profile feud for months as Moraes leads a battle against disinformation in Brazil.</p>

<p>Musk has previously declared himself a "free speech absolutist," but since he took over the platform formerly known as Twitter in 2022 he has been accused of turning it into a megaphone for right-wing conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>He is a vocal supporter of former US president Donald Trump's bid to regain the White House.</p>

<p>Moraes ordered the "immediate, complete and comprehensive suspension of the operation of" X in the country, telling the national communications agency to take "all necessary measures" to implement the order within 24 hours.</p>

<p>He threatened a fine of 50,000 reais ($8,900) to anyone who used "technological subterfuges" to get around the block, such as a VPN.</p>

<p>The judge also demanded Google, Apple and internet providers "introduce technological obstacles capable of preventing the use of the X application" and access to the website -- though he later walked back that order.</p>

<p>The social media platform has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<p>Musk shut X's business operations in Brazil earlier this month, claiming Moraes had threatened the company's previous legal representative with arrest to force compliance with "censorship orders."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Moraes told Musk he had 24 hours to find a new representative or he would face suspension.</p>

<p>Shortly after the deadline passed, X said in a statement that it expected Moraes to shut it down "simply because we would not comply with his illegal orders to censor his political opponents."</p>

<h3><strong>'Who does Musk think he is?'</strong></h3>

<p>The standoff with Musk began when Moraes ordered the suspension of several X accounts belonging to supporters of Brazil's former far-right president Jair Bolsonaro, who tried to discredit the voting system in the 2022 election, which he lost.</p>

<p>Brazilian authorities are investigating whether Bolsonaro plotted a coup attempt to prevent current President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from assuming office in January 2023.</p>

<p>Online users blocked by Moraes include figures such as far-right ex-congressman Daniel Silveira, who was sentenced to nine years in prison in 2022 on charges of leading a movement to overthrow the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>In April, Moraes ordered an investigation of Musk, accusing him of reactivating some of the banned accounts.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Musk's satellite internet operator Starlink said it had received an order from Moraes that froze its accounts and prevented it from conducting financial transactions in Brazil.</p>

<p>Starlink alleged that the order "is based on an unfounded determination that Starlink should be responsible for the fines levied -- unconstitutionally -- against X."</p>

<p>The company said on X that it intended "to address the matter legally."</p>

<p>Musk is also the subject of a separate judicial investigation into an alleged scheme where public money was used to orchestrate disinformation campaigns in favor of Bolsonaro and those close to him.</p>

<p>"Any citizen from anywhere in the world who has investments in Brazil is subject to the Brazilian Constitution and laws," Lula told a local radio station on Friday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Who does (Musk) think he is?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nvneif7g_elon-musk_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[X users in Brazil were presented with a message asking them to reload the browser (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raid-by-us-iraqi-forces-kill-15-isis-members-in-west-iraq-6457753]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Raid By US, Iraqi Forces Kill 15 ISIS Members In West Iraq]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raid-by-us-iraqi-forces-kill-15-isis-members-in-west-iraq-6457753]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 10:15:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A joint operation by American and Iraqi forces killed 15 members of the Islamic State group in western Iraq, US Central Command (CENTCOM) said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A joint operation by American and Iraqi forces killed 15 members of the Islamic State group in western Iraq, with seven US troops injured during the operation, US Central Command (CENTCOM) said Friday.</p>

<p>The raid targeted Islamic State leaders and was carried out early Thursday morning, resulting "in the death of 15 ISIS operatives" with "no indication of civilian casualties," CENTCOM said on the social media platform X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">U.S. Central Command (CENTCOM) forces and Iraqi Security Forces conducted a partnered raid in Western Iraq in the early hours of Aug. 29, resulting in the death of 15 ISIS operatives. The ISIS element was armed with numerous weapons, grenades, and explosive "suicide" belts. There… <a href="https://t.co/fCOFyxtke1">pic.twitter.com/fCOFyxtke1</a></p>
— U.S. Central Command (@CENTCOM) <a href="https://twitter.com/CENTCOM/status/1829690125896351762?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>It said the IS members were "armed with numerous weapons, grenades, and explosive 'suicide' belts," and that Iraqi forces were continuing "to further exploit the locations raided," only specifying that the operation occurred in western Iraq.</p>

<p>Five US troops were wounded during the raid and another two were injured in falls, a defense official said. One of the wounded was evacuated for treatment, as was one of the personnel injured in a fall.&nbsp;</p>

<p>All seven were in stable condition, the official said.</p>

<p>"ISIS remains a threat to the region, our allies, as well as our homeland. US CENTCOM alongside our coalition and Iraqi partners, will continue to aggressively pursue these terrorists," CENTCOM added.</p>

<p>The operation comes as Baghdad and Washington have been engaged in months of talks over the presence of anti-jihadist coalition forces in Iraq.</p>

<p>Despite Iraq's stated goal of a full withdrawal of the forces, no timeline has been made public.</p>

<p>The United States has some 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria as part of the international coalition against the Islamic State group.</p>

<p>Coalition forces have been targeted dozens of times with drones and rocket fire in both Iraq and Syria, as violence related to the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza that broke out in early October has drawn in Iran-backed armed groups across the Middle East.</p>

<p>Last winter, the Islamic Resistance of Iraq, a loose alliance of Iran-backed groups, claimed some 175 rocket and drone attacks against US troops in Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>US forces have carried out multiple retaliatory strikes against these militant factions in both countries.</p>

<p>Thursday's raid also comes just under a week after US forces killed a senior leader of an Al-Qaeda-affiliated militant group in Syria.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-09/uscrsqr8_us-troops-in-iraqafp650_625x300_11_September_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US has some 2,500 troops in Iraq and 900 in Syria as international coalition against ISIS (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/work-somewhere-else-ecuadors-narco-violence-threatens-scientists-6457669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Work Somewhere Else": Ecuador's Narco Violence Threatens Scientists]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/work-somewhere-else-ecuadors-narco-violence-threatens-scientists-6457669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 09:53:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Biologist Cesar Garzon was searching for a small, endangered parakeet in southern Ecuador when he was warned he may be kidnapped, highlighting the danger for scientists in the biodiverse country engulfed in narco violence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Biologist Cesar Garzon was searching for a small, endangered parakeet in southern Ecuador when he was warned he may be kidnapped, highlighting the danger for scientists in the biodiverse country engulfed in narco violence.</p>

<p>"Do your work somewhere else because it is dangerous here," he said a man told him in April, in the troubled mining town of Camilo Ponce Enriquez.</p>

<p>That night, the town's mayor was shot dead. Earlier this month, a clash between criminal groups in the town left five dead, two of whom were found decapitated, and one burned.</p>

<p>Garzon, a bird expert at the state-run National Institute of Biodiversity (Inabio), tried to continue his research in a neighbouring town, whose mayor was also killed.</p>

<p>Tired of the ever-present danger, he packed his bags and returned to Quito.</p>

<p>Garzon has been studying the El Oro parakeet for two decades, working for its conservation and supporting the sustainable management of its habitats.</p>

<p>Mostly green, with a red forehead, the bird is endemic to Ecuador and has only been seen in the country's southwest provinces of Azuay and El Oro.</p>

<p>With only an estimated 1,000 specimens remaining, the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) lists it as in danger of extinction.</p>

<p>Garzon visited Camilo Ponce Enriquez, in Azuay province, to track down and study the endangered parakeet.</p>

<p>But the gold-rich town is in the grips of the Los Lobos drug trafficking gang, which finances its activities with illegal mining.</p>

<p>"We are left with uncertainty and frustration (...) There is a lack of information on that site," he told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He said the violence was a blow to conservation as there "could be important areas that are home to endemic or threatened species and we can't do anything."</p>

<h3><strong>'Windows of opportunity'</strong></h3>

<p>Sandwiched between Colombia and Peru -- the world's top cocaine producers -- once-peaceful Ecuador has seen violence explode in recent years as enemy gangs with links to Mexican and Colombian cartels vie for control.</p>

<p>As the gangs have gained ground, homicides in Ecuador soared from six per 100,000 inhabitants in 2018 to a record 47 per 100,000 in 2023.</p>

<p>Mario Yanez, another biologist from Inabio, said his current work revolves around finding "windows of opportunity" to continue researching despite the violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scientists work closely with local communities and authorities and do shorter field trips or focus on similar species located in less risky areas.</p>

<p>"The levels of violence have led to total restrictions in certain areas of the country," especially on the coast and where there is mining, said Yanez.</p>

<p>These places carry the "stigma" of the violence and that "unfortunately is limiting international cooperation funds to be able to carry out conservation actions," he added,</p>

<p>The private Lalo Loor reserve in southwestern Manabi is one of Ecuador's last intact remnants of a unique ecosystem known as a coastal dry forest, home to many endemic species.</p>

<p>The province is also a drug trafficking stronghold. Due to the security crisis, American universities cancelled an annual visit of researchers and students to the reserve, a major source of income for Lalo Loor.</p>

<p>Their continued absence could force the reserve's administrative office to shutter, manager Mariela Loor said.</p>

<p>Judith Denkinger, a German biologist at the private Universidad San Francisco de Quito, told AFP that since 2022 she has put on hold her two decades of research into humpback whales on the coast of the conflict-ridden northwestern province of Esmeraldas, bordering Colombia.</p>

<p>She has been unable to gather photographic or acoustic records of the humpback whales that come to the equatorial Pacific to mate and give birth.</p>

<p>She also highlighted the plight of fishermen -- who she often works with at sea.</p>

<p>"Pirates, who are usually drug traffickers, come and threaten them, hijack their boat or steal their motor or kidnap them" to force them into drug trafficking, she said.</p>

<p>Daniel Vizuete, a specialist in Social Studies of Science and Technology at the Flacso University in Quito, said research related to the environment was "perhaps the most eroded precisely because it occurs ... in places where institutions are weaker."</p>

<p>"That means that even the lives of researchers can be at risk," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also points to other possible effects of criminal violence on science such as a "setback in terms of participation of women."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5km2t37_el-oro-parakeet-_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biologist Cesar Garzon has been studying the rare El Oro parakeet for two decades now.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/she-is-a-marxist-slipping-in-polls-trump-targets-kamala-harris-past-6457509]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["She Is A Marxist": Slipping In Polls, Trump Targets Kamala Harris' Past]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/she-is-a-marxist-slipping-in-polls-trump-targets-kamala-harris-past-6457509]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 09:16:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[New York, Aug 31 (IANS) Needling her as “Comrade Kamaala” and describing his Democratic Party rival as an inveterate second-generation Marxist, Donald Trump on Friday campaigned in Pennsylvania, a key milestone on the road to the White House, where h]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Needling her as “Comrade Kamaala” and describing his Democratic Party rival as an inveterate second-generation Marxist, Donald Trump on Friday campaigned in Pennsylvania, a key milestone on the road to the White House, where his lead in polls appears to be evaporating.</p>

<p>While Kamala Harris has moved to the centre and, at least publicly, renounced her radical past, Trump played back on giant TV screens at his rally in Johnstown clips of Harris' old statements aimed at her party's left.</p>

<p>During her failed run for the presidential nomination in 2019, Harris had vowed to ban fracking – a way of drilling for natural gas in shale formations underground – and Trump kept hammering at it because that is an important issue for Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In an interview on Thursday, Harris acknowledged she had changed her position and would not ban fracking, while also declaring repeatedly, “My values have not changed”.</p>

<p>With a phalanx of labourers dressed in their work clothes topped by hardhats standing behind him, he declared that from Day One, his policy would be “Drill baby, drill” for fossil fuels including gas.</p>

<p>At his rally in an indoor arena in Johnstown, her long ago pronouncements – that she has since walked back – on ending private health insurance, decriminalising illegal border crossing, cutting funding for police, and compulsorily buying back guns from owners rolled on screens, and Trump turned them into a handy scare tactic.</p>

<p>“She is a Marxist, her father is a Marxist”, Trump said, referring to her father Donald Harris, the Jamaica-born Stanford University emeritus professor of economics, from whom she is estranged.</p>

<p>RealClear Politics aggregation of Pennsylvania polls shows that Trump's 3 per cent lead over Harris in July when Biden withdrew has disappeared with the Democrat now having a narrow 0.8 per cent lead.</p>

<p>In the US system where the state-wise composition of the electoral college can override the national popular votes, Pennsylvania is one of the battleground states that go either way and help determine the winner.</p>

<p>Nationally Reuters/Ipsos and Morning Consult polls taken since last week give her a 4 per cent lead and the overall RealClear Politics aggregation puts her ahead by 1.8 per cent.</p>

<p>One of the clips projected was of her agreeing with an interviewer that she would agree to change government dietary guidelines to reduce the consumption of red meat, a category that includes beef.</p>

<p>He criticised her for this at the rally, as he has at previous campaign stops.</p>

<p>It could be interpreted as a subtle dig at her Indian heritage as he raised it days after having claimed that Harris has all along been an Indian and only recently proclaimed her African American background.</p>

<p>(In reality, her public acknowledgment of her Indian heritage came long after projecting her political persona as Black.)</p>

<p>At the rally he gave a shout-out to Tulsi Gabbard, the first Hindu elected to Congress, for leaving the Democratic Party to support him.</p>

<p>“I feel very happy to get” her endorsement, he said</p>

<p>While Trump chastised Harris' flip-flops, he too showed at the rally what would be a dissent from the core of conservative orthodoxy by reaffirming his backing for insurance or government-funded in vitro fertilisation.</p>

<p>A Bench of conservative judges in Alabama ruled that eggs fertilised through medical procedures are considered “unborn children” creating a legal quagmire that the Republican leaders are trying to get out of.</p>

<p>"We need more babies to be born in America", said the father of five from three marriages.</p>

<p>Trump's rallies are staged as political theater where he keeps his faithful amused and aroused jumping back and forth disjointedly between topics, leavening them with humor, mostly at the expense of his adversaries.</p>

<p>He called this speaking style, “weaving”, while he acknowledged some others dub it "rambling".</p>

<p>“I'll talk about nine things and they all come back brilliantly together”, he said.</p>

<p>Trump railed against the news media calling it biased and a man jumped into the media enclosure.</p>

<p>The intruder was hit by police with a jolt of electricity from a Taser device to subdue him and as he was led away to the crowd's cheers, the Republican candidate asked, “Is there anywhere that's more fun to be than a Trump rally”?</p>

<p>He joked that Harris would ask to join his Make America Great Again Movement and wear its signature red cap because she was backpedaling her past pronouncements.</p>

<p>He nicknamed Harris' running mate Tim Walz as “Tampon Tim” for the state he governs, Minnesota, putting female hygiene products in boys' school bathrooms in the name of equality for transgender students.</p>

<p>Plunging into divisive cultural issues, he said that he would ban men from participating as women in sports, stop sex change therapy for children, and reinforce parents' rights.</p>

<p>He added he would criminalise burning the national flag and enforce laws against damaging national monuments.</p>

<p>On foreign policy, he talked of his interactions with Presidents Xi Jinping of China and Vladimir Putin of Russia, North Korean dictator Kim Jong Un, and Taliban leader Mullah Abdul Ghani Baradar and his tough bargaining.</p>

<p>Harris would not be able to stand up to the likes of Xi and Putin, he asserted.</p>

<p>He blamed her for the Afghanistan withdrawal debacle in which 13 US military personnel were killed and defended his visit to their graves at the military cemetery in Washington where his entourage had a run-in with a Defence employee who said she was enforcing rules against politicising the place.</p>

<p>He said that he only agreed to the request from family members for pictures at the gravesite.</p>

<p>(Arul Louis can be contacted at arul.l@ians.in and followed at @arulouis)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lqgn5nn_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-alexandre-de-moraes-controversy-explained-why-brazil-supreme-court-judge-banned-x-6457462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Brazil Supreme Court Judge Banned X And What Elon Musk Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-alexandre-de-moraes-controversy-explained-why-brazil-supreme-court-judge-banned-x-6457462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 09:01:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After a months-long standoff over disinformation, a Brazilian Supreme Court judge suspended billionaire Elon Musk's social media network X in the country on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a months-long standoff over disinformation, a Brazilian Supreme Court judge banned billionaire Elon Musk's social media network X in the country on Friday. The judge, Alexandre de Moraes, ordered the "immediate, complete and comprehensive suspension of the operation of" X in the country and told the national communications agency to take "all necessary measures" to implement the order.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazils-supreme-court-orders-suspension-of-elon-musks-x-amid-row-6456202" target="_blank">Alexandre de Moraes</a> also threatened a fine of 50,000 reais ($8,900) to anyone who used "technological subterfuges" to get around the block, such as a VPN or the virtual private network.</p>

<h3><strong>The Elon Musk-Brazil Judge Controversy</strong></h3>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-slams-brazil-pseudo-judge-after-order-to-suspend-x-6456714" target="_blank">Elon Musk-Alexandre de Moraes controversy</a> began when the Supreme Court judge ordered the suspension of several accounts on X, formerly known as Twitter, belonging to supporters of Brazil's former president Jair Bolsonaro, who tried to discredit the voting system in the 2022 election, which he lost.</p>

<p>Brazilian authorities are investigating whether Bolsonaro plotted a coup attempt to prevent current President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva from assuming office in January 2023.</p>

<p>In April, Moraes ordered an investigation of Musk, accusing him of reactivating some of the banned accounts.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-compares-brazils-chief-justice-to-harry-potter-villain-voldemort-6362346" target="_blank"><strong>ALSO READ | Elon Musk Compares Brazil's Chief Justice To Harry Potter Villain Voldemort</strong></a></p>

<p>X claims that Moraes threatened to arrest one of the company's legal representatives in Brazil if it did not comply.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-to-close-brazil-operations-over-censorship-orders-6359957" target="_blank">Musk's platform had shut all of its Brazil offices</a> due to what it called "censorship" by the judge, though its service had remained available for users in the country.</p>

<p>"We have a right to defend fundamental rights. Those who violate democracy, who violate fundamental human rights, whether in person or through social media, must be held accountable," Moraes said in a speech on Friday, apparently referring to X.</p>

<h3><strong>Ban On Elon Musk' X In Brazil</strong></h3>

<p>The Brazilian Supreme Court judge said the suspension would remain until all related court orders on X were complied with, including the payment of fines amounting to 18.5 million reais ($3.28 million), which he had previously slapped on the social media network for ignoring judicial orders.</p>

<p>The order will also be valid until a representative of the company in the country is appointed, he said.</p>

<p>Moraes also froze the financial assets of Musk's Starlink by issuing an order to block the accounts of the satellite internet network that has rapidly expanded the number of its users in Brazil.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-threatens-to-suspend-elon-musks-x-in-country-within-24-hours-6441356" target="_blank">he told Musk he had 24 hours</a> to find a new representative or he would face suspension. However, as the deadline passed, X said in a statement that it expected Moraes to shut it down "simply because we would not comply with his illegal orders to censor his political opponents."</p>

<p>X reportedly has more than 22 million users in Brazil.</p>

<h3><strong>What Elon Musk Said</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-says-need-to-move-brazil-employees-to-safe-place-5404285" target="_blank">Elon Musk</a>, who took over X in 2022, reacted sharply to the ban and branded Alexandre de Moraes an "evil dictator cosplaying as a judge".</p>

<p>He also accused him of "trying to destroy democracy in Brazil."</p>

<p>"Free speech is the bedrock of democracy and an unelected pseudo-judge in Brazil is destroying it for political purposes," he wrote on X.</p>

<p>"They're shutting down the #1 source of truth in Brazil," Musk added.</p>

<p><em>(With agency inputs)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s5ibj3ao_elon-musk-brazil_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brazil Supreme Court Judge Alexandre de Moraes and Elon Musk have been in a public feud for months]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indigenous-women-fight-to-search-1950s-cia-funded-human-experiments-site-6457357]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indigenous Women Fight To Search 1950s CIA-Funded Human Experiments Site]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indigenous-women-fight-to-search-1950s-cia-funded-human-experiments-site-6457357]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 08:36:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of Indigenous women are hoping to stop the bulldozers at a former Montreal hospital which they believe could hold the truth about children still missing from a grisly half-century-old CIA experiment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of Indigenous women are hoping to stop the bulldozers at a former Montreal hospital which they believe could hold the truth about children still missing from a grisly half-century-old CIA experiment.</p>

<p>They have spent the last two years trying to delay the construction project by McGill University and the Quebec government.</p>

<p>"They took our children and had all kinds of things done to them. They were experimenting on them," said Kahentinetha, an 85-year-old activist from the Mohawk community of Kahnawake, southwest of Montreal, who goes by just one name.</p>

<p>The activists are relying on archives and testimonies that suggest the site contains unmarked graves of children formerly interned at the Royal Victoria Hospital and Allan Memorial Institute, a neighbouring psychiatric hospital.</p>

<p>In the 1950s and 1960s, behind the austere walls of the old psychiatric institute, the US Central Intelligence Agency funded a human experiments program called MK Ultra.</p>

<p>During the Cold War, the program aimed to develop procedures and drugs to effectively brainwash people.</p>

<p>Experiments were conducted in Britain, Canada and the United States, subjecting people -- including Indigenous children in Montreal -- to electroshocks, hallucinogenic drugs, and sensory deprivation.</p>

<p>"They wanted to erase us," said Kahentinetha.</p>

<p>A leading figure in the Indigenous rights movement who has travelled to Britain and the United States to denounce colonialism, she called this fight "the most important of (her) life."</p>

<p>"We want to know why they did this and who's going to take the blame for it," she said.</p>

<h2><strong>Sniffer dogs</strong></h2>

<p>In the fall of 2022, the mothers obtained an injunction to suspend work on a new university campus and research centre at the site -- a project worth Can$870 million (US$643 million).</p>

<p>Fellow activist Kwetiio, 52, who also uses just one name, said they insisted on arguing the case themselves without lawyers, "because in our ways, no one speaks for us."</p>

<p>Last summer, sniffer dogs and specialized probes were brought in to search the property's expansive and dilapidated buildings. They managed to identify three areas of interest for excavations.</p>

<p>But, according to McGill and the government's Societe Quebecoise des Infrastructure (SQI), "no human remains have been discovered."</p>

<p>The Mohawk mothers accuse the university and the government infrastructure agency of breaching an agreement by selecting the archaeologists who did the search and then ending their work too soon.</p>

<p>"They gave themselves the power to lead the investigation of crimes that were potentially committed by their own employees in the past," says Philippe Blouin, an anthropologist working with the mothers.</p>

<p>Even though their appeal was dismissed earlier this month, they have vowed to continue their fight.</p>

<p>"People should know history, so that it does not repeat itself," said Kwetiio.</p>

<p>In recent years, Canada has opened its eyes to past atrocities.</p>

<p>Generations of Indigenous children were sent to residential schools where they were stripped of their language, culture and identities in what a 2015 truth and reconciliation report said amounted to "cultural genocide."</p>

<p>Between 1831 and 1996, some 150,000 Indigenous children were taken from their homes and placed in 139 such schools. Several thousand never returned to their communities.</p>

<p>In May 2021, the discovery of unmarked graves of 215 children at the Kamloops Indian Residential School in British Columbia started a national reflection on this dark chapter of Canadian history, while sparking searches for more graves across Canada.</p>

<p>"It was not only residential schools, it involved hospitals, sanatoriums, churches and orphanages too," said Kwetiio.</p>

<p>For her, what is most important is shedding light on what happened in order for "things to change," and to recreate "the harmony that we had before colonialism."</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-05/krki1f9g_coronavirus-hospital-generic-afp_625x300_23_May_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Between 1831 and 1996, some 150,000 Indigenous children were taken from their homes.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/week-after-deadly-knife-attack-5-killed-in-german-bus-stabbing-6457197]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Week After Deadly Knife Attack, 5 Killed In German Bus Stabbing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/week-after-deadly-knife-attack-5-killed-in-german-bus-stabbing-6457197]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 07:46:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman stabbed and wounded five people in a bus in western Germany on Friday, police said, one week after a deadly knife attack that shook the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman stabbed and wounded five people in a bus in western Germany on Friday, police said, one week after a deadly knife attack that shook the country.</p>

<p>The 32-year-old suspect was arrested after the incident in the town of Siegen with no indications it was a terrorist attack, the local police force said in a statement.</p>

<p>Three of the five victims are in life-threatening condition, one is seriously wounded and the fifth is only lightly injured.</p>

<p>Germany was rocked by a stabbing attack one week ago that left three people dead and eight wounded in the western city of Solingen.</p>

<p>The identity of the suspected attacker, a 26-year-old Syrian man who was previously due for deportation to Bulgaria, stoked debate about Germany's immigration and asylum policies.</p>

<p>The killings have prompted Chancellor Olaf Scholz's government to announce new restrictions on carrying knives at public gatherings and on long-distance transport, as well as curbing benefits for some illegal migrants.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, police shot dead a man suspected of attacking passers-by with knives in the western town of Moers near Solingen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/i0l77h5o_german-police-generic_625x300_29_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The government is bringing new restrictions on carrying knives at public gatherings (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptian-worker-killed-in-hotel-fight-israeli-tourists-wounded-6457165]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Egyptian Worker Killed In Hotel Fight, Israeli Tourists Wounded]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/egyptian-worker-killed-in-hotel-fight-israeli-tourists-wounded-6457165]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 07:32:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Egyptian worker was killed Friday in a hotel fight that wounded three Arab-Israeli tourists and other workers in the Egyptian seaside town of Taba, a medical source told AFP.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Egyptian worker was killed Friday in a hotel fight that wounded three Arab-Israeli tourists and other workers in the Egyptian seaside town of Taba, a medical source told AFP.</p>

<p>The worker succumbed to his injuries "in an ambulance transporting him from Taba" on the border with Israel to Sharm al-Sheikh, 200 kilometres south, the source said, requesting anonymity because they were not authorised to speak to the media.</p>

<p>Three other workers and three "Arab 48" tourists were also wounded, state-linked Egyptian media Al-Qahera News reported.</p>

<p>"Arab 48" is a term that refers to Palestinians and their descendants who remained in Israel following its creation in 1948.</p>

<p>Friday's fight broke out between hotel staff and the tourists "who attempted to obtain services from the hotel without charge", the channel reported.</p>

<p>Al-Qahera News, which is linked to state intelligence, reported security authorities were investigating the incident.</p>

<p>A high-level security source denied Israeli media reports describing the altercation as a "stabbing operation".</p>

<p>The incident occurred in the Egyptian border town of Taba in South Sinai, which is a popular tourist destination for Israelis.</p>

<p>Egypt was the first Arab country to sign a peace treaty with Israel and has for decades played a key role as a mediator between Israeli and Palestinian officials, including in the current war in the Gaza Strip.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4oc4qcp_crime-scene-generic-_625x300_17_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fight allegedly broke out between hotel staff and the tourists (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-isi-undeniably-complicit-with-terrorists-ex-us-security-advisor-6457136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak's ISI "Undeniably Complicit" With Terrorists: Ex US Security Advisor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-isi-undeniably-complicit-with-terrorists-ex-us-security-advisor-6457136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 07:22:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There is an "undeniable complicity" of Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) with terrorist groups, former US National Security Advisor Lt Gen (retd) H R McMaster has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is an "undeniable complicity" of Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) with terrorist groups, former US National Security Advisor Lt Gen (retd) H R McMaster has said, revealing that during his tenure under then President Donald Trump, the White House faced resistance from the state department and Pentagon over providing security aid to Islamabad.</p>

<p>Despite directions from Trump to stop all aid to Pakistan till it stops giving safe havens to terrorists, McMaster in his latest book 'At War with Ourselves: My Tour of Duty in the Trump White House' says that the then Defence Secretary Jim Mattis was planning to deliver a military aid package to Islamabad that included over USD 150 million worth of armoured vehicles.</p>

<p>However, the aid was stopped after his intervention, McMaster writes in the book that hit the bookstores this week.</p>

<p>“It was difficult to get State and Defence even to comply with Trump's directives to stop certain activities. I discovered that contrary to the South Asia strategy, which called for the suspension of all aid to Pakistan with a few exceptions, when Mattis visited Islamabad in the coming weeks, the Pentagon was going to deliver a military aid package that included more than USD 150 million worth of armoured vehicles,” he writes.</p>

<p>McMaster says soon after he came to know about it, he called for a meeting with Mattis, the deputy director of the Central Intelligence Agency, Gina Haspel, and other senior officials.</p>

<p>“I started by noting that the president (Trump) had been very clear on multiple occasions to suspend aid to the Pakistanis until they halted support for terrorist organisations that were killing Afghans, Americans, and coalition members in Afghanistan...We had all heard Trump say, 'I do not want any money going to Pakistan',” he says.</p>

<p>Mattis, the former NSA writes, noted the possibility that Pakistan might retaliate in certain ways, but others, including Ambassador David Hale, who had joined by video from Islamabad, did not share those concerns.</p>

<p>“Mattis reluctantly halted that shipment of assistance, but other aid would continue, prompting Trump to tweet on New Year's Day, 'The United States has foolishly given Pakistan more than 33 billion dollars in aid over the last 15 years and they have given us nothing but lies &amp; deceit thinking of our leaders as fools. They give safe haven to the terrorists we hunt in Afghanistan with little help. No more!',” he writes.</p>

<p>“Pakistan was not changing its behaviour, and almost as an insult, the government released Hafiz Saeed, the mastermind behind the 2008 Mumbai terrorist attacks, on the eve of Mattis's visit. Moreover, a recent event in Pakistan involving hostages had exposed the undeniable complicity of Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence with the terrorists,” McMaster writes.</p>

<p>He notes that news reports that time criticised the president's tweet as capricious and devoid of a coherent policy. But halting assistance was a critical part of the South Asia strategy that Trump had approved at Camp David in August, he says.</p>

<p>"A lunch that the president hosted with the vice president, Tillerson, Mattis, Kelly, and me on December 14 helped me understand why it was difficult to implement Trump's guidance on Pakistan or to foster cooperation on contingency plans for North Korea,” says McMaster.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/0a19pbic_terrorist-generic-ndtv-file_625x300_16_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-space-x-to-restart-falcon-9-launch-after-landing-mishap-6457106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Space X To Restart Falcon 9 Launch After Landing Mishap]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-space-x-to-restart-falcon-9-launch-after-landing-mishap-6457106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 31 Aug 2024 07:16:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US regulators on Friday cleared SpaceX to restart launching its stalwart Falcon 9 rocket, as a probe continues into a rare mishap this week during a first-stage booster landing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US regulators on Friday cleared SpaceX to restart launching its stalwart Falcon 9 rocket, as a probe continues into a rare mishap this week during a first-stage booster landing.</p>

<p>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) grounded the Falcon 9 rocket on Wednesday after a first-stage booster tipped over and exploded while attempting to land on a droneship off the Florida coast.</p>

<p>The early morning launch was otherwise successful, delivering the latest batch of 21 Starlink internet satellites into orbit.</p>

<p>"The SpaceX Falcon 9 vehicle may return to flight operations while the overall investigation of the anomaly during the Starlink Group 8-6 mission remains open, provided all other license requirements are met," the FAA said in a statement Friday.</p>

<p>A webcast from Elon Musk's company showed the first stage, which normally fires its thrusters to achieve a precise upright landing, tilting and blowing up as it descended onto a droneship off the Florida coast.</p>

<p>Although landing the booster is a secondary objective, and no lives or public property were at risk, the reusability of the entire rocket system is crucial to SpaceX's business model.</p>

<p>It broke a more than three-year streak of hundreds of successful booster landings.</p>

<p>Falcon 9 is the workhorse of SpaceX's fleet, trusted by the US government and private industry to propel satellites and astronauts into orbit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was last grounded for around two weeks in July when its second-stage engine experienced an anomaly that prevented it from deploying another batch of Starlink satellites at the correct altitude, leading them to burn up on re-entry through Earth's atmosphere</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ut46gm18_space-x-falcon-9-launch-_625x300_31_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The reusability of the entire rocket system is crucial to SpaceX's business model.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>