<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 23:43:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cosmic-ballet-2-galaxies-merge-in-space-webb-telescope-sends-in-pics-6093460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Cosmic Ballet": 2 Galaxies Merge In Space, Webb Telescope Sends In Pics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cosmic-ballet-2-galaxies-merge-in-space-webb-telescope-sends-in-pics-6093460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 23:36:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA released a pair of images taken by the James Webb Space Telescope showing two galaxies in the process of merging in sort of a cosmic ballet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA released on Friday a pair of images taken by the James Webb Space Telescope showing two galaxies - one nicknamed the Penguin and the other the Egg - in the process of merging in sort of a cosmic ballet as the U.S. space agency marked two years since it unveiled the orbiting observatory's first scientific results.</p>

<p>Webb, which was launched in 2021 and began collecting data the following year, has reshaped the understanding of the early universe while taking stunning pictures of the cosmos. The two galaxies in the images are situated 326 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Hydra. A light year is the distance light travels in a year, 5.9 trillion miles (9.5 trillion km).</p>

<p>"We see two galaxies, each a collection of billions of stars. The galaxies are in the process of merging. That's a common way that galaxies like our own build up over time, to grow from small galaxies - like those that Webb has found shortly after the Big Bang - into mature galaxies like our own Milky Way," said Jane Rigby, NASA Webb senior project scientist.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/hofnufao_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>Since becoming operational, Webb has observed galaxies teeming with stars that formed within a few hundred million years of the Big Bang event that marked the beginning of the universe about 13.8 billion years ago.</p>

<p>The mingling Penguin and Egg galaxies are collectively known as Arp 142. They are shown in the imagery joined by a haze that is a mix of stars and gas amid their slow-motion merger.</p>

<p>The Penguin galaxy, so dubbed because its shape from the perspective of the telescope resembles that flightless bird, including a beak-like region, is formally called NGC 2936. It is a spiral-shaped galaxy, now a bit distorted. The Egg galaxy, also named for its shape, is formally called NGC 2937. It is a compact elliptical-shaped galaxy. Together, their appearance is suggestive of a penguin guarding its egg.</p>

<p>Their interaction, according to NASA, was set in motion between 25 and 75 million years ago, and they are expected to become a single galaxy hundreds of millions of years from now.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/li3kc9cg_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>Webb has detected the earliest-known galaxies and has provided insight into areas such as the composition of planets beyond our solar system, known as exoplanets, and the nature of star-forming regions in the cosmos.</p>

<p>"This mission has allowed us to look back to the most distant galaxies ever observed and understand the very early universe in a new way," said Mark Clampin, astrophysics division director at NASA headquarters. "For example, with Webb, we've found that these very early galaxies are more massive and brighter than we expected, posing the question: How did they get so big so quickly?"</p>

<p>Webb was designed to be more sensitive than its Hubble Space Telescope predecessor, which also is continuing its work. Webb looks at the universe mainly in the infrared, while Hubble has examined it primarily at optical and ultraviolet wavelengths.</p>

<p>"Webb is the largest, most powerful telescope ever put in space. It specializes in capturing infrared light - wavelengths of light longer than our eyes can see. With its incredible sensitivity to those wavelengths, we've been able to look back into the early universe in a way previous missions couldn't, see through dust and gas into the heart of star formation, and examine the composition of exoplanet atmospheres like never before," Clampin said.</p>

<p>Looking ahead, Clampin added, "Some of Webb's most exciting investigations will be the things we haven't even thought of yet."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uh2kf9_galaxies-merging-webb-telescope-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Rho Ophiuchi cloud complex seen in a composite of separate exposures acquired by Webb Telescope]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-presents-bill-to-get-millions-of-stray-dogs-off-the-streets-6093213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkey Presents Bill To Get Millions Of Stray Dogs Off The Streets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-presents-bill-to-get-millions-of-stray-dogs-off-the-streets-6093213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:53:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Turkey's ruling party presented a bill to parliament on Friday that aims to round up millions of stray dogs, a plan that has alarmed animal lovers who say a mass neutering campaign would be a better solution than locking dogs up in shelters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Turkey's ruling party presented a bill to parliament on Friday that aims to round up millions of stray dogs, a plan that has alarmed animal lovers who say a mass neutering campaign would be a better solution than locking dogs up in shelters.</p>

<p>Under the draft law proposed by the AK party, municipalities would be charged with getting strays off the street and into shelters until they are adopted. Aggressive dogs or any with untreatable diseases would be put down.</p>

<p>"Streets are not a space for dogs to live. But they have the right to live in more qualified shelters," Abdullah Guler, chair of the AK party's parliamentary group, told reporters.</p>

<p>An earlier version of the bill, which was leaked to Turkish media months ago, said all street dogs could be put down within a month but the provision was removed after public outcry, including from opposition politicians.</p>

<p>The population of street dogs in Turkey is estimated to be 4 million, and 2.5 million dogs have been neutered in the past 20 years by municipalities, according to the draft bill.</p>

<p>Under current legislation, municipalities have to neuter and vaccinate all street dogs and leave them where they were found following treatment.</p>

<p>There are currently 322 animal shelters with a capacity to host a total of 105,000 dogs, according to the bill.</p>

<p>The draft bill also requires all municipalities to spend at least 0.3% of their annual budget on animal rehabilitation services and building shelters.</p>

<p>Municipalities will be given time until 2028 to build new shelters and improve current shelters, the bill says.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/mnmn4gg_turkey-stray-dogs-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The population of street dogs in Turkey is estimated to be 4 million (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-must-comply-with-us-rights-agency-pregnancy-bias-probe-new-york-federal-judge-6093181]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Must Comply With US Rights Agency's Pregnancy Bias Probe: Judge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amazon-must-comply-with-us-rights-agency-pregnancy-bias-probe-new-york-federal-judge-6093181]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:48:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York federal judge has ordered Amazon.com to comply with a subpoena from a US civil rights agency investigating claims that the online retailer discriminated against pregnant warehouse workers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York federal judge has ordered Amazon.com to comply with a subpoena from a U.S. civil rights agency investigating claims that the online retailer discriminated against pregnant warehouse workers.</p>

<p>U.S. District Judge Lorna Schofield in Manhattan late Thursday rejected Amazon's claims that the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) subpoena was too broad and sought irrelevant information.</p>

<p>The EEOC is seeking data on requests that pregnant workers at five U.S. warehouses made for accommodations such as limits on heavy lifting and additional breaks, and whether Amazon granted or denied them.</p>

<p>The commission's probe was prompted by complaints from five women who say they faced pregnancy discrimination while working at Amazon warehouses in New Jersey, Connecticut, North Carolina, and California.</p>

<p>Amazon provided the EEOC with more than 200,000 pages of data in response to the subpoena, but not the specific information requested by the agency, according to court filings.</p>

<p>Schofield in her ruling said the information sought in the subpoenas was necessary for the EEOC to determine whether Amazon engaged in illegal discrimination. The judge gave Amazon until Aug. 9 to comply with the subpoena.</p>

<p>Amazon did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Friday. An EEOC spokesman declined to comment.</p>

<p>In 2022, a New York state agency filed an administrative complaint accusing Amazon of requiring pregnant and disabled warehouse workers to take unpaid leaves of absence, even if they were capable of working, instead of providing accommodations. That case is pending.</p>

<p>Amazon has denied wrongdoing and said it strives to support its workers, but acknowledged in a statement responding to the New York complaint that "we don't always get it right."</p>

<p>The EEOC launched its probe last year and issued a subpoena seeking five categories of information, including data on accommodations Amazon provided to warehouse workers with disabilities. At the time, federal law only required companies to provide the same accommodations to pregnant workers that they gave to employees with disabilities.</p>

<p>A law passed later last year mandates that employers accommodate workers' pregnancies regardless of how they treat workers with disabilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5if0puog_amazon-logo-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amazon has provided over 200,000 pages of data in response to the subpoena (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-population-to-peak-at-10-3-billion-in-2080s-un-report-6093168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Population To Peak At 10.3 Billion In 2080s: UN Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-population-to-peak-at-10-3-billion-in-2080s-un-report-6093168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:42:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Earth's population will peak in the mid-2080s at around 10.3 billion people, then drop slightly to a level much lower than anticipated a decade ago, the United Nations said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earth's population will peak in the mid-2080s at around 10.3 billion people, then drop slightly to a level much lower than anticipated a decade ago, the United Nations said.</p>

<p>The current population of 8.2 billion people will rise to that maximum over the next 60 years, then dip to 10.2 billion by the end of the century, says a report released Thursday entitled "World Population Prospects 2024."</p>

<p>It said the size of the world's population in 2100 will be six percent lower, or 700 million people fewer, than what was anticipated in June 2013.</p>

<p>"The demographic landscape has evolved greatly in recent years," said Li Junhua, UN Under-Secretary-General for Economic and Social Affairs.</p>

<p>He said the unexpected population peak stems from several factors that include lower levels of fertility in some of the world's largest countries, especially China.</p>

<p>He said this lower maximum will also come earlier than previously calculated and this is a hopeful sign as the world fights global warming: fewer humans accounting for less aggregate consumption would mean less pressure on the environment.</p>

<p>"However, slower population growth will not eliminate the need to reduce the average impact attributable to the activities of each individual person," this official said.</p>

<p>More than a quarter, or 28 percent, of the world's population, now lives in one of 63 countries or areas where the population has already peaked, including China, Russia, Japan, and Germany, the report said.</p>

<p>Nearly 50 other countries should join that group over the next 30 years, including Brazil, Iran, and Turkey.</p>

<p>However, population growth will continue in more than 120 countries beyond 2054. These include India, Indonesia, Nigeria, Pakistan, and the United States, according to the UN.</p>

<p>A rise in global life expectancy -- interrupted by the COVID-19 pandemic -- has resumed, with an average of 73.3 years of longevity in 2024. It will average 77.4 years in 2054.</p>

<p>So the world's population will get more and more gray. By the late 2070s, the number of people 65 or older is projected to be 2.2 billion, surpassing those under 18, the study predicts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/610ld0o_population-generic-pixabay_625x300_28_February_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The size of the world's population in 2100 will be six percent lower, the report said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rugby-players-charged-with-aggrevated-rape-in-argentina-6093121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 French Rugby Players Charged With "Aggravated" Rape In Argentina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-french-rugby-players-charged-with-aggrevated-rape-in-argentina-6093121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:37:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two French international rugby players were formally charged Friday with the aggravated rape of an Argentine woman after a night out following a match, according to a prosecution statement.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two French international rugby players were formally charged Friday with the aggravated rape of an Argentine woman after a night out following a match, according to a prosecution statement.</p>

<p>The accused, Hugo Auradou, 20, and Oscar Jegou, 21, chose "not to testify" at a hearing in the city of Mendoza, where the rape is alleged to have occurred after a game between France and Argentina on Saturday.</p>

<p>The prosecutor's office "proceeded to formally charge the two French citizens... for the crime of sexual assault with penetration aggravated by the participation of two people," said the statement, using the Argentine legal definition of rape.</p>

<p>The pair will remain in custody as further investigations are carried out. A request by the defense for them to be placed under house arrest "will be resolved in due course," the statement said.</p>

<p>The two men were arrested Monday in Buenos Aires after a 39-year-old woman accused them of raping her multiple times and beating her in a Mendoza hotel room after the match, part of a tour of South America by the French national squad.</p>

<p>The men deny the accusation, saying they had consensual sexual relations with the woman.</p>

<p>The players were transferred Thursday by car from Interpol's Buenos Aires headquarters to Mendoza, some 1,000 kilometers west (620 miles).</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the 39-year-old woman's lawyer, Natacha Romano, said her client was hospitalized Thursday after feeling ill emotionally and physically "because of everything that happened."</p>

<p>Psychologist Nicolas Yungman, who was not treating the woman, told local media that her symptoms, as described, could be indicative of post-traumatic stress disorder.</p>

<p>The woman will receive treatment at a health facility for 24 to 48 hours, Romano said.</p>

<p><strong>Up To 20 Years In Jail</strong></p>

<p>If found guilty, the players face between eight and 20 years in prison.</p>

<p>Defense attorney Romano told AFP on Wednesday her client had suffered "fierce" violence at the hands of her assailants in a hotel room, with injuries to her face, back, breasts, legs and ribs as well as various bite and scratch marks.</p>

<p>The woman claims to have been raped "at least six times" by one of the men and once by the other, according to the lawyer.</p>

<p>She allegedly tried to escape several times.</p>

<p>The attack allegedly took place Saturday night at the Diplomatic Hotel in Mendoza, where France's players and staff were staying after beating Argentina.</p>

<p>Romano told AFP the woman had gone with one of the men from a nightclub to a hotel room, where she alleges she was held against her will and abused for several hours.</p>

<p>"The violence was fierce," said Romano. "There is more than one crime to investigate."</p>

<p>Lawyer Rafael Cuneo Libarona, who represents the players, arrived in Mendoza on Wednesday and said "sexual relations" had been "consensual."</p>

<p>"There are witnesses who saw her leave (the hotel). There are cameras that saw her leave. Apparently no injuries are seen in the footage," Libarona -- who is the brother of Justice Minister Mariano Cuneo Libarona -- told journalists.</p>

<p>Romano told AFP "the overwhelming proof that there was no consent is the victim's body" and the wounds she bears.</p>

<p>French Rugby Federation (FFR) president Florian Grill, who is in Argentina, told AFP the players have "a quite different version" of events to that of the woman, with "a lot of inconsistencies."</p>

<p>"We are not judges. We are not investigators. But we think that the Argentine justice system should look at the case very quickly," he said.</p>

<p>Aradou and Jegou have been replaced by lock Mickael Guillard and flanker Judicael Cancoriet for Saturday's second match against Argentina in Buenos Aires.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/oshohg3c_arrest-generic_625x300_17_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pair will remain in custody as further investigations are carried out (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-joe-biden-hits-campaign-trail-as-calls-to-quit-grow-stronger-6093088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Defiant Joe Biden Hits Campaign Trail As Calls To Quit Grow Stronger]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/defiant-joe-biden-hits-campaign-trail-as-calls-to-quit-grow-stronger-6093088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 22:30:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden returns to the campaign trail Friday, pushing ahead with his reelection bid after a mixed performance at a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden returns to the campaign trail Friday, pushing ahead with his reelection bid after a mixed performance at a major news conference failed to silence calls for him to quit.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old will give a speech bashing rival Donald Trump in Detroit in the rust-belt state of Michigan, a crucial battleground state that the Democrat must win in November's election.</p>

<p>A defiant Biden insisted in a pivotal appearance at a NATO summit on Thursday that he would run again, and win -- despite concerns about his age and health following a disastrous debate performance two weeks ago.</p>

<p>But a series of gaffes, including referring to Vice President Kamala Harris as "Vice President Trump," kept Biden's fitness for a second term under the microscope.</p>

<p>The top Democrat in the House of Representatives, Hakeem Jeffries, said he had met with Biden late Thursday, as the number of members calling on the president to step aside rose to 20.</p>

<p>Jeffries said he and Biden "expressed the full breadth of insight, heartfelt perspectives, and conclusions about the path forward" but did not give further details.</p>

<p>The president has faced a steady drumbeat of Democrats calling for him to abandon his 2024 candidacy since the June 27 debate, during which Biden often lost his train of thought and appeared tired.</p>

<p>But Biden has obstinately dug in and insists that he can convince voters to back him despite most polls showing him trailing the criminally convicted, twice-impeached Trump.</p>

<p><strong>"Most Qualified"</strong></p>

<p>The campaign event in Detroit is his fourth trip this year to the state, part of the industrial "blue wall" along with Wisconsin and Pennsylvania that were key to his 2020 win against his rival.</p>

<p>Biden's speech is expected to focus on "Project 2025", a blueprint by hardline conservatives for the first days of a Trump term that Democrats have pinned on the former president, despite the 78-year-old's denials.</p>

<p>The press conference on Thursday appeared to buy Biden some time even if it was far from a knockout blow, with three more lawmakers urging him to quit just minutes after it finished.</p>

<p>Biden said he was the "most qualified person to run for president," rejecting calls for him to step aside before the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>He acknowledged he had to "allay fears" in the Democratic party and should "pace myself a little more" after blaming jet lag and cold for his stumbling debate performance.</p>

<p>Biden also fielded a series of foreign and domestic policy questions with detailed if meandering answers and relatively few slip-ups, though he did mix up Europe and Asia.</p>

<p>But there were damaging moments on Thursday, with the Trump-Harris mixup and an earlier gaffe at the NATO summit in which he introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as Russian strongman Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>The concerns over Biden are also affecting Democratic donors, with Hollywood star and high-profile supporter George Clooney calling on Biden to step aside on Wednesday.</p>

<p>A number of other key donors have told the largest Biden campaign fund that around $90 million in pledged donations is on hold if he carries on running, the New York Times reported on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pn27j9kg_joe-biden-_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden insists that he can convince voters to back him (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-prisoners-to-be-released-early-to-ease-crowding-in-uk-jails-6092566]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Of Prisoners To Be Released Early To Ease Crowding In UK Jails]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-of-prisoners-to-be-released-early-to-ease-crowding-in-uk-jails-6092566]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 21:03:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of prisoners are to be released early starting September to prevent the "collapse" of the prison system, the UK's new justice minister announced on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of prisoners are to be released early starting September to prevent the "collapse" of the prison system, the UK's new justice minister announced on Friday.</p>

<p>Shabana Mahmood said failure to do so risked the "total breakdown of law and order", with just 700 places left for men, and jails operating at 99 percent capacity since 2023.</p>

<p>England and Wales have the highest per capita prison population in Western Europe.</p>

<p>The release initiative would not apply to violent offenders serving more than four years, sex offenders, and those in prison for domestic abuse offences as well as those on life sentences.</p>

<p>The chief inspector of prisons, Charlie Taylor, said this week that urgent action was required, as prisons were at "breaking point".</p>

<p>Mahmood, appointed last week after Labour's general election win, warned in dramatic language that if prisons ran out of cell space, there could be "van-loads of dangerous people circling the country with nowhere to go".</p>

<p>"With officers unable to act, criminals could do whatever they want, without consequence. We could see looters running amok, smashing in windows, robbing shops, and setting neighbourhoods alight," she said in a speech at a prison.</p>

<p>"In short, if we fail to act now, we face the collapse of the criminal justice system. And a total breakdown of law and order."</p>

<p>Under the plans, prisoners who are eligible for automatic release after serving half their sentence will be freed earlier than normal.</p>

<p>The plans involve a temporary reduction of how long prisoners must serve behind bars, from 50 percent to 40 percent of their sentence.</p>

<p>The releases will start in September to give the Prison and Probation Service time to plan.</p>

<p>The total number of prisoners hit over 87,505 on Friday -- of whom over 83,800 were men -- leaving just 1,451 spaces available, official figures showed.</p>

<p>Since the start of 2023, the average occupancy rate in men's prisons had "routinely been higher than 99 percent", according to the Ministry of Justice.</p>

<p>Officials say the prison system needs a buffer of around 1,425 cell spaces in men's prisons at all times to deal with sudden influxes of inmates.</p>

<p>Six new prisons to create an extra 20,000 places are being built.</p>

<p>The Prison Governors' Association (PGA) said it welcomed the speed of the new measures while demanding a "full review" and that "the public must never be placed in this position again".</p>

<p>PGA chairman Mark Fairhurst said the measures would free up around 4,500-5,000 more spaces and give prisons around 12 to 18 months before further steps would be needed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/c9cdh8ao_us-prison-generic-us-jail-generic-getty_625x300_24_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[England and Wales have the highest per capita prison population in Western Europe (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-sister-princess-anne-resumes-public-duties-after-hospitalisation-6092511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles III's Sister Anne Resumes Public Duties After Hospitalisation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-iii-sister-princess-anne-resumes-public-duties-after-hospitalisation-6092511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:56:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Princess Anne, the sister of British head of state King Charles III, returned to public duties Friday, weeks after she was treated in hospital after being struck by a horse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Princess Anne, the sister of British head of state King Charles III, returned to public duties Friday, weeks after she was treated in hospital after being struck by a horse.</p>

<p>Anne, 73, presented awards and met winners at a charity horseriding event in Gloucestershire, southwestern England, in a reported phased return to public appearances.</p>

<p>The Princess Royal, as she is also known, suffered concussion and minor head injuries at her Gatcombe Park estate in Gloucestershire in late June and spent five nights in hospital in Bristol.</p>

<p>She has since been recovering at her home on the sprawling estate and following standard concussion protocols.</p>

<p>It is believed she was struck by a horse as she was walking within the protected perimeter of its grounds, which hosts equestrian events.</p>

<p>The princess's medical team said at the time her injuries were consistent with a potential impact from a horse's head or legs.</p>

<p>She is a skilled horsewoman who competed at the 1976 Montreal Olympics and is the mother of British rider Zara Tindall, who won eventing team silver at the 2012 London Olympics.</p>

<p>Anne has stepped in to represent Charles while he postponed public engagements during his cancer treatment, and rode at his official birthday parade last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9rhec228_princess-anne-_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Princess Anne had suffered concussion and minor head injuries last month (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-developing-dislike-button-for-downvoting-replies-report-6088984]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X Developing 'Dislike' Button For Downvoting Replies: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-developing-dislike-button-for-downvoting-replies-report-6088984]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:33:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk-run X is developing a downvoting feature which will be used to improve the ranking of replies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk-run X is developing a downvoting feature which will be used to improve the ranking of replies.</p>

<p>While the company hasn't announced its plans officially, recent findings suggest that the 'downvote' feature might actually resemble a 'dislike' button instead of a Reddit-style downvote icon, reports TechCrunch.</p>

<p>As per code references found in the X iOS app show a button that seems like a broken heart icon next to the microblogging platform's heart-shaped 'like' button as well as direct references to a 'downvote' feature.</p>

<p>The feature was tested by the company in 2021, ahead of Elon Musk's acquisition.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, reverse engineer Aaron Perris, @aaronp613 on X, discovered references in X's iOS app that indicated a downvote feature that appeared to be in development.</p>

<p>Now, he has found more image files in the iOS app that show the button could be styled as a broken heart as well as more direct references to the feature itself, the report mentioned.</p>

<p>Initially, the company had tested both upvoting and downvoting buttons across all posts. However, the latest tests show that X is only considering allowing downvotes on replies.</p>

<p>In June, Musk confirmed the rollout of a new feature that will hide all likes by default for X users.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kn2mlivo_elon-musk-with-x-logo-getty-images_625x300_12_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The feature was tested by the company in 2021, ahead of Elon Musk's acquisition.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oil-tanker-seized-by-iran-in-2023-bound-for-oman-port-shows-tracking-data-6092319]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oil Tanker Seized By Iran In 2023 Bound For Oman Port: Tracking Data]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oil-tanker-seized-by-iran-in-2023-bound-for-oman-port-shows-tracking-data-6092319]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 20:25:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chevron-chartered oil tanker seized by Iran more than a year ago is heading toward the Sohar port in Oman, LSEG ship tracking data showed on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chevron-chartered oil tanker seized by Iran more than a year ago is heading toward the Sohar port in Oman, LSEG ship tracking data showed on Friday.</p>

<p>On Thursday, ship tracking data showed the vessel moving to international waters, with the destination showing as Khor Fakkan in the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>The Marshall Islands-flagged Advantage Sweet was boarded by Iran's military in the Gulf of Oman in April 2023 after an alleged collision with an Iranian boat.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from Chevron.</p>

<p>The US State Department called in March for the immediate release of the tanker.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/shjh31to_advantage-sweet-oil-tanker-reuters_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marshall Islands-flagged oil tanker Advantage Sweet had been chartered by oil major Chevron]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-first-breast-milk-bank-in-karachi-shuts-after-clerics-deem-it-un-islamic-6092125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak's First Breast Milk Bank Shuts After Clerics Deem It "Un-Islamic"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-first-breast-milk-bank-in-karachi-shuts-after-clerics-deem-it-un-islamic-6092125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:58:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A hospital that launched the first breast milk bank for premature babies in Pakistan is negotiating for it to be reopened after clerics deemed it un-Islamic, doctors and the national Islamic council said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A hospital that launched the first breast milk bank for premature babies in Pakistan is negotiating for it to be reopened after clerics deemed it un-Islamic, doctors and the national Islamic council said Friday.</p>

<p>The milk bank in Karachi received religious approval in December from a provincial Islamic seminary, but that approval was withdrawn almost as soon as the facility opened in June, forcing it to shut.</p>

<p>"Breast milk is the only way to improve the chances of the survival of premature babies," said Jamal Raza, a doctor and the executive director of the Sindh Institute of Child Health and Neonatology hospital, where the bank was set up.</p>

<p>"People have no idea what this is about. Only premature babies were going to be given this milk," Raza added.</p>

<p>The facility was intended to help premature babies survive in a country where the neonatal mortality rate is 39 deaths per 1,000 live births, according to the UN children's agency -- one of the highest in South Asia.</p>

<p>A religious edict, or fatwa, approving the facility was issued in December 2023 by Jamia Darul Uloom, an Islamic advisory body in the province.</p>

<p>However, the government's National Council of Islamic Ideology later questioned whether it risked breaking Islamic codes on kinship, which dictate that husband and wife cannot be breastfed by the same woman.</p>

<p>"The child's family must know who the donors are to not complicate the issue of future marriages between such families," the head of research at the council, Inamullah, who goes by one name, told AFP</p>

<p>"We are confident that the outcome will be favourable."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qrhvq5mo_pakistan-breast-milk-bank-facebook_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The facility was intended to help premature babies survive]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gavin-plumb-arrested-after-undercover-us-cop-exposed-plot-to-rape-kill-uk-tv-star-holly-willoughby-6091998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Arrested After Undercover US Cop Exposed Plot To Rape, Kill UK TV Star]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gavin-plumb-arrested-after-undercover-us-cop-exposed-plot-to-rape-kill-uk-tv-star-holly-willoughby-6091998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:36:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A would-be attacker who planned to kidnap, rape, and murder one of the UK's top celebrities was on Friday given a life sentence with a minimum jail term of 15 years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A would-be attacker who planned to kidnap, rape, and murder one of the UK's top celebrities was on Friday given a life sentence with a minimum jail term of 15 years.</p>

<p>Gavin Plumb, 37, was last week found guilty of planning to "ambush" television presenter Holly Willoughby, 43, at her home, before taking her to a dungeon-type room.</p>

<p>He was caught after a US undercover police officer infiltrated an online group and forwarded Plumb's posts to the FBI.</p>

<p>US law enforcement officers then handed the evidence to UK police, who raided Plumb's home in Harlow, southeast England. They found an "abduction kit", which included cable ties and chloroform.</p>

<p>Willoughby, a daytime television presenter described by Judge Edward Murray as a "well-known and well-loved public figure", said the case had had a "life-changing" impact, according to a summary of her victim impact statement read in court.</p>

<p>"It is clear, the prosecution submits, ... that the extent of the shock and fear caused by this offending has been impossible to convey," said prosecutor Alison Morgan.</p>

<p>Morgan also said the media had not reported the full extent of his plans as they were "so depraved and vile", but the court was told that Plumb had intended to harm Willoughby's husband and children.</p>

<p>Plumb, who has a string of previous convictions relating to kidnapping and false imprisonment, told the undercover police officer online that he planned to slit Willoughby's throat as he tried to convince him to join in the plot, the court heard.</p>

<p>His legal team said that he "worshipped and was obsessed" with Willoughby and was "devastated to be the cause of such pain to her".</p>

<p>Nicola Rice, a specialist prosecutor with the Crown Prosecution Service, called Plumb "a dangerous man who plotted unspeakable violence against one of the nation's most familiar faces.</p>

<p>"Despite his attempts to pass himself off as a harmless fantasist, the prosecution persuaded the jury that Plumb posed a very real threat," she added.</p>

<p>In England and Wales, life imprisonment is a sentence that lasts until a prisoner dies, but in most cases, the judge sets a minimum term, after which they become eligible for parole.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kuvq9eeg_holly-willoughby_625x300_25_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An "abduction kit" was found at the home of the man (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-as-russian-regional-airliner-crashes-near-moscow-report-6091810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed As Russian Regional Airliner Crashes Near Moscow: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-as-russian-regional-airliner-crashes-near-moscow-report-6091810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 19:09:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian regional airliner carrying three crew members crashed in a forested area near Moscow on Friday, killing all on board, Russian news agencies reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian regional airliner carrying three crew members crashed in a forested area near Moscow on Friday, killing all on board, Russian news agencies reported.</p>

<p>The plane, a Russian-designed Superjet 100, was carrying out a test flight after undergoing scheduled repairs and crashed a little over an hour after taking off, the TASS news agency said.</p>

<p>"According to preliminary information, three pilots were killed. All those on board," emergency services were quoted as saying by the agency.</p>

<p>The plane was headed to Moscow's Vnukovo airport, according to state media.</p>

<p>It crashed in a forested area of the Kolomensky District, a municipality about 60 kilometres (37 miles) southeast of the capital, the RIA news agency reported.</p>

<p>A plume of grey smoke could be seen rising from the crash site in photos and videos shared on social media.</p>

<p>Russian investigators have opened a criminal probe into the crash, according to the RIA news agency.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/e7rcvtag_superjet-100-afp_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plane was headed to Moscow's Vnukovo airport, Russia's state media said (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-political-candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-asks-viewers-if-shes-sexy-6091632]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Political Candidate Strips In Video, Asks Viewers If She's ''Sexy'']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japanese-political-candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-asks-viewers-if-shes-sexy-6091632]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:46:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the footage, Ms Uchino is shown seated at a table wearing a button-up shirt as she addresses Japanese voters in an anime-style voice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A female political candidate in Tokyo's gubernatorial election has stirred controversy after she stripped herself on the national television broadcast. In a bizarre video promoting her campaign,&nbsp;Airi Uchino of the NHK Party stripped down to a tube top and asked viewers if she was "sexy" enough to win votes, the&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/11/world-news/candidate-strips-in-video-to-win-votes-in-tokyo-gubernatorial-race/"><em>New York Post</em> </a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the footage, Ms&nbsp;Uchino is shown seated at a table wearing a button-up shirt as she addresses Japanese voters in an anime-style voice. She then strips down to a revealing tube top, striking a pose that suggests she is topless.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''I'm so cute; please watch my campaign broadcast. Do you think I'm sexy?'', she says in the video that has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/mrjeffu/status/1806463678247830011">gone viral on X.&nbsp;</a>She further invited viewers to add her on the messaging app LINE, promising to respond to each message personally and&nbsp;delivered the rest of her speech in a nude-coloured tube top.</p>

<p>This political stunt has raised eyebrows, with many criticising her for objectifying herself and prioritising her physical appearance over policy and leadership qualities. Many said that they felt embarrassed, while some questioned how such a spectacle could have been permitted.</p>

<p>One user wrote, ''While it is true that people strive to stand out, and our society's obsession with appearances often rewards outlandish behaviour, nevertheless, individuals who lack substance will inevitably be unmasked by the passage of time.''</p>

<p>Another commented, ''At this point, they should change the rules… the race is turning into a farce and distracting people from the real issues. Democracy and all but this is not it.'' A third said, ''No matter how much you talk about freedom of speech in elections, this goes against public welfare.''</p>

<p>Seems her unconventional approach didn't work as&nbsp;Yuriko Koike, 71, secured a third consecutive four-year term in the Tokyo gubernatorial election that was held on July 7, according to&nbsp;<em><a href="https://mainichi.jp/english/articles/20240707/p2g/00m/0na/039000c" target="_blank">Mainichi</a>.&nbsp;</em>Ms Koike became Tokyo's first female governor in 2016 and won her second term in 2020.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6sqn3rd8_airi-uchino_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This unconventional approach has raised eyebrows, with many criticizing her.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pushpa-kamal-dahal-prachanda-firebrand-nepal-maoist-turned-pm-forced-out-by-ally-6091624]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Prachanda": Firebrand Nepal Maoist Turned PM Forced Out By Ally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pushpa-kamal-dahal-prachanda-firebrand-nepal-maoist-turned-pm-forced-out-by-ally-6091624]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 18:44:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Pushpa Kamal Dahal lived in seclusion directing Nepal's guerrilla war but emerged from the jungle to lead the Himalayan republic when his cadres laid down their arms and joined mainstream politics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Pushpa Kamal Dahal lived in seclusion directing Nepal's guerrilla war but emerged from the jungle to lead the Himalayan republic when his cadres laid down their arms and joined mainstream politics.</p>

<p>Still widely known by his nom de guerre Prachanda ("The Fierce One"), Dahal on Friday lost a parliamentary vote of confidence that will force him to relinquish the nation's revolving door premiership for the third time.</p>

<p>The civil war he launched in 1996 drew disaffected Nepalis into his Maoist rebellion with a rousing call to end centuries of feudal inequality, ultimately claiming more than 17,000 lives and leaving thousands more still missing to this day.</p>

<p>With a peace settlement that abolished Nepal's monarchy and brought the Maoists into government, Dahal was able to claim victory when the conflict ended a decade later.</p>

<p>"We believe that the country has adopted the agenda of the Maoists," he said in a 2022 interview with local broadcaster Kantipur.</p>

<p>Dahal was born into a high-caste Hindu family in 1954 but grew up in the poverty endemic to rural Nepal at the time, and spent his childhood herding goats and buffalo.</p>

<p>The extreme privation of his childhood spurred an interest in far-left ideology and he joined a communist party in 1980 at the age of 25.</p>

<p>He worked as a teacher but gradually became convinced that an armed insurgency was the only way to bring radical change to one of the world's poorest countries.</p>

<p>Through the war, he was a mysterious figure, anonymous to the public except for his wartime alias, until he emerged in 2006 to address his cadres as peace talks began.</p>

<p>Dahal steered his party to an unexpected victory in elections two years later but resigned after nine months following a deadlock over attempts to integrate former Maoist fighters into the army.</p>

<p>He has since gone on to serve as prime minister two more times, including another administration that lasted less than a year and his current stint of barely 18 months -- both common lengths of tenure under the ever-shifting alliances of Nepal's parliament.</p>

<p><strong>"Abandoning Rank And File"</strong></p>

<p>Dahal and his party colleagues credit the war for increasing the political representation of marginalised groups and improving their livelihoods.</p>

<p>He has been branded a dynamic and charismatic leader for his ability to navigate the choppy waters of Nepalese politics.</p>

<p>However, critics say he is an opportunist who has formed alliances with various parties to suit his own personal interests.</p>

<p>Since joining parliament he has come under fire for his lavish lifestyle, notably when it emerged that he had rented a sprawling luxurious estate in Kathmandu.</p>

<p>Many former guerrillas have quit the party, accusing Dahal and other leaders of betraying their sacrifices.</p>

<p>Two deputy leaders seen as likely successors were among those to depart, helping Dahal consolidate power.</p>

<p>Critics also accused him of fostering a culture of nepotism in the party by promoting his daughters and relatives.</p>

<p>Aditya Adhikari, an author who has written on the Maoist movement, said in 2016 that Dahal began to be seen after the war as someone attracted not just to "money and power".</p>

<p>"But also to people outside the movement who were rich and powerful, abandoning the rank and file and alienating his base."</p>

<p>Dahal married his wife Sita when the pair were still teenagers and she was by his side during the civil war, but little else is publicly known about her life before the conflict's end.</p>

<p>She died in 2023 after a long illness. The couple had four children, two of whom also died.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-03/pushpa-kamal-dahal-prachanda_650x400_51489649865.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The extreme privation of his childhood spurred Prachanda's interest in far-left ideology (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-pm-loses-vote-of-confidence-in-parliament-6091107]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nepal PM Loses Vote Of Confidence In Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nepal-pm-loses-vote-of-confidence-in-parliament-6091107]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 17:38:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nepal Prime Minister Pushpa Kamal Dahal 'Prachanda' on Friday lost a vote of confidence in Parliament after the Communist Party of Nepal-Unified Marxist Leninist (CPN-UML) withdrew its support for his government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nepal Prime Minister Pushpa Kamal Dahal 'Prachanda' on Friday lost a vote of confidence in Parliament after the Communist Party of Nepal-Unified Marxist Leninist (CPN-UML) withdrew its support for his government.</p>

<p>Prachanda, 69, received 63 votes in the 275-member House of Representatives (HoR). There were 194 votes against the motion.</p>

<p>At least 138 votes are needed to win the vote of trust.</p>

<p>Prachanda has survived four trust votes since he assumed the post on December 25, 2022.</p>

<p>Former prime minister K P Sharma Oli-led CPN-UML withdrew support from the Prachanda-led government last week after inking a power-sharing deal with the largest party in the House - Nepali Congress.</p>

<p>Nepali Congress President Sher Bahadur Deuba has already endorsed Oli as the next prime minister.</p>

<p>The Nepali Congress has 89 seats in the HoR, while CPN-UML has 78 seats. Their combined strength of 167 is much more than the 138 required for a majority in the lower house</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/b9pqo8g8_nepal-pm-pushpa-kamal-dahal-prachanda-ani_625x300_06_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 138 votes are needed to win the vote of trust. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/12-pilot-whales-euthanised-after-mass-stranding-on-scotland-beach-6090988]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[12 Pilot Whales Euthanised After Mass Stranding On Scotland Beach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/12-pilot-whales-euthanised-after-mass-stranding-on-scotland-beach-6090988]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 17:22:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A dozen whales that survived a mass stranding this week off the northeast coast of Scotland had to be put down, a British marine life rescue charity has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A dozen whales that survived a mass stranding this week off the northeast coast of Scotland had to be put down, a British marine life rescue charity has said.</p>

<p>Seventy-seven long-finned pilot whales were found washed ashore on Thursday, with 65 already dead, by the British Divers Marine Life Rescue (BDMLR) in the Sanday island of Scotland's Orkney archipelago.</p>

<p>"Sadly the remaining 12 pilot whales have been euthanised due to their condition deteriorating from the many hours they have spent stranded on the beach", the BDMLR said in a statement late Thursday.</p>

<p>Having been at the beach for a long time led to "crush injury from their own weight and the high likelihood that they have inhaled water with the incoming tide".</p>

<p>They had also sunk deeper into the sand when the tide washed over them and were unable to refloat themselves, the charity added.</p>

<p>"There are no obvious indications as to why they all stranded," the statement said, adding that the organisation would try to recover as many of the whales as possible for post-mortem examinations.</p>

<p>When the BDMLR initially found the whales after a report early on Thursday, they had already been stranded for several hours.</p>

<p>Such mass strandings are not uncommon among pilot whales who tend to travel in tightly-knit groups.</p>

<p>"This is definitely one of the larger mass strandings but not necessarily the largest", BDMLR told AFP.</p>

<p>Last year, 55 pilot whales washed ashore on the island of Lewis, off northwest Scotland.</p>

<p>Much bigger strandings have taken place in other parts of the world, with the largest in parts of New Zealand and Australia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/doadcf_pilot-whales_625x300_25_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[77 long-finned pilot whales were found washed ashore on an island of Scotland. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-extends-compulsory-military-service-for-men-to-36-months-report-6090607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Extends Compulsory Military Service For Men To 36 Months: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-extends-compulsory-military-service-for-men-to-36-months-report-6090607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:34:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli government's security cabinet has approved a plan to extend compulsory military service for men to 36 months from the current 32 months, Israel's Ynet news outlet reported on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli government's security cabinet has approved a plan to extend compulsory military service for men to 36 months from the current 32 months, Israel's Ynet news outlet reported on Friday.</p>

<p>The 36-month rule will stay in force for the next eight years, Ynet reported, after a meeting of the security cabinet that took place late on Thursday.</p>

<p>The measure is likely to be submitted to a vote in a meeting of the full cabinet on Sunday, it said.</p>

<p>Israel's military commanders have said they need to boost manpower so they can sustain the war with the Hamas terrorist group in Gaza and a confrontation with the Lebanon-based Hezbollah militia.</p>

<p>In a separate initiative, Israel is planning to send draft notices to thousands of ultra-Orthodox seminary students who were previously exempt from military service.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/iveite1g_israel-army-reuters-_625x300_15_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 36-month rule will stay in force for the next eight years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-boy-arrested-after-uk-gurdwara-attack-with-bladed-weapon-cops-6090560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17-Year-Old Boy Arrested After UK Gurdwara Attack With Bladed Weapon: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-boy-arrested-after-uk-gurdwara-attack-with-bladed-weapon-cops-6090560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:29:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old boy remains in custody after two women were injured in an incident involving a "bladed weapon" at a gurdwara in Kent, south-east England, local police said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old boy remains in custody after two women were injured in an incident involving a "bladed weapon" at a gurdwara in Kent, south-east England, local police said on Friday.</p>

<p>Kent Police said its officers were called to the Siri Guru Nanak Darbar Gurdwara in Gravesend on Thursday evening to investigate reports that a male had entered the place of worship and attempted to assault those inside.</p>

<p>"It was reported that a male had entered the location and attempted to assault those in attendance whilst armed with a bladed weapon. Nobody was seriously injured during the incident but two women required medical attention for cuts and bruises," Kent Police said in a statement.</p>

<p>The officers arrested the teenage boy on suspicion of attempted murder and a religiously aggravated public order offence and also recovered the bladed weapon from the scene. The police have described it as an "isolated incident" and said that nobody else is currently being sought in connection with their investigation into the attack.</p>

<p>"We understand the community's concerns in relation to the events at the gurdwara, however we are treating it as an isolated incident," said Detective Superintendent Ian Dyball of Kent Police.</p>

<p>"Patrols will remain in the area for reassurance and we thank the community for their ongoing support and assistance," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/ima4e49o_uk-police_625x300_14_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The officers arrested the teenage boy on suspicion of attempted murder. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/hugs-aside-how-much-do-india-and-russia-mean-to-each-other-today-6090515]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Hugs Aside, This Is How Much India And Russia Really Mean To Each Other]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/hugs-aside-how-much-do-india-and-russia-mean-to-each-other-today-6090515]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 16:21:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[How much do Russia and India matter to each other today? This question can be answered only after stripping it of all the romanticism defining the India-Russia relationship.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5lqdv0ro_modi-putin_625x300_12_July_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Everyone loves a good host. Everyone loves a powerful host. Everyone loves a host who gives guided tours.</p>

<p>In this limited regard, the Prime Minister of India is no different from this author. Both are cherished guests in their gracious hosts' respective homes, and this summer sojourn is loaded with meaning for all and sundry. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-russia-sign-9-agreements-on-trade-climate-during-pm-modis-moscow-visit-6070175">Prime Minister Narendra Modi's Moscow visits</a>, six so far, always generate interest across global capitals. The latest two-day visit is no exception.</p>

<h2><strong>Beyond The Romanticism</strong></h2>

<p>Once we are done decoding the symbolism behind the Putin-Modi "bear hug" and the host driving his Indian counterpart in an electric car, it needs to come down to the brass tacks. How much do Russia and India matter to each other today? This question can be answered only after stripping it of all the romanticism defining the India-Russia relationship.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Modi's Putin meeting has happened at an interesting juncture in history for both the leaders. While the Indian Prime Minister has just started his consecutive third term with a much smaller mandate than his previous two stints, Putin's domestic base is shaky as usual. The Western world, however, continues to view them critically.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/russia-visit-an-emphatic-foreign-policy-statement-from-modi-3-0-6083426">Also Read | Russia Visit: An Emphatic Foreign Policy Statement From Modi 3.0</a></strong></p>

<p>The Western capitals are already abuzz with how India has flouted the 'rules' to pursue its own interests. Much like China. Or Iran. Or other countries challenging the West's diktats to isolate Putin by continuing their economic and diplomatic relations with Russia. For India, the biggest challenge is to set itself apart from the so-called 'untouchables'. But how does India do it when it already has the status of being the second-largest importer of Russian oil? Modi is now the recipient of the Russian government's highest civilian honour, the Order of St. Andrew. The timing of this trip has been a bit tricky for Modi, for sure, with Russia bombing a children's hospital in Ukraine on the same day. India can choose to ignore Ukraine's president, Volodymyr Zelenskyy, sharing his disappointment, but what is this Russian friendship worth to India today, if it only comes with expressions of reproach and disappointment from friends?</p>

<h2><strong>Friends And Enemies</strong></h2>

<p>India has a China issue. Not a problem as the world would want India to believe, but an issue - a neighbourhood issue. Russia's alleged no-limits friendship with China is India's ace in this geopolitical game. China does not care for its enemies' threats; it may listen to its friends, now scattered far and few between. India knows well to lean on such friends. New Delhi's ideological flexibility allows it to do so.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The international system is anarchic. The most basic motive driving states is survival," says the propounder of the theory of offensive realism, John Mearsheimer. India carries out its offensive with charm. 'Strategic autonomy' is a theoretical concept for the West, if it applies to countries it doesn't think of as deserving of the said autonomy. India has been able to survive as a functioning democracy for more than seven decades, in part, because of its strategic autonomy. Not descending into the nadir of foreign-aided civil wars, coups, and constitutional chaos like its neighbours has been India's biggest achievement since independence.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Modi's Card In Moscow</strong></h2>

<p>The deterioration of US-China relations in the aftermath of the Tiananmen Square incident in 1989 coincided with the beginning of the rise of India and China as economic powers to reckon with. The economic reforms of the early 1990s paved the way for India's quick, and resilient, rise. Whether we could have done better or what more could have been done to keep the momentum going is another debate altogether. How China surpassed India significantly is also not germane to the issue at hand. What is, indeed, important is India's present stance as an important regional player. And this is the card that Modi carried to Moscow.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modi-hails-russia-as-indias-all-weather-friend-lauds-vladimir-putins-leadership-6066720">Also Read |&nbsp;PM Modi Hails Russia As India's "All-Weather Friend", Lauds Putin's Leadership</a></strong></p>

<p>Putin is relying on its space and nuclear power to not only assert its regional dominance but also consolidate its position in the global world order. India, too, has made significant strides in these areas. India needs nuclear tech, Russia is willing to sell it. The calculation is simple. The six nuclear plants under discussion, the establishment of defence production facilities, military cooperation, the development of national payment systems to discard the dollar dependence, and an unending supply of Russian oil to fuel India's infrastructure dreams are important for both Moscow and New Delhi. And they are equally important for policymakers and analysts in the West. With a freshly renewed friendship with Russia, where can India be pegged in the new geopolitical order?&nbsp;</p>

<p>Modi's visit to Moscow has been undertaken from a position of power. It is neither a hollow gesture of sanctimony nor should it be seen as escapism. No wonder it has irked the many power centres in the US and Europe. But India has done nothing new or extraordinary or even in contravention of the country's long-held foreign policy. New Delhi remains non-aligned. But it's also beginning to look out for itself.&nbsp;</p>

<p>And good friends and hosts enable anyone attempting to do so.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Nishtha Gautam is a Delhi-based author and academic.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eine8298_modi-putin_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>