<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:50:28 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-thanks-biden-for-pledge-of-smooth-power-transfer-at-white-house-7012701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Power Transition Will Be "As Smooth As You Can Get", Says Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-thanks-biden-for-pledge-of-smooth-power-transfer-at-white-house-7012701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:16:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump thanked President Joe Biden for pledging a smooth transfer of power as the victorious Republican made a historic return visit to the White House on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump thanked President Joe Biden for pledging a smooth transfer of power as the victorious Republican made a historic return visit to the White House on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Politics is tough, and in many cases it's not a very nice world. It is a nice world today and I appreciate it very much," Trump said after the two men shook hands in the Oval Office.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, added that the transition would be "smooth as you can get."</p>

<p>Biden greeted Trump in front of a roaring fire, offering him congratulations and saying: "Welcome back."</p>

<p>The 81-year-old Biden invited his sworn rival to the White House -- despite the fact that Trump, who refused to admit his 2020 election loss, never afforded Biden the same courtesy.</p>

<p>Biden, who dropped out of the election in July but saw his successor Kamala Harris lose to Trump last week, said he was "looking forward to having a smooth transition."</p>

<p>"We'll do everything we can to make sure you're accommodated, (have) what you need," he told Trump.</p>

<p><strong>Triumphant Trump&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Their talks after the public handshake may have been a bitter pill to swallow for Biden, who branded Trump a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>Biden was expected to push during the meeting for Trump to continue US support for Ukraine's fight against Russia, which the Republican has called into question.</p>

<p>Ahead of the White House visit, Trump addressed Republicans from the House of Representatives at a Washington hotel near the Capitol, which a mob of his supporters marched in 2021 to try to reverse his election loss.</p>

<p>An ebullient Trump suggested that he could even be open to a third term in office -- which would violate the US constitution.</p>

<p>"I suspect I won't be running again unless you say, 'He's good, we got to figure something else,'" he said, drawing some laughter.</p>

<p>Trump's party looks set to take both chambers of Congress and consolidate his extraordinary comeback.</p>

<p>He was accompanied at the meeting with Republicans by the world's richest man Elon Musk, whom he named on Tuesday as head of a new group aimed at slashing government spending.</p>

<p>Trump has launched a flurry of nominations as he moves swiftly to name his administration.</p>

<p><strong>Picking his team</strong></p>

<p>Biden's Oval Office invitation restored a presidential transition tradition that Trump tore up when he lost the 2020 election, refusing to sit down with Biden or even attend the inauguration.</p>

<p>Then-president Barack Obama had welcomed Trump to the White House when the tycoon won the 2016 election.</p>

<p>But by the time Trump took his last Marine One flight from the White House lawn on January 20, 2021, he had also been repudiated by many in his own party for having stoked the assault on the Capitol.</p>

<p>That period of disgrace soon evaporated, however, as Republicans returned to Trump's side, recognizing his unique electoral power at the head of his right-wing movement.</p>

<p>Trump enters his second term with a near total grip on his party and the Democrats in disarray.</p>

<p>He has spent the week since the election at his Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida assembling his top team, as the world watches to see how closely he sticks to his pledges of isolationism, mass deportations and sweeping tariffs.</p>

<p>Trump named Space X, Tesla and X boss Musk, and businessman Vivek Ramaswamy, to lead a "Department of Government Efficiency ('DOGE')" -- a tongue-in-cheek reference to an internet meme and cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Trump is moving quickly to fill out his administration, picking a host of ultra-loyalists.</p>

<p>Trump nominated Fox News host and army veteran Pete Hegseth as his incoming defense secretary. An outspoken opponent of so-called "woke" ideology in the armed forces, Hegseth has little experience similar to managing the mammoth US military budget and bureaucracy.</p>

<p>Trump named South Dakota Governor Kristi Noem -- an ally who famously wrote about shooting her dog because it did not respond to training -- as head of the Department of Homeland Security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fn547nk_trump-biden_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump added that the transition would be "smooth as you can get."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-governments-efficiency-panel-headed-by-elon-musk-might-work-7012643]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Musk's US Government Efficiency Panel Might Work]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-governments-efficiency-panel-headed-by-elon-musk-might-work-7012643]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 22:05:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has tasked Elon Musk with setting up a panel to streamline the US government. Although the president-elect has said little about how this group would operate, Musk has previously set an ambitious goal of cutting $2 trillion of spending.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has tasked Elon Musk with setting up a panel to streamline the US government. Although the president-elect has said little about how this group would operate, Musk has previously set an ambitious goal of cutting $2 trillion of spending.</p>

<p>Here is how this new panel, which will be headed up by Musk, the world's richest person, and former Republican Presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy, might work.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DOES MUSK WANT TO CUT?</strong></p>

<p>Musk said at a Trump rally at Madison Square Garden in October that the federal budget could be reduced by "at least" $2 trillion. Discretionary spending, including defense spending, is estimated to total $1.9 trillion out of $6.75 trillion in total federal outlays for fiscal 2024, according to the Congressional Budget Office, suggesting Musk's target would be very difficult to meet.</p>

<p>Musk, whose companies include the electric vehicle maker Tesla and commercial space company SpaceX, has a deep knowledge of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Pentagon, agencies he has extensive contracts with for rockets, satellites and other space operations.</p>

<p>He has also tussled with regulators within the Department of Transportation, including the Federal Aviation Administration, which has a say in his company's rocket launches, and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, which is investigating autonomous driving functions in his cars.</p>

<p>Ramaswamy, who founded pharmaceutical company Roivant Sciences, has worked with the Food and Drug Administration, an agency he has previously called "corrupt". On social media site X in 2023 he added that "Countless FDA regulations and actions are hypocritical, harmful &amp; unconstitutional."</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAVE MUSK AND TRUMP SAID ABOUT THE PANEL?</strong></p>

<p>Trump in a statement on Tuesday said the panel would "provide advice and guidance from outside of government," on slimming down the government, cutting regulations, reducing spending and restructuring federal agencies.</p>

<p>Trump wants to abolish the Department of Education, and leave states in control of schooling, and decimate what he terms the "deep state" - career federal employees he says are clandestinely pursuing their own agendas.</p>

<p>Trump and Musk have suggested the panel will be able to make dramatic cuts, but generally speaking large budgetary actions are the remit of Congress. They can take advice from outside panels like the proposed efficiency panel, or disregard it.</p>

<p>In an effort to be transparent, Musk said the panel will post its "actions" for public comment.</p>

<p>"Anytime the public thinks we are cutting something important or not cutting something wasteful, just let us know!" he said on X.</p>

<p>He also mentioned a list of "dumb" spending, which he noted would be "extremely entertaining".</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IS THE PRECEDENT FOR THE EFFICIENCY PANEL?</strong></p>

<p>Former President Ronald Reagan announced in February 1982 that he would form a group of private sector experts to recommend ways to eliminate inefficiency and waste. That June, he issued an executive order forming the President's Private Sector Survey on Cost Control in the Federal Government, which became known as the Grace Commission for its chairman J. Peter Grace, the former CEO of W.R. Grace and Co.</p>

<p>Grace raised money to fund the effort through a foundation. About 150 business leaders volunteered their time on an executive committee that oversaw 36 Grace Commission task forces, which reviewed agencies or functions.</p>

<p>The Commission issued a report in January 1984 with some 2,500 recommendations, and the various task forces came out with reports as well.</p>

<p>"Most of the recommendations, especially those requiring legislation from Congress, were never implemented," the Reagan Library said.</p>

<p>In March 2017, Trump signed an executive order that aimed to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and accountability of federal agencies and to "eliminate or reorganize unnecessary federal agencies." It directed each federal agency to submit a proposed plan to reorganize. He also signed a separate executive order to place "regulatory reform" task forces and officers within federal agencies.</p>

<p>Trump also tried to kill at least 19 agencies but was unsuccessful during his first term. He called for eliminating the Overseas Private Investment Corporation that helps spur private investment in foreign development projects and the Corporation for Public Broadcasting. He also tried to cut funding for Amtrak, subsidies for rural airline service and the Special Olympics.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT EXPERIENCE DOES MUSK HAVE WITH COST CUTTING?</strong></p>

<p>After Musk bought the social media app Twitter, he laid off roughly 3,700 employees, or half its workforce, as advertisers pulled spending. Hundreds more employees subsequently resigned. He later renamed the social media site "X", but its valuation has shrunk dramatically under Musk's ownership.</p>

<p>Musk has had much greater success in space. SpaceX's Falcon 9 rocket slashed launch costs with its reusability, sprouting new satellite markets and giving rise to the company's fast-growing Starlink constellation, which has disrupted the established satellite communications industry and helped shape modern military strategies and turned SpaceX into a major defense contractor.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT ARE THE RULES FOR A PANEL LIKE THIS?</strong></p>

<p>The committee would likely operate under the Federal Advisory Committee Act, a 1972 law ensuring panels provide advice that is prompt, objective and open to the public. It also mandates cost controls and record keeping requirements that apply to the roughly 1,000 committees with some 60,000 members advising the President and the executive branch at any given time.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u864ihd8_elon-musk_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Elon Musk have suggested the panel will be able to make dramatic cuts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-talks-of-constitution-breaking-3rd-term-as-president-details-here-7012449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Hints At Constitution-Breaking 3rd Term As President. Details Here]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-talks-of-constitution-breaking-3rd-term-as-president-details-here-7012449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 21:33:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, who has recently been elected for a second term as President of the United States, has told House Republicans that he might consider a constitution-breaking third term in office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump, who has recently been elected for a second term as President of the United States, has told House Republicans that he might consider a constitution-breaking third term in office. President-elect Trump, who has a penchant for making controversial statements, said "I suspect I won't be running again unless you (supporters) say otherwise".</p>

<p>During his speech to fellow Republicans elected to the House of Representatives, Mr Trump said, "I suspect I won't be running again unless you say, 'He's good, we got to figure something else'." His statement at a hotel in Washington DC ahead of his meeting with President Joe Biden was cheered by his supporters.</p>

<p>It is common knowledge that there are provisions in place in the US Constitution which restricts a US President from standing for re-election for a third term, but how safe are those safeguards? Here's a look at whether Donald Trump can run again for presidency in 2028.</p>

<p>The 22nd Amendment of the United States Constitution stops any President from running for a third term, so if Donald Trump wants to seek a third term, he will first have to scrap that amendment. Doing so is a daunting task as it requires the President to garner an overwhelming amount of support from Congress as well as state legislatures. This is something that Trump is unlikely to be able to achieve.</p>

<p>According to an article in US-based news website <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/383616/trump-third-term-constitution-22nd-amendment" rel="No follow, no index" target="_blank">Vox</a>, which interviewed a law professor from Stanford University who specialises in constitutional interpretation, a question about the possibility of such a Constitutional amendment was asked. His reply was clear - "No, there are none. This will be his last run for President," the law professor said.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT IS THE 22nd AMENDMENT?</strong></h2>

<p>The 22nd Amendment of the US Constitution says that a President can have two terms in office and no further. It is applicable to Presidents, both in consecutive and non-consecutive terms.</p>

<p>According to Section 1 of the 22nd Amendment of the Constitution of the United States, "No person shall be elected to the office of the President more than twice, and no person who has held the office of President, or acted as President, for more than two years of a term to which some other person was elected President shall be elected to the office of the President more than once. But this Article shall not apply to any person holding the office of President when this Article was proposed by the Congress, and shall not prevent any person who may be holding the office of President, or acting as President, during the term within which this Article becomes operative from holding the office of President or acting as President during the remainder of such term."</p>

<p>While Section 2 states that "This article shall be inoperative unless it shall have been ratified as an amendment to the Constitution by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years from the date of its submission to the States by the Congress."</p>

<h3><strong>HISTORY OF THE 22nd AMENDMENT</strong></h3>

<p>The provision to restrict US Presidents strictly to a maximum of two terms first came into force in 1951, when both Republicans and Democrats had demanded for such a provision to be in place. This was because former US President Franklin D Roosevelt was elected to the highest office for an unprecedented four times. In 1945, he had died in office during his fourth term.</p>

<p>Though Roosevelt was the only President to be elected more than two times, American lawmakers from both parties had decided that the presidential terms must have a ceiling limit, and hence the 22nd Amendment came into force, restricting all Presidents then on to a maximum of two terms.</p>

<p>Since US's first President and founding father George Washington had served for a maximum of two terms, both parties agreed that this was the legacy to be followed.</p>

<h3><strong>CAN AN AMENDMENT IN THE US CONSTITUTION BE REPEALED?</strong></h3>

<p>The checks and balances in place to ensure that an Amendment to the Constitution is not easily repealed are watertight. It dissuades and discourages amendments from being scrapped or repealed. However, it is not impossible.</p>

<p>In order to do so, a bill for such order would have to be agreed to by two-thirds majority (67 per cent) of both the House and the Senate. The House of Representatives has 435 members, of which 290 must vote for such a revocation. Similarly, in the Senate, which has 100 members, 67 must agree with it. That is not all. Should a bill be passed by the House and the Senate, it then goes to each of the states - which need to pass it with a three-fourths majority, and since the United States of America are 50 states, 38 of them would have to agree to it.</p>

<p>It is safe to assume that to cross all three hurdles would be highly unlikely for Donald Trump.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1oqbsaio_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_06_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump hints at running for President for a third term - something that is not constitutional]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-carbon-emissions-hit-record-high-in-2024-7012372]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global Carbon Emissions Hit Record High In 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/global-carbon-emissions-hit-record-high-in-2024-7012372]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 21:21:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Our latest annual stocktake shows the world is on track to reach a new record: 37.4 billion tonnes of CO emitted from fossil fuels in 2024. This is an increase of 0.8% from the previous year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Carbon dioxide (CO₂) emissions from fossil fuels continue to increase, year on year. This sobering reality will be presented to world leaders at the international climate conference COP29 in Baku, Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>Our latest annual stocktake shows the world is on track to reach a new record: 37.4 billion tonnes of CO₂ emitted from fossil fuels in 2024. This is an increase of 0.8% from the previous year.</p>

<p>Adopting renewable energy and electric vehicles is helping reduce emissions in 22 countries. But it's not enough to compensate for ongoing global growth in fossil fuels.</p>

<p>There were also signs in 2023 suggesting natural systems may struggle to capture and store as much CO₂ in the future as they have in the past. While humanity is tackling deforestation and the growth in fossil CO₂ emissions is slowing, the need to reach an immediate peak and decline in global emissions has never been so acute.</p>

<h3><br />
The Global Carbon Project</h3>

<p>The Global Carbon Budget is an annual planetary account of carbon sources and sinks, which soak up carbon dioxide and remove it from the atmosphere.</p>

<p>We include anthropogenic sources from human activities such as burning fossil fuels or making cement as well as natural sources such as bushfires.</p>

<p>When it comes to CO₂ sinks, we consider all the ways carbon may be taken out of the atmosphere. This includes plants using CO₂ to grow and CO₂ being absorbed by the ocean. Some of this happens naturally and some is being actively encouraged by human activity.</p>

<p>Putting all the available data on sources and sinks together each year is a huge international effort involving 86 research organisations, including Australia's CSIRO. We also use computer models and statistical approaches to fill out the remaining months to the end of the year.</p>

<h3><br />
Fossil fuel emissions up</h3>

<p>This year's growth in carbon emissions from fossil fuels is mainly from fossil gas and oil, rather than coal.</p>

<p>Fossil gas carbon emissions grew by 2.4%, signalling a return to the strong long-term growth rates observed before the COVID pandemic. Gas emissions grew in most large countries, but declined across the European Union.</p>

<p>Oil carbon emissions grew by 0.9% overall, pushed up by a rise in emissions from international aviation and from India.</p>

<p>The rebound in international air travel pushed aviation carbon emissions up 13.5% in 2024, although it's still 3.5% below the pre-COVID 2019 level.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, oil emissions from the United States and China are declining. It's possible oil emissions have peaked in China, driven by growth in electric vehicles.</p>

<p>Coal carbon emissions went up by 0.2%, with strong growth in India, small growth in China, a moderate decline in the US, and a large decline in the European Union. Coal use in the US is now at its lowest level in 120 years.</p>

<p>The United Kingdom closed its last coal power plant in 2024, 142 years after the first one was opened. With strong growth in wind energy replacing coal, the UK CO₂ emissions have almost been cut in half since 1990.</p>

<h3><br />
Changing land use</h3>

<p>Carbon emissions also come from land clearing and degradation. But some of that CO₂ can be taken up again by planting trees. So we need to examine both sources and sinks on land.</p>

<p>Global net CO₂ emissions from land use change averaged 4.1 billion tonnes a year over the past decade (2014-23). This year is likely to be slightly higher than average with 4.2 billion tonnes, due to drought and fires in the Amazon. That amount represents about 10% of all emissions from human activities, the rest owing to fossil fuels.</p>

<p>Importantly, total carbon emissions - the sum of fossil fuel emissions and land-use change emissions - have largely plateaued over the past decade, but are still projected to reach a record of just over 41 billion tonnes in 2024.</p>

<p>The plateau in 2014-23 follows a decade of significant growth in total emissions of 2% per year on average between 2004 and 2013. This shows humanity is tackling deforestation and the growth of fossil CO₂ emissions is slowing. However, this is not enough to put global emissions on a downward trajectory.</p>

<h3><br />
More countries are cutting emissions - but many more to go</h3>

<p>Fossil CO₂ emissions decreased in 22 countries as their economies grew. These countries are mainly from the European Union, along with the United States. Together they represent 23% of global fossil CO₂ emissions over the past decade (2014-23).</p>

<p>This number is up from 18 countries during the previous decade (2004-13). New countries in this list include Norway, New Zealand and South Korea.</p>

<p>In Norway, emissions from road transport declined as the share of electric vehicles in the passenger car fleet grew - the highest in the world at over 25% - and biofuels replaced fossil petrol and diesel. Even greater reductions in emissions have come from Norway's oil and gas sector, where gas turbines on offshore platforms are being upgraded to electric.</p>

<p>In New Zealand, emissions from the power sector are declining. Traditionally the country has had a high share of hydropower, supplemented with coal and natural gas. But now wind and particularly geothermal energy is driving fossil generation down.</p>

<p>We are projecting further emissions growth of 0.2% in China, albeit small and with some uncertainty (including the possibility of no growth or even slight decline). China added more solar panels in 2023 than the US did in its entire history.</p>

<h3><br />
Nature shows troubling signs</h3>

<p>In the 1960s, our activities emitted an average of 16 billion tonnes of CO₂ per year globally. About half of these emissions (8 billion tonnes) were naturally removed from the atmosphere by forests and oceans.</p>

<p>Over the past decade, emissions from human activities reached about 40 billion tonnes of CO₂ per year. Again, about half of these emissions (20 billion tonnes) were removed.</p>

<p>In the absence of these natural sinks, current warming would already be well above 2°C. But there's a limit to how much nature can help.</p>

<p>In 2023, the carbon uptake on land dropped 28% from the decadal average. Global record temperatures, drought in the Amazon and unprecedented wildfires in the forests of Canada were to blame, along with an El Nino event.</p>

<p>As climate change continues, with rising ocean temperatures and more climate extremes on land, we expect the CO₂ sinks to become less efficient. But for now, we expect last year's land sink decline will recover to a large degree as the El Nino event has subsided.</p>

<h3>Looking ahead</h3>

<p>Our latest carbon budget shows global fossil fuel emissions continue to increase, further delaying the peak in emissions. Global CO₂ emissions continue to track in the middle of the range of scenarios developed by the Intergovenmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). We have yet to bend the emissions curve into the 1.5-2°C warming territory of the Paris Agreement.</p>

<p>This comes at a time when it's clear we need to be reducing emissions, to avoid worsening climate change.</p>

<p>We also identified some positive signs, such as the rapid adoption of renewable energy and electric cars as they become cheaper and more accessible, supporting the march toward a net-zero emissions pathway. But turning these trends into global decarbonisation requires a far greater level of ambition and action.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jb3e9h3g_climate-change-global-warming-greenhouse-gas-emissions-pixabay_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The world is on track to reach a new record: 37.4 billion tonnes of CO emitted from fossil fuels in 2024]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-reaches-its-record-high-of-90-000-amid-trump-elect-7012114]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin Reaches Record High Of $90,000 As Trump Pledges To Ease Regulations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bitcoin-reaches-its-record-high-of-90-000-amid-trump-elect-7012114]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:50:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bitcoin struck a record high above $93,000 Wednesday as the world's biggest cryptocurrency benefits from president-elect Donald Trump's pledge to ease regulation around digital tokens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin struck a record high above $93,000 Wednesday as the world's biggest cryptocurrency benefits from president-elect Donald Trump's pledge to ease regulation around digital tokens.</p>

<p>The volatile asset has rocketed more than 30 percent in value since Trump won last week's US presidential election, smashing its record-high on several occasions and breaching $90,000 for the first time Wednesday.</p>

<p>The Republican said during campaigning that he planned to make the United States the "bitcoin and cryptocurrency capital of the world".</p>

<p>"The main catalyst for the recent surge on the price of bitcoin is the victory of Donald Trump," Alexander Londono, market analyst at ActivTrades, noted Wednesday.</p>

<p>"This is due to the fact that Trump has been an outspoken supporter of cryptocurrencies and is willing to deregulate the sector to make it more investor friendly."</p>

<p>Londono added that the rally "is based on emotions and future expectations, which may or may not become real".</p>

<p><strong>'Broader surge'</strong></p>

<p>Other cryptocurrencies are also benefiting, including Dogecoin, supported by Elon Musk, boss of Tesla.</p>

<p>Bitcoin's "rally and the broader surge across cryptocurrencies have set global markets ablaze, stirring up waves of excitement and speculation", said independent markets analyst Stephen Innes.</p>

<p>Trump on Tuesday announced that Musk, the world's richest man, will lead a new US government-efficiency group tasked with cutting federal waste.</p>

<p>Musk became a key ally to Trump during his campaign, reportedly spending over $100 million to help him win and repeatedly boosting his candidacy on X, the social platform he owns.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrencies have made headlines since their creation, from their extreme volatility to the collapse of several industry giants, foremost among them the FTX exchange platform.</p>

<p>Bitcoin was conceived in 2008 by a person or group writing under the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto.</p>

<p>The digital currency is created -- or "mined" -- as a reward when powerful computers solve complex problems to validate transactions made on the blockchain.</p>

<p>The previous Trump term as president saw corporate tax cuts that brought more liquidity to markets, encouraging investment into cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Trump announced in September that he, along with his sons and entrepreneurs, would launch a digital currency platform named World Liberty Financial.</p>

<p>But it had a faltering sales launch earlier this month, with only a fraction of its tokens that went on the market finding a buyer.</p>

<p>In the run-up to the election, Trump apparently became the first former president to use bitcoin in a purchase, as he bought burgers at a New York City restaurant, which hailed it as a "historic transaction".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mibgdj5_bitcoin-cryptocurrency-istock_625x300_11_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump became the first former president to use bitcoin in a purchase. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/my-body-has-changed-but-sunita-williams-on-her-health-aboard-space-station-7012028]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Body Has Changed, But....": Sunita Williams On Health Aboard Space Station]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/my-body-has-changed-but-sunita-williams-on-her-health-aboard-space-station-7012028]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 20:37:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams, who has been in space since June, has put an end to swirling "rumours" about her health, saying she weighs the same as she did when she arrived at the International Space Station (ISS).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin NASA astronaut Sunita Williams, who has been in space since June, has put an end to swirling "rumours" about her health, saying she weighs the same as she did when she arrived at the International Space Station (ISS).</p>

<p>The "rumours" were sparked by recent images of her "gaunt" appearance, where she looked weaker and thinner after spending at least 150 days in space, triggering concerns of rapid weight loss.</p>

<p>"...I think my body has changed a little bit but I weigh the same...," Williams, who is the Space Station Commander, told the media in a video interview that was shared by NASA.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="515" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9UMzOwlv7iM" title="NASA Astronaut Suni Williams Talks with New England Sports Network – Tuesday, November 12, 2024" width="700"></iframe></p>

<p>"There are a lot of changes that go on here... It's funny, I think there's some rumours around that I am losing weight and stuff... No, I am actually right at the same amount... we go weigh ourselves, we have a spring mass... Butch and I weigh ourselves the same way that I was when I got up here," she added.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and her fellow astronaut Barry (Butch) Willmore have been at the ISS for nearly five months. The duo had launched aboard Boeing's Starliner spacecraft on June 5 for its first crewed flight, and arrived at the space station on June 6. They, however, faced delays, space debris threats, helium leaks and technical glitches on the Starliner spacecraft on which they travelled.</p>

<p>On August 24, NASA said it's too risky to bring the two astronauts back to Earth in the troubled new capsule, and they'll have to wait until February for a ride home with SpaceX.</p>

<p>As Ms William's images of "sunken cheeks" and a thinner physique surfaced, the astronaut said the change in appearance was due to a "fluid shift" in the body.</p>

<p>"I think things shift around quite a bit... you have a fluid shift where you know the folks in space... their heads look a bit bigger because the fluids even out along the body. But now, you know, we've been up here for a couple of months, we've been working out here. We've got a bike, we've got a treadmill and we've got weight-lifting equipment," she said.</p>

<p>"I could definitely tell that weightlifting, which is not something that I do all the time, is something that has changed me. My thighs are a little bit bigger, my body is a little bit bigger, we do a lot of squats. And just to go back to the treadmill...why... It's because we are working on our bone density in our hips and in our feet. So, I think my body has changed a little bit but I weigh the same...," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dlpu640o_sunita-williams-butch-wilmore_625x300_25_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry (Butch) Willmore have been at the ISS for nearly five months.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/australias-social-media-ban-barking-up-the-wrong-tree-7011403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Australia's Under-16 Social Media Ban: Barking Up The Wrong Tree]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/australias-social-media-ban-barking-up-the-wrong-tree-7011403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:13:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said about the social media ban proposal that it was for the mums and dads who were always worried about social media. Great. But there are pitfalls too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/social_media_jeremy_bezanger_unsplash_1648640519600.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Australia has taken the lead in launching the world's first social media ban for teenagers under the age of 16. Usually the word ‘ban' awakens a mob on social media waxing eloquent about democracy and freedom of choice, this time around, people are rather confused.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The hesitation to not immediately oppose it makes sense, especially to those who have children. Parents are a worrisome bunch. To my mother, for instance, a missed call may as well be a signal from the universe declaring me dead. Such anxieties are exacerbated in the age of the internet, of social media, and of never-ending ‘doomscrolling'.</p>

<h2><strong>Is It Parents Or Internet?</strong></h2>

<p>It's not entirely unjustified either. A simple Google search of ‘teen dies by suicide because of social media' is enough to paint a picture of what social media brings to our children: bullying, harrassment, insecurities, peer pressure, unrealistic standards. To make matters worse, we now have chat bots. Last month, a 14-year-old boy shot himself, believing he was ‘going home' to the love of his life, an AI bot. The leaked chats between the bot and the boy indicated that the former's language may have played a part in leading the impressionable teen to take his own life. However, many on social media blamed the parents.</p>

<p>Questions were raised: Why couldn't the parents see the warning signs? Were there some underlying mental health issues? The online mob was divided. One section wanted stricter regulations for AI and chatbots. Others, who contended that AI was bound to become an integral part of our lives, pointed to the callousness of the parents, who later admitted that their teen son did look distressed at times and didn't have many friends. Both sides were right and wrong in equal measure.</p>

<p>Parenting or lifestyle magazines these days are flush with articles targeted towards parents of young adults or prepubescent children, warning them about how social media is harming their child. They have some great suggestions: limit screen time, put parental locks, invest more in offline activities or simply talk to the children. These are all good points but with little practical impact. What about when parents themselves are addicted to social media?</p>

<h2><strong>A Complicated Ban To Enforce</strong></h2>

<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said about the social media ban proposal that it was for the ‘mums and dads' who were always worried about social media. Great. But there are pitfalls too.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though the proposal claims ‘parental consent' would not change this universally applicable law, it doesn't specify what happens in cases where a family of vloggers or bloggers has kids featuring in their content. The proposed law bans a child from registering on social media platforms, but all of that is meaningless if the child is being used by a parent for engagement. Such children are exploited by their parents for their social media content: bathtime, meals, family conversations, or even relatively private phases is all fair game for parents. Will Australia propose a regulation for this sector?&nbsp;</p>

<p>Second, it is unclear how the tech platform will regulate the ban. I was on Orkut when I was 13. Let's say social media platforms demand ID proof, can the child not provide forged documents? Let's say the platforms are asked to verify posted pictures. But what if the child never posts anything and just uses social media to consume content, in the process getting insidiously influenced by it?</p>

<p>Bans don't usually work. If anything, a banned product, in the absence of adequate enforcement, ends up becoming a guilty pleasure for most. It's the sine qua non of the great teenage rebellion. It's time lawmakers the world around understood that when formulating laws for the young.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(The author is Assistant Producer, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/social_media_jeremy_bezanger_unsplash_1648640519600.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-set-for-white-house-meeting-after-harris-election-loss-7011218]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden, Trump Set For White House Meeting After Harris Election Loss]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-trump-set-for-white-house-meeting-after-harris-election-loss-7011218]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:53:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Biden congratulated Trump on November 6 and invited him to the White House, demonstrating his commitment to a peaceful transfer of power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump broke two significant traditions after losing the 2020 election - declining to invite President-elect Joe Biden to the White House and skipping Biden's inauguration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, these customs will be reinstated as Trump and Biden are set to meet at the Oval Office today, marking Trump's first return to the White House since his presidency ended amidst election denialism four years ago.</p>

<p>Trump's comeback was sealed after winning all seven swing states, securing 312 electoral votes to Vice President Kamala Harris' 226, and potentially winning the popular vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a gesture of goodwill, President Biden congratulated Trump on November 6 and invited him to the White House, demonstrating his commitment to a peaceful transfer of power.</p>

<p>According to White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, Biden's invitation stems from his belief in upholding norms and ensuring a smooth transition.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She said, "It is important not just because it's important to him, but it's important to the American people. The American people deserve this. They deserve a peaceful transfer of power. They deserve a smooth transition. And that's what you're going to see."</p>

<p>The meeting's agenda will be private, but reporters will be present to capture the beginning of the discussion. National security adviser Jake Sullivan revealed that Biden and Trump will discuss domestic and foreign policy issues.</p>

<p>The two leaders have been at odds for years, with vastly differing views on key policies such as climate change, Russia, and trade. Biden has expressed concerns about Trump's impact on democracy, while Trump has criticised Biden's competence</p>

<p>This meeting signifies a return to presidential tradition, particularly after Trump's contentious departure from office. His impeachment by the House for "incitement of insurrection" following the January 6, 2021, US Capitol storming added to the tension. Today's meeting marks a step towards reconciliation and reinforces the importance of democratic norms.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/658hp91_biden-trump_625x300_27_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This meeting signifies a return to presidential tradition after Trump's contentious departure from office]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-the-guardian-quits-x-citing-disturbing-content-on-platform-7011083]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's 'The Guardian' Quits X Citing "Disturbing Content" On Platform]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-the-guardian-quits-x-citing-disturbing-content-on-platform-7011083]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:37:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British news publisher the Guardian said on Wednesday it will no longer post to X, citing "disturbing content" on the social media platform, including racism and conspiracy theories.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British news publisher the Guardian said on Wednesday it will no longer post to X, citing "disturbing content" on the social media platform, including racism and conspiracy theories.</p>

<p>The left-leaning Guardian, which has 10.7 million followers on X, becomes the first large UK media company to retreat from the platform that Elon Musk purchased in 2022.</p>

<p>Critics say Musk's hands-off approach has allowed lies and hate speech to spread on the platform formerly known as Twitter.</p>

<p>"We think that the benefits of being on X are now outweighed by the negatives and that resources could be better used promoting our journalism elsewhere," the Guardian said in an editorial published on its website.</p>

<p>"This is something we have been considering for a while given the often disturbing content promoted or found on the platform, including far-right conspiracy theories and racism."</p>

<p>In response, Musk posted on X and said of the Guardian: "They are irrelevant."</p>

<p>Musk, who supported Donald Trump ahead of his U.S. election victory this month, has said he is defending freedom of speech.</p>

<p>Trump on Tuesday named Musk to a role aimed at creating a more efficient government.</p>

<p>The role of X and other platforms came under the spotlight in Britain this year when far-right and racist violence broke out after online posts falsely claimed that an attack in the northern English town of Southport, where three young girls were killed, was the work of an Islamist migrant.</p>

<p>Reuters was first to report last month that a British police force had quit posting on X, with several more reviewing their involvement.</p>

<p>In recent months, some British charities, health and educational establishments have said they will no longer post to X.</p>

<p>Britain's government continues to post on X but does not use it for paid communications. It does, however, advertise on Meta's Instagram and Facebook, a government source told Reuters last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9a849ioo_the-guardian_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In response, Musk posted on X and said of the Guardian: "They are irrelevant." (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-priest-who-married-prince-harry-and-meghan-markle-steps-down-over-child-abuse-scandal-7010953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Church Of England Head Resigns Over Child Abuse Scandal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-priest-who-married-prince-harry-and-meghan-markle-steps-down-over-child-abuse-scandal-7010953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:19:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Justin Welby, who officiated at Prince Harry and Meghan Markle's wedding and led King Charles III's coronation, has faced mounting calls to step down.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Archbishop of Canterbury Justin Welby, the spiritual head of the global Anglican community, announced his resignation on Tuesday amid criticism over his handling of abuse allegations within the church.</p>

<p>In a statement, Welby admitted to failing to ensure a thorough investigation into claims of abuse by a volunteer at Christian summer camps decades ago.</p>

<p>Welby, who officiated at the wedding of Prince Harry and Meghan Markle and led King Charles III's coronation, faced mounting calls to step down after a recent report concluded he had not done enough to stop one of the Church's most prolific abusers, the <em>Reuters </em>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Church historians and commentators noted this marks the first time an Anglican archbishop has resigned due to an abuse scandal.</p>

<p>In his resignation letter, Welby stated he must accept "personal and institutional responsibility" for the Church's lack of action on these "heinous abuses."</p>

<p>"The past few days have intensified my deep sense of shame over the Church of England's historic safeguarding failures," Welby said. "As I step down, I do so in sorrow alongside all victims and survivors of abuse."</p>

<p>Welby's decade-long tenure saw him navigating challenges over LGBTQ rights and women's ordination, which created tensions between liberal churches in the West and conservative counterparts in Africa.</p>

<p>Anglican churches in countries like Uganda and Nigeria are expected to welcome his resignation, having previously voiced a lack of confidence in him.</p>

<p>The next Archbishop will face the task of uniting the increasingly divided Anglican community and addressing a decline in church attendance, which has fallen by 20% in Britain since 2019.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for British Prime Minister Keir Starmer expressed respect for Welby's decision.</p>

<p>Archbishop of York Stephen Cottrell, the Church's second-ranking cleric, called Welby's resignation "the right and honorable decision."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s84lclf_justin-welby_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Welby was the most senior cleric of the Church of England]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-think-he-s-gonna-kill-it-donald-trump-s-granddaughter-on-his-second-term-7010919]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["He's Gonna Kill It": Kai Trump On Grandfather Donald Trump's 2nd Term]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/i-think-he-s-gonna-kill-it-donald-trump-s-granddaughter-on-his-second-term-7010919]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:16:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kai Trump, the granddaughter of Donald Trump, is excited about her grandfather's second term in the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kai Trump, the granddaughter of Donald Trump, is 'excited' about her grandfather's second term in the White House. In a video posted by a user, Kai shared her perspective on Donald Trump's vision for the future, saying, "I'm really excited to see what he's gonna do for the next few years. I think he's gonna kill it."</p>

<p>Speaking about Donald Trump's second term, she added, "Every single thing he does, he puts 100% of his effort into it and I think he's gonna do an amazing job."</p>

<p>"He deserves this more than anyone else in the whole world," she said. "He's going to kill it and make America great again. And he's really going to do what's right for the people,"&nbsp;The 17-year-old vlogger said.</p>

<p>"He doesn't need this job, he doesn't need it at all, he can just play golf for the rest of his life and live in Mar-a-Lago. But he wants to fight for this country, and he has a vision and he's gonna follow through on that vision," Kai said.</p>

<p>Watch the video here:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Kai Trump on her grandfather <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@realDonaldTrump</a>:<br />
<br />
“I'm really excited to see what he's gonna do for the next few years. I think he's gonna kiII it. Every single thing he does, he puts 100% of his effort into it and I think he's gonna do an amazing job.”<br />
<br />
???????????? <a href="https://t.co/B8bhI3JOfp">pic.twitter.com/B8bhI3JOfp</a></p>
— TONY™ (@TONYxTWO) <a href="https://twitter.com/TONYxTWO/status/1856419699531055155?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>So far, the video has amassed over 1.9 million views, with many users lauding the 17-year-old for her confidence and outlook.<br />
<br />
“Kai is everything we'd expect from the next generation of the Trump family! She's a star,” one user wrote.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Kai is everything we'd expect from the next generation of the Trump family! She's a star ????</p>
— Laurel (@CoxLaurel44498) <a href="https://twitter.com/CoxLaurel44498/status/1856429598491247031?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user expressed a similar sentiment, saying, “Every kid in that family is going to be successful.”<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Every kid in that family is going to be successful.</p>
— eastcoastal (@EastCoastalDB) <a href="https://twitter.com/EastCoastalDB/status/1856425174700032219?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
A third, tagging Kai Trump, highlighted her potential impact, saying she “can be an influential voice for the next generation that will be eligible to vote in 2028 and we couldn't ask for a better MAGA ambassador.”<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/KaiTrump?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@kaitrump</a> can be an influential voice for the next generation that will be eligible to vote in 2028 and we couldn't ask for a better MAGA ambassador. Thank you young lady, I know that you're grandpa is very proud!!!????????????????????</p>
— Elongated Muskrat???????????????? (@GhostOfFlappyD) <a href="https://twitter.com/GhostOfFlappyD/status/1856468841796132870?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
Another user shared their optimism, saying, “When I hear young Americans speak like this, it gives me great hope for our future.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">When I hear young Americans speak like this, it gives me great hope for our future.</p>
— Extreme Fitness (@GregSteubs39958) <a href="https://twitter.com/GregSteubs39958/status/1856428103960269127?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
“She's awesome!! How much do you want to bet the libs will take the "he's going to kill it" and run with their narrative???” read another comment.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">She's awesome!! How much you want to bet the libs will take the "he's going to kill it" and run with their narrative??? ????????????</p>
— Kim (@Texasgirlkiwi) <a href="https://twitter.com/Texasgirlkiwi/status/1856428647885738167?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><br />
A few days ago, Kai, who shares her vlogs with 1.78 lakh subscribers on YouTube, gave fans a sneak peek into the family's election night celebrations after Donald Trump's victory over Kamala Harris. In a behind-the-scenes video, she shared moments leading up to a family photograph, which also featured tech mogul Elon Musk. The video opens with Kai getting her makeup done, reflecting on the election and the significance of the night. She also mentioned that she hadn't seen her grandfather in a while due to his busy campaign schedule, adding she was "super excited" to finally meet him.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q4indsj8_kai-trump-with-donald-trump_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A few days ago, Kai gave fans a sneak peek into the family's election night celebrations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ikramuddin-kamil-taliban-in-1st-appointment-in-india-taliban-names-young-student-its-envoy-in-mumbai-7010911]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In 1st Appointment In India, Taliban Names Young Student Its Envoy In Mumbai]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ikramuddin-kamil-taliban-in-1st-appointment-in-india-taliban-names-young-student-its-envoy-in-mumbai-7010911]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:11:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Taliban regime has appointed a young Afghan student in India, Ikramuddin Kamil, as Acting Consul at Afghanistan's Consulate in Mumbai. This is the first appointment by the Taliban, which India does not recognise, since it took power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Taliban regime has appointed a young Afghan student in India, Ikramuddin Kamil, as Acting Consul at Afghanistan's Consulate in Mumbai. This is the first appointment by the Taliban - which New Delhi does not recognise - in India since it took power in Afghanistan in 2021.</p>

<p>India withdrew its diplomats from Kabul and other cities after the takeover and diplomats appointed by the previous Ashraf Ghani government in Afghanistan left India and took asylum in other countries. A lone former diplomat has stayed in India and kept the Afghanistan mission and consulates running.</p>

<p>Mr Kamil's appointment comes days after a delegation led by JP Singh, joint secretary of the Pakistan-Afghanistan-Iran division of the external affairs ministry visited Afghanistan and held talks with Mullah Mohammad Yaqoob, the acting defence minister of the Taliban, in Kabul.</p>

<p>Sher Mohammad Abbas Stanikzai, the Taliban's deputy foreign minister for political affairs, announced Mr Kamil's appointment on X on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Mr Kamil has studied in India for seven years, pursuing a doctorate in law from the South Asia University in Delhi on a scholarship provided by the Ministry of External Affairs. He is reportedly in Mumbai and already carrying out his duties.</p>

<p>While India has not officially reacted, sources in the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said Mr Kamil is being seen as an Afghanistani working for Afghans in India and not in terms of any affiliation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The sources said Afghan diplomats manning the country's embassy and consulates in India have sought refuge in different Western countries and have left India. A lone former diplomat has stayed in India and kept the consulates running but, they said, the Afghan community based in India needs consular services and more staff members are required to be able to do so.</p>

<p>"A young Afghan student, who the MEA is familiar with, and who has studied in India for seven years while completing his doctorate from South Asia University on an MEA scholarship, has agreed to function as a diplomat in the Afghan Consulate. As far as his affiliation or status is concerned, for us, he is an Afghan national working for Afghans in India," a source said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To a question on whether this signals that the Taliban would be recognised by India, the source said, "There is a set process for recognition of any Government and India will continue to work with the international community on this issue."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h04unb08_ikramuddin-kamil_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sources at the Centre said Mr Kamil is being seen as an Afghanistani working for Afghans in India.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/church-of-england-faces-pressure-over-abuse-scandal-after-archbishop-quits-7010844]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Church Of England Faces Pressure Over Abuse Scandal After Archbishop Quits]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/church-of-england-faces-pressure-over-abuse-scandal-after-archbishop-quits-7010844]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 18:01:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Church of England faced pressure on Wednesday to ensure people are held to account for systematically covering up allegations of abuse, one day after the Archbishop of Canterbury resigned over a church abuse scandal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Church of England faced pressure on Wednesday to ensure people are held to account for systematically covering up allegations of abuse, one day after the Archbishop of Canterbury resigned over a church abuse scandal.</p>

<p>Justin Welby quit on Tuesday as spiritual leader of the global Anglican Church, saying he had failed to ensure a proper investigation into allegations of abuse by a volunteer at Christian summer camps decades ago.</p>

<p>Welby resigned after coming under pressure over a report that found failings in the handling of the case of John Smyth, a barrister who abused at least 115 children and young men before his death.</p>

<p>The report has increased pressure on others to be held accountable for safeguarding failures.</p>

<p>"We ... know that some people pretty systematically covered this up and that those people do need to be brought to account," Archbishop of York Stephen Cottrell, the second-most senior bishop in the Church of England, told BBC Radio.</p>

<p>Cottrell said there were lessons to be learned from the review, but that he was not referring to bishops.</p>

<p>"The church is a very, very large organisation and a very dispersed organisation. We're a place where ... thousands and thousands of people, anyone can be part of our church, so safeguarding such an organisation is a challenge."</p>

<p><strong>BISHOP FACES CALLS TO RESIGN</strong></p>

<p>The Bishop of Lincoln, Stephen Conway, who was briefed about the abuse allegations against Smyth in 2013 - the same year as Welby - is facing calls to resign. The BBC quoted an unnamed victim of Smyth as saying that Conway did not do enough when he was informed of the abuse.</p>

<p>Conway apologised on Tuesday for not rigorously pursuing Lambeth Palace, Welby's office, about the matter, saying he had done all in his authority as a bishop.</p>

<p>The review said Welby was ill-advised about the actions taken in Conway's then diocese of Ely, adding that he was incorrectly informed that a referral had been made to the police.</p>

<p>"It was my understanding that this matter was reported to the police in Cambridgeshire (in eastern England) and duly passed on to the police in Hampshire where the abuse had occurred," Conway said.</p>

<p>Asked about Welby's omissions, Cottrell said: "There have been great steps taken in the safeguarding of the church under his watch, but on this case, perhaps he relied too much on others."</p>

<p>Welby spent years trying to prevent the global Anglican communion from fracturing, often struggling to please liberals or conservatives as they fought over homosexual rights and women clergy.</p>

<p>But Archbishop Stephen Kaziimba, as the head of Uganda's Anglican Church had been rebuked by Welby for supporting a strict anti-homosexuality law in Uganda, said on Wednesday that Welby had split the Anglican communion worldwide.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dlps1v8o_justin-welby_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Welby quit on Tuesday as spiritual leader of the global Anglican Church.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-nsa-nominee-mike-waltz-said-on-indias-pivotal-role-in-the-21st-century-7010548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Trump's NSA Nominee Said On India's Pivotal Role In The 21st Century]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-donald-trumps-nsa-nominee-mike-waltz-said-on-indias-pivotal-role-in-the-21st-century-7010548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:29:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mike Waltz, named National Security Adviser by President-elect Donald Trump, emphasised that he was excited about the enormous momentum in the partnership between US and India - the oldest and the largest democracies in the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ties between India and the US are "most important" of all relationships in the 21st century, according to Congressman Mike Waltz, who has been named the National Security Adviser by President-elect Donald Trump. Highlighting the significance, Mr Waltz, who is the co-chair of the Congressional India Caucus, said ties between India and America will "determine whether this is a century of light or a century of darkness".</p>

<p>The Congressman made these remarks at an event hosted by the US-India Strategic and Partnership Forum (USISPF) at Stanford University for the INDUSUSX Summit in September.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“The bottom line is, in my view, this (US-India) is the most important relationship of the 21st century. This will determine whether this is a century of light or a century of darkness,” Mr Waltz said in his video message to the summit, which he could not attend due to his engagements in the election.</p>

<p>He also encouraged further collaboration between the two countries to maintain a free and open Indo-Pacific and protect India's sovereignty, particularly along the Line of Control (LoC).</p>

<p>“Consider my office and my team an open door to further this relationship as we press forward, and keeping the Indo-Pacific free and open and protecting Indian sovereignty particularly on the Line of Control (LoC) and ensuring that the world that we leave behind for our children and grandchildren is in line with our shared values,” he said.</p>

<p>Mr Waltz further emphasised that he was excited about the enormous momentum in the partnership between the oldest and the largest democracies in the world. "Let's keep the momentum (in the US-India relationship) going," he said.</p>

<p>He noted that growing momentum in US-India relations is evident through initiatives like iCET and INDUS-X, and highlighted several areas of cooperation including joint production of the Apache helicopter fuselages by Boeing and Tata, advancements in ship repair, quantum computing, artificial intelligence, and data management - all of which are crucial for both nations to advance in the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Waltz visited India in August with his co-chair Congressman Ro Khanna to participate in the Independence Day celebrations. In his speech, the Congressman also praised Prime Minister Narendra Modi's “incredible” address at the Red Fort, and called the Independence Day celebrations "an amazing event.”<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rk0ie17s_narendra-modi-donald-trump-modi-trump-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mike Waltz, Trump's NSA said India-US ties will determine if it'll be a century of light or darkness]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-vivek-ramaswamy-the-biotech-billionaire-now-part-of-donald-trump-s-new-government-initiative-7010367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Vivek Ramaswamy, The Biotech Entrepreneur Now Part Of Trump 2.0]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-vivek-ramaswamy-the-biotech-billionaire-now-part-of-donald-trump-s-new-government-initiative-7010367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 17:07:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump announced that biotech investor Vivek Ramaswamy, who ended his Presidential bid in January 2024, will work closely with Mr Musk on this initiative.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump is back in the saddle and has started building his cabinet ahead of a second term in the White House. Apart from appointing loyalist Pete Hegseth as Secretary of Defence and hardliner Mike Huckabee as Ambassador to Israel, the US President-Elect has also announced a new Department of Government Efficiency (D.O.G.E.). It will be led by none other than tech mogul Elon Musk.</p>

<p>But he's not alone. Mr Trump announced that biotech investor Vivek Ramaswamy, who ended his Presidential bid in January 2024, will work closely with Mr Musk on this initiative.</p>

<p><strong>Who is Vivek Ramaswamy?</strong></p>

<p>Born in Cincinnati, Ohio, on August 9, 1985, Vivek Ramaswamy has made a name as a biotech entrepreneur and a political thinker, who isn't shy of airing anti-woke and anti-establishment views. His journey from a modest upbringing in Ohio to a prominent role in conservative circles highlights his drive to shake up traditional structures in both business and government.</p>

<p><strong>Early life and academics</strong></p>

<p>Vivek Ramaswamy's parents emigrated from Kerala to the United States in the 1970s. His father was an engineer and patent lawyer for General Electric, while his mother was a geriatric psychiatrist. Mr Ramaswamy was an academically and athletically gifted student, who excelled in tennis and graduated as valedictorian from a Jesuit High School in Cincinnati. He went on to study biology at Harvard University and graduated in 2007. Later, he attended Yale Law School and received his Juris Doctor in 2013. It was at Yale that he met his wife, Apoorva Tewari, a medical student and future surgeon.</p>

<p><strong>Making a mark as an entrepreneur</strong></p>

<p>In 2014, at 29, Vivek Ramaswamy founded Roivant Sciences, a biotech company focused on acquiring underdeveloped pharmaceuticals and advancing them through clinical trials. He identified overlooked drugs with potential and brought them to market faster than the industry standard. Through Roivant, Mr Ramaswamy earned significant wealth, with the company's portfolio expanding to include several "vant" subsidiaries such as Myovant and Urovant, each targeting different therapeutic areas. By 2023, he was reported to have accumulated over $250 million in personal earnings from his ventures.</p>

<p>A key financial milestone for Roivant occurred in 2020 when the Japanese pharmaceutical firm Sumitomo Dainippon acquired a 10% stake in Roivant and five of its drugs in a deal valued at $3 billion. This transaction reportedly brought Ramaswamy an estimated $176 million in capital gains.</p>

<p><strong>Opposition to 'woke capitalism'</strong></p>

<p>Though Vivek Ramaswamy largely avoided politics in his early career, 2020 saw a turning point. He expressed concerns about corporate America's involvement in social and political issues. His opinion piece in The Wall Street Journal criticised corporates, arguing they prioritised profit-driven social stances at the expense of public trust and integrity. In 2021, he published his book, 'Woke, Inc.: Inside Corporate America's Social Justice Scam,' in which he critiqued the ways companies engaged with social issues, saying such involvement was often superficial, profit-driven and even harmful to democratic values. He suggested that companies adopting diversity quotas or divesting from environmentally harmful enterprises were merely attempting to attract customers or distract from other questionable actions rather than genuinely supporting ethical causes.</p>

<p>To counter what he saw as the pitfalls of "woke capitalism," Vivek Ramaswamy launched Strive Asset Management in 2022, an "anti-woke" index fund provider. Unlike major asset management firms that promoted Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) investing, Strive aimed to keep politics out of its investment principles.</p>

<p>Backed by investors such as Peter Thiel and JD Vance, Strive presented itself as an alternative for those who wanted to support companies without the pressure of social or environmental mandates. The firm gained rapid traction, with assets surpassing $1 billion by September 2023. Ramaswamy's net worth was around $1 billion at the same time.</p>

<p><strong>2024 US presidential run</strong></p>

<p>In February 2023, Vivek Ramaswamy announced he would run for Presidency, entering the Republican race alongside Donald Trump and Nikki Haley. Throughout his campaign, Ramaswamy embraced traditional conservative stances, supporting abortion restrictions and opposing affirmative action. But he also promoted several unconventional policies. Among his proposals were raising the standard voting age to 25, curbing birthright citizenship, and deploying the US military to Mexico to annihilate drug cartels.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He also pledged to significantly reduce the federal workforce by firing over 75 per cent of federal employees and eliminating agencies such as the FBI, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Department of Education, while also dismantling teachers' unions. On climate, he provocatively suggested that Americans should "be proud to live a high-carbon lifestyle," adding "more people are dying of bad climate change policies than they are of actual climate change."</p>

<p>Early in the campaign, Vivek Ramaswamy gained visibility and emerged as a formidable challenger to Mr Trump. By August 2023, he was known for his media blitz, reportedly conducting about 30 interviews in 24 hours and appearing on over 150 podcasts within six months. His debate performance in August drew praise from CNN as a "breakout moment," and a Washington Post poll indicated that among Republican voters who watched, only Ron DeSantis performed better. Donald Trump had opted out of the debate.</p>

<p>Despite his strong start, Mr Ramaswamy's momentum slowed in the following months, with DeSantis and Haley surpassing him in the polls. After finishing fourth in the Iowa Republican caucus on January 15, 2024, he suspended his campaign. That night, he informed supporters of his decision to endorse Mr Trump.</p>

<p><strong>Appointment to the Department of Government Efficiency</strong></p>

<p>Donald Trump has appointed Mr Ramaswamy to co-lead the newly formed Department of Government Efficiency with Musk. This department, a key initiative of Trump 2.0, aims to optimise government spending and enhance accountability. Ramaswamy's involvement in the Trump administration reflects his rise as a key figure in conservative political thought. During his campaign and beyond, he became known for similar ideas to Trump's. He often described himself as a "Trump 2.0" figure. His campaign speeches praised Trump's leadership, and he endorsed Trump as "the greatest president" in recent history.</p>

<p><strong>Financial success</strong></p>

<p>Beyond his political pursuits, Vivek Ramaswamy's business achievements have garnered him recognition as one of the wealthiest young entrepreneurs in the US. His fortunes, largely derived from his role in biotech and venture capital, are estimated to exceed $1 billion, securing him a place on Forbes' "Richest Entrepreneurs Under 40" list.</p>

<p>Mr Ramaswamy's fortune has also benefited from strategic investments and business moves, including subsidiaries like Myovant Sciences, which raised $218 million in a high-profile IPO in 2016.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8nug74qo_vivek-ramaswamy-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy's parents emigrated from Kerala to the United States in the 1970s.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-govt-gives-highest-priority-to-over-35-million-indian-diaspora-says-eam-jaishankar-on-website-launch-for-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-7010128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[35 Million-Strong Indian Diaspora Modi Government's Priority: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modis-govt-gives-highest-priority-to-over-35-million-indian-diaspora-says-eam-jaishankar-on-website-launch-for-pravasi-bharatiya-divas-7010128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:39:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr. Jaishankar said that the Indian diaspora is a pillar of strength in tackling global issues highlighting the journey of Indians abroad which is more than a tale of migration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The official website for the 18th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas Convention was jointly launched by External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar, along with Odisha Chief Minister Mohan Charan Majhi, who said that the government under the inspirational leadership of Prime Minister Narendra Modi accords the highest priority to the well-being of more than 35 million Indian diaspora.<br />
The EAM posted on X: "Delighted to launch the 18th Pravasi Bharatiya Divas #PBD website alongside Odisha CM @MohanMOdisha ji and MoS @KVSinghMPGonda."</p>

<p>He further wrote on X: "MEA is proud to partner with Odisha and welcome our diaspora to the temple city of Bhubaneshwar to experience India's rich culture and heritage. Our biennial #PBD is a longstanding occasion to renew bonds and develop friendships. Invite ~CHECK~ diaspora to register in large numbers and join us in this celebration of our shared roots."</p>

<p>He said that the Indian diaspora is a pillar of strength in tackling global issues highlighting the journey of Indians abroad which is more than a tale of migration.</p>

<p>Mr. Jaishankar added that Pravasi Bhartiya Diwas is more than just a celebration, it is an invitation to action.</p>

<p>He said that 'Viksit Bharat ki Sankalpna Mein Pravasi Bhartiyon Ka Yogdan', that is diaspora's contribution to a developed India, is the theme for the Pravasi Bharatiya Diwas convention to be held early next year</p>

<p>The Pravasi Bharatiya Divas (PBD) Convention is a flagship event of the government that provides a key platform for engaging with the Indian diaspora around the world.</p>

<p>The convention will be held from January 8-10, 2025, at Bhubaneswar in collaboration with the Odisha government.</p>

<p>While launching the website (pbdindia.gov.in), Mr. Jaishankar said that Prime Minister Modi's regular interactions with the diaspora during his official visits abroad and their unwavering support of India's growth story are testimony to the strong bonds shared between India and its global community.</p>

<p>He expressed confidence that the Indian diaspora will continue to play a crucial role in India's march towards a Viksit Bharat.</p>

<p>"Today, as we confront various global challenges, the strength of our diaspora provides us a pillar of support and a strong foundation to address them adequately. I am confident that the diaspora will continue to play a notable role in India's march towards becoming Viksit Bharat by 2047. Let us walk this path together with the strength and unity that has always defined us. That is why we have chosen 'Viksit Bharat ki Sankalpna Mein Pravasi Bhartiyon Ka Yogdan', which is the diaspora's contribution to a Viksit Bharat, as the overarching theme for the upcoming 18th Pravasi Bhartiya Diwas," Mr. Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>He emphasised that the Indians who have migrated have done works that have left a unique legacy both in India and in their host countries.</p>

<p>"The event will also showcase exhibitions on Ramayana and for the first time highlight the contributions of the diaspora to technology as part of our message that India moves on both tradition and technology together. The Odisha government also intends to install an exhibition to showcase its rich cultural heritage, diversity, and artistry. The Ministry will be extending invitations to the winners of the ongoing Bharat Pujaniya Quiz and to participants of two batches of its flagship Know India program to attend the upcoming PBD. The website of the 18th PBD has been designed and developed to serve as a single point for important information required by Pravasis. It would facilitate registration of participants, booking of accommodation, and other necessary formalities. It also provides details of the program, logistics, advisories, tourist attractions, and religious sites in Odisha. With the launch of the website today, the registration process for participants is now open and delegates are encouraged to register as soon as possible," Mr. Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>He also urged the diaspora to popularise the event among other Indians to make the event a huge success.</p>

<p>Odisha Chief Minister Majhi urged the Indian diaspora across the world to visit Odisha and hoped that they would be able to witness and appreciate the rich historical, cultural, and spiritual heritage of the state.</p>

<p>He encouraged them to participate in next year's convention in large numbers.</p>

<p>The theme of the PBD Convention for 2025 is "Diaspora's Contribution to a Viksit Bharat".</p>

<p>It will be inaugurated by Prime Minister Modi. A youth edition of the convention will be held in partnership with the Ministry of Youth Affairs and Sports. President Droupadi Murmu will confer the Pravasi Bharatiya Samman Awards and preside over the valedictory session.</p>

<p>The launch of the PBD website marks the commencement of online registration for participating in the convention 2025.</p>

<p>The website will also facilitate reservation of accommodation in Odisha and provide detailed information on the event.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ok72tep8_s-jaishankar-x-handle_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr. Jaishankar said that the Indian diaspora is a pillar of strength in tackling global issues]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-whats-climate-finance-and-why-are-countries-fighting-over-it-at-cop29-7009993]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What's Climate Finance And Why Countries Are Fighting Over It At COP29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-whats-climate-finance-and-why-are-countries-fighting-over-it-at-cop29-7009993]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:23:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Countries are negotiating a higher target for payments starting next year, but some have been reluctant to confirm its size until it is clear which countries will contribute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The main task for nearly 200 countries at the UN's COP29 climate summit is to broker a deal that ensures up to trillions of dollars in financing for climate projects worldwide.</p>

<p>Here is what you need to know about the Nov. 11-22 summit talks on finance.</p>

<h2><strong>WHAT IS THE GOAL?</strong></h2>

<p>Wealthy countries pledged in 2009 to contribute USD100 billion a year to help developing nations cope with the costs of a transition to clean energy and adapting to the conditions of a warming world.</p>

<p>Those payments began in 2020 but were only fully met in 2022. The USD100 billion pledge expires this year.</p>

<p>Countries are negotiating a higher target for payments starting next year, but some have been reluctant to confirm its size until it is clear which countries will contribute.</p>

<p>Instead, they are circling around the idea of a multi-layered target, with a core amount from wealthy countries' government coffers, and a larger sum that includes financing from other sources such as multilateral lending institutions or private investors.</p>

<p>In the past, public money made up the bulk of contributions to the USD100 billion goal.</p>

<h3><strong>WHO SHOULD CONTRIBUTE?</strong></h3>

<p>Donald Trump's victory in the U.S. election has overshadowed the COP29 talks, because of expectations he will halt U.S. climate finance contributions.</p>

<p>That would leave a hole in any new global target that other donors would struggle to fill. Some climate negotiators also expect the overall target agreed at COP29 to be smaller, given the expected lack of contributions from the world's biggest economy.</p>

<p>The U.S. provided nearly USD10 billion in international climate finance last year, less than the European Union's USD31 billion contribution.</p>

<p>So far, only a few dozen rich countries have been obliged to pay U.N. climate finance and they want fast-developing nations, such as China and Gulf oil nations to start paying as well.</p>

<p>Beijing opposes this, saying that as a developing country it does not have the same responsibility as long-industrialised nations like Britain and the United States.</p>

<p>While China is already investing hundreds of billions of dollars in electric vehicles and renewable energy abroad, it does so on its own terms.</p>

<p>Any COP29 deal would need consensus approval.</p>

<h3><strong>HOW MUCH IS NEEDED?</strong></h3>

<p>Developing countries say the specific amount needed to tackle climate change should be the starting point for negotiations to ensure the final target adequately covers their needs.</p>

<p>By most estimates, developing countries need more than USD 1 trillion per year to meet their climate goals and protect their societies from extreme weather.</p>

<p>Many countries have come to the Baku talks with a number in mind.</p>

<p>Arab countries including Saudi Arabia want a funding target of USD 1.1 trillion per year, with $441 billion directly from developed country governments in grants.</p>

<p>India, African countries and small island nations have also said more than USD 1 trillion should be raised per year, but with mixed views on how much should come from wealthy governments.</p>

<p>The rich countries expected to provide the money have not specified a target sum, though the U.S. and the EU have agreed it must be more than the previous USD 100 billion target.</p>

<p>Some developed country diplomats say that, with national budgets already stretched by other economic pressures, a major increase beyond USD 100 billion is unrealistic.</p>

<h3><strong>WHY IT MATTERS</strong></h3>

<p>Climate change has accelerated. Human activities - mainly, burning fossil fuels - have heated up the planet's long-term average temperature by around 1.3 Celsius, turbocharging disastrous floods, hurricanes and extreme heatwaves.</p>

<p>Countries' plans for emissions cuts are not enough to slow climate change, and would instead lead to far worse warming.</p>

<p>Next year's U.N. deadline for countries to update their national climate plans is a last opportunity to avert disaster, scientists say.</p>

<p>Negotiators have said a failure at COP29 to produce a major funding deal could result in countries offering weak climate plans on the grounds that they cannot afford to implement more ambitious ones.</p>

<p>Most of the world's climate-friendly spending so far has been skewed towards major economies such as China and the United States. Africa's 54 countries received just 2 per cent of global renewable energy investments over the last two decades.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gbtfbi2_pollution-climate-change-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[COP29 2024:Countries' plans for emissions cuts are not enough to slow climate change.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taliban-conduct-sixth-public-execution-since-return-to-power-in-2021-7009994]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taliban Conducts 6th Public Execution Since Return To Power In 2021]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taliban-conduct-sixth-public-execution-since-return-to-power-in-2021-7009994]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:23:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taliban authorities in eastern Afghanistan on Wednesday executed a convicted murderer by gunfire at a sports stadium, in the sixth public execution since their return to power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taliban authorities in eastern Afghanistan on Wednesday executed a convicted murderer by gunfire at a sports stadium, in the sixth public execution since their return to power.</p>

<p>The condemned man was shot with three bullets to the chest by a member of the victim's family in front of thousands of spectators in Gardez, the capital of Paktia province, according to an AFP journalist at the scene.</p>

<p>The evening before the execution the governor's office called on officials and residents to "attend this event" on social media.</p>

<p>"A murderer was sentenced to retaliation punishment," said a statement from Afghanistan's supreme court which named the condemned as Mohammad Ayaz Asad.</p>

<p>The execution order was signed by the Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada, the court said.</p>

<p>The convict had been in detention since before the Taliban came to power for killing another man, Habibullah Saif-ul-Qatal, while the case was "examined very precisely and repeatedly" by three military courts, the statement said.</p>

<p>The victim's family was given the opportunity to stay the execution, but they refused, the statement added.</p>

<p>Among the crowd at the execution were high level officials, including Interior Minister Sirajuddin Haqqani.</p>

<p><strong>'Eye for an eye'</strong></p>

<p>Public executions were common during the Taliban's first rule from 1996 to 2001, but according to an AFP tally only a handful have been carried out since their return to power in August 2021.</p>

<p>In 2022, Akhundzada ordered judges to fully implement all aspects of the Taliban government's interpretation of Islamic law -- including "eye for an eye" punishments known as "qisas", allowing for the death penalty in retribution for the crime of murder.</p>

<p>In February, three public executions were carried out within a week.</p>

<p>Two men were executed by multiple gunshots to the back in front of a large crowd in eastern Ghazni city, followed days later by a similar public execution in northern Jowzjan province.</p>

<p>Corporal punishments -- mainly flogging -- have been common under the Taliban authorities and employed for crimes including theft, adultery and alcohol consumption.</p>

<p>Law and order is central to the severe ideology of the Taliban, who emerged from the chaos of a civil war following the withdrawal of Soviet forces from Afghanistan in 1989.</p>

<p>One of the most infamous images from that era depicted the 1999 execution of a woman wearing an all-covering burqa in a Kabul stadium. She had been accused of killing her husband.</p>

<p>The United Nations and rights groups such as Amnesty International have condemned the Taliban government's use of corporal punishment and the death penalty.</p>

<p>China, Iran, Saudi Arabia, Egypt and the United States were respectively ranked the world's most prolific practitioners of the death penalty in 2022, according to Amnesty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/3folm19g_taliban-generic_625x300_30_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The execution order was signed by the Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-racism-against-indians-is-growing-in-canada-7009914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: 'Seen As Competition': Why Racism Against Indians Is Growing In Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-racism-against-indians-is-growing-in-canada-7009914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:14:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There has been a growing sentiment in Canada that the country has lost control over immigration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Indians at a consular camp in Brampton, Ontario on November 3." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o3qgbf48_canada_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Indians at a consular camp in Brampton, Ontario on November 3." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Indians at a consular camp in Brampton, Ontario on November 3 (<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">PTI)</span></p>
</div>

<p>Every morning, Pushkar Chawla makes it a point to reach the local bus stop on time, hoping to catch the bus to his workplace in Brampton, Canada. But he is apprehensive about the bus driver, about whether the driver will stop for him to board when there is no white person at the bus stop. “The bus driver stops only if there's a white person; otherwise, he drives by,” says Chawla.</p>

<p>In the same city—Brampton—Gursimran Singh Talwar faces a ‘subtle kind of racism' when he is labelled as ‘too serious' or ‘quiet' by his colleagues. “My social relationships and professional growth were impacted by these presumptions. My Canadian identity is not entirely acknowledged, as I'm constantly asked, 'Where are you really from?'" says Talwar.</p>

<p>The recent surge of hateful incidents has coincided with rising tensions between India and Canada, worsening the climate of discrimination. However, this year, the cases of xenophobia can largely be traced back to anti-immigration rhetoric spread online, particularly in social media comment sections and TikTok clips mocking Indians. So much so that hate towards Indians and South Asians seems to have been normalised in Canada.</p>

<h2><b>Immigration Is Irking Canadians</b></h2>

<p>Increased immigration has reinforced the narrative that all current societal problems are due to immigrants. Sadly, the anti-India rhetoric is influencing public discourse and shaping harmful policies.</p>

<p>The recent attack on Hindu devotees at the Hindu Sabha temple in Brampton by a pro-Khalistani mob has shaken the Indian community. Once considered largely law-abiding, thousands of Indian-origin people—both Hindus and Sikhs—protested against the violence. It was also a demonstration of their unity, given that a small group of pro-Khalistanis have been patronised by Justin Trudeau's government for vote-bank politics.</p>

<p>Canada used to be seen as the most accepting country in the world for migrants. However, things have changed dramatically on the ground. “The large number of Indian immigrants arriving in recent years has increased their presence in schools, workplaces, and neighbourhoods. This change has made some Canadians uneasy, as they see Indians as competition for jobs,” says Chawla.</p>

<p>The derogatory social media posts spreading falsehoods about Indians have gained traction in online publications and mainstream media, giving them credibility. In July, two posts about Indians' 'toilet habits' went viral. One video on TikTok claimed that Indian immigrants were soiling Wasaga Beach in Ontario; another post on X featured a photo of a turbaned man allegedly relieving himself in a parking lot in Brampton. Later, cyber experts suggested that both posts were likely doctored, but this did not stop the chain of hate-mongering.</p>

<p>In October, amid the ongoing diplomatic tensions between India and Canada, Ashwin Annamalai, a Canadian citizen of Indian origin, shared a disturbing video online. Annamalai was seen being the target of a racist outburst from a Canadian white woman who wrongly assumed he was an Indian national.</p>

<p>According to Canada's 2021 census, Sikhs constituted 2.1% of the population, yet they remain frequent targets of racist stereotypes and attacks. As per the Canadian Race Relations Foundation, hate crimes against South Asians increased by 143% between 2019 and 2022, and a quarter of South Asian-Canadians reported experiencing discrimination or harassment in 2022 alone.</p>

<p>“Preconceived notions about Indians being ‘too successful' or ‘too different' are examples of stereotypes that fuel prejudice. Xenophobic feelings were heightened by the COVID-19 outbreak, as many people linked the virus to Asians,” says Talwar.</p>

<h2><b>No Longer A 'Model Minority'?</b></h2>

<p>Canada has been plagued with economic challenges, ranging from a strained healthcare system to a housing crisis and a rising cost of living. White native Canadians increasingly view immigrants, particularly those of Indian and South Asian origin, as being responsible for the crisis.</p>

<p>There has been a growing sentiment in Canada that the country has lost control over immigration. Immigrants are being blamed for the housing and infrastructure crisis and are seen as competing with Canadians for jobs.</p>

<p>Data from the September 2024 Environics Focus Canada survey reveals that 58% of Canadians, the highest since 1998, believe there is too much immigration. As a result, the Canadian government recently made significant cuts to the number of immigrants allowed into Canada. The number of new permanent residents (PRs) is expected to be reduced by nearly 20% from next year.</p>

<p>“Some native Canadians no longer see Indians as a ‘model minority' since many Indian immigrants have succeeded in industries like technology and healthcare,” says Eshan Sodhi, a resident of Mississauga. International students—most of whom are from India—have also been blamed for Canada's housing woes and skyrocketing rents.</p>

<p>On November 8, Canada discontinued the Student Direct Stream visa programme for international students. The programme, which specifically focused on bringing student immigrants from 14 countries, including India, was implemented by Immigration, Refugees and Citizenship Canada (IRCC) in 2018 to expedite study permit applications. Sources suggest that the government closed the programme due to negative reactions from native Canadians over the housing and resource crisis.</p>

<p>The already tense relations between Canada and India following the assassination of a prominent Khalistan separatist last year have made the situation even more fraught. The latest attack on a Hindu temple in Brampton has only added to the tension.</p>

<p>“The Khalistani movement and other political issues have also fuelled unfavourable opinions, especially in the context of Canada-India relations. Finally, the rise in nationalism and anti-immigration sentiment has increased distrust toward immigrant communities, particularly Indians,” says Sodhi.</p>

<p><em>(The author is Contributing Editor, NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lqmpjav_canada_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indians at a consular camp in Brampton, Ontario on November 3 (PTI)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-threatens-nearly-half-of-warm-water-coral-species-report-7009907]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Climate Change Threatens Nearly Half Of Warm-Water Coral Species: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/climate-change-threatens-nearly-half-of-warm-water-coral-species-report-7009907]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 16:13:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Almost half of all warm-water species of coral are threatened with extinction -- and climate change is the chief culprit, a new report said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost half of all warm-water species of coral are threatened with extinction -- and climate change is the chief culprit, a new report said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The updated risk assessment from the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) was announced at the COP29 climate summit in Azerbaijan, which is being skipped by the leaders of many top polluting nations.</p>

<p>Oceans have absorbed around 90 percent of the excess heat in the atmosphere due to the release of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases.</p>

<p>Rising ocean temperatures have spurred mass bleaching events at coral reefs across the world, threatening crucial ecosystems for marine life as well as the livelihoods of people who rely on them.</p>

<p>The updated assessment of the IUCN's Red List of Threatened Species looked at reef-building corals, which live in warm, shallow waters in tropical areas.</p>

<p>Its analysis found that 892 reef-building coral species are now considered threatened, representing 44 percent of the total.</p>

<p>This marked a significant increase from the last assessment in 2008, when a third of all species was listed as threatened.</p>

<p>The organisation is still assessing the extinction risk for cold-water coral, which lives in deeper, darker ocean waters, making it difficult to study.</p>

<p>The IUCN called on negotiators at the COP29 conference to act quickly to reduce planet-heating fossil fuel emissions.</p>

<p>"Healthy ecosystems like coral reefs are essential for human livelihoods -- providing food, stabilising coastlines, and storing carbon," IUCN chief Grethel Aguilar said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Climate change remains the leading threat to reef-building corals and is devastating the natural systems we depend on."</p>

<p>As well as global warming, pollution, disease, unsustainable fishing and agricultural runoff also threaten the world's coral.</p>

<p>Most reef-building coral is found across the Indo-Pacific region, such as Australia's Great Barrier Reef which suffered one its worst-ever bleaching events this year.</p>

<p>The IUCN's updated assessment included results from a study about reef-building coral in the Atlantic Ocean, which was published in the PLOS One journal on Wednesday.</p>

<p>That study found that almost one in three -- or 23 out of 85 -- species of Atlantic coral is critically endangered, more than previously thought.</p>

<p>Staghorn coral and elkhorn coral were given as examples of two critically endangered species in the Caribbean that have been hit hard by warming waters, pollution -- and hurricanes.</p>

<p>"Without relevant decisions from those with the power to change this trajectory, we will see the further loss of reefs, and progressive disappearance of coral species at larger and larger scales," warned IUCN coral specialist David Obura.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u9j09i_cop29_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rising ocean temperatures have spurred mass bleaching events at coral reefs across the world. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>