<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 09:53:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-tv-anchor-fired-over-social-media-post-criticising-mens-body-odour-6405859]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan TV Anchor Fired Over Social Media Post Criticising Men's Body Odour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-tv-anchor-fired-over-social-media-post-criticising-mens-body-odour-6405859]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 08:22:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Tokyo-based television news anchor was fired from her job and faced online backlash after a controversial post on social media in which she criticised men's hygiene habits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Tokyo-based television news anchor was fired from her job and faced online backlash after a controversial post on social media in which she criticised men's hygiene habits. According to the <em>South China Morning Post (SCMP)</em>, Yuri Kawaguchi, 29, is a freelance announcer known for her feminist views. She also works as a lecturer on harassment prevention. She faced severe backlash online after she claimed that men's body odour was hard to endure and suggested they shower more often.</p>

<p>In a now-deleted post on X (formerly Twitter), Ms Kawaguchi voiced her frustration about men's hygiene during the sweltering summer months, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3275405/feminist-japan-tv-anchor-fired-raising-stink-over-hard-endure-mens-body-odour" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet</a>. "I'm really sorry if there's a personal situation, but the smell of men in the summer or the body odour of unsanitary people is so uncomfortable," she wrote, advising men to shower more frequently and use deodorant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I want to be clean, so I take several showers a day, use freshening wipes, and apply sweat inhibitors year-round. I think more men should do this," the 29-year-old added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Kawaguchi's post, perceived as discriminatory against men, offended many online. "Only blaming men is infuriating and undoubtedly discrimination. Women, especially older women, can have body odour too. I'm really uncomfortable with this," one social media user wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her post also prompted scrutiny of her private life, including her divorce. She was labelled as a "materialistic woman out of touch with the struggles of ordinary people".&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the controversy escalated, Ms Kawaguchi issued a public apology and removed the post. &nbsp;"This time, because of my careless remarks, many people were upset and hurt. I will deeply reflect on this. In the future, I will work hard not to hurt anyone with my remarks. I am really sorry," she said.</p>

<p>However, the apology did little to quell the uproar. VOICE, the agency that managed Ms Kawaguchi, announced that it was terminating her contract, citing "defamation of the honour of the opposite sex" as the reason. In a statement, the agency said it had received numerous complaints and emails, and stressed that it was against their principles for a professional to use language that harms others and causes discomfort.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/female-intern-in-vietnam-resigns-after-kiss-threat-from-male-colleague-at-team-building-event-6405668">Female Intern In Vietnam Resigns After Kiss Threat From Male Colleague At Team-Building Event</a></strong></p>

<p>Another firm which hired the anchor as a lecturer for harassment prevention education also terminated her contract. But the decision of these two companies was criticised by Japanese netizens as "too extreme". While some said that the 29-year-old's dismissal shows a mirror to the challenges faced by women in a male-dominated society in Japan, most were not kind.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A woman asks men to be tidy and maintain decorum, yet it triggers outrage. It just shows that Japan has been a male-dominated society for too long. No matter how dirty men are, as soon as a woman complains, they punish her," one person wrote.</p>

<p>"Why are Japanese men so sensitive? They cannot handle a bit of criticism. Women are expected to maintain beauty, cleanliness, and fitness without complaint, yet men face no such expectations. If that isn't gender bias, then what is?" said another.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/r70fthmo_yuri-kawaguchi_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The anchor's post prompted scrutiny of her private life, including her divorce.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-and-proud-how-kamala-harris-is-winning-over-indian-americans-6405829]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Asian And Proud: How Kamala Harris Is Winning Over Indian-Americans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-asian-and-proud-how-kamala-harris-is-winning-over-indian-americans-6405829]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 08:11:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In her acceptance speech for the Democratic nomination, Kamala Harris vowed to resist the influence of authoritarian leaders, who she implied have allegedly manipulated Donald Trump's foreign policy by appealing to his autocratic tendencies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In her acceptance speech for the Democratic nomination, Kamala Harris vowed to resist the influence of authoritarian leaders, who she implied have allegedly manipulated Donald Trump's foreign policy by appealing to his autocratic tendencies. In a bid to position herself against Republican frontrunner Trump, Harris is stressing her resolve on national security, portraying the billionaire as a riskier alternative.</p>

<p>In her speech, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-donald-trump-race-to-us-election-photo-finish-6400682" target="_blank">Harris</a> made it abundantly clear that her presidency would mark a definitive break from the Trump era, particularly in foreign policy. "I will not cozy up to tyrants and dictators," she declared.</p>

<p>As Dr Sweta Chakraborty, a Climate Surrogate for the Harris campaign, explains, Harris's approach to policy formation is rooted in a clear-eyed assessment of the threats facing the country, both from foreign adversaries and from within. Dr Chakraborty, who has been closely involved in the campaign and was present at the Democratic National Convention (DNC) in Chicago, noted that Harris's message is resonating strongly with Indian-Americans and other minority communities who see in her as their leader.</p>

<h3><strong>Indian-American Perspective</strong></h3>

<p>"Kamala Harris is polling a few points ahead of Donald Trump and will surely get a surge following the DNC. Indian-Americans like myself are banding together and supporting her through various efforts and speciality collaborations. For example, we are raising funds through 'South Asians in Climate' after the DNC and ahead of the 'Harris for President Climate Group' official launch this September. South Asians are in. Climate voters are in, and as a South Asian climate surrogate, I represent both voter groups that broadly support Kamala Harris for President," Dr Chakraborty told NDTV.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-presidential-election-when-kamala-harris-gave-her-watch-to-chitthi-aunt-recalls-fond-memories-6403270">When Kamala Harris Gave Her Watch To 'Chitthi': Aunt Recalls Fond Memories</a></p>

<p>Born in Oakland, California in 1964, Harris's father is Donald Harris, a man of Afro-Jamaican descent while his mother is Shyamala Gopalan, who emigrated to the US at the age of 19 to pursue her doctorate in nutrition and endocrinology.</p>

<p>"Having a President who shares ancestry with South Asians in America shows that South Asian immigrants and their offspring have a clear place in America. A daughter of India can make it to the highest elected office in the United States, which shows that the sky is the limit for the Indian diaspora in the US. Indians in the US already enjoy the status as the highest-earning demographic. An Indian will elevate that status and make history for minorities and women more broadly," Dr Chakraborty said.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>The Usha Vance Factor</strong></h3>

<p>However, Harris is not the only Indian-American whose name and image are plastered across the US presidential campaign. Over at the Republican camp, Trump's Vice President pick JD Vance's wife is Usha Vance who traces her roots to Andhra Pradesh's Vadluru.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Usha's father, Chilukuri Radhakrishnan, was brought up in Chennai but went to the US to pursue higher studies. Usha was raised in San Diego, California and she met JD Vance at Yale Law School before getting married in 2014.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Video </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-kamala-harris-grandnieces-tutorial-on-pronouncing-leaders-name-6399146">Kamala Harris' Grandnieces' Tutorial On Pronouncing Leader's Name</a></p>

<p>"Usha Vance and her husband are trading in their morals for power," Dr Chakraborty alleged. "It is clear they had authentically shared liberal values with friends and classmates from university, but edited and adjusted their stances to maneuver in the conservative party, which they perceived would be the easier route to power."</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris vs Donald Trump&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Dr Chakraborty highlighted a stark contrast between Harris and Trump: where Trump has prioritised tax breaks for billionaires and deregulation of corporate polluters, Harris has pledged to hold the oil and gas industry accountable, invest in a clean energy economy, and ensure that the benefits of climate action are shared by all Americans, not just the wealthy elite.</p>

<p>When Harris ran for vice president in 2020, her climate plan was even more aggressive than what ultimately passed during Joe Biden's presidency as the Inflation Reduction Act - a landmark climate legislation in American history. Now, as she prepares to release her full climate agenda in September, Harris is positioning herself as the 'Climate President' for the United States, Dr Chakraborty said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As an Indian woman, she also represents members of American society that have been historically disenfranchised. She is physically the opposite of Biden and represents the ascendency of women and a future society that is more equitable and fair to all genders and races," she said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/obhmofm8_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris's mother is Shyamala Gopalan, who emigrated to the US at the age of 19.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-soldiers-detain-ex-supreme-court-judge-near-border-with-india-6404803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladeshi Soldiers Detain Ex-Supreme Court Judge Near Border With India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshi-soldiers-detain-ex-supreme-court-judge-near-border-with-india-6404803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 08:06:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A retired judge of Bangladesh's Supreme Court was detained from the northeastern frontier with India in Sylhet while he was allegedly attempting to flee the country, the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) said late on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A retired judge of Bangladesh's Supreme Court was detained from the northeastern frontier with India in Sylhet while he was allegedly attempting to flee the country, the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) said late on Friday.</p>

<p>The report came hours after the arrest of Awami League leader ASM Firoz from his residence.</p>

<p>The BGB headquarters, in an SMS, informed reporters that they have detained former top appellate division judge of the Supreme Court Shamsuddin Chowdhury Manik as he was trying to cross over to India through Sylhet's Kanaighat border.</p>

<p>Newspaper Prothom Alo said Manik was kept at a BGB outpost till midnight citing the camp's in-charge.</p>

<p>Bangladesh descended into chaos after ousted premier Sheikh Hasina's government collapsed and she fled to India on August 5 amid violent protests over quota for government jobs, while the Army stepped in to fill the power vacuum.</p>

<p>Before that, anti-government protests had killed more than 500 people since mid-July. Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus took oath as the Chief Adviser of the interim government on August 8.</p>

<p>Since August 5, a number of leaders of the deposed regime, including senior ministers, have been arrested -- many of them on murder charges.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Army has earlier said that several hundred leaders of Hasina's Awami League and others have been sheltered in cantonments as their lives were at risk.</p>

<p>Former law minister Anisul Huq and the ex-premier's private sector affairs adviser Salman F Rahman were the first to be arrested from Dhaka's main river port Sadarghat terminal area as they were allegedly trying to leave Dhaka on a boat.</p>

<p>A number of members of Hasina's cabinet, including former foreign minister Hassan Mahmud and former social welfare minister Dipu Moni, several lawmakers and leaders of Awami League and its allies, including pro-left Workers Party chairman Rashed Khan Menon, and a number of recently sacked military and civil officials have been arrested.</p>

<p>This included sacked major general Ziaul Hassan, who was serving as the head of the government's telecommunications system, and Chittagong Port Authority chairman rear admiral Mohammad Sohail, who once was the spokesman of the elite anti-crime Rapid Action Battalion.</p>

<p>A TV journalist couple Farzana Rupa and her husband Shakil Ahmed have also been arrested.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pagcgin_bsf-generic-border-security-force-ani_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BSF personnel keep vigil amid high alert at the India-Bangladesh international Border.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/female-intern-in-vietnam-resigns-after-kiss-threat-from-male-colleague-at-team-building-event-6405668]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Female Intern In Vietnam Resigns After Kiss Threat From Male Colleague]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/female-intern-in-vietnam-resigns-after-kiss-threat-from-male-colleague-at-team-building-event-6405668]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 07:27:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A female intern in Vietnam recently resigned from her job after an older male colleague allegedly threatened to kiss her at a company team-building event.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A female intern in Vietnam recently resigned from her job after an older male colleague allegedly threatened to kiss her at a company team-building event. According to the <em>South China Morning Post (SCMP)</em>, the woman, identified as Huynh Anh My, said that during an internship last year, she took part in a mandatory event with a company in Hanoi. However, after she was forced to play a "weird, perverted" game at the boozy event, she resigned from the firm, saying that the incident made her feel so anxious and terrified that she could not face anyone at the office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Huynh said that the team-building event was mandatory for all. Skipping the seaside trip would have resulted in penalties or extra work, she told a local Vietnamese news outlet, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3275417/shocked-vietnam-woman-resigns-after-kiss-threat-older-colleague-team-building-event" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>SCMP</em></a>. She said that she and her colleagues were on the beach taking part in a water-carrying competition when she began to feel tired.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The weather was scorching, and I was exhausted from hauling buckets of water. I noticed that a female colleague sat to rest but was playfully pushed into the sea by a male colleague. I could not help but think, this is torture, not team-building," Ms Huynh said.</p>

<p>After the competition, the intern said that her team leader suggested everyone play a drinking game. "A male colleague, about the same age as my father said if I did not finish three glasses of alcohol in one go, I had to kiss him," she said.</p>

<p>Ms Huynh was aghast and wondered to herself why there were such "weird, perverted games". She said that the male colleague then walked over to her, grabbed her hand, and insisted she drink.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I burst into tears because he kept getting close to my face and I was so scared. It wasn't until I managed to drink all three glasses that he finally stopped and moved on to another girl," she continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"After this, I was terrified and anxious for days, and I could not face anyone at the company. Eventually, I resigned," the woman told the outlet. She also said that before resigning, she reported the incident to her supervisor but received no feedback.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/youve-accomplished-nothing-intern-shares-worst-interview-experience-with-crypto-ceo-6400062">"You've Accomplished Nothing": Intern Shares "Worst Interview Experience" With Crypto CEO</a></strong></p>

<p>Ms Huynh's story has gone viral online. "This is sexual harassment. Team-building activities should be gentle and respectful to all employees," wrote one user. "Not only young women, but people of any age and gender can experience workplace harassment," said another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In my previous company, I had to carry a female colleague in a princess-style during a group activity, and both of us felt very uncomfortable with it," shird a third user.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i4eliqh_employee-generic-_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The team-building event was mandatory for all, the woman said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-elite-snipers-8-kills-how-deadly-russian-prison-standoff-unfolded-6405603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ISIS, Elite Snipers, 8 Kills: How Deadly Russian Prison Standoff Unfolded]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isis-elite-snipers-8-kills-how-deadly-russian-prison-standoff-unfolded-6405603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 07:08:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Four jail staffers were killed after a group of prisoners staged a violent revolt at the high-security IK-19 Surovikino penal colony in Russia's Volgograd region on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Four jail staffers were killed after a group of prisoners staged a violent revolt at the high-security IK-19 Surovikino penal colony in Russia's Volgograd region on Friday. The prisoners, armed with knives and claiming allegiance to the so-called Islamic State (ISIS), took hostages and temporarily seized control of a section of the prison, leading to a dramatic and deadly standoff with Russian special forces.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The crisis began during what was supposed to be a routine disciplinary commission meeting, a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2yp4gg0z5o">report </a>said. As the meeting was in progress, a group of inmates, later identified as Ramzidin Toshev (28) Rustamchon Navruzi (23), Nazirchon Toshov (28) and Temur Khusinov (29), launched their attack. All four men, hailing from Uzbekistan and Tajikistan, slashed guards with knives, injuring several and taking eight prison employees and four fellow convicts hostage.</p>

<p>During the siege, an image circulated on social media, showing an inmate holding a knife over a bloodied prison guard. Another video showed the attackers in the prison yard where one of their hostages was in a sitting position with his face covered in blood. In videos released by the attackers, they declared their allegiance to ISIS and claimed the attack was an act of revenge for the persecution of Muslims.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/history-made-today-says-ukraine-president-volodymyr-zelensky-after-meeting-pm-narendra-modi-10-points-6403784">"History Made Today," Says Zelensky After Meeting PM Modi: 10 Points</a></p>

<p>As the situation escalated, Russian special forces, including heavily armed troops and elite snipers from the Rosgvardia National Guard, were deployed to the scene. The prison, located in the remote town of Surovikino, approximately 850 kilometres south of Moscow, became a battleground.</p>

<p>After hours of tense negotiations and strategic planning, the special forces stormed the facility. In the ensuing operation, all four attackers were shot dead by snipers, effectively ending the standoff. However, four prison employees lost their lives, with three killed on the spot and a fourth succumbing to injuries in the hospital. Additionally, several other guards and prisoners sustained injuries, some of which were severe.</p>

<p></p>

<p>"Snipers of the special forces of the Russian National Guard in the Volgograd region, with four precise shots, neutralised four prisoners who had taken prison employees hostage. The hostages have been released," said state news agency RIA, quoting the national guard.</p>

<p>This marks the second such incident in recent months, following a similar hostage-taking event in June at a prison in the Rostov region, where ISIS-affiliated prisoners also attempted a revolt, resulting in the deaths of five prisoners and the capture of one.</p>

<p>In response to the Volgograd standoff, Russian President Vladimir Putin was briefed during a virtual meeting with security chiefs, where it was confirmed that the situation posed no immediate threat to the civilian population. "Everyone on our territory is obliged to respect and comply with the laws of Russia. We will not allow anyone to try to incite ethnic discord," said Volgograd's regional governor, Andrei Bocharov.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7qi00f6g_russia-prison-standoff-reuters-_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In total, 8 were killed in the Volgograd prison standoff.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-talks-with-volodymyr-zelensky-announces-new-military-aid-for-ukraine-6405191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Talks With Zelensky, Announces New Military Aid For Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-talks-with-volodymyr-zelensky-announces-new-military-aid-for-ukraine-6405191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 04:46:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden spoke with his Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday and announced a new round of military aid for Kyiv that the Pentagon valued at $125 million.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden spoke with his Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday and announced a new round of military aid for Kyiv that the Pentagon valued at $125 million.</p>

<p>The call between the two leaders came ahead of Ukraine's independence day, and on the same day that Washington announced sweeping sanctions against hundreds of individuals and companies tied to Russia's invasion of the country.</p>

<p>"I am proud we will announce a new package of military aid for Ukraine today," Biden said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The package includes air defense missiles to protect Ukraine's critical infrastructure; counter-drone equipment and anti-armor missiles to defend against Russia's evolving tactics on the battlefield; and ammunition for frontline soldiers and the mobile rocket systems that protect them," he said.</p>

<p>"Russia will not prevail in this conflict. The independent people of Ukraine will prevail -- and the United States, our allies, and our partners, will continue to stand with them every step of the way," Biden added.</p>

<p>The US Defense Department later said the package is worth $125 million and consists of items drawn from American stocks, providing Kyiv with "additional capabilities to meet its most urgent needs."</p>

<p>Zelensky praised the military aid announcement, saying there is an especially urgent requirement for air defenses.</p>

<p>"I welcomed the new US military aid package and emphasized that Ukraine urgently requires the delivery of weapons from the announced packages, particularly additional air defense systems, to reliably protect our cities, communities and critical infrastructure," he said in a post on X.</p>

<p>The United States has been a key military backer of Ukraine, committing more than $55 billion in weapons, ammunition and other security aid since Russia launched its full-scale invasion in February 2022.</p>

<p>- New sanctions on Russia -</p>

<p>The latest aid announcement comes as Ukrainian troops press an attack into Russia's western Kursk region -- an offensive that is the most serious attack by a foreign army on Russian territory since World War II.</p>

<p>Earlier on Friday, the US Treasury, State and Commerce departments announced new sanctions that build on a raft of existing measures enacted against Russia over the invasion.</p>

<p>The sanctions target nearly 400 individuals and entities both inside and outside of Russia "whose products and services enable Russia to sustain its war effort and evade sanctions," the US Treasury Department announced in a statement.</p>

<p>Among those sanctioned were 60 Russia-based defense and technology firms "critical for the sustainment and development of Russia's defense industry," it added.</p>

<p>The State Department said in a separate statement that it was responsible for 190 of the sanctions, and that Treasury was responsible for close to 200 others.</p>

<p>It added that its designations "aim to disrupt sanctions evasion and target entities in multiple third countries," including China, along with businesses supporting the development of Russian energy projects.</p>

<p>Alongside the sanctions unveiled Friday, the Commerce Department announced it was taking "aggressive action" to further restrict the supply of items made in the United States, or labeled as such, to both Russia and Belarus, due to "the Kremlin's illegal war on Ukraine."</p>

<p>"Today's actions will further constrain Russia's ability to arm its military by targeting illicit procurement networks designed to circumvent global export controls," the department said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/tjjj9r4s_biden-zelensky_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden spoke with his Ukrainian counterpart Volodymyr Zelensky on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-says-it-killed-leader-of-al-qaeda-aligned-group-in-syria-6405103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Military Says It Killed Leader Of Al Qaeda-Aligned Group In Syria]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-military-says-it-killed-leader-of-al-qaeda-aligned-group-in-syria-6405103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 04:14:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The U.S. military said it carried out a strike in Syria on Friday that killed a senior leader of an Al Qaeda aligned group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American forces killed a senior leader of an Al-Qaeda-affiliated militant group in a strike in Syria on Friday, the US military said.</p>

<p>The strike targeted Abu Abdul Rahman al-Makki, who was "a Hurras al-Din Shura Council member and senior leader responsible for overseeing terrorist operations from Syria," the US Central Command (CENTCOM) said in a social media post.</p>

<p>"Hurras al-Din is an Al-Qaeda-associated force based in Syria that shares Al-Qaeda's global aspirations to conduct attacks against US and Western interests," CENTCOM said.</p>

<p>The Syrian Observatory for Human Rights war monitor had earlier said that a drone strike on a motorcycle in the southern Idlib countryside had killed Makki, who it said was a Saudi national.</p>

<p>The US military has around 900 troops in Syria as part of the international coalition against the Islamic State group. The coalition was established in 2014 to help combat the jihadists, who had taken over vast swathes of Iraq and Syria.</p>

<p>American forces periodically carry out strikes in Syria targeting militants from IS -- which has since lost the territory it once held -- and other jihadist groups that are deemed to pose a threat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/us-army-reuters_650x400_81504721306.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The U.S. military said it carried out a strike in Syria on Friday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/several-people-dead-in-stabbing-incident-in-western-germany-report-6404899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Several People Dead In Stabbing Incident In Western Germany: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/several-people-dead-in-stabbing-incident-in-western-germany-report-6404899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 03:03:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Several individuals were killed on Friday night when a man stabbed passers-by at random with a knife at a city festival in the western German city of Solingen, newspaper Bild reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several people were killed on Friday night when a man knifed passers-by at random at a festival in the western German city of Solingen, newspaper Bild reported.</p>

<p>Bild said the event occurred around 9:45 p.m. (1945 GMT) and that at least three people were dead and multiple people were wounded.</p>

<p>Witnesses said the perpetrator was at large, the paper added.</p>

<p>The local newspaper Solingen Tageblatt reported on its website that the attack occurred at a festival to honour the town's 650 years.</p>

<p>Local police said they were not yet able to comment.</p>

<p>Local news reports said the stabbings occurred at the Fronhof, a market square in the town where live bands were playing.</p>

<p>Solingen is in North Rhine-Westphalia state, Germany's most populous and bordering the Netherlands.</p>

<p>Fatal stabbings and shootings in Germany are relatively uncommon.</p>

<p>In June, a 29-year-old policeman died after being stabbed in the German city of Mannheim during an attack on a right-wing demonstration.</p>

<p>There was a stabbing attack on a train in 2021, injuring several.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/i0l77h5o_german-police-generic_625x300_29_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several people dead in stabbing incident in the western German city of Solingen.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-in-ukraine-volodymyr-zelensky-says-pm-modi-wants-peace-more-than-vladimir-putin-6404752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky Says "PM Modi Wants Peace More Than Putin"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-in-ukraine-volodymyr-zelensky-says-pm-modi-wants-peace-more-than-vladimir-putin-6404752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 02:16:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy on Friday said he looks forward to visiting India as it can be a "key" in the global diplomatic efforts to end the war between his country and Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy on Friday said he looks forward to visiting India as it can be a "key" in the global diplomatic efforts to end the war between his country and Russia.</p>

<p>"India (is a) big influential country, not only in the world (but) also through the circle of very skeptical countries. If we will change India's attitude to this war and to Russia, we will stop the war, because Putin will want to stop it," Zeleskyy said in reply to a question while interacting with the visiting Indian media.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian president described Prime Minister Narendra Modi's first visit to Kyiv as "historic." During their bilateral talks, PM Modi invited Zelenskyy to visit India.</p>

<p>"Modi's visit was historic," and added: "I very much need your country on our side, not balancing between the US and Russia." PM Modi's nearly nine-hour visit to Ukraine, the first by an Indian prime minister since Ukraine's independence in 1991, came six weeks after he held summit talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin in July in Moscow.</p>

<p>During the bilateral talks, PM Modi had earlier told Zelenskyy that both Ukraine and Russia should sit together without wasting time to find ways to end the ongoing war and that India had been on the side of peace since the beginning of the conflict in February 2022.</p>

<p>"When you begin a strategic partnership, and you begin some dialogue, you don't need to lose time. That's why I think it will be good to meet together again, and if our meeting will be in India, I'll be happy," Zelenskyy said.</p>

<p>"I think, to understand a country is to understand people also. It's better to be in your country because to find the key to your country and to your Prime Minister is to see your people and I need very much to find the key to your country, because I very much need your country on our side, not balancing between the US and Russia," he said.</p>

<p>"It's not about your historical choice, but who knows, maybe your country can be the key in this diplomatic influence," he said, adding, "That's why I'll be happy to come to India as soon as your government, Prime Minister (PM Modi) will be ready to see me." Replying to another question, he said, "We want him (PM Modi) very much to have peace summits, and of course we will be happy to work on it and of course, if he has his ideas, we will be happy to discuss it.</p>

<p>"But we don't change our territories on any propositions ... we don't change our people to any propositions, our territories our values and our freedom and democracy to any propositions ... we will not change," he said.</p>

<p>"PM Modi wants peace more than Putin. The problem is Putin doesn't want (peace). I don't know what they spoke during their meeting. But I ...." Zelenskyy said and shrugged with an expression of exasperation.</p>

<p>Asked about the discussion about defence production, Zelenskyy said, "We spoke basically about some technologies (but) we are open for a very big deal if India will be ready." Answering a question about India not supporting a UN resolution (against Russia some months ago), Zelenskyy said he wanted to forgo what happened in the past and "before new resolutions, we have to speak, we have to make more strong relations between our country (and India) before new decisions." "We will not have big challenges in our relations in the future. And I will focus on it, on future relations between our countries," he added.</p>

<p>Pointing out that there are very significant contracts between India and Russia vis-a-vis oil, the Ukrainian president said, "Putin is afraid of losing the economy, he has nothing except for oil, his main currency is oil. They do have a kind of energy-based economy, and they're export-oriented." "So, the countries importing energy resources from the Russian Federation, then they will be helping the whole world," he added.</p>

<p>On Indian citizens in Ukrainian prison, Zelenskyy denied there were any but added that if there were, he would release them and immediately inform PM Modi.</p>

<p>He said he read media reports about the death of some Indian nationals working for the Russian Army in its war with Ukraine.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/sep8ise_zelensky-pm-modi_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky described PM Modi's first visit to Kyiv as "historic".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-suspends-us-presidential-campaign-endorses-donald-trump-6404539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert Kennedy Jr Suspends US Presidential Campaign, Endorses Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-kennedy-jr-suspends-us-presidential-campaign-endorses-donald-trump-6404539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 24 Aug 2024 01:04:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said on Friday he would suspend his campaign, and endorsed Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said on Friday he would suspend his campaign, and endorsed Republican Donald Trump, likely ending a presidential bid that he began as a Democrat trading on one of the most famous names in American politics.</p>

<p>His campaign indicated that he feared staying in the race would siphon support from former President Trump, who is locked in a tight contest with Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris ahead of the Nov. 5 election.</p>

<p>An environmental lawyer, anti-vaccine activist and son and nephew of two titans of Democratic politics who were assassinated during the turbulent 1960s, Kennedy entered the race in April 2023 as a challenger to President Joe Biden for the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>With voters at the time turned off by both the aging Biden and the legally embattled Trump, interest in Kennedy soared. He shifted his plans and decided to run as an independent, and a November 2023 Reuters/Ipsos poll showed Kennedy drawing the support of 20% of Americans in a three-way race with Biden and Trump.</p>

<p>He ran a high-profile advertisement during the February 2024 Super Bowl that invoked his father, U.S. Senator Robert F. Kennedy, and uncle, U.S. President John F. Kennedy, and drew outrage from much of his high-profile family, who condemned his campaign.</p>

<p>For a time, both the Biden and Trump campaigns showed signs they were worried that Kennedy could draw enough support to change the election outcome. He faced an uphill battle in winning spots on the ballot as an independent but secured key positions including in Georgia, Michigan, Minnesota and North Carolina -- half of the competitive swing states expected to determine the election's outcome.</p>

<p>But as the race changed quickly in the last two months -- with Trump surviving an assassination attempt and the 81-year-old Biden bowing to pressure from his own party and passing the campaign torch to Harris -- voter interest in Kennedy, 70, waned.</p>

<p>An Ipsos poll early this month showed his national support had fallen to 4%, a tiny number, but one that could still be meaningful in a tight race such as the current Trump-Harris matchup.</p>

<p>His campaign had signaled over the past few days that a change was coming, as Kennedy set his Phoenix address. His running mate Nicole Shanahan said in an interview earlier that if the pair stayed in the race as independents, they could ultimate boost Harris' chances.</p>

<p>In exchange for endorsing Trump, Kennedy was hoping for a job in a potential Trump administration, a super PAC supporting Kennedy told Reuters on Wednesday. He also wanted Trump to allow his political movement to continue in some fashion, which could include staying on the ballot in some states.</p>

<p>Kennedy painted himself as a political outsider. He told Reuters in an interview in March that if elected president he would not restrict abortion, would repeal many provisions of Biden's signature Inflation Reduction Act and would seek to close down the southern border to immigrants entering the U.S. illegally. He also offered staunch support for Israel.</p>

<p>Trump mega-donor Timothy Mellon, an 82-year-old banking heir, has given millions of dollars this election cycle in support of Kennedy, and given $75 million in support of Trump, according to Federal Election Commission filings through July 31.</p>

<p>Shanahan has donated over $15 million to the Kennedy campaign, FEC filings showed.</p>

<p>In a video of a phone call posted online last month, Trump suggested to Kennedy that the independent candidate could do something to support the Trump campaign. Soon after, both candidates spoke a day apart from each other at a bitcoin conference in Nashville, trying to court votes.</p>

<p>BEAR, BRAIN WORMS &nbsp;</p>

<p>Kennedy said this month in a video posted online that he dumped a dead bear in New York City's Central Park a decade ago and staged it to look like a bike had hit it. He proclaimed he had "so many skeletons in my closet" after a former family babysitter accused him of sexual assault. He denied that a picture of him posing with the barbecued carcass of a large animal belonged to a canine.</p>

<p>And then there was the brain worm. Kennedy had a parasite in his brain more than a decade ago, but has since fully recovered, a fact unearthed by the New York Times and confirmed by the campaign.</p>

<p>Those stories prompted ridicule from late-night talk show hosts.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party especially has been ruthless in their opposition to Kennedy's candidacy including waging legal challenges against his ballot access, as concern grew that Kennedy could hurt the party's chances in November.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/h3r1nft8_robert-kennedy-jr_625x300_23_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Independent presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said on Friday he would suspend his campaign.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-countries-with-confirmed-cases-of-new-mpox-variant-6404124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A List Of Countries With Confirmed Cases Of New Mpox Variant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-list-of-countries-with-confirmed-cases-of-new-mpox-variant-6404124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 23:22:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Health Organization declared mpox a global public health emergency for the second time in two years, following an outbreak of the viral infection in the Democratic Republic of Congo that has spread to neighbouring countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Health Organization declared mpox a global public health emergency for the second time in two years, following an outbreak of the viral infection in the Democratic Republic of Congo that has spread to neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>A new form of the virus, clade Ib, triggered global concern as it seems to be spreading quickly and little is known about the strain. The disease transmits through close contact.</p>

<p>The new strain has spread to at least two countries outside Africa.</p>

<p>The following are the countries that have reported cases of clade Ib mpox:</p>

<p><strong>DEMOCRATIC REPUBLIC OF CONGO</strong></p>

<p>Two strains of mpox are spreading in the Democratic Republic of Congo - the endemic clade I and the new clade Ib, which spreads more easily through close contact, including sexual.</p>

<p>As of August 11, DRC has seen a total of 3,235 cases and 19 deaths in 2024. The country has confirmed 38 cases of mpox in the past two weeks, according to WHO data.</p>

<p><strong>SWEDEN</strong></p>

<p>Global health officials on August 15 confirmed an infection with a new strain of the mpox virus in Sweden, the first sign of its spread outside the African continent.</p>

<p>Swedish health officials said at a press conference that the person was infected while in Africa with the clade Ib type of mpox involved in the recent outbreak. The person is receiving treatment.</p>

<p><strong>THAILAND</strong></p>

<p>An mpox case reported in Thailand was confirmed to be of the clade Ib strain of the virus, the first in the country, a disease control official said on Aug. 22.</p>

<p>The case was first reported on Aug. 21, and Thailand had said it was a 66-year-old European man who had arrived from an African country where the disease was spreading.</p>

<p><strong>BURUNDI</strong></p>

<p>As of August 18, Burundi has 153 cases of clade Ib mpox with zero deaths. The country reported 113 cases of clade Ib mpox in the past two weeks, according to WHO data.</p>

<p><strong>KENYA</strong></p>

<p>On July 29, Kenya's health ministry confirmed one case of clade Ib mpox, the first-ever case of mpox identified in the country. No deaths had been reported as of August 8, according to WHO data.</p>

<p><strong>RWANDA</strong></p>

<p>As of August 7, four confirmed clade Ib mpox cases and zero deaths had cumulatively been reported by the country, according to WHO data.</p>

<p><strong>UGANDA</strong></p>

<p>As of August 18, Uganda has identified three cases of clade Ib mpox, with no deaths, according to WHO data. The cases are among the first confirmed mpox cases identified in the country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5gmol1no_mpox_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new strain has spread to at least two countries outside Africa (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/space-junk-long-march-6a-chinas-reckless-space-activities-fuel-debris-crisis-report-6404066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Rocket Debris May Stay In Orbit For Decades, Experts Warn]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/space-junk-long-march-6a-chinas-reckless-space-activities-fuel-debris-crisis-report-6404066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 23:12:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite China's assurances on debris mitigation, experts worry about the growing risk from such incidents, emphasizing the need for better international regulation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After accomplishing a noteworthy milestone of launching 18 Qianfan satellites, China's Long March 6A rocket broke apart on August 6, producing almost 300 pieces of trackable debris in low Earth orbit.</p>

<p>The first wave of these satellites was supposed to form China's "own version of Elon Musk's Starlink," the Qianfan ("Thousand Sails") broadband network. The rocket was launched from the Taiyuan Satellite Launch Centre, located in the Shanxi Province of North China.</p>

<p>A report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/china/china-rocket-space-debris-5e02a603"><em>The Wall Street Journal </em></a>states that the breakup of the rocket generated a new concern over Beijing's attitude towards space junk.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rocket-ends-up-as-300-piece-space-junk-after-satellite-constellation-launch-6297963"><strong>Also Read | China Rocket Ends Up As 300-Piece Space Junk After Satellite Constellation Launch</strong></a><br />
<br />
The report quoted LeoLabs, a US space-tracking firm, as saying the event might create at least 700 fragments floating some 500 miles above earth, making it one of the largest rocket breakups in history. Starlink said the debris didn't pose significant immediate risks to its fleet, but the fragments are likely to remain in space for decades due to the incident occurring at a high altitude."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/USSPACECOM?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#USSPACECOM</a> statement on the break-up of a Chinese Long March 6A rocket: <a href="https://t.co/Kf5cz0iZky">pic.twitter.com/Kf5cz0iZky</a></p>
 U.S. Space Command (@US_SpaceCom) <a href="https://twitter.com/US_SpaceCom/status/1821615199230816555?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>China and other countries are pressing ahead with plans to increase rocket launches, raising risks for humans and satellites in orbit. Yet there is little global policing of unsustainable practices.</p>

<p>Who can enforce anything in space? It's a bit like the Wild West at times," Quentin Parker, director of the Laboratory for Space Research at the University of Hong Kong, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/china/china-rocket-space-debris-5e02a603"><em>WSJ.</em></a></p>

<p>Darren McKnight, senior technical fellow at LeoLabs, said China's recent record on generating debris related to Long March 6 launches was worrisome. I hope it's a wake-up call for them, and they'll be part of the international dialogue," he said.</p>

<p>A Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman, Lin Jian, said last week that China attaches great importance to space debris mitigation" and has taken active efforts to fulfill relevant international obligations." Without giving details, he said China took necessary measures after the recent rocket breakup.</p>

<p>It also said in the report that the Chinese activities in space are pointing toward a worrisome tendency in the direction of space junk. In 2022, a rocket stage from China had an uncontrolled re-entry into the Sulu Sea, wherein NASA criticised it for less-than-adequate data provision. Major pieces of junk have been created by Chinese rocket launches, including Long March 6A missions, which are notorious for their bad history. While other countries did better, Chinese behavior was largely responsible for space debris that affects low-Earth orbit environments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c67l51q8_long-march-6a-rocket-_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China's Long March 6A rocket broke apart on August 6, creating nearly 300 debris pieces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-asked-netanyahu-to-pull-israeli-troops-from-egypt-gaza-border-report-6403947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Asked Netanyahu To Pull Israeli Troops From Egypt-Gaza Border: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-asked-netanyahu-to-pull-israeli-troops-from-egypt-gaza-border-report-6403947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:51:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden asked Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to move Israeli troops back from Gaza's border with Egypt as part of an initial phase of a ceasefire deal so that talks could continue, Axios reported on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. President Joe Biden asked Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to move Israeli troops back from Gaza's border with Egypt as part of an initial phase of a ceasefire deal so that talks could continue, Axios reported on Friday.</p>

<p>Netanyahu partially accepted Biden's request made in their call on Wednesday and agreed to give up an Israeli troop position along one part of the Egypt-Gaza border, three Israeli officials told Axios.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/slhn9fr_biden-and-netanyahu_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-400-more-targets-for-aiding-russias-war-effort-6403763]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Sanctions 400 More Targets For Aiding Russia's War Effort]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-sanctions-400-more-targets-for-aiding-russias-war-effort-6403763]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:24:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States unveiled sweeping sanctions Friday against almost 400 individuals and companies tied to Russia's war in Ukraine, a day before Ukraine's independence day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States unveiled sweeping sanctions Friday against almost 400 individuals and companies tied to Russia's war in Ukraine, a day before Ukraine's independence day.</p>

<p>The moves announced by the US Treasury, State and Commerce departments build on a raft of existing sanctions against Russia over the invasion, which is now well into its third year.</p>

<p>"Russia has turned its economy into a tool in service of the Kremlin's military-industrial complex," Deputy Treasury Secretary Wally Adeyemo said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Treasury's actions today continue to implement the commitments made by President Biden and his G7 counterparts to disrupt Russia's military-industrial base supply chains and payment channels," he added.</p>

<p>The sanctions target nearly 400 individuals and entities both inside and outside of Russia "whose products and services enable Russia to sustain its war effort and evade sanctions," the department announced in the statement.</p>

<p>Among those sanctioned were 60 Russia-based defense and technology firms "critical for the sustainment and development of Russia's defense industry," it added.</p>

<p>The State Department said in a separate statement that it was responsible for 190 of the sanctions, and that Treasury was responsible for close to 200 others.</p>

<p>It added that its designations "aim to disrupt sanctions evasion and target entities in multiple third countries," including China, along with businesses supporting the development of Russian energy projects.</p>

<p>Alongside the sanctions unveiled Friday, the US Commerce Department announced it was taking "aggressive action" to further restrict the supply of items made in the United States, or labeled as such, to both Russia and Belarus, due to "the Kremlin's illegal war on Ukraine."</p>

<p>"Today's actions will further constrain Russia's ability to arm its military by targeting illicit procurement networks designed to circumvent global export controls," the department said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/thjcjens_us-flag-generic_625x300_28_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-export-strategy-causes-global-market-havoc-report-6403729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Export Strategy Causes Global Market Havoc: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-export-strategy-causes-global-market-havoc-report-6403729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:19:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chinas aggressive manufacturing and export strategy under Xi Jinping, driven by the "establish the new before breaking the old" policy, is intensifying global trade tensions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's 'Made in China' products have already established a firm foothold in the international market, surpassing the expansion of any other nation in history. Manufacturers all over the world are under tremendous pressure due to the flood of cheaper Chinese goods. China is now focussing more on exporting in an effort to take the lead in the world's manufacturing sector.</p>

<p>According to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/china/china-trade-war-xi-manufacturing-49f81f68"><em>The Wall Street Journal,</em></a>&nbsp;Chinese President Xi Jinping has increased his focus on the manufacturing sector, with a high percentage of production going to export, in response to the slow economic development that his government is facing in recent past. China is once again ramping up its massive export machinery, giving rivals little opportunity to survive in the market.</p>

<p>The impact of China's manufacturing dominance is evident in various sectors. For instance, a Massachusetts startup called CubicPV betting on silicon wafers, a high-tech component in solar panels. Buoyed by President Biden's climate legislation enacted two years ago, with billions of dollars in tax credits and government loans, CubicPV announced plans in late 2022 for a $1.4 billion wafer plant in Texas.</p>

<p>Since then, China has nearly doubled its output of silicon wafers-way more than it needs. The extra wafers had to go somewhere, and they went overseas, pushing prices down by 70%. CubicPV had to halt its production plan early this year, putting engineers and other employees out of work, citing "a distorted market as a result of China's overcapacity."</p>

<p>In another case, thousands of miles away, in Chile, iron ore miner and steelmaker CAP is struggling with China's continued commitment to low-end commodity manufacturing as an onslaught of cheap Chinese metal hits its shores. The firm said this month that it would shutter its giant Huachipato steel mill in central Chile indefinitely, with the loss of some 2,200 jobs. The company said it can't compete with low-priced Chinese metal even after the government raised tariffs on steel bars and other imported products.</p>

<p>Beijing's strategy of bolstering its manufacturing sector through aggressive exports is creating significant challenges for businesses around the world. This escalating trade tension raises concerns about the potential for a new global trade war.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/china/china-trade-war-xi-manufacturing-49f81f68"><em>The WSJ report</em></a> further mentioned that other countries have opened antidumping investigations to see whether Chinese goods are being sold below fair value. India is examining Chinese pigments and chemicals. Japan is looking at electrodes. The UK is investigating imports of excavators and biodiesel, while Argentina and Vietnam are probing Chinese microwave ovens and wind towers.</p>

<p>Xi Jinping's "establish the new before breaking the old" strategy prioritizes building new industries like EVs and semiconductors while maintaining traditional ones like steel. Despite acknowledging overcapacity, China continues to invest heavily in manufacturing, driven by concerns about industrial security and economic stability. This approach is straining global trade relations and causing economic hardship in other countries.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4afg8f8_chinas-aggressive-manufacturing_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China is ramping up its vast export capabilities again, leaving competitors with no refuge.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-ukraine-visit-all-about-bhishm-cubes-mobile-hospitals-from-india-to-war-hit-ukraine-6403667]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[All About BHISHM Cubes - Mobile Hospitals From India To War-Hit Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-ukraine-visit-all-about-bhishm-cubes-mobile-hospitals-from-india-to-war-hit-ukraine-6403667]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 22:09:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi Ukraine Visit: Prime Minister Narendra Modi today offered indigenously developed four BHISHM (Bharat Health Initiative for Sahyog Hita and Maitri) Cubes to Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy during his visit to the war-torn country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today offered indigenously developed four BHISHM (Bharat Health Initiative for Sahyog Hita and Maitri) Cubes to Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky during his visit to the war-torn country. BHISHM Cubes contain essential medicines and equipment designed to provide medical care for emergency situations, a statement from the Ministry of External Affairs said.</p>

<p>BHISHM Cubes are portable medical units designed deliver essential healthcare services in disaster-stricken areas. According to an official statement, the cube has medicines and equipment for the first line of care for all kinds of injuries and medical situations.</p>

<p>"It also includes surgical equipment for a basic operation room that can manage 10-15 basic surgeries per day. The Cube can handle about 200 cases of diverse nature in emergencies such as trauma, bleeding, burns, fractures, etc. It can also generate power and oxygen in limited amounts. A team of experts from India has been deployed to provide initial training to the Ukrainian side to operate the cube," the statement said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PM <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> handed over BHISHM Cubes to President <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ZelenskyyUa</a>. The indigenously developed BHISHM Cubes contain essential medicines and equipment designed to provide medical care for emergency situations. <a href="https://t.co/IZuxkxNeRK">pic.twitter.com/IZuxkxNeRK</a></p>
 PMO India (@PMOIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/PMOIndia/status/1826975716350537918?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script><p<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<p>The gesture underscored India's continued commitment to provide humanitarian assistance to war-ravaged Ukraine, it added.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy thanked <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/white-house-says-pm-modis-visit-to-ukraine-potentially-helpful-6403084">PM Modi</a> for the humanitarian assistance of the Cubes which will help expedite the treatment of the injured and save precious lives.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/white-house-says-pm-modis-visit-to-ukraine-potentially-helpful-6403084">White House Says PM Modi's Visit To Ukraine Potentially "Helpful"</a></strong></p>

<h3><strong>What Are BHISHM Cubes?</strong></h3>

<p>Initiated under the umbrella of Project Aarogya Maitri, BHISHM cube is a mobile hospital made through packing all essential medicines and equipment in cubical boxes (15 inches each) in a well-organised manner. They are arranged according to the types of injuries and medical issues that could be encountered in a war or natural disaster.</p>

<p>These cubes are then positioned on a framework that is adjustable, strong and permits multi-mode transport (by air, sea, land and drone). They can be carried by a person as their maximum weight is 20 kg.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MIBePositive?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MIBePositive</a> | 28-06-2024<br />
Stories that Inspire!<br />
<br />
Introducing the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/BHISHMCube?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#BHISHMCube</a>: A Revolutionary Mobile Hospital<br />
<br />
?The BHISHM Cube is a cutting-edge, portable medical unit designed to deliver essential healthcare services in disaster-stricken areas. This innovative solution is a <a href="https://t.co/W7aOrmo1wD">pic.twitter.com/W7aOrmo1wD</a></p>
 Ministry of Information and Broadcasting (@MIB_India) <a href="https://twitter.com/MIB_India/status/1806643702779306118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Equipped with all the necessary medical supplies, the BHISHM Cube can provide critical care to up to 200 casualties. They can handle cases of diverse nature in emergency situations such as trauma, bleeding, burns, fractures, shock, apart from managing initial triage and classification, officials told news agency PTI.</p>

<p>It also has the ability to support basic surgeries and can also generate its own power and oxygen in limited amounts and duration, they added.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-ukraine-visit-pm-modi-holds-talks-with-ukraine-president-in-kyiv-full-joint-statement-6402100">PM Modi Holds Talks With Ukraine President In Kyiv. Full Joint Statement</a></strong></p>

<h3><strong>PM Modi Ukraine Visit</strong></h3>

<p>PM Modi <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-ukraine-visit-pm-modi-holds-talks-with-ukraine-president-in-kyiv-full-joint-statement-6402100">held "productive talks" with Volodymr Zelensky</a> with an assurance of contributing personally to ending its raging war with Russia. It is the first-ever visit to Ukraine by an Indian prime minister after the country became independent in 1991. His trip comes amid Kyiv's fresh military offensive in Russia's western Kursk region.</p>
</p<blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hkr1gk_bhishm-cubes_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BHISHM Cubes are equipped with all the necessary medical supplies]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-reports-16th-polio-case-of-2024-to-launch-vaccination-campaign-6403477]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Reports 16th Polio Case Of 2024, To Launch Vaccination Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-reports-16th-polio-case-of-2024-to-launch-vaccination-campaign-6403477]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 21:40:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan reported another case of poliovirus after a child was paralysed in the Sindh province, increasing the country's total tally to 16 in 2024, an official told the media on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan reported another case of poliovirus after a child was paralysed in the Sindh province, increasing the country's total tally to 16 in 2024, an official told the media on Friday.</p>

<p>An official from the Regional Reference Laboratory for Polio Eradication at the National Institute of Health (NIH) in Islamabad said that the wild Poliovirus type-1 (WPV1) was confirmed in a 29-month-old girl from Hyderabad district of the province, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>According to the official, poliovirus traces have been reported in 62 districts of the South Asian country so far this year, a significant increase from 28 districts last year.</p>

<p>"This is the first polio case from Hyderabad and the third from Sindh, and the 16th case in Pakistan this year," said the NIH official, adding that 12 cases were reported from the southwestern Balochistan province, three from Sindh, and one from the eastern Punjab province.</p>

<p>Prime Minister's Focal Person for Polio Eradication Ayesha Raza Farooq said, "The latest case is a clear reminder that until we eradicate this virus from our country, no child anywhere is safe from its devastating effects."</p>

<p>She added that WPV1 was consistently being reported in sewage samples of Hyderabad for the last four months, reiterating the continued risk of polio circulating anywhere in the country.</p>

<p>"We are operating on an emergency footing in all provinces given the intensity of the outbreak and extent of virus spread. The polio program has been implementing a comprehensive roadmap to interrupt virus transmission, beginning with an extensive, large-scale polio vaccination campaign from September 9," she said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Muhammad Anwar-ul-Haq, coordinator of the National Emergency Operations Centre for Polio Eradication, said a thorough investigation was being conducted to identify the origins of the virus and immunisation of children.</p>

<p>"Poliovirus has been circulating in adjacent districts of Karachi and Hyderabad for several months," he said.</p>

<p>"Every child's wellbeing is important to us, and we will be launching a vaccination campaign in all affected districts from September 9 to boost children's immunity."</p>

<p>Polio has been eliminated in developed nations but persists in parts of India, Nigeria, Afghanistan and Pakistan.</p>

<p>Many Pakistanis, particularly those residing in the conservative tribal areas, consider polio vaccination a Western campaign aimed at sterilising the country's population. In 2012, the local Taliban ordered a ban on immunisation against polio in some tribal districts.</p>

<p>Nearly a dozen policemen have been killed this year while on security duty during vaccination campaigns which are frequently targeted by operatives.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/6g2u64t8_pakistan-polio-generic-afp_625x300_25_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polio has been eliminated in most of the developed nations . (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-hollywood-actor-with-109-convictions-jailed-for-assaulting-ex-girlfriend-6403437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-Hollywood Actor With 109 Convictions Jailed For Assaulting Ex-Girlfriend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-hollywood-actor-with-109-convictions-jailed-for-assaulting-ex-girlfriend-6403437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 21:32:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident, captured on a doorbell camera, took place in Newcastle on December 11, 2023, and violated an existing restraining order against Hoganson.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former British film actor knwown for his leading role of the 1988 Hollywood film <em>Empire State</em> has been jailed for 18 months for an attack on his ex-girlfriend, according to <em>The Metro.</em></p>

<p>Jason Hoganson, who in the film took the role of an enigmatic Geordie drifter with such actors as Ray McAnally, Jamie Foreman, and Martin Landau, was convicted of assault following the incident. The attack occurred in a public street; details of this have not been disclosed.</p>

<p>Producers discovered Hoganson while he was studying the art of drama. He had already received critical acclaim for his talent and potential. The role in Empire State was a big break for him.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/22/former-hollywood-star-109-convictions-jailed-attacking-ex-21474047/"><em>The Metro</em>,</a> Newcastle Crown Court heard Hoganson, who now has 109 convictions on his record, was caught on a doorbell video camera when he attacked his former partner in Newcastle on December 11 last year. Prosecutor Amy Levitt said Hoganson already had a restraining order to keep him away from the woman when he attacked her.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Footage shows the defendant assaulting the complainant. He slaps her to the face and she walks away. He walks after her," Miss Levitt told the court.</p>

<p>"There are further hits and a push, where she falls to the floor.The assault continues while she's lying on the floor.She describes him, having pushed her, hit her, kicked her and put his body weight on her. The assault lasted around three minutes," Miss Levitt added.</p>

<p>Miss Levitt said Hoganson had previously been made the subject of a restraining order-preventing him from contacting the victim-when he was convicted of battery and criminal damage in May last year. Hoganson, of no fixed address, has pleaded guilty to assault by beating and to breaching the restraining order.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/f6jf0ni_jason-hoganson_625x300_23_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite his early acclaim in drama, Hoganson now has 109 convictions on his record.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/progress-made-white-house-on-high-stakes-gaza-truce-talks-held-in-cairo-6403314]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Progress Made": White House On High-Stakes Gaza Truce Talks Held In Cairo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/progress-made-white-house-on-high-stakes-gaza-truce-talks-held-in-cairo-6403314]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 21:14:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Talks in Cairo on reaching a Gaza truce have made progress, the White House said Friday, as it urged Israel and Hamas to move forward.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Talks in Cairo on reaching a Gaza truce have made progress, the White House said Friday, as it urged Israel and Hamas to move forward.</p>

<p>The White House confirmed that CIA chief William Burns and senior official Brett McGurk were taking part in discussions which started at a preliminary level Thursday evening.</p>

<p>"There has been progress made. We need now for both sides to come together and work towards implementation," National Security Council spokesman John Kirby told reporters.</p>

<p>"The preliminary talks that we had going into Cairo last night were constructive in nature. So we want to see that same sort of momentum continue here over the next couple of days," he said.</p>

<p>Kirby said that reports that the diplomacy was "near collapse" were inaccurate.</p>

<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken visited the Middle East this week and said that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu was onboard with a US proposal to bridge gaps and reach a ceasefire in the more than 10-month conflict.</p>

<p>Kirby said that the United States continued to believe that Netanyahu accepted the proposal, even though the right-wing leader has insisted on Israeli troops staying on the Gaza-Egypt border, butting heads with both Washington and Cairo.</p>

<p>Kirby appealed again to Hamas to accept the proposal, which was laid out last week in talks in the Qatari capital Doha.</p>

<p>"Think about what this deal will do for the people of Gaza. It gets them a period of calm and a potential end of the war and the violence and the bloodshed," Kirby said.</p>

<p>"It also gets them, because of the stop in the fighting, an incredible opportunity for all of us -- and I mean all of us, including the United States -- to dramatically increase the humanitarian assistance that's getting in," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3q9uvvno_israel-gaza_625x300_23_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kirby said that reports that the diplomacy was "near collapse" were inaccurate (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-dead-14-missing-after-heavy-rains-trigger-floods-in-china-report-6403237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[11 dead, 14 Missing After Heavy Rains Trigger Floods In China: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/11-dead-14-missing-after-heavy-rains-trigger-floods-in-china-report-6403237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 23 Aug 2024 21:02:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eleven people have been killed and 14 more are missing after heavy rain in recent days lashed China's northeastern province of Liaoning, state broadcaster CCTV reported Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eleven people have been killed and 14 more are missing after heavy rain in recent days lashed China's northeastern province of Liaoning, state broadcaster CCTV reported Friday.</p>

<p>"On the evening of August 23, a press conference was held in Huludao City, Liaoning Province on flood prevention and control and disaster relief," CCTV reported.</p>

<p>At the press conference, it was announced that "this round of heavy rainfall caused extremely serious damage to Huludao City, especially Jianchang County and Suizhong County. Roads, electricity, communications, houses, crops, etc. were severely affected.</p>

<p>"After several rounds of checking households and persons, it was found that the disaster has caused 10 deaths with 14 people missing," CCTV said, adding that an official also died "while saving people".</p>

<p>The report stated that "all-out search and rescue efforts are underway for missing persons".</p>

<p>State media reported Thursday that over 50,000 people had been evacuated in Huludao, due to heavy rains that had persisted over several days.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/8f8f8an8_china-floods-afp-_625x300_12_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 50,000 people had been evacuated in Huludao (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>