<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 03:50:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-the-name-of-globalisation-we-actually-hollowed-out-s-jaishankar-7090638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In The Name Of Globalisation, We Actually Hollowed Out...": S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-the-name-of-globalisation-we-actually-hollowed-out-s-jaishankar-7090638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:07:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the name of open economy, we allowed other countries to get an advantageous playing field in the country and this has to stop, said External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>In the name of open economy, we allowed other countries to get an advantageous playing field in the country and this has to stop, said External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Saturday.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar was delivering a virtual keynote address at the 8th India Idea Conclave at Bengaluru. This year, the conclave, organised by India Foundation, is exploring the theme, 'building Brand Bharath'.</p>

<p>"In the name of globalisation, we actually hollowed out the manufacturing. SMEs have been hurting for the last 30 years because they see unfair competition, see subsidised goods coming into the country. If we cannot protect them, they cannot compete," he said.</p>

<p>According to S Jaishankar, under Modi's 'Brand Bharath', this is being done differently as 'Make in India' has moved from aspiration to an assertion.</p>

<p>"Look at semi conductors industry. We understand today semi conductor will be a make or break for a country like India," he said, adding that where India that is Bharath is doing things differently is in taking the hard calls were necessary.</p>

<p>One such call is being prudent on foreign direct investments (FDI), said S Jaishankar.</p>

<p>"I can tell you, in every FDI negotiation, we think very long, very hard. We are very concerned both about the social fabric and employment consequences of an FDI, as well as its national security implications," the Minister said.</p>

<p>He added that the Modi government will never sign an FDI if these are not addressed.</p>

<p>"And I think that is the departure from the past," he said.</p>

<p>The minister also said since PM Modi took over, if he has to pick a region where India has really built a Brand Bharath, it would be the Middle East.</p>

<p>According to him, traditional belief is that if a country does well with Israel, it will lose all other players in the region. But he pointed out that India has proved this conventional wisdom wrong in the last 10 years.</p>

<p>"Today, Brand Bharath is seen as an ambitious brand. We are not just one among many willing to go with the flow. We will take the hard calls, put in resources, and we will stay in touch with the contemporary world... Under PM Modi, that really has been the big change, which is why our brand is different," said S Jaishankar.</p>

<p>The India Idea Concalve concludes on November 24.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n2g27oq_s-jaishankar-ani_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The India Idea Concalve concludes on November 24. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-kill-120-palestinians-in-gaza-over-48-hours-7090578]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Strikes Kill 120 Palestinians In Gaza Over 48 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-kill-120-palestinians-in-gaza-over-48-hours-7090578]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:50:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli military strikes across the Gaza Strip have killed at least 120 Palestinians over the last 48 hours and hit a hospital on the northern edge of the enclave, wounding medical staff and damaging equipment, Palestinian medics said on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli military strikes across the Gaza Strip have killed at least 120 Palestinians over the last 48 hours and hit a hospital on the northern edge of the enclave, wounding medical staff and damaging equipment, Palestinian medics said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Among the dead were seven members of one family whose house was hit overnight in the Zeitoun suburb of Gaza City, the health officials said. The rest were killed in separate Israeli strikes in central and southern Gaza.</p>

<p>At the same time, Israeli forces deepened their incursion and bombardment of the northern edge of the enclave, their main offensive since early last month.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the armed wing of Hamas said a female Israeli hostage in the group's custody had been killed in a northern area under attack by Israeli forces.</p>

<p>"The life of another female prisoner who used to be with her remains in imminent danger," spokesperson Abu Ubaida added, accusing the government of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of being to blame.</p>

<p>An Israeli military spokesperson said it was investigating the Hamas report.</p>

<p>"At this point, we are unable to confirm or deny it," the spokesperson said. "Hamas continues to engage in psychological terrorism and act in a cruel manner."</p>

<p>A group representing hostages' families did not immediately reply to a request for comment.</p>

<p><strong>DAMAGE, INJURIES AT HOSPITAL</strong></p>

<p>Israel's military says its operations in northern Gaza aim to prevent Hamas fighters from carrying out attacks and regrouping. Local residents say they fear the goal is to permanently depopulate a strip of territory as a buffer zone, something Israel denies.</p>

<p>At Kamal Adwan Hospital, one of three medical facilities on the northern edge of Gaza that is barely operational, director Hussam Abu Safiya said the ongoing Israeli bombardment in the area appeared aimed at forcing hospital staff to evacuate - something they have refused to do since the incursion began.</p>

<p>"Yesterday (Friday), from the afternoon until midnight, the bombardment directly targeted the entrance to the emergency and reception area several times," he said in a statement, adding that 12 staff members including doctors and nurses were injured.</p>

<p>The strike also caused significant damage that disrupted the electrical generator, oxygen supply network and water supply, he added.</p>

<p>Asked to comment on Abu Safiya's statement, the Israeli military said that following an initial review it was "not aware of a strike in the area of the Kamal Adwan Hospital", adding that it does everything possible to avoid harming civilians.</p>

<p>Israel says Hamas uses hospitals and civilians as human shields, and has made public videos and photos to support that claim. Hamas rejects the allegations and says it does not use the civilian population or facilities for military purposes.</p>

<p>Israel's 13-month campaign in Gaza has killed more than 44,000 people and displaced nearly all the enclave's population at least once, according to Gaza officials.</p>

<p>The war was launched in response to an attack by Hamas-led fighters who killed 1,200 people and captured more than 250 hostages in Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, Israel has said.</p>

<p>Months of attempts to negotiate a ceasefire have yielded scant progress and negotiations are now on hold, with mediator Qatar having suspended its efforts until the sides are prepared to make concessions.</p>

<p>Hamas wants a deal that ends the conflict, and leads to the release of Israeli and foreign hostages held captive in Gaza as well as Palestinians jailed by Israel, while Netanyahu has said the war can end only once Hamas is eradicated.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s2v5mfs_gaza-afp_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-bert-strikes-uk-and-ireland-brings-extreme-flooding-and-travel-chaos-7090576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storm Bert Strikes UK And Ireland, Brings Extreme Flooding And Travel Chaos]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-bert-strikes-uk-and-ireland-brings-extreme-flooding-and-travel-chaos-7090576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:50:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain and Ireland faced travel chaos on Saturday as a winter storm battered northwest Europe with strong winds, heavy rain, snow and ice.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Storm Bert has wreaked havoc in parts of Ireland and Britain, causing severe flooding and widespread disruption. Dramatic events occurred in Donegal as rushing waters caused streets like Bridge Street to become rivers, raising worries about public safety.</p>

<p>Translink, a public transport company in Northern Ireland, warned customers to prepare for "severe disruption" and look for alternate travel alternatives as a result of the massive damage to Northern Ireland's railway infrastructure. The storm's effects highlight the region's continued vulnerability to severe weather.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Storm Bert left at least 60,000 properties in Ireland without power and closed roads and some ferry and train routes on both sides of the Irish Sea.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">STORM BERT HITS UK AND IRELAND ???? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StormBert?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#StormBert</a><br />
<br />
- 60,000 Irish homes and businesses lose power<br />
- Flooding in Donegal, Ireland, makes roads impassable<br />
- Train routes suspended in Scotland<br />
- Weather warnings issued in the UK for wind, snow, and ice<br />
- "Status red" warning declared… <a href="https://t.co/360k9U5jHz">https://t.co/360k9U5jHz</a> <a href="https://t.co/TwGJdRI8D5">pic.twitter.com/TwGJdRI8D5</a></p>
— Weather monitor (@Weathermonitors) <a href="https://twitter.com/Weathermonitors/status/1860291031293661532?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Media footage showed flooding in the west of Ireland, while floods prompted rail closures in Northern Ireland and snow impacted travel across Britain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The heaviest snow hit Scotland and parts of northern and central England, with dozens of flood alerts in place.</p>

<p>The UK Met Office issued warnings for snow and ice for those regions, warning there was a "good chance some rural communities could be cut off.".</p>

<p>Scottish hills could see up to 40 centimetres (16 inches) of snow, while winds approaching 70 miles (113 kilometres) per hour were recorded in parts of Britain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ferry operator DFDS cancelled services on some routes until Monday, with sailings from Newhaven and Dover in southern England to Dieppe and Calais in France severely affected.</p>

<p>Flights were disrupted at Newcastle airport due to heavy snow, with some flights diverted to Belfast and Edinburgh.</p>

<p>Met Eireann, the Irish National Meteorological Service, had also issued a yellow warning for "very strong winds and heavy rain."</p>

<p>The worst impacted areas for power outages in Ireland were in western and northwestern counties, according to ESB Networks, which runs the country's electricity system.</p>

<p>"Crews and contractors are deployed and restoring power in impacted areas where it is safe to do so," it said.</p>

<p>More than 4,000 properties across Britain were without power by mid-Saturday-the majority in southwest England-with the National Grid operator saying power had been restored to "many homes and businesses."<br />
<br />
<em>(With inputs from AFP)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6svhb5h_storm-bert_625x300_23_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Storm Bert left at least 60,000 properties in Ireland without power, and closed roads.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-says-lebanon-7090533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[15 Killed In Israeli Strike On Beirut, Says Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/15-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-beirut-says-lebanon-7090533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:41:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon said an Israeli air strike in the heart of Beirut that brought down a residential building and jolted residents across the city killed at least 15 people on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon said an Israeli air strike in the heart of Beirut that brought down a residential building and jolted residents across the city killed at least 15 people on Saturday.</p>

<p>A Lebanese security source told AFP that the strike had "targeted a leading Hezbollah figure", but a Hezbollah lawmaker denied any official of the Iran-backed group was present.</p>

<p>The attack in the capital was followed by others in the city's southern suburbs after calls by the Israeli military to evacuate.</p>

<p>Israel has not commented on the strike in central Beirut.</p>

<p>Rescue operations were underway in the area on Saturday morning, with an excavator removing the rubble of the eight-storey building.</p>

<p>"The strike was so strong it felt like the building was about to fall on our heads," said Samir, 60, who lives in a building facing the one that was destroyed.</p>

<p>He said he fled his home in the middle of the night with his wife and children.</p>

<p>"We saw two dead people on the ground... The children started crying and their mother cried even more," he told AFP.</p>

<p>The Israeli strike, which hit the working-class Basta neighbourhood, killed at least 15 people and wounded 63, Lebanon's health ministry said.</p>

<p>"The final death toll will be determined after DNA tests are carried out," the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>The state-run National News Agency (NNA) said Israeli jets had launched six missiles at the structure, causing "widespread destruction in buildings" nearby.</p>

<p>The predawn attack in Basta was not preceded by an evacuation warning from Israel's military.</p>

<p><strong>'Diplomatic resolution'</strong></p>

<p>Similar strikes carried out without warning outside of Hezbollah's traditional bastions have tended to target senior figures but Hezbollah lawmaker Amin Sherri denied any official was present at the time of the strike.</p>

<p>"There was no party figure in the two targeted buildings," the NNA quoted him as saying as he visited the site.</p>

<p>The health ministry said the Israeli air force also hit eastern Lebanon, killing eight people in the town of Shmostar overlooking the Bekaa Valley, another Hezbollah stronghold.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy strike on Shmostar killed eight people, including four children, and nine others were injured, including four in critical condition," a ministry statement said.</p>

<p>Israel stepped up its campaign against the Hezbollah group in late September, targeting its strongholds in Lebanon's east and south as well as south Beirut, and later sending in ground troops after nearly a year of limited cross-border exchanges of fire.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry says more than 3,650 people have been killed since October 2023, when Hezbollah began trading fire with Israel in solidarity with its Palestinian ally Hamas. Most of the deaths have been since September this year.</p>

<p>In a telephone call with Israeli Defence Minister Israel Katz on Saturday, Pentagon chief Lloyd Austin "reiterated US commitment to a diplomatic resolution in Lebanon that allows Israeli and Lebanese civilians to return safely to their homes on both sides of the border", a spokesperson said.</p>

<p>US envoy Amos Hochstein has been shuttling between Lebanon and Israel this week in a bid to broker a ceasefire in the Israel-Hezbollah war.</p>

<p>After talks in Beirut earlier this week, he had said that a deal was "within our grasp" but as he headed to Israel both sides put out statements that dented hopes of rapid progress.</p>

<p><strong>Deadly strikes on Gaza</strong></p>

<p>The war in Gaza was triggered by Hamas's unprecedented October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>At least 44,176 people have been killed in Gaza during more than 13 months of war, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Civil defence agency spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP on Saturday that 19 people were killed and more than 40 wounded by predawn Israeli air strikes and tank fire.</p>

<p>Umm Muhammad Abu Sabla, the sister of one of the victims of Saturday's strikes, told AFP she rushed to the scene to find "people carrying body parts from under the rubble".</p>

<p>"Our entire life is misery. Let them kill us all so we can be relieved from this suffering," the 62-year-old said in the main southern city of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>The war has created a humanitarian crisis in the besieged territory, where people are experiencing acute shortages of food, fuel and medicines.</p>

<p>In his call with Katz, the Pentagon chief "urged the government of Israel to continue to take steps to improve the dire humanitarian conditions in Gaza".</p>

<p>The United Nations and others have repeatedly decried humanitarian conditions, particularly in northern Gaza.</p>

<p>The UN says more than 100,000 have been displaced from the area since early October, and an official told the Security Council last week that people "are effectively starving".</p>

<p>The trickle of aid entering Gaza was the principal basis cited by the International Criminal Court in the arrest warrants it announced on Thursday for Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and former defence minister Yoav Gallant.</p>

<p>The court said there were "reasonable grounds" to believe the pair bore "criminal responsibility" for the war crime of starvation as a method of warfare and crimes against humanity, including over "the lack of food, water, electricity and fuel, and specific medical supplies".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mctoeodg_beirut-strike_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has not commented on the strike in central Beirut.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktok-ceo-sought-musks-input-ahead-of-trump-administration-report-7090482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[TikTok CEO Sought Musk's Input Ahead Of Trump Administration: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktok-ceo-sought-musks-input-ahead-of-trump-administration-report-7090482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:31:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[ByteDance-owned TikTok Chief Executive Officer Shou Zi Chew has sought input on US matters from Elon Musk, a close adviser to President-elect Donald Trump, the Wall Street Journal reported on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ByteDance-owned TikTok Chief Executive Officer Shou Zi Chew has sought input on US matters from Elon Musk, a close adviser to President-elect Donald Trump, the Wall Street Journal reported on Saturday citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Chew initiated messages with the Tesla CEO in recent weeks and asked for his opinions on topics ranging from the incoming administration to potential tech policy, the report added.</p>

<p>Elon Musk, TikTok, ByteDance and the Trump administration did not immediately respond to Reuters' requests for comments.</p>

<p>Both executives have not discussed specific measures to keep TikTok running in the United States, the Journal reported, adding that Chew has kept ByteDance's senior leadership informed of the talks, with executives cautiously optimistic about finding a way forward.</p>

<p>ByteDance executives had been hedging their bets before the US election, meeting with people close to Trump and with people close to Democratic nominee Kamala Harris, the report added.</p>

<p>Trump, who unsuccessfully tried to ban TikTok in 2020, has said if elected in November he would not allow TikTok to be barred.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vqgg5uk8_elon-musk-donald-trump-afp_625x300_04_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President-Elect Donald Trump and Tesla CEO Elon Musk.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-armed-wing-says-israeli-woman-hostage-killed-in-north-gaza-7090449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Armed Wing Says Israeli Woman Hostage Killed In North Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-armed-wing-says-israeli-woman-hostage-killed-in-north-gaza-7090449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 23:26:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas's armed wing said Saturday an Israeli woman taken hostage during the October 2023 attack had been killed in a combat zone in northern Gaza and the Israeli military said it was investigating.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas's armed wing said Saturday an Israeli woman taken hostage during the October 2023 attack had been killed in a combat zone in northern Gaza and the Israeli military said it was investigating.</p>

<p>Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades spokesman Abu Obeida said contact had been restored with the woman's captors after a break of several weeks and it was established that the hostage had been killed in an area of north Gaza where the Israeli army has been operating.</p>

<p>Abu Obeida's statement did not further identify the hostage or say how or when she was killed.</p>

<p>The Israeli army told AFP it was looking into the claim.</p>

<p>Abu Obeida said that the woman had been held with a second female hostage whose life was in danger.</p>

<p>During last year's Hamas attack which triggered the Gaza war, militants took 251 hostages, of whom 97 are still held in Gaza, including 34 the army says are dead.</p>

<p>Ten female hostages, including five soldiers, were believed to remain alive in custody before Abu Obeida's statement, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>During a one-week truce in November last year, 105 hostages were freed, including 80 Israelis who were exchanged for 240 Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<p>The Israeli government has come under immense public pressure to agree a new deal to bring the remaining hostages home while they are still alive.</p>

<p>The Hostage and Missing Families Forum campaign group did not wish to comment on Saturday's claim.</p>

<p>"Nothing is known other than what Hamas is saying. Our only reliable source is the Israeli army," the group told AFP.</p>

<p>Hamas's attack on October 7 last year resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign has killed 44,176 people in Gaza, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry that the United Nations considers reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ffef62o_gaza_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli army told AFP it was looking into the claim. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/left-naked-reality-show-contestant-survived-for-15-months-eating-dog-food-read-his-story-7089531]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Left Naked, Reality Show Contestant Survived For 15 Months Eating Dog Food]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/left-naked-reality-show-contestant-survived-for-15-months-eating-dog-food-read-his-story-7089531]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 20:58:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Unaware that he was being filmed, he competed in challenges for basic survival. His story of loneliness and struggle is now featured in a documentary.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tomoaki Hamatsu, better known as Nasubi, a comedian who appeared on the extreme Japanese game show <em>'A Life In Prizes'</em>, has given very painful details of his 15-month ordeal, which included being videotaped eating dog food, being held in total seclusion, and having to compete in tasks to survive. The show, which debuted in 1998, attracted up to 30 million people at its height and became an international hit.</p>

<p>Nasubi, who stayed naked during the broadcast, was locked in an empty apartment and had to win prizes to meet basic needs like food. He was unaware that his actions were being broadcast to millions across Japan. His story is now featured in a Hulu documentary titled <em>The Contestant.</em></p>

<p>"I came across his story when I was working on a different project and got lost down one of those internet rabbit holes," Clair Titley, director of The Contestant, told<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cz99yr6dq41o"><em> BBC.</em></a></p>

<p>"But I found that a lot of what I had come across was almost derogatory. Nothing had really talked about Nasubi's story in depth. [I had] all these questions, such as, Why did he stay in there, and what effect it had on him. So I contacted him with that premise, that I wanted to make a film about his experience."</p>

<p>Nasubi, who is now 48, claimed that he was left feeling nervous and confused by the lack of information provided by the producers. Only a phone for emergencies was provided to him, and he had to write 300 sweepstakes entries every day to win necessities like crackers, which prevented him from going hungry. It took him three weeks to earn his first reward.</p>

<p>Nasubi admitted that, while initially excited, he soon became overwhelmed by the loneliness and isolation. "The hardest part was definitely the loneliness," he said, adding that he struggled to overcome it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s4iko0c8_nasubi-extreme-game-show_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nasubi, a comedian, endured 15 months of isolation and extreme conditions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-going-bankrupt-very-fast-elon-musk-offers-solution-7088804]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["America Going Bankrupt Super Fast": Elon Musk Offers Solution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/america-going-bankrupt-very-fast-elon-musk-offers-solution-7088804]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 19:19:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk, tasked by President-elect Donald Trump to rein in the excessive US spending, has warned that America could be nearing the verge of bankruptcy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk, tasked by President-elect Donald Trump to rein in the excessive US spending, has warned that America could be nearing the verge of bankruptcy. The world's richest man and a close adviser of Mr Trump, Elon Musk has been tasked to spearhead the newly created Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) under the upcoming Republican administration, to find ways of saving taxpayer dollars.</p>

<p>"America is currently headed for bankruptcy super fast," Mr Musk posted to X (formally Twitter), the social media platform he bought in 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Musk wrote this in response to a post on the Department of Government Efficiency's X handle that noted "the US Government spent USD 6.16. trillion while only bringing in USD 4.47 trillion" in 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">America is currently headed for bankruptcy super fast <a href="https://t.co/Tm6JFJ6mef">https://t.co/Tm6JFJ6mef</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1860212805439488130?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"This trend must be reversed, and we must balance the budget," the DOGE account added.</p>

<p>During his election campaign, one of the promises made by President-Elect Trump was the formation of DOGE to dismantle the government bureaucracy and cut wasteful spending.&nbsp;Earlier this year, while talking about skyrocketing US debts, Mr Trump had floated the idea of using Bitcoin to “pay off" "USD 35 trillion".</p>

<p>The President-elect is relying on two successful businessmen -- Mr Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy -- to dig into the details and give recommendations to his administration to restrict spending.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a report by Forbes, the national debt of the US crossed the USD 34 trillion mark at the beginning of 2024, largely due to Covid and lockdown stimulus measures that sent inflation spiralling and forced the Federal Reserve to hike interest rates at a historical clip.</p>

<p>Mr Trump said, "..hand them a little crypto check, right? We'll hand them a little bitcoin and wipe out our USD 35 trillion,” according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mikepatton/2024/11/20/trumps-department-of-government-efficiency-is-poised-to-cut-waste/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Forbes </a>report.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the Republicans won 'Trifacta' of victories in the US, Mr Musk in a post on X said, “Excess government spending is driving America into bankruptcy,” adding, “This debt growth is unsustainable.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>The name of the DOGE department is a nod to the 2013 famous Shiba Inu dog meme, which is also linked to the dogecoin cryptocurrency. According to Mr Musk, Dogecoin is his "favourite" cryptocurrency and is accepted as payment by his Tesla car company.</p>

<p>Bitcoin is a decentralised digital currency that operates without a financial system or government authorities. According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.investopedia.com/news/how-bitcoin-works/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Investopedia</a>, bitcoin can be used as an alternative to fiat currencies through crypto exchanges, utilizing peer-to-peer transfers on a digital network that records all transactions. This network is powered by a blockchain, an open-source program that chains transaction histories to prevent manipulation.</p>

<p>Bitcoin's price today is USD 97,455.70, which represents a change of +4.31% in the last 24 hours.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/04dtmd6g_elon-musk_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Elon Musk said bitcoin can be used to "pay off" "USD 35 trillion" US debt.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-respite-for-elon-musk-after-market-regulators-probe-into-44-billion-twitter-takeover-7088239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Respite For Musk After Market Regulator's Probe Into Twitter Takeover]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/court-respite-for-elon-musk-after-market-regulators-probe-into-44-billion-twitter-takeover-7088239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 18:07:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A judge in the United States has rejected the request of the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to sanction tech billionaire Elon Musk for skipping a meeting with the regulator, to watch one of his rockets launch.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A judge in the United States has rejected the request of the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to sanction tech billionaire Elon Musk for skipping a meeting with the regulator, to watch one of his rockets launch. Mr Musk was ordered by a court to meet the SEC officials in September to provide testimony for the regulator's probe into his USD 44 billion takeover of X (Twitter at the time).</p>

<p>On Friday, US District Judge Jacqueline Scott Corley said there was no need to sanction the billionaire for his absence, as he agreed to reimburse the SEC to cover the airfare of three agency lawyers he stood up in Los Angeles on September 10.</p>

<p>Mr Musk finally complied with the order and met with the SEC lawyers to give testimony on October 3.</p>

<p>"Because the present circumstances forestall any occasion for meaningful relief that the court could grant, the SEC's request is moot," Corley wrote in the order.</p>

<p>The order said that having only to repay travel costs would not deter many other people from ignoring court orders, "much less someone of Mr Musk's extraordinary means."</p>

<p>The SEC urged the federal judge to impose sanctions on Mr Musk to remind him that flouting her order was not a "trivial matte," according to a report by Bloomberg.</p>

<p>However, the report said that Mr Musk's lawyer, Alex Spiro, contested the claim and argued that the billionaire's failure to show up for the deposition was justified because he had an urgent obligation as the head of SpaceX, and had to travel to Florida for the Cape Canaveral launch of a rocket on a commercial spacewalk mission.</p>

<p>Mr Spiro contended that his client's voluntary offer to reimburse the agency for USD 2,923 was sufficient. Mr Musk is worth USD 321.7 billion, according to Forbes magazine.</p>

<p>Any statement from Mr Musk's Lawyers or the SEC was not available at the time of filing this story.</p>

<h2><strong>Market Regulator's Probe</strong></h2>

<p>The SEC is investigating whether Musk -- whose businesses include electric car maker Tesla and rocket company SpaceX and who is the world's richest person-- violated securities laws in early 2022 by waiting at least 10 days too long to disclose he had begun accumulating Twitter stock.</p>

<p>Critics and some investors have said this let him buy shares cheaply before he eventually disclosed a 9.2 per cent Twitter stake, and shortly thereafter offered to buy the whole company.</p>

<p>In July, Mr Musk said he misunderstood SEC disclosure rules and that "all indications" suggested he made a "mistake."</p>

<p>The SEC also sued Mr Musk in 2018 over his Twitter posts about taking Tesla private. He settled that lawsuit by paying a USD 20 million fine, agreeing to let Tesla lawyers review some posts in advance and stepping down as Tesla's chairman.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nihm36r8_elon-musk_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk is worth USD 321.7 billion, according to Forbes magazine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/severed-horses-head-terror-echoes-the-godfather-in-sicilian-mafia-intimidation-7087805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Horse's Head Terror Echoes The Godfather In Sicilian Mafia Intimidation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/severed-horses-head-terror-echoes-the-godfather-in-sicilian-mafia-intimidation-7087805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 17:19:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a chilling Mafia-style warning, a severed horse's head was discovered on the property of a construction contractor in Altofonte, Sicily.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a typical Italian mafia intimidation practice, a horse's copped off head was found on the property of a businessman in Sicily. The grim discovery, which resembles a scene straight out of a mafia blockbuster <em>The Godfather</em> was made in Altofonte, a village on the outskirts of Palermo. The animal's head, completely soaked in blood, was left on the seat of a digger machine that belonged to the Italian businessman. The businessman is a construction contractor who works near Sicily's regional capital, Palermo. The body of a pregnant cow and its calf were also left on the site.</p>

<p>Angela De Luca, the mayor of Altofonte, said her community had been deeply disturbed. "I was petrified; I can't comprehend such barbarity," she said. "This act seems to take us back to the Middle Ages, with its unacceptable methods."</p>

<p>Marlon Brando played Don Vito Corleone in the iconic 1972 movie, which ends with a horse's head in the bed of cruel film director Jack Woltz after Woltz denies Corleone's godson a part.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/21/severed-horse-head-found-at-sicilian-property-in-echo-of-godfather-scene"><em>The Guardian,</em></a> the news sparked a row on the island, where more than 20 mafia bosses have been released from prison in recent months after serving their sentences. Delivering severed animal heads or dismembered animal bodies is among the most common intimidation tactics employed by the mafia in Sicily, predating<em>&nbsp;The Godfather.</em></p>

<p>According to investigators, the tactic serves the dual purpose of terrorising its victims and striking at their most cherished bonds: animals to which they are often deeply attached. Last May, the head of a goat was found in front of the home of a construction entrepreneur in Palermo, and in 2023, a pig's head was hung at the gate of a police station in the province of Messina.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jqnhi13_the-godfather_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marlon Brando played Don Vito Corleone in the iconic 1972 movie.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-how-the-british-empire-robbed-india-of-45-trillion-7087633]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How The British Empire Robbed India Of $45 Trillion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-how-the-british-empire-robbed-india-of-45-trillion-7087633]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 16:55:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the nearly two-century-long rule over India between 1757 and 1947, the British Empire exploited the country's resources, wealth, and people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During the nearly two-century-long rule over India between 1757 and 1947, the British Empire exploited the country's resources, wealth, and people. The impact of colonial rule is felt to this day. According to renowned economist Utsa Patnaik, professor emeritus at New Delhi's Jawaharlal Nehru University, the British drained approximately $45 trillion from India between 1765 and 1938, a sum 17 times the current GDP of the UK.</p>

<p>This figure is substantial, but how did such an enormous amount of wealth end up in British hands? The story begins with the British East India Company, which, after gaining control of India, established a monopoly on its trade. The Company initially bought goods from India using silver, but over time, they developed a cunning system to exploit Indian resources without paying for them.</p>

<p>The process was simple yet devious. The East India Company began collecting taxes from Indian farmers and weavers, and instead of using the collected funds for local development or compensation, they used a portion of it to buy goods from the Indian producers. However, these purchases were made using the tax money collected from the same people. This system allowed the British to acquire goods for free, while the Indian producers were essentially robbed of their wealth.</p>

<p>Much of the goods that were "purchased" from India were re-exported, generating huge profits for Britain and multiplying the returns for the colonial power. The British didn't just consume these goods, they sold them at a markup in other countries, pocketing not only the original value of the goods but also the profits.</p>

<p>Once the British Raj was established in 1858. after the first war of Independence in 1857, this system evolved into an even more exploitative mechanism. Indian goods were exported to foreign markets, but payments were still funnelled through London. Traders wishing to purchase Indian goods had to use British-issued Council Bills, which they could only buy with gold or silver. This meant all the precious metals that should have gone directly to Indian producers instead ended up in British coffers. As a result, while India had a trade surplus with the rest of the world, the profits were effectively syphoned off by Britain.</p>

<p>Utsa Patnaik's research showed how India was a major source of funding for Britain's imperial ambitions. The wealth extracted from India financed British industrialisation and also funded the British wars of conquest, including the invasion of China in the 1840s and the suppression of the Indian Rebellion of 1857.</p>

<p>Apart from that, the income that should have been invested in India's development was instead used to fuel European capitalist expansion, benefiting other parts of the world, including Canada and Australia.</p>

<p>This drain continued for decades, and the consequences for India were devastating. During the period of British rule, India's per capita income remained stagnant, and in the late 19th century, it even collapsed. Famine, poverty, and disease ravaged the population, and tens of millions of Indians died as a result of British policies such as exporting food grains during times of famine.</p>

<p>Despite this grim reality, some voices in Britain still promote the narrative that British rule in India was beneficial. Historian Niall Ferguson has suggested that British colonialism helped "develop" India, but Utsa Patnaik's findings have painted a very different picture. British rule in India was not a gesture of benevolence, but rather a systematic exploitation of the country's resources for Britain's gain.</p>

<p>Had India been able to retain the wealth and resources it produced, the country's course could have been vastly different. With the drain of $45 trillion, India could have potentially become an economic powerhouse, avoiding much of the poverty and suffering that followed British rule. The wealth that Britain extracted from India played a significant role in its own industrialisation, at the expense of the very people it governed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-03/vk29aad8_dandi-march_625x300_12_March_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This drain continued for decades, and the consequences for India were devastating.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-ministers-to-discuss-icc-warrant-for-israels-netanyahu-next-week-says-italy-pm-meloni-7087483]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[G7 Ministers To Discuss ICC Warrant For Netanyahu Next Week: Italy PM Meloni]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g7-ministers-to-discuss-icc-warrant-for-israels-netanyahu-next-week-says-italy-pm-meloni-7087483]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 16:33:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[G7 ministers meeting in Italy next week will discuss the International Criminal Court's arrest warrant for Benjamin Netanyahu, Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni said Friday, saying the issue required further analysis]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>G7 ministers meeting in Italy next week will discuss the International Criminal Court's arrest warrant for Benjamin Netanyahu, Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni said Friday, saying the issue required further analysis.</p>

<p>Israel and its allies denounced the ICC's decision on Thursday to issue an arrest warrant for the Israeli premier, even as Turkey -- and rights groups -- welcomed the move.</p>

<p>Meloni's hard-right coalition government appeared divided.</p>

<p>Defence Minister Guido Crosetto said Thursday that Italy would have to arrest Israel's premier if he visited, only for Meloni's deputy prime minister, Matteo Salvini, to say Netanyahu would be welcome in Italy.</p>

<p>"In the coming days I will delve deeper into the reasons that led to the ICC's decision. Reasons that should always be objective and not political in nature," Meloni said in a statement.</p>

<p>She said the issue would be put on the agenda of a meeting of Group of Seven foreign ministers in Fiuggi, near Rome, on Monday and Tuesday.</p>

<p>The ICC also issued arrest warrants for Netanyahu's former defence minister and for Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>"One point remains clear from this government -- there cannot be an equivalence between the responsibility of the state of Israel and the terrorist organisation Hamas," Meloni said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2r0v7l1_italy-prime-minister-giorgia-meloni_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Giorgia Meloni's hard-right coalition government appeared divided on ICC warrants.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-calls-his-officials-criminals-media-wrong-over-leaks-fake-report-on-indian-leadership-7087186]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trudeau Calls Officials "Criminals" Over Fake Report On Indian Leadership]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-calls-his-officials-criminals-media-wrong-over-leaks-fake-report-on-indian-leadership-7087186]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 15:51:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid heightened diplomatic tension with India, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau called his own intelligence officials 'criminals' for linking Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar to violence in Canada.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid heightened diplomatic tension with India, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau called his own intelligence officials "criminals" for linking Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Foreign Minister Subrahmanyam Jaishankar to violence on Canadian soil.</p>

<p>Addressing media in Brampton on Friday, Trudeau said, "We have seen, unfortunately, that criminals leaking top-secret information to the media have consistently gotten those stories wrong."</p>

<p>"That's why we had a national enquiry into foreign interference, which has highlighted that criminals leaking information to media outlets are unreliable on top of being criminals," he added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Reacting on Globe &amp; Mail report on PM Modi, EAM, NSA, Canada PM Justin Trudeau terms his officials 'criminals' for leaking information to media on Indian Leadership; Terms media reports 'wrong'<br />
<br />
Ctsy: CPAC <a href="https://t.co/eQji6hKkNw">pic.twitter.com/eQji6hKkNw</a></p>
— Vipul? (@_lonewolf0308) <a href="https://twitter.com/_lonewolf0308/status/1860252885897851072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The development came after Canada, on Thursday, fact-checked and denied a report linking top Indian leaders to criminal activities on Canadian soil.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a statement posted on a government website, Nathalie Drouin, Mr Trudeau's intelligence adviser, said: "The Government of Canada has not stated, nor is it aware of the evidence, linking Prime Minister Modi, Minister Jaishankar, or NSA Doval to the serious criminal activity within Canada. Any suggestion to the contrary is both speculative and inaccurate."</p>

<p>Canada's statement came after Globe and Mail newspaper published a report this week, alleging that Canadian security agencies believed PM Modi knew about the violent plots and said Mr Jaishankar and National Security Adviser (NSA) Ajit Doval were also in the loop.</p>

<p>Last month, The Canadian foreign ministry alleged Union Home Minister Amit Shah was behind a campaign of intimidation in Canada. Ottawa says it has evidence linking Indian government agents to the 2023 murder of Khalistan terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar, who held a Canadian passport.</p>

<p>The ties between the two countries have come under severe strain following Trudeau's allegations in September last year of a "potential involvement" of Indian agents in the killing of Khalistan terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar, who held a Canadian passport.</p>

<p>New Delhi rejected Trudeau's charges as "absurd". India has maintained that the main issue between the two countries is that of Canada giving space to pro-Khalistan elements operating from Canadian soil with impunity.</p>

<p>The row has escalated to a point where both countries have expelled each other's top diplomats.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/644mqu68_trudeau-india-pc_625x300_15_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau addressed allegations of a link between PM Modi and criminal activity in Canada]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-to-go-uk-way-on-netanyahu-arrest-trudeau-says-will-abide-by-icc-warrant-7086684]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trudeau Confirms Canada Will Arrest Netanyahu After World Court Order]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-to-go-uk-way-on-netanyahu-arrest-trudeau-says-will-abide-by-icc-warrant-7086684]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 14:43:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After the United Kingdom, Canada said it would "abide" by the arrest warrant issued against Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu by the International Criminal Court (ICC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the United Kingdom, Canada said it would "abide" by the arrest warrant issued against Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu by the International Criminal Court (ICC).&nbsp;"We stand up for international law, and we will abide by all the regulations and rulings of the international courts," Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is just who we are as Canadians," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ICC issued arrest warrants for Israeli premier and his former defence minister Yoav Gallant on Thursday for "crimes against humanity" committed since the Israel-Hamas war began more than a year ago, triggered by the militant Palestinian group's October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>A warrant was also issued for Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif.</p>

<p>Earlier on Friday, the British government indicated that Netanyahu could be arrested on the ICC arrest warrant if he travelled to the UK.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer's spokesman said: "The UK will always comply with its legal obligations as set out by domestic law and indeed international law."</p>

<p>However, he refused to be drawn specifically on whether UK police would detain Netanyahu, telling reporters he would not "get into hypotheticals in relation to individual cases".</p>

<p>Both the UK and Canada are part of the Five Eyes, an intelligence alliance also composed of Australia, New Zealand, and the United States. Other countries that agreed to follow through with the ICC's decision include-- Belgium, the European Union, France, Iran, Ireland, Jordan, The Netherlands, Norway, Sweden, South Africa, Switzerland, and Turkey among others.</p>

<p>Other key Five Eyes member US has, however, called the move 'outrageous'. "The ICC issuance of arrest warrants against Israeli leaders is outrageous," President Joe Biden said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Let me be clear once again: whatever the ICC might imply, there is no equivalence - none - between Israel and Hamas. We will always stand with Israel against threats to its security," the statement added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the warrant was supported by&nbsp;US Senator Bernie Sanders, who took to X and said: “All launched indiscriminate attacks against civilians and caused unimaginable human suffering”.</p>

<p>“If the world does not uphold international law, we will descend into further barbarism,” he added.</p>

<p>Other countries to declare 'disagreement' with ICC decisions include-- Argentina, Austria, and Hungary, among others.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8npvqse8_benjamin-netanyahu-yoav-gallant_625x300_21_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ICC issued arrest warrants for Israeli premier Netanyahu and his former defence minister Yoav Gallant]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-chief-discusses-global-security-with-donald-trump-7086677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO Chief Discusses 'Global Security' With Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-chief-discusses-global-security-with-donald-trump-7086677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 14:41:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NATO chief Mark Rutte held talks with US President-elect Donald Trump in Florida on the "global security issues facing the alliance", a spokeswoman said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO chief Mark Rutte held talks with US President-elect Donald Trump in Florida on the "global security issues facing the alliance", a spokeswoman said Saturday.</p>

<p>The meeting took place on Friday in Palm Beach, NATO's Farah Dakhlallah said in a statement.</p>

<p>In his first term Trump aggressively pushed Europe to step up defence spending and questioned the fairness of the NATO transatlantic alliance.</p>

<p>The former Dutch prime minister had said he wanted to meet Trump two days after Trump was elected on November 5, and discuss the threat of increasingly warming ties between North Korea and Russia.</p>

<p>Trump's thumping victory to return to the US presidency has set nerves jangling in Europe that he could pull the plug on vital Washington military aid for Ukraine.</p>

<p>NATO allies say keeping Kyiv in the fight against Moscow is key to both European and American security.</p>

<p>"What we see more and more is that North Korea, Iran, China and of course Russia are working together, working together against Ukraine," Rutte said recently at a European leaders' meeting in Budapest.</p>

<p>"At the same time, Russia has to pay for this, and one of the things they are doing is delivering technology to North Korea", which he warned was threatening to the "mainland of the US (and) continental Europe".</p>

<p>"I look forward to sitting down with Donald Trump to discuss how we can face these threats collectively," Rutte said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/nhi1sk7_nato_625x300_20_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NATO allies say keeping Kyiv in the fight against Moscow is key to both European and American security.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-ancient-hot-water-on-mars-indicator-of-its-habitable-past-7086548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Discovery Of Ancient Hot Water On Mars Indicator Of Its Habitable Past]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/discovery-of-ancient-hot-water-on-mars-indicator-of-its-habitable-past-7086548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 14:21:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australian researchers have discovered the oldest direct evidence of hot water activity on Mars, revealing that the planet may have once been habitable.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australian researchers have discovered the oldest direct evidence of hot water activity on Mars, revealing that the planet may have once been habitable.</p>

<p>In a study published on Saturday, a team led by researchers from Curtin University in Western Australia analyzed a 4.45 billion-year-old zircon grain from the famous Martian meteorite NWA7034, also known as Black Beauty, that was found in the Sahara Desert in 2011.</p>

<p>The researchers found that the grain of zircon, a type of mineral, contained geochemical fingerprints of water-rich fluids, suggesting that water was present during early Martian magmatic activity.</p>

<p>Aaron Cavosie, a co-author of the study from Curtin's School of Earth and Planetary Sciences, said that the discovery would open up new avenues for understanding ancient Martian hydrothermal systems, as well as the planet's past capacity to support life.</p>

<p>"We used nano-scale geochemistry to detect elemental evidence of hot water on Mars 4.45 billion years ago," he said, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"Hydrothermal systems were essential for the development of life on Earth and our findings suggest Mars also had water, a key ingredient for habitable environments, during the earliest history of crust formation."</p>

<p>He said that even though Mars' crust endured major meteorite impacts that caused surface upheaval, the research shows that water was present on the planet during the early Pre-Noachian period prior to about 4.1 billion years ago.</p>

<p>The study also involved researchers from the University of Adelaide and was led by Jack Gillespie, a former research associate at Curtin's School of Earth and Planetary Sciences now at the University of Lausanne in Switzerland.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jmtbn33g_mars_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research suggested that water was present during early Martian magmatic activity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/profoundly-saddened-laos-government-after-6-tourists-die-of-contaminated-alcohol-7086511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Profoundly Saddened": Laos Government After 6 Tourists Die]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/profoundly-saddened-laos-government-after-6-tourists-die-of-contaminated-alcohol-7086511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 14:18:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alcohol tainted with methanol, a toxic alcohol usually used in industrial and household products like antifreeze, is suspected to be the cause of the deaths.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Laos government said Saturday it was "profoundly saddened" by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/four-tourists-die-after-suspected-laos-methanol-poisoning-7070694">deaths of foreign tourists in Vang Vieng</a>, with the toll from a suspected methanol poisoning incident now at six.</p>

<p>Two Danish citizens, an American, a Briton and two Australians have now died after being rushed to hospital following a night out in backpacker hot spot Vang Vieng.</p>

<p>They were among a group of about a dozen foreigners who fell ill and were rushed to hospital shortly after November 12.</p>

<p>In a statement on its website, Laos' Ministry of Foreign Affairs said Saturday it expressed "sincere sympathy and deepest condolences to the families of the deceased", adding an investigation was underway.</p>

<p>Australian Holly Bowles, 19, became the incident's latest fatality on Friday when she died in a Bangkok hospital surrounded by family.</p>

<p>Canberra is pressing Laotian authorities for a full and transparent investigation into what happened.</p>

<p>Vang Vieng has been a fixture on the Southeast Asia backpacker trail since Laos' secretive communist rulers opened the country to tourism decades ago.</p>

<p>The town was once synonymous with backpackers behaving badly at jungle parties but has since re-branded as an eco-tourism destination.</p>

<p>The Vietnamese manager of the Nana Backpackers Hostel where the tourists were staying has been detained for questioning, the Laos tourist police told AFP.</p>

<p>No charges have been filed thus far.</p>

<p>Police in Laos could not be reached for comment on Saturday.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-contaminated-alcohol-in-laos-led-to-multiple-tourist-deaths-7084970">Explained: How Contaminated Alcohol In Laos Led To Multiple Tourist Deaths</a></p>

<p>Alcohol tainted with methanol, a toxic alcohol usually used in industrial and household products like antifreeze, is suspected to be the cause of the deaths.</p>

<p>It can be added to liquor to increase its potency but can cause blindness, liver damage and death.</p>

<p>Danish, Australian and British officials released statements confirming the deaths of their nationals in the week following the incident.</p>

<p>On their travel advice websites, UK and Australian authorities have warned their citizens to beware of methanol poisoning while consuming alcohol in Laos.</p>

<p>But in Vang Vieng, business seemed to be going on as usual.</p>

<p>"I heard the news but everything is normal here," Michael, a manager at Vangvieng Rock Backpacker Rooftop Hostel told AFP on Friday, asking to use only one name.</p>

<p>"The high season is about to start, so we are welcoming more tourists every day."</p>

<p>"There are still many tourists in town, and they go partying," a receptionist at Vang Vieng Chill House Hostel told AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vlpvv6t8_laos_625x300_21_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canberra is pressing Laotian authorities for a full and transparent investigation into what happened.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harshita-brella-murder-her-husband-kept-asking-for-dowry-sister-of-indian-woman-24-found-dead-in-uk-7086357]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Her Husband Kept Asking For Dowry": Sister Of Indian, 24, Found Dead In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harshita-brella-murder-her-husband-kept-asking-for-dowry-sister-of-indian-woman-24-found-dead-in-uk-7086357]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 13:56:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Days after 24-year-old Harshita Brella - an Indian woman from Delhi living with her husband in the UK - was found dead with her body stashed away in the boot of a car, his family has pointed to a dowry angle in the case.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days after 24-year-old Harshita Brella - an Indian woman from Delhi living with her husband in the UK - was found dead with her body stashed away in the boot of a car, his family has pointed to a dowry angle in the case.</p>

<p>Harshita Brella married Pankaj Lamba - who has been missing since her murder - on March 22 this year. Now, Sonia Brella, the elder sister of Harshita, suspects that she was murdered for dowry even though they had given the Lamba family gold and money during the wedding.</p>

<p>"The family had given a lot of dowry to Pankaj but still he was not happy, he kept demanding dowry from us," she told ANI.</p>

<p>An investigation by the Northamptonshire Police suggests that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/harshita-brella-murder-family-claims-accused-husband-preplanned-killing-7082982">Harshita Brella</a> was murdered on November 10. On the same night, she was seen walking with her husband by a boating lake in Corby where she lived.</p>

<p>As per the police, Harshita Brella's body had been transported from Corby to east London - some 145 kilometers away - by car, which was found parked with her body on Brisbane Road, Ilford on November 14. The car allegedly belonged to her husband.</p>

<p>Earlier, her father, Sabir Brella, also alleged that Lamba and his family used to harass her for dowry. "Pankaj used to beat her and force her to get money. Due to the regular fights, she started living separately and working in a warehouse. Despite living separately, he would handle her bank accounts," he said.</p>

<p>However, she kept giving money to him "with a hope that some day things will become normal", her father said, adding, " She didn't know that this would be the end.</p>

<p>"On August 29, when Pankaj had beaten her she lodged a complaint against him. Subsequently, his family members had come at our house here and again started demanding dowry, due to which my father sold some property to fulfill their demand and by February we were able to fulfill the demand. We were about to fulfil their demands after we got the money in hand," Sonia Brella said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/family-of-indian-origin-woman-found-dead-in-car-boot-in-uk-call-for-justice-7059224">Harshita Brella</a> was the subject of a 28-day domestic violence order against Lamba, which had not been renewed at the time of her killing.</p>

<p>"She used to give us every moment's information. This case was closed on October 30 when Pankaj paid the fine, but Harshita was not informed about it," her sister claimed.</p>

<p>Recalling her last video call with Harshita, her sister said, "We had the last video call with Harshita on November 10 when she told us that she was preparing food for Pankaj who was coming over for dinner."</p>

<p>"From the next day her phone was not reachable. We had a feeling that Pankaj had killed her by then," she added.</p>

<p>Even as the police are looking for Pankaj Lamba and released a series of CCTV images of him, her family claimed that he fled to India a day after the brutal murder.</p>

<p>"We have proof of him coming back to India, which we have told to London police. Here no one is helping us. We have also approached our local police and filed a complaint of dowry harassment against Pankaj and her parents," Sonia Brella said.</p>

<p>Harshita Brella's body might reach India in a week or two, she added.</p>

<p>Her sister also alleged that Lamba's family knows his whereabouts and is aware of the murder: "When I called Pankaj's mother about the news, she coolly replied that at least my sister was returning back. She said her son's whereabouts are not known. But, on the other hand, they are not even trying to find his whereabouts and are calm. This behaviour raises suspicions."</p>

<p>Earlier this week, an inquest into Harshita Brella's killing was opened in Northampton and adjourned until May 21, 2025, while the murder investigation remains ongoing. The provisional cause of her death was noted as "manual strangulation pending toxicology and histology" at the inquest hearing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v3k0pumg_harshita-brella_625x300_20_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harshita Brella married Pankaj Lamba - who has been missing since her murder - in March this year]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-to-balance-compliance-and-tech-advances-under-donald-trump-administration-7086350]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia To Balance "Compliance And Tech Advances" Under Trump Administration]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-to-balance-compliance-and-tech-advances-under-donald-trump-administration-7086350]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 13:54:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nvidia reported record-high quarterly revenue on the back of strong AI chip demand, though investors are wary of US-China tensions reheating during a new Trump term.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang said Saturday that his company will balance legal compliance and technological advances under the incoming administration of Donald Trump, and nothing will stop the global advancement of artificial intelligence.</p>

<p>The US chipmaking giant this week reported record high quarterly revenue on the back of strong AI chip demand, though investors are wary of US-China tensions reheating during a new Trump term.</p>

<p>The Taiwan-born entrepreneur was in Hong Kong to receive an honorary doctorate in engineering from the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.</p>

<p>"Whatever happens, we'll balance simultaneously compliance with laws and policies, continue to advance our technology, and support and serve customers all over the world," Huang told reporters on Saturday.</p>

<p>"We'll continue to do that and we'll be able to do that just fine."</p>

<p>The Biden administration has restricted Nvidia from selling some of its top AI chips to China, which it sees as a strategic competitor in the field of advanced semiconductors.</p>

<p>Huang said Saturday that "open science and open research in AI is absolutely global... nothing that I see in the future is going to stop that."</p>

<p>Huang said in a speech that the "age of AI has started" and lauded China's "significant contributions" to the scientific research that push forward AI technology.</p>

<p>"AI is certainly the most important technology of our time, and potentially at all times," he said.</p>

<p>Tech giants around the world have invested tens of billions of dollars into Nvidia's technology to train their generative AI models and support their heavy computing needs.</p>

<p>Nvidia surpassed Apple early this month to become the highest valued company in the world as the artificial intelligence boom continues to excite Wall Street.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8r260268_nvidia_625x300_23_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Biden administration has restricted Nvidia from selling some of its top AI chips to China.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-dirty-harry-among-2-convicted-after-gujarati-family-froze-to-death-on-us-canada-border-7085988]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Among 2 Convicted After Gujarati Family's Death On US-Canada Border]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-dirty-harry-among-2-convicted-after-gujarati-family-froze-to-death-on-us-canada-border-7085988]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 23 Nov 2024 13:02:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has convicted two, including an Indian national, of charges related to Human smuggling after an Indian migrant family froze to death while attempting to cross the Canada-US border during a blizzard in 2022.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States has convicted two, including an Indian national, of charges related to Human smuggling after an Indian migrant family froze to death while attempting to cross the Canada-US border during a blizzard in 2022. A Minnesota jury found that Harshkumar Ramanlal Patel, an Indian national known by the alias “Dirty Harry,” and Florida resident Steve Shand, were part of a sophisticated illegal operation that has brought increasing numbers of Indians into the US, prosecutors said.</p>

<p>Patel (29) and Shand (50) were each convicted on four counts related to human smuggling, including conspiracy to bring migrants into the country illegally. The most serious counts carry maximum sentences of up to 20 years in prison, The Associated Press reported quoting the US Attorney's Office.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the guidelines for federal sentencing in the US rely on complicated formulas. according to Minnesota US Attorney Andy Luger, various factors will be considered to determine what sentences prosecutors will recommend for the convicted.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Case</strong></h2>

<p>The victims—39-year-old Jagdish Patel, his wife Vaishaliben, who was in her mid-30s, their 11-year-old daughter Vihangi, and three-year-old son Dharmik—were found frozen to death near Emerson town of Manitoba province by Canadian authorities on January 19, 2022, while trying to cross the border into Minnesota in a scheme Patel and Shand organized.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The family was originally from Dingucha village in Gujarat's Gandhinagar district. Patel and his wife were reportedly schoolteachers and their family was fairly well off by local standards. Patels were part of an 11-member group of undocumented Indian migrants who had paid smugglers to navigate their illegal entry into the US.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Verdict</strong></h3>

<p>The verdict in the case came on Friday at the end of the five-day federal trial in Minnesota's Fergus Falls.</p>

<p>Condemning the operation, US Attorney Luger said, "This trial exposed the unthinkable cruelty of human smuggling and of those criminal organizations that value profit and greed over humanity."</p>

<p>“To earn a few thousand dollars, these traffickers put men, women and children in extraordinary peril leading to the horrific and tragic deaths of an entire family. Because of this unimaginable greed, a father, a mother and two children froze to death in sub-zero temperatures on the Minnesota-Canadian border,” he added.</p>

<p>During the trial, Defence attorneys from both accused were pitted against each other. Shand's team said that their client was unwittingly roped into Patel's smuggling scheme, while Patel's lawyers argued that he had been misidentified.</p>

<p>Patel's team said that “Dirty Hary,” the alleged nickname for their client found in Shand's phone, is a different person, according to The Canadian Press.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, the prosecutors argued that Patel was the coordinator of the smuggling operation while Shand was a driver. They said that Shand was to pick up 11 Indian migrants on the Minnesota side of the border, however, only seven survived the foot crossing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Patel family was found by Canadian authorities later that morning, dead from the cold.</p>

<p>During the trial, Yash Patel, a 29-year-old survivor who managed to cross over and reach the van driven by Shand on the fateful day, also testified. He told the court that the group had separated after stepping into the blizzard. The van was later caught by the Border Patrol Police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trial also included an inside account of an alleged participant in the smuggling ring. Rajinder Singh, 51, a survivor of the treacherous journey across the northern border, testified that he made over USD 400,000 smuggling over 500 people through the same network that included Patel and Shand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per the AP report, Singh said most of the people he smuggled came from Gujarat state. He said the migrants would often pay smugglers about USD 100,000 to get them from India to the US, where they would work to pay off their debts at low-wage jobs in cities around the country. According to Singh, smugglers ran their finances through “hawala,” an informal money transfer system that relies on trust.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-01/ik24iltg_patel-family-canada-us-border-death_625x300_28_January_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harshkumar Patel or "Dirty Harry" was convicted on four counts related to human smuggling.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>