<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:51:06 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-hits-out-at-trumps-staff-over-pushing-military-cemetery-worker-6450011]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Army Hits Out At Trump's Staff Over Pushing Military Cemetery Worker]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-army-hits-out-at-trumps-staff-over-pushing-military-cemetery-worker-6450011]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:51:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US Army on Thursday took aim at Donald Trump's staff over a visit by the Republican presidential candidate to the country's most hallowed resting place for its war dead.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Army on Thursday took aim at Donald Trump's staff over a visit by the Republican presidential candidate to the country's most hallowed resting place for its war dead.</p>

<p>The incident has mushroomed into an uncharacteristically public dispute between the military and a former US commander in chief, with Trump lashing out and accusing President Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris of having "killed" American soldiers through "gross incompetence" in Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Trump went to Arlington National Cemetery just outside Washington with family members of some of the 13 service members killed in a 2021 bombing during the last hours of the US withdrawal from Afghanistan.</p>

<p>His campaign posted photos from the visit, including one showing him giving a thumbs-up gesture while standing with relatives at the grave of one of the US Marines killed.</p>

<p>The Army said an Arlington employee was "abruptly pushed aside" when she sought to ensure a law prohibiting political activity on cemetery grounds was followed.</p>

<p>"This incident was unfortunate, and it is also unfortunate that the (Arlington National Cemetery) employee and her professionalism has been unfairly attacked," an Army spokesperson said in a statement.</p>

<p>Going on the offensive, Trump's campaign co-manager Chris LaCivita has described the employee as a "despicable individual," while campaign spokesman Steven Cheung said she was "clearly suffering from a mental health episode."</p>

<p>Doubling down, LaCivita later reposted video of Trump's presence at Arlington and said he hoped it would "trigger the hacks" at the US Army secretary's office.</p>

<p>Trump has made criticism of Biden's handling of the retreat from Afghanistan a key note of his campaign ahead of November's election.</p>

<p>The US withdrawal was made as part of a peace deal signed by the Trump administration with the Taliban.</p>

<p>At a Thursday rally in Michigan, Trump defended his gravesite visit and savaged Biden and Harris, his 2024 White House rival, over Afghanistan.</p>

<p>"They asked me to go yesterday to Arlington and I did," Trump said of the families, adding that "bad people" accused him of inappropriate political activity.</p>

<p>"Joe Biden killed their children, by incompetence... Kamala killed their children -- just as though they had a gun in their hand -- by gross incompetence," Trump told supporters.</p>

<p>"Not one general or incompetent bureaucrat was fired," over the deadly pullout, he added. "And then they accuse me of having a picture taken at the tombstone with the family." &nbsp;</p>

<p>Uproar over the incident at Arlington on Monday is the latest controversy in Trump's troubled relationship with the military.</p>

<p>While often touting his support for the armed forces, he privately mocked the war dead while he was president and did not want to be seen near military amputees, according to his former chief of staff.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9tmmam9k_trump-cemetery_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-executed-for-killing-college-student-raping-his-sister-in-1995-6449882]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Executed For Killing College Student, Raping His Sister In 1995]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-executed-for-killing-college-student-raping-his-sister-in-1995-6449882]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:24:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man convicted of murdering a college student and raping his sister while the siblings were on a camping trip was executed in the southern US state of Florida on Thursday, prison officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man convicted of murdering a college student and raping his sister while the siblings were on a camping trip was executed in the southern US state of Florida on Thursday, prison officials said.</p>

<p>Loran Cole, 57, was put to death by lethal injection at 6:15 pm (2215 GMT) at the Florida State Prison in Raiford, the Florida Department of Corrections said in a statement.</p>

<p>Cole was sentenced to death in December 1995 for the February 1994 murder of an 18-year-old Florida State University student, who was on a camping trip with his sister in the Ocala National Forest.</p>

<p>Cole was also convicted of sexually assaulting the murder victim's elder sister, who was tied to a tree but managed to escape the next day.</p>

<p>An accomplice, William Paul, was sentenced to life in prison.</p>

<p>The US Supreme Court denied Thursday afternoon -- without comment -- Cole's appeal to stay his execution on the grounds he had Parkinson's disease and the lethal injection would "very likely cause him needless pain and suffering."</p>

<p>There have been 13 executions in the United States this year.</p>

<p>The death penalty has been abolished in 23 US states, while six others -- Arizona, California, Ohio, Oregon, Pennsylvania and Tennessee -- have moratoriums in place.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n6vf3cdk_loran-cole_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-flip-flop-claims-my-values-have-not-changed-6449726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Rejects "Flip-Flop" Claims: "My Values Have Not Changed"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-flip-flop-claims-my-values-have-not-changed-6449726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 08:45:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris defended her policy shifts on key issues Thursday, insisting in the first interview of her US presidential campaign that her "values have not changed."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris defended her policy shifts on key issues Thursday, insisting in the first interview of her US presidential campaign that her "values have not changed."</p>

<p>The 59-year-old Democrat also said that she would name a Republican to her cabinet if she wins November's election, in her joint CNN sit-down with her running mate Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Rival Donald Trump branded the US vice president the "greatest flip-flopper" as he addressed a rally in the swing state of Michigan.</p>

<p>Harris said her positions had evolved on the issues of fracking, which she previously opposed, and illegal migration over the Mexican border, on which she has taken an increasingly tough stance.</p>

<p>"I think the most important and most significant aspect of my policy perspective and decisions is my values have not changed," Harris said in an excerpt of the CNN interview. The full version is being screened at 9pm (0100 GMT Friday).</p>

<p>Republicans had criticized Harris for not giving any interviews since President Joe Biden dropped out of the White House race nearly six weeks ago.</p>

<p>Harris has enjoyed a honeymoon period with surging polls and record fundraising, but has also faced scrutiny for keeping many of her policies vague.</p>

<p>But in a gesture of unity she said it would be to the "benefit of the American public" to have a Republican in her cabinet if elected.</p>

<p>The first female, Black and South Asian vice president in US history meanwhile brushed aside Trump's recent comments questioning her racial identity. "Same old, tired playbook," she said.</p>

<p>Harris gave the interview while on a campaign bus tour of Georgia, one of the seven battleground states that are expected to decide the November 5 election.</p>

<h2>'Tight race'</h2>

<p>A number of polls out Thursday showed Harris ahead of Trump, if only marginally, with several of them finding increased support for Harris in battleground states.</p>

<p>A Bloomberg/Morning Consult poll found Harris leading in six out of the seven swing states while a Fox poll also showed increasing support in the battlegrounds.</p>

<p>At a rally in Savannah at the end of the two-day swing in Georgia, which Democrats flipped from Trump in 2020, she admitted it was "going to be a tight race until the very end."</p>

<p>Trump has himself been hitting the campaign trail hard in recent days, after a period where the 78-year-old former president appeared to struggle to find his footing against a new, younger, female candidate.</p>

<p>Speaking at an event in Potterville, Michigan on Thursday, Trump targeted Harris on her immigration policy shifts: "Now she's saying, 'Oh we want to build a strong border."</p>

<p>"Where has she been for three and a half years?"</p>

<p>Yet both Trump and Harris appear to be making gestures towards the center ground.</p>

<p>Trump said in an interview with NBC News Thursday that if elected, either the government or insurance companies would cover the cost of in vitro fertilization (IVF) for Americans.</p>

<p>Reproductive rights have been a major vulnerability for Trump since the Supreme Court gutted federal protections for abortion access in 2022, and an Alabama court ruled in February that frozen embryos created via IVF should be considered children.</p>

<p>Harris's speech meanwhile focused on the cost of living. She repeated her pledge to give tax cuts to families in the first year of a child's life "to help pay for that car seat, or the crib, or the baby clothes."</p>

<p>Her CNN interview is being closely watched in a year where big set-piece political events have shown their ability to produce surprises, like Biden's debate disaster on June 27 that led to him quitting the race.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are set to face off in their pivotal first debate on September 10 in Philadelphia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-cnn-interview-america-will-become-wasteland-6449722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["America Will Become Wasteland": Donald Trump Slams Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-slams-kamala-harris-cnn-interview-america-will-become-wasteland-6449722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 08:41:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican Donald Trump on Friday slammed his rival Kamala Harris after the Democrat gave her first major interview since her dramatic entry into the US presidential election after Joe Biden's exit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican Donald Trump on Friday slammed his rival Kamala Harris after the Democrat gave her first major interview since her dramatic entry into the US presidential election after Joe Biden's exit. Ms Harris, 59, spoke to CNN and described Mr Trump as "pushing an agenda and an environment that is about diminishing the character and the strength of who we are as Americans, really dividing our nation."</p>

<p>"I think people are ready to turn the page on that," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-ready-to-turn-the-page-on-donald-trump-says-kamala-harris-6449417#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> said. "People are ready for a new way forward."</p>

<p>Attacking Ms Harris, Mr Trump said she "rambled incoherently" in the interview, which came ahead of the US Election Day on November 5.</p>

<p>"I just saw Comrade Kamala Harris' answer to a very weakly-phrased question, a question that was put in more as a matter of defense than curiosity, but her answer rambled incoherently, and declared her "values haven't changed." On that I agree, her values haven't changed - The Border is going to remain open, not closed, there will be Free Healthcare for Illegal Aliens, Sanctuary Cities, No Cash Bail, Gun Confiscation, Zero Fracking, a Ban on Gasoline-Powered Cars, Private Healthcare will be abolished, a 70-80% tax rate will be put in place, and she will Defund the Police. America will become a WASTELAND," he said in a post on his Truth Social media platform.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113047834410575093/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p>He also branded the interview "BORING!!!".</p>

<p>In another post, he also said he "looks so forward" to debating <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-kamala-harris-was-doing-when-joe-biden-quit-us-presidential-race-6449446#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> and "exposing her for the fraud she is".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Harris has changed every one of her long held positions, on everything. America will never allow an election WEAPONIZING MARXIST TO BE PRESIDENT OF THE US," he wrote.</p>

<p><iframe allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="truthsocial-embed" src="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/113048338913573380/embed" style="max-width: 100%; border: 0" width="600"></iframe><script src="https://truthsocial.com/embed.js" async="async"></script></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vs-kamala-harris-the-battle-over-hot-mics-heats-up-ahead-of-key-debate-6435273" target="_blank">Donald Trump and Kamala Harris are scheduled to debate</a> on September 10.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Mr Trump addressed a rally in Michigan and called Ms Harris the "greatest flip-flopper".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-flip-flop-claims-my-values-have-not-changed-6449726" target="_blank">Ms Harris has rejected criticism</a> that she has shifted positions on politically sensitive issues including fracking, which she once opposed but now supports, and illegal migration over the Mexican border, where she has taken a harder line.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lqgn5nn_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump branded Kamala Harris' interview "BORING"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/43-hour-flightime-32-000-km-87-year-old-pope-francis-epic-voyage-6449694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[43-Hour Flightime, 32,000 km: 87-Year-Old Pope Francis' Epic Voyage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/43-hour-flightime-32-000-km-87-year-old-pope-francis-epic-voyage-6449694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 08:40:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[By embarking aged 87 on the farthest journey of his papacy, Pope Francis is doing something some believed impossible -- and seeking to silence those who doubt his ability to fulfil his role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By embarking aged 87 on the farthest journey of his papacy, Pope Francis is doing something some believed impossible -- and seeking to silence those who doubt his ability to fulfil his role.</p>

<p>The pontiff's 12-day trip to Indonesia, Papua New Guinea, East Timor and Singapore starting next week involves 43 hours of flight time and a distance of 32,000 kilometres (almost 20,000 miles).</p>

<p>It would be something of an odyssey for anyone, but particularly for someone who has been plagued in recent years by health issues, sparking speculation he might step down as head of the Catholic Church.</p>

<p>The trip was originally planned for 2020 but postponed due to the Covid pandemic, and now takes place just three months before his 88th birthday.</p>

<p>Weeks ago few observers thought Francis was capable of such a gruelling voyage, with the corridors of the Vatican buzzing with concerns over his health.</p>

<p>At Easter, the holiest week in the Christian calendar, Francis withdrew from several events, weakened by a lingering flu.</p>

<p>Months earlier, bronchitis caused him to cancel a trip to United Nations climate talks in Dubai in December.</p>

<p>In June 2023, he also underwent hernia surgery that left him hospitalised for 10 days.</p>

<p>Now some are wondering: is it reasonable for the octogenarian to keep up the frantic pace, with 16 speeches and countless meetings and ceremonies scheduled across four countries?</p>

<p>"The pope still believes that we need to push a little further," a senior Vatican diplomat told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He feels capable of making this trip this year. Next year, it will be less certain."&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Thrives on contact</h2>

<p>Former pope Benedict XVI in 2013 became the first since the Middle Ages to step down, citing his declining physical and mental health -- and Francis has left the door open to following suit.</p>

<p>But the Argentine Jesuit has repeatedly stressed that he is not there yet and views travelling as particularly important, a cornerstone of his ministry that prioritises spreading the faith.</p>

<p>With this 45th trip abroad, Francis returns to his love as a pastor among his flock, far from the bureaucracy of the Vatican and close to ordinary people, who seem to give him energy and momentum.</p>

<p>The constraints linked to his health are nevertheless real.</p>

<p>The pope's mobility has visibly declined in recent years. Since 2022, he has relied on a wheelchair for knee pain and recurring sciatica, or nerve pain.</p>

<p>Now unable to climb a flight of stairs, Francis has to use an elevator to board his plane. He also now sits, rather than stands, during the press conferences he holds on the return flight of each voyage.</p>

<p>Although the pope always travels with his personal doctor and a nurse, no "new features" have been ordered for this particular trip, according to a Vatican source.</p>

<p>"His general condition is good, there were no concerns this summer," said the source.</p>

<p>The Vatican has provided no details on any precautions taken for the pope's health, such as possible arrangements made with local hospitals.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During Francis' trip to Africa early in 2023, a fully equipped ambulance followed the pope everywhere, ready to intervene if necessary.</p>

<h2>'Strength of spirit'</h2>

<p>Within the Vatican, the pope's willingness to make the trip has aroused "admiration", a Vatican source told AFP.</p>

<p>At the same time, the source said, it has stirred "concern, and even a certain annoyance at the pope's relentlessness, which puts his health and security services on edge".</p>

<p>For Andrea Ungar, president of the Italian Society of Gerontology and Geriatrics, "this trip demonstrates once again the pope's strength of spirit and shows how, despite age, things can still be done."</p>

<p>"Strong motivation gives incredible energy," Ungar said, adding that the pope was a "great example" for older people to remain active.</p>

<p>"The more you stand still, the more you stay still," he said.</p>

<p>Little chance of standing still for Francis, who will have less than two weeks at home after his long journey before setting off again, this time for a four-day trip to Luxembourg and Belgium starting on September 26.</p>

<p>October will be devoted to the General Assembly of the Synod of Bishops, to determine the future path and priorities of the global Catholic Church.</p>

<p>In December, Francis will kick off the 2025 Jubilee, a year-long pilgrimage event in which some 32 million faithful are expected in Rome.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7uculc6_pope-francis_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-accused-of-deserting-anti-abortion-movement-in-battle-with-kamala-harris-6449649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Accused Of Deserting Anti-Abortion Movement In Battle With Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-accused-of-deserting-anti-abortion-movement-in-battle-with-kamala-harris-6449649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 08:29:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump has been accused of deserting the anti-abortion movement as he seeks to negate attacks by Kamala Harris over one of the most polarizing issues of the US election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has been accused of deserting the anti-abortion movement as he seeks to negate attacks by Kamala Harris over one of the most polarizing issues of the US election.</p>

<p>The Republican nominee brags often about his role in overturning the constitutional right to abortion in the United States.</p>

<p>But -- under relentless fire from Harris and the Democratic Party, and with a majority of Americans supporting access to the procedure -- the former president is now risking the ire of his right-wing base by claiming to promote "reproductive rights."</p>

<p>"Trump's abandonment of Pro-Lifers is complete," said a headline in the conservative National Review last week.</p>

<p>Jeremy Boreing, the co-founder of right-wing website The Daily Wire, attacked the former president as "philosophically malleable."</p>

<p>"His first term was perhaps the most pro-life in actual effect of any administration in our history. That is his legacy -- if he will keep it," Boreing said on X.</p>

<p>The backlash came after Trump took to his Truth Social platform last week to target Democrats, who had for days been attacking him over abortion at their national convention in Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My Administration will be great for women and their reproductive rights," he wrote, hours after Harris accused him and the Republican Party of being "out of their minds" as she used her convention speech to criticize their abortion stance.</p>

<p>Trump's post was "the worst statement Donald Trump has made" since he launched his campaign for president in 2015, Boreing said.</p>

<p>It was "hard to interpret in any other way than as an affirmatively pro-choice statement," wrote Philip Klein, editor of the National Review Online, referring to abortion rights.</p>

<p>"By the common usage of the term, if you support reproductive rights it means you want broader access to abortion."</p>

<h3><strong>'Beyond this Trump moment'</strong></h3>

<p>Conservatives -- along with everyone else -- have long grappled with how to understand Trump's stance on abortion, which has shifted often over the years.</p>

<p>His stacking of the Supreme Court with justices handpicked for their abortion views allowed it to overturn Roe v Wade, the 1973 ruling that had enshrined the procedure as a right.</p>

<p>That seismic move in 2022 made him a hero to many in the anti-abortion movement, which had driven conservative voters to the polls for decades.</p>

<p>"I was able to kill Roe v. Wade," he wrote in a Truth Social post last year. "Without me, the pro Life movement would have just kept losing."</p>

<p>But since then the issue has become an electoral problem for the Republican Party, firing up voters in many local, state and national elections to back Democrats, who have vowed to restore Roe.</p>

<p>Meanwhile the anti-abortion movement is pushing Trump to go further, with some decrying fertility treatments such as in-vitro fertilization (IVF) and others focused on demanding an unpopular national abortion ban.</p>

<p>Trump has appeared to want it both ways, dodging the question of a ban by insisting repeatedly that "everyone" wanted individual states to make their own decisions on abortion, even as he accuses Harris and the Democrats of "executing" babies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In another Truth Social post last week he also called the Republican Party a "leader" on IVF.</p>

<p>He announced Thursday -- without any details on funding -- that as president he would mandate free IVF treatments for any Americans who wanted it.</p>

<p>He also suggested in an interview with NBC that he would vote to overturn Florida's ban on abortions after six weeks' pregnancy, which was "too short." His campaign then quickly walked this back, saying Trump did not actually specify how he'd vote when the referendum takes place in his home state in November.</p>

<p>Trump will "further alienate pro-lifers and divide his own party while doing absolutely zero to win over anybody pro-choice," Klein wrote in the National Review.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That doesn't mean that conservatives will suddenly start voting for Harris, but for many on the right it appears to be time to move on.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The cause is way bigger and younger than Donald Trump," Marjorie Dannenfelser, the president of Susan B. Anthony Pro-Life America, an anti-abortion non-profit, told AFP.</p>

<p>"It will shape the (Republican Party) beyond this Trump moment."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jkb4o3qo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_22_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cindy-rodriguez-singh-fbi-offers-25-000-reward-on-woman-wanted-for-sons-murder-6449262]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[$25,000 Reward For Woman, With Ties To India, Wanted For Son's Murder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cindy-rodriguez-singh-fbi-offers-25-000-reward-on-woman-wanted-for-sons-murder-6449262]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 07:21:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is offering a reward of up to USD 25,000 for information leading to the arrest and conviction of Cindy Rodriguez Singh, wanted for allegedly killing her young son.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is offering a reward of up to USD 25,000 for information leading to the arrest and conviction of Cindy Rodriguez Singh, wanted for allegedly killing her young son.</p>

<p>Notably, Rodriguez Singh has ties to India and Mexico. She is wanted for allegedly killing her 6-year-old son, who hasn't been seen alive since October 2022.</p>

<p>At the request of the Texas Department of Family and Protective Services, Everman Police Department officers conducted a welfare check on behalf of the boy on March 20, 2023.</p>

<p>During the welfare check interview, Rodriguez Singh lied to officers when she explained that the boy was living with his biological father in Mexico, and had been there since November 2022, according to the official website of the FBI.</p>

<p>On March 22, 2023, Rodriguez Singh, her husband, and six other juvenile children boarded an international flight bound for India. It was determined that the missing child was not present, and did not board the flight.</p>

<p>On October 31, 2023, Cindy Rodriguez Singh was charged with capital murder in District Court of Tarrant County, Fort Worth, Texas. On November 2, 2023, a federal arrest warrant was issued for Rodriguez Singh in the United States District Court, Northern District of Texas, Fort Worth, Texas, after she was charged with Unlawful Flight to Avoid Prosecution.</p>

<p>In making the announcement, Dallas FBI Special Agent in Charge Chad Yarbrough asked the media and public to help locate Rodriguez Singh.</p>

<p>"Cindy Rodriguez Singh is wanted for allegedly murdering her own young son," Yarbrough said. "I am confident that the combination of publicity, significant reward offering, and the team of experienced investigators assembled by the FBI Fort Worth Resident Agency violent crime squad, Everman Police Department, Tarrant County District Attorney's Office and Texas DPS-Texas Rangers will lead to her arrest."</p>

<p>The FBI on its official website further said that Rodriguez Singh's last confirmed sighting was on March 22, 2023, as she, her husband, and six juvenile children, boarded an international flight to India. She was born in Dallas, Texas, in 1985 and is 39 years old.</p>

<p>The fugitive is between 5 feet, 1 inch and 5 feet, 3 inches tall; 120- 140 pounds; has a medium complexion and tattoos on her back, both legs, right arm, right hand, and right calf. She has brown eyes and brown hair.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dn2r0j4o_cindy-rodriguez-singh-fbi_625x300_30_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cindy Rodriguez told the officers that the boy was living with his biological father in Mexico.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-kamala-harris-was-doing-when-joe-biden-quit-us-presidential-race-6449446]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Just Had Pancakes": Kamala Harris On Joe Biden's Call That Made History]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-kamala-harris-was-doing-when-joe-biden-quit-us-presidential-race-6449446]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 07:21:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris on Friday described for the first time US President Joe Biden's phone call informing her he was planning to quit the race to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris on Friday described for the first time US President Joe Biden's phone call informing her he was planning to quit the race to the White House. Speaking to CNN, Ms Harris, who has replaced Mr Biden as the Democratic presidential candidate, said she was at home making pancakes and bacon for her nieces when her phone rang.</p>

<p>"My family was staying with us, and including my baby nieces, and we had just had pancakes," she recalled in an interview with CNN about the Sunday afternoon call in July.</p>

<p>Ms Harris and the children were chatting -- "Auntie, can I have more bacon?' 'Yes, I'll make you more bacon'" -- she said.</p>

<p>"And the phone rang, and it was Joe Biden," she added.</p>

<p>"It was Joe Biden, and he told me what he had decided to do. And I asked him, 'Are you sure?' And he said, 'Yes'."</p>

<p>"My first thought was not about me, to be honest with you. My first thought was about him," Ms Harris said in her first one-on-one interview with a major news network since Joe Biden ended his reelection campaign last month and endorsed her.</p>

<p>Mr Biden, 81, ended his second-term bid on July 21 after his disastrous June 27 debate performance against his Republican rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-ready-to-turn-the-page-on-donald-trump-says-kamala-harris-6449417" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> triggered a slow-burning Democrat revolt against him.</p>

<p>"He (Biden) has the intelligence, the commitment, and the judgment and disposition that I think the American people rightly deserve in their president," Ms Harris said in her joint CNN sit-down with her running mate Tim Walz.</p>

<p>She also said she is running for president because she believes that she is the "best person to do this job at this moment for all Americans, regardless of race and gender."</p>

<p>The US Vice President also said that Americans were ready to "turn the page" on divisions she blamed on her rival Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"Sadly in the last decade, we have had in the former president someone who has really been pushing an agenda and an environment that is about diminishing the character and the strength of who we are as Americans, really dividing our nation," the Democrat said.</p>

<p>"And I think people are ready to turn the page on that," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6o5s14u8_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden ended his second-term bid on July 21 and endorsed Kamala Harris (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-ready-to-turn-the-page-on-donald-trump-says-kamala-harris-6449417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US "Ready To Turn The Page" On Donald Trump, Says Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/americans-ready-to-turn-the-page-on-donald-trump-says-kamala-harris-6449417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 07:13:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris said in her first interview of her presidential campaign Thursday that Americans were ready to "turn the page" on divisions she blamed on her rival Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris declared Thursday that Americans are ready to turn the page on Donald Trump and chart a new path for the country, in her first major interview since her dramatic entry into November's presidential election.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, aimed to stake out a centrist position on CNN, insisting that she will be tough on illegal immigration and support controversial oil and gas fracking -- but not abandon her longtime liberal values.</p>

<p>The first female and Black and South Asian vice president described Trump as "pushing an agenda and an environment that is about diminishing the character and the strength of who we are as Americans, really dividing our nation."</p>

<p>"I think people are ready to turn the page on that," she said. "People are ready for a new way forward."</p>

<p>The Democrat also said that she would name a Republican to her cabinet if she wins November's election, in her joint CNN sit-down with her running mate Tim Walz.</p>

<p>Trump meanwhile branded Harris the "greatest flip-flopper" as he addressed a rally in the swing state of Michigan, before mocking her appearance in the interview.</p>

<p>"She didn't look like a leader to me," the Republican said.</p>

<p>Harris rejected criticism that she has shifted positions on politically sensitive issues including fracking, which she once opposed but now supports, and illegal migration over the Mexican border, where she has taken a harder line.</p>

<p>"As president I will not ban fracking," she said -- clearly aiming to settle the controversy in fossil-fuel-rich Pennsylvania, one of the vital battleground states in what's expected to be a tight election.</p>

<p>Addressing criticism that she had been too soft on immigration -- a core part of Trump's message -- Harris said that as president she would sign tough legislation.</p>

<p>Harris is reaching for centrist voters worried by immigration and fuel costs. But in a nod to her left-leaning supporters, she insisted that she had not fundamentally shifted.</p>

<p>"My values have not changed," Harris said.</p>

<p>On another hot-button topic on the US political landscape, Harris urged a ceasefire in Gaza, but told CNN that she would not change President Joe Biden's policies for key US ally Israel, including deliveries of weaponry.</p>

<h2><strong>Honeymoon period?</strong></h2>

<p>Republicans had criticized Harris for not giving any interviews since Biden abruptly dropped out of the White House race nearly six weeks ago, following mounting concerns over his health and age at 81.</p>

<p>Harris has enjoyed a honeymoon period with surging polls and record fundraising, but has also faced scrutiny for keeping many of her policies vague as she pulls her campaign together.</p>

<p>Harris gave the interview while on a campaign bus tour of Georgia, one of the seven battleground states that are expected to decide the November 5 election.</p>

<p>A number of polls out Thursday showed Harris ahead of Trump, if only marginally, with several of them finding increased support for Harris in battleground states.</p>

<p>A Bloomberg/Morning Consult poll found Harris leading in six out of the seven swing states while a Fox poll also showed increasing support in the battlegrounds.</p>

<p>At a rally in Savannah at the end of the two-day swing in Georgia, which Democrats flipped from Trump in 2020, she admitted it was "going to be a tight race until the very end."</p>

<p>Trump has himself been hitting the campaign trail hard in recent days, after a period where the 78-year-old former president appeared to struggle to find his footing against a new, younger, female candidate.</p>

<p>Speaking at an event in Potterville, Michigan on Thursday, Trump targeted Harris on her immigration policy shifts: "Now she's saying, 'Oh we want to build a strong border."</p>

<p>"Where has she been for three and a half years?"</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are set to face off in their pivotal first debate on September 10 in Philadelphia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lvclrp8k_kamala-harris_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-says-chatgpts-weekly-users-have-grown-to-200-million-6449414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Says ChatGPT's Weekly Users Have Grown To 200 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-says-chatgpts-weekly-users-have-grown-to-200-million-6449414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 07:11:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI startup OpenAI said on Thursday its chatbot ChatGPT now has more than 200 million weekly active users, double the number it had in the last fall season.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AI startup OpenAI said on Thursday its chatbot ChatGPT now has more than 200 million weekly active users, double the number it had in the last fall season.</p>

<p>ChatGPT, launched in 2022, can generate human-like responses based on user prompts and had 100 million weekly active users, OpenAI CEO Sam Altman had said in November.</p>

<p>OpenAI said 92% of Fortune 500 companies are using its products and the use of its automated Application Programming Interface, or API, which allows software programs to talk to each other, has doubled since the launch of ChatGPT-4o mini in July.</p>

<p>GPT-4o mini is a cost-efficient small AI model, aimed at making its technology more affordable and less energy-intensive, allowing the startup to target a broader pool of customers.</p>

<p>ChatGPT has driven AI's popularity and fueled a meteoric rise in the valuation of the San Francisco-based OpenAI.</p>

<p>Separately, AI startups OpenAI and Anthropic signed deals with the U.S. government for research, testing and evaluation of their artificial intelligence models, the U.S. Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute said earlier in the day.</p>

<p>Media reports said Apple and Nvidia are in talks to invest in OpenAI as part of a new fundraising round that would value the ChatGPT maker above $100 billion.</p>

<p>OpenAI-backer Microsoft is also expected to invest in the firm, according to the reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ke9eh2_openai-chatgpt_625x300_16_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI said 92% of Fortune 500 companies are using its products.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-video-games-turned-nvidia-into-a-tech-giant-6449326]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Video Games Turned Nvidia Into A Tech Giant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-video-games-turned-nvidia-into-a-tech-giant-6449326]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 06:44:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Until quite recently, Nvidia wasn't much of a household name outside of Silicon Valley or Wall Street.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Until quite recently, Nvidia wasn't much of a household name outside of Silicon Valley or Wall Street. But times clearly have changed for the Santa Clara, California-based tech company with the easily mispronounced moniker. Across a growing range of technologies and gadgets, tiny chips made by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/nations-building-their-own-ai-models-add-to-nvidias-growing-chip-demand-6442955">Nvidia play an outsized</a> role in our lives. And thanks to the explosion of artificial intelligence, perhaps our future as well.</p>

<p>But before <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-chief-says-new-blackwell-chip-will-have-lots-and-lots-of-supply-6442491">Nvidia became the world's most valuable</a> chipmaker, the $3 trillion company had a more humble calling: making graphics cards for video game consoles. In the Bloomberg Originals mini-documentary How Nvidia Changed the Game, we show how a gargantuan technology company that's held investors in its thrall got so big seemingly overnight.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nvidia didn't have a great day on Wednesday (or today for that matter)-not because its $32.5 billion revenue projection for the third quarter was somehow terrible, but rather because it didn't blow the doors off of analyst projections. However, none of the Wall Street handwringing that's followed diminishes the story of how the company managed to succeed thanks to an incredible bit of long-term planning.</p>

<p>Today, Nvidia dominates the graphics industry. But when it started back in the 1990s, it was just one of many fledgling tech companies with similar ideas. Chief Executive Officer Jensen Huang chose to focus on an area where there was a lot of money to be made: video games. While using the cash that tumbled in to fund Nvidia's research and development, he leveraged the company's accelerating chip technology to branch out to a wider range of products and sectors.</p>

<p>In How Nvidia Changed the Game, Bloomberg Originals shows how this strategy eventually placed Nvidia at the heart of dual revolutions in cryptocurrency and-most importantly-artificial intelligence.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ik7ra1ng_nvidia-reuters_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Today, Nvidia dominates the graphics industry.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-heatwave-over-60-million-americans-under-alert-as-heatwave-hits-us-6449113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 60 Million Americans Under Alert As Heatwave Hits US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-heatwave-over-60-million-americans-under-alert-as-heatwave-hits-us-6449113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 06:41:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A heat wave brought record-high temperatures to US Midwest states this week, with more than 60 million people included in alerts over the conditions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A heat wave brought record-high temperatures to US Midwest states this week, with more than 60 million people included in alerts over the conditions.</p>

<p>A late-season high-pressure system over cities in the Midwest regions such as Chicago, Des Moines and Topeka has left them experiencing rare "extreme heat" for a long period of time, Xinhua news agency reported, citing the US National Weather Service (NWS).</p>

<p>The NWS warned the public of the combined dangers of heat and humidity associated with heat waves.</p>

<p>US Midwest states have set up several public cooling centres in preparation for the dangerous heat.</p>

<p>Extreme heat together with humidity is one of the leading weather-related killers in the United States. Approximately 1,220 people in the country are killed by extreme heat every year, according to the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/s22fr4gg_us-heatwave-generic-reuters_625x300_20_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Midwest states have set up several public cooling centres in preparation for the dangerous heat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-a-rally-in-michigan-donald-trump-pledges-free-ivf-for-all-in-second-term-6449085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At A Rally In Michigan, Trump Pledges Free IVF For All In Second Term]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-a-rally-in-michigan-donald-trump-pledges-free-ivf-for-all-in-second-term-6449085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 05:30:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said Thursday he would have the government or insurance companies cover the cost of in-vitro fertilization for "all Americans who need it" in a second term -- although he declined to say how he would pay for it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Thursday he would have the government or insurance companies cover the cost of in-vitro fertilization for "all Americans who need it" in a second term -- although he declined to say how he would pay for it.</p>

<p>Reproductive rights have been a major vulnerablity for the Republican White House nominee ever since the Supreme Court gutted federal protections for abortion access in 2022.</p>

<p>Trump's weakness was further exacerbated after an Alabama court ruled in February that frozen embryos created via IVF should be considered children.</p>

<p>Trump said he supported IVF after several clinics paused their care following the Alabama decision.</p>

<p>"I'm announcing today in a major statement that, under the Trump administration, your government will pay for -- or your insurance company will be mandated to pay for -- all costs associated with IVF treatment," he told a rally in Potterville, Michigan.</p>

<p>He offered no detail on how his proposal would work, including how it would be funded, but when the announcement was previewed in an interview with NBC ahead of the event, Trump said one option would be to have insurance companies pay "under a mandate."</p>

<p>Experts say the 2022 US Supreme Court ruling effectively granted states the final say on questions of personhood, paving the way for wide-reaching impacts on other areas of reproductive health, including IVF.</p>

<p>Few Americans have insurance plans that cover fertility treatments in any case, with costs of $20,000 or more for a single, 18-month round of IVF treatment too expensive for many.</p>

<p>The ex-president added that under a second Trump term, new parents would be able to deduct "major newborn expenses" from their tax bill, proclaiming that "we're pro-family."</p>

<p>Although his support for IVF has been consistent since the February ruling, Trump claimed numerous ideological positions on abortion before settling on his current view that the legalities around the procedure should be up to the states.</p>

<p>He told NBC News in 1999 he was "very pro-choice" before announcing he was "pro-life" in 2011 and that women who seek abortions should get "some form of punishment" in 2016.</p>

<p>Trump has taken credit for installing the Supreme Court justices who struck down federal abortion rights, and signaled Thursday how he may vote in a Florida referendum this fall which seeks to reverse his home state's six-week ban.</p>

<p>"I want more than six weeks," he told the Daily Mail. "I think six weeks is a mistake. And I'll be expressing that soon, but I want more than six weeks."</p>

<p>Trump and his election rival, Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris, are campaigning in swing states this week as they embark on the most intense phase of the campaign.</p>

<p>Harris, rallying in Savannah, Georgia, told supporters Trump would sign a national abortion ban into law if he won.</p>

<p>"Ours is a fight for the future. And it is a fight for freedom. Like the freedom of a woman to make decisions about her own body, and not have her government tell her what to do," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/kr9u49fk_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_20_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said he supported IVF after several clinics paused their care following the Alabama decision.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/powerful-typhoon-shanshan-slams-japan-multiple-deaths-reported-6449023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Powerful Typhoon Shanshan Slams Japan, Multiple Deaths Reported]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/powerful-typhoon-shanshan-slams-japan-multiple-deaths-reported-6449023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 05:08:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One of Japan's strongest typhoons in decades dumped torrential rain across southern regions on Thursday, leaving at least five people dead and injuring dozens, local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of Japan's strongest typhoons in decades dumped torrential rain across southern regions on Thursday, leaving at least five people dead and injuring dozens, local media reported, as authorities warned millions to seek higher ground due to possible flooding and landslides.</p>

<p>Typhoon Shanshan packed gusts of up to 252 kilometres (157 miles) per hour as it smashed into Japan's main southern island of Kyushu early Thursday, making it the most powerful storm this year and one of the strongest at landfall since 1960.</p>

<p>The storm then weakened, with maximum gusts of 162 kph at 5:00 pm (0800 GMT), the weather office said, but it was still dumping heavy rain across Kyushu and beyond as it moved slowly towards the main island of Honshu.</p>

<p>Five people have been found dead in the storm, Jiji Press reported, including a man whose two-story home collapsed in Tokushima Prefecture.</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) warned that "the risk of a disaster due to heavy rain can rapidly escalate in western Japan as Friday approaches".</p>

<p>Even before Shanshan hit, heavy precipitation led to three members of the same family being killed in a landslide late Tuesday in Aichi prefecture around 1,000 kilometres (600 miles) from Kyushu.</p>

<p>Authorities issued their highest alert in several areas of the country, with more than five million people advised to evacuate, although it was unclear how many did.</p>

<p>Kunisaki city in the Oita region of Kyushu warned inhabitants to "evacuate to a safe place or higher place such as the second floor of your house" because of the risk of flooding.</p>

<p>At least 80 people were injured across Kyushu, the JMA said.</p>

<p>Rains turned rivers into raging torrents while winds smashed windows and blew tiles off roofs. TV images showed flooded roads and power lines being repaired.</p>

<p>The coastal city of Miyazaki, littered with debris from nearly 200 damaged buildings, reported 25 injuries -- including some from a tornado.</p>

<p>Some parts of Miyazaki prefecture saw record rains for August, with the town of Misato recording a staggering 791.5 millimetres (31 inches) in 48 hours, the JMA said.</p>

<p>Worried student Aoi Nishimoto, 18, said he had called his family in Miyazaki to see if they were safe.</p>

<p>"Our home is fine, but there was a tornado in Miyazaki and power went out in some places," he told AFP in Kyushu's main city of Fukuoka.</p>

<p>"This year, I am away from my parents' home for the first time. So it's a bit scary being all alone," fellow student Rio Ohtsuru, 19, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Maybe I will look for a flashlight in case of a power outage," she said.</p>

<p>Kyushu's utility operator said 187,010 houses were without power elsewhere on the island.</p>

<p>- Climate change -</p>

<p>Shanshan comes in the wake of Typhoon Ampil, which dumped heavy rain that disrupted hundreds of flights and trains this month but caused only minor injuries and damage.</p>

<p>Typhoons in the region have been forming closer to coastlines, intensifying more rapidly and lasting longer over land due to climate change, according to a study released last month.</p>

<p>Another released by World Weather Attribution (WWA) on Thursday said that climate change turbocharged Typhoon Gaemi, which killed dozens of people across the Philippines, Taiwan and China this year.</p>

<p>In the city of Usa, retiree Fukashi Oishi looked forlornly at an old tree opposite his house that was already mature when he was a child but had snapped and fallen on the road.</p>

<p>"Oh, it's so sad," he told AFP.</p>

<p>- Toyota production halt -</p>

<p>Auto giant Toyota suspended production at all 14 of its factories in Japan.</p>

<p>Nissan and Honda also halted operations at their Kyushu plants, as did chipmakers including Tokyo Electron, reports said.</p>

<p>Kyushu is a hub for the semiconductor industry, with chip giant Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company opening a plant there in February.</p>

<p>Japan Airlines and ANA cancelled more than 1,000 domestic flights and four international flights for Thursday and Friday, affecting more than 44,000 passengers.</p>

<p>Rail operators suspended most Shinkansen bullet trains between Kyushu's Hakata and Tokyo, and said services would be disrupted elsewhere on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g2i6ksg8_japan-typhoon_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japana Typhoon: At least 80 people were injured across Kyushu, the weather office said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fight-is-for-americas-future-kamala-harris-at-georgia-rally-6448997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Fight Is For America's Future": Kamala Harris At Georgia Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fight-is-for-americas-future-kamala-harris-at-georgia-rally-6448997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:51:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential nominee and Vice President Kamala Harris on Thursday emphasised that the current presidential fight is for the future of the United States and asserted that the future is always worth fighting for.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential nominee and Vice President Kamala Harris on Thursday emphasised that the current presidential fight is for the future of the United States and asserted that the future is always worth fighting for.</p>

<p>The remarks by Harris came while she addressed a rally in Georgia. Harris during the rally said that they are running as the underdog in the upcoming presidential elections in the country and expressed confidence that she will secure victory in the elections.</p>

<p>"68 days to go... We are here to speak the truth and one of the things that we know is that we are running as the underdog. And we have some hard work ahead of us. But we like hard work. Hard work is good work. And with your help, we are going to win this November," Harris said.</p>

<p>She further said that during her entire career, she has always stood up for people. She said, "I am no stranger to tough fights... I was a courtroom Prosecutor. So every day in the courtroom, I stood proudly before a judge and I spoke five words--Kamala Harris For The People. My entire career, I only had one client--the people. I stood for women and children against predators who used to abuse them... and for seniors facing abuse. I would tell you that those fights were not easy and neither were the elections that put me in those offices."</p>

<p>She further said, "But we never gave up because the future is always worth fighting for. And that is the fight we are in right now. A fight for America's future. We fight for the future with affordable childcare, paid leave and affordable healthcare."</p>

<p>Earlier, Harris said that she intends to appoint a Republican to her cabinet if she wins the upcoming presidential elections, CNN reported.</p>

<p>The remarks by the Vice President came in a joint interview with Walz on CNN.</p>

<p>Harris pledged to serve as a president for all Americans. In the interview, she expressed her willingness to appoint a Republican to her Cabinet if elected. However, she didn't specify a particular individual.</p>

<p>"I've got 68 days to go with this election, so I'm not putting the cart before the horse," she said. "But I would, I think. I think it's really important. I have spent my career inviting diversity of opinion. I think it's important to have people at the table when some of the most important decisions are being made that have different views, different experiences. And I think it would be to the benefit of the American public to have a member of my Cabinet who was a Republican," according to CNN.</p>

<p>Harris was nominated as the Democratic nominee after President Joe Biden quit the presidential race amid mounting concerns over his age, particularly after his poor show in the debate with Donald Trump in June.</p>

<p>If elected president, the 59-year-old Harris would become the first woman in history to become the US president. The vice president is only the second woman ever nominated for the presidency by a major political party.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ng5483kg_kamala-harris_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During election rally, Kamala Harris expressed confidence that she will secure victory in the elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lawsuit-claiming-elon-musk-tesla-rigged-dogecoin-dismissed-6448942]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lawsuit Claiming Elon Musk, Tesla Rigged Dogecoin Dismissed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lawsuit-claiming-elon-musk-tesla-rigged-dogecoin-dismissed-6448942]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 04:39:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk and his electric vehicle company Tesla won the dismissal of a federal lawsuit accusing them of defrauding investors by hyping the cryptocurrency dogecoin and conducting insider trading, causing billions of dollars of losses.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk and his electric vehicle company Tesla won the dismissal of a federal lawsuit accusing them of defrauding investors by hyping the cryptocurrency dogecoin and conducting insider trading, causing billions of dollars of losses.</p>

<p>The decision was issued on Thursday night by U.S. District Judge Alvin Hellerstein in Manhattan.</p>

<p>Investors accused Musk of using Twitter posts, a 2021 appearance on NBC's "Saturday Night Live" and other publicity stunts to trade profitably at their expense through several dogecoin wallets that he or Tesla controlled.</p>

<p>According to the investors, Musk deliberately drove up dogecoin's price more than 36,000% over two years and then let it crash, with he and Tesla often timing trades to Musk's public statements and activities concerning dogecoin.</p>

<p>Investors said this included when Musk sold dogecoin in April 2023 after he replaced the blue bird logo of Twitter, now known as X, with dogecoin's Shiba Inu dog logo, causing dogecoin's price to rise 30%.</p>

<p>In seeking a dismissal, Musk's lawyers said the plaintiffs still had no case despite filing five versions of their lawsuit, which originally sought $258 billion, over two years.</p>

<p>The lawyers said there was nothing wrong with Musk's "innocuous and often silly tweets" about dogecoin, and no proof either that Musk owned two wallets where suspicious trading was conducted, or that he or Tesla ever sold dogecoin.</p>

<p>On "Saturday Night Live," Musk called dogecoin a "hustle" while playing a fictitious financial expert on a segment of "Weekend Update."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/puugc1eg_elon-musk_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-war-explained-how-ai-is-leading-israels-bombing-campaign-in-gaza-6448734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How AI Is Leading Israel's Bombing Campaign In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-war-explained-how-ai-is-leading-israels-bombing-campaign-in-gaza-6448734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:23:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military campaign in Gaza - which started after the deadly October 7 last year in which over 1,100 people were brutally killed - has entered its 10th month and over 40,000 people have died.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military campaign in Gaza - which started after the deadly October 7 last year in which over 1,100 people were brutally killed - has entered its 10th month and over 40,000 people have died.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As violence rages in the Gaza Strip, Israel has opened a different front in the West Bank, another Palestinian territory. The large-scale military operation in the West Bank has entered its second day and at least 16 people have died.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As Israel's "war" drags on for 10 months, the focus is back on Israel's AI tools that have been extensively used in its bombing campaign in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>'Gospel', 'Alchemist', 'The Death of Wisdom' and 'Lavender' are not titles of a novel but names of the Artificial Intelligence (AI) tools that have been used to process vast amounts of data, identify suspects who have links with Hamas and the Palestinian Islamic Jihad and to strike them.</p>

<p>A detailed investigation by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.972mag.com/lavender-ai-israeli-army-gaza/" rel="no index, no follow">+972 Magazine and Local Call</a> reveals some disturbing details from Israel's bombing campaign, especially how the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) fully relied on a tool for its bombing missions.</p>

<p><strong>'Lavender' and its use case</strong></p>

<p>Lavender, developed by Israel's elite intelligence division, Unit 8200, operates as an AI-powered database designed to identify potential targets linked to Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad (PIJ). Lavender uses machine learning algorithms and processes vast amounts of data to pinpoint individuals deemed "junior" militants within these armed groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lavender initially identified as many as 37,000 Palestinian men associated with Hamas or PIJ. The usage of AI to identify targets marks a significant change in how the Israeli intelligence apparatus, Mossad and Shin Bet, function - relying on more labour-intensive human decision-making.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/o4og57oo_deir-elbalah-gaza-israel-strike_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Soldiers often made decisions in as little as 20 seconds to determine whether to bomb these identified targets based on Lavender's information, primarily to ascertain the gender of the target. Human soldiers frequently followed the machine's information unquestioningly, despite the AI program's error margin of up to 10 per cent, meaning it could be incorrect up to 10 per cent of the time.</p>

<p>According to the report, the program often targeted individuals with minimal or no affiliation with Hamas.</p>

<p><strong>Gospel - Israel's Another AI Arm</strong></p>

<p>Systems such as "Gospel" are being used to allow automatic tools to produce targets at a fast pace, and works by improving accurate and high-quality intelligence material according to the requirement," the IDF said.<br />
"With the help of artificial intelligence, and through the rapid and automatic extraction of updated intelligence - it produces a recommendation for the researcher, with the goal being that there will be a complete match between the machine's recommendation and the identification performed by a person," the IDF added.</p>

<p>The AI platforms crunch data to select targets for air strikes. Ensuing raids can then be rapidly assembled with another artificial intelligence model called Fire Factory,<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-07-16/israel-using-ai-systems-to-plan-deadly-military-operations" rel="no index, no follow"> Bloomberg reported</a>. Fire Factory calculates munition loads, prioritizes and assigns thousands of targets to aircraft and drones, and proposes a schedule, the report added.</p>

<p>The report by +972 Magazine mentions the book 'The Human-Machine Team: How to Create Synergy Between Human and Artificial Intelligence That Will Revolutionize Our World'. The author 'Brigadier General YS', who is reportedly the commander of the 8200 Intelligence Unit of Israel, makes a case for the use of AI in "deep defence" and gives scenarios that could threaten Israel in the future.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the chapter "Deep Defense:" New Potentials, the author says "Deep defence is the ability of national establishments to use The Human-Machine Team concept to address security challenges to expose issues in new ways that were heretofore impossible."</p>

<p>The Human-Machine Team should have the ability to identify tens of thousands of targets before the battle begins and thousands of targets should be identified every day. The author makes a case where he explains why it is important to create such tools so that the military can strike at the right targets at the right time with less collateral damage.</p>

<p><strong>What About AI in the Russia-Ukraine War?</strong></p>

<p>AI begets AI. The use of automated tools like unmanned FPV drones, and robots has reduced the human-risk factor for warring nations but has increased the dependency on technology, which seems like a win-win situation for a nation but the ethical and legal concerns of using AI are always followed by the benefits of the technology.</p>

<p>The Russia-Ukraine war is a testing lab for future tools for fighting in combat. The concept of drone attacks has proliferated to different conflicts in different regions, especially non-state actors like Houthi rebels and Hezbollah fighting Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The deployment of automated drones does not simply define the use of AI in conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/3un9tu5g_ukraine-drone_625x300_10_January_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>AI is primarily used to analyze geospatial intelligence by processing satellite images and decoding open-source intelligence like videos, and photos available online. Surveillance drone footage, on-ground human intelligence (HUMINT), satellite images, and open-source data are all combined and processed by AI tools to deliver an outcome that is used to conduct missions. This represents the use of data analytics on the battlefield.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a report by National Defense magazine, Ukraine reportedly used Clearview AI, a software tool from a US-based firm, for facial recognition to identify dead soldiers and Russian assailants and combat misinformation. US firms like Primer have deployed tools to decode Russian encrypted messages delivered through radio.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ukraine is working on developing AI-enabled drones to counter radio jamming. Cheap FPV drones, widely used for several months, have witnessed a drop in their hits due to the jamming of radio signals, a form of Electronic Warfare which Russians are masters of.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are already working with the concept that soon, there will be no connection on the front line" between pilot and UAV, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/artificial-intelligence/ukraine-rushes-create-ai-enabled-war-drones-2024-07-18/#:~:text=AI%20is%20already%20being%20used,hundreds%20of%20kilometres%20inside%20Russia." rel="no index, no follow">Reuters reported</a>, quoting Max Makarchuk, the AI lead for Brave1, a defence tech accelerator set up by the Ukrainian government.</p>

<p>Radio jamming blocks the operator's contact with the munition (a drone) by forming a protective invisible layer around the target, therefore resulting in damage to the drone. Automating the final part of the drone's flight can enable success.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/commentary/struggling-not-crumbling-russian-defence-ai-time-war" rel="no follow, no index">Russia is focusing on developing AI</a> systems to counter the West and fight Ukraine on the battlefield. If numbers are compared then Russia is way ahead of Ukraine in terms of military prowess but the Red Army has suffered huge losses on the battlefield.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Areas like increasing command, control and communication with AI-enabled decision-making, developing smarter weapons, which it calls "intellectualization of weapons", and developing more unmanned aerial/ground vehicles and AI-enabled guidance systems for missiles, are in Moscow's focus.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The maker of the Russian Kamikaze drone KUB-LA, ZALA Aero Group, claims it is capable of selecting and engaging targets using AI. The Lancet-3 loitering munition is highly autonomous and the use of sensors enables it to locate and destroy a target without human guidance, even being capable of returning to the operator if a target has not been found.</p>

<p>In May, a Russian <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ria.ru/20230524/spetsoperatsiya-1873760329.html" rel="no index, no follow">S-350 Vityaz</a>, surface-to-air-missile reportedly shot down an aircraft in autonomous mode, which was claimed as the first AI-enable missile kill. The system detected, tracked and destroyed a Ukrainian air target without human assistance. The claim remains contested.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Heavy investment on both sides of the border reaffirms the central role of AI in war and how future wars could be co-commanded by technology and a human.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mq9rsdc_gaza-august-2024-afp-_625x300_10_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Heavy investment on both sides of the border reaffirms the central role of AI in war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-says-chatgpts-weekly-users-have-grown-to-200-million-6448705]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ChatGPT's Weekly Users Have Grown To 200 Million, Says OpenAI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-says-chatgpts-weekly-users-have-grown-to-200-million-6448705]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 03:11:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI startup OpenAI said on Thursday its chatbot ChatGPT now has more than 200 million weekly active users, double the number it had in the last fall season.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>AI startup OpenAI said on Thursday its chatbot ChatGPT now has more than 200 million weekly active users, double the number it had in the last fall season.</p>

<p>ChatGPT, launched in 2022, can generate human-like responses based on user prompts and had 100 million weekly active users, OpenAI CEO Sam Altman had said in November.</p>

<p>OpenAI said 92% of Fortune 500 companies are using its products and the use of its automated Application Programming Interface, or API, which allows software programs to talk to each other, has doubled since the launch of ChatGPT-4o mini in July.</p>

<p>GPT-4o mini is a cost-efficient small AI model, aimed at making its technology more affordable and less energy-intensive, allowing the startup to target a broader pool of customers.</p>

<p>ChatGPT has driven AI's popularity and fueled a meteoric rise in the valuation of the San Francisco-based OpenAI.</p>

<p>Separately, AI startups OpenAI and Anthropic signed deals with the U.S. government for research, testing and evaluation of their artificial intelligence models, the U.S. Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute said earlier in the day.</p>

<p>Media reports said Apple and Nvidia are in talks to invest in OpenAI as part of a new fundraising round that would value the ChatGPT maker above $100 billion.</p>

<p>OpenAI-backer Microsoft is also expected to invest in the firm, according to the reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/msft5rq8_chatgpt_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-emmanuel-macron-says-he-was-not-aware-of-telegram-chief-pavel-durovs-arrival-in-france-6448507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Macron Says He Was Not Aware Of Telegram Chief Durov's Arrival In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-president-emmanuel-macron-says-he-was-not-aware-of-telegram-chief-pavel-durovs-arrival-in-france-6448507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 02:09:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French President Emmanuel Macron was not aware of Telegram owner Pavel Durov's arrival in France on Saturday and had not been scheduled to meet him, he told a news conference on Thursday during a two-day visit in Serbia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French President Emmanuel Macron was not aware of Telegram owner Pavel Durov's arrival in France on Saturday and had not been scheduled to meet him, he told a news conference on Thursday during a two-day visit in Serbia.</p>

<p>"I was absolutely unaware of Mr Durov's arrival in France, and that is quite normal because I'm not aware of the comings and goings of citizens from all over the world, whether they have French citizenship or not," Macron said.</p>

<p>Durov was arrested by French police after his jet landed at an airport near Paris. On Wednesday, a French judge put Durov, who has French and UAE citizenship, under formal investigation for suspected complicity in running an online platform that allows illicit transactions, child sex abuse images, drug trafficking and fraud.</p>

<p>Macron also defended France's decision in 2021 to give Durov French citizenship under a rare procedure for high-profile individuals.</p>

<p>"It's part of a strategy to allow women and men, whether artists, athletes or entrepreneurs, when they make the effort to learn the French language and that they develop wealth, innovation ... to be given French nationality," Macron said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2c802dbc_macron-nato-summit_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I was absolutely unaware of Mr Durov's arrival in France," Emmanuel Macron said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/social-media-platform-x-down-for-thousands-of-users-report-6448458]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Social Media Platform X Down For Thousands Of Users: Reportc]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/social-media-platform-x-down-for-thousands-of-users-report-6448458]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 30 Aug 2024 01:55:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media platform X suffered outages on Thursday afternoon, according to outage tracking website Downdetector.com.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media platform X suffered outages on Thursday afternoon, according to outage tracking site Downdetector.com.</p>

<p>The website, which tracks outages by collating status reports from several sources including users, showed more than 37,000 reports of outages in the U.S. as of 3:54 pm ET (7:54 pm GMT)</p>

<p>The platform was impacted by an outage earlier in April.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/4itvtgpo_elon-musk-x-560_625x300_02_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The platform was impacted by an outage earlier in April.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>