<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 19:41:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-says-wont-be-intimidated-by-putins-warning-to-west-7081059]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sweden Says Won't Be Intimidated By Putin's Warning To West]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sweden-says-wont-be-intimidated-by-putins-warning-to-west-7081059]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 19:35:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said Friday after President Vladimir Putin hinted at strikes on Western countries supplying weapons to Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said Friday after President Vladimir Putin hinted at strikes on Western countries supplying weapons to Ukraine.</p>

<p>The Swedish minister's remarks came as he announced "substantial funding" to Ukraine for the procurement of long-range missiles and drones.</p>

<p>"The Russian escalation and provocation that we've been noticing recently is an attempt to scare us from supporting Ukraine, and that will fail. This will not happen," Jonson told reporters at a joint press conference in Stockholm with his Ukrainian counterpart Rustem Umerov.</p>

<p>"Supporting Ukraine is both the right thing to do and it's a smart thing to do, and it's an investment into our own security, because (Ukraine's) security is also our security," he said.</p>

<p>"Ukraine has the full right, in accordance with international law, to defend itself inside and outside of its territory, and we're glad if we can further develop both your capability to produce long-range missiles and also long-range strike drones," Jonson told Umerov.</p>

<p>Putin said Thursday that the conflict in Ukraine had characteristics of a "global" war, criticising Ukraine's allies for granting permission for Kyiv to use Western-supplied weapons to strike targets on Russian territory.</p>

<p>In recent days Ukraine has fired US and UK-supplied missiles at Russian territory for the first time, escalating already sky-high tensions in the nearly three-year-long conflict.</p>

<p>"We consider ourselves entitled to use our weapons against the military facilities of those countries that allow their weapons to be used against our facilities," Putin said.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7465u5_swedens-defence-minister-pal-jonson-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sweden will not be intimidated by Russia's provocations, Defence Minister Pal Jonson said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-notre-dame-de-paris-rises-from-the-ashes-set-to-reopen-next-month-7080469]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Notre-Dame In Paris Rises From The Ashes, Set To Reopen Next Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-notre-dame-de-paris-rises-from-the-ashes-set-to-reopen-next-month-7080469]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:12:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five years after a massive fire engulfed the centuries-old Notre-Dame de Paris and toppled its iconic spire, leaving a gaping hole in the heart of Paris while the world watched helplessly, the Catholic cathedral has been restored to its former glory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five years after a massive fire engulfed the centuries-old Notre-Dame de Paris and toppled its iconic spire, leaving a gaping hole in the heart of Paris while the world watched helplessly, the Catholic cathedral has been restored to its former glory and is set to reopen next month amid grand celebrations.</p>

<p>X boss Elon Musk, in a post on the micro-blogging site, provided a glimpse into the gothic monument that, several reports claimed, has been rebuilt with the help of hundreds of specialist artisans and millions of donations.</p>

<p>"Notre-Dame has been restored," Musk said on X, as he shared a 94-minute clip of the renovated cathedral that is set to reopen on December 7.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Notre-Dame has been restored!<br />
<a href="https://t.co/g7RKQDHRlr">pic.twitter.com/g7RKQDHRlr</a></p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1859593835535331439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A report by the National Geographic said everything has been spruced up - the frescoes, checked floor and the bells - which have been removed from the belfry, cleaned of lead dust, and restored at the Norman foundry where they were first cast - among others. A high-tech new lighting system will also contribute to the effect.</p>

<p>According to Forbes, the renovation was carried out at a cost of around 500 million euros.</p>

<p>"A surplus of about 140 million euros will be used for future preservation work on the 861-year-old building," Philippe Jost, who has overseen the project, told Forbes.</p>

<p>An AFP report said before the fire, Notre-Dame was among the most visited buildings in Europe, with 14 to 15 million a year expected to visit once the cathedral reopens next month.</p>

<p>On April 15, 2019, a fire broke out in the attic, beneath the cathedral's roof, causing severe damages to the wooden spire, which had collapsed, and the wooden roof, besides the cathedral's upper walls.</p>

<p>Several works of art and religious relics were moved to safety but others suffered smoke damage. Some of the exterior art was also damaged or destroyed in the blaze. At least two police officers and one firefighter were injured as around 400 firefighters worked through the night, taking roughly around nine hours to extinguish the blaze.</p>

<p>According to the European Commission (a politically independent executive arm of the European Union), a large part of the cathedral roof and spire were made of lead, and some studies suggested that 150 kg of lead was spread during the fire. Others hinted that one tonne of lead must have fallen within one kilometre of the cathedral.</p>

<p>The exact cause of the fire could not be determined but French authorities claimed an electrical fault or a cigarette may have been responsible for the fire, according to Reuters.</p>

<p>Notre-Dame did not hold a Christmas mass in 2019, for the first time since 1803. French President Emmanuel Macron had announced a five-year plan to rebuild what was lost.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/igee9dfo_notre-dame-restoration_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A fire broke out at the Notre-Dame de Paris on April 15, 2019.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-things-to-know-about-pam-bondi-donald-trumps-new-choice-for-attorney-general-7080431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Things To Know About Pam Bondi, Trump's New Choice For Attorney General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-things-to-know-about-pam-bondi-donald-trumps-new-choice-for-attorney-general-7080431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:08:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Continuing with his trend of picking loyalists, Donald Trump has made yet another nomination picking Pam Bondi as Attorney General. This came after Matt Gaetz withdrew his candidacy amid a deluge of allegations regarding sex trafficking and drug use.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Pam Bondi wrote history in 2010 when she was elected as the first female attorney general of Florida. She had already spent more than 18 years as a prosecutor in the Hillsborough County State Attorney's Office; she rose to fame only after holding the state's principal legal officer position. In office, Bondi highlighted the issue of human trafficking and advocated for stricter laws on the matter. She also started a litigation in Florida against opioid manufacturers. She held the position for a period of 8 years, from 2011-2019.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">As a longtime ally of Trump, Bondi was present as one of his lawyers during his first impeachment trial when the latter was accused but not convicted of abusing his powers for allegedly pressuring the Ukraine president to investigate his Democrat rivals while withholding $400 million military assistance to the country.&nbsp;Bondi stood by Trump's claims of Joe Biden engaging in corruption along with son Hunter. Although the accusations have never been substantiated, her eagerness to support Trump gained her a principal spot at the Republican National Convention, the same year.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Bondi was entangled in a 16-month long custody battle over a dog called Master Tank who was rescued in Florida after Hurricane Katrina. She then adopted him and renamed him Noah. The Louisiana family that previously had him learned about his whereabouts in 2006.&nbsp;However, Bondi refused to give him back citing negligence by the earlier owners. "I took a dog who was a walking skeleton," she told St. Petersburg Times. "That's what was wrong with him before the hurricane." She added that if it had been a stable environment, she would have dropped the dog back herself. Subsequently the two sides settled before the trial with Bondi returning the dog.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Pam Bondi reinforced Trump's claims of election fraud in 2020 when Joe Biden won the presidential elections. a Fox News host asked her "Pam, did you just say fake ballots?" to which she responded saying, "There could be. That's the problem." Although she did not provide any evidence.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Trump and Bondi go back quite a few years. He said in a Truth Social post, "I have known Pam for many years -- She is smart and tough, and is an AMERICA FIRST Fighter, who will do a terrific job as Attorney General!" In 2013, Bondi received a $25,000 donation for her fundraising committee for her attorney general reelection campaign.&nbsp;During that time her office had a case that probed Trump and Trump University. Ultimately she did not join the lawsuit and moreover, both of them denied that the donation was the reason she was not part of the lawsuit.&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h3b63g9_pam-bondi-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has picked Pam Bondi as Attorney General.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/speed-range-threat-all-about-russias-oreshnik-missile-fired-on-ukraine-7080192]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Speed, Range, Threat: All About Russia's Oreshnik Missile Fired On Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/speed-range-threat-all-about-russias-oreshnik-missile-fired-on-ukraine-7080192]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 17:37:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new intermediate-range ballistic missile called Oreshnik used by Russia in a strike on Ukraine is a nuclear-capable weapon that has not been previously mentioned in public.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new intermediate-range ballistic missile called Oreshnik used by Russia in a strike on Ukraine is a nuclear-capable weapon that has not been previously mentioned in public.</p>

<p>In an unscheduled television appearance on Thursday, Russian President Vladimir Putin said the strike on the city of Dnipro had tested in combat conditions "one of the newest Russian mid-range missile systems".</p>

<p>He said missile engineers had christened the missile Oreshnik, or hazel tree in Russian.</p>

<p>Putin said it had been deployed "in a non-nuclear hypersonic configuration" and said that the "test" had been successful and had hit its target.</p>

<p><strong>Speed</strong></p>

<p>Air defences cannot intercept the Oreshnik, which attacks at a speed of Mach 10, or 2.5-3 kilometres per second, Putin said.</p>

<p>Hypersonic missiles travel at speeds of at least Mach 5 -- five times the speed of sound -- and can manoeuvre mid-flight, making them harder to track and intercept.</p>

<p>"Modern air defence systems... cannot intercept such missiles. That's impossible," Putin said.</p>

<p>"As of today there are no means of counteracting such a weapon," the president boasted.</p>

<p><strong>Warheads</strong></p>

<p>The Oreshnik missile could have three to six warheads, military expert Viktor Baranets wrote in the Komsomolskaya Pravda tabloid.</p>

<p>Igor Korotchenko, editor of the Moscow-based National Defence journal, told TASS state news agency that based on video footage of the strike, Oreshnik has multiple independently guided warheads.</p>

<p>In this case they were conventional, but it could also carry nuclear warheads, military experts said.</p>

<p>The "practically simultaneous arrival of the warheads at the target" shows the system is "very effective", Korotchenko said, calling it a "masterpiece of modern Russian solid-fuel military missile construction".</p>

<p><strong>Range</strong></p>

<p>The missile was reported by Ukrainian media to have been fired from the Kapustin Yar range in the Astrakhan region, around 900 kilometres (550 miles) from Dnipro.</p>

<p>Putin described the missile in Russian as "medium-range" but Russian military experts said the English term would be "intermediate-range".</p>

<p>An intermediate-range ballistic missile (IRBM) has a range of 1,000-5,500 kilometres, a level below that of an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM).</p>

<p>Military expert Ilya Kramnik told Izvestia newspaper that Oreshnik's range could be at the top end of intermediate, around 3,000 - 5,000 kilometres.</p>

<p>"In any case we witnessed the first combat use in history by Russia of an intermediate-range missile," Dmitry Kornev, editor of Military Russia website, told Izvestia.</p>

<p><strong>Origins</strong></p>

<p>The US Department of Defense described Oreshnik as an "experimental" missile based on Russia's RS-26 Rubezh ICBM.</p>

<p>Little is known about Rubezh, a modification of Topol ICBM.</p>

<p>TASS state news agency reported, citing a source, in 2018 that development of Rubezh was frozen under the state weapons programme up to 2027, to prioritise another system, Avangard.</p>

<p>Russian weapons expert Yan Matveyev wrote on Telegram that Oreshnik probably had two stages and would be "quite expensive", heavy and not mass-produced.</p>

<p><strong>Threat</strong></p>

<p>Its range means "Oreshnik can threaten practically all of Europe" but not the United States, weapons expert Pavel Podvig, director of the Russian Nuclear Forces Project, told Russian Telegram channel Ostorozhno Novosti.</p>

<p>The US and the Soviet Union in 1987 signed a treaty agreeing to give up all use of missiles with a range of 500 to 5,500 kilometres.</p>

<p>Both Washington and Moscow withdrew from the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty in 2019, each accusing the other of violations.</p>

<p>Putin said Thursday that Russia will "address the question of further deployment of intermediate and shorter-range missiles based on the actions of the United States and its satellites".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ftmou98_russia-missile-attack_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin said missile engineers had christened the missile Oreshnik]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baku-climate-summit-explainer-the-climate-conundrum-at-cop29-7079967]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explainer: The Climate Conundrum At COP29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baku-climate-summit-explainer-the-climate-conundrum-at-cop29-7079967]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 17:07:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The COP29 summit at Baku is ending, yet a draft text with a proposed figure for climate finance and emission reductions goals is elusive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The COP29 summit at Baku is ending, yet a draft text with a proposed figure for climate finance and emission reductions goals is elusive. The key goal of COP29 is to agree on how much money should be provided by developed countries to developing countries to help them deal with climate-induced weather disasters and changeover to cleaner energy systems.</p>

<p>An earlier pledge to provide $100 billion per year expires in 2025. At the Baku summit, delegates were to decide on a 10-fold increase in financial flows to at least $1 trillion annually from 2026.</p>

<p>The proposed figures on finance, called NCQG (New Collective Quantified Goal), will sum up cooperation on three issues - quantity, quality, and contributors.</p>

<p><strong>Sticking Points</strong></p>

<p>According to developing countries including India, developed countries are pushing for higher reduction goals without a financial commitment.</p>

<p>One of the major disagreements between developed and developing nations is over the balance between emission reduction and climate finance. The argument from developing countries is that they should not be forced to commit stringent mitigation goals without enough money on the table to address climate change.</p>

<p>The developed countries are keen to expand their contributor base to include emerging economies, which has been opposed by the developing countries as a violation of the 2015 Paris Agreement.</p>

<p>Developing countries, including India and China, have repeatedly demanded $1.3 trillion from the national budgets of the rich developed countries. They have maintained that this money is a legal obligation under the Paris Agreement, and not charity.</p>

<p>The $1.3 trillion amount is based on cost estimates by the Independent High-Level Expert Group on Climate Finance, a new body appointed by the United Nations, for developing and deploying technology that would keep the global temperature increase below 2 degrees Celsius (3.6 degrees Fahrenheit), compared to the pre-industrial average.</p>

<p>The source of the hundreds of billions, if not trillions, of funds that developing countries say they require to adapt to a fast-changing climate, is also a subject of contention. Whether the money will come from governments, multilateral banks, or the private sector has become a flashpoint in the summit.</p>

<p>Developed nations have been silent on the amount so far, but have been vocal in supporting a multi-layered approach to financing climate action, including support from public and private funds.</p>

<p><strong>Tussle Over Source Of Funding</strong></p>

<p>The developing countries, particularly those facing debt crises, have called for prioritising public finance over private finance, raising concerns about accessibility and adequacy of market-based mechanisms.</p>

<p>Until now, a major portion of previous climate fundings have been in the form of high interest loans where the receiver country has had to then pay interest on the principal amount. This type of funding places the burden on the financial health of the recipients, who are mostly the least developed countries.</p>

<p>At COP29, the least developed countries, especially from Africa, have highlighted their vulnerabilities to climate-induced disasters like drought, food shortage, water scarcity, and displacement, and the high cost their countries are paying to meet the challenges year-on-year.</p>

<p>This year, the delegates from developing and least developed countries have voiced apprehensions about relying on market-based fundings for meeting their climate challenges. They have also flagged the need for clear and transparent mechanisms that can track and account flow of climate finance.</p>

<p>Bolivian representative Diego Pacheco, speaking on behalf of Like-Minded Developing Countries, said developed countries are trying to shift their own responsibility on to developing countries, which is in violation of the Paris Agreement and not acceptable. India and China are part of this group.</p>

<p><strong>What's Worrying Developed Countries</strong></p>

<p>Also complicating the talks is the demand by developed nations to include China and Saudi Arabia among their ranks, thus becoming donor countries liable for financial contributions. Developed countries are upset about China being bracketed in the developing country category.</p>

<p>The financing question has become even more tricky with Donald Trump's election victory in the US. The world's biggest economy and history's biggest emitter, is expected to withdraw from the Paris Agreement when Trump takes office, which means the country would very likely default on whatever financial commitments the final agreement sets out. This will hugely impact climate funding.</p>

<p><strong>The Way Out</strong></p>

<p>With little progress in the first week of COP29, the Azerbaijani presidency gave the responsibility to a pair of ministers from developed and developing countries to take the negotiations further. Egypt and Australia were told to hold discussions on the structure, contributors, and overall "quantum" of the new finance goal.</p>

<p>Ministers from Norway and South Africa were tasked with shaping the outcome on emission reduction goals. These two factors - the basic formulation of a reduction plan (how countries would make climate commitment to meet Paris Agreement goals) and the new finance goal - are the main reasons for the near-collapse of talks in Baku.</p>

<p>The only significant takeaway until now has been the inclusion of tourism in the action agenda of the UN Climate Change Conference, with more than 50 governments endorsing the COP29 Declaration. The aim is to support the tourism sector, a key economic driver, in adopting sustainable practices to reduce its environmental impact.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://w.ndtvimg.com/sites/3/2023/06/12125202/climate5-1.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The only significant takeaway until now has been the inclusion of tourism in the action agenda.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/part-of-londons-gatwick-airport-evacuated-as-cops-investigate-security-incident-7079908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Part Of London's Gatwick Airport Evacuated As Cops Probe Security Incident]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/part-of-londons-gatwick-airport-evacuated-as-cops-investigate-security-incident-7079908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:55:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[London's Gatwick Airport today evacuated people from a large part of the airport over a security threat, the airport authorities said in a post on social media website X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>London's Gatwick Airport today evacuated people from a large part of the airport over a security threat, the airport authorities said in a post on social media website X. It said that passengers will not be allowed to enter the section of the airport till the incident is addressed.</p>

<p>"A large part of the South Terminal has been evacuated as a precaution while we continue to investigate a security incident," the airport management said.</p>

<p>It further stated that the part of the airport which is affected due to this is "a large part of the South Terminal", adding that "We continue to investigate a security incident."</p>

<p>Requesting passengers to cooperate and remain calm, the airport authority said, "Safety and security of our passengers and staff remains our top priority. We are working hard to resolve the issue as quickly as possible."</p>

<h2><strong>LONDON ON ALERT</strong></h2>

<p>The police in London are on high alert after a suspicious package outside the US Embassy in the city. The police had to carry out a controlled explosion to tackle the situation.</p>

<p>London's Metropolitan Police carried out the controlled explosion after evacuating the area and setting up cordons near the site. The US Embassy is located near Nine Elms, just south of the River Thames.</p>

<p>After the controlled explosion was conducted successfully, the police released a statement on social media website X saying "</p>

<p>"We can confirm that the 'loud bang' reported in the area a short time ago was a controlled explosion carried out by officers. Enquiries are still ongoing and cordons will remain in place for the time being."</p>

<p>The US Embassy in London also shared an update on X saying that an investigation over "a suspicious package" is currently being carried out, and that the area around the embassy and roads leading to it have been closed till further notice "out of an abundance of caution".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tjrlccq8_london-gatwick-airport-south-terminal-istock_625x300_22_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A large part of the South Terminal at London's Gatwick Airport has been evacuated for security.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-police-conduct-controlled-explosion-outside-us-embassy-7079650]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[London Police Conduct "Controlled Explosion" Outside US Embassy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/london-police-conduct-controlled-explosion-outside-us-embassy-7079650]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 16:21:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK police said Friday officers had carried out a controlled explosion after "a suspicious package" was found outside the United States embassy in London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK police said Friday officers had carried out a controlled explosion after "a suspicious package" was found outside the United States embassy in London.</p>

<p>The capital's Metropolitan Police force conducted the explosion after setting up cordons near the high-security site in Nine Elms, just south of the River Thames.</p>

<p>"We can confirm that the 'loud bang' reported in the area a short time ago was a controlled explosion carried out by officers," the force said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We're aware of speculation online about an incident in the vicinity of the US Embassy in Nine Elms.<br />
<br />
Cordons are in place in the area as a precaution while officers investigate a suspect package.<br />
<br />
We will provide a further update in due course.</p>
— Metropolitan Police (@metpoliceuk) <a href="https://twitter.com/metpoliceuk/status/1859895814459695433?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Enquiries are still ongoing and cordons will remain in place for the time being."</p>

<p>The US embassy said in a post on its X account that local authorities were investigating "a suspicious package" outside the building.</p>

<p>It added that police had closed a nearby road "out of an abundance of caution".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/65u9rvc8_london-police-generic_650x400_02_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Enquiries are still ongoing," said London Police (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-to-afghanistan-how-womens-basic-rights-are-being-eroded-across-world-7079187]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iraq To Afghanistan: How Women's Basic Rights Are Being Eroded Across World]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-to-afghanistan-how-womens-basic-rights-are-being-eroded-across-world-7079187]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 15:20:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From Iraq to Afghanistan to the US, basic freedoms for women are being eroded as governments start rolling back existing laws.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From Iraq to Afghanistan to the US, basic freedoms for women are being eroded as governments start rolling back existing laws.</p>

<p>Just a few months ago a ban on Afghan <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c20rq73p3z4o">women speaking in public</a> was the latest measure introduced by the Taliban, who took back control of the country in 2021. From August the ban included singing, reading aloud, reciting poetry and even laughing outside their homes.</p>

<p>The Taliban's ministry for the propagation of virtue and the prevention of vice, which implements one of the most radical interpretations of Islamic law, enforces these rules. They are part of a broader set of <a href="https://www.wbur.org/onpoint/2024/09/27/afghan-women-taliban-human-rights">“vice and virtue”</a> laws that severely restrict women's rights and freedoms. Women are even banned <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/afghan-women-cannot-pray-loudly-recite-front-women-says-taliban-minist-rcna177990">from reading the Quran</a> out loud to other women in public.</p>

<p>In the past three years in Afghanistan, the Taliban has taken away many basic rights from women who live there, so that there's very little that they are allowed to do.</p>

<p>From 2021, <a href="https://www.usip.org/tracking-talibans-Mistreatment-women">the Taliban started</a> introducing restrictions on girls receiving education, starting with a ban on coeducation and then a ban on girls attending secondary schools. This was followed by closing blind girls' schools in 2023, and making it mandatory for girls in grades four to six (ages nine to 12) to cover their faces on the way to school.</p>

<p>Women can no longer attend universities or receive a degree certificate nationally, or follow midwifery or nursing training in the Kandahar region. <a href="https://www.usip.org/tracking-talibans-Mistreatment-women">Women are no longer allowed</a> to be flight attendants, or to take a job outside the home. Women-run bakeries in the capital Kabul have now been banned. Women are mostly now unable to earn any money, or leave their homes. In April 2024, the Taliban in Helmand province told media outlets to even refrain from airing women's voices.</p>

<p>Afghanistan is ranked last on the <a href="https://giwps.georgetown.edu/the-index/">Women, Peace and Security Index</a> and officials at the UN and elsewhere have called it <a href="https://www.passblue.com/2023/06/21/the-gender-apartheid-happening-in-afghanistan-un-experts-say-should-be-labeled-an-international-crime/">“gender apartheid”</a>. Afghan women are putting their lives on the line — facing surveillance, harassment, assault, arbitrary detention, torture and exile — to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e7hgYu43Krk">protest against</a> the Taliban.</p>

<p>Many diplomats discuss how important it is to <a href="https://press.un.org/en/2022/sc15038.doc.htm">“engage”</a> with the Taliban, yet this has not stopped the assault on women's rights. When diplomats “engage”, they tend to focus on counter-terrorism, counternarcotics, business deals, or <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2023/04/05/taliban-afghanistan-hostage-diplomacy-western-prisoners/">hostage</a> returns. Despite everything that has happened to Afghan women <a href="https://asiapacific.unwomen.org/en/digital-library/publications/2023/09/summary-report-of-country-wide-womens-consultations">over a short period</a>, critics suggest this rarely makes it onto diplomats' priority list.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="260" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e7hgYu43Krk?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="440"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Afghan women protest via song against the Taliban.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2>Iraq's age of consent</h2>

<p>Meanwhile, in Iraq, on August 4 2024, an amendment to Iraq's 1959 personal status law which would possibly lower the age of consent for marriage <a href="https://time.com/7011752/proposed-bill-amendment-iraq-could-allow-girls-as-young-as-nine-to-marry/">to nine years old</a> from 18 (or 15 with permission from a judge and parents) was proposed by member of parliament Ra'ad al-Maliki and supported by conservative Shia factions in the government.</p>

<p>The law would have the potential of having matters of family law – such as marriage – adjudicated by religious authorities. This change could not only legalise child marriage but also strip women of rights related to divorce, child custody and inheritance.</p>

<p>Iraq already has a high rate of <a href="https://www.girlsnotbrides.org/learning-resources/child-marriage-atlas/atlas/iraq/#:%7E:text=Minimum%20legal%20age%20of%20marriage%20below%2018%20years,-What's%20the%20prevalence&amp;text=28%25%20of%20girls%20in%20Iraq,%2C%20Muthana%20(27%25).">underage marriage</a>, with 7% of girls married by 15 years old, and <a href="https://www.girlsnotbrides.org/learning-resources/child-marriage-atlas/atlas/iraq/#:%7E:text=Minimum%20legal%20age%20of%20marriage%20below%2018%20years,-What's%20the%20prevalence&amp;text=28%25%20of%20girls%20in%20Iraq,%2C%20Muthana%20(27%25).">28%</a> married before the legal age of 18.</p>

<p>Unregistered marriages, not legally recorded in court but conducted through religious or tribal authorities, <a href="https://pdf.usaid.gov/pdf_docs/PA00K2Z4.pdf">prevent girls from accessing civil rights</a>, and leave women and girls vulnerable to exploitation, abuse and neglect, with limited options for seeking justice.</p>

<p>Many women's groups have already <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/article/2024/aug/09/proposed-iraqi-law-change-would-legalise-child-say-activists">mobilised against the law</a>. But the amendment has <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2024/10/iraq-reject-changes-to-personal-status-law-which-would-allow-child-marriage-and-further-entrench-discrimination/">passed its second reading</a> in parliament. If introduced, it could pave the way for further modifications that deepen sectarian divides and move the country further away from a unified legal system. It would also be an especially troubling step backward in protecting children's rights and gender equality.</p>

<h2>Abortion rights in the US</h2>

<p>Meanwhile, in the US, women's access to abortion has been eroded significantly in the past few years. In late 2021, the US was officially labelled a <a href="https://msmagazine.com/backsliding-democracies/">backsliding democracy</a> by an international thinktank.</p>

<p>Six months later, the landmark US Supreme Court ruling of Roe v Wade, which had safeguarded the constitutional right to abortion for nearly 50 years, was overturned. This led to a cascade of restrictive laws, with more than a quarter of US states enacting outright bans or <a href="https://reproductiverights.org/maps/abortion-laws-by-state/">severe restrictions on abortion</a>.</p>

<p>Republican US congresswoman Marjorie Taylor Greene suggested, in May 2022, that women should stay celibate if they did not <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/marjorie-taylor-greene-celibacy-abortion-dont-have-sex-1707684">want to get pregnant</a>. If only all women had that choice. In fact, in the US a sexual assault occurs <a href="https://rainn.org/statistics/victims-sexual-violence">every 68 seconds</a>. One in every five American women has been the victim of <a href="https://www.nsvrc.org/statistics">an attempted or completed rape</a>. From 2009-13, US Child Protective Services agencies found strong evidence indicating that <a href="https://paar.net/child-family-services/statistics/">63,000 children per year were victims of sexual abuse</a>.</p>

<p>These developments reflect a troubling pattern. There is evidence from Donald Trump's first term that there could be further erosion of women's rights in his second presidency. During his previous term there were significant <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-a-second-trump-presidency-is-likely-to-threaten-abortion-rights-and-womens-healthcare-globally-243346">attempts to weaken healthcare access</a>, with his foreign policy reinstating the <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/gpr/2020/04/unprecedented-expansion-global-gag-rule-trampling-rights-health-and-free-speech">“global gag rule”</a> restricting access to women's reproductive healthcare worldwide via funding conditions.</p>

<h2>Fragility of women's rights</h2>

<p>If the world can tolerate the Taliban's abuses, Iraq's restrictive laws and the US restrictions on abortion access, it reveals the fragility of women's and girls' rights globally, and how easy it is to take them away.</p>

<p>The UN agency, UN Women, says it could take another <a href="https://www.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/2022-09/Progress-on-the-sustainable-development-goals-the-gender-snapshot-2022-en_0.pdf">286 years</a> to close the global gender gaps in legal protections. <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/press-releases/2024/06/gender-backlash-underscores-urgency-achieve-substantive-equality-women-and">No country has yet achieved gender equality</a>, based on the gender pay gap, legal equality and <a href="https://www.statista.com/topics/7625/gender-equality-worldwide/#topicOverview">social inequality</a> levels. Women and girls continue to face discrimination in all corners of the world, and it seems to be getting worse. But despite everything women <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uNLvTBZD5AE">continue to resist</a>.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243302/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(Author:&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/hind-elhinnawy-417908">Hind Elhinnawy</a>, Senior Lecturer, School of Social Sciences, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/nottingham-trent-university-1338">Nottingham Trent University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/how-womens-basic-rights-and-freedoms-are-being-eroded-all-over-the-world-243302">original article</a>.</em></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rn17u4hg_womens-right_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-world-court-warrant-wont-stop-israel-defending-itself-7078939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Netanyahu Says World Court Warrant Won't Stop Israel Defending Itself]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-says-world-court-warrant-wont-stop-israel-defending-itself-7078939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:46:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Thursday that an arrest warrant issued against him by the International Criminal Court over his conduct of the Gaza war would not stop him defending Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Thursday that an arrest warrant issued against him by the International Criminal Court over his conduct of the Gaza war would not stop him defending Israel.</p>

<p>"No outrageous anti-Israel decision will prevent us –- and it will not prevent me –- from continuing to defend our country in every way," Netanyahu said in a video statement. "We will not yield to pressure," he vowed.</p>

<p>The premier is accused alongside his former defence minister Yoav Gallant of "war crimes" and "crimes against humanity" for Israel's actions in Gaza.</p>

<p>He described Thursday's decision as a "dark day in the history of nations".</p>

<p>"The International Criminal Court in The Hague, which was established to protect humanity, has today become the enemy of humanity," he said, adding that the accusations were "utterly baseless".</p>

<p>Israel has been fighting in Gaza since October 2023, when a cross-border attack by Hamas militants resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Its retaliatory campaign has led to the deaths of 44,056 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>UN agencies have warned of a severe humanitarian crisis in Gaza, including possible famine, due to a lack of food and medicines.</p>

<p>The court said it had found "reasonable grounds" to believe Netanyahu and Gallant bore "criminal responsibility" for the war crime of starvation as a method of warfare, as well as the crimes against humanity of murder, persecution, and other inhumane acts.</p>

<p>Netanyahu said the court was accusing Israel of "fictitious crimes", while ignoring "the real war crimes, horrific war crimes being committed against us and against many others around the world".</p>

<p>In addition to Netanyahu and Gallant, the court also issued an arrest warrant for Hamas military wing chief Mohammed Deif, who Israel said was killed in an air strike last July.</p>

<p>Hamas has never confirmed his death.</p>

<p>Netanyahu mocked the court's decision to issue a warrant for "the body of Mohammed Deif."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The International Criminal Court at The Hague issued an arrest warrant against Netanyahu]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/artificial-intelligence-india-ranks-second-globally-in-ai-specialists-third-in-research-publications-report-7078867]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Ranks 2nd Globally In AI Specialists, 3rd In Research Publications]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/artificial-intelligence-india-ranks-second-globally-in-ai-specialists-third-in-research-publications-report-7078867]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:32:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India is among the top ten countries in Artificial Intelligence (AI) readiness, and the country holds immense potential for public sector transformation through AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India is among the top ten countries in Artificial Intelligence (AI) readiness, and the country holds immense potential for public sector transformation through AI, according to a report.</p>

<p>"Readiness" for AI refers to an economy's ability to effectively implement and integrate AI. The report by Boston Consulting Group (BCG) based on data from 73 economies showed that India ranks second globally in AI specialists, and third in research publications, with a strong base in AI-related patents.</p>

<p>On the other hand, over 70 per cent of the economies studied score below average in critical areas such as ecosystem participation, skills, and research and development.</p>

<p>"India's journey to becoming an AI contender underscores the nation's emphasis on integrating technology into high-priority sectors like agriculture, education, and healthcare. As one of the top 10 countries in AI readiness, India holds immense potential for public sector transformation through AI," said Saibal Chakraborty, India Leader, Technology and Digital Advantage Practice, BCG.</p>

<p>"India ranks second globally in AI specialists and 3rd in research publications, with a strong base in AI-related patents," he added.</p>

<p>The report further showed that AI exposure spans several key sectors in India. Business services account for 16 per cent of GDP and have significant AI exposure, with potential improvements in administrative efficiency for government operations.</p>

<p>Retail and wholesale make up 10 per cent of GDP, where AI could streamline public distribution and supply chain management, reducing wastage. Public services represent 6 per cent of GDP, with opportunities for AI to enhance service delivery and emergency response.</p>

<p>Agriculture, forestry, and fisheries contribute 17 per cent of GDP and could use AI in precision farming and risk assessment to boost productivity.</p>

<p>The construction sector, at 8 per cent of GDP, can utilise AI for infrastructure planning and asset maintenance. Arts, recreation, and personal services, also at 8 per cent, could benefit from AI in managing public facilities.</p>

<p>"Realising this potential requires a multi-faceted approach: strengthening infrastructure, enhancing AI research capabilities, and expanding workforce training. Investments in research hubs, cloud capabilities, and data systems are critical, alongside efforts to expand AI education in rural areas and foster public-private collaborations," Chakraborty said.</p>

<p>The report also called for regulatory frameworks to address the ethical use of AI, monitor bias, and ensure responsible adoption of the technology.</p>

<p>Aparna Bharadwaj, managing director, BCG urged "policymakers to act decisively to prepare for an AI-driven world". This can be achieved by "enhancing resilience, productivity, job creation, modernisation, and competitiveness".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3928vl9_artificial-intelligence-_625x300_17_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India is among the top ten countries in AI readiness (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-doomsday-fish-found-on-california-beach-cool-creature-fascinates-scientists-7078456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare 'Doomsday Fish' Washes Up On California Beach, Fascinates Scientists]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-doomsday-fish-found-on-california-beach-cool-creature-fascinates-scientists-7078456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 13:33:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alison Laferriere, a doctoral student at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography, made the unusual find while walking her dog.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rare deep-sea creature, known as the ‘doomsday fish,' recently washed ashore the Grandview Beach in Encinitas, California.</p>

<p>Alison Laferriere, a doctoral student at the Scripps Institution of Oceanography, spotted it while walking her dog. Initially mistaking the long, slender form for debris, Laferriere quickly recognised the creature as an oarfish — a rare species.<br />
<br />
In a social media post, Scripps Institution of Oceanography wrote, “Just when you thought the oarfish hype had died down, look what decided to make another appearance.”<br />
<br />
Scripps added, “Last week, another oarfish washed up on Grandview Beach in Encinitas and was spotted by Scripps Oceanography PhD candidate Alison Laferriere. This cool creature is a bit smaller than the one recovered in La Jolla this August, measuring roughly 9 to 10 feet long.<br />
<br />
“Ben Frable, manager of the Scripps Oceanography Marine Vertebrate Collection, jumped into action and contacted the NOAA Fisheries Service team to recover the specimen and transport it to the Southwest Fisheries Science Center.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">“Like with the previous oarfish, this specimen and the samples taken from it will be able to tell us much about the biology, anatomy, genomics and life history of oarfishes.” - Scripps Marine Vertebrate Collection Manager Ben <a href="https://twitter.com/Frable?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@Frable</a> <a href="https://t.co/GbOPGN064C">pic.twitter.com/GbOPGN064C</a></p>
— Scripps Institution of Oceanography (@Scripps_Ocean) <a href="https://twitter.com/Scripps_Ocean/status/1856817277045543344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“We took samples and froze the specimen awaiting further study and final preservation in the Marine Vertebrate Collection,” Frable said.<br />
<br />
On the second oarfish washing up on California's shores this year, Frable said the occurrence may be linked to changing ocean conditions and an increased presence of the species in the region.</p>

<p>“Many researchers have suggested this as to why deep-water fish strand on beaches. Sometimes it may be linked to broader shifts such as the El Nino and La Nina cycle but this is not always the case. There was a weak El Nino earlier this year. This wash-up coincided with the recent red tide and Santa Ana winds last week but many variables could lead to these strandings,” Frable added.</p>

<p>The oarfish, distinguished by its long eel-like body, bright red dorsal fins, and gaping mouth, is a deep-sea creature that has captured both scientific and popular imagination. According to <a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/long-fish-predicts-earthquake-legend" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Atlas Obscura</a>, in Japanese folklore, the appearance of the oarfish is considered a harbinger of impending disaster, particularly earthquakes.</p>

<p>This superstition gained notoriety after multiple oarfish were found along Japan's coast prior to the 2011 earthquake, sparking widespread belief in its connection to natural disasters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/f8scf5lg_oarfish_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-gave-north-korea-anti-air-missiles-in-exchange-of-troops-south-korea-7078300]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Gave North Korea Anti-Air Missiles In Exchange Of Troops: S Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-gave-north-korea-anti-air-missiles-in-exchange-of-troops-south-korea-7078300]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 13:18:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia gave North Korea anti-air missiles in exchange for deploying troops to support Moscow's war in Ukraine, Seoul's top security advisor said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia gave North Korea anti-air missiles in exchange for deploying troops to support Moscow's war in Ukraine, Seoul's top security advisor said Friday.</p>

<p>The United States and South Korea have accused the nuclear-armed North of sending more than 10,000 soldiers to help Russia fight Ukraine, with experts saying Kim Jong Un was eager to gain advanced technology, and battle experience for his troops, in return.</p>

<p>Asked what Seoul believes Pyongyang has received for the troops, top security advisor Shin Won-sik said: "It has been identified that equipment and anti-aircraft missiles aimed at reinforcing Pyonyang's vulnerable air defense system have been delivered to North Korea."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Speaking to local broadcaster SBS, Shin added that North Korea has received "various forms of economic support" and "following the failure (launch) on May 27, North Korea has been working on satellite-related technology".</p>

<p>Experts have previously said that in return for the troops, North Korea was likely aiming to acquire military technology, ranging from surveillance satellites to submarines, as well as possible security guarantees from Moscow.</p>

<p>North Korean leader Kim and Russian President Vladimir Putin signed a strategic partnership treaty in June, during the Kremlin chief's visit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It obligates both states to provide military assistance "without delay" in the case of an attack on the other and to cooperate internationally to oppose Western sanctions.</p>

<p>Putin hailed the deal as a "breakthrough document".</p>

<p>Experts say Pyongyang could be using Ukraine as a means of realigning foreign policy.</p>

<p>By sending soldiers, North Korea is positioning itself within the Russian war economy as a supplier of weapons, military support and labor -- potentially bypassing its traditional ally, neighbour and main trading partner, China, according to analysts.</p>

<p>Russia can also provide North Korea access to its vast natural resources, such as oil and gas, they say.</p>

<p>North Korean Foreign Minister Choe Son Hui recently visited Moscow and said her country would "stand firmly by our Russian comrades until victory day".</p>

<p>She called Moscow's offensive against Ukraine a "sacred struggle" and said Pyongyang believed in Putin's "wise leadership".</p>

<p>North Korea and Russia are under rafts of UN sanctions -- Kim for his nuclear weapons program, and Moscow for the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>When asked publicly about the deployment of North Korean troops last month, Putin deflected the question to criticise the West's support of Ukraine.</p>

<p>North Korea said last month that any troop deployment to Russia would be "an act conforming with the regulations of international law", but stopped short of confirming that it had sent soldiers.</p>

<p>North Korea's deployment of troops has led to a shift in tone from Seoul, which has resisted calls to send lethal weapons to Kyiv, but recently indicated it might change its longstanding policy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-03/2mej6kl_russian-troops-reuters_625x300_02_March_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Experts say Pyongyang could be using Ukraine for realigning foreign policy. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-how-barack-obama-narrated-new-netflix-docuseries-our-oceans-7078212]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: How Barack Obama Narrated New Netflix Docuseries 'Our Oceans']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-how-barack-obama-narrated-new-netflix-docuseries-our-oceans-7078212]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 13:02:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Netflix's new nature documentary series "Our Oceans" is dedicated to the world's five oceans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Netflix on Thursday started streaming its new nature documentary series "Our Oceans". Narrated by former US President Barack Obama, the five-episode docuseries is dedicated to the world's five oceans - Pacific, Indian, Atlantic, Arctic, and Southern.</p>

<p>In a video shared on Instagram, Netflix showed Mr Obama doing a voice-over inside a recording booth.</p>

<p>"Here we go... Our oceans are vast realms of wonder, danger and mystery. Explore new worlds just below the surface," he can be heard saying.</p>

<p>"That's it. It's a wrap," Mr&nbsp;Obama says as he finishes his recording.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCpWMibymNS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCpWMibymNS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCpWMibymNS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCpWMibymNS/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Netflix US (@netflix)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>"Our Oceans" is directed by Emmy-winning wildlife filmmaker James Honeyborne and produced by Higher Ground Productions, which was founded by Barack Obama and his wife, Michelle Obama.</p>

<p>Launched in 2018, Higher Ground has already released about 18 projects, including the animated show "Waffles + Mochi" and the docuseries "Working: What We Do All Day", which follows Mr Obama visiting people in their homes and their workplaces to learn more about their lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2022, the Higher Ground produced a natural history docuseries called "Our Great National Parks", which was also narrated by Mr&nbsp;Obama. The 63-year-old leader had even won a Primetime Creative Arts Emmy Award for Outstanding Narrator.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/o7o06fro_barack-obama-netflix_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Our Oceans" is directed by Emmy-winning wildlife filmmaker James Honeyborne]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-bert-warning-issued-for-heavy-snow-rain-and-travel-chaos-in-uk-7078171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Storm Bert: Warning Issued For Heavy Snow, Rain And Travel Chaos In UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/storm-bert-warning-issued-for-heavy-snow-rain-and-travel-chaos-in-uk-7078171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:58:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The warning covers parts of Angus, Perth and Kinross, Stirlingshire, Aberdeenshire and some of the Highlands and Argyll and Bute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Several parts of the UK are bracing for heavy snow, rain and strong winds with weather forecasters warning of Storm Bert's arrival this weekend. According to the <em>BBC</em>, more than 100 schools in Scotland and almost 200 in Devon and Cornwall have been closed due to snow. The Met Office has issued a yellow alert for snow and ice till Friday (November 22). Bret is the second named storm of the season to bring extreme weather events to parts of the UK, the outlet further said.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">⚠️Yellow weather warning issued⚠️ <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/StormBert?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#StormBert</a> will also bring very strong winds to parts of west Wales, northwest England, coastal parts of northeast England, parts of Scotland and to much of Northern Ireland<br />
<br />
Saturday 0500 – 1900<br />
<br />
Latest info ? <a href="https://t.co/QwDLMfS950">https://t.co/QwDLMfS950</a><br />
<br />
Stay… <a href="https://t.co/CP9OcSzrbx">pic.twitter.com/CP9OcSzrbx</a></p>
— Met Office (@metoffice) <a href="https://twitter.com/metoffice/status/1859583281261576624?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The storm has been named by Ireland's Met Eireann, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvglm32ydnzo">said the <em>BBC</em></a>.</p>

<p>Wind gusting up to 70 mph (113 kmph) and heavy rain are expected in some areas. It could also lead to travel disruptions and flooding, with parts of Wales and Southwest England expected to received 100 mm of rain.</p>

<p>Local authorities have issued warnings for drivers asking them to check forecasts before taking out their vehicles. In areas that are expected to bear the brunt of Storm Bert, motorists have been advised to drive with "extreme caution".</p>

<p>Devon and Cornwall Police has already received many calls about collisions due to the conditions, as per the <em>BBC</em> report.</p>

<p>The warning covers parts of Angus, Perth and Kinross, Stirlingshire, Aberdeenshire and some of the Highlands and Argyll and Bute.</p>

<p>"A northerly airflow will continue to feed snow showers into Scotland over the next few days, with this reaching lower levels at times and bringing the potential for some travel disruption," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.sky.com/story/storm-bert-second-named-storm-of-season-to-bring-snow-rain-and-70mph-winds-to-uk-at-weekend-13257186"><em>Sky News</em></a> quoted Met Office chief meteorologist Matthew Lehnert as saying.</p>

<p>"Overnight temperatures will drop below zero fairly widely over the next few days, which has resulted in some ice warnings, with further warnings likely through this week," the meteorologist further said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ugrnk578_storm-bert-uk_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Storm Bert has been named by Ireland's Met Eireann.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/understanding-iccs-arrest-warrant-on-netanyahu-what-led-to-this-and-what-happens-next-7078170]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What World Court's Arrest Warrant For Netanyahu Means]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/understanding-iccs-arrest-warrant-on-netanyahu-what-led-to-this-and-what-happens-next-7078170]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:57:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The International Criminal Court (ICC) has issued an arrest warrant for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, citing "reasonable grounds" for his criminal responsibility for war crimes and crimes against humanity in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The International Criminal Court (<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-leaders-split-as-icc-issues-arrest-warrant-for-netanyahu-7075339 ">ICC) has issued an arrest warrant for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</a>, citing "reasonable grounds" for his criminal responsibility for war crimes and crimes against humanity in Gaza. A statement from the ICC's pre-trial chamber revealed that Israel's challenges to the court's jurisdiction were rejected.</p>

<p>The ICC also issued arrest warrants for Israel's former Defence Minister Yoav Gallant and Hamas's military chief Mohammed Deif. Earlier, Israel claimed that Deif was killed in August.</p>

<p>Netanyahu <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-says-icc-arrest-warrant-will-not-stop-israel-defending-itself-7075250 ">condemned the ICC's decision</a>, calling it “anti-Israel” and “antisemitic.” While the White House rejected the ICC's decision, several European countries said they would abide by the court's ruling.</p>

<p><b>What is the International Criminal Court?</b></p>

<p>The International Criminal Court (ICC), headquartered in The Hague, Netherlands, investigates and prosecutes individuals accused of genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity, and aggression. Governed by the Rome Statute, it serves as a court of last resort, complementing national judicial systems. With over 900 staff from 100 countries, the ICC has six official languages and two working languages, English and French.</p>

<p>Since its inception, the court has handled 32 cases, issued 59 arrest warrants, secured 11 convictions, and acquitted four individuals. Its efforts include victim participation, independent prosecution, and fair trial guarantees. It is supported by a budget of €187 million for 2024.</p>

<p><b>What is the arrest warrant by the ICC against Netanyahu?</b></p>

<p>The warrants were issued in response to accusations of crimes against humanity and war crimes related to Israel's military actions in Gaza, particularly after the October 7, 2023, attack by Hamas. The warrants specifically cite crimes such as murder, persecution, and using starvation as a weapon of war.</p>

<p><b>How the international community reacted</b></p>

<p>Israel and its allies, including the United States, rejected the ruling, claiming the ICC lacked jurisdiction, adding the country had the right to self-defence. Human rights groups and countries like Turkey supported the warrants, calling them an important step towards justice.</p>

<p>Some countries, including the Netherlands, have already said they would comply with the ICC's decision, while others, like the UK, expressed support for Israel's right to self-defence despite the ICC warrants.</p>

<p>The ICC's involvement began in 2018 when Palestine referred the situation to the court. In 2023 and 2024, multiple countries, including South Africa and Chile, added further referrals. Despite Israel not being a signatory to the Rome Statute, which governs the ICC, Palestine's status and the broader context allow the ICC to pursue the case.</p>

<p><b>What it means</b></p>

<p>While Israel is not an ICC member and does not recognize the court's jurisdiction, the warrants could affect their international travel. However, they are not at risk of arrest in Israel.</p>

<p>The 124 members of the Rome Statute, the treaty that established the ICC, are obliged to arrest the two Israelis and hand them over to the court.</p>

<p>"These decisions are binding on all states party to the Rome Statute, which includes all EU member states," Josep Borrell, the EU's foreign policy chief, posted on X.</p>

<p>Enforcement of such warrants has been inconsistent, with some countries like South Africa and Mongolia previously failing to arrest individuals under similar warrants.</p>

<p>The warrants are unlikely to lead to immediate trials, as the ICC does not prosecute in absentia except in rare cases. Netanyahu and Gallant have reaffirmed their commitment to continue the war in Gaza, despite the warrants.</p>

<p>While the arrest warrants may not result in immediate arrests, they serve as a moral victory for Palestine and intensify international pressure on Israel, limiting Netanyahu's ability to travel to certain countries without facing potential embarrassment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdpp60fk_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The warrants were issued in response to accusations of crimes against humanity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chimps-are-upping-their-tool-game-says-study-why-it-holds-relevance-for-humans-7078064]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chimps Are Upping Their Tool Game. Why It Holds Relevance For Humans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chimps-are-upping-their-tool-game-says-study-why-it-holds-relevance-for-humans-7078064]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:44:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chimpanzees are steadily honing their tool-using skills -- a process unfolding over millennia, driven by the exchange of ideas through migrations between populations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"Planet of the Apes" may have been onto something.</p>

<p>Chimpanzees are steadily honing their tool-using skills -- a process unfolding over millennia, driven by the exchange of ideas through migrations between populations, according to a new study published Thursday in Science.</p>

<p>The finding in chimps -- humans' closest living relatives -- holds relevance for us too, as it supports the idea that, deep in the mists of time, our own ape ancestors leveraged social connections to improve their technologies, lead author Cassandra Gunasekaram told AFP.</p>

<p>Scientists have long marveled at chimps' ability to pass down intricate behaviours, like tool use, from one generation to the next.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yet while human civilization has leapt from the Stone Age to the Space Age, chimpanzee "culture" -- defined as socially learned behaviors -- seemed to have remained static.</p>

<p>Gunasekaram, a doctoral student at the University of Zurich, set out to challenge this assumption.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Connections spark innovation</strong></h3>

<p>She and colleagues combined genetic data tracing ancient chimpanzee migrations across Africa with observations of 15 distinct foraging behaviors across dozens of populations and the four subspecies.</p>

<p>These behaviors were categorized into three levels: those requiring no tools, those with simple tools, like using chewed leaves as a sponge to absorb water from tree holes, and the most complex, which involve toolsets.</p>

<p>One striking example of toolset use comes from Congo, where chimps use a stout stick to bore a tunnel into the ground to reach a termite nest, then modify a plant stem by chewing its tip into a brush to "fish" for termites in the tunnel they've made.</p>

<p>The study found that advanced tool use strongly correlated with populations connected by genetic exchanges over the last 5,000-15,000 years, suggesting such behaviors spread when groups interacted.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Areas where three subspecies overlap exhibited the most complex tool use, highlighting how cross-group connections foster cultural knowledge.</p>

<p>By contrast, simpler behaviors, such as foraging without tools, seemed less tied to migration and likely evolved independently in different regions.</p>

<h3><strong>Foraging efficiently</strong></h3>

<p>Gunasekaram said this mirrors how trading ideas and incremental innovation have been critical to human technological progress, taking us from early abacuses to modern smartphones.</p>

<p>"They've become so complex that one person alone could not reinvent them from scratch," she said.</p>

<p>But unlike humans, chimps have far fewer opportunities to encounter new individuals and ideas -- migrations occur gradually, driven by sexually mature females moving to new communities to avoid inbreeding.</p>

<p>Analyzing ancient genetic flows helped the team overcome one of the biggest challenges in studying the evolution of chimpanzee culture: the limited window of observation, as the species has only been researched scientifically for about a century.</p>

<p>What's more, "Chimpanzee tools are made of sticks and stems, which are all perishable," Gunasekaram explained, making it nearly impossible to trace how their artifacts have evolved over time.</p>

<p>So, will chimps one day rival human ingenuity? Hardly. But given enough time, they could become more efficient foragers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For example, some populations are already more advanced in cracking nuts with hammers and anvils made of stone , and one particularly innovative group has even invented a stabilizer for the anvil, said Gunasekaram.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/nkbbme78_chimpanzees-_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Scientists have long marveled at chimps' ability to pass down intricate behaviours.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/third-world-war-has-begun-says-ukraines-ex-military-commander-valery-zaluzhny-amid-russia-conflict-7077937]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["World War 3 Has Begun": Ukraine Ex-Military Commander Amid Russia Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/third-world-war-has-begun-says-ukraines-ex-military-commander-valery-zaluzhny-amid-russia-conflict-7077937]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:25:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Valery Zaluzhny, former military Commander-in-Chief of Ukraine, believes World War III is underway, adding the direct involvement of Russian allies in the conflict indicates the same.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Valery Zaluzhny, former military Commander-in-Chief of Ukraine, believes World War III is underway, adding the direct involvement of Russian allies in the conflict indicates the same.</p>

<p>"I absolutely believe that in 2024 we can believe that the Third World War has begun," Mr Zaluzhny said during a speech at the Ukrainska Pravda's UP100 award ceremony.</p>

<p>Now serving as Ukraine's envoy to the United Kingdom, Mr Zaluzhny pointed to the direct involvement of Russia's autocratic allies as a significant factor in the war's global expansion.</p>

<p>"Soldiers from North Korea are standing in front of Ukraine. Let's be honest. Already in Ukraine, the Iranian 'Shahedis' are killing civilians absolutely openly, without any shame," he continued, stressing North Korean troops and Chinese weapons were now actively contributing to the war.</p>

<p>Mr Zaluzhny urged Ukraine's allies to take decisive action and prevent the conflict from spreading beyond the country's borders. "It is still possible to stop it here, on the territory of Ukraine. But for some reason, our partners do not want to understand this. It is obvious that Ukraine already has too many enemies," he warned.</p>

<p>His comments came amid heightened tensions, with Moscow reportedly deploying over 10,000 North Korean troops to the Kursk region and utilising Iranian drones and other advanced weaponry against Ukraine.</p>

<p>"Ukraine will survive with technology, but it is not clear whether it can win this battle alone," Mr Zaluzhny said.</p>

<p>His speech also coincided with Russia's use of a hypersonic ballistic missile in Dnipro, an attack that Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky condemned as a severe escalation. "This is a clear and severe escalation in the scale and brutality of this war," Mr Zelensky said.</p>

<p>Valery Zaluzhny has remained a significant voice in Ukraine's military and political discourse despite his dismissal earlier this year. Once celebrated for stopping Russia's initial invasion in February 2022, tensions with President Zelensky led to his ousting. General Oleksandr Syrskyi replaced him, reportedly for his closer alignment with Mr Zelensky's strategies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8bj2ia_ukraine-russia-war-_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-gifts-north-korea-over-70-animals-in-symbolic-gesture-of-support-7077331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lion, Bears, Cockatoos: Vladimir Putin's "Gifts" To Kim Jong's North Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-gifts-north-korea-over-70-animals-in-symbolic-gesture-of-support-7077331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:19:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian President Vladimir Putin has sent more than 70 animals, including an African lion, brown bears, and cockatoos, to Pyongyang, in a gesture showing the growing ties between Russia and North Korea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has sent more than 70 animals, including an African lion, brown bears, and cockatoos, to Pyongyang, in a gesture showing the growing ties between Russia and North Korea. This unusual diplomatic move is a symbol of solidarity and a strengthening relationship between the two nations in recent months.<br />
<br />
The animals, including two yaks, were transferred from the Moscow Zoo to the Pyongyang Central Zoo by air, accompanied by a team of veterinarians. According to the Russian Ministry of Natural Resources and Environment, “This is a gift to Pyongyang from Vladimir Putin.”<br />
<br />
The move follows a series of events that highlight the deepening alliance between Russia and North Korea, including the deployment of North Korean troops to Russia in August, where they assisted Russian forces in the ongoing war against Ukraine.<br />
<br />
Speaking about the gift, Russian Minister of Natural Resources, Alexander Kozlov, said, “Cooperation between Russia and the Democratic People's Republic of Korea is not only about economics, trade and industry. It is also a long list of nature conservation projects. Now, the friendship between the Moscow and Pyongyang Zoos has been added to them.”<br />
<br />
Apart from the yaks, the animals sent to North Korea included an African lion, two brown bears, five white cockatoos, 25 species of pheasants and 40 mandarin ducks, all of which were transferred to the Pyongyang Central Zoo.<br />
<br />
Svetlana Akulova, the General Director of Moscow Zoo, emphasised the animals' relocation is part of a broader effort to strengthen scientific and educational cooperation between the two nations “With the support of the Moscow government, we plan to expand cooperation with North Korean colleagues in matters related to joint scientific and educational activities, as well as the exchange of experience and information on caring for rare species of animals,” Akulova said<br />
<br />
This exchange is not the first of its kind. Earlier this year, in April, Russia sent over 40 animals, including eagles, parrots, and pythons, to the Pyongyang Zoo, according to a report in Russian news agency, TASS. In return, North Korean leader Kim Jong Un sent Putin two rare Pungsan hunting dogs in June 2024, ahead of the Russian President's planned visit to Pyongyang.<br />
<br />
In June, Russia and North Korea renewed a Cold War-era mutual defence pact, and according to the Pentagon, over 10,000 North Korean troops have been deployed to Russia's Kursk region, where fierce fighting with Ukrainian forces has been underway since August, reported <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/21/world/asia/putin-russia-north-korea-animals.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a>.<br />
<br />
North Korea continues to grapple with the severe effects of international sanctions, food shortages, and a humanitarian crisis exacerbated by the Covid-19 pandemic and natural disasters.<br />
<br />
The country's most pressing needs are far from just zoo animals. It faces significant challenges in acquiring essential resources such as foreign currency, oil and advanced weapons expertise critical to its military ambitions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3otp2uto_russia-north-korea-lions-_625x300_22_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The animals sent to North Korea included an African lion and two brown bears.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-what-king-charles-coronation-cost-uk-taxpayers-7077889]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Is What King Charles Coronation Cost UK Taxpayers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-what-king-charles-coronation-cost-uk-taxpayers-7077889]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:18:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles III's coronation last year cost British taxpayers 72 million pounds ($90.7 million), official accounts released late Thursday revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles III's coronation last year cost British taxpayers 72 million pounds ($90.7 million), official accounts released late Thursday revealed.</p>

<p>Critics have argued taxpayer spending on the events was too large and out of touch given the huge demands on stretched public funds and economising in recent years by many Britons.</p>

<p>The figures showed the Department for Culture, Media and Sport (DCMS) spent 50.3 million pounds, while the interior ministry's costs for policing the "once-in-a-generation" event totalled 21.7million pounds.</p>

<p>Charles was formally crowned monarch at Westminster Abbey in a May 2023 ceremony attended by dignitaries from around the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A star-studded concert at Windsor Castle took place the following night.</p>

<p>The disclosure of the final bill, which had been estimated at more than 100 million pounds, is nonetheless set to spark fresh condemnation from anti-monarchists in the UK.</p>

<p>They have been stepping up their criticisms of the royal family and what they say are excessive and unfair financial benefits it receives in straitened times.</p>

<p>The country has been gripped by post-pandemic cost pressures, with decades-high inflation during much of last year, while flatlining economic growth has led to declining living standards.</p>

<p>Sceptics also note that the UK monarch, who receives more public money than European counterparts, is a multimillionaire able to foot more of the institution's bills.</p>

<p>More than half of Britons told pollsters YouGov before the coronation that the government should not be funding it.</p>

<p>The royals this month faced calls for more transparency and reform of their private estates, after an investigation alleged they have been profiting from public bodies while benefiting from major tax exemptions.</p>

<p>In its annual report and accounts, DCMS said it "successfully delivered on the central weekend of His Majesty King Charles III's Coronation, enjoyed by many millions both in the UK and across the globe".</p>

<p>DCMS was the lead government department working with the royal household on the coronation, which it described as a "once-in-a-generation moment".</p>

<p>It added the events "offered a unique opportunity to celebrate and strengthen our national identity and showcase the UK to the world".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/04878pg8_king-charles-coronation_625x300_06_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Charles was formally crowned monarch at Westminster Abbey in a May 2023 ceremony.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-from-firebrands-to-stalwarts-who-is-in-donald-trumps-top-team-7077718]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Firebrands To Stalwarts, Who Is In Donald Trump's Top Team?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-from-firebrands-to-stalwarts-who-is-in-donald-trumps-top-team-7077718]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 22 Nov 2024 11:55:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump is handing top roles in his future administration to a mix of allies, provocateurs, and a few relatively conventional figures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump is handing top roles in his future administration to a mix of allies, provocateurs, and a few relatively conventional figures.</p>

<p>Most positions require Senate approval, which brings added scrutiny.</p>

<p><strong>Here is who Trump has chosen so far:</strong></p>

<h3><strong>Health Secretary: RFK Jr.</strong></h3>

<p>Leading vaccine skeptic Robert F. Kennedy Jr. is the scion of the famous Democratic political dynasty and a conspiracy theorist.</p>

<p>The 70-year-old has promoted the disproven idea that childhood vaccines cause autism. He endorsed Trump after first seeking the Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, TV celebrity Mehmet Oz, a former surgeon, will lead the United States' massive public health insurance programs in his first public office role.</p>

<h3><strong>Attorney General: Pam Bondi&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Pam Bondi, the former state attorney general of Florida from 2011-2019 and staunch Trump ally, is the president-elect's second pick to lead the US Department of Justice.</p>

<p>Bondi, who defended Trump during his first impeachment trial, was nominated after ex-congressman Matt Gaetz withdrew his name amid renewed attention to sexual misconduct allegations.</p>

<h3><strong>'Government Efficiency': Elon Musk</strong></h3>

<p>Tech tycoon Musk, the world's richest person, was tapped to lead a new Department of Government Efficiency, along with wealthy Trump ally Vivek Ramaswamy. Both will supposedly remain private citizens.</p>

<p>Musk says he is targeting $2 trillion in cuts from the federal government's $7 trillion budget, pledging to test legal boundaries to achieve it.</p>

<h3><strong>Secretary of State: Marco Rubio</strong></h3>

<p>Amid the intensifying US power struggle with China, Trump tapped Senator Rubio of Florida, a relatively traditional conservative hawk, as top diplomat.</p>

<p>Born to Cuban immigrants, Rubio is a fervent Israel supporter and longtime critic of Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<h3><strong>Defense Secretary: Pete Hegseth</strong></h3>

<p>Fox News host and former soldier Hegseth was nominated to head the Pentagon, which employs some 2.9 million people, despite a slim CV.</p>

<p>He was investigated for an alleged 2017 sexual assault but no charges were filed.</p>

<h3><strong>Director of National Intelligence: Tulsi Gabbard&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Gabbard, a former Hawaii congresswoman, also switched sides from the Democrats to back Trump's reelection.</p>

<p>She has stood out for endorsing Kremlin justifications about its invasion of Ukraine, and controversially met in 2017 with Syrian leader Bashar al-Assad.</p>

<h3><strong>Homeland Security Secretary: Kristi Noem</strong></h3>

<p>South Dakota Governor Noem became famous for admitting she shot an "untrainable" pet dog, saying it showed her ability to make tough choices.</p>

<p>She would play a key role in Trump's promise to restrict immigration and deport undocumented migrants, along with hard-liners Tom Homan and Stephen Miller, who will be "border czar" and White House deputy chief of staff, respectively.</p>

<h3><strong>Education Secretary: Linda McMahon</strong></h3>

<p>Former wrestling executive Linda McMahon will head a department that Trump has pledged to abolish, vowing to "send education back to the states."</p>

<p>McMahon is a major Trump donor and led the Small Business Administration during his first term.</p>

<h3><strong>Interior Secretary: Doug Burgum</strong></h3>

<p>Burgum, North Dakota's governor, would lead a department that oversees federal lands and natural resources, with additional clout as head of a new National Energy Council aimed at expanding oil and gas production.</p>

<p>Climate group Evergreen Action warned that the billionaire could turn the Interior Department into a "tool for fossil fuel corporations."</p>

<h3><strong>Others</strong></h3>

<p><strong>Energy Secretary</strong>: Fracking magnate Chris Wright</p>

<p><strong>Commerce Secretary</strong>: Wall Street investor Howard Lutnick</p>

<p><strong>Transportation Secretary</strong>: Fox News host and ex-congressman Sean Duffy</p>

<p><strong>Veterans Affairs Secretary</strong>: Iraq war veteran and former congressman Doug Collins</p>

<p><strong>CIA Director</strong>: Former director of national intelligence John Ratcliffe</p>

<p><strong>National Security Advisor</strong>: China hawk Mike Waltz, an Army colonel and Florida congressman</p>

<p><strong>Environmental Protection Agency</strong>: Former New York congressman Lee Zeldin</p>

<p><strong>Federal Communications Commission Chair</strong>: Big Tech critic Brendan Carr</p>

<p><strong>UN Ambassador</strong>: New York congresswoman Elise Stefanik, a pro-Israel stalwart</p>

<p><strong>NATO Ambassador</strong>: Former acting attorney general Matthew Whitaker</p>

<p><strong>Ambassador to Israel</strong>: Ex-Arkansas Governor Mike Huckabee</p>

<p><strong>White House Chief of Staff</strong>: Trump campaign manager Susie Wiles</p>

<p><strong>White House Press Secretary</strong>: Former Trump campaign spokeswoman Karoline Leavitt</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/olssbbvg_donald-trump_625x300_22_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Senate approval is required for most positions in the Trump cabinet.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>