<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 17:05:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-and-a-ceasefire-slip-out-of-focus-as-lebanon-conflict-rages-6707519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Lebanon Conflict Rages, Gaza And A Ceasefire Slip Out Of Focus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gaza-and-a-ceasefire-slip-out-of-focus-as-lebanon-conflict-rages-6707519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 16:41:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinians fear the crisis in Lebanon is diverting the world's attention from Gaza, where Israeli strikes killed dozens more people this week, and diminishing already dim prospects for a ceasefire a year into a war that has shattered the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinians fear the crisis in Lebanon is diverting the world's attention from Gaza, where Israeli strikes killed dozens more people this week, and diminishing already dim prospects for a ceasefire a year into a war that has shattered the enclave.</p>

<p>An escalation in the conflict between Israel and Iran-backed militant group Hezbollah over the past two weeks has led to clashes between Israeli and Hezbollah forces inside Lebanon and fueled fears of a wider regional war.</p>

<p>Both Israel and its Hamas foes in Gaza say the Lebanon conflict could help end the Gaza conflict, but some analysts, officials from mediating countries, and Gazans, are sceptical.</p>

<p>"The focus is on Lebanon, which means the war in Gaza isn't ending anytime soon," Hussam Ali, a 45-year-old Gaza City resident who said his family had been displaced seven times since the conflict between Israel and Hamas began on Oct. 7 last year, told Reuters via a chat app.</p>

<p>When Iran launched ballistic missiles at Israel late on Tuesday, provoking an Israeli promise of a "painful" response, some Gazans welcomed the salvo visible in the skies overhead as a sign Tehran was fighting for their cause.</p>

<p>Sami Abu Zuhri, a senior Hamas official, said prospects for a Gaza ceasefire deal, which would see the release of Israeli hostages held in Gaza and Palestinians jailed by Israel, were distant before the escalation in Lebanon. A regional conflagration could lead to pressure on Israel to strike a deal in Gaza, he said.</p>

<p>But with attention swinging to Lebanon, the war in Gaza risked being prolonged, said Ashraf Abouelhoul, managing editor of state-owned newspaper Al-Ahram in Egypt, which has helped to mediate months of ceasefire negotiations.</p>

<p>"The most dangerous thing isn't that the media attention is going somewhere else, it is the fact that no one in the world is now talking about a deal or a ceasefire, and that frees Israel's hand to continue its military offensive and plans in Gaza," he said.</p>

<p><strong>STALLED TALKS</strong></p>

<p>Inside Gaza there has been no sign of a let-up in Israel's offensive against Hamas. On Thursday, local medics reported at least 99 Palestinian deaths in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>Egypt, which has been alarmed by the Israeli offensive on the other side of its border with Gaza and has lost billions of dollars in Suez Canal revenues during the war, is frustrated that its mediation efforts have failed to secure a truce.</p>

<p>US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told reporters that the US remained focused on securing a ceasefire though Hamas had for weeks "refused to engage".</p>

<p>Hamas officials and Western diplomats said in August that negotiations had stalled due to new Israeli demands to keep troops in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Whereas Israel has been saying since Oct. 7 that military force and putting pressure on Hamas and Hezbollah will help to bring the hostages home we have seen that the exact opposite is true," said Nomi Bar-Yaacov, an expert on Middle East diplomacy at London-based think-tank Chatham House.</p>

<p>Israel's escalated campaign against Hezbollah "is putting the ceasefire in Gaza on the back burner, given that the focus is now on trying to dismantle as much of Hezbollah's military arsenal as possible," she said.</p>

<p>An official briefed on the Gaza ceasefire talks told Reuters nothing would happen until after the US presidential election on Nov. 5, "because nobody can effectively pressure (Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin) Netanyahu, which is the key impediment to a Gaza ceasefire deal".</p>

<p>The official said that during UN General Assembly meetings last week Hezbollah wanted a proposal for a 21-day ceasefire with Israel to be linked to a ceasefire deal in Gaza, but Israel rejected this and the plan was dropped. Top Israeli officials publicly dismissed the idea of a quick ceasefire with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel's killing of Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah last week complicated chances for mediation, two Egyptian security sources said. Egypt's efforts became limited to containing any further escalation, the sources said.</p>

<p><strong>ROCKETS</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah began firing rockets into Israel at the start of the Gaza war in support of Hamas, causing the evacuation of tens of thousands of residents whom Israel says need to return home.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, nearly 1,900 people have been killed and more than 9,000 wounded in Lebanon in nearly a year of cross-border fighting, with most of the deaths occurring in the past two weeks, according to Lebanese government statistics.</p>

<p>More than a million Lebanese have been forced to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The casualty figures are still a fraction of those in Gaza, where the health ministry says at least 41,788 Palestinians have been killed and 96,794 wounded since Oct. 7 last year.</p>

<p>The Gaza war began after Hamas led a shock incursion into Israel, killing about 1,200 people and taking more than 250 hostage, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>"We feel for the people of Lebanon and we don't want them to go through the devastation and starvation we are enduring," said Ghada, a 50-year-old mother of five living in a tent in the central Gaza city of Deir Al-Balah, where a million people are sheltering.</p>

<p>"I am afraid the world has become less interested in what happens to us here."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k8ri1jd8_gaza-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-in-lahore-swallows-3-vehicles-causes-traffic-disruptions-6707460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive Sinkhole In Lahore Swallows 3 Vehicles, Causes Traffic Disruptions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-sinkhole-in-lahore-swallows-3-vehicles-causes-traffic-disruptions-6707460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 16:34:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pictures and videos of the incident have gone viral on social media, showing locals helping the trapped commuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive sinkhole suddenly appeared on a main road in Johar Town, Lahore, swallowing three vehicles - a car and two motorcycles - and causing major traffic disruptions. Two people, who were trapped inside the car when the sinkhole suddenly formed, sustained injuries but were rescued with the help of nearby residents, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.geo.tv/latest/566765-watch-massive-lahore-sinkhole-swallows-three-vehicles">Geo News</a></em> reported. They were taken to a hospital. According to the Lahore Development Authority (LDA), the sinkhole was caused by an underground sewer line leakage, which weakened the road over time.</p>

<p>Pictures and<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/ShirazHassan/status/1840764018845245451/video/1"> videos </a>of the incident have gone viral on social media, showing locals helping the trapped commuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="cy">Sinkhole near Johar town, Lahore. <a href="https://t.co/2yVGB5dKlX">pic.twitter.com/2yVGB5dKlX</a></p>
— Basit Alvi (@bpk69) <a href="https://twitter.com/bpk69/status/1840809891466002665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The incident prompted swift action from the Chief Traffic Officer (CTO) of Lahore, who diverted traffic from the affected area, leading to increased congestion on alternative routes. A traffic response unit was also deployed to mitigate the situation.</p>

<p>This is not an isolated incident, as Johar Town has experienced multiple sinkholes in recent months, causing injuries and damage. Notably, the area's infrastructure has been severely impacted by record-breaking rains in August, damaging drainage systems and roads, particularly in Khayaban-i-Firdausi. Residents and commuters are urging authorities to address the recurring infrastructure issues and improve road safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“The road has become extremely dangerous for motorists, as sinkholes can emerge at any time, putting lives at risk. Look at this incident – the car fell in, injuring the driver and his friend,” a witness told&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1862231/three-injured-as-car-bike-fall-into-sinkhole" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Dawn</a>.</em></p>

<p>A sinkhole is a depression or hole in the ground that forms when a layer of soil or rock is removed or collapses, often suddenly and without warning. This phenomenon can occur due to various natural or human-induced reasons, including karst terrain, groundwater, weathering, and earthquakes, as well as mining, drilling, construction, and water leakage. Sinkholes can vary greatly in size, from small depressions to massive craters, and can extend hundreds of feet in depth, posing significant risks to structures, infrastructure, and human life.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q2a15ut_-sinkhole-in-lahore_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is not an isolated incident as Johar Town has experienced multiple sinkholes in recent months]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-arrested-for-filming-women-minors-in-mall-restroom-using-hidden-camera-6707005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Arrested For Filming Women In Mall Restroom Using Hidden Camera]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-arrested-for-filming-women-minors-in-mall-restroom-using-hidden-camera-6707005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:39:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Andy Cardenas, the teenager, has been charged with invasion of privacy for placing a hidden camera in a mall restroom]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US teenager has been arrested on charges of using a hidden camera in a mall toilet to record numerous women and at least four minors. The incident occurred at the Newport Centre Mall in Jersey City, where officials reported that the 18-year-old, Andy Cardenas, now faced a charge of invasion of privacy.</p>

<p>“On Friday, August 9, 2024, an adult female discovered a black device while using the family restroom located on the first floor of JC Penney,” the Hudson County prosecutor's office said in a press release.</p>

<p>Upon discovering the concealed device, she promptly handed it to the authorities, leading to an investigation by the Hudson County prosecutor's office.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESS RELEASE: Man Charged After Recording Device Found in Mall Restroom <a href="https://t.co/KnWuarPLvP">pic.twitter.com/KnWuarPLvP</a></p>
— ProsecutorSuarezHCPO (@HCPOProsecutor) <a href="https://twitter.com/HCPOProsecutor/status/1841539307128992169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to a report by a <a href="https://www.nj.com/hudson/2024/10/dozens-of-women-and-4-girls-filmed-by-hidden-camera-inside-bathroom-at-nj-mall-teen-is-arrested.html">local news outlet</a>, authorities reviewed the footage obtained through a communications data warrant and discovered “approximately 35 videos of adult women who were exposed using the restroom, approximately four videos of female minors who were exposed using the restroom, and one video of a male and woman in the restroom together engaging in sexual acts,” as stated in Cardenas' criminal complaint.</p>

<p>Crucially, the footage also captured a male figure — later identified as Cardenas — setting up the hidden camera inside the JC Penney toilet. This led to his identification and arrest.</p>

<p>Authorities are still piecing together the timeline of the suspect's activities, as the footage lacks any dates or timestamps. They are also uncertain about the locations where all the videos were filmed. To identify more potential victims, the prosecutor's office has released images of four unrecognised restrooms.</p>

<p>The Hudson County prosecutor's office said, “Multiple electronic/digital files were recovered from the recording device, which contained images from several unidentified restrooms. The Special Victims Unit is seeking the public's help identifying the location of the restrooms in the attached photos. It is not yet known how long the recording device was being utilised.”<br />
<br />
Cardenas was arrested on October 1 and released on a summons pending his first court appearance, which is tentatively scheduled for October 22, stated the press release.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8qhrb7t8_us-teen-_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Andy Cardenas, 18, was arrested and charged with one count of invasion of privacy]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israeli-man-who-lost-wife-son-in-october-7-attack-pain-doesnt-subside-6706986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Pain Doesn't Subside": Israeli Man Who Lost Wife, Son In October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israeli-man-who-lost-wife-son-in-october-7-attack-pain-doesnt-subside-6706986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:36:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Avida Bachar runs his hands across the steel surface of a door that is pierced with bullet holes and is still stained by his son Carmel's]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Avida Bachar runs his hands across the steel surface of a door that is pierced with bullet holes and is still stained by his son Carmel's blood, nearly a year after the 15-year-old was killed during Hamas' October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>Bachar also lost his wife Dana that day, when the operatives stormed through their home at Kibbutz Be'eri, setting fire to houses and killing or kidnapping men, women and children. In all, the kibbutz, a tight-knit community just three miles (five km) from Gaza, lost about a tenth of its roughly 1,000 residents.</p>

<p>Bachar's family, like most others on the kibbutz, took shelter in the safe room when Hamas started firing rockets from Gaza into Israel that morning.</p>

<p>But kibbutz safe rooms were built to protect residents against rockets - not a ground assault by dozens of heavily armed men who shot through the steel door, threw grenades through the window and set Bachar's home ablaze.</p>

<p>"I miss them endlessly," 51-year-old Bachar said of his wife and son. "(The pain) doesn't fade or subside. It's strong, all the time."</p>

<p>But Bachar, who lost a leg in the attack, remains hopeful that Kibbutz Be'eri can still heal in time. He is sustained in his optimism by his daughter Hadar, now 14, who was wounded in the attack.</p>

<p>"Hadar is okay. Hadar is 10 times stronger than me. Kids see the here and now. I imagine Hadar getting married in a few years without her mother by her side and I fall apart," he added.</p>

<p>Bachar returned to Be'eri after a six-month hospitalisation and is now busy overseeing the jojoba harvest and getting used to his prosthetic leg. "In two weeks we start to harvest the avocado," he said, donning an 'I Love Be'eri' T-shirt.</p>

<p><strong>SAFE HAVEN</strong></p>

<p>Be'eri was established in 1946 with the aim of creating a collective, egalitarian farming community. Its main source of income these days is its print shop, which was back up and running just weeks after the Hamas attack.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of Oct. 7, most of its surviving residents were evacuated to a hotel by the Dead Sea. A few have now gone back to live on the kibbutz, where many houses still stand damaged by the grenades and gunfire, ransacked, or burnt.</p>

<p>"This place will flourish again and we will recover with it. If I fast-forward three or four years ahead, I have no doubt we will be in a better place," said Bachar.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, his daughter Hadar is staying with her aunt, until Bachar can join her, at the temporary residence being built for the community in Hatzerim, a kibbutz in the Negev desert, around 18 miles (29 km) away.</p>

<p>Close to 70% of Kibbutz Be'eri's surviving population, mostly families, have moved to Hatzerim since the start of the school year in September, said Iftah Celniker, Be'eri's community director.</p>

<p>Keeping the community together while uprooted has been their main challenge, said Celniker. But the ties between the kibbutz members remain strong while the houses in Be'eri are being torn down and rebuilt.</p>

<p>It could take many months before they all go back to Be'eri. "It will take time not only to build Be'eri but to build the confidence of it being a safe haven," said Celniker.</p>

<p>Hamas operatives killed 1,200 people and took some 250 hostages in their Oct. 7 rampage, according to Israeli tallies, prompting an Israeli military offensive in which Gaza health officials say more than 41,000 Palestinians have been killed.</p>

<p><strong>'OUR PLACE TO FIGHT FOR'</strong></p>

<p>Anger still smoulders among Be'eri residents towards the Israeli army for failing to protect their kibbutz and towards the government, which many say is not doing enough to bring back the 101 hostages still held in Gaza, at least half of whom are believed to be still alive. The operatives took 10 hostages from Be'eri, of whom at least three are thought to be still alive.</p>

<p>One of the killed hostages from Be'eri is Carmel Gat, 40, whose body was found in a Hamas tunnel in southern Gaza with five other hostages. The gunmen killed the six people when they spotted Israeli soldiers in the vicinity, authorities said.</p>

<p>Gat had survived in captivity until the end of August. Hostages who had been with her and were released during a brief November truce said she had helped them get through their time in captivity with yoga and meditation.</p>

<p>Gat's mother Kinneret was killed by Hamas on Oct. 7 in the kibbutz. Her sister-in-law was kidnapped and released in November.</p>

<p>A banner with a photo of a smiling Carmel hangs over the wreckage of the family home at Be'eri, as her younger brother Or sifts through the family belongings in the ravaged house.</p>

<p>Outside, a pomegranate hangs off a tree with no one to pick it. The fruit is a traditional food of the Jewish new year which begins on Thursday. Despite his family's ordeal, Or can still see a future in which he one day raises a family in Be'eri.</p>

<p>"Our safety will never be the same again but this is the place for all of our life, for the happiest moments and the horrible moments - this is our place to live in, our place to fight for," Or Gat said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l6ut6kf8_avida-bachar-reuters_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Avida Bachar was injured following a deadly attack by Hamas gunmen from Gaza.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/panic-after-bank-of-america-customers-see-zero-balance-in-their-accounts-heres-what-happened-6706966]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bank Of America Customers See Zero Balance In Their Accounts. What Happened]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/panic-after-bank-of-america-customers-see-zero-balance-in-their-accounts-heres-what-happened-6706966]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:32:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some users who managed to access their accounts found their balances displayed as $0, sparking widespread alarm and concern.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of Bank of America customers encountered difficulties accessing their online accounts on Wednesday afternoon, as the bank experienced a large-scale outage. Customers took to social media to report issues, stating they were unable to view their account balances. Even more concerning, some users who managed to access their accounts found their balances displayed as $0, sparking widespread alarm and concern.</p>

<p>Reports of problems spiked around 12:45 pm ET on Downdetector, a platform that tracks outages. Complains about the issue flooded in from major cities like New York, Los Angeles, San Francisco, Seattle, Dallas, Phoenix, Houston, and Chicago, according to Downdetector's outage map</p>

<p>Affected customers received error messages stating "accounts temporarily unavailable" or "some accounts and balances are temporarily unavailable".&nbsp;For many, a ''Connection Error'' message popped up while trying to log into the banking app. The message said it was ''unable to complete your request'' and asked the user to ''try again later.''</p>

<p>Customers affected by the Bank of America outage flocked to social media platforms, including X (formerly Twitter) and Reddit, to share their experiences and seek confirmation that others were facing similar issues.&nbsp;Frustrated customers also expressed challenges in reaching Bank of America's customer service, citing long wait times, unsuccessful attempts to contact representatives, and automated messages with no resolution.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/BankofAmerica?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BankofAmerica</a> what's going on???? Why isn't anyone talking about their accounts showing a zero balance!!!! <a href="https://t.co/09Z3jsOMdg">pic.twitter.com/09Z3jsOMdg</a></p>
— Skeptical Optimistic (@MiiSSMaryy) <a href="https://twitter.com/MiiSSMaryy/status/1841529451227598872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hey Bank of America.....GIVE ME MY MONEY BACK!<br />
I need to buy food &amp; pay bills <a href="https://t.co/MVncXwdqPA">pic.twitter.com/MVncXwdqPA</a></p>
— Elihu Who (@ElihuWho) <a href="https://twitter.com/ElihuWho/status/1841611437321711618?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I'm having a heart attack this morning thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/BankofAmerica?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@BankofAmerica</a> - they REALLY need to be addressing this <a href="https://t.co/jXQU1M2s19">pic.twitter.com/jXQU1M2s19</a></p>
— Jessica (Pixels) (@GermaricanMix) <a href="https://twitter.com/GermaricanMix/status/1841537995637399711?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p data-analytics-observe="off" data-article-gutter="true" data-component-name="paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="cms.cnn.com/_components/paragraph/instances/cm1s6po720005356mu4m9zosl@published"></p>

<p data-analytics-observe="off" data-article-gutter="true" data-component-name="paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="cms.cnn.com/_components/paragraph/instances/cm1s6po720005356mu4m9zosl@published">In a statement to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/02/business/bank-of-america-outage/index.html" rel="nofollow, noindex">CNN</a></em>, Bank of America acknowledged that “some clients are experiencing an issue accessing their accounts and balance information today.”</p>

<p data-analytics-observe="off" data-article-gutter="true" data-component-name="paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="cms.cnn.com/_components/paragraph/instances/cm1schupm0001356kg9mjx284@published">''These issues are being addressed and have largely been resolved. We apologize for any inconvenience,'' the bank added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Despite the bank's claims of resolution, many customers continued to report issues, with some even being barred from entering physical Bank of America locations.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3d2eg4fg_bank-of-america_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Customers affected by the Bank of America outage flocked to social media platforms]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-government-chief-2-senior-leaders-killed-in-strike-says-israel-6706854]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Says Hamas Government Chief, 2 Top Leaders Eliminated In Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-government-chief-2-senior-leaders-killed-in-strike-says-israel-6706854]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:17:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Thursday said a strike three months ago killed three senior Hamas leaders in Gaza, where the army has been battling the Palestinian operatives for nearly a year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military on Thursday said a strike three months ago killed three senior Hamas leaders in Gaza, where the army has been battling the Palestinian operatives for nearly a year.</p>

<p>The military said the strike killed Rawhi Mushtaha, the head of the Hamas government in the Gaza Strip, and Sameh al-Siraj, who held the security portfolio for Hamas's political bureau, and Sami Oudeh, a commander.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Approximately 3 months ago, in a joint IDF and ISA strike in Gaza, the following terrorists were eliminated:<br />
<br />
?Rawhi Mushtaha, the Head of the Hamas government in Gaza<br />
?Sameh al-Siraj, who held the security portfolio on Hamas' political bureau and Hamas' Labor Committee<br />
?Sami… <a href="https://t.co/6xpH6tOOot">pic.twitter.com/6xpH6tOOot</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1841767112735383665?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Mushtaha was one of Hamas' most senior operatives and had a direct impact on decisions relating to Hamas' force deployment," said the military in a statement.</p>

<p>The military called Mushtaha the "right-hand man" to Hamas's top leader Yahya Sinwar.</p>

<p>In 2015, the US State Department had designated Mushtaha as a "specially designated global terrorist".</p>

<p>The European Council on Foreign Relations described Mushtaha as a member of Hamas's Gaza politburo who also oversaw its financial affairs.</p>

<p>The ECFR said Siraj was a politburo member, while Oudeh was said to be the leader of the group's internal security agency.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign to wipe out Hamas is believed to have severely weakened the group by killing several of its leaders and thousands of fighters, while also reducing swaths of the territory it rules to rubble.</p>

<p>The Gaza war was sparked by Hamas's October 7 attack, which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,788 people in Gaza, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>"Mushtaha was one of Hamas' most senior operatives and had a direct impact on decisions relating to Hamas' force deployment," said the military in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nqr2m52_hamas-leaders_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The military called Mushtaha the "right-hand man" to Hamas's top leader Yahya Sinwar. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-signs-into-new-law-bill-despite-warnings-eu-thinks-its-queerphobic-6706846]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Georgia Signs Into New Law Bill Despite Warnings, EU Thinks Its Queerphobic]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-signs-into-new-law-bill-despite-warnings-eu-thinks-its-queerphobic-6706846]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:16:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The speaker of Georgia's parliament on Thursday signed into law a bill similar to Russian legislation that curbs the rights of LGBTQ people, despite warnings from the EU.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The speaker of Georgia's parliament on Thursday signed into law a bill similar to Russian legislation that curbs the rights of LGBTQ people, despite warnings from the EU.</p>

<p>The move came a day after Georgia's pro-Western president Salome Zurabishvili -- at loggerheads with the ruling Georgian Dream party -- refused to sign the bill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bill is similar to Moscow's "gay propaganda" law, which also bans gender reassignment and nullifies same-sex marriages performed abroad or on Georgian territory.</p>

<p>"In conformity with the constitution, I signed today the law 'on family values and the protection of minors', which Salome Zurabishvili didn't sign," speaker Shalva Papuashvili said on Facebook.</p>

<p>The ruling Georgian Dream pushed the bill through parliament last month, a vote boycotted by the opposition and which has fuelled tensions ahead of crucial October 26 parliamentary elections.</p>

<p>Papuashvili said the measure "is based on common sense, historical experience and centuries-old Christian, Georgian, and European values, rather than on changeable ideas and ideologies".</p>

<p>He claimed that the "law protects the rights of all citizens".</p>

<p>But rights group and Western countries have said that it is discriminatory and creates a dangerous environment for LGBTQ people.</p>

<p>Last month, a well-known Georgian transgender woman was stabbed to death, an attack that came during the push for the law.</p>

<p>The bill also comes after Tbilisi's recent adoption of an anti-NGO "foreign influence law", which triggered weeks of mass anti-government protests and Western condemnation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Critics accuse the ruling Georgian Dream party of moving closer into the Kremlin's orbit and jeopardising Georgia's bid for EU membership.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/a5cso9e8_-lgbtq_625x300_22_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Western countries have said that it creates a dangerous environment for LGBTQ people. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-new-pm-to-introduce-happiness-index-in-first-parliamentary-speech-6706765]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan's New PM To Introduce Happiness Index In First Parliamentary Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japans-new-pm-to-introduce-happiness-index-in-first-parliamentary-speech-6706765]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 15:02:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba will propose a new happiness index during his first parliamentary policy speech on Friday, local media have reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba will propose a new happiness index during his first parliamentary policy speech on Friday, local media have reported.</p>

<p>The index, formulated by the public and private sectors, is expected to be proposed alongside Ishiba's plans for the economy and tackling the country's shrinking population.</p>

<p>Ishiba, 67, became prime minister on Tuesday after winning a tightly contested ruling party leadership vote last week.</p>

<p>He has said he intends to call a snap election for October 27 to shore up his mandate for policies, such as increased support for regional governments and low-income households.</p>

<p>It is unclear how his speech will address foreign policy matters, but public broadcaster NHK and other outlets reported on Thursday that Ishiba will likely renew vows to fight inflation and announce a plan for a new monetary stimulus package.</p>

<p>The yen surged last Friday after the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) voted Ishiba leader, because he had broadly backed the Bank of Japan's exit from its ultra-loose policies.</p>

<p>But Ishiba told reporters late Wednesday that he did not think the environment was right for further interest rate hikes, sending the Japanese currency south again.</p>

<p>The premier will also announce plans to increase Japan's average minimum wage to 1,500 yen ($10.22) by 2030, from the current 1,055 yen, local media reported.</p>

<p>These attempts to shore up per-capita GDP in the world's number-four economy are part of his vision to raise the public's level of happiness, they said.</p>

<p>He is also expected to call the rapidly ageing population a "silent crisis" that "affects the core of our nation", according to NHK.</p>

<p>Ishiba will reportedly discuss plans to launch a new disaster management ministry in the earthquake and flood-prone country, as well as stressing the importance of nuclear energy.</p>

<p>Nuclear power is a divisive topic in Japan, supported by the business lobby but with the public still wary after the 2011 tsunami-triggered catastrophe in Fukushima.</p>

<p>Takahide Kiuchi, executive economist at Nomura Research Institute and a former Bank of Japan board member, said Ishiba's speech would "likely to be made with a strong awareness of the upcoming general election".</p>

<p>"It appears that the Ishiba government is prioritising winning the election and consolidating its base of power," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/et9st8c8_shigeru-ishiba_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shigeru Ishiba, 67, became Japan's prime minister on Tuesday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-secretly-funded-right-wing-group-long-before-donald-trump-endorsement-sources-6706711]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk Secretly Funded Right-Wing Group Long Before Trump Endorsement: Sources]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-secretly-funded-right-wing-group-long-before-donald-trump-endorsement-sources-6706711]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:55:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk secretly funded a conservative political group in recent years, according to four people familiar with his donations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk secretly funded a conservative political group in recent years, according to four people familiar with his donations, illustrating quiet financial support for right-wing causes even before the billionaire entrepreneur in July endorsed former President Donald Trump's bid for re-election.</p>

<p>Two of the people familiar with the donations told Reuters that Musk's contributions to the organization, Building America's Future, had started by 2022. One of those people and a third source said the donations amounted to millions of dollars, significantly boosting a group whose advertisements and social media campaigns have criticized the Biden administration and progressive political platforms of the sort that Musk himself has increasingly denounced.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Reuters was unable to determine a precise amount and timeline for the contributions or identify documentation linking the organization's finances to Musk. Earlier on Wednesday, The Wall Street Journal reported that Musk had financed other pro-Republican groups.</p>

<p>Musk didn't respond to emails seeking comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Building America's Future didn't respond, either.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The magnate behind ventures including carmaker Tesla, space contractor SpaceX and the social media platform X, Musk for many years was careful to avoid suggestions that he favoured either major U.S. political party. As recently as March, months before he publicly backed Trump and announced plans to finance a political action committee to work against Democrats, he wrote on social media: "Just to be super clear, I am not donating money to either candidate for US President."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Donations to Building America's Future, however, would show he was already using his vast resources to fund right-wing causes. As a non-profit 501(c)(4) group, the organization isn't required by federal law to disclose its financial backers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although such groups aren't allowed to finance candidates' political campaigns, they can espouse political causes. As such, they are commonly referred to as "dark money" groups - used by political operatives, Democrats and Republicans alike, to hide the financial origins of influence campaigns.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Musk's case, the four people familiar with his donations told Reuters, the contributions to Building America's Future remained closely guarded. Three of the people were briefed on the donations by executives at or linked to the organization and the fourth was consulted on the matter by a Musk aide.&nbsp;</p>

<p>All spoke with Reuters on the condition that they not be identified by name.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>"STOP CACKLING KAMALA"</strong></h3>

<p>Revenues at Building America's Future, according to government data, climbed from some $11 million in 2021 to about $53 million in 2022, the year two of the people said Musk had already started his donations. The figures are the most recent available from the Internal Revenue Service, which requires tax-exempt organizations to disclose their revenues. &nbsp;</p>

<p>It's unclear whether Musk still funds the organization or how much in total he may have donated.</p>

<p>Over the last two years, Building America's Future has attacked the Biden administration on a host of topics, including illegal immigration, an issue that Musk frequently comments on. One recent anti-immigration video posted online by the group claims that Vice President Kamala Harris, Trump's opponent in the November election, "led the invasion" of migrants across the Mexican border and has always "put illegals first."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Building America's Future also recently launched a $10 million advertising campaign meant to undermine Black support for Harris, according to an August report by NBC News. The campaign criticizes the White House's effort to ban menthol cigarettes. Research shows that cigarettes, long marketed to African Americans, are even more dangerous to smokers' health than regular tobacco.</p>

<p>"Instead of focusing on important issues," one video says, "Biden's priority is banning menthol cigarettes," trying to tell adults "what they can and cannot do."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk's political leanings have moved rightward in recent years.</p>

<p>Although he has said he has voted for Democratic presidential candidates including Biden and Hillary Clinton, Musk became an outspoken critic of the current administration, claiming the White House gave a "very cold shoulder" to Tesla and SpaceX. A White House spokesperson declined to comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk, ranked by Forbes as the world's richest individual, has also become a fierce critic of identity politics. He has used his frequent posts on X to propagate demonstrably false conspiracy theories about Jewish people, immigrants and looming "civil war" in Britain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After Musk's recent embrace of Trump, the former president said if elected he would put Musk in charge of a government efficiency commission.&nbsp;</p>

<p>America PAC, a political action committee Musk recently said he is financing, as of this week has spent $77 million on a get-out-the-vote campaign to encourage infrequent voters to support Trump, according to federal electoral filings. Musk's exact financial contribution to America PAC is unclear.</p>

<p>In addition to their Musk link, America PAC and Building America's Future overlap in terms of personnel, according to electoral filings and people familiar with the operations of both groups. One of those people is Generra Peck, a former campaign manager for Florida Governor Ron DeSantis and now one of the key leaders at America PAC. Peck didn't respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Like Building America's Future, America PAC's messaging has featured aggressive personal criticisms of Harris. Flyers distributed by the group in Arizona, reviewed by Reuters, feature photos of the vice president laughing and read: "stop cackling Kamala."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d89c4me8_elon-musk-donald-trump-_625x300_20_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's political leanings have moved rightward in recent years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/annular-solar-eclipses-ring-of-fire-seen-in-easter-island-and-patagonia-6706631]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Annular Solar Eclipse's 'Ring of Fire' Seen In Easter Island And Patagonia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/annular-solar-eclipses-ring-of-fire-seen-in-easter-island-and-patagonia-6706631]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:41:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The moon blotted out most of the sun across the Pacific Ocean on Wednesday afternoon, giving just a few specks of land an impressive annular "ring of fire" eclipse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The moon blotted out most of the sun across the Pacific Ocean on Wednesday afternoon, giving just a few specks of land an impressive annular "ring of fire" eclipse.</p>

<p>Only Easter Island and a small area near the southern tip of Chile and Argentina witnessed an annular eclipse, lasting just a few minutes.</p>

<p>"The ring of fire is a once-in-a-lifetime experience," Rocio Garcia, a tourist on Easter Island told Reuters on Tuesday. "Especially here in Rapa Nui with the Moai in the background it will be spectacular."</p>

<p>An annular eclipse happens when the moon is too far away from Earth to completely blot out the sun, like a total eclipse, creating a dark silhouette surrounded by a bright ring of light called an antumbra, or more casually, a "ring of fire".</p>

<p>As the sun darkened over the island on Wednesday afternoon, people gathered outdoors, chanted, played music, and wore special eyewear to catch a glimpse of the eclipse.</p>

<p>"I got excited when people were shouting. Everybody's fervor made it more exciting," said Alejandra Astudillo, an Easter Island resident.</p>

<p>An estimated 175,000 people live in the path of the eclipse's annularity, giving far-flung residents and eclipse-chasing tourists a stunning view.</p>

<p>"It was an extraordinary phenomenon that's not often seen," said Esteban Sanchez in Las Horquetas, Argentina, one of the few towns in the eclipse's direct path. "This is the first time I've seen that and it was really good."</p>

<p>The southern half of South America, along with parts of Antarctica and Hawaii, saw a partial eclipse according to a map plotted out by NASA.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/hii8n5ng_ring-of-fire-annual-solar-eclipse_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An annular eclipse happens when the moon is too far away from Earth to completely blot out the sun.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/you-will-never-be-my-president-indian-users-reply-to-donald-trump-goes-viral-6706543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You Will Never Be My President": Indian User's Reply to Trump Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/you-will-never-be-my-president-indian-users-reply-to-donald-trump-goes-viral-6706543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:30:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A month ahead of the US election, with campaigning at a peak, former President Donald Trump's automated messages have sparked a viral reaction with an Indian user receiving an update today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A month ahead of the US election, with campaigning at a peak, former President Donald Trump's automated messages have sparked a viral reaction with an Indian user receiving an update today.</p>

<p>The tweet, from the former President's X (formerly Twitter) handle, was directed at Roshan Rai, who describes himself as an Indian first and "cricketoholic" in his bio.</p>

<p>"I'll send you IMPORTANT ELECTION UPDATES for North Carolina. Make sure you are ready to VOTE FOR DONALD J. TRUMP by November 5th. Reply #stop to opt-out" it read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/RoshanKrRaii?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RoshanKrRaii</a><br />
<br />
I'll send you IMPORTANT ELECTION UPDATES for North Carolina. Make sure you are ready to VOTE FOR DONALD J. TRUMP by November 5th.<br />
<br />
Reply <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/stop?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#stop</a> to opt-out.</p>
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1841721180970983844?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>To this, Roshan Rai quipped, "Thanks, but you will never be my President. Kamala Harris will never be my President either. &nbsp;Actually, I am from India."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Thanks, but you will never be my President.<br />
<br />
Kamala Harris will never be my President either.<br />
<br />
Actually I am from India ? <a href="https://t.co/gKbkNYa18P">https://t.co/gKbkNYa18P</a></p>
— Roshan Rai (@RoshanKrRaii) <a href="https://twitter.com/RoshanKrRaii/status/1841721658496741760?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Rai's retort has drawn the attention of several Internet users. It also shows the unexpected reach of Trump's automated messaging system beyond American borders, thereby highlighting the impact of Trump's social media strategy, which has been a hallmark of his political approach since 2015.</p>

<p>The X exchange raises questions about the appropriateness of such outreach to international audiences. A study by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w24631">National Bureau of Economic Research</a> in 2018, indicated that bots played a critical role in swaying votes during the 2016 elections and Twitter bots may have boosted Donald Trump's votes by a good 3.23%.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As Trump gears up for the upcoming election next month after having survived not one, but two assassination attempts, his reliance on social media continues to draw both criticism and amusement from users worldwide. Earlier this year, in August, Trump had taken to social media to express his approval for pop star Taylor Swift's faux endorsement of himself, using AI-generated images. However, this soon turned into an &nbsp;"I HATE TAYLOR SWIFT" post on social media following Swift's actual endorsement of Trump's rival Kamala Harris.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gfbm3a8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The use of automated messages is not new for Donald Trump. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-husband-douglas-emhoff-slapped-ex-girlfriend-for-flirting-with-another-man-report-6706449]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris' Husband Slapped Ex Girlfriend For Flirting With Another Man: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-husband-douglas-emhoff-slapped-ex-girlfriend-for-flirting-with-another-man-report-6706449]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:12:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The report said Kamala Harris' husband Douglas Emhoff allegedly struck the woman, a New York attorney, in the face while waiting in a valet line in 2012.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Months after US Vice President Kamala Harris' husband Douglas Emhoff admitted to having an extra-marital affair during his first marriage, a report has claimed that he allegedly slapped his ex-girlfriend for "flirting" with a valet worker.</p>

<p>The report, published by a British tabloid on Wednesday, said that Second Gentleman allegedly struck the woman, a New York attorney, in the face while waiting in a valet line late at night after the Cannes Film Festival event in France in May 2012.</p>

<p>The report, citing the woman's friends, said the woman had been dating Emhoff, a lawyer, for three months when the incident took place.</p>

<p>Earlier in August, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-husband-admits-to-cheating-on-1st-wife-with-childs-teacher-6258995" target="_blank">Emhoff</a>, 59, acknowledged that he had an affair during his first marriage (with Kerstin) after the alleged details of the relationship were published by a British tabloid.</p>

<p>"During my first marriage, Kerstin and I went through some tough times on account of my actions. I took responsibility, and in the years since, we worked through things as a family and have come out stronger on the other side," Emhoff said in a statement provided exclusively to CNN.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/momla-and-dougie-kamala-harris-husband-shares-their-love-story-6383149" target="_blank">Kamala Harris' Husband Shares Their Love Story</a></strong></p>

<p>His acknowledgment came after a British tabloid reported that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-kamala-harris-husband-says-hes-never-won-a-debate-against-his-wife-6509524" target="_blank">Emhoff</a> had an affair with a teacher who worked at a school his children attended and that resulted in the end of his first marriage.</p>

<p>It was reported that the woman became pregnant and that, according to a close friend, she "did not keep the child."</p>

<p>Emhoff and Kerstin ended their marriage in 2009 and have two children - Cole and Ella.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-1-month-to-go-6704245" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a>, who married Emhoff in 2014, was aware of the affair before their marriage.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/595i2aag_doug-emhoff-kamala-harris_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident occured in 2012, two years before Kamala Harris married Douglas Emhoff]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-conditions-of-irans-nuclear-facilities-amid-israel-conflict-6706415]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Conditions Of Iran's Nuclear Facilities Amid Israel Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-conditions-of-irans-nuclear-facilities-amid-israel-conflict-6706415]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 14:09:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday, there is speculation that Israel could strike Iran's nuclear facilities as it has long threatened to do.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday, there is speculation that Israel could strike Iran's nuclear facilities as it has long threatened to do.</p>

<p>Below are some of Iran's main nuclear facilities.</p>

<h3><strong>URANIUM ENRICHMENT AT ITS HEART</strong></h3>

<p>Iran's nuclear programme is spread over many locations. While the threat of Israeli airstrikes has loomed for decades, only some of the sites have been built underground.</p>

<p>The United States and the UN nuclear watchdog believe Iran had a coordinated, secret nuclear weapons programme that it halted in 2003. The Islamic Republic denies ever having had one or planning to have one.</p>

<p>Iran agreed to restrictions on its nuclear activities in exchange for relief from international sanctions under a 2015 deal with world powers. That pact fell apart after then-President Donald Trump pulled out of the United States in 2018 and Iran started abandoning the restrictions the next year.</p>

<p>Iran has been expanding its uranium enrichment programme ever since, reducing the so-called "breakout time" it would need to produce enough weapons-grade uranium for a nuclear bomb to a matter of weeks from at least a year under the 2015 accord.</p>

<p>Actually making a bomb with that material would take longer. How long is less clear and the subject of debate.</p>

<p>Iran is now enriching uranium to up to 60% fissile purity, close to 90% of weapons-grade, at two sites, and in theory, it has enough material enriched to that level, if enriched further, for almost four bombs, according to a yardstick of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), the U.N. watchdog.</p>

<h3><strong>NATANZ</strong></h3>

<p>A complex at the heart of Iran's enrichment programme on a plain abutting mountain outside the Shi'ite Muslim holy city of Qom, south of Tehran. Natanz houses facilities including two enrichment plants: the vast, underground Fuel Enrichment Plant (FEP) and the above-ground Pilot Fuel Enrichment Plant (PFEP).</p>

<p>An exiled Iranian opposition group revealed in 2002 that Iran was secretly building Natanz, igniting a diplomatic standoff between the West and Iran over its nuclear intentions that continues today.</p>

<p>The FEP was built for enrichment on a commercial scale, able to house 50,000 centrifuges. Around 14,000 centrifuges are currently installed there, roughly 11,000 of which are in operation, refining uranium to up to 5% purity.</p>

<p>Diplomats with knowledge of Natanz describe the FEP as being about three floors below ground. There has long been debate about how much damage Israeli airstrikes could do to it.</p>

<p>Damage has been done to centrifuges at the FEP by other means, including an explosion and power cut in April 2021 that Iran said was an attack by Israel.</p>

<p>The above-ground PFEP houses only a few hundred centrifuges but Iran is enriching to up to 60% purity there.</p>

<h3><strong>FORDOW</strong></h3>

<p>On the opposite side of Qom, Fordow is an enrichment site dug into a mountain and therefore probably better protected from potential bombardment than the FEP.</p>

<p>The 2015 deal with major powers did not allow Iran to enrich Fordow at all. It now has more than 1,000 centrifuges operating there, a fraction of them advanced IR-6 machines enriching to up to 60%.</p>

<p>In addition, Iran recently doubled the number of centrifuges installed at Fordow, with all the new ones being IR-6 machines.</p>

<p>The United States, Britain and France announced in 2009 that Iran had been secretly building Fordow for years and had failed to inform the IAEA. US President Barack Obama said then: "The size and configuration of this facility is inconsistent with a peaceful programme."</p>

<h3><strong>ISFAHAN</strong></h3>

<p>Iran has a large nuclear technology centre on the outskirts of Isfahan, its second-largest city.</p>

<p>It includes the Fuel Plate Fabrication Plant (FPFP) and the uranium conversion facility (UCF) that can process uranium into the uranium hexafluoride that is fed into centrifuges.</p>

<p>There is equipment at Isfahan to make uranium metal, a process that is particularly proliferation-sensitive since it can be used to devise the core of a nuclear bomb.</p>

<p>The IAEA has said there are machines for making centrifuge parts at Isfahan, describing it in 2022 as a "new location".</p>

<h3><strong>KHONDAB</strong></h3>

<p>Iran has a partially built heavy-water research reactor originally called Arak and now Khondab. Heavy-water reactors pose a nuclear proliferation risk because they can easily produce plutonium which, like enriched uranium, can be used to make the core of an atom bomb.</p>

<p>Under the 2015 deal, construction was halted, and the reactor's core was removed and filled with concrete to make it unusable. The reactor was to be redesigned "to minimise the production of plutonium and not to produce weapon-grade plutonium in normal operation". Iran has informed the IAEA that it plans to bring the reactor online in 2026.</p>

<h3><strong>TEHRAN RESEARCH CENTRE</strong></h3>

<p>Iran's nuclear research facilities in Tehran include a research reactor.</p>

<h3><strong>BUSHEHR</strong></h3>

<p>Iran's only operating nuclear power plant, on the Gulf Coast, uses Russian fuel that Russia then takes back when it is spent, reducing the proliferation risk.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mdncltuo_-natanz-uranium-facility-in-iran_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Natanz uranium facility in Iran houses two enrichment plants.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-iran-execution-list-benjamin-netanyahu-benjamin-netanyahu-israel-defence-minister-on-irans-rumoured-hit-list-6706316]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu, Israel Defence Minister On Iran's Rumoured 'Hit List']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-iran-execution-list-benjamin-netanyahu-benjamin-netanyahu-israel-defence-minister-on-irans-rumoured-hit-list-6706316]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 13:52:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has an 'execution list' of 'Israeli terrorists' - including Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant, as well as the commanders of the Israel's Army, Navy, and Air Force - according to a poster circulated on X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/iran" target="_blank">Iran</a> has an 'execution list' of 'Israeli terrorists' - including Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/benjamin-netanyahu" target="_blank">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant, as well as the commanders of the Israel's Army, Navy, and Air Force - according to a poster circulated on X, one version of which was shared by @Revenge_is_near.</p>

<p>Neither government has yet responded to this poster so far, although whispers from within Iranian military intelligence suggest senior Israeli leaders, if not Netanyahu himself, may be targeted.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other high-ranking military leaders on the list are Chief of General Staff Herzi Halevi and his deputy, Amir Baram, and the heads of the Northern, Southern, and Central Command - Major Generals Ori Gordin, Yehuda Fox, and Eliezer Toledani. Military intelligence chief Aharon Haliva is also named.</p>

<p>If the list is genuine, it would appear that Iran targeting Benjamin Netanyahu is a direct response to reports that Israel is looking to press its advantage - after crippling the leadership structure of Iran-backed Hezbollah - by executing Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, that country's Supreme Leader.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">???? Just like Israel, now Iran publishes it's own terrorist list that Iran will love to kill <a href="https://t.co/mDL32HGapa">pic.twitter.com/mDL32HGapa</a></p>
— Palestinian??? (@Revenge_is_near) <a href="https://twitter.com/Revenge_is_near/status/1841410554801328469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>And, if genuine, it mirrors a (pre-attack) list released by Israel last month that said it had eliminated top commanders of the Hezbollah's elite Radwan Force, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/hezbollah-confirms-death-two-top-commanders-14-other-members-in-idf-beirut-airstrike/" target="_blank">The Times of Israel</a> reported. Israeli forces named 11 Hezbollah commanders killed and shared a poster on Instagram of the broken command structure.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Image shared on Instagram by @stateofisrael" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/67brdmp8_israel-poster-of-killed-hezbollah-commanders_625x300_03_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Image shared on Instagram by @stateofisrael" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Image shared on Instagram by @stateofisrael</p>
</div>

<p>In the aftermath of the attack Tuesday <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-iran-made-a-big-mistake-and-will-pay-for-it-6696140" target="_blank">Netanyahu told Iran it had made "a big mistake"</a>.</p>

<p>Targeting Defence Minister Gallant would also be a significant move. In October last year - ordering a complete blockade on the Gaza Strip that left millions of civilians starving, before Israeli fighter jets' merciless bombing - Gallant infamously described Palestinians as "animals".</p>

<p>And eliminating the raft of senior Israeli military leaders will be seen as payback for Tel Aviv killing at least eight top Hezbollah leaders, as well as those from Palestinian terror group Hamas and other associated Islamic groups.</p>

<p>Tension between Tel Aviv and Tehran escalated sharply - as have fears of an all-out war in West Asia - after Tuesday's large-scale missile offensive, the second against Israel in seven months.</p>

<p><strong>EXPLAINED |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-israel-might-react-to-iranian-missile-attack-6702387" target="_blank">How Israel Might React To Iranian Missile Attack?</a></p>

<p>The first - in which around 200 ballistic missile and explosive drones were fired at Israel in April - was in retaliation for an airstrike on the Iranian consulate in Damascus in Syria.</p>

<p>Tuesday's missile strike, Iran has said, was its response to Israel's killing Friday of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh. Nasrallah, 64, was killed in airstrikes targeting dozens of sites - that Tel Aviv claims were linked to the Hezbollah - in eastern and southern Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-killed-in-strikes-on-beirut-says-israel-army-6669105" target="_blank">Hezbollah Chief Killed In Israel Strike: "Will No Longer Terrorise"</a></p>

<p>Israel also claims last week's strikes dealt heavy blows to Hezbollah's command structure.</p>

<p>Two days later - on Monday - Hamas said an Israeli strike had also killed one of its senior commanders in Lebanon - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/hamas-leader-lebanon-israeli-airstrike-seventh-hezbollah-commander/" target="_blank">Fatah Sharif and his family died in airstrikes</a> in the southern port city of Tyre. Yet another - on a residential building in central Beirut - killed a member of an Islamic group allied with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Over the past 10 days Israel has reportedly targeted and executed at least eight senior Hezbollah leaders, including founding members. The group on Sunday said Nabil Kaouk, the deputy chief of its Central County and a veteran of the 2006 war with Israel, had also died in an airstrike.</p>

<p>Later that day Hezbollah said Ali Karaki, another senior commander, had also died.</p>

<p>These strikes have been seen by many as signs Israel is following ex Prime Minister&nbsp;Naftali Bennett's 'Octopus Doctrine', which calls for&nbsp;a direct fight with Iran instead of dealing with Hezbollah or Hamas.</p>

<p>Israel, after the terror attack by Hamas in October last year, had vowed to wipe out the Palestinian group, and similar declarations have been made by Tel Aviv as it opens this second front.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-guards-say-attack-on-israel-response-to-killing-of-hezbollah-chief-hamas-leader-6695237" target="_blank">Iran Guards Threaten "Crushing Attacks" If Israel Responds To Missiles</a></p>

<p>Iran's missile strikes have left diplomats in the region and in the West scrambling to avoid a full-blown war, and Tehran has warned of "crushing attacks" if Israel retaliates, which it has said it will do.</p>

<p>Guy Nir, spokesperson for the Israeli embassy in India, told NDTV Tehran would get an appropriate response. "If he (the Ayatollah) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them. Israel's response is going to be strategic and pin-pointed... not a full-scale war."</p>

<p><strong>EXCLUSIVE |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-will-irans-missile-attack-lead-to-a-full-scale-war-israeli-spokesperson-guy-nir-gives-a-hint-6696110" target="_blank">Will Iran's Attack Lead To Full-Scale War? Israel Spokesperson Says...</a></p>

<p>Any hope the US will step in to broker peace may not come to pass, with Washington saying it will work with Israel to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-lebanon-hezbollah-after-irans-missile-attack-on-israel-us-severe-consequences-warning-6696958" target="_blank">make sure Iran faces "severe consequences"</a> for its military action.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, meanwhile, Israel bombed Lebanon again, this time targeting southern suburbs of capital Beirut, which are seen as more Hezbollah strongholds.</p>

<p>Nearly 1,900 people have been killed and more than 9,000 wounded in Lebanon - most in the past two weeks - in almost a year of cross-border fighting, according to the Lebanese government, while Palestine health authorities said Israel's strikes have killed over 41,000, including women and children.</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/3pt3goso_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters_625x300_20_September_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-is-uk-pm-starmer-so-upset-with-elon-musk-6706301]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Is UK PM Starmer So Upset With Elon Musk?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-is-uk-pm-starmer-so-upset-with-elon-musk-6706301]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 13:50:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The relationship between Musk and Starmer has been frosty at best since the Labour Party came to power in July. Starmer, many believe, is upset with the American billionaire for his unsavoury remarks on how the Labour government handled the riots.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4892565_musk_625x300_03_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Less than a year ago, tech billionaire Elon Musk was Britain's star guest at a conference, with the then Prime Minister, Rishi Sunak, playing the role of a fawning interviewer to the world's richest man. A year on, things have changed in Britain. The Labour government, which came to power in July, has decided not to invite Musk to a mega investment summit to be held in London on October 14.</p>

<p>The Tesla and X boss ostensibly did not like the snub and hit back at the UK government with full force, urging the guests not to go to the UK. "I don't think anyone should go to the UK when they're releasing convicted paedophiles in order to imprison people for social media posts," he said when he learnt he was not invited.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Origin Story</strong></h2>

<p>It is true that many prisoners have been released recently under a government scheme to decongest overcrowded British jails. But there is no evidence to suggest that sex offenders or paedophiles were let out. Musk's tweets have sparked controversy and raised concerns about the spread of misinformation, with the British media reminding the tech billionaire of his recent acts of "spreading disinformation" about the UK. A few weeks ago, Musk shared a baseless report that the UK was building internment camps in the Falkland Islands for rioters, though he swiftly deleted the tweet after facing backlash.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer addressed Musk's latest provocative comments during his recent visit to the UN General Assembly (UNGA) in New York. Dismissing them as being vastly different from the positive feedback received from investors, Starmer claimed that the latter have expressed strong interest in attending and that they praised their meeting with the UK government as the best they've had.</p>

<h2><strong>Why The Summit Is Important</strong></h2>

<p>The summit - in its third edition since 2021 - aims to attract significant investment to drive economic growth, a top priority for the Labour government. According to a government release, last year's meeting generated a promise of nearly £30 billion of investment. This year, as Chancellor (finance minister) Rachel Reeves and Business and Trade Secretary (minister) Jonathan Reynolds join Starmer in showcasing the UK's potential, the government hopes to secure an investment commitment worth around 60 billion pounds in sectors like technology, green energy and artificial intelligence (AI).</p>

<p>But the elephant in the room is the government's cold shoulder to Musk. It has ignited debate about the UK's true commitment to openness and whether it's willing to engage with influential business leaders who are critical of the Labour government. As the government seeks to reset relations with global trading partners and promote innovation, Musk supporters and the opposition Conservative Party have raised questions about Starmer's willingness to walk the talk. Despite the tech billionaire's inflammatory comments, the Labour government's decision to ignore him smacks of vindictiveness and pettiness. Musk is no ordinary man. His influence on modern business, technology, and society is undeniable. I rate him alongside the Israeli historian and thinker Yuval Noah Harari -- both being the visionaries of our time, but with distinct approaches. I would like to say that while Harari focuses on the bigger picture, encouraging introspection and societal evolution, Musk actively shapes the future through groundbreaking technologies. There is no doubt that both visionaries inspire and challenge our understanding of human potential.</p>

<h2><strong>Musk, Agent Provocateur</strong></h2>

<p>The relationship between Musk and Starmer has been frosty at best since the Labour Party came to power in July. Starmer, many believe, and justifiably, is upset with the American billionaire for his unsavoury remarks on how the Labour government handled the nationwide riots in August. Following the horrific Southport stabbing that claimed the lives of three children, Musk donned the role of an agent provocateur as he unleashed a barrage of criticism against Starmer and his new government. In one of his tweets, he ominously forecast a 'civil war' in the UK. Musk has 193 million followers on X, which means whatever he says on the platform gets amplified across the world in seconds. There is no doubt that as violence and riots spread across the country, fueled by misinformation and far-right extremism, Musk's misleading tweets added fuel to the fire.</p>

<p>The response from Labour MPs was swift and stinging. Leading voices within the party accused Musk of deliberately spreading disinformation and seeking to sow division within British society. One Labour MP described Musk's intervention as "grossly irresponsible", suggesting that his comments were intended to play into existing societal fractures for personal or ideological reasons.</p>

<h2><strong>But It's Not Easy To Just Dismiss Musk</strong></h2>

<p>Starmer's office, too, condemned Musk's "civil war is inevitable" comment and said there was no justification for such remarks. But it's not easy to silence Musk, who is seen in many right-wing circles as a defender of free speech. He doubled down on Starmer and posted a series of provocative tweets, even accusing the British police of being harsher on White protesters during the riots.</p>

<p>To Starmer's comment on X that "We will not tolerate attacks on mosques and on Muslim communities", Musk replied, "Shouldn't you be concerned about attacks on 'all' communities?" In another post, he claimed the UK was censoring online content, and asked "Is this Britain or the Soviet Union?"</p>

<h2><strong>Governments And Businessmen Have Clashed Often</strong></h2>

<p>The clash between Musk and the UK government is not an isolated incident. Throughout history, influential industrialists and businessmen have challenged governments, often sparking tensions and drama. Indian-born British industrialists, the Hinduja brothers, were embroiled in the "Hinduja Affair" during Tony Blair's premiership. The brothers were accused of bribing Indian officials to secure defense contracts. Blair's government faced allegations of improperly granting the Hindujas British passports. But an investigation cleared them. However, the scandal led to the resignation of Blair's minister, Peter Mandelson. The episode underlined the complex relationships between business, politics, and national interest.</p>

<p>Media mogul Rupert Murdoch's showdown with the Margret Thatcher government began when he acquired The Times and The Sunday Times newspapers. Murdoch's media empire was investigated for unexplained business dealings, which eventually led him to sell The Times.</p>

<p>It is a widely known fact that billionaire investor George Soros has long been a thorn in the side of Hungary's nationalist government, led by Prime Minister Viktor Orbán. Soros's Open Society Foundation (OSF) promoted democratic values and human rights, which Orbán saw as a threat to his rule. His government launched a campaign against Soros, accusing him of promoting immigration and undermining Hungarian culture. The government also passed laws restricting NGOs, allegedly targeting OSF. Soros ultimately closed the OSF's Budapest office, citing "unprecedented" government harassment.</p>

<h2><strong>Can Regulation Tame X?</strong></h2>

<p>Under the Online Safety Act, social media platforms are required to proactively remove illegal content, including inflammatory material, and prevent it from appearing in the first place. The UK's communications regulator, Ofcom, has the power to punish non-compliant platforms with fines up to &amp;#163;18 million or 10% of their global annual turnover. It is believed the new act, passed last year, gives the government enough power to tame social platforms if they were found to be spreading falsehood in society.</p>

<p>It is reported that some Labour MPs have quietly suggested that action must be taken against Elon Musk for his inflammatory tweets during the riots in August and he should be summoned by Parliament to face questions from MPs. But there are no strong indications of that happening. Not as yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/82jjoun_musk_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-couldnt-stop-the-joy-newlyweds-first-dance-in-an-underground-bunker-in-israel-6706103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid Iran's Attack, Newlyweds' First Dance In Israel Bunker]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-couldnt-stop-the-joy-newlyweds-first-dance-in-an-underground-bunker-in-israel-6706103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 13:22:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video of a newlywed couple in Jerusalem dancing in an underground bunker as Iran strikes missiles has gone viral on the internet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Love conquers all and a video of a newlywed couple dancing in an underground bunker is a testimony of that. The video shows a couple in Jerusalem, dancing hand-in-hand, for the first time after the wedding ceremonies, while Iran rained missiles on Israel. Shared on the micro-blogging website X (formerly known as Twitter), the couple is seen decked up in wedding attire.</p>

<p>The beautiful moment was captured and shared on the internet by a social media user Saul Sadka. They captioned the video “Iran couldn't stop the joy at this Jerusalem wedding even for a moment.”</p>

<p>Watch it here:</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Iran couldn't stop the joy at this Jerusalem wedding even for a moment. ❤️ <a href="https://t.co/kMWzbhrNRA">pic.twitter.com/kMWzbhrNRA</a></p>
— Saul Sadka (@Saul_Sadka) <a href="https://twitter.com/Saul_Sadka/status/1841168698117181792?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>According to the New York Post, the couple was forced to take shelter when Iran attacked Israel with a barrage of 181 ballistic missiles, each having a warhead payload of between 700-1,000 kilograms, which can destroy entire buildings.</p>

<p>The clip was filmed in an underground shelter near one of Jerusalem's biggest hotels, the Notre Dam Hotel, according to a comment by Bible scholar and author Saul Sadka.</p>

<p>The video caught netizen's attention, pushing them to share their emotions. One user wrote, “Nice to see a good story come out of all this mayhem. We all need to hold onto stories like this to keep our perspective and balance in an unbalanced world.”</p>

<p>Another user wished the best for the couple and wrote, “May they have many happy years together.”</p>

<p>Another said, “Bless them and their reunion, it's not fair on them.”</p>

<p>“They will remember this moment forever,” wrote another. To which, Saul Sadka replied, “So will I! And I don't know them.”</p>

<p>Iran launched a barrage of 181 ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday (October 1) night, triggering nationwide air raid sirens and forcing nearly 10 million Israelis into bomb shelters. Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) claimed responsibility for the missile assault, targeting three Israeli military bases near Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>Although the majority of missiles were intercepted, there were scattered reports of damage and injuries. In Tel Aviv, two civilians were lightly injured by shrapnel, while in the West Bank city of Jericho, a Palestinian civilian was killed by debris from one of the missiles, news agency AFP reported. The Israeli military quickly announced that the immediate threat had passed, and civilians were allowed to leave bomb shelters after an hour.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/l2ph7c98_newlywed-couple-in-jerusalem-dance_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-conducts-drone-attacks-on-israels-tel-aviv-goals-achieved-6705938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Conduct Drone Attacks On Tel Aviv: "Goals Achieved"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-conducts-drone-attacks-on-israels-tel-aviv-goals-achieved-6705938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi rebels conducted drone attacks on "vital targets" in Israel's Tel Aviv, backing the Palestinian and Lebanese wars against Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthi rebels conducted drone strikes in Israel's Tel Aviv early this morning, backing the Palestinian and Lebanese wars against Israel. The operation achieved its goals as the drones successfully reached their targets, the Houthis said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The Drone Air Force of the Yemeni Armed Forces carried out a military operation targeting a vital target in the Yaffa area "Tel Aviv" in occupied Palestine using several Yaffa drones. The operation successfully achieved its goals, with the drones reaching their targets without the enemy being able to intercept or down them," said statement read.</p>

<p>The armed forces said the attack, which was part of its fifth phase of the "Battle of the Promised Conquest", was in support of the people of Palestine and Lebanon, and Hamas's "Al-Aqsa Flood".</p>

<p>Houthis rebels, who control most parts of Yemen and consider Israel their enemy, entered the war in support of the Hamas after the conflict started in the Middle East last year. They are part of Iran's "Axis of Resistance" against Israel and the United States.</p>

<p>Houthis have fired multiple missiles at Israeli cities while Israel has been conducting airstrikes in Yemen, targeting crucial infrastructure including power plants. Seaports used by Houthi rebels to transfer Iranian weapons also came under attack in recent times.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5evso97g_yemen-drone-strike-on-tel-aviv_625x300_03_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/shailaja-paik-macarthur-foundation-indian-american-professor-researching-dalit-women-gets-8-00-000-genius-grant-6705861]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-American Professor Researching Dalit Women Gets $8 Lakh "Genius" Grant]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/shailaja-paik-macarthur-foundation-indian-american-professor-researching-dalit-women-gets-8-00-000-genius-grant-6705861]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:47:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shailaja Paik is a distinguished research professor of history at the University of Cincinnati, where she is also an affiliate faculty in Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies, and Asian Studies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Indian-American professor, Shailaja Paik, conducting research on and writing about Dalit women has received a $800,000 "genius" grant from the MacArthur Foundation which gives out awards every year to people with extraordinary achievements or potential.</p>

<p>Announcing her fellowship, the Foundation said, "Through her focus on the multifaceted experiences of Dalit women, Paik elucidates the enduring nature of caste discrimination and the forces that perpetuate untouchability."</p>

<p>Ms Paik is a distinguished research professor of history at the University of Cincinnati, where she is also an affiliate faculty in Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies, and Asian Studies.</p>

<p>"Paik provides new insight into the history of caste domination and traces the ways in which gender and sexuality are used to deny Dalit women dignity and personhood," the Foundation said.</p>

<p>The MacArthur Fellowships, popularly known as "genius" grants, are given to people across a spectrum from academia and science to arts and activism, who according to the Foundation are "extraordinarily talented and creative individuals as an investment in their potential".</p>

<p>The selections are made anonymously based on recommendations received and it does not allow applications or lobbying for the grants, which come without any strings and are spread over five years.</p>

<p>The Foundation said that her recent project focused "on the lives of women performers of Tamasha, a popular form of bawdy folk theatre that has been practised predominantly by Dalits in Maharashtra for centuries".</p>

<p>"Despite the state's efforts to reframe Tamasha as an honourable and quintessentially Marathi cultural practice, ashlil (the mark of vulgarity) sticks to Dalit Tamasha women," it said.</p>

<p>Based on the project, she published a book, "The Vulgarity of Caste: Dalits, Sexuality, and Humanity in Modern India".</p>

<p>It said, "Paik also critiques the narrative of Dr B.R. Ambedkar, the twentieth century's most influential caste abolitionist" and the architect of India's Constitution.</p>

<p>In an interview with National Public Radio (NPR), the US government-subsidised broadcaster, she said that she was herself a member of the Dalit community who grew up in Pune in a slum area and was inspired by her father's dedication to education.</p>

<p>After getting her masters' degree from the Savitribai Phule University in Pune, she went to the University of Warwick in the UK for her PhD.</p>

<p>She did a stint as a visiting assistant professor of South Asian history at Yale University.</p>

<p>Since the programme began in 1981, fellowships have been granted to 1,153 people.</p>

<p>Previous MacArthur Fellows include writers Ruth Prawer Jhabvala, and Ved Mehta, poet A.K. Ramanujam, economists Raj Chetty and Sendhil Mullainathan, mathematician L Mahadevan, computer scientists Subhash Khot and Shwetak Patel, physical biologist Manu Prakash, musician Vijay Gupta, community organiser Raj Jayadev, and lawyer and activist Sujatha Baliga.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vcmjni08_shailaja-paik_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shailaja Paik is a distinguished research professor of history at the University of Cincinnati]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-economic-forums-new-playbook-on-funding-for-renewable-energy-6705162]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[World Economic Forum's New Playbook On Funding For Renewable Energy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-economic-forums-new-playbook-on-funding-for-renewable-energy-6705162]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:22:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The World Economic Forum has launched the Playbook of Solutions, a digital platform that shares 100 successful ways to unlock funding for clean energy in 47 developing countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.weforum.org/press/2024/10/new-digital-platform-outlines-100-actionable-solutions-for-unlocking-clean-energy-investment-in-emerging-markets/#:~:text=The%20World%20Economic%20Forum%20launches,energy%20financing%20in%20developing%20economies">World Economic Forum</a> has launched the Playbook of Solutions, a digital platform that shares 100 successful ways to unlock funding for clean energy in 47 developing countries. These solutions aim to speed up the shift to renewable energy by showing how policy changes, financial tools and partnerships can attract investments.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To meet the global goal of tripling renewable energy by 2030, investment in clean energy needs to increase significantly, especially in emerging economies, which will account for most of the world's energy demand by 2035. However, these countries currently receive only a small share of global clean energy investments due to risks and regulatory challenges.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Policy measures:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Energy Policy: </strong>Focus on providing incentives (like feed-in tariffs) and improving licensing processes for renewable energy projects.</li>
	<li><strong>Climate Policy: </strong>Set long-term goals for reducing emissions and adopt carbon pricing strategies.</li>
	<li><strong>Financial Market Policy: </strong>Ensure access to long-term financing and improve credit ratings for renewable energy projects.</li>
	<li><strong>Investment Policy: </strong>Treat foreign and domestic investors equally, protect intellectual property, and enforce contracts to reduce risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Integrated Country Platforms: </strong>Use comprehensive strategies, like Egypt's renewable energy laws and financial packages, to attract investment.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>De-risking Tools:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Portfolio Approaches:</strong> Diversifying investments to manage risk.</li>
	<li><strong>Blended Finance: </strong>Combining public and private funds to reduce risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Guarantees and Insurances: </strong>Tools like government guarantees to protect investors.</li>
	<li><strong>Refinancing: </strong>Lowering costs through favourable loans or refinancing options.</li>
	<li><strong>Currency Risk Mitigation: </strong>Managing currency fluctuations to protect investments.</li>
	<li><strong>Better Transparency: </strong>Ensuring transparency to build investor confidence.</li>
</ul>

<h2><strong>Finance Mechanisms:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Equity Financing: </strong>Investors provide capital for a share of profits.</li>
	<li><strong>Debt Financing:</strong> Borrowing funds for clean energy projects.</li>
	<li><strong>Bonds:</strong> Issuing bonds to raise money for renewable energy projects.</li>
	<li><strong>Debt Swaps:</strong> Exchanging debt for investments in clean energy.</li>
	<li><strong>Energy Service Agreements:</strong> Contracts where companies provide energy services in return for payment.</li>
	<li><strong>Purchase Agreements: </strong>Long-term contracts to buy clean energy.</li>
	<li><strong>Carbon Financing: </strong>Earning funds from carbon credits by reducing emissions.</li>
</ul>

<p>India is aiming to add 300 GW of renewable energy by 2030, which presents significant investment opportunities. To attract clean energy investments, the country has implemented integrated policies and financial incentives, including tax benefits. It has also established the Greenhouse Gas Program to monitor emissions effectively. India also started a fossil fuel subsidy swap in 2013 to level the playing field between fossil fuels and renewable energy sources.</p>

<h2><strong>Key concepts related to clean energy financing:</strong></h2>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Counterparty Guarantees: </strong>A party guarantees another will fulfil a third party's obligations.</li>
	<li><strong>Liquidity Facilities: </strong>Short-term funding to cover cash flow gaps.</li>
	<li><strong>Convertible Instruments: </strong>Products that can convert into equity, reducing investment risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Refinancing: </strong>Changing loan terms to improve borrowing conditions.</li>
	<li><strong>All-Equity Bridge Financing: </strong>Temporary funding for short-term expenses until long-term financing is secured.</li>
	<li><strong>Project Preparation Activities: </strong>Steps taken before financial closure to minimise risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Technical Assistance: </strong>Advisory support to reduce transaction risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Project Preparation Facilities (PPFs): </strong>Funding structures for project preparation.</li>
	<li><strong>Currency Risk Mitigation: </strong>Strategies to protect against currency fluctuations.</li>
	<li><strong>Local Currency Financing: </strong>Borrowing in the currency of income to reduce risks.</li>
	<li><strong>Equity Financing: </strong>Investors own shares in projects, providing long-term capital.</li>
	<li><strong>Debt Financing: </strong>Raising money by selling debt instruments.</li>
	<li><strong>Concessional Loans: </strong>Loans with favourable terms for accessible financing.</li>
	<li><strong>Revolving Credit Facilities (RCFs): </strong>Flexible borrowing options.</li>
	<li><strong>Securitisation: </strong>Pooling debts to create securities for investors.</li>
	<li><strong>Microfinance Loans: </strong>Small loans for individuals or small businesses lacking access to traditional banking.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/ld1r5iao_solar-energy_625x300_26_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-map-fruit-fly-brain-breakthrough-for-human-animal-insights-6705625]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Map Fruit Fly Brain, Breakthrough For Human, Animal Insights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-map-fruit-fly-brain-breakthrough-for-human-animal-insights-6705625]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Oct 2024 12:13:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists announced on Thursday a milestone in neurobiological research with the mapping of the entire brain of an adult fruit fly, a feat that may provide insight into brains across the animal kingdom, including people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists announced on Thursday a milestone in neurobiological research with the mapping of the entire brain of an adult fruit fly, a feat that may provide insight into brains across the animal kingdom, including people.</p>

<p>The research detailed more than 50 million connections between more than 139,000 neurons - brain nerve cells - in the insect, a species whose scientific name is Drosophila melanogaster and is often used in neurobiological studies. The research sought to decipher how brains are wired and the signals underlying healthy brain functions. It also could pave the way for mapping the brains of other species.</p>

<p>"You might be asking why we should care about the brain of a fruit fly. My simple answer is that if we can truly understand how any brain functions, it's bound to tell us something about all brains," said Princeton University professor of neuroscience and computer science Sebastian Seung, one of the co-leaders of the work published in a series of studies in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>While some people may be more interested in swatting flies than studying them, some of the researchers found aesthetic satisfaction in peering at the fruit fly brain, less than 0.04 inches (1 mm) wide.</p>

<p>"It's beautiful," said University of Cambridge neuroscientist and research co-leader Gregory Jefferis.</p>

<p>The map devised by the researchers provided a wiring diagram, known as a connectome, for the brain of an adult fruit fly. Similar research previously was conducted with simpler organisms, such as the worm Caenorhabditis elegans and the fruit fly's larval stage. The adult fruit fly presented more complicated behaviours to study through its brain wiring.</p>

<p>"One of the major questions we're addressing is how the wiring in the brain, its neurons and connections, can give rise to animal behaviour," said Princeton neuroscientist Mala Murthy, another of the co-leaders of the research.</p>

<p>"And flies are an important model system for neurosciences. Their brains solve many of the same problems we do... They're capable of sophisticated behaviours like the execution of walking and flying, learning and memory behaviours, navigation, feeding and even social interactions, which is a behaviour that we studied in my lab at Princeton," Murthy added.</p>

<p>One of the studies analyzed brain circuits underlying walking and discovered how flies halt. Another analyzed the fly's taste network and grooming circuits behind behavior such as when it uses a leg to remove dirt from its antennae. Another looked at the visual system including how the fly's eyes process motion and color information. Still, another one analyzed connectivity through the brain, discovering a large assemblage of "hub neurons" that may speed up information flow.</p>

<p>The researchers fashioned a map tracking the organization of the hemispheres and behavioural circuits inside the fly's brain. They also identified the full set of cell classes in its brain, pinpointing different varieties of neurons and chemical connections - synapses - between these nerve cells, and looked at the types of chemicals secreted by the neurons.</p>

<p>The work was conducted by a large international collaboration of scientists known as the FlyWire Consortium.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/vba6av58_fruit-fly_625x300_07_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The researchers identified the full set of cell classes in the fruit fly's brain.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>