<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:55:55 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-2-most-dramatic-moments-of-the-us-election-2024-6940045]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The 2 Most Dramatic Moments Of The US Election 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-2-most-dramatic-moments-of-the-us-election-2024-6940045]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:40:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US voters will either pick their first female, Black and Asian leader - or reappoint a chief executive seeking an unprecedented return to the White House he left in disgrace nearly four years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the most turbulent presidential campaign in decades enters its final hours, Americans can be forgiven for wondering: What just happened?</p>

<p>Kamala Harris and Donald Trump are separated by the narrowest of margins in polls – which show Tuesday's election is a coin flip – and by a chasm in their future vision for the world's premier economic and military power. US voters will either pick their first female, Black and Asian leader – or reappoint a chief executive seeking an unprecedented return to the White House he left in disgrace nearly four years ago.</p>

<p>That's the cast – and then consider the backdrop. The cycle began in a country still reeling from the once-in-a-century Covid-19 pandemic, when Americans elected Joe Biden as the oldest president in US history, and Trump's supporters attacked the Capitol to try and reverse his loss. It's since encompassed the outbreak of major wars in Europe and the Middle East, raising fears the US could get sucked in; a spike in inflation like no American aged under 40 had ever witnessed; and a rollback of federal abortion rights by the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>And even that is just a sliver of the drama and chaos that Americans have experienced during the 2024 campaign itself.</p>

<p>Democrats ditched incumbent president Biden in favor of his deputy — Vice President Harris — without consulting their voters. GOP candidate Trump bulldozed his way through primaries, at times campaigning from the New York courtroom where he was ultimately convicted for paying hush money to an adult film star – and then was shot and injured at a rally.</p>

<p><strong>‘That Was the Craziest'</strong></p>

<p>No wonder so many Americans, from first-time voters to seasoned movers and shakers in the campaign-finance world, are still trying to gather their bearings.</p>

<p>Gideon Stein — an entrepreneur, philanthropist and major Democratic donor — is clear about the turning point. “The debate on June 27,” he says. “That to me was the craziest.”</p>

<p>Back then, Biden was still seeking re-election but struggling to ignite much enthusiasm. Dogged by questions about his fitness for another term, he proposed an early debate against Trump in June. To say the strategy backfired is an understatement. So halting and incoherent was the president's performance that he could no longer hold back the dam of angst around his age.</p>

<p>“That's why I got engaged and used my voice as a donor,” says Stein, who was among the group of key Democratic funders who made it clear to the party that they'd withhold donations until Biden was replaced on the ballot. “We were going to continue to invest down ballot, but weren't going to invest in the presidential because everything we were seeing was that he was going to lose.”</p>

<p>Biden ended his reelection campaign and endorsed Harris as his successor. Looking back, Stein says it was the right move: Democrats have a much better shot at keeping the White House with the vice president atop the ticket. He made good on his promise to the party to donate $3.5 million, disbursing some of it over the past week.</p>

<p>Still, the incident left Democrats with a compressed calendar to introduce Harris to the nation — and a credibility gap to address. Before Biden's debate performance, party officials had mocked and disputed concerns about his age. “They were telling us he was bench-pressing 350 pounds, doing summersaults,” says Eric Levine, a Republican donor who voted for Trump and raised about $1.8 million for down ballot races.</p>

<p><strong>‘Coming After You'</strong></p>

<p>Levine agrees that the president's withdrawal is the most memorable moment of 2024 – “that, and the assassination attempt.”</p>

<p>The moment of maximum drama on the GOP side arrived on July 13, when a bullet grazed Trump's ear at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, killing an attendee. Photos showed a bloodstained ex-president defiantly pumping his fist.</p>

<p>For Eric Marks, a 57-year-old from Kalamazoo, Michigan, that was the most impactful incident of the election. “If the people coming after you know that you're standing up for the truth and they have something to hide, they're going to do whatever they can do to silence you,” he says. US officials have said the shooter was 20-year-old Thomas Matthew Crooks, who was killed by the Secret Service.</p>

<p>In their truncated three-month-long contest, Trump and Harris have offered sharply different programs for the country that clarify the high stakes.</p>

<p>On the economy, Harris has focused on the so-called sandwich generation, those caught between raising kids and caring for elderly parents. She's promised to provide as much as $25,000 in down-payment assistance for first-time homebuyers, and to expand the child tax credit.</p>

<p>Trump says he'll reduce the corporate tax rate and abolish taxes on Social Security and overtime pay, among other plans. He's also vowed to crack down on undocumented migrants by deporting millions of them.</p>

<p>These messages are getting amplified in advertising campaigns blitzing the country, and especially the handful of states that will likely be decisive: Michigan, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania, Nevada, Arizona, North Carolina and Georgia. A record $15.9 billion will be spent on federal elections, including House and Senate races, according to OpenSecrets.</p>

<p>Chris Martin, a 38-year-old Black man in Sandy Springs, Georgia — a northern suburb of Atlanta – admits to election fatigue. Every other commercial is political, voters are constantly hammered by text messages from the campaigns, and it's getting a bit much.</p>

<p>“It's this whole us versus them thing going on, and I'm sick of it,” says Martin, who highlighted Trump's unsubstantiated claims that Haitian immigrants in Ohio were eating pets. “It's nasty stuff, and it's along the lines of race and nationality. The stuff they say about immigrants, it's just awful.”</p>

<p>Internationally, the Democratic candidate has espoused a similar position to Biden, endorsing the US role in NATO and support for Ukraine against Russia's invasion. She's had to contend with a schism within the Democratic party driven by Israel's war in Gaza, which is pressuring Harris' support in Michigan, a swing state with a large Arab-American population. Opposition to the war consumed the headlines last spring as student protests erupted on college campuses across the US.</p>

<p>Trump, in a continuation of his first-term stance, has questioned America's global security commitments. He's vowed to resume his trade war with China, by ramping up tariffs on the US's closest economic competitor, and threatens a broad 10% duty on other countries too.</p>

<p><strong>‘Never as Dramatic'</strong></p>

<p>The global backdrop is contributing to election tensions on both sides, according to Rocky Raczkowski, a Republican and former member of the Michigan House of Representatives. “There is economic unease and world turmoil unease with what's happening with Ukraine, Israel and Iran,” he says. “There is also malaise among Democrats, especially progressives, that the system isn't working for them. And there is anger among Republican voters who think the system is selling us down the road to other countries.”</p>

<p>Whether it's driven by events at home or abroad, angst around the vote is widespread. An Oct. 31 AP-NORC Center poll found seven in ten Americans are either anxious or frustrated with the 2024 presidential campaign – an even higher share than in the pandemic-disrupted election of 2020.</p>

<p>Taryn Carthers is one of them. A 21-year-old retail worker who lives northwest of Atlanta, she hasn't followed many campaigns —- but says this one is the craziest.</p>

<p>“I remember being in elementary school when Obama and Romney were running for office,” she says. “It was never as dramatic as what we are dealing with now.” Carthers has gone from being demoralized when Biden led the Democratic ticket, to reinvigorated by the ascent of Harris – and now she says she's despondent again over all the stress. “I'm excited to vote, but also very excited for this election season to be over.”</p>

<p>In the campaign's last week, both sides have been trying to capitalize on missteps from their opponents in order to sway remaining undecided voters who could tilt the outcome.</p>

<p>Trump held a rally at New York City's Madison Square Garden on Oct. 27, where his allies made racist and misogynistic remarks — including calling Puerto Rico a “floating island of garbage” — that Democrats pounced on. But a presidential gaffe during a subsequent attempt to capitalize on the incident, in which Biden appeared to describe Trump's supporters as garbage, allowed Republicans an outrage cycle of their own. Even as Biden insisted he was only referring to the comedian who cast the original insult, Trump took to the campaign trail in a garbage truck.</p>

<p><strong>‘Alone With Our Thoughts'</strong></p>

<p>Trump has also sought to keep the embers of his 2020 revolt burning, maintaining without evidence that the vote that year was fraudulent – and potentially sowing distrust in the soon-to-be-revealed 2024 results. States have bolstered election protocols to guard against disruptions.</p>

<p>The GOP contender, ever superstitious, is scheduled to wrap up his campaign in Grand Rapids, Michigan for the third straight cycle – before heading to Florida to await the count. Harris will hold a rally on the steps of the Philadelphia Art Museum, made famous by the movie “Rocky,” and then return to Washington. She'll spend election night at her alma mater Howard University.</p>

<p>In Madison, Wisconsin, Debra Zillmer has hit on her own election strategy: get out of town. The 70-year-old, a retired orthopedic surgeon who's voting for Harris, has taken to traveling with her husband in their recreational vehicle to escape from the swing state. Her motive will likely resonate with many Americans, in the final days of a disorienting campaign.</p>

<p>“We just have to get out of there, be alone with our thoughts, not be watching the news all the time,” Zillmer says. “I find it very unsettling.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8v43jf7o_us-election_625x300_02_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iowa-shocker-kamala-harris-takes-lead-where-donald-trump-won-twice-before-6940019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Takes Lead In Iowa, Where Donald Trump Won Twice Before]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iowa-shocker-kamala-harris-takes-lead-where-donald-trump-won-twice-before-6940019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:33:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iowa seems to hold the potential to become a swing state in the electoral battle between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ignored by both the Democrat and Republican campaigns ahead during the Presidential primaries, Iowa now seems to hold the potential to become a swing state in the electoral battle between Kamala Harris and Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The latest poll by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.desmoinesregister.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/11/02/iowa-as-a-swing-state-iowa-poll-shows-harris-and-trump-in-tight-race/76020309007/">Des Moines Register</a> newspaper showed Ms Harris leading 47 percent to 44 percent over Mr Trump, buoyed by the support of women and independent voters. The latter was quick to reject the poll as "fake" and "skewed". "One of my enemies just puts out a poll -- I am 3 down. (Iowa Senator) Joni Ernst called me, everyone's called me, they said you are killing in Iowa. The farmers love me and I love them," he said at a rally in key battleground state of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Iowa, which was not a battleground state ahead of the November 5 US Presidential elections, was not on the itineraries of the two nominees, who made multiple campaign visits to the seven swing states ― Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>More than 75 million Americans have already cast their votes as of Sunday, according to the University of Florida's Election Lab that tracks early and mail-in voting across the US. The poll of 808 likely Iowa voters, which include those who have already voted as well as those who say they definitely plan to vote, was conducted from October 28 to 31, Des Moines Register said.</p>

<p>Women, especially those who are 65 and older and those who self-identify as independents, are spearheading the shift to Ms Harris, the poll shows. Senior women support the Democrat over the Republican nominee 63 percent to 28 percent, and women who are political independents favor Ms Harris by 57 percent to 29 percent. Mr Trump maintains large margins with groups that are core to his base: men, rural Iowans and those who describe themselves as evangelical.</p>

<p>Interestingly, though the state was clinched by Mr Trump by nearly 10 points in each of the last two elections. That, however, does not qualify it as a Republican stronghold as it was bagged by Barack Obama in 2008 and 2012.</p>

<p>In the election campaign, Ms Harris has been projecting the election as the one to protect the country's fundamental freedoms, safeguard constitutional values and ensure women's rights. Mr Trump has been promising to rebuild the economy and rid the US from illegal migration.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8mon83b_us-election_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 75 million Americans have already cast their votes as of Sunday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cleaning-up-pristine-beaches-means-spotting-plastic-trash-from-space-6940013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cleaning Up Pristine Beaches Means Spotting Plastic Trash From Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cleaning-up-pristine-beaches-means-spotting-plastic-trash-from-space-6940013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:31:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Plastics are ubiquitous in natural systems, and tiny pieces of the material have been found everywhere from the Arctic to the Mariana Trench.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Plastics are ubiquitous in natural systems, and tiny pieces of the material have been found everywhere from the Arctic to the Mariana Trench. To test a theory that satellites could help detect the waste on beaches, Jenna Guffogg hauled discarded scraps from a clam-shell child's pool, bubble wrap, single-use PET bottles, and a blue polyester tarp to her local seashore in Australia.</p>

<p>The data scientist laid out weathered fragments in fourteen rectangles each covering about 2.25-square-meters (24-square-feet). Within a couple of hours, Maxar Technologies Inc.'s WorldView-3 satellite flew nearly 620 kilometers (385 miles) overhead and snapped a picture. Within a week, she got data and a few months later, she had an answer: the trash can be spotted from space.</p>

<p>Guffogg's findings, published in a study in Marine Pollution Bulletin, show how the use of satellites to locate plastic waste on beaches could aid efforts to curb the estimated 19 to 23 million metric tons of the material that enters marine and coastal ecosystems each year. That total is currently projected to about double by 2030.</p>

<p>The rising volume of waste is an increasingly urgent issue for world leaders: Diplomats will descend on South Korea in a few weeks for the final round of United Nations talks on a legally binding plastic pollution treaty. Negotiations are likely to pit oil, gas, and petrochemical producers like China, Saudi Arabia, and Russia against a group including European Union members, Canada, Mexico, and Australia. The former wants to see a treaty that only tracks plastic waste, while the latter wants one that tackles production.</p>

<p>Regardless of the outcome of those talks, Guffogg and other scientists are building frameworks that can help prioritize cleanups of existing waste that threaten marine, animal, and human life. While her study analyzed just one beach area near Shallow Inlet, about 100 miles southeast of Melbourne, Guffogg wants to expand her research to see how the approach could work globally.</p>

<p>"The best case scenario would be we use technology like this to start developing maps that can show us where these plastic hot spots are," said Guffogg. "Then you can direct cleanup efforts, be that by governments or other groups."</p>

<p>Her analysis is the latest in a series of innovations catalyzed by remote-sensing technologies like multispectral satellites, drones and land-based sensors. Those tools are allowing scientists to quickly identify and track climate and environmental flashpoints from methane leaks to wildfires. The approach is also helping governments to shape their policy responses.</p>

<p>Satellite observations of methane are enabling authorities to hold fossil fuel operators accountable for the emissions, and the data has helped instigate a series of pledges to take action by nations and companies. Still, methane pollution from oil, coal, and gas remains near record levels.</p>

<p>A small but growing community of scientists like Guffogg, a sessional lecturer at RMIT University in Melbourne, are applying many of the same principles to track plastics.</p>

<p>The Coastal Marine Litter Observatory, a spin-off company from the University of the Aegean, in Greece, has developed a platform that uses an algorithm to process high-resolution drone images of beaches and detect evidence of plastics. The results are uploaded to a database that's been used by governments and non-profits, like the Athanasios C. Laskaridis Charitable Foundation, for targeted cleanups.</p>

<p>Guffogg's homemade targets were larger than much of the debris that washes ashore. So while satellites won't be able to spot most small individual pieces of plastic, the technique should help in discovering accumulations of the waste. "As long as there's enough plastics gathered in an area we can spot them," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/ocean-plastic-waste-istock-650_625x300_1528443813190.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rising volume of waste is an increasingly urgent issue for world leaders. (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-bites-baby-a-last-week-of-us-election-oddities-6939976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Bites Baby: A Last Week Of US Election Oddities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-bites-baby-a-last-week-of-us-election-oddities-6939976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:29:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It has been a wild US presidential election campaign, and the final week provided another selection of weird and wonderful offbeat moments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been a wild US presidential election campaign, and the final week provided another selection of weird and wonderful offbeat moments.</p>

<p><strong>Biden's baby bite</strong></p>

<p>President Joe Biden took a playful bite into the leg of a baby dressed as a chicken at the White House's Halloween party.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old pretended to sink his teeth into the child as he stood beside First Lady Jill Biden... who was wearing a giant panda costume to greet children.</p>

<p><strong>'Tis the election</strong></p>

<p>For "Queen of Christmas" Mariah Carey, her favorite season may be just around the corner, but she reminded Americans that the election comes first in a social media clip.</p>

<p>Carey, wearing festive attire, launched into her hit track "All I Want For Christmas Is You" -- before actor Kerry Washington brought her to a halt.</p>

<p>"No, no, no, it's not your season yet Mariah. It's voting season," Washington said.</p>

<p><strong>Trash talk</strong></p>

<p>Kamala Harris's running mate Tim Walz, who nurtures a working man persona, ribbed Trump for stumbling during a photo op this week.</p>

<p>"This dude's nearly 80-years-old. He damn near killed himself getting into a garbage truck," Walz told a Pennsylvania rally, after video showed Trump stumbling as he twice missed the door handle at an airport in Wisconsin.</p>

<p><strong>A lot of Trump</strong></p>

<p>A touring, nude, 40-foot statue depicting Donald Trump -- complete with genitalia -- divided opinions when it appeared in Philadelphia in the swing state of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"I love freedom of speech," one local told The Philadelphia Inquirer. But a Republican Party official was less happy, slamming it as "appalling."</p>

<p>Police reportedly requested the removal of the unflattering artwork, which has been traveling the country ahead of the election.</p>

<p><strong>Dough-mocracy</strong></p>

<p>There are a myriad of reasons Americans will vote, but for some, it may be as simple as the promise of a sweet treat.</p>

<p>Krispy Kreme announced it will give a free doughnut on Election Day to people who vote, celebrating what it called "doughmocracy."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3uoj3goo_joe-biden-bites-a-baby_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Joe Biden took a playful bite into the leg of a baby dressed as a chicken.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-canada-cops-assault-hindu-devotees-during-protest-over-temple-attack-6939909]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Canada Cops Assault Hindu Devotees During Protest Over Temple Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-canada-cops-assault-hindu-devotees-during-protest-over-temple-attack-6939909]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:17:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian cops clashed with Hindu devotees protesting an attack on a temple near Toronto by "anti-India elements". The cops assaulted protesters, many of whom were waving the Indian flag, showed a video shared by a Canadian journalist.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian cops clashed with Hindu devotees protesting an attack on a temple near Toronto by "anti-India elements". The cops assaulted the temple-goers, many of whom were waving the Indian flag, showed a video shared by a Canadian journalist. It also captured a cop charging at a protester and landing multiple punches times on him.</p>

<p>"He is hitting with a stick," the woman who filmed the video is heard saying as she points to an officer, accusing him of assaulting the protesters. The enraged crowd soon starts shouting "take him out".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING: The RCMP start attacking Hindu worshippers on their own temple grounds in Surrey BC.<br />
Watch as an RCMP officer goes into the crowd to go after Hindu devotees after pushing them back to protect the Khalistanis who came to harass the temple goers on Diwali. Punching Hindus… <a href="https://t.co/uugAJun59q">pic.twitter.com/uugAJun59q</a></p>
— Daniel Bordman (@DanielBordmanOG) <a href="https://twitter.com/DanielBordmanOG/status/1853241154554233025?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The journalist who shared the video claimed that the cops went after the Hindu devotees to protect the "Khalistanis who came to harass the temple goers on Diwali".</p>

<p>A mob stormed the Hindu Sabha temple in Brampton earlier in the day and attacked devotees, which Prime Minister Justin Trudeau condemned. "The acts of violence at the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton today are unacceptable. Every Canadian has the right to practice their faith freely and safely," Trudeau posted on X.</p>

<p>The Indian embassy said "anti-India elements" orchestrated the violence outside its consular camp co-organized by the temple. Calling it "deeply disappointing", the embassy said there were similar attempts to disrupt camps in Surrey and Vancouver over the past two days.</p>

<p>The incidents come amid diplomatic tensions between the two countries triggered by Trudeau's accusation that India was behind the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. India, which trashed the charges as baseless, had also accused Canada of providing a safe haven to terrorists and extremists.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vesirv_canadian-cops-assault-devotees_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-in-good-health-chinese-space-station-crew-returns-after-six-months-6939901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["All In Good Health": Chinese Space Station Crew Returns After Six Months]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/all-in-good-health-chinese-space-station-crew-returns-after-six-months-6939901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:14:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A three-person Chinese crew returned to Earth early Monday after more than six months aboard the Tiangong space station.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-person Chinese crew returned to Earth early Monday after more than six months aboard the Tiangong space station, state news agency Xinhua reported.</p>

<p>Ye Guangfu, Li Cong and Li Guangsu were all "in good health" after touching down in the return capsule of their Shenzhou spaceship at the Dongfeng landing site in Inner Mongolia, Xinhua said.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? Meet our heroes!<br />
<br />
?Astronauts Ye Guangfu, Li Cong and Li Guangsu were out of the return capsule of the Shenzhou XVIII manned spaceship early on Monday morning, all in good physical condition. [?/CMS] <a href="https://t.co/1ccjPxql9l">pic.twitter.com/1ccjPxql9l</a></p>
— Chinese Space Station (@CNSpaceStation) <a href="https://twitter.com/CNSpaceStation/status/1853218029100061106?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The three men had traveled to Tiangong in late April and were met on October 30 by three new astronauts, including the country's only woman spaceflight engineer, with whom they did a five-day handover before making their return journey.</p>

<p>China has ramped up plans to achieve its "space dream" under President Xi Jinping.</p>

<p>Its space programme was the third to put humans in orbit and has also landed robotic rovers on Mars and the Moon.</p>

<p>Crewed by teams of three astronauts that are rotated every three-six months, the Tiangong space station is the programme's crown jewel.</p>

<p>Its core module was launched in 2021, and it is planned to be used for about 10 years.</p>

<p>Beijing says it is on track to send a crewed mission to the Moon by 2030, where it intends to construct a base on the lunar surface.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fpeqapoo_chinese-space-station-crew_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-embark-on-final-campaign-6939831]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Election 2024: Kamala Harris And Donald Trump Embark On Final Campaign]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-and-donald-trump-embark-on-final-campaign-6939831]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:00:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bitter rivals Kamala Harris and Donald Trump embark on a final frenzied campaign blitz Monday with both hitting must-win Pennsylvania on the last day of the tightest and most volatile US presidential election in memory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitter rivals Kamala Harris and Donald Trump embark on a final frenzied campaign blitz Monday with both hitting must-win Pennsylvania on the last day of the tightest and most volatile US presidential election in memory.</p>

<p>Republican Trump has promised a "landslide" as he seeks a sensational return to the White House, while Democrat Harris said the "momentum" was on the side of her bid to be America's first woman president.</p>

<p>But the polls suggest a different story on the eve of Election Day -- total deadlock in surveys nationally and in the seven swing states where the result is expected to be decided.</p>

<p>Now a race of dramatic twists, including two bids to kill Trump and Harris's shock late entrance, is coming down to the most viciously fought-over battleground.</p>

<p>Harris will spend the whole day campaigning in the rust-belt state of Pennsylvania, culminating in a huge rally in its biggest city Philadelphia featuring singer Lady Gaga. Trump will travel to North Carolina, Pennsylvania and then Michigan.</p>

<p>In a sign of how crucial Pennsylvania is to their chances of occupying the Oval Office, Trump and Harris will even hold dueling rallies in the industrial city of Pittsburgh.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania is the single biggest swing state prize under the US Electoral College system, which awards influence in line with population.</p>

<p><strong>'You're fired'</strong></p>

<p>Both sides say they are encouraged by huge early turnout numbers, with over 78 million people having voted already, around half of the total number of ballots cast in 2020.</p>

<p>The incredible closeness of the 2024 White House race reflects a deeply divided United States, as it chooses between two candidates whose visions could scarcely be more different.</p>

<p>Former president Trump has doubled down on his dark and violent rhetoric in his pursuit of a second term which would make him the first convicted felon and, at 78, the oldest major party candidate ever elected.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris has meanwhile made an astonishing rise to the top of the Democratic ticket after President Joe Biden dropped out of the race in July.</p>

<p>Harris is hoping abortion is a key issue that can hurt Trump, especially with woman voters, while Trump has focused on migrants and the economy and dubbed political opponents the "enemy from within."</p>

<p>They have both embarked on a frenetic zig-zag through the swing states, with raucous rallies and even an appearance by Harris on the famed television show "Saturday Night Live."</p>

<p>On the campaign trail Sunday, Trump mused to supporters that he wouldn't mind if journalists were shot, raised baseless allegations of election fraud and dwelt in gory detail on crimes by undocumented immigrants.</p>

<p>"Kamala -- you're fired, get out," Trump told cheering supporters in Macon, Georgia.</p>

<p>Trump also said he "shouldn't have left" the White House after he lost his 2020 reelection bid to Biden, and then tried to overturn the results, culminating in the January 6, 2021 assault on the US Capitol.</p>

<p>Fears are mounting that he would again refuse to accept defeat.</p>

<p><strong>'We have momentum'</strong></p>

<p>For Harris's part, after a series of more encouraging recent polls, she told a raucous rally in Michigan on Sunday that "we have momentum -- it's on our side."</p>

<p>Harris also courted the large Arab-American community in Michigan that has denounced US handling of the Israel-Hamas war, saying she would do "everything in my power to end the war in Gaza."</p>

<p>The world is anxiously watching the election, which could have profound implications for conflicts in the Middle East and Russia's war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The final days of the campaign have meanwhile seen both candidates roll out high-profile surrogates.</p>

<p>Right-wing tech tycoon Elon Musk has been making controversial $1 million giveaways to registered voters, while Harris has relied on the star power of former president Barack Obama and ex-first lady Michelle Obama and singer Beyonce.</p>

<p>But outgoing President Biden has been notably absent from the trail since a gaffe in which he referred to Trump's supporters as "garbage" last week.</p>

<p>Biden will spend most of the last day of the campaign at the White House, while Harris will start her day with an event in his hometown of Scranton, Pennsylvania.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lqgn5nn_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_28_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Republican Trump has promised a "landslide" as he seeks a sensational return to the White House.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-new-defendants-to-take-stand-as-france-mass-rape-trial-resumes-6939760]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8 New Defendants To Take Stand As France Mass Rape Trial Resumes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-new-defendants-to-take-stand-as-france-mass-rape-trial-resumes-6939760]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:53:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The trial of a Frenchman who recruited dozens of strangers to rape his drugged wife at their home resumes on Monday, with the cases of eight new defendants to be examined in court.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The trial of a Frenchman who recruited dozens of strangers to rape his drugged wife at their home resumes on Monday, with the cases of eight new defendants to be examined in court.</p>

<p>The case of Dominique Pelicot, 71, and 50 other co-defendants aged 26 to 74 years old has caused outrage and sparked protests since it opened on September 2 in the southern city of Avignon.</p>

<p>For refusing to be ashamed and demanding the trial be open to the public, his ex-wife Gisele Pelicot, also 71, has become a feminist heroine in France and abroad.</p>

<p>The court has already questioned 36 of the defendants, including Pelicot himself, and will after a week's break on Monday start examining eight more of the co-accused.</p>

<p>Antoine Camus, one of Gisele Pelicot's lawyers, said the international attention had given his client the strength to carry on.</p>

<p>"It's an endurance race, but she of course remains ready for the fight and determined to see it through, because she has also been uplifted by this wave of support in France and abroad," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"She very often receives many accounts that uplift her and help her in this marathon, which she is completing not just for herself."</p>

<p>The abuse was uncovered after police in 2020 arrested Dominique Pelicot for filming up women's skirts in a local supermarket.</p>

<p>He has admitted to raping his then wife Gisele Pelicot and enlisting dozens to join him between 2011 and 2020, meticulously documenting the abuse in thousands of images investigators found on his hard drives.</p>

<p><strong>Driver, cleaner, HIV positive man</strong></p>

<p>But his co-accused, most of whom risk up to 20 years in jail for aggravated rape in convicted, have largely claimed they had no idea it was rape.</p>

<p>They have said they thought they were taking part in the sex game of a libertine couple.</p>

<p>"It's really tiring for Gisele Pelicot to almost systematically hear the same explanations from the accused," Camus said. "That was victim of rape 'by accident', rape 'by error of judgement', or 'reluctant' rape."</p>

<p>The next eight men to be cross-examined from Monday include a 36-year-old truck driver, a 31-year-old labourer, a 36-year-old cleaner and a 42-year-old restaurant manager.</p>

<p>Among them is a 50-year-old software technician who has been accused of planning to imitate Dominique Pelicot's methods on his own wife.</p>

<p>An HIV-positive single man, now aged 63, has been charged with visiting the Pelicot home in the southern town of Mazan six times to abuse Gisele Pelicot, not once using a condom.</p>

<p>The court will also examine the case of a 30-year-old who is the only co-defendant being tried in absentia.</p>

<p><strong>'Abused his own daughter'</strong></p>

<p>Finally, an unemployed 41-year-old has been accused of raping Gisele Pelicot in 2019, with the complicity of her then husband, at the home of the couple's daughter in the Paris region.</p>

<p>He denied committing rape of the first day of the trial.</p>

<p>The couple's two sons and daughter, who goes by her pen name Caroline Darian, have regularly appeared at the trial to support their mother.</p>

<p>But Darian was not present at some of the more recent hearings.</p>

<p>In late October, after the trial reached half-mark, she announced on Instagram that she was checking in to a clinic for a few days to recharge and "to be able to sleep again".</p>

<p>Darian, who in 2022 wrote a book "Et j'ai cesse de t'appeler papa" ("And I stopped calling you dad"), has campaigned for awareness about the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse.</p>

<p>She left the courtroom in tears early during the trial as the presiding judge recounted how her father also had naked photomontages of her on his computer.</p>

<p>"I too am a victim of Dominique P," Darian wrote on Instagram.</p>

<p>"He drugged me without my knowledge, and without a doubt abused his own and only daughter."</p>

<p>The trial is to last until December 20.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7r768c2_gisele-pelicot_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gisele Pelicot has become a feminist heroine in France and abroad.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrias-alpine-refuges-and-trails-crumble-as-climate-warms-6939497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Austria's Alpine Refuges And Trails Crumble As Climate Warms]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrias-alpine-refuges-and-trails-crumble-as-climate-warms-6939497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:14:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Experts say warmer temperatures across the Alps are accelerating glacier melt and thawing permafrost, the year-round ice that binds together giant slabs of rock.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The historic Zittel hut on top of a snow-capped mountain high in the Austrian Alps has weathered many a storm.</p>

<p>But ever more extreme climate change is taking a terrible toll on the century-old wooden refuge.</p>

<p>"When your hand fits into a crack in the foundation, there is need for action," said Georg Unterberger, who is in charge of mountain refuges and trails at the Austrian Alpine club.</p>

<p>The trails up to refuge on the 3,106-metre (10,190-foot) Sonnblick mountain are also suffering.</p>

<p>Experts say warmer temperatures across the Alps are accelerating glacier melt and thawing permafrost, the year-round ice that binds together giant slabs of rock.</p>

<p>This has increased the danger of sudden rockfalls and landslides, damaging paths and putting more pressure on the often ageing and neglected huts.</p>

<p>Austria's Alpine clubs are currently closing up to four huts a year as they become unsafe or too costly to maintain.</p>

<p>With the country heavily dependent on Alpine tourism, the cost of keeping up the trails "have doubled in the last five years", said Unterberger, who also works as a building surveyor.</p>

<p>Each year about one million people visit the more than 200 mountain huts the Austrian Alpine club -- the country's biggest -- operates.</p>

<p><strong>'Struggling on all fours'</strong></p>

<p>The trail up to the Zittel in the Salzburg region was always a black-rated one, but "now it's even more dangerous", Unterberger told AFP.</p>

<p>Hikers may now need climbing gear to reach it as the retreating glacier that once went all the way up to the popular refuge has exposed steep rock faces and vast fields of scree.</p>

<p>"I've seen hikers struggle on all fours to make it," Unterberger said, adding that work on trails has dramatically increased in recent years, with ropes and steel rungs having to be put in place.</p>

<p>At the Zittel hut, the crumbling foundation and the weather-worn wooden shingles require urgent renovation and thermal insulation.</p>

<p>Thawing permafrost threatened the very existence of the hut and the adjacent observatory -- one of the world's oldest high-altitude weather stations -- already years ago, with the peak at risk of falling apart.</p>

<p>To keep it from disintegrating, workers rammed steel anchors 20 metres into the mountain top and further supported the summit with concrete braces.</p>

<p>For now the peak is stable, but further measures cannot be ruled out.</p>

<p>More money is needed to remedy the decaying infrastructure in the Austrian Alps, with experts saying 272 out of 429 mountain refuges, as well as 50,000 kilometres (31,000 miles) of trails, are in dire need of repair.</p>

<p>In a petition earlier this year, the cash-strapped Alpine clubs urged the government to provide an emergency fund of 95 million euros ($103 million).</p>

<p>So far the government has pledged just three million euros.</p>

<p>Unlike in neighbouring Switzerland, where the cantons are in charge of maintaining the trail network, Austrian Alpine clubs heavily rely on ever scarcer volunteers.</p>

<p>"Many of our 25,000 volunteers are more than 65 years old and recruiting young people has been a challenge," said Unterberger, observing a trend towards "micro-volunteering" for a few hours or a day, but not more.</p>

<p><strong>'Critical situation'</strong></p>

<p>The Zittel refuge shares the summit with the Sonnblick observatory, which has been measuring and documenting the changes to climate since it opened in 1886.</p>

<p>Up on the mountain, the temperature has been recorded for 138 years straight, the longest uninterrupted high-altitude data anywhere in the world.</p>

<p>This data helps scientists worldwide to refine their climate models -- while it also offers a glimpse into the future.</p>

<p>Since the 1950s all high mountain regions like "the Alps, the Rocky Mountains, the Andes, the Himalayas -- have already seen an average annual temperature increase of more than two degrees Celsius", which is twice the global average, observatory head Elke Ludewig told AFP.</p>

<p>"As nice as it is to still see snow and glaciers, we really have a critical situation here in terms of the rate at which temperatures are increasing," she said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/agqt1gag_austria-alpine-refuges_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Temperature rise has increased the danger of sudden rockfalls and landslides.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-to-africa-calls-for-britain-to-pay-reparations-are-growing-6939422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India To Africa, Calls For Britain To Pay Reparations Are Growing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-to-africa-calls-for-britain-to-pay-reparations-are-growing-6939422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:08:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Patrick Robinson, a UN judge, indicated last year that the United Kingdom may owe over $24 trillion in reparations for its role in the trans-Atlantic slave trade.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3bsdpl08_uk_625x300_04_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The most memorable moment of King Charles and Queen Camilla's recent royal tour of Australia and Samoa was Australian indigenous senator Lidia Thorpe's insult to the monarchy. She was escorted out of Canberra's Parliament House after she heckled the King and accused him of genocide. The British media was incensed, calling her “outburst” simply “rude” and “ill-mannered”.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>True, Senator Thorpe's behaviour may be unwarranted. However, it ensured that the royal visit was anything but forgettable. A couple of days later, the issue of reparations raised by the former British colonies at the two-day biennial Commonwealth Summit in Samoa was another rough treatment the British royalty received in quick succession.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Direct Message In Samoa</strong></h2>

<p>Set roughly midway between New Zealand and Hawaii, the summit in Samoa last month saw King Charles and UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer join leaders from 56 Commonwealth nations. It coincided with the BRICS Summit in Kazan and therefore received little coverage in India. Anyway, the setting may have been remote, but the message on reparations was direct and one that won't be easy to ignore. Good that the leaders of two heavyweight Commonwealth countries, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and South African President Cyril Ramaphosa, were attending the BRICS summit. Their presence would have made things more difficult for the UK government. India was represented at the summit by Union Minister of Parliamentary Affairs, Kiren Rijiju.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, calls for the UK to pay monetary compensation and extend a formal apology over its role in the trans-Atlantic slave trade resurfaced with fresh urgency at the summit. The UK, expectedly, had vetoed the proposal to directly address reparations in the summit's final communique. Instead, the document tiptoed around the issue, referencing only the possibility of “future discussions” on “reparatory justice” regarding the trans-Atlantic trade in enslaved Africans.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prime Minister Keir Starmer rejected calls for an apology and reparations, telling delegates that it was futile to have "very long, endless discussions" about the past. Instead, he urged the former colonies to focus on issues of the present, such as climate change, which his government could help. Speaking at the summit in Samoa, King Charles sounded more conciliatory: “None of us can change the past. But we can commit, with all our hearts, to learning its lessons and to finding creative ways to right the inequalities that endure.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>For the leaders of former colonies, however, this side-step will not likely put the topic to rest anytime soon</p>

<h2><strong>Apologies From Just A Few</strong></h2>

<p>Privately, some families who owned thousands of slaves have apologised for their part in the slave trade. For example, last year, descendants of the family of 19th-century British Prime Minister William Gladstone visited Barbados, St. Lucia and other Caribbean islands to acknowledge and apologise for their ancestor's involvement in slavery. John Gladstone, William's father, owned slaves on plantations in the Caribbean. William Gladstone, however, was a prominent abolitionist. Caribbean leaders welcomed the apology, calling it a step towards healing and reconciliation.</p>

<p>Like Britain, most European colonial powers have expressed regret over their past sins. But they have not formally apologised for it. The only notable exceptions are the Netherlands and Belgium. They have apologised for both colonial atrocities and slave trade involvement, though no monetary compensation has been promised.</p>

<h2><strong>Britain Owes Former Colonies $24 Trillion</strong></h2>

<p>Patrick Robinson, a UN judge, indicated last year that the United Kingdom may owe over $24 trillion in reparations for its role in the trans-Atlantic slave trade. In a report co-authored by him and published last year in June, he says he considers this figure a conservative assessment, noting the vast and lasting damage inflicted by the slave trade. The report calculates that in total, reparations to be paid by 31 former slaveholding colonial powers—including Spain, the United States and France—amount to $107.8 trillion. Expressing astonishment, Robinson remarked that certain states involved in slavery appear to ignore their obligations, stating, "Once a state has committed a wrongful act, it's obliged to pay reparations."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Robinson, known for presiding over the trial of former Yugoslav President Slobodan Milosevic, emphasised the principle that reparations are a duty, not an option. He has been a member of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) since 2015 and has been researching reparations as part of his honorary presidency of the American Society of International Law. It is nearly obvious that the former colonial powers, who are among some of the richest countries in the world, thanks to their colonial exploits, appear to be in no mood to pay compensation packages to the nations affected by the slave trade&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>"Am I Not A Man And A Brother"</strong></h2>

<p>The expansionist British Empire's exploitative system was based on three sins against humanity—colonisation, slave trade and indentured labour. Indentured labour was targeted against India more specifically.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One of the most enduring symbols from the 19th century's abolitionist movement is the sketch of a Black man in chains. If you take a closer look, it shows an enslaved Black man, kneeling in chains, with the words "Am I not a man and a brother" encircling him. The image and the plea punch a deep yearning for the enslaved African and Caribbean man's freedom and equality. This emblem challenged the cruelty of slavery and called for justice.</p>

<p>The British Empire bears a dark legacy as one of the largest forces in the trans-Atlantic slave trade, a tragedy that caused immense suffering and disruptions. Yet, it is only fair to acknowledge at the outset that Britain was also home to a powerful abolitionist movement that rallied the public at the grassroots level and pushed Parliament to abolish slavery in 1833. The Slavery Abolition Act undoubtedly marked a significant turn in the global fight against enslavement. It outlawed slavery in most of the British Empire.</p>

<p>But the abolition of one sin gave birth to another, equally evil in nature, indentured labour, which directly impacted India.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Slaves vs Coolies</strong></h2>

<p>Which is worse: the brutal reality of the slave trade or the ruthless grind of indentured labour—the so-called “coolies” of the British Raj? Each system wore a different mask, but all served the same purpose: to sustain the empire on the backs of exploited labour. The slave trade was raw oppression, tearing people from their homelands, stripping them of their identity and treating them as property. Then came indentured labour, not quite as blatant, but equally unforgiving. This “sanitised” slavery trapped workers in harsh conditions with barely a trace of freedom—a palatable replacement for the colonial conscience.</p>

<p>The British Empire ended the slave trade with the 1833 Abolition Act, yet hardly skipped a beat before instituting indentured labour the very next year, in 1834. Records show that private plantation owners actively lobbied the Empire for cheap labour from India, which soon became the backbone of colonial projects in far-flung corners of the Empire. Hundreds of thousands of Indian labourers—mostly poor, unlettered and desperate—were 'contracted' to work on plantations in the Caribbean countries and railroads, especially in East Africa. Many were coerced into these agreements, often only needing to affix a thumbprint to a piece of paper they couldn't read. What they signed away was their freedom, shackled to a five-year contract with slim hope for escape from abusive conditions. The British National Library has huge archives of papers pointing to several incidents of revolt by the labourers, many of whom were killed or maimed as punishment.<br />
<br />
So, which system bears the greater sin? Hard to say. But perhaps the most enduring sin is the claims by a few apologists in the West—which include some right-wing politicians—that these practices helped famine-stricken Indians improve their lives and that the entire colonial project was part of “civilising” the coolies.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/erl4htio_uk_625x300_04_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-is-the-iranian-woman-arrested-for-stripping-to-protest-moral-policing-6939288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Two Days After Iranian Woman's Arrest For Stripping, Her Whereabouts Unknown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-is-the-iranian-woman-arrested-for-stripping-to-protest-moral-policing-6939288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:48:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two days ago, a video surfaced showing an Iranian woman stripping down to her underwear to protest harassment by the moral police at a university in Tehran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two days ago, a video surfaced showing an Iranian woman stripping down to her underwear to protest harassment by the moral police at a university in Tehran. Footage on social media showed her being bundled into a car by men in plain clothes and being driven off to an undisclosed location.</p>

<p>The woman, who has not been identified, was allegedly harassed inside Tehran's prestigious Islamic Azad University by members of the Basij paramilitary force who ripped her headscarf and clothes, according to reports by several news outlets and social media channels outside Iran.</p>

<p>Azad University's public relations director Amir Mahjob said in a post on X that the student, separated from her husband and a mother of two, “had a mental disorder". Local newspaper Farhikhtegan too stated that she had been admitted to a mental health facility.</p>

<p>Two days later, her whereabouts remain unknown, which has prompted Amnesty International's Iran chapter to call for her immediate release. "Authorities must protect her from torture and other ill-treatment, and ensure access to family and lawyer. Allegations of beatings and sexual violence against her during arrest need independent and impartial investigations," the organisation said.</p>

<p>Mai Sato, the United Nations Special Rapporteur on the Islamic Republic of Iran, said on X that she would be “monitoring this incident closely, including the authorities' response.”</p>

<p>It is mandatory for women in Iran to wear a headscarf and loose-fitting clothes in public, the violation of which had led to the arrest of Iranian-Kurdish Mahsa Amini in 2022. Later, she died in custody, leading to vehement protests across the country where women removed and event burnt their headscarves. Iranian actress Hengameh Ghaziani was among those detained for removing her hijab on Instagram in solidarity with the movement. A subsequent crackdown left over 500 protesters dead.</p>

<p>Iran's morality police or Gasht-e-Ershad was established in 2006 to ensure the strict implementation of veiling laws that have existed since the 1980s. They patrol public places and have been present increasingly in schools and colleges, and monitor women's attire.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Since then, women have been protesting these laws, by wearing tight clothes or showing their hair in public and on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hfoa5qi8_iran-woman-protesting_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The woman, who has not been identified, was allegedly harassed inside Tehran's Islamic Azad University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dna-test-revealed-two-women-were-swapped-at-birth-6939126]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A DNA Test Revealed Two Women Were Swapped At Birth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-dna-test-revealed-two-women-were-swapped-at-birth-6939126]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:45:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two families in the West Midlands are seeking compensation after a DNA test revealed two baby girls were switched at birth in an NHS hospital 55 years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two families in the West Midlands are seeking compensation after a DNA test revealed two baby girls were switched at birth in an NHS hospital 55 years ago. Mr Tony, who took a DNA home-testing kit out of curiosity, discovered his supposed sister, Ms Jessica, was not biologically related to him. Instead, the test revealed a stranger, Ms Claire, as his full sibling. Further investigation confirmed Claire and Jessica were born in the same hospital around the same time.</p>

<p>Ms Joan, Mr Tony's mother, expressed her joy at having a daughter when Jessica was born in 1967. “It was a wonderful feeling, at long last having a girl,” she recalled to the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp3njqd9nl9o  " rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;(Jessica and Claire are not their real names - both have been changed, to protect the women's identity)..&nbsp;</p>

<p>Using the messaging service from the DNA company, Mr Tony reached out to Ms Claire, who had also taken the same DNA test two years earlier. Ms Claire had experienced her own confusion when she received her results, having no connection to her supposed ancestry and discovering a genetic link to a first cousin she didn't recognise. Ms Claire, who had always felt like an “imposter” in her family, recalled thinking, “Yes, I'm adopted.”</p>

<p>Ms Claire was resolute in her desire to meet Mr Tony and their shared mother, Joan. “I just wanted to see them, meet them, talk to them and embrace them,” she said.</p>

<p>When Mr Tony finally revealed the truth to Ms Joan, she was desperate for answers. She recalled the night of Ms Jessica's birth with vivid detail: “They took me in on a Sunday… It snowed that day.” After holding her newborn daughter for just a few minutes, she was taken to the nursery, and the next morning, she was mistakenly given Ms Jessica instead of Ms Claire.</p>

<p>The families have since met, and Ms Claire has been integrating into her biological family. “It just felt right,” said Ms Joan, Ms Claire's biological mother. “I thought she looked just like I did in my younger days.”</p>

<p>The NHS trust has admitted liability for the baby swap, describing it as an “appalling error.” Compensation negotiations are ongoing.</p>

<p>Ms Joan stressed that her love for Ms Jessica, the woman she raised, remains unchanged. “She's still my daughter and she always will be.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/u5neef4g_twins-generic_625x300_03_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The investigation confirmed Claire and Jessica were born in the same hospital around the same time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monkeys-know-who-will-win-us-election-2024-heres-how-6939238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Monkeys Know Who Will Win US Election 2024. Here's How]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/monkeys-know-who-will-win-us-election-2024-heres-how-6939238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:40:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Election Day looms with Kamala Harris and Donald Trump locked in a dead heat, pollsters and pundits are scrambling for clues to predict the outcome.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Election Day looms with <a href="https://theconversation.com/why-the-margin-of-error-matters-more-than-ever-in-reading-2024-election-polls-a-pollster-with-30-years-of-experience-explains-240633">Kamala Harris and Donald Trump locked in a dead heat</a>, pollsters and pundits are scrambling for clues to predict the outcome.</p>

<p>But what if the answer lies not in political data or campaign strategies, but in the instincts of a primitive part of the human brain?</p>

<p>New research I conducted with rhesus macaque monkeys suggests that when it comes to decisions like voting, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.17.613526">people are not nearly as rational</a> as they would like to believe.</p>

<p>It's easy to associate instinctual reactions – like the fight-or-flight response or reflexively pulling away from a hot surface – with the primitive motive for survival. But humans also have a rational brain that can gather and weigh evidence, deliberating thoughtfully rather than relying on knee-jerk reactions. Why that rational brain seems to be hijacked by primitive instincts in situations where rationality would serve people better is one of the many reasons <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=U9Hu2rcAAAAJ&amp;hl=en&amp;oi=ao">my neuroscience colleagues and I</a> have been studying rhesus macaques for the past 25 years.</p>

<p>These monkeys are <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49922-6">remarkably similar to people</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/hmg/ddn167">genetically</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2019.0612">physiologically</a> and <a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/1866-1955-4-21">behaviorally</a>. These similarities have allowed researchers to make incredible medical breakthroughs, including the development of <a href="https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1458-24.2024">vaccines for polio, HIV/AIDS and COVID-19</a>, as well as <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1902300116">deep brain stimulation treatment for Parkinson's disease</a> and other neurological disorders.</p>

<p>My research on candidate preference is part of an overall focus on <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-25607-1">enhancing scientists'</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abl5794">understanding of</a> the ability to <a href="https://doi.org/10.1101/2023.07.17.549328">interact effectively with others and to navigate social conflicts</a>, the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-020-00746-9">neural circuits</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-024-07178-6">that support it</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-022-01197-0">and how these circuits can deteriorate</a> due to disease or external factors like inequality – all to better support those affected by these challenges.</p>

<p><strong>Power of first impressions</strong></p>

<p>Previous research revealed that human adults and preschoolers alike can <a href="https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1110589">accurately predict election outcomes</a> after <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0705435104">quick exposure to candidate photos</a>. Plenty of evidence supports the idea that our primitive brain drives us to quickly form first impressions based on physical appearance – it was key to survival, after all.</p>

<p>But researchers don't yet understand why this bias persists. New research with rhesus macaques has provided some answers.</p>

<p>In the study, which is under review at the journal Proceedings of the Royal Society B, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.17.613526">we showed monkeys pairs of candidate photos</a> from U.S. gubernatorial and senatorial elections, and they correctly predicted the outcomes based solely on visual features.</p>

<p>Specifically, the monkeys spent more time looking at the loser than the winner. This “gaze bias” predicted not only the election outcomes but also the candidates' vote share. Monkeys tended to look at the candidates with more masculine facial features – and these were the candidates more likely to win in the real elections. Jaw prominence had a direct relationship with vote share.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="black and white headshots of a woman and a man, with green markings on her face and a small purple mark on his" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=429&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=429&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=429&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=539&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=539&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629387/original/file-20241031-17-cemesh.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=539&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Green and purple markings trace the monkey's gaze. Monkeys spent longer looking at the losing candidate than the eventual winner – in this case, Mitt Romney, who defeated Shannon O'Brien in 2002 to become governor of Massachusetts.</span> <span class="attribution"><span class="source">Y. Jiang</span></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2013.03.022">Previous research</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2005.01.044">helps explain the monkeys' gaze bias</a>. When monkeys were shown pictures of unfamiliar but powerful male monkeys, they would only glance briefly at them, presumably because monkeys interpret staring as a sign of aggression. But their gaze lingered when shown a low-status male monkey or a female.</p>

<p>Those preferences were on full display when we showed the macaques photos from the most recent races involving Donald Trump. Their gaze bias, driven by primitive instincts, indicated the winners. The monkeys looked the longest at the Democratic opponent in the contest between Trump and Hillary Clinton. There was less of a gaze bias in the matchup with Joe Biden. And the monkeys looked for about the same amount of time at Trump as at Harris. That means among the three most recent Democratic candidates, based solely on visual features, the monkeys predicted Harris stands the best chance of winning against Trump.</p>

<p><strong>An evolutionary hangover</strong></p>

<p>Our findings suggest that voters instinctively react to cues of physical strength – <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-018-06987-4">cues that are equally evident</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10764-019-00104-y">to our monkey relatives</a>. This “evolutionary hangover” illustrates how traits and behaviors that were once essential for survival persist even when they are no longer relevant.</p>

<p>The macaques' ability to predict winners based on physical attributes alone challenges the notion that humans have evolved beyond superficial judgments in leadership selection. For those who pride themselves on rational decision-making, especially in vital decisions like voting, it's a startling discovery.</p>

<p>Clearly people's choices are not based solely on visual cues. But the evidence suggests that such factors could be more influential than you think. When you enter the voting booth, part of your brain might be drawing on ancient instincts, subconsciously evaluating who looks like they could best lead the tribe.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="side by side headshots of Trump and Harris" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/629382/original/file-20241031-15-alalfn.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">An informed voter goes on more than just looks.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://newsroom.ap.org/detail/Election2024ExplainerTop25/77d9396905ca47df923fcde646ebc52a/photo?Query=Harris%20Trump%20debate&amp;mediaType=photo&amp;sortBy=creationdatetime:desc&amp;dateRange=Anytime&amp;totalCount=584&amp;currentItemNo=15">AP Photo/Alex Brandon</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Staying rational, not primal</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/article/this-is-your-brain-on-decision-making/">Raising awareness</a> of these <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0806761106">primal preferences</a> is the first step in <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2017/10/18/look-before-you-leap-17-ways-to-slow-down-impulsive-decisions/">reducing their influence</a>.</p>

<p>Political campaigns already tap into these instincts by highlighting a candidate's physical strength and assertiveness. As voters, we can counteract their efforts by leaning into our rational brain's capacity to understand and assess their policies and experience – something our primitive ancestors couldn't do.</p>

<p>Techniques for choosing rationally rather than instinctively include exposing yourself to diverse perspectives, actively questioning your assumptions and considering the long-term outcomes of policies. Such deliberate steps toward making informed decisions take on new importance when you understand how your brain can be swayed at the ballot box by outdated preferences.</p>

<p>Of course, voters are not macaques. But the underlying instincts people share with our primate relatives could still subtly shape our decisions.</p>

<p>Acknowledging the role of these ancient cues can help people become more intentional in how they exercise their power in the voting booth. As democracy evolves, so too should humans' understanding of how to engage with it.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/242653/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(Author:&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/michael-platt-2248742">Michael Platt</a>, Professor of Marketing and Psychology and Neuroscience, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-pennsylvania-1017">University of Pennsylvania</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/monkeys-know-who-will-win-the-election-primal-instincts-humans-share-with-them-shape-voters-choices-242653">original article</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/usf1lj9g_monkey_625x300_11_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/still-waiting-democrat-mayor-demands-donald-trump-pay-nearly-500-000-in-unpaid-bills-6939193]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Democrat Mayor Demands Trump Pay $500,000 In Unpaid Bills For Rallies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/still-waiting-democrat-mayor-demands-donald-trump-pay-nearly-500-000-in-unpaid-bills-6939193]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:34:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump left an unpaid bill of $211,176 in public safety costs in 2019 when he conducted a rally at the Santa Ana Star Center in Albuquerque]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With only a day left for the US presidential election, Republican nominee Donald Trump has once again come under the scanner for not paying bills after conducting his mega political rallies. When Trump returned to Albuquerque, New Mexico, for the first time in five years to conduct a rally last week, Democrat Mayor Tim Keller demanded that the Republican leader clear his previous dues. Keller took to his official social media handle and took a jab at Trump while posting an image of a skeleton working on a laptop, implying it had been several years of waiting for the Republican leader to clear his longstanding dues.</p>

<p>"Still waiting for Trump to pay the half million he owes. Maybe he's making a special Halloween delivery to the Duke City? We won't hold our breath," Keller posted on X (formerly Twitter), which invited cheeky responses from the netizens.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Still waiting for Trump to pay the half million he owes. Maybe he's making a special Halloween delivery to the Duke City? We won't hold our breath. <a href="https://t.co/3Yqzp0ISnj">pic.twitter.com/3Yqzp0ISnj</a></p>
— Mayor Tim Keller (@MayorKeller) <a href="https://twitter.com/MayorKeller/status/1852034643014406512?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>According to the city of Albuquerque, Trump left an unpaid bill of $211,176 in public safety costs in 2019 when he conducted a rally at the Santa Ana Star Center in Rio Rancho, which is a part of the Albuquerque metropolitan area.</p>

<p>The amount had since swelled to $444,986 including interest over the years. The mayor's office stated that police officers, first responders and other city employees who assisted with the rally, worked a combined overtime of 1,500 hours that night for the rally, which had not been compensated so far.</p>

<p>Last month, a report in <em>NBC</em> claimed that Mr Trump owed at least five cities, including those in the swing state of Pennsylvania, more than $750,000 for campaign events since 2016. Quizzed about the mounting dues, the Trump campaign said questions "related to local law enforcement and first responder costs should be directed to US Secret Service".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-donald-trump-leads-kamala-harris-in-all-swing-states-6938403" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Battleground Breakdown: What You Need To Know About The 7 Swing States</strong></a></p>

<h2><strong>US election</strong></h2>

<p>After months of intense and bitter poll campaigning, America goes to polls on Tuesday (Nov 5). As per <em>AtlasIntel's </em>latest poll, Mr Trump is leading Kamala Harris in all the seven swing states. In Arizona, Trump holds his widest margin - with a 51.9 per cent to 45.1 per cent lead over Harris.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in Nevada, 51.4 per cent of voters chose Trump while 45.9 per cent opted for Harris. Despite the lead in polls, experts believe that the final election outcome might be much closer than anticipated.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v5klevj8_donald-trump-afp_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-how-votes-will-be-counted-6938996]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Presidential Election: How Votes Will Be Counted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-how-votes-will-be-counted-6938996]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:29:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States is hours away from going out to cast the ballot.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States is hours away from going out to cast the ballot. Democratic nominee Kamala Harris and Republican candidate Donald Trump have been tirelessly campaigning for the past few months, reaching out to voters and presenting their case. &nbsp;</p>

<p>This time, nearly 95 per cent of registered voters live in areas where paper ballots will be the primary way to vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Here's a breakdown of how votes are cast and counted in the US elections.</strong></p>

<p><strong>How US Elections Are Organised</strong></p>

<p>Unlike many countries with centralised election bodies, the US has a highly decentralised election system. While the Federal Election Commission oversees campaign finance laws, state and local authorities manage the election process. Each state sets its election regulations, from voter eligibility to ballot design and counting procedures. Thus, voting and vote-counting processes can vary widely across the country.</p>

<p><strong>Voting Methods In The 2024 Elections</strong></p>

<p>Voters in the US cast their ballots through three primary methods:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Handmarked Paper Ballots: The most common method, used by 69.9 per cent of voters, involves marking paper ballots by hand.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Ballot Marking Devices (BMDs): Used by 25.1 per cent of voters, BMDs are computerised systems that allow voters to select options on a screen, and then print a paper ballot to confirm their choices. This method, implemented under the Help America Vote Act (HAVA), includes accessibility features for individuals with disabilities.</li>
	<li>Direct Recording Electronic (DRE) Systems: This electronic method, similar to India's EVMs, stores votes electronically without a paper trail. DRE use has declined sharply due to security concerns, with only 5 per cent of voters relying on these systems in Louisiana and Nevada.</li>
</ul>

<p>The 2000 election, marked by the infamous "butterfly ballot" issues in Florida, stressed the need for ballot clarity and led to an initial shift toward electronic voting. Security concerns - especially following reports of interference in the 2016 election - marked a return to paper-based systems. Today, electronic voting is limited, with most jurisdictions relying on hand-marked ballots or BMDs.</p>

<p><strong>How Votes Are Counted</strong></p>

<p>Votes cast on hand-marked paper ballots and BMDs are typically scanned using optical scanners that automatically record and tabulate results. This process is followed by a state-level audit, which may include machine-assisted or manual verification. States have different timelines for certifying results, with the final official vote tally required by December 11 this year.</p>

<p><strong>In-Person Votes</strong></p>

<p>Votes cast on Election Day or during early voting are counted after the polls close. Paper ballots are sent to counting centres, while digital voting machine data is transmitted electronically or hand-delivered for processing.</p>

<p><strong>Mail-In Ballots</strong></p>

<p>Mail-in ballot processing and counting rules vary by state. Many states allow officials to verify ballots before Election Day, but counting often begins on Election Day, with results held until after polls close.</p>

<p><strong>Verification Of Mail-In Ballots</strong></p>

<p>Every state requires a signature on mail-in ballots. Many use signature matching, and some require additional verification, such as a witness signature or notarisation depending on the state's rules.</p>

<p><strong>Ballot Curing</strong></p>

<p>In states allowing ballot curing, voters can fix errors, like mismatched signatures, to ensure their ballot is counted. Some states require curing by Election Day, while others allow it after. Eight states do not allow ballot curing.</p>

<p><strong>Provisional Ballots</strong></p>

<p>Provisional ballots are used if voter eligibility is uncertain, and they are hand-counted after verification. Military and overseas ballots also add to the timeline due to their verification requirements.</p>

<p><strong>The Electoral College&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>The US President is chosen by 538 electors representing all states and the District of Columbia, based on each state's population. Except in Maine and Nebraska, each state operates under a "winner-take-all" system, awarding all its electoral votes to the candidate who wins the popular vote in that state. To win, a candidate must secure at least 270 electoral votes.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Certification And Inauguration</strong></p>

<p>On January 6, a joint session of Congress, presided over by the Vice President, counted the electoral votes. If a candidate reaches 270 votes, they are declared the President-elect, even if they lost the national popular vote. Inauguration takes place on January 20, when the President-elect is sworn into office for a four-year term.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ockvg5ro_us-voters-reuters_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Voters in the US cast their ballots through three primary methods]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cassius-worlds-largest-captive-crocodile-dies-in-australian-6939050]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cassius, World's Largest Captive Crocodile, Dies In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cassius-worlds-largest-captive-crocodile-dies-in-australian-6939050]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:24:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cassius, the world's largest known crocodile in captivity, has died in a Queensland wildlife sanctuary in Australia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cassius, the world's largest known crocodile in captivity, has died in a Queensland wildlife sanctuary in Australia. The massive saltwater crocodile, nearly 5.5 metres (18 feet) in length and weighing close to one tonne, was estimated to be over 110 years old, although his exact age remained unknown, according to a report in the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clyvzyyd6l7o" rel="nofollow,noindex">BBC</a>.</p>

<p>Cassius lived at the Marineland Melanesia Crocodile Habitat on Green Island since being captured in Australia's Northern Territory during the 1980s.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://www.facebook.com/marinelandgreenisland" rel="nofollow,noindex">post on Facebook</a>, Marineland Melanesia paid tribute to Cassius, describing him as “our beloved mate” and “a cherished member of our family.”</p>

<p>The post read, “It is with deep sadness that we share the passing of our beloved mate Cassius. He was more than just a crocodile, he was a cherished member of our family and brought joy and companionship to his best mate George for over 37 years. George had only recently relocated into Cairns from Marineland after 52 years living on Green Island to an assisted care residence on the 5th of October.”</p>

<p>“Cassius's condition declined since the 15th of October. He was very old and believed to be living beyond the years of a wild Croc. Cassius will be deeply missed, but our love and memories of him will remain in our hearts forever. Thank you to everyone who visited Cassius throughout his life and offered kindness along the way. Please be advised that we may be operating in a limited capacity over the next few days and we apologise for any inconvenience this may cause,” they concluded.</p>

<p>Cassius's life in the wild was filled with adventure. The crocodile was known for hunting cattle and even damaging boat propellers before his eventual capture. The sanctuary's founder, George Craig, bought him in 1987, bringing him to his new home on Green Island.</p>

<p>Known for his immense size, Cassius earned the <a href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/largest-crocodile-in-captivity" rel="nofollow,noindex">Guinness World Record</a> in 2011 as the largest captive crocodile. According to the Guinness World Record, “Cassius, an Australian saltwater crocodile (Crocodylus porosus), is the largest crocodile in captivity at 5.48 m (17 ft 11.75 in). The Australian saltwater crocodile is the largest and most fearsome of today's species. Specimens can live for more than 100 years, can grow to 7 m (23 ft) and weigh more than 1 tonne (1.1 ton).”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ipd86oa_cassius-worlds-largest-captive-crocodile_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cassius lived at the Marineland Melanesia Crocodile Habitat on Green Island.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-happens-in-the-booth-stays-in-the-booth-kamala-harris-banks-on-womens-votes-6938997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["What Happens In Booth, Stays In Booth": Kamala Harris Banks On Women's Votes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-happens-in-the-booth-stays-in-the-booth-kamala-harris-banks-on-womens-votes-6938997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 11:00:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In an ad for Kamala Harris, a woman marks her ballot for the Democratic candidate while her husband thinks she's voting for Republican Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In an ad for Kamala Harris, a woman marks her ballot for the Democratic candidate while her husband thinks she's voting for Republican Donald Trump: "What happens in the booth, stays in the booth" a voiceover says.</p>

<p>The 30-second-clip, narrated by actor Julia Roberts, shows the couple arriving at a polling station wearing baseball caps featuring the American flag, a symbol often sported by Trump supporters.</p>

<p>The ad, financed by a religious nonprofit, has elicited fury in the Trump camp, with the former president calling it "stupid" and asking "Can you imagine a wife not telling her husband who she's voting for?"</p>

<p>In the ad, the wife exchanges knowing glances with another female voter, before filling in her choice for Harris.</p>

<p>"You can vote any way you want, and no one will ever know," the voiceover says, before the husband asks "Did you make the right choice?"</p>

<p>"Sure did, honey," the woman replies.</p>

<p><strong>Unprecedented gender gap</strong></p>

<p>On conservative Fox News, a host recently said his wife secretly voting for Harris would be "the same thing as having an affair," while former Republican House speaker Newt Gingrich said the Harris spot was an example of the depth of her camp's "corruption."</p>

<p>Anti-Trump political group The Lincoln Project aired a similar ad showing two upper-middle class men who assure each other their wives are voting for Trump. The women -- and other females at the voting precinct -- then fill in their ballots for Harris.</p>

<p>The videos, and the furious reaction from Trump supporters, illustrate two key facets of the US presidential campaign.</p>

<p>One is that Trump and Harris are truly fighting for every last vote, in what is perhaps the most down-to-the-wire presidential race in modern US history.</p>

<p>The other is that Harris is counting heavily on mobilizing women in the ultra-tight race that will see a gender gap in votes like never before.</p>

<p>According to a latest poll by NBC, there is a 34-percentage point difference between male and female intended voters.</p>

<p>Harris has a 16-point lead among women while Trump has an 18-point lead among men.</p>

<p>The unprecedented gap comes with Harris's campaign having leaned heavily on reproductive and abortion rights, following the Supreme Court strike-down of the federal right to the procedure in 2022.</p>

<p><strong>Clooney surprise</strong></p>

<p>More broadly, the election is a clash between the "traditional and kind of patriarchal masculinity" espoused by Trump and Harris's policies which are "less aligned with stereotypical gender roles," said Kelly Dittmar, a political science professor at Rutgers University.</p>

<p>Former Republican congresswoman Liz Cheney, who has stumped for Harris, is openly betting on "secret" votes for the Democrat.</p>

<p>"I think you're going to have, frankly, a lot of men and women who will go into the voting booth and will vote their conscience and will vote for Vice President Harris," said Cheney, who is the daughter of former vice president Dick Cheney.</p>

<p>"They may not ever say anything publicly but the results will speak for themselves," she said.</p>

<p>Former first lady Michelle Obama recently hammered home the point, reminding the female electorate: "If you are a woman who lives in a household of men that don't listen to you or value your opinion, just remember that your vote is a private matter."</p>

<p>The Harris campaign's quest for "secret" voters doesn't stop with women. The group that funded the Julia Roberts-narrated ad, Vote Common Good, recently released a second spot, this time featuring two male voters casting their ballots for her without telling their Trump-supporting buddies.</p>

<p>The ad is narrated by another star, George Clooney.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/06v6q8sc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_25_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-elects-a-president-a-look-at-the-race-to-the-white-house-6938839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How US Elects A President: A Look At The Race To The White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-us-elects-a-president-a-look-at-the-race-to-the-white-house-6938839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:59:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the date for the US presidential election nears, the race between Democratic nominee Kamala Harris and her Republican counterpart Donald Trump has heated up.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the date for the US presidential election nears, the race between Democratic nominee Kamala Harris and her Republican counterpart Donald Trump has heated up. Even though American citizens prepare to cast their votes on November 5, the electoral journey began many months ago, and it involves a complex process.</p>

<p><strong>Early preparations</strong></p>

<p>A year before the election, candidates from the two main political parties, the Democrats and Republicans, start their campaigns. They assemble teams, launch fundraising initiatives and embark on nationwide tours to garner support.</p>

<p><strong>Campaign kick-off</strong></p>

<p>As campaigns ramp up, candidates engage in televised debates, which serve as a platform to articulate their policies and defend positions on various issues.</p>

<p><strong>Election process</strong></p>

<p>The US presidential election process can seem overwhelming, with terms like ‘Electoral College,' ‘National Conventions,' ‘Primary' and ‘Caucus' often confusing. Let's understand them better first:</p>

<p><strong>Here's what they mean:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Primaries: Primaries allow party members to vote for their preferred candidate in a secret ballot, similar to a general election. The results determine the allocation of delegates who will support candidates at the national conventions.</li>
	<li>Caucuses: Caucuses involve party members gathering to discuss and publicly vote for their preferred candidate. This interactive process also impacts the number of delegates each candidate receives for the conventions.</li>
	<li>National Conventions: National conventions are important for each political party. Delegates endorse their chosen candidates, leading to the official announcement of the presidential nominee. The selected candidate also names their Vice President or running mate.</li>
	<li>Electoral College: The Electoral College is a mechanism through which electors from each state cast their votes to elect the President. Each state is allocated a specific number of electors based on its Congressional representation, totalling 538 electors nationwide. After the general election, each elector casts one vote, with a majority of 270 needed to win.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Here's a breakdown of the election timeline:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>Spring of the year before the election: Candidates announce their intentions to run, starting their campaigns. They officially register with the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to run for president.</li>
	<li>Summer of the year before the election to spring of election year: Primary and Caucus debates are held across the country.</li>
	<li>January to June of election year: States and political parties conduct presidential Primaries and Caucuses, allowing voters to express their preferences for candidates.</li>
	<li>July to early September: Each party hosts nominating conventions to select their presidential candidates. It is during these conventions that the chosen presidential candidates usually announce their Vice-Presidential nominees.</li>
	<li>September and October: Candidates participate in a series of presidential debates, providing voters with an opportunity to assess their stance on issues and policies they will work on, should they get elected.</li>
	<li>Early November: The voting takes place on the first Tuesday of November in the election year.</li>
	<li>December: Members of the Electoral College cast their votes for president, finalising the nation's leader.</li>
	<li>Early January of the next calendar year: Congress officially counts the electoral votes, confirming the results.</li>
	<li>January 20: On Presidential Inauguration Day, the newly elected president is sworn in.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/31viumgo_-white-house_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Presidential Inauguration Day, the newly elected president is sworn in.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-to-spend-election-night-at-howard-the-black-harvard-6938940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris To Spend Election Night At Howard, The Black Harvard]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-kamala-harris-to-spend-election-night-at-howard-the-black-harvard-6938940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:52:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will watch Tuesday's election night from the campus of Howard University -- her alma mater -- a fitting place for possibly the most significant night of her life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris will watch Tuesday's election night from the campus of Howard University -- her alma mater -- a fitting place for possibly the most significant night of her life.</p>

<p>Nicknamed "the Black Harvard," the Washington school occupies a central role in the US vice president's biography: Since graduating there in 1986, she has frequently returned at key moments.</p>

<p>"Howard University is one of the most important aspects of my life," she said in 2019 as a candidate in the Democratic presidential primaries, "and it is where I first ran for my first elected office," as a student council representative.</p>

<p>"So this is where it all began."</p>

<p>Her presence there Tuesday night -- when Harris could become the first Black woman to be elected US president -- is thus deeply symbolic.</p>

<p>The US Congress founded Howard in 1867, two years after the Civil War had put an end to slavery in the mostly Southern states where it remained legal.</p>

<p>The school took its name from Oliver Howard, a Northerner known as "the Christian general" who had promoted higher education for freed slaves.</p>

<p>Howard has built a reputation as one of the best of the roughly 100 institutions known as Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), which draw mostly Black and minority students.</p>

<p>The campus of Howard, which has around 11,000 students, features several imposing red-brick buildings with traditional white columns arrayed around a large central lawn commonly known as The Yard.</p>

<p>It was in an amphitheater there that, in mid-August, Kamala Harris prepared for her lone debate against Republican rival Donald Trump -- telling students that someday, "you might be running for president of the United States."</p>

<p><strong>Celebrity graduates</strong></p>

<p>Among Howard's most illustrious graduates have been author and Nobel laureate Toni Morrison, and famed civil rights leader Thurgood Marshall, who in 1967 became the first Black justice appointed to the US Supreme Court.</p>

<p>It was Marshall's example, Harris later said, that inspired the future lawyer to choose Howard for her university studies in 1982.</p>

<p>There she joined the debate club and took part in anti-apartheid demonstrations.</p>

<p>She also joined Alpha Kappa Alpha (AKA), one of the nation's largest sororities, founded at Howard in 1908.</p>

<p>AKA makes no presidential endorsements, but its national membership of some 300,000 has given Harris a far-reaching network of activist supporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1vroln44_kamala-harris_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-just-carbon-dioxide-other-greenhouse-gases-are-too-warming-the-planet-6938899]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Not Just Carbon Dioxide, Other Greenhouse Gases Are Too Warming The Planet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-just-carbon-dioxide-other-greenhouse-gases-are-too-warming-the-planet-6938899]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:47:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While carbon dioxide (CO2) is the best-known greenhouse gas, several others, including methane and nitrous oxide, are also driving global warming and altering the Earth's climate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While carbon dioxide, or CO2, is the best known greenhouse gas, several others, including methane and nitrous oxide, are also driving global warming and altering the Earth's climate.</p>

<p>Atmospheric concentrations of all three hit new highs in 2023, locking in future temperature increases for years to come, the World Meteorological Organization reported in October.</p>

<p><strong>Methane</strong></p>

<p>CO2 accounts for about two-thirds of the warming attributed to greenhouse gases, said Piers Forster, an expert at the University of Leeds and author of reports by the IPCC, the UN's climate science panel.</p>

<p>Methane, or CH4, is the second most important greenhouse gas linked to human activity after CO2.</p>

<p>Around 40 percent of methane comes from natural sources, notably wetlands, but the majority (around 60 percent) is linked to human activities such as agriculture (ruminant breeding and rice cultivation), fossil fuels and waste.</p>

<p>Its warming power is more than 80 times greater over 20 years than that of CO2, but its lifespan is shorter, making it an important lever in attempts to limit global warming in the short term.</p>

<p>Reducing methane emissions "would have a strong short-term cooling effect, because atmospheric methane concentrations would drop quickly", said Mathijs Harmsen, a researcher at the PBL Netherlands Environmental Assessment Agency.</p>

<p>Policies should "focus on capturing the low hanging fruit, so the very low-cost measures such as reducing natural gas leaks", he said.</p>

<p>Despite a global commitment to reduce planet-heating emissions signed by many countries, including the European Union and the United States, the trend is not positive.</p>

<p>"Methane is rising faster in relative terms than any major greenhouse gas and is now 2.6-fold higher than in pre-industrial times," said an international group of researchers under the aegis of the Global Carbon Project, in a study published in the academic journal Environmental Research Letters.</p>

<p><strong>Nitrous oxide</strong></p>

<p>Nitrous oxide, or nitrous protoxide (N2O), is the third major greenhouse gas and almost 300 times more potent than CO2.</p>

<p>It is mainly emitted by synthetic nitrogen fertilisers and manure used in agriculture.</p>

<p>Other emissions come from human activities (the chemical industry, wastewater, fossil fuels) or natural sources (the soil and oceans).</p>

<p>"Global human-induced emissions, which are dominated by nitrogen additions to croplands, increased by 30 percent over the past four decades," concluded a major study in the journal Nature in 2020.</p>

<p>The key to the problem lies in more efficient use of fertilisers.</p>

<p>"Two-thirds of the climate change mitigation potential of N2O could be realised by reducing fertilisers on just 20 percent of the world's cropland, particularly in humid subtropical agricultural regions," wrote French researcher Philippe Ciais in 2021.</p>

<p><strong>Fluorinated gases</strong></p>

<p>Fluorinated greenhouse gases (PFCs, HFCs and SF6) are found in fridges, freezers, heat pumps, air conditioners and electrical networks.</p>

<p>Even when in small quantities, they stand out for their extremely high warming capacity.</p>

<p>For example, SF6, which is found in electrical transformers, has a greenhouse effect 24,000 times greater than CO2 over a 100-year period.</p>

<p>The Montreal Protocol signed in 1987, and ratified by 195 countries, has already significantly reduced the atmospheric presence of CFCs, another ozone-depleting fluorinated gas.</p>

<p>In 2016 the Kigali agreement also provided for the phasing out of HFCs.</p>

<p>And last year the EU sealed a pact to progressively ban the sale of equipment containing fluorinated gases, in particular HFCs, with the aim of eliminating them completely by 2050.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2h752rag_methane_625x300_25_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>