<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:56:38 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-student-leader-nahid-islam-key-faces-in-new-bangladesh-government-6274762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex-PM, Nobel Winner, Student Leader: Key Faces In New Bangladesh Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-student-leader-nahid-islam-key-faces-in-new-bangladesh-government-6274762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:39:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh Protest: A new "interim government" - to be advised, most likely, by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus - is taking shape in crisis-hit Bangladesh following Sheikh Hasina resigning as Prime Minister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new "interim government" - to be advised, most likely, by Nobel laureate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/muhammad-yunus" target="_blank">Muhammad Yunus</a> - is taking shape in crisis-hit <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/bangladesh" target="_blank">Bangladesh</a> following <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a> resigning as Prime Minister.</p>

<p>Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin gave his assent late Monday for that temporary administration. A meeting was held at his residence that was attended by the chiefs of the country's Army, Navy, and Air Force, as well as political party leaders and civil society members.</p>

<p>In speculation that has emerged (inevitably so) since Mrs Hasina quit, three key names are at the forefront, two of whom are the Army, which took charge after Mrs Hasina quit, and which may have given her a 45-minute ultimatum; and her nemesis and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia, who was jailed in 2018 on corruption charges and whose release was ordered by the President.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Khaleda Zia</strong></h3>

<p>In 1991 Mrs Zia, now 78 and unwell, became Bangladesh's first woman Prime Minister.</p>

<p>She won a second term in 1996 but the elections were boycotted and denounced as unfair by the major opposition parties, including Sheikh Hasina's Awami League. Her second term lasted 12 days; a caretaker government was installed and fresh elections were held, which Mrs Hasina won.</p>

<p>Mrs Zia returned to power five years later.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-khaleda-zia-jailed-bangladesh-ex-pm-set-to-be-released-amid-turmoil-6273897" target="_blank">Who Is Khaleda Zia, Jailed Ex-PM To Be Freed Amid Turmoil</a></p>

<p>In 2007 she was arrested on corruption charges. She was convicted and jailed in 2018, but multiple health concerns meant she has spent most of the time since in a hospital.</p>

<p>It is unclear if she will be well enough to assume the Prime Minister's post, should she be selected.</p>

<p>The third is Mr Yunus, who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for founding the Grameen Bank, a microfinance organisation working towards community development in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus is widely seen as protesting students' pick - a bid to ensure the focus of their agitation does not get ignored as Sheikh Hasina's rivals scramble to pick up power following her resignation.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Md Yunus</strong></h3>

<p>An economist with a PhD from Vanderbilt University - a private research institution in Tennessee in the United States - Mr Yunus taught there briefly before returning to Bangladesh to head the department at Chittagong University.</p>

<p>He set up the Grameen Bank in 1983. The bank provides tiny loans (as small as Rs 2,000) to women in rural Bangladesh to start small businesses. This helped millions lift themselves out of poverty, earning him the nickname 'banker to the poor'. The model is now replicated in over 100 countries.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/unstable-bangladesh-can-lead-to-volcanic-eruption-says-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-6271452" target="_blank">Unstable Bangladesh Can Lead To "Volcanic Eruption", Says Nobel Laureate</a></p>

<p>However, in June he was indicted on charges of corruption and embezzlement of 252.2 million taka (Rs 219.4 crore) from the workers' welfare fund of his telecoms company, Grameen Telecom.</p>

<p>The 83-year-old has denied wrongdoing and claimed the charges are politically motivated. In January, he was also sentenced to six months in prison for labour law violations but secured bail.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-who-is-muhammad-yunus-possible-advisor-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6273576" target="_blank">Who Is Md Yunus, Possible Advisor Of Interim Bangladesh Government</a></p>

<p>Also in the fray is Tariq Rahman, the exiled Chairperson of Mrs Zia's Bangladesh Nationalist Party.</p>

<p>As in the case of Khaleda Zia, there is no formal confirmation Mr Rahman will be party of any new government, but there is strong speculation to suggest Mrs Zia and her BNP could make a return.</p>

<p>Mr Rahman is widely expected to return to Bangladesh, at least according to news agency ANI, which quoted BNP Secretary General Mirza Fakhrul Islam Alamgir to that effect.</p>

<p>A potential fifth figure is Nahid Islam, a Dhaka University student seen as the protest leader.</p>

<h3><strong>Who Is Nahid Islam</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Islam, a Sociology student, served as a National Coordinator for the 'Students Against Discrimination' Movement, which demanded reforms to the quota system for government jobs.</p>

<p>In the flurry of announcements and statements made last night Mr Islam claimed an outline for the interim government would be revealed within 24 hours.</p>

<p>Mr Nahid has been vocal against Sheikh Hasina's party, calling them "terrorists" on the roads.</p>

<p>In July he was abducted by at least 25 men in plain clothes from a house in Sabujbagh.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Who Is Nahid Islam, Student Leader Of Protests Against Sheikh Hasina</a></p>

<p>He was blindfolded, handcuffed and tortured during repeated interrogations about his involvement in the protests. Two days later, he was found unconscious and battered under a bridge in Purbachal.</p>

<p>He was kidnapped a second time a week later by individuals claiming to be from intelligence agencies, including the Dhaka Metropolitan Police's Detective Branch. But the police denied involvement.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Sheikh Hasina Resignation</strong></h3>

<p>Mrs Hasina, 76, a five-time PM and daughter of the country's founding father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman - quit and fled Dhaka Monday evening after weeks of violent protests over a government jobs quota.</p>

<p>Shortly after Ms Hasina resigned, Army chief General Waker-Uz-Zaman said the military will form an "interim government" and urged to protesters to stand down.</p>

<p>Over 400 people have died in clashes between authorities and mobs for and against the scheme assuring 30 per cent quota to family members of Bangladesh's 1971 war with Pakistan.</p>

<p>The protests that have roiled Bangladesh were sparked by Mrs Hasina's government announcing a 30 per cent quota for family members of her country's 1971 war of independence against Pakistan.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protest-bangladesh-updates-india-faces-tightrope-walk-after-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6273466#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">India's Diplomatic Problem In Dhaka Power Shift, Sheikh Hasina's Ouster</a></p>

<p>The students' movement gathered pace after the Bangladesh Supreme Court reinstated the quota, after first slashing it to five per cent. The students have alleged the quota is discriminatory.</p>

<p>Mrs Hasina left Dhaka in a military aircraft and flew to India's Hindon Air Force Base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad; she is expected to fly to London to claim political asylum.</p>

<p>Mrs Hasina was met on arrival by National Security Advisor Ajit Doval. There is no word yet if Prime Minister Narendra Modi will meet her.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/centre-calls-for-all-party-meet-over-bangladesh-s-jaishankar-to-attend-6273367#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"Want To Give Her Time," S Jaishankar Told MPs On Sheikh Hasina: Sources</a></p>

<p>Mr Modi has been briefed and External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar today chaired an all-party meeting to discuss the Bangladesh issue. He briefed all parties about steps being taken by the government to address potential security, economic, and diplomatic repercussions.</p>

<p>India's Border Security Force is on high alert across the country's 4,096 km border with Bangladesh, with field commanders ordered to take "on ground" positions and be prepared for anything. Indian Railways and the country's airlines have temporarily stopped services to Bangladesh.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-03/khaleda-zia_650x400_61425570214.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh Crisis: Ex-PM Khaleda Zia's release from jail has been ordered (File Photo).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-sued-by-fliers-after-massive-outage-disrupts-air-travel-6274235]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[CrowdStrike Sued By Fliers After Massive Outage Disrupts Air Travel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/crowdstrike-sued-by-fliers-after-massive-outage-disrupts-air-travel-6274235]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:37:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[CrowdStrike's legal troubles from last month's massive global computer outage deepened on Monday, as the cybersecurity company was sued by air travellers whose flights were delayed or cancelled.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CrowdStrike's legal troubles from last month's massive global computer outage deepened on Monday, as the cybersecurity company was sued by air travellers whose flights were delayed or cancelled.</p>

<p>In a proposed class action filed in the Austin, Texas, federal court, three fliers blamed CrowdStrike's negligence in testing and deploying its software for the outage, which also disrupted banks, hospitals and emergency lines around the world.</p>

<p>The complainants said that as fliers scrambled to get to their destinations, many spent hundreds of dollars on lodging, meals and alternative travel, while others missed work or suffered health problems from having to sleep on the airport floor.</p>

<p>They said CrowdStrike should pay compensatory and punitive damages to anyone whose flight was disrupted after technology-related flight groundings for Southwest Airlines and other carriers in 2023 made the outage "entirely foreseeable."</p>

<p>CrowdStrike said in a statement: "We believe this case lacks merit and we will vigorously defend the company."</p>

<p>It provided an identical statement in response to a shareholder lawsuit filed on July 31, after the company's stock price had fallen by about one-third.</p>

<p>The outage stemmed from a flawed software update that crashed more than 8 million computers.</p>

<p>Delta Air Lines has said it may take legal action against Austin-based CrowdStrike after canceling more than 6,000 flights, at a cost of about $500 million.</p>

<p>On Sunday, CrowdStrike said it was neither grossly negligent nor at fault for Delta's problems, and that the Atlanta-based carrier did not accept its offer for help.</p>

<p>Delta faces a US Department of Transportation probe into why it needed more time than rivals to recover from the outage.</p>

<p>Monday's case is del Rio et al v CrowdStrike Inc,&nbsp;US District Court, Western District of Texas, No. 24-00881.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/180nuaq8_delta-airlines_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Delta Air Lines may sue CrowdStrike after canceling over 6,000 flights. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-co-founder-john-schulman-exits-chatgpt-joins-rival-anthropic-6274280]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Co-Founder John Schulman Exits ChatGPT, Joins Rival Anthropic]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-co-founder-john-schulman-exits-chatgpt-joins-rival-anthropic-6274280]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:33:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[John Schulman, one of the co-founders of artificial intelligence company OpenAI, has left the ChatGPT maker for rival Anthropic, he said in a post on social media platform X late Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Schulman, one of the co-founders of artificial intelligence company OpenAI, has left the ChatGPT maker for rival Anthropic, he said in a post on social media platform X late Monday.</p>

<p>"This choice stems from my desire to deepen my focus on AI alignment, and to start a new chapter of my career where I can return to hands-on technical work," Schulman said in his X post.</p>

<p>OpenAI's President and co-founder Greg Brockman is also taking a sabbatical through the end of the year, he said in a X post late Monday.</p>

<p>The news was first reported by The Information, which added that Peter Deng, a product manager who joined OpenAI last year, has also exited the company.</p>

<p>OpenAI did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>The move comes as OpenAI faces significant personnel changes, with the company's AI safety leader Aleksander Madry being reassigned to another role in July.</p>

<p>Another one of OpenAI's co-founders and chief scientist, Ilya Sutskever, left the company in May. Andrej Karpathy, who was also one of the AI firm's founding members left OpenAI in February and started an AI-integrated education platform in July.</p>

<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk, who was also one of the co-founders of OpenAI and left three years later, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-revives-lawsuit-against-openai-ceo-sam-altman-6268971" target="_blank">revived his lawsuit</a> against the company and CEO Sam Altman on Monday, saying that the firm put profits and commercial interests ahead of public good.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2s2967a8_john-schulman-openai_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[John Schulman said he wants to deepen his focus on AI alignment (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sonova-launches-real-time-ai-powered-hearing-aid-sphere-infinio-makes-market-history-6274596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Swiss Firm Launches AI-Powered Hearing Aid, World's First Such Product]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sonova-launches-real-time-ai-powered-hearing-aid-sphere-infinio-makes-market-history-6274596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:28:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Switzerland's Sonova on Tuesday introduced a hearing aid that utilises real-time artificial intelligence to improve speech clarity from background noise, the first such product in the global market.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland's Sonova on Tuesday introduced a hearing aid that utilises real-time artificial intelligence to improve speech clarity from background noise, the first such product in the global market.</p>

<p>Along with the hearing aid, named Sphere Infinio, Sonova is launching a new Infinio platform.</p>

<p>Sonova had said in May it expected major product launches to drive sales and profit growth in the second half of its fiscal year, without providing further details.</p>

<p>"The launch of both new platform and product should be a surprise to the market because nobody knew this technology and this benefit (real-time AI), which is quite significant, will be available for anyone already this year," CEO Arnd Kaldowski told Reuters in an interview.</p>

<p>Kaldowski reiterated that Sonova's second-half results were going to be stronger on a year-on-year basis, and confirmed its full-year outlook.</p>

<p>Sphere Infinio uses new DEEPSONIC chip technology that has 53 times more processing power than what is currently used by the hearing aid industry, the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>Sonova views Infinio and its existing Lumity platform as the main future growth drivers for its hearing instrument business, which brings in around half of its total sales.</p>

<p>The hearing aid industry has been showing signs of softer market dynamics in Europe and the US, while analysts have also flagged tough competition in the market.</p>

<p>A number of hearing aid firms, including Italy's Amplifon and Denmark's Demant and GN Store Nord, have warned on profits this summer, citing volatility in the market.</p>

<p>"We will need to see how the market evolves and the customer reaction to the products. But we are good with our full-year guidance even with the currently somewhat slower market," Kaldowski said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gmd1j478_hearing-aid_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The launch should be a surprise to the market because nobody knew about this technology, says CEO. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-could-disrupt-middle-east-6274610]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Hamas Chief's Assassination Could Disrupt Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-assassination-could-disrupt-middle-east-6274610]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:16:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's assassination of Hamas' political leader will have far-reaching consequences for any chance in peace in the Middle East]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's assassination of Hamas' political leader will have far-reaching consequences for any chance in peace in the Middle East</p>

<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-03/iran-says-ismail-haniyeh-was-killed-by-short-range-projectile-/104180416"><u>assassination of Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh</u></a>&nbsp;in Tehran, where he was attending the inauguration of Iranian President Mesud Pezeshkian, &nbsp;is a watershed moment, marking the intensification of the ongoing Israeli-Palestine war.</p>

<p>While Israel always maintained a policy of hitting Hamas leaders anywhere in the world, there has been an understanding between Israel and the Arab states about not targeting them outside Palestine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Haniyeh's assassination is the first such targeted killing since the 2010 death of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2010/02/dubai_police_chief_99_sure_mos.html">Hamas leader Mohmoud Al Mabhouh</a>&nbsp;in Dubai.</p>

<p>Haniyeh, who was seen as a pragmatist capable of uniting Hamas' competing factions and the nearest thing to a statesman the organisation had, had emerged as a far more significant threat to Israel than anyone else inside Hamas.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His elimination is one of the biggest achievements of Israeli intelligence and embattled Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Indeed, it could be a lifeline for Netanyahu, who is deeply unpopular in Israel for his handling of the conflict.</p>

<h3><b>Dangerous escalation</b></h3>

<p>But it is also a dangerous escalation and could have serious implications for the region and its fragile security arrangement, with Iran threatening&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c6p2ydk7er1o"><u>revenge</u></a>&nbsp;for Haniyeh's killing.</p>

<p>Israel has broken several established rules on which the fragile regional security depended for so long.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's regional security doctrine depended on two principles.</p>

<p>First, as the Arab streets have been massively unhappy with their regimes for a very long time, the plight of Palestinian people continues to be the biggest source of anger and frustration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Without a brutal repressive system in place, Arab public opinion would have become violent as happened during the failed Arab uprisings in 2010.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ruling class often distributes subsidies and freebies and relies on more radical&nbsp;<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/islamism-salafism-and-jihadism-a-primer/"><u>Salafi Islamism</u></a>&nbsp;(pure or authentic Islam, found in the lived example of the early, righteous generations of Muslims, known as the&nbsp;<i>Salaf</i>) to calm down the populace.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since the Gaza war, Arab opinion has been&nbsp;<a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/america-losing-arab-world"><u>dangerously anti-American and anti-Western</u></a>, and Israel's expanding war theatre beyond Gaza is pushing Arab regimes deeper into troubled waters.</p>

<p>To keep a lid on boiling public opinion is one of the most important aspects that Israel had to help the Gulf States achieve.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But with this Gaza war — in which more than 39,000 Gazans, including 14,000 children, have been killed — Israel has done serious harm to the Gulf and Arab States' ability to control their population.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Second, the fragile security in the region stands on secret bilateral and regional agreements between Israel, the United States and the Gulf regimes to pursue a common security arrangement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That is to keep radical Islam and its allies, Iran and its proxies, away from gaining any influence in the region, at any cost.</p>

<p>The current Gaza war and the assassination of Haniyeh will further discredit pro-West Arabs and their initiatives on Palestine, including the Abraham Accords.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the last few decades, Gulf states have separated Gulf security from the wider Arab security.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><b>Iran a bigger threat</b></h3>

<p>For Arab security, the resolution of the Palestinian crisis still remains the most important issue to be resolved while for Gulf security,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.chathamhouse.org/publications/the-world-today/2024-02/gulf-states-have-power-revive-two-state-solution"><u>Iran remains a bigger threat</u></a>&nbsp;than the Israeli occupation.</p>

<p>As a result, any Gulf-led initiative for Palestine has been primarily driven by its quest to sideline Iran and its proxies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the last few years, Iran and the Gulf states have joined&nbsp;<a href="https://carnegieindia.org/research/2024/08/how-gulf-states-are-reinterpreting-national-security-beyond-their-land-borders-abdullah-baabood?lang=en&amp;center=middle-east"><u>China -mediated dialogue</u></a>&nbsp;for regional security.</p>

<p>In this Gaza crisis, the Americans and Israelis may lose some of the Gulf states, particularly Saudi Arabia, in their plans to revive the Abraham Accords.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Egypt, Jordan and other Arab states have become more frustrated over being sidelined by the Gulf states and for sacrificing Arab security to the Gulf security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Finally, Haniyeh's assassination has weakened and divided the Palestinian Authority, helping everyone except Palestinians and their prospects of achieving statehood. Today's Palestinian authority has lost its appeal and influence as it once had under the charismatic leadership of Yasser Arafat.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hamas has filled the gap left by the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.arabnews.com/node/2395986/middle-east"><u>unpopular and corrupt&nbsp;</u></a>leadership of Mahmoud Abbas. By killing Hamas' top leader, Israel has unilaterally changed the rules of Arab and Gulf security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The new Palestinian response to the Gaza crisis may not be totally in control of the Gulf states as the Americans and Israelis would have desired.</p>

<p>Egypt heavily relied on Hamas to maintain the fragile security between Gaza and the Sinai Peninsula. Egypt felt betrayed and isolated by the Americans and Israelis. The assassination is a serious setback for Egypt as well.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Interestingly,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.africanews.com/2024/02/15/egypt-and-turkey-renew-ties-over-israels-looming-offensive-on-rafah-in-southern-gaza/"><u>Turkey and Egypt</u></a>&nbsp;have spoken more frequently these days about the Gaza crisis and about helping each other. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.egypttoday.com/Article/1/133933/Photos-Turkish-FM-visits-Rafah-border-crossing-Arish-port-in"><u>Turkish foreign minister is in Cairo</u></a>&nbsp;and has also visited the Rafah border to inspect the distribution of Turkish assistance.</p>

<p>When Egyptian President Abdelfattah Al Sisi visits Ankara next month, Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan may offer him bigger opportunities to revive Egypt's historical role in the Arab world.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel and its Western backers must be concerned about how the regional powers realign their interests and strategies for new regional security with Palestine at the centre.&nbsp;</p>

<p><i>Omair Anas</i><i>&nbsp;is Assistant Professor of International Relations at Ankara Yildirim Beyazit University, Turkiye, He is also a member of the Centre for India-West Asia Dialogue, a think tank based in New Delhi.</i></p>

<p><i>Originally published under&nbsp;</i><a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><i>Creative Commons</i></a><i>&nbsp;by&nbsp;</i><a href="https://360info.org/"><i>360info</i></a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/un7jfe78_ismail-haniyeh-_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh's elimination is one of the biggest achievements of Israeli intelligence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-security-meet-and-a-phone-call-the-hours-before-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6274604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Went Down At Sheikh Hasina's Home Before She Fled Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-security-meet-and-a-phone-call-the-hours-before-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6274604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:14:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina did not want to resign as Bangladesh Prime Minister and wanted security forces to intensify the crackdown on nationwide protests, but security bosses said the protests cannot be contained by force, according to a report in Prothom Alo]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Hasina did not want to resign as Bangladesh Prime Minister and wanted security forces to intensify the crackdown on nationwide protests, but security bosses said the protests cannot be contained by force, according to a report in Prothom Alo newspaper.</p>

<p>The report details what went down in the Prime Minister's official residence before her last-minute escape in a military aircraft, shortly before hundreds of protesters stormed in and went on the rampage.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cr38mubg_sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>Morning Meet With Security Chiefs</strong></p>

<p>According to the Prothom Alo report, the Awami League leader called the top officers of the security establishment and police force to her residence. The death count was rising, and some of her advisors had tried to talk her into transferring the power to the Army. But the 76-year-old five-time Prime Minister was adamant. She asked the forces to strengthen the curfew already in place. On the streets, however, the situation was changing fast. Despite the curfew, protesters had started gathering at various spots in Dhaka.</p>

<p>At her meeting with the security bosses, she questioned why they had not been able to contain the protests. She pointed to visuals of protesters climbing atop police vehicles and asked why the forces were not cracking down harder. At one point, she reminded them that they had been elevated to these positions because she trusted them.</p>

<p>During the meeting, Sheikh Hasina praised police's response to the protests. But the police chief conveyed that the situation is such that police won't be able to contain it for long.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n066ubeo_sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>Son Convinced Hasina To Leave</strong></p>

<p>The security forces, the report says, tried to explain to her that more force is not the answer. But the veteran leader did not budge. Then the officers spoke to Sheikh Hasina's sister Rehana in another room and urged her to convince the Prime Minister to step down. Rehana spoke to Hasina, but that did not help. At this point, Sheikh Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed Joy stepped in. Based in the US, Joy spoke to his mother and managed to convince her to resign.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/she-didnt-want-to-leave-we-insisted-sheikh-hasinas-son-to-ndtv-6271386">Speaking to NDTV</a>, Joy yesterday said his mother did not want to leave Bangladesh. "She wanted to stay, she did not want to leave the country at all. But we kept insisting that it wasn't safe for her. We were concerned for her physical safety first; so we persuaded her to leave," he said.</p>

<p>"I spoke to her this morning. The situation in Bangladesh, as you can see, is anarchy. She is in good spirits, but she is very disappointed. It's very disheartening for her because it was her dream to turn Bangladesh into a developed country and she worked so hard for it over the last 15 years, keeping it safe from militants and as well as from terrorism and in spite of all of that this vocal minority, the opposition, the militants have now seized power," he said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ko02c0rg_mujibur-rahman-statue_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>The Speech That Was Not Recorded</strong></p>

<p>The crowd of protesters was swelling, and intelligence inputs said Ganabhaban -- the Prime Minister's official residence -- may be stormed. Sheikh Hasina was given 45 minute to pack up. She wanted to record one last speech addressing the people of the country, but there was no time. Accompanied by sister Rehana, she left hom. There was a short halt at Bangabhaban, the Bangladesh President's official residence, where she completed the resignation formalities.</p>

<p>Around 2.30 pm, the ousted leader took off in a military aircraft, bringing the curtain down on her 15-year uninterrupted term. Her ouster and flight also represents a massive shift in Bangladesh politics. Fifty years after her father and Bangladesh's tallest leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahaman led the struggle for the country's independence, Ms Hasina was forced to flee as protesters vandalised her father's statues. The legacy of Mujibur Rahman, fondly known as Bangabandhu, is no longer a symbol of Bangladesh's war of liberation. Instead, it represents her daughter's politics that protesters claim focused on suppressing dissent.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6mnm646o_sheikh-hasina_650x400_05_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><strong>What Led To This</strong></div>
</div>

<p>The protests in Bangladesh, which began last month, started as an agitation against a quota system under which 30 per cent of government jobs were reserved for family members of Muktijoddhas -- those who fought in Bangladesh's war of independence in 1971. The protesters said this system favours supporters of the ruling Awami League and wanted a merit-based system to replace it. As the protests grew, the Awami League dispensation tried to crush it with an iron fist. And then, a remark by Hasina sparked fury. "If not the grandchildren of the freedom fighters, then who will get quota benefits? The grandchildren of the 'Razakars'?" she asked. A paramilitary force recruited by the Pakistan Army during the 1971 liberation war, Razakars carried out mass atrocities, including mass killings, rapes, and torture. Naturally, the remark touched a raw nerve.</p>

<p>Reservation has been a burning issue in Bangladesh for years now. In 2018, an agitation on this issue forced the government to water down the reservation system and cancelled quotas for some positions.</p>

<p>The latest unrest was sparked by a high court order that declared illegal the 2018 government circular cancelling 30 per cent quota for freedom fighters' descendants in government jobs. This order was scrapped by the country's Supreme Court. The Supreme Court ordered that 93 per cent of government jobs must be allocated on merit and the remaining be reserved for relatives of freedom fighters. But even the top court's order could not pacify the protesters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina did not want to resign till the last hour, a report has said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-crisis-live-conspiracy-angle-in-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-what-government-sources-said-6274539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Conspiracy Angle In Sheikh Hasina's Ouster? What Government Sources Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-crisis-live-conspiracy-angle-in-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-what-government-sources-said-6274539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:08:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There could be a conspiracy angle in former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's ouster, the government said at today's all-party meeting on the ongoing political crisis in the neighbouring state, sources have said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There could be a conspiracy angle in former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's ouster, the government said at today's all-party meeting on the situation in the violence-hit country, sources have said.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar, it is learnt, said that several political players could be involved in the conspiracy to topple Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishnakar was responding to Congress MP Rahul Gandhi who had asked if there could be an involvement of foreign powers, specifically Pakistan, in the dramatic developments in Dhaka over the past few weeks.</p>

<p>The government has been keeping a watch on the evolving situation and all possible angles were being looked into, he said.</p>

<p>The Foreign Minister briefed the leaders of all parties about steps taken by the Indian government to address the potential security, economic, and diplomatic repercussions of this situation.</p>

<p>He said that the government is in touch with the Bangladeshi Army - which is set to form an interim government after Ms Hasina's ouster - to ensure the safety of Indian nationals and the minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar said the government is giving time to Sheikh Hasina - who arrived in India after her ouster - to "recover" and let them know about her next move.</p>

<p>Besides S Jaishankar, Home Minister Amit Shah, Defence Minister Rajnath Singh, and Parliamentary Affairs Minister Kiren Rijiju also attended the meeting.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon Air Force base in Uttar Pradesh's Ghaziabad, which is 30km from Delhi last evening. She was received by National Security Advisor Ajit Doval.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina is expected to leave for London later, sources told NDTV, where she may seek political asylum. However, there is no confirmation on whether the UK has offered asylum to her.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina had sought to quell nationwide protests against her government but she fled the country after fresh clashes on Sunday in which nearly 100 people were killed.</p>

<p>The anti-government rallies that began last month against civil service job quotas escalated into some of the worst unrest of Prime Minister Hasina's 15-year rule and shifted into wider calls for the 76-year-old to step down.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jem8luuo_bangladesh-protest-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina arrived in India yesterday after her ouster]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-killed-in-violence-across-bangladesh-after-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6274199]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 100 Killed In Violence Across Bangladesh After Sheikh Hasina's Ouster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-killed-in-violence-across-bangladesh-after-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6274199]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:05:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Over 100 people have been killed in the violence across Bangladesh as chaos reined supreme hours after Sheikh Hasina resigned as prime minister and fled the country on Monday, reports said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 100 people have been killed in the violence across Bangladesh as chaos reined supreme hours after Sheikh Hasina resigned as prime minister and fled the country on Monday, reports said today.</p>

<p>The situation in Dhaka was largely calm this morning after a day of unrest and a night of tension. Buses and other public transport were on the streets and traders were opening shops. Government vehicles were heading to offices. Many battery-run rickshaws plied the roads, BDNews24.com newsportal said.</p>

<p>As the news of Hasina's departure spread on Monday, hundreds of people broke into her residence, vandalising and looting the interiors, providing dramatic expression to the anti-government protests.</p>

<p>Hasina's residence Sudha Sadan and other establishments were attacked, vandalised and set on fire in the capital. The residences and business establishments of ministers, party MPs and leaders of Hasina's Awami League government were also attacked in Dhaka and outside Dhaka.</p>

<p>According to local media reports, 119 people have been killed in the violence and attacks on Hindu temples and widespread looting in the capital and various other places.</p>

<p>At least 109 people were killed in clashes in different parts of the country, including Dhaka, at the last moment of the one-point demand of the anti-discrimination student movement on Monday, Bengali language daily Prothom Alo reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Earlier, the newspaper reported the death of 98 people till 12 pm on Sunday. Another 16 deaths were reported in the middle of the night. The total death countstood at 114 on Sunday.</p>

<p>"With this, the total death count stood at 440 in 21 days from July 16 to yesterday," the paper said.</p>

<p>It said that 37 bodies were brought to the Dhaka Medical College Hospital between 11 am and 8 pm on Monday.</p>

<p>Citing hospital sources, it said 500 people were brought to the hospital with various injuries, including bullet injuries.</p>

<p>The Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported that at least 18 people were killed in Savar and Dhamrai areas, on the outskirts of the capital, after clashes broke out between police and miscreants on Monday.</p>

<p>Ten people were killed in the capital's Uttara on Monday after individuals in civilian clothes reportedly opened fire on protesters.</p>

<p>Six people were killed in Habiganj, eight in Jessore, three in Khulna, three in Barisal, 11 in Lakshmipur, six in Kushtia, three in Satkhira and six in Sreepur of Gazipur, the paper said.</p>

<p>Late Monday night, President Mohammed Shahabuddin asked all the political parties to normalise the law and order situation in the country and directed the armed forces to take stern measures to protect the lives and properties of the people and state assets.</p>

<p>The educational institutions in the country were reopened on Tuesday following a long period of closure due to violence surrounding the student movement.</p>

<p>However, the educational institutions in the national capital saw low attendance, the Dhaka Tribune newspaper reported.</p>

<p>"The institution is open, and some girls have come, but attendance is low. Attendance will increase in a couple of days," Md Rahamot Ullah, principal of Kisholoy Girls' School and College in the Mohammadpur area of the capital, was quoted as saying by the paper.</p>

<p>Trouble had been steadily escalating since the government's announcement of the quota system in June this year.</p>

<p>The clashes between protesters demanding Hasina's resignation and the ruling Awami League supporters in different parts of Bangladesh on Sunday erupted days after more than 200 people were killed in violent clashes between police and mostly student protesters.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/32iukmo_bangladesh-unrest-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Over 100 people have been killed in the violence across Bangladesh as chaos reined supreme.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/months-before-ouster-sheikh-hasina-had-made-this-explosive-allegation-6274497]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Months Ago, Sheikh Hasina Had Claimed She Got An "Offer" From "White Man"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/months-before-ouster-sheikh-hasina-had-made-this-explosive-allegation-6274497]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:01:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Months before her tragic fall as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh, Sheikh Hasina had claimed that "conspiracies" were being hatched to topple her government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Months before her tragic fall as the Prime Minister of Bangladesh, Sheikh Hasina had claimed that "conspiracies" were being hatched to topple her government and that she may be assassinated just like her father and independence hero Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.</p>

<p>She had also alleged a "white man's" plot to carve a new "Christian country" out of Bangladesh and Myanmar.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina had said she was offered an easy re-election in January - which she anyway achieved in a one-side election boycotted by her arch-rival Khaleda Zia's party. The condition was that she had to allow a foreign country build an airbase in Bangladesh, she claimed, suggesting this was why her government had always been in trouble.</p>

<p>"If I allowed a certain country to build an airbase in Bangladesh, then I would have had no problem," she had said in May. The offer came from a "white man", she said, but fell short of naming any country. "It may appear it is aimed at only one country, but it is not. I know where else they intend to go."</p>

<p>"There will be more trouble," she had warned.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina resigned and fled Bangladesh amid deadly protests yesterday as the country's military took over.</p>

<p>On her claim that many foreigners had their eyes on Bangladesh, she had said, "Like East Timor...they will carve out a Christian country, taking parts of Bangladesh (Chattogram) and Myanmar with a base in the Bay of Bengal."</p>

<p>However, she had vowed not to bow down to any pressure.</p>

<p>Bangladesh saw one of its deadliest demonstrations on Sunday with over 100 protesters dying in clashes with cops. The total deaths since the beginning of the protests have crossed 400.</p>

<p>The protesters breached the Prime Minister's residence on Monday, but Ms Hasina avoided a direct confrontation, having already resigned and fled the country in a military plane.</p>

<p>The country's army chief called a press conference hours later and declared an interim government would be formed to run the country.</p>

<p>Later in the day, Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon Air Force base in India - about 30 km from capital Delhi. She is likely to leave for London where she may seek asylum, sources told NDTV.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qd5o8k6g_sheikh-hasina_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina had said she was offered an easy re-election in January. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/absolutely-pathetic-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-says-hes-lying-about-her-6274448]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Transgender Daughter Says He "Just Won't Stop Lying" About Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/absolutely-pathetic-elon-musks-transgender-daughter-says-hes-lying-about-her-6274448]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:52:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vivian said that when she was six years old, Mr Musk referred to Arabic as the "language of the enemy" and that he is not the champion of equality that he loves to pretend to be.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk's estranged transgender daughter <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/endlessly-proud-elon-musks-ex-girlfriend-grimes-comes-out-in-support-of-his-transgender-daughter-6199807">Vivian Jenna Wilson</a>, recently "disowned" him. Now, she has launched a fresh attack against the SpaceX Chief who had alleged that she was "killed" by "woke mind virus". She said that the 53-year-old "just won't stop lying" about her and he lives in his "own delusional fantasy land." She further said that he is a bigot who has been sued for discrimination on several occasions and that he often cheats on his relationships.</p>

<p>This comes after Mr Musk responded to a throwback post of his children and wrote, "All 5 boys super happy." In response to the post, Vivian took to Meta's Threads and wrote, "Look, I don't know if you genuinely believe this or if you live in your own delusional fantasy land and frankly, I don't care. It seems to me like you're trying to rebuild your brand image as the 'caring paternal father' which I will not let go unchallenged. If I'm going to be honest, this is absolutely pathetic. You just won't stop lying about me in interviews, books, social media, etc. Thank god you're absolutely terrible at it because otherwise this would be significantly more difficult."</p>

<blockquote class="text-post-media" data-text-post-permalink="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/C-TZfctS7pz" data-text-post-version="0" id="ig-tp-C-TZfctS7pz" style=" background:#FFF; border-width: 1px; border-style: solid; border-color: #00000026; border-radius: 16px; max-width:540px; margin: 1px; min-width:270px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style=" padding: 40px; display: flex; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;">
<div style=" display:block; height:32px; width:32px; padding-bottom:20px;"><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/C-TZfctS7pz" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank"><svg aria-label="Threads" height="32px" role="img" viewbox="0 0 192 192" width="32px" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"> <path d="M141.537 88.9883C140.71 88.5919 139.87 88.2104 139.019 87.8451C137.537 60.5382 122.616 44.905 97.5619 44.745C97.4484 44.7443 97.3355 44.7443 97.222 44.7443C82.2364 44.7443 69.7731 51.1409 62.102 62.7807L75.881 72.2328C81.6116 63.5383 90.6052 61.6848 97.2286 61.6848C97.3051 61.6848 97.3819 61.6848 97.4576 61.6855C105.707 61.7381 111.932 64.1366 115.961 68.814C118.893 72.2193 120.854 76.925 121.825 82.8638C114.511 81.6207 106.601 81.2385 98.145 81.7233C74.3247 83.0954 59.0111 96.9879 60.0396 116.292C60.5615 126.084 65.4397 134.508 73.775 140.011C80.8224 144.663 89.899 146.938 99.3323 146.423C111.79 145.74 121.563 140.987 128.381 132.296C133.559 125.696 136.834 117.143 138.28 106.366C144.217 109.949 148.617 114.664 151.047 120.332C155.179 129.967 155.42 145.8 142.501 158.708C131.182 170.016 117.576 174.908 97.0135 175.059C74.2042 174.89 56.9538 167.575 45.7381 153.317C35.2355 139.966 29.8077 120.682 29.6052 96C29.8077 71.3178 35.2355 52.0336 45.7381 38.6827C56.9538 24.4249 74.2039 17.11 97.0132 16.9405C119.988 17.1113 137.539 24.4614 149.184 38.788C154.894 45.8136 159.199 54.6488 162.037 64.9503L178.184 60.6422C174.744 47.9622 169.331 37.0357 161.965 27.974C147.036 9.60668 125.202 0.195148 97.0695 0H96.9569C68.8816 0.19447 47.2921 9.6418 32.7883 28.0793C19.8819 44.4864 13.2244 67.3157 13.0007 95.9325L13 96L13.0007 96.0675C13.2244 124.684 19.8819 147.514 32.7883 163.921C47.2921 182.358 68.8816 191.806 96.9569 192H97.0695C122.03 191.827 139.624 185.292 154.118 170.811C173.081 151.866 172.51 128.119 166.26 113.541C161.776 103.087 153.227 94.5962 141.537 88.9883ZM98.4405 129.507C88.0005 130.095 77.1544 125.409 76.6196 115.372C76.2232 107.93 81.9158 99.626 99.0812 98.6368C101.047 98.5234 102.976 98.468 104.871 98.468C111.106 98.468 116.939 99.0737 122.242 100.233C120.264 124.935 108.662 128.946 98.4405 129.507Z"></path></svg></a></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #999999; font-weight: 400; padding-bottom: 4px; "><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/C-TZfctS7pz" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank">Post by @vivllainous</a></div>

<div style=" font-size: 15px; line-height: 21px; color: #000000; font-weight: 600; "><a href="https://www.threads.net/@vivllainous/post/C-TZfctS7pz" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%; font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, sans-serif;" target="_blank">View on Threads</a></div>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://www.threads.net/embed.js"></script>

<p>She accused him of misgendering her multiple times. "If you're going to lie about me, why would you choose a method so obnoxious in its stupidity. It's beyond stupid, it's desperate. The fact anyone believed this for even five seconds is beyond me. Not to mention going out of your way to misgender me which is both completely transparent and honestly just sad," she continued.</p>

<p>Notably, the 20-year-old legally changed her name and gender at the age of 18. This legal transition occurred on June 22, 2022, at a court in California. "I no longer live with or wish to be related to my biological father in any way, shape, or form," Ms Wilson had said back then.</p>

<p>Vivian continued, adding that Mr Musk wants to portray himself as a "western values/Christian family man." She said, "I understand your new angle is this 'western values/christian family man' thing but it's such a weird choice. You are not a family man, you are a serial adulterer who won't stop f***** lying about your own children. You are not a christian, as far as I'm aware you've never stepped foot in a church."</p>

<p>She also levelled some more accusations about the billionaire. Vivian said that when she was six years old, Mr Musk referred to Arabic as the "language of the enemy" and that he is not the champion of equality that he loves to pretend to be.</p>

<p>The 20-year-old also questioned his climate change claims and his space exploration programs. She wrote on the social media platform, "You are not 'saving the planet', you do not give a f*** about climate change and you're lying about multi-planetary civilization as both an excuse, and because you want to seem like the CEO from Ready Player One."</p>

<p>"You single-handedly disillusioned me with how gullible we are as a species because somehow people keep believing you for reasons that continue to evade me," she concluded.</p>

<p>Notably, the world's richest man had claimed in a recent interview that during the pandemic, he was tricked into signing documents for "one of his older boys" Vivian Jenna Wilson. He said that his "son is dead" and also referred to gender-reassignment surgery as "child mutilation and sterilisation".</p>

<p>"I was tricked into doing this. I lost my son, essentially. They call it 'deadnaming' for a reason. The reason they call it 'deadnaming' is because your son is dead," Mr Musk said, claiming that the experience set him on a mission to combat what he described as the "woke mind virus". "I vowed to destroy the woke mind virus after that. And we're making some progress," he added.</p>

<p>Responding to this, Ms Wilson said that she "disowned" him and not the other way round. She shared a screenshot of Mr Musk's post in which he claimed that his son was born "gay and slightly autistic" and said "entire thing was made up".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/a945hc54_elon-musk_625x300_24_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vivian accused Mr Musk of misgendering her multiple times.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-if-hes-disrespectful-reveals-new-book-6274241]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Queen Camilla Keeps Prince William In Check If He's Disrespectful, Says Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-if-hes-disrespectful-reveals-new-book-6274241]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:16:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[These claims came from royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, "Catherine, the Princess of Wales".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Queen Camilla subtly reminds Prince William and keeps him in check whenever she feels that he is not respecting his father, a new book has claimed, as per a report in the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/entertainment/queen-camilla-keeps-prince-william-in-check-when-hes-disrespectful-book/">New York Post</a></em>. These claims came from royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, "Catherine, the Princess of Wales".&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an excerpt from his book, Mr Jobson discussed a specific instance in which Prince William and his wife, Kate Middleton, requested to be included in the security convoy of King Charles and Queen Camilla as they headed out of Windsor Castle. However, the younger royals kept the King and Queen waiting. This did not sit well with Queen Camilla, who then took a “subtle” jab at the Cambridges.</p>

<p>The book explains, "When Charles was kept waiting several minutes for the couple, Camilla insisted they go without them. As William and Catherine emerged, all they could see were the blue flashing lights of the motorbikes disappearing in the distance."</p>

<p>According to the <em>BBC</em>, this revelation comes at a time when the 77-year-old Queen Camilla and Prince William have grown “much closer” amid King Charles and Kate's cancer diagnosis. “They have been left, almost literally, nursing the crown while the king and the princess recover,” BBC royal correspondent Jennie Bond told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ok.co.uk/royal/queen-camilla-prince-william-royal-32356261"><em>OK! magazine.</em></a></p>

<p>“Times of adversity often bring people much closer together. For all the progress that has been made in cancer treatment, it is still a scary thing,” she said.</p>

<p>“And while Camilla and William put on a brave face for the world (and no doubt for their spouses, too), there may be times when they confide in one another about how they are dealing with it all,” Ms Bond added.</p>

<p>Further, she said that the 42-year-old Prince and his stepmother developed a close relationship after they saw several hardships together, including the death of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip. “When the late queen died, William spoke of how (Camilla) had been at his side at ‘the happiest moments' and ‘saddest days of his life'. Now, Camilla is sharing some of those times with him, and it must surely cement their relationship,” the correspondent said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t8d1p53o_william-camilla_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[William and Queen Camilla developed a close relationship after they saw several hardships together.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centre-not-to-relax-4-billion-tax-demands-for-infosys-report-6274117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Centre Not To Relax $4 Billion Tax Demand To Infosys: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/centre-not-to-relax-4-billion-tax-demands-for-infosys-report-6274117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:07:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The central government is not considering any relaxation over the 320 billion rupees ($4 billion) tax demand it sent to Infosys, according to a government source.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The central government is not considering any relaxation over the $4 billion tax demand it sent to Infosys, according to a government source.</p>

<p>The tax demand on Infosys is in accordance to the good and services tax rules and the country's second-largest IT services firm has sought 10 days to submit its response after meeting tax officials, the source said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-01/n7u94t2_infosys_625x300_12_January_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Infosys is India's second-largest IT services company (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Nahid Islam, Student Leader Who Led Protests Against Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:05:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After nearly a month of anti-quota and anti-government demonstrations that swept across Bangladesh, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After nearly a month of anti-quota and anti-government demonstrations that swept across Bangladesh, Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country. Her resignation came in the face of countrywide demonstrations led by student leader Nahid Islam. What started as a call for reform in the country's quota policy for the families of freedom fighters slowly morphed into an anti-government movement demanding Sheikh Hasina's resignation. &nbsp;<br />
<br />
On Monday, protesters defied a nationwide curfew, stormed the Prime Minister's residence, and declared victory for the people's movement.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>Some facts about student leader Nahid Islam:</strong><br />
<br />
1. Nahid Islam is currently a student in the Sociology Department at Dhaka University.&nbsp; He is known for his work as a human rights defender.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
2. He serves as one of the National Coordinators for the 'Students Against Discrimination' Movement, a student-led protest demanding reforms to the quota system in government jobs in Bangladesh. The movement began after the Supreme Court of Bangladesh reinstated a 30 per cent quota for descendants of war veterans and freedom fighters in June 2024. The movement argued the quota was a discriminatory and politically manipulated system to access government jobs.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
3. Mr Nahid has been vocal against Sheikh Hasina's party, the Awami League, describing them as "terrorists" deployed on the roads. Previously, addressing protesters at Shahbagh, he declared students had "picked up sticks today" and were ready to "take up arms" if sticks didn't work.<br />
<br />
4. On 19 July 2024, <a href="https://www.frontlinedefenders.org/en/profile/nahid-islam ">Nahid Islam was abducted</a> by at least 25 men in plain clothes from a house in Sabujbagh. He was blindfolded, handcuffed and tortured during repeated interrogations about his involvement in the protests. Two days later, he was found unconscious and battered under a bridge in Purbachal.<br />
<br />
5. Nahid Islam was kidnapped a second time on 26 July 2024 from Gonoshasthaya Nagar Hospital in Dhanmondi. Individuals claiming to be from various intelligence agencies, including the Dhaka Metropolitan Police's Detective Branch, took him away. However, the police have denied any involvement.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fk0gu7l_nahid-islam-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nahid Islam is currently a student in the Sociology Department at Dhaka University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-supporter-who-rioted-at-us-capitol-to-get-his-spear-headdress-back-6273898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Supporter Who Rioted At US Capitol To Get His Spear, Headdress Back]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-supporter-who-rioted-at-us-capitol-to-get-his-spear-headdress-back-6273898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 12:00:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jacob Chansley, 36, known as the "QAnon Shaman," became one of the faces of the January 6, 2021 assault on the Capitol because of his red, white and blue face paint, bare chest and unusual headgear.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A self-proclaimed "shaman" who was among the Donald Trump supporters who breached the US Capitol can have his horned fur headdress and spear returned to him, a judge ruled on Monday.</p>

<p>Jacob Chansley, 36, known as the "QAnon Shaman," became one of the faces of the January 6, 2021 assault on the Capitol because of his red, white and blue face paint, bare chest and unusual headgear.</p>

<p>Chansley, also known as Jake Angeli, was among the first of hundreds of rioters to break into the Capitol on January 6, 2021 as lawmakers were certifying Democrat Joe Biden's victory over Trump in the 2020 presidential election.</p>

<p>He pleaded guilty to a single felony charge of obstructing an official proceeding and was sentenced to 41 months in prison, although he received an early release in May of last year.</p>

<p>In a lawsuit filed in Washington, Chansley asked a judge for the return of his property seized by the authorities following his arrest.</p>

<p>"Since the government has not established that it still needs these items as evidence and has not sought their forfeiture, the Court will grant Mr Chansley's motion," District Judge Royce Lamberth said.</p>

<p>The items to be returned include Chansley's "horned coyote-tail headdress" and a six-foot pole with a metal spearhead fixed to the top.</p>

<p>Before the January 6 riot, Chansley, a promoter of QAnon conspiracy theories, had traveled the country appearing at rallies in support of Trump, who is running for re election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3jgg4a58_qanon-shaman_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The items to be returned include Chansley's "horned coyote-tail headdress" and a six-foot pole]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar-rahul-gandhis-pak-question-at-meeting-on-bangladesh-s-jaishankars-reply-6274003]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rahul Gandhi's Pak Question At Meeting On Bangladesh, S Jaishankar's Reply]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar-rahul-gandhis-pak-question-at-meeting-on-bangladesh-s-jaishankars-reply-6274003]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:40:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Leader of the Opposition Rahul Gandhi fielded two key questions to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar during the all-party meeting on the situation in Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Prime Minister amid violent protests.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Leader of the Opposition Rahul Gandhi fielded three key questions to External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar during the all-party meeting on the situation in Bangladesh after Sheikh Hasina's ouster as Prime Minister amid violent protests.</p>

<p>Mr Gandhi asked what is the government's short-term and long-term strategy in dealing with diplomatic ramifications of the power shift in Dhaka, sources have said. The minister replied that it is a developing situation and the Centre is analysing it closely so that it can fine-tune its next move.</p>

<p>The Congress leader also asked if there could be an involvement of foreign powers, specifically Pakistan, in the dramatic developments in Dhaka over the past few weeks that culminated in Hasina's ouster, the sources said. The Centre replied that it is investigating this angle. A source also pointed out that the government had said that a Pakistan diplomat had been constantly changing his social media display picture to reflect the situation in Bangladesh amid violent protests. The Centre said is probing if this points to anything bigger.</p>

<p>He also asked if New Delhi had foreseen the dramatic turn of events in Bangladesh. To this, the External Affairs Minister replied that India is monitoring the situation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Congress and the other Opposition parties have pledged their full support to the Narendra Modi government in its handling of the neighbourhood crisis.</p>

<p>Following the meeting, External Affairs Minister Jaishankar put out a post on X, appreciating the Opposition's unanimous support. "Briefed an All-Party meeting in Parliament today about the ongoing developments in Bangladesh. Appreciate the unanimous support and understanding that was extended," he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Briefed an All-Party meeting in Parliament today about the ongoing developments in Bangladesh.<br />
<br />
Appreciate the unanimous support and understanding that was extended. <a href="https://t.co/tiitk5M5zn">pic.twitter.com/tiitk5M5zn</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1820688949305597964?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>At the meeting, also attended by Defence Minister Rajnath Singh and Home Minister Amit Shah, the Centre told MPs from all parties about the background to the crisis in Bangladesh and how it reached this point. They were also briefed about the situation there and how Ms Hasina escaped to India as her residence was stormed by protesters.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina is still in India and is likely to fly to the UK for political asylum. The Centre also told the all-party meet how it plans to respond to Ms Hasina, known to be New Delhi's old friend. Sources said New Delhi wants to give her time to decide her next course of action.</p>

<p>The government also told the meeting that it is in touch with Bangladesh Army, which has announced the formation of an interim government. The government told the Opposition parties that it is watching the developments closely and will take appropriate action at the right time.</p>

<p>There are about 20,000 Indian nationals in Bangladesh and about 8,000 have returned. The government is in touch with them and the high commission is functioning. The Centre, sources said, is also tracking reports of attacks on minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Speaking to NDTV after the meeting, Congress MP Karti Chidambaram said that India's primary concern is the safety of Indian nationals in Bangladesh and the situation at the borders. Asked if the Opposition is satisfied with the way the government is handling the situation, he said, "The fact that the External Affairs Minister briefed all party leaders is a very welcome step. And we are with the government as far as national security is concerned."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e5i79bqo_jaishankar-briefs-opposition-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar chaired an all-party meeting on Bangladesh today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-default-search-tactics-uphold-illegal-monopoly-rules-us-district-court-judge-amit-mehta-6273849]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Court Details How Google Built Illegal Search Monopoly]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/googles-default-search-tactics-uphold-illegal-monopoly-rules-us-district-court-judge-amit-mehta-6273849]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:38:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. District Judge Amit Mehta on Monday ruled that Google had violated antitrust law by spending billions of dollars to secure exclusive agreements with developers, carriers and equipment makers to be the default search engine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US District Judge Amit Mehta on Monday ruled that Google had violated antitrust law by spending billions of dollars to secure exclusive agreements with developers, carriers and equipment makers to be the default search engine.</p>

<p>Here are some key statements the judge made in his 277-page ruling:</p>

<p>"Google is a monopolist, and it has acted as one to maintain its monopoly."</p>

<p>"Sure, users can access Google's rivals by switching the default search access point or by downloading a rival search app or browser. But the market reality is that users rarely do so."</p>

<p>"The default is extremely valuable real estate. Because many users simply stick to searching with the default, Google receives billions of queries every day through those access points."</p>

<p>"Google, of course, recognises that losing defaults would dramatically impact its bottom line. For instance, Google has projected that losing the Safari default would result in a significant drop in queries and billions of dollars in lost revenues."</p>

<p>"The distribution agreements have caused a third key anticompetitive effect: They have reduced the incentive to invest and innovate in search."</p>

<p>"There is no genuine 'competition for the contract.' Google has no true competitor."</p>

<p>"Google has not achieved market dominance by happenstance. It has hired thousands of highly skilled engineers, innovated consistently, and made shrewd business decisions. The result is the industry's highest quality search engine, which has earned Google the trust of hundreds of millions of daily users."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lmr52voo_google_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google has no true competitor, rules US District Judge. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-khaleda-zia-jailed-bangladesh-ex-pm-set-to-be-released-amid-turmoil-6273897]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Khaleda Zia, Jailed Bangla Ex-PM Set To Be Released Amid Turmoil]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-khaleda-zia-jailed-bangladesh-ex-pm-set-to-be-released-amid-turmoil-6273897]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:21:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fall of the Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh points to a big change in the country's political landscape - led by possibilities that the Awami League leader's arch-rival Khaleda Zia may again aim for power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fall of the Sheikh Hasina government in Bangladesh points to a big change in the country's political landscape - led by possibilities that the Awami League leader's arch-rival Khaleda Zia may again aim for power. Ms Zia, the key opposition leader who heads the Bangladesh Nationalist Party, had been elected thrice, though she could run governments for only two terms.</p>

<p>The jailed former premier is now set to leave the prison. Hours after Ms Hasina's ouster yesterday, Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin ordered her release.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are 5 points on the jailed leader:</strong></h2>

<ol>
	<li>Khaleda Zia was born in Jalpaiguri in undivided India. Her husband, Lt Gen Ziaur Rehman, a ruthless military officer, served as the President of Bangladesh from 1977 until he was assassinated I 1981.</li>
	<li>She became the first woman prime minister of Bangladesh in 1991, running the country through a period of serious civil unrest. Falling short of a majority, she had formed the government with the help of the Jamaa-e-Islami.</li>
	<li>Ms Zia went on to win to a second term in 1996, but the elections were boycotted and denounced as unfair by the major opposition parties, including Awami League. Her government lasted only 12 days, after which a caretaker government was installed and fresh elections were called in June. Awami League won the June elections and Ms Hasina went on to became the prime minister for the first time.</li>
	<li>Khaleda Zia returned to power five years later as an alliance of four parties led by her won the elections. She stepped down in 2006 and was arrested for corruption a year later. The former premier had denied the charges and termed the verdict as politically-motivated.</li>
	<li>In 2018, Ms Zia was convicted of corruption charges and jailed for 17 years. Her convicted left her ineligible to contests elections later that year. The BNP leader, who was in poor health, had been largely confined to hospital.</li>
</ol>

<h2><strong>Bangladesh Turmoil</strong></h2>

<p>Bangladesh saw one of its deadliest demonstrations on Sunday with nearly 100 protesters dying in clashes with cops. In the fallout, the protesters breached the Prime Minister's residence on Monday. Ms Hasina avoided a direct confrontation, having already resigned and fled the country in a military plane. The country's army chief called a press conference hours later and declared an interim government would be formed to run the country.</p>

<p>Later in the day, Ms Hasina landed at the Hindon Air Force base in India - about 30 km from capital Delhi. She is likely to leave for London where she may seek asylum, sources told NDTV.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2as3jkt_khaleda-zia_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Khaleda Zia is now set to leave the prison. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-who-is-muhammad-yunus-possible-advisor-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6273576]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Muhammad Yunus, Possible Advisor Of Interim Bangladesh Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-who-is-muhammad-yunus-possible-advisor-of-interim-bangladesh-government-6273576]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:09:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hours after Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country, the coordinators of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement proposed an interim government headed by Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hours after <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/unstable-bangladesh-can-lead-to-volcanic-eruption-says-nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-6271452">Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina</a> resigned and fled the country, the coordinators of the Anti-Discrimination Student Movement proposed an interim government headed by Nobel Laureate Dr Muhammad Yunus. The student movement cited the emergency, including indiscriminate firing, attacks on temples and widespread looting, as the reason for announcing the proposal earlier than expected.</p>

<p>The anti-quota stir, which started roughly a month ago, slowly transformed into anti-government demonstrations. On Monday, the protesters, defying the nationwide curfew, stormed the Prime Minister's home and declared a win for the people of Bangladesh.</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts about Muhammad Yunus:</strong></p>

<p>1. Muhammad Yunus was born in 1940 in Chittagong, a seaport city in Bangladesh. He pursued his early education at Dhaka University in Bangladesh. Later, he received a Fulbright scholarship to study economics at Vanderbilt University in the United States, where he earned his PhD in economics in 1969.</p>

<p>2. After obtaining his PhD, Mr Yunus became an assistant professor of economics at Middle Tennessee State University. In the mid-1970s, he returned to Bangladesh and took up the position of head of the economics department at Chittagong University. At the time, Mr Yunus started providing small personal loans to destitute basket weavers, and the idea later inspired him to establish the Grameen Bank in 1983.</p>

<p>3. The bank focused on providing tiny loans (as small as Rs 2000) to women in rural Bangladesh to start small businesses – poultry farming, weaving or selling goods. The loans were offered without collateral, and repayment was based on trust and peer pressure. This approach helped millions lift themselves out of poverty, earning Mr Yunus the nickname “Banker to the Poor”. The Grameen Bank model has since been replicated in over 100 countries worldwide.</p>

<p>4. Throughout his life, Mr Yunus received numerous international awards and held several significant positions. From 1993 to 1995, he was a member of the International Advisory Group for the Fourth World Conference on Women, appointed by the UN Secretary-General. He also served on the Global Commission of Women's Health, the Advisory Council for Sustainable Economic Development, and the UN Expert Group on Women and Finance. Notable awards during this period include the Independence Day Award (1987), Bangladesh's highest award; the World Food Prize (1994); and the King Hussein Humanitarian Leadership Award (2000).&nbsp;In 2006, the Nobel Committee jointly awarded the Nobel Peace Prize to Muhammad Yunus and Grameen Bank for their groundbreaking work in microfinance and economic empowerment in the country.</p>

<p>5. In June 2024, Muhammad Yunus was indicted by a Bangladesh court on charges of corruption and embezzlement of 252.2 million taka (Rs 219.4 crore) from the workers' welfare fund of his telecoms company, Grameen Telecom. Grameen Telecom owns a 34.2 per cent stake in Grameenphone, the country's largest mobile phone company. Mr Yunus and 13 others were accused of misappropriating funds and engaging in money laundering. The 83-year-old denied any wrongdoing and claimed the charges were politically motivated. In January, he was also sentenced to six months in prison for labour law violations but got out on bail.</p>

<p>Over the last month, since the beginning of the anti-quota protests primarily led by students, at least 300 people lost their lives after authorities took action against demonstrators across Bangladesh. The protesters argued that the government's job reservation policy for freedom fighters' families favoured the Awami League members. They demanded a merit-based system, instead.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8v0rqhuo_muhammad-yunus-reuters_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus has received numerous international awards and held several significant positions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/torture-passengers-struggle-to-breathe-after-ac-malfunctions-on-thai-airways-plane-6273796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Passengers Struggle To Breathe After AC Malfunctions On Thai Airways Plane]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/torture-passengers-struggle-to-breathe-after-ac-malfunctions-on-thai-airways-plane-6273796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 11:08:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[We were hot and couldn't breathe. At least in a sauna, you can leave when you want," said a passenger on the flight.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident, passengers on Thai Airways flight TG 917 flight suffered panic attacks and struggled to breathe when the plane was halted for two hours after the air condition system malfunctioned, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/05/lifestyle/we-got-trapped-in-a-sweltering-sauna-airplane-we-were-so-hot-we-couldnt-breathe/"><em>New York Post</em></a>. The incident took place on July 25 on a Boeing 777. The flight from London to Bangkok was later cancelled entirely.</p>

<p>Due to this, passengers were stuck inside the plane in heat while crew members monitored the situation and attempted to fix it. "People were stuck on the plane and couldn't leave. We were hot and couldn't breathe. At least in a sauna, you can leave when you want," said Warawalan Maksaen, 26, a student at the University of Exeter.</p>

<p>She added, "This was like a form of torture."</p>

<p>According to another passenger, the temperature was so high that passengers began sweating heavily and one even experienced a panic attack. Ms Maksaen claims that throughout this time, neither food nor water was given, which made the situation worse. Two hours later, a flight attendant opened the door to allow in fresh air and provided water in the kitchen area.</p>

<p>However, because of the airport's curfew, no technicians were accessible, and the passengers were forced to disembark at 11 pm after being forced to spend several hours inside the sweltering hot aircraft.</p>

<p>The flight was rescheduled for the next day and passengers were given two options for their accommodation. "We could either sleep in the airport until the rescheduled flight or take a bus to find a hotel. Myself and a lot of the other passengers went to the bus station to wait for transportation to a hotel," the 26-year-old added.</p>

<p>"There was no help from the airline, and the last group of passengers waited aimlessly until the last three buses arrived at 2 am," she told the outlet.</p>

<p>Adding to the horrifying experience, the hotel provided by the airline only had eight rooms available. As families were prioritised, solo travellers like Ms Maksaen were left to sort their lodgings on their own.</p>

<p>Further, the plane's engine did not start when the passengers boarded the flight again the following day at 3:45 pm, forcing them to wait inside the aircraft before disembarking once again. At 6:49 pm, the passengers were eventually permitted to get on the aircraft. "I was so disappointed by Thai Airways. Their service was appalling, and I sent a complaint email after the incident. I have received a compensation offer, either as cash or a discount voucher for my next flight, which I chose as cash because I do not want to fly with this airline again," Ms Maksaen concluded.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b9jaug3g_-thai-airways_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on July 25 on a Boeing 777.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-controversial-us-influencer-gifts-donald-trump-a-tesla-cybertruck-and-rolex-during-interview-6273722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Controversial YouTuber Gifts Donald Trump A Tesla Cybertruck, Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-controversial-us-influencer-gifts-donald-trump-a-tesla-cybertruck-and-rolex-during-interview-6273722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 10:51:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gifts, valued at over $60,000, may pose legal challenges for Trump due to exceeding federal campaign contribution limits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Adin Ross, a streamer known for his provocative content and multiple bans from Twitch, recently interviewed former US President Donald Trump and presented him with a customised Tesla Cybertruck,&nbsp;<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/08/05/donald-trump-tesla-cybertruck-adin-ross-elon-musk/">Fortune</a></em> reported. Following the 60-minute interview, Mr Ross escorted Donald Trump outside his Mar-a-Lago residence to unveil the customised Tesla Cybertruck.</p>

<p>The vehicle's exterior featured a striking design, showcasing an image of Trump with a bloodied face and raised fist, taken moments after an assassination attempt at a rally, surrounded by numerous American flags and a prominent red "Make America Great Again" logo emblazoned on the front. Mr Ross also gifted Trump a gold Rolex watch during the interview.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The gifts, valued at over $60,000, may pose legal challenges for Trump due to exceeding federal campaign contribution limits.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">JUST IN: Donald Trump gets into a Cybertruck with Kick streamer Adin Ross during Ross' stream at Mar-a-Lago.<br />
<br />
Trump immediately went on the Cybertruck's massive 18.5-inch display to pick out a song.<br />
<br />
Trump decided to go with California Dreamin' before changing the song to play… <a href="https://t.co/622PlviN6Z">pic.twitter.com/622PlviN6Z</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1820527341153792418?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>''That's an Elon,'' Trump joked as he saw the car, referring to Tesla CEO Elon Musk. ''It's beautiful. It's incredible.'' The duo had a&nbsp;lighthearted and entertaining time together in the vehicle, jamming out to a playlist of classic hits from the Beach Boys, Elvis Presley, Michael Jackson, and even the iconic "YMCA" song.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Donald Trump in Tesla Cybertruck.<br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/yMbIfNoAu3">pic.twitter.com/yMbIfNoAu3</a></p>
— DogeDesigner (@cb_doge) <a href="https://twitter.com/cb_doge/status/1820531756875083879?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk also reacted to an image of Trump near the Cybertruck with fire emojis.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="qme">??</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1820558416160448691?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>During the interview, the 45th president also revealed that his 18-year-old son is a fan of Mr Ross. ''My son Barron says hello. He's a great young guy but he's a big fan of yours,'' Trump said.</p>

<p>Notably, Adin Ross has been banned from Twitch multiple times for hate speech and inappropriate content and has supported controversial figures like Andrew Tate. He&nbsp;has also displayed pornographic images during his livestreams and promoted gambling to an audience that includes young boys.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This development comes as the Trump campaign seeks to strengthen its appeal among younger voters. Before President Biden's unexpected exit from the race last month, some polls indicated that Trump was making headway with younger men in particular.</p>

<p>Catering to younger audiences, Trump promised to ''save TikTok'' and encouraged users of the popular short-form video platform to support him, despite having advocated for the social media company's ban during his presidency.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5ou3ohc8_-tesla-cybertruck_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Adin Ross has been banned from Twitch multiple times for hate speech and inappropriate content]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>