<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:47:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-cloud-outage-news-steve-jobs-1995-interview-as-microsoft-battles-global-outage-steve-jobs-3rd-rate-products-jab-6139662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Steve Jobs' "3rd-Rate Products" Jab At Microsoft Amid Global Cloud Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-cloud-outage-news-steve-jobs-1995-interview-as-microsoft-battles-global-outage-steve-jobs-3rd-rate-products-jab-6139662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:19:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft makes "third-rate products" - Apple co-founder Steve Jobs' damning assessment of the Seattle-based software giant, made back in 1995, went viral Friday as the company battles a major Windows outage issue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/microsoft-windows" target="_blank">Microsoft</a> makes "third-rate products" - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/apple" target="_blank">Apple</a> co-founder <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/steve-jobs" target="_blank">Steve Jobs</a>' damning assessment of the Seattle-based software giant, made back in 1995, went viral Friday as the company battles a major <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975" target="_blank">Windows outage issue that has affected millions of users</a>, including commercial services like airlines.</p>

<p>Microsoft Inc. said the error was due to a recent CrowdStrike update, and that it is working recover all affected services. In a detailed post on X the company said it is also "working on rerouting impacted traffic to alternate systems to alleviate impact in a more expedient fashion".</p>

<p>Meanwhile, as the company races to resolve the problem, an interview Steve Jobs gave nearly three decades ago has re-emerged online and has been widely shared.</p>

<p>"The only problems with Microsoft is that they have no taste... they have absolutely no taste. I don't mean that in a small way... I mean that in a big way. They don't think of original ideas and don't bring much culture into their products," Jobs told Bob Cringely, the tech journalist.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Steve Jobs about Microsoft - They make third class products. Today many people would be feeling it.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Microsoft?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Microsoft</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bluescreen?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#bluescreen</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Windows?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Windows</a><br><br> <a href="https://t.co/IYnKvGaFaf">pic.twitter.com/IYnKvGaFaf</a></p>&mdash; Ashutosh Mishra (@caashutosh22) <a href="https://twitter.com/caashutosh22/status/1814209634292408371?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"... you say, 'Well, why is that important?' Well, proportionally-spaced fonts come from typesetting and beautiful books. That's where one gets the idea (and) if it weren't for the Mac, they would never have that in their products," he explained.</p>

<p>"And so, I guess I am saddened... not by Microsoft's success. I have no problem with their success. They've earned their success... for the most part."</p>

<p>"I have a problem with the fact that they just make really third-rate products."</p>

<h3><strong>Microsoft Cloud Outage Explained</strong></h3>

<p>According to Microsoft's Service Health Status updates, the preliminary root cause is "a configuration change in a portion of our Azure backend workloads (that has) caused interruption between storage and compute resources, and which (has) resulted in connectivity failures..."</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-outage-how-to-resolve-dreaded-blue-screen-of-death-6139017#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">What Is Causing Dreaded Windows 'Blue Screen Of Death'?</a></p>

<p>These failures affected "downstream (and dependent) Microsoft 365 services".</p>

<p>CrowdStrike Engineering - a cybersecurity services firm that works with Microsoft - has identified a content deployment related to this issue and reverted those changes, and posted steps for resolution for affected Windows users.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Windows Systems Restarting, Throwing 'Blue Screen Of Death' Errors</a></p>

<p>Services, including critical providers like police and government, across the world have been affected.</p>

<h3><strong>Microsoft Services Affected In India</strong></h3>

<p>In India, SpiceJet has said it is experiencing "technical challenges" that have affected online ticket booking and check-in, as well as other functionalities.</p>

<p>" We kindly request passengers with upcoming travel plans to arrive at the airport earlier than usual to complete check-in at our counters," the airline said on X.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-outage-crowdstrike-spicejet-indigo-akasa-air-blue-screen-of-death-error-full-list-of-services-hit-in-india-6139361#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Microsoft 'Blue Screen Of Death': Full List Of Services Hit In India</a></p>

<p>New airline Akasa Air and industry veterans IndiGo have put out similar messages. Flight services at Chennai and Mumbai airports have also begun to be affected, sources have told NDTV.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-10/steve-jobs_650x400_71444446908.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/halfway-through-the-current-solar-cycle-the-sun-is-starting-its-next-6139499]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Halfway Through The Current Solar Cycle, The Sun Is Starting Its Next]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/halfway-through-the-current-solar-cycle-the-sun-is-starting-its-next-6139499]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:15:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Even though the Sun is just halfway through its current cycle, the first rumblings of its next 11-year solar cycle have been detected in sound waves within it, according to a team of researchers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even though the Sun is just halfway through its current cycle, the first rumblings of its next 11-year solar cycle have been detected in sound waves within it, according to a team of researchers.</p>

<p>This current cycle is presently reaching its peak, or solar maximum that occurs when the Sun's magnetic field flips and its poles swap places, until mid-2025.</p>

<p>It impacts the Sun's surface activity, with sunspots, flares, and coronal mass ejections all increasing during solar maximum.</p>

<p>This causes an increase in electromagnetic energy heading towards Earth, making auroras more visible and at lower altitudes.</p>

<p>The current solar cycle, known as Cycle 25, began in 2019. It is not expected to end for another six years but researchers from the University of Birmingham have spotted the first signs that the next solar cycle is beginning.</p>

<p>They presented the findings at the Royal Astronomical Society's National Assistance Astronomy in Hull.</p>

<p>Dr. Rachel Howe, Helioseismology Research Fellow at the University of Birmingham, and her team have detected early signs of solar cycle 26 through internal sound waves in the Sun, revealing bands of faster and slower rotation.</p>

<p>This pattern, observed using helioseismic data from GONG, MDI, and HMI since 1995, shows faster-moving material drifting toward the Equator before each solar cycle starts.</p>

<p>Comparing data from Solar Cycles 23, 24, and 25, researchers note a repeating but not identical pattern.</p>

<p>Dr. Howe, monitoring these changes for 25 years, is excited about the first hints of Cycle 26, expected to start around 2030, offering insights into the Sun's plasma and magnetic fields.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/cqi3c0n_the-sun-generic_625x300_13_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This current cycle is presently reaching its peak, or solar maximum. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-microsoft-outage-fliers-get-handwritten-boarding-passes-after-microsoft-outage-hits-systems-6139541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fliers Get Handwritten Boarding Passes After Microsoft Outage Hits Systems]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-microsoft-outage-fliers-get-handwritten-boarding-passes-after-microsoft-outage-hits-systems-6139541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 14:03:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With a global Microsoft outage hitting tech systems in airports across the world, air carriers in India are checking in passengers manually.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a global Microsoft outage hitting tech systems in airports across the world, air carriers in India are checking in passengers manually.</p>

<p>Most of the country's air carries, including Vistara, IndiGo, SpiceJet and Akasa Air, have been affected by the global crisis that has crippled multiple sectors, including aviation, supermarkets, emergency response, stock exchanges and the media.</p>

<p>The air carriers have put out statements, informing fliers that many of their online services have been affected and that they are working to fix them at the earliest.</p>

<p>Akshay Kothari, co-founder of US-based firm NotionHQ, shared on X a picture of his "first handwritten boarding pass" before travelling</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Microsoft / CrowdStrike outage has taken down most airports in India. I got my first hand-written boarding pass today ? <a href="https://t.co/xsdnq1Pgjr">pic.twitter.com/xsdnq1Pgjr</a></p>
— Akshay Kothari (@akothari) <a href="https://twitter.com/akothari/status/1814202068531552666?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"The Microsoft/CrowdStrike outage has taken down most airports in India. I got my first hand-written boarding pass today," he posted on X.</p>

<p>The boarding was like one most of us have never seen, with flight number, seat number and boarding time written by hand.</p>

<p>Millions of Windows users worldwide are experiencing the Blue Screen of Death that is causing computers to shut down or restart. In some cases, computers are restarting repeatedly, affecting services as users lose unsaved data and critical time.</p>

<p>As the systems shut down, a message on the screen says, "Your PC ran into a problem and needs to restart. We're just collecting some error info, and then we'll restart for you."</p>

<p>Blue Screen errors, also known as black screen errors or STOP code errors, can occur when a critical issue forces Windows to unexpectedly shut down or restart.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4lntlmuo_indigo-boarding-pass_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Akshay Kothari, a flier, shared on X a photo of his handwritten boarding pass]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-showing-blue-screen-of-death-error-heres-how-you-can-fix-it-6139367]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Windows Showing Blue Screen Of Death Error? Here's How You Can Fix It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-showing-blue-screen-of-death-error-heres-how-you-can-fix-it-6139367]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 13:37:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Windows users worldwide are experiencing the dreaded Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error, causing their systems to suddenly shut down or restart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Windows users worldwide are experiencing the dreaded Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error, causing their systems to suddenly shut down or restart. Microsoft has identified the issue as a recent <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820 ">CrowdStrike update</a> gone wrong.</p>

<p><strong>Why is this happening?</strong></p>

<p>CrowdStrike Engineering acknowledged the problem, stating, "CrowdStrike Engineering has identified a content deployment related to this issue and reverted those changes."</p>

<p>The bug, linked to CrowdStrike's update, has disrupted operations across numerous companies, banks and government offices globally. This issue has affected essential services and daily operations.</p>

<p><strong>Immediate fixes</strong></p>

<p>CrowdStrike has also provided workaround steps:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Boot Windows into Safe Mode or the Windows Recovery Environment (press F8 or Shift + F8 to enter Safe Mode).</li>
	<li>Go to a specific folder on your computer - C:\Windows\System32\drivers\CrowdStrike</li>
	<li>Locate the file matching "C-00000291*.sys" and delete it.</li>
	<li>Boot the host normally (Restart your computer).&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p>The <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/resolving-blue-screen-errors-in-windows-60b01860-58f2-be66-7516-5c45a66ae3c6 ">BSOD</a>, also known as a STOP, can occur when a serious bug or a virus causes Windows to shut down or restart unexpectedly, often displaying a message like "Windows has been shut down to prevent damage to your computer." Both hardware and software issues can cause these errors.</p>

<p><strong>Tips by Microsoft</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>If you have recently added new hardware, shut down your PC, remove the hardware, and try restarting.</li>
	<li>If you're having trouble restarting, you can start your PC in Safe Mode.</li>
	<li>Make sure your Windows operating system is up to date by checking for the latest updates. Go to Settings &gt; Update &amp; Security &gt; Windows Update.</li>
	<li>If the issue continues, consider restoring Windows to an earlier point in time before the error occurred. Navigate to Control Panel &gt; System and Security &gt; System &gt; System Protection &gt; System Restore.</li>
	<li>If none of these steps helps, try the Blue Screen Troubleshooter in the Get Help app:</li>
	<li>In Windows, open Get Help.</li>
	<li>In the Get Help app, type "Troubleshoot BSOD error".</li>
	<li>Follow the guided walkthrough in the Get Help app.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/befdi148_computer-generic_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cyber-outage-hits-government-media-and-telcos-in-australia-and-new-zealand-6139360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cyber Outage Hits Government, Media And Telcos In Australia, New Zealand]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cyber-outage-hits-government-media-and-telcos-in-australia-and-new-zealand-6139360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 13:36:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A cyber outage related to an issue at global cybersecurity firm Crowdstrike and Microsoft hit media, retailers, banks, airlines and telecoms companies across Australia and New Zealand on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cyber outage related to an issue at global cybersecurity firm Crowdstrike and Microsoft hit media, retailers, banks, airlines and telecoms companies across Australia and New Zealand on Friday.</p>

<p>Australia's largest bank, Commonwealth Bank said some customers had been unable to transfer money due to the service outage. National airline Qantas and Sydney airport said planes were delayed but still flying.</p>

<p>Victorian state police said some internal systems had been hit by the outage but emergency services were operating normally. The output of a number of media companies was also disrupted.</p>

<p>"Like a number of other organisations, global issues affecting CrowdStrike and Microsoft are disrupting some of our systems," a spokesperson for telecoms firm Telstra said on Friday.</p>

<p>"The issue is causing some holdups for some of our customers and we thank them for their patience."</p>

<p>Crowdstrike ran a recorded phone message on Friday when Reuters contacted its technical support saying it was aware of reports of crashes on Microsoft's Windows operating system relating to its Falcon sensor, without mentioning Australia.</p>

<p>There was no information to suggest the outage was a cyber security incident, the office of Australia's National Cyber Security Coordinator Michelle McGuinness said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"I am aware of a large-scale technical outage affecting a number of companies and services across Australia this afternoon," it said in the statement which did not mention Crowdstrike.</p>

<p>"Our current information is this outage relates to a technical issue with a third-party software platform employed by affected companies."</p>

<p>A spokesperson for New Zealand's parliament said its computer systems had also been affected.</p>

<p>State broadcaster ABC said it was experiencing a "major network outage", without giving a reason.</p>

<p>In a pre-recorded message played on Sky News Australia as regular programming was disrupted, correspondent Tom Connell said the outage was not believed to be the result of a hack.</p>

<p>"Our computers, our systems are down, all the things that make Sky News run down and indeed for many other major companies around the country," he said.</p>

<p>A Reuters reporter saw error messages on payment systems at grocery chain Harris Farm in Sydney on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0qs8jbe8_microsoft_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia's largest bank said some customers had been unable to transfer money due to the service outage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/riots-break-out-in-leeds-bus-set-on-fire-police-car-flipped-over-6139119]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Riots Break Out In London, Bus Set On Fire, Police Car Flipped Over]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/riots-break-out-in-leeds-bus-set-on-fire-police-car-flipped-over-6139119]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:56:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A riot has broken out in UK's Leeds after police were called to attend an incident involving some agency workers and children, officials said on Thursday night.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A riot has broken out in UK's Leeds after police were called to attend an incident involving some agency workers and children, officials said on Thursday night.</p>

<p>According to West Yorkshire Police, they were called to an ongoing incident at Luxor Street, Harehills, at 5 p.m. on Thursday. On arrival, officers "found an ongoing disturbance which involved some agency workers and some children."</p>

<p>Soon, a crowd started to gather at the location after which officers decided to remove the agency workers and the children to a safe place. However, tensions grew and "pockets of disorder" broke out in the area.</p>

<p>Purported footage shared on social media showed a large crowd of people in the street and a police car being flipped onto its side while a bus was being set on fire.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Riots have erupted in Harehills, Leeds tonight after Social Services took children away from a Roma Gypsy family, with a police car overturned and a bus now set on fire.<br />
<br />
Britain needs to stop importing people with an alien culture and value system. Enough is enough. <a href="https://t.co/QJ4NKPaEUy">pic.twitter.com/QJ4NKPaEUy</a></p>
— Cillian (@CilComLFC) <a href="https://twitter.com/CilComLFC/status/1814045787472761246?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"More officers have been deployed to the area to assist with the management of this incident. Some road closures are also being implemented and people are advised to avoid the area at this time," the West Yorkshire Police said in a statement.</p>

<p>"No injuries have been reported and enquiries are ongoing at the scene," it added.</p>

<p>UK Home Secretary Yvette Cooper took to social media platform X to condemn the violence. She posted: "I am appalled at the shocking scenes and attacks on police vehicles &amp; public transport in Leeds tonight (Thursday night). Disorder of this nature has no place in our society. My thanks go to West Yorkshire police for their response. I am being kept regularly updated."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qtbg82_leeds-riots-x-_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions grew and "pockets of disorder" broke out in the area.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blue-screen-of-death-flights-markets-banks-stock-exchange-microsoft-outage-crippling-sectors-6139053]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Massive Worldwide Microsoft Outage: Flights, Markets, Stock Exchange Down]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blue-screen-of-death-flights-markets-banks-stock-exchange-microsoft-outage-crippling-sectors-6139053]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:40:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From flights to supermarkets to banking operations, the global Microsoft outage is disrupting multiple sectors and threatens to lead to massive issues if it is not resolved soon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From flights to supermarkets to banking operations, the global Microsoft outage is disrupting multiple sectors and threatens to lead to massive issues if it is not resolved soon.&nbsp;In India, almost all air carriers -- Vistara, IndiGo,&nbsp;SpiceJet and Akasa Air -- are facing technical issues that are affecting booking, check-in and flight updates. The airlines are now checking in passengers manually.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ImportantUpdate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ImportantUpdate</a>: We are currently experiencing technical challenges with our service provider, affecting online services including booking, check-in, and manage booking functionalities. As a result, we have activated manual check-in and boarding processes across airports. We…</p>
— SpiceJet (@flyspicejet) <a href="https://twitter.com/flyspicejet/status/1814194223052144749?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"We're currently facing a technical issue in providing updates on flight disruptions. Our team is actively working to resolve this issue. We regret for any inconvenience caused and will update you once the issue is resolved. Thank you for your patience and co-operation," Spicejet has said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TravelUpdate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TravelUpdate</a>: Due to infrastructure issues with our service provider, some of our online services, including booking, check-in and manage booking services will be temporarily unavailable. Currently we are following manual check-in and boarding processes at the airports and hence…</p>
— Akasa Air (@AkasaAir) <a href="https://twitter.com/AkasaAir/status/1814182658840134131?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Akasa Air said some of their online services are currently unavailable. "Due to infrastructure issues with our service provider, some of our online services, including booking, check-in and manage booking services will be temporarily unavailable. Currently we are following manual check-in and boarding processes at the airports and hence request passengers with immediate travel plans to reach the airport early to check-in at our counters,"&nbsp;Akasa Air posted on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our systems are currently impacted by a Microsoft outage, which is also affecting other companies. During this time booking, check-in, access to your boarding pass, and some flights may be impacted. We appreciate your patience.</p>
— IndiGo (@IndiGo6E) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiGo6E/status/1814197878954348642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>IndiGo, too, has put out a statement. "Our systems are currently impacted by a Microsoft outage, which is also affecting other companies. During this time booking, check-in, access to your boarding pass, and some flights may be impacted. We appreciate&nbsp;your&nbsp;patience," it said.</p>

<p>Vistara has also mentioned technical challenges. "We're experiencing technical challenges across various aspects of our operations due to a global outage at our service provider's end. We are working with them to resolve the issue as quickly as possible. We regret any inconvenience caused and appreciate your patience," it has said in a post on X.</p>

<p>Delhi airport has said that some services have been affected. "Due to the global IT issue, some of the services at the Delhi Airport were temporarily impacted. We are closely working with all our stakeholders to minimise the inconvenience to our flyers.&nbsp;Passengers are requested to be in touch with the airline concerned or the help desk on ground for updated flight information. We regret the inconvenience caused to our passengers,"&nbsp;they said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Due to the global IT issue, some of the services at the Delhi Airport were temporarily impacted.<br />
<br />
We are closely working with all our stakeholders to minimise the inconvenience to our flyers.</p>
— Delhi Airport (@DelhiAirport) <a href="https://twitter.com/DelhiAirport/status/1814203660186120407?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Systems are also down at Bengaluru airport, although the exact number of flights delayed is not known yet.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Among the countries worst affected is Australia.&nbsp;According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.smh.com.au/national/australia-news-live-cfmeu-fallout-continues-energy-ministers-to-discuss-cost-of-living-20240719-p5juwi.html">The Sydney Morning Herald</a>, the outage has hit ABC News 24 that struggled to play news packages. The crisis then hit Woolworths supermarkets where checkout systems crashed due to the outage. Several customers also complained that their cards are not working. Police systems went down too.</p>

<p>Melbourne airport said in a statement that check-in process of several airlines are affected due to a global technology issue. Virgin Australia has said the outage is preventing all planes from coming and going at Sydney Airport. "The airline has put a stop on in-and-out flights, so it's a complete ground stop; there's no flights coming in and there's no flights going out," a staff member said at the Virgin Australia lounge, according to The Sydney Morning Herald.</p>

<p>The London Stock Exchange, reports said, has been affected by the outage. The US' Federal Aviation Administration has said all&nbsp;flights from several major US airlines – including Delta, United and American Airlines – were grounded Friday morning due to a communication issue.&nbsp;911 emergency services in several states of the US have been hit too. British news channel Sky News is off air for hours now.</p>

<p>As for Europe, technical issues are causing check-in delays in Amsterdam. At&nbsp;Berlin Brandenburg airport in Germany, flight operations had to cancelled due to the "technical problem", a spokeswoman told AFP. She said she cannot say when flight movement would resume.&nbsp;Zurich airport, the largest in Switzerland, suspended all flight arrivals because of the tech outage, AFP has reported.</p>

<p>Millions of Windows users worldwide are experiencing the Blue Screen of Death that is causing computers to shut down or restart. In some cases, computers are restarting repeatedly, affecting services as users lose unsaved data and critical time.</p>

<p>As the systems shut down, a message on the screen says, "Your PC ran into a problem and needs to restart. We're just collecting some error info, and then we'll restart for you."</p>

<p>Blue Screen errors, also known as black screen errors or STOP code errors, can occur when a critical issue forces Windows to unexpectedly shut down or restart.</p>

<p>Microsoft 365 has said in a statement that they are investigating the issue.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0qs8jbe8_microsoft_625x300_28_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-outage-how-to-resolve-dreaded-blue-screen-of-death-6139017]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Is Causing The Dreaded 'Blue Screen Of Death' On Windows?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-outage-how-to-resolve-dreaded-blue-screen-of-death-6139017]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:34:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Cloud Outage: A major tech issue has affected millions of Windows computer systems worldwide, causing a sudden shutdown or restart. Microsoft Inc. said the error is due to a recent CrowdStrike update.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975" target="_blank">major tech issue has affected millions of Windows computer systems</a> worldwide, causing a sudden shutdown or restart. Microsoft Inc. said the error is due to a recent CrowdStrike update.</p>

<p>According to Microsoft's <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://status.cloud.microsoft/" target="_blank">Service Health Status</a> updates, the preliminary root cause is "a configuration change in a portion of our Azure backend workloads (that has) caused interruption between storage and compute resources, and which (has) resulted in connectivity failures..."</p>

<p>These failures, the company said, had affected "downstream (and dependent) Microsoft 365 services".</p>

<p>CrowdStrike Engineering - a cybersecurity services firm that works with Microsoft - has identified a content deployment related to this issue and reverted those changes.</p>

<p>The company has posted steps for resolution for affected Windows users.</p>

<h3><strong>Workaround</strong></h3>

<div class="sp_only-ul-ol sp_only-ul-ol-2">
<ol>
	<li>Boot Windows into Safe Mode or the Windows Recovery Environment.</li>
	<li>Navigate to the C:\Windows\System32\drivers\CrowdStrike directory.</li>
	<li>Locate the file matching C-00000291*.sys and delete it.</li>
	<li>Boot the host normally.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<h3><strong>What Microsoft Said</strong></h3>

<p>In a detailed thread on X, the software services giant said it is "investigating an issue impacting users ability to access various Microsoft 365 apps and services".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Windows Systems Restarting, Throwing 'Blue Screen Of Death' Errors</a></p>

<p>"We're working on rerouting impacted traffic to alternate systems to alleviate impact in a more expedient fashion," Microsoft said, adding, "We're still observing a positive trend in service availability while we continue to redirect impacted traffic."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We're working on rerouting the impacted traffic to alternate systems to alleviate impact in a more expedient fashion. More info is posted in the admin center under MO821132 and on <a href="https://t.co/Htn4qQEnsp">https://t.co/Htn4qQEnsp</a></p>
— Microsoft 365 Status (@MSFT365Status) <a href="https://twitter.com/MSFT365Status/status/1814088695710204374?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"We still expect users will continue to see gradual relief as we continue to mitigate the issue."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our services are still seeing continuous improvements while we continue to take mitigation actions. More details can be found within the admin center under MO821132 and <a href="https://t.co/Htn4qQEnsp">https://t.co/Htn4qQEnsp</a></p>
— Microsoft 365 Status (@MSFT365Status) <a href="https://twitter.com/MSFT365Status/status/1814181228196835622?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Services are seeing "continuous improvements while we continue to take mitigation actions".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-said-on-windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-error-6138997#pfrom=home-ndtv_topstories_lastestImg" target="_blank">What Microsoft Said After Global Outage Hits Flight, Bank Ops</a></p>

<p>"We remain committed in treating this event with the highest priority and urgency while we continue to address the lingering impact for the remaining Microsoft 365 apps that are in a degraded state."</p>

<h3><strong>Affected And Recovering Microsoft Services</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft said impacted services may include, but are not limited to, services and software like PowerBI, Fabric, and Teams, as well as the Microsoft 365 admin center.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blue-screen-of-death-flights-markets-banks-stock-exchange-microsoft-outage-crippling-sectors-6139053#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Flights, Markets, Banks, Stock Exchange: Microsoft Outage Crippling Sectors</a></p>

<p>It also said "internal telemetry and customer signals" suggest some services had recovered, at least partially. These include Defender, OneNote, OneDrive for Business, and SharePoint Online.</p>

<h3><strong>Worldwide Windows Outage Impact</strong></h3>

<p>Services, including critical providers like police and government, across the world have been affected.</p>

<p>In India, SpiceJet has said it is experiencing "technical challenges" that have affected online ticket booking and check-in, as well as other functionalities.</p>

<p>" We kindly request passengers with upcoming travel plans to arrive at the airport earlier than usual to complete check-in at our counters," the airline said on X.</p>

<p>New airline Akasa Air and industry veterans IndiGo have put out similar messages. Flight services at Chennai and Mumbai airports have also begun to be affected, sources have told NDTV.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/SI8mcURA1H">pic.twitter.com/SI8mcURA1H</a></p>
— IndiGo (@IndiGo6E) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiGo6E/status/1814195364146057572?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Around the world, Australia's Virgin Australia said it is "aware of a large-scale IT outage impacting airlines and other businesses" and that it too had been affected.</p>

<p>"We are working to resolve this issue as soon as possible..." the airline said.</p>

<p>There are reports of flights being grounded in Australia and the United States.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Melbourne Airport is experiencing a global technology issue which is impacting check-in procedures for some airlines. Passengers flying with these airlines this afternoon are advised to allow a little extra time to check-in. Please check with your airline for flight updates. <a href="https://t.co/pFjOjReMKX">pic.twitter.com/pFjOjReMKX</a></p>
— Melbourne Airport (@Melair) <a href="https://twitter.com/Melair/status/1814187188029894969?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In the former country, the airports in Sydney and Melbourne have cited a "global technology issue" impacting its services. Contingency plans have been activated, both airports said.</p>

<p>Reuters, meanwhile, has reported of services being affected at the airport in German capital Berlin, and Spanish airport operators have confirmed an "incident" at their facilities, the BBC reported.</p>

<p>The tech problem has affected banks and financial services also, with reports the London Stock Exchange faces minor problems. The United Kingdom's Sky News network is off air, the BBC said.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/7j3qq4no_windows-computer-unsplash_625x300_22_December_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Microsoft Outage Today: Windows is the world's most popular computer operating system (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-said-on-windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-error-6138997]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Microsoft Said After Global Outage Hits Flight, Bank Ops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-said-on-windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-error-6138997]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:30:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of Microsoft Windows users across the world are currently experiencing the Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error, which is causing their systems to suddenly shut down or restart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Users of&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820" target="_blank">Microsoft Windows</a>&nbsp;across the world are currently experiencing the "Blue Screen of Death" (BSOD) error, which is causing their systems to suddenly shut down or restart.</p>

<p>The users were unable to access various Microsoft 365 apps and services due to an error caused by a recent update at global cybersecurity firm&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/microsoft-windows-outage-how-to-resolve-dreaded-blue-screen-of-death-6139017" target="_blank">CrowdStrike</a>.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blue-screen-of-death-flights-markets-banks-stock-exchange-microsoft-outage-crippling-sectors-6139053" target="_blank">Microsoft outage</a> began early this morning today and has reportedly affected several companies, airlines, banks, and government offices across India, the US, and Australia.</p>

<p>Pictures posted on social media showed users' screens stuck on the recovery page displaying the following message: "It looks like Windows didn't load correctly. If you'd like to restart and try again, choose Restart my PC below."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/58darqgg_microsoft-error_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>"We remain committed in treating this event with the highest priority and urgency while we continue to address the lingering impact for the Microsoft 365 apps that are in a degraded state," the company said.</p>

<p>"Our services are still seeing continuous improvements while we continue to take mitigation actions," it added.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975" target="_blank">Microsoft Faces Global Outage: Live Updates</a></strong></p>

<p>Blue Screen errors, also sometimes called black screen errors or STOP code errors, can occur if a serious problem causes Windows to shut down or restart unexpectedly.</p>

<h3><strong>What Caused Microsoft Windows Error</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft said the preliminary root cause was a "configuration change" in a portion of its Azure backend workloads.</p>

<p>It caused interruption between storage and compute resources which resulted in connectivity failures that affected downstream Microsoft 365 services dependent on these connections, the US-based company said.</p>

<h3><strong>Microsoft Services That Are Hit</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft said the impacted services include:&nbsp;</p>

<p>- PowerBI: Users may notice that their service is in read-only mode while we address impact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Fabric: Users may notice that their service is in read-only mode while we address impact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Teams: Users may be unable to leverage Microsoft Teams functions including presence, group chats, and user registration.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft 365 admin center: Admins may be intermittently unable to access the Microsoft 365 admin center and any action may be delayed if accessible.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Purview: Users will see a delay in events being processed in Microsoft Purview.</p>

<p>- Viva Engage: Users may be unable to access Viva Engage.</p>

<h3><strong>Microsoft Services That Have Been Recovered</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft said its "internal telemetry and customer signals" indicate that the following services have recovered:&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Defender: Users may be intermittently unable to access the Microsoft Defender portal. Additionally, users may notice delays of up to two hours when raising new detections.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Defender for Endpoint: Admins and users may notice API requests failing and errors when opening Alerts in the Alerts page. &nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft Intune: Users may experience failures with device check-in, syncing and device enrollment.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Microsoft OneNote: Users may be unable to sync content, have delays syncing notebooks, or may be unable to open notebooks.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- OneDrive for Business: Users may be unable to access OneDrive for Business content.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- SharePoint Online: Users may be unable to access SharePoint Online sites.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Windows 365: Admins may be unable to manage existing Cloud PCs or provision new Cloud PCs. End users in the impacted region may not be able to access their Cloud PC.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Microsoft Outage Hits Flight Ops In India</strong></h3>

<p>In India, airlines Spicejet and Akasa Air said they were facing technical issues that affected their booking, check-in, and flight updates.</p>

<p>"We're currently facing a technical issue in providing updates on flight disruptions. Our team is actively working to resolve this issue. We regret for any inconvenience caused and will update you once the issue is resolved. Thank you for your patience and co-operation," Spicejet said in a post on X.</p>

<p>Akasa Air said some of their online services, including bookings and check-ins were temporarily unavailable due to "infrastructure issues" with their service provider.</p>

<p>"Due to infrastructure issues with our service provider, some of our online services, including booking, check-in and manage booking services will be temporarily unavailable. Currently, we are following manual check-in and boarding processes at the airports and hence request passengers with immediate travel plans to reach the airport early to check-in at our counters. We sincerely regret the inconvenience caused and want to assure you that our teams are working with our service provider to resolve the same at the earliest," Akasa Air posted on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qtcdjbb_microsoft-_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Microsoft Windows users are currently experiencing the "Blue Screen of Death" error (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Faces Global Outage, Multiple Users Affected: Live Updates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:27:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of Windows users across the globe are experiencing the Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error which is causing the system to suddenly shut down or restart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Windows users across the globe are experiencing the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-blue-screen-of-death-flights-markets-banks-stock-exchange-microsoft-outage-crippling-sectors-6139053">Blue Screen of Death (BSOD)</a> error which is causing the system to suddenly shut down or restart. Microsoft in a message said that the error is being caused due to a recent CrowdStrike update.</p>

<p>Microsoft said its outage started with a subset of its customers experiencing issues with multiple Azure services in the Central US region.</p>

<p>Azure is a cloud computing platform that provides services for building, deploying, and managing applications and services.</p>

<p>Separately, Microsoft said it was investigating an issue impacting various Microsoft 365 apps and services.</p>

<h3><strong>Here are the live updates of Microsoft Cloud outage:</strong></h3>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/aqohae1g_microsoft_625x300_08_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Microsoft Windows Outage Live Updates: Microsoft said it was investigating the issue.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-whats-behind-bangladesh-protests-that-have-killed-39-6138968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What's Behind Bangladesh Protests, That Have Killed 39]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-whats-behind-bangladesh-protests-that-have-killed-39-6138968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 12:24:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The unrest also led to widespread disruption of communication services on Friday, with internet and mobile services cut off in many areas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 39 people have been killed and over 2,500 have sustained injuries in Bangladesh after clashes between students, government supporters and armed police following protests against service job quotas.</p>

<p>The demonstrations began last month after the High Court reinstated a quota system, reserving 30 per cent of government jobs for family members of freedom fighters and veterans from the 1971 War of Independence.</p>

<p>However, the Supreme Court has since suspended the High Court's order and is set to hear the government's challenge on August 7.</p>

<p>In 2018, the quota system was scrapped by Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's government following similar student-led protests.</p>

<h3><strong>What do Bangladesh protestors demand?</strong></h3>

<p>The protesters are demanding the government scrap the quota system, which they claim benefits only the ruling Awami League party led by Sheikh Hasina. Prime Minister Hasina, the daughter of Bangladesh's founding father Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, has been accused of using the quota system to reward her party's loyalists. Protestors allege the system is unfair and limits their job opportunities.</p>

<p>However, Prime Minister Hasina, refusing to accept any demands, has referred to the protesters as "razakar", an offensive term used to describe those who betrayed the country by collaborating with the Pakistani army in 1971.</p>

<h3><strong>What is quota system in Bangladesh?</strong></h3>

<p>The quota system in Bangladesh was introduced in 1972 and has undergone several changes since then. Before it was abolished in 2018, the system reserved 56 per cent of government jobs for various groups, but the majority of these quotas benefited freedom fighters' families.</p>

<p>Here's how the quotas were allocated:</p>

<p>Women: 10 per cent<br />
Underdeveloped districts: 10 per cent<br />
Indigenous communities: 5 per cent<br />
Disabled people: 1 per cent<br />
The system has now been reinstated again.</p>

<h3><strong>Situation in Bangladesh</strong></h3>

<p>Violence erupted across Bangladesh as police and protesters clashed in various parts of the country, including the capital, Dhaka. The protests, although going on for weeks, took a dark turn on Wednesday when Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina appeared on TV to address the escalating clashes. However, her appearance on a national broadcasting channel seemed to have the opposite effect, as the demonstrators set fire to the country's state broadcaster building on Thursday.</p>

<p>The unrest also led to widespread disruption of communication services on Friday, with internet and mobile services cut off in many areas. The protesters, comprising students, were armed with sticks and rocks, and attempted to shut down transportation services nationwide. Police cracked down on protesters, firing rubber bullets, sound grenades and tear gas to disperse them, reported Reuters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3mat8d78_bangladesh-protest_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The demonstrations began last month]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Windows Computers Lead To 'Blue Screen Of Death' Due To CrowdStrike Error]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/windows-systems-restarting-throwing-blue-screen-of-death-due-to-crowdstrike-error-6138820]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 11:58:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Global Outage: Millions of Windows users across the globe are experiencing the Blue Screen of Death (BSOD) error which is causing the system to suddenly shut down or restart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Windows users across the globe are experiencing the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/resolving-blue-screen-errors-in-windows-60b01860-58f2-be66-7516-5c45a66ae3c6">Blue Screen of Death</a> (BSOD) error which is causing the system to suddenly shut down or restart. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-global-outage-live-updates-microsoft-faces-global-outage-multiple-users-affected-6138975">Microsoft </a>in a message said that the error is being caused due to a recent CrowdStrike update.</p>

<p>The bug has affected several companies, banks and government offices across the globe. Most Indian airlines have taken to X (formerly Twitter) to share the update with fliers.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TravelUpdate?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TravelUpdate</a>: Due to infrastructure issues with our service provider, some of our online services, including booking, check-in and manage booking services will be temporarily unavailable. Currently we are following manual check-in and boarding processes at the airports and hence…</p>
— Akasa Air (@AkasaAir) <a href="https://twitter.com/AkasaAir/status/1814182658840134131?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Our systems are currently impacted by a Microsoft outage, which is also affecting other companies. During this time booking, check-in, access to your boarding pass, and some flights may be impacted. We appreciate your patience.</p>
— IndiGo (@IndiGo6E) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiGo6E/status/1814197878954348642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Social media users posted pictures showing their screens stuck on the recovery page displaying the message: "It looks like Windows didn't load correctly. If you'd like to restart and try again, choose Restart my PC below."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I am aware of a large-scale technical outage affecting a number of companies and services across Australia this afternoon.<br />
<br />
Our current information is this outage relates to a technical issue with a third-party software platform employed by affected companies.</p>
— National Cyber Security Coordinator (@AUCyberSecCoord) <a href="https://twitter.com/AUCyberSecCoord/status/1814183822692598205?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Major US carriers including American Airlines, Delta Airlines and United Airlines issued ground stops on Friday morning citing communication issues. US Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg said the department was monitoring the flight cancellation and delay issues at Frontier, adding that the agency will hold the company and all other airlines "to their responsibilities to meet the needs of passengers".</p>

<p>Microsoft, in a statement, said it was taking "mitigation actions" after service issues. "Our services are still seeing continuous improvements while we continue to take mitigation actions," the company said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"We remain committed in treating this event with the highest priority and urgency while we continue to address the lingering impact for the Microsoft 365 apps that are in a degraded state," the company added.</p>

<h2><strong>What is Blue Screen of Death</strong></h2>

<p>Blue Screen errors, also known as black screen errors or STOP code errors, can occur when a critical issue forces Windows to unexpectedly shut down or restart. You may encounter a message stating, "Windows has been shut down to prevent damage to your computer" or a similar notification.</p>

<p>These errors can stem from hardware or software problems. If you recently installed new hardware and encountered a Blue Screen error, try shutting down your PC, removing the new hardware, and attempting to restart. If restarting poses difficulty, you can initiate your PC in safe mode. For detailed steps, refer to the instructions on starting your PC in safe mode in Windows.</p>

<p>Additionally, consider updating Windows with the latest patches through Windows Update, seeking assistance from other sources, or restoring Windows to a previous restore point.</p>

<h3>How to Fix Windows Blue Screen Error</h3>

<p>If none of these measures resolve the Blue Screen error, utilize the Blue Screen Troubleshooter available in the Get Help app:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Open the Get Help app in Windows.</li>
	<li>Type "Troubleshoot BSOD error" in the search bar of the Get Help app.</li>
	<li>Follow the step-by-step instructions provided in the Get Help app.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/b20d3j08_microsoft-blue-screen-error_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Windows crashed, consider updating Windows with the latest patches through Windows Update]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-shooters-father-called-cops-about-missing-gun-before-attack-report-6138622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Shooter's Father Called Cops About Missing Gun Before Attack: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-shooters-father-called-cops-about-missing-gun-before-attack-report-6138622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 11:21:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Donald Trump: Before Thomas Matthew Crooks aimed his AR-15 gun at Former US President Donald Trump during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, his father contacted the police, concerned about his son's location.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before Thomas Matthew Crooks aimed his AR-15 gun at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/too-painful-wont-narrate-again-donald-trump-recounts-being-shot-at-6137658">former US President Donald Trump</a> during a campaign rally in Pennsylvania, his father contacted the police, concerned about his son's location when a gun, one of the many he owned, was missing from their home.</p>

<p>The call, another red flag in a series of warnings to law enforcement before the attack, came from Crooks' father Matthew Crooks after his son disappeared without any notice, a report by BBC said.</p>

<p>While some reports suggest the call happened before the shootingm others suggest Matthew Crooks called police after the shooting.</p>

<p>The gun, used by Crooks in the unsuccessful assassination bid, was identified as his father's 5.56 caliber AR-style rifle which he purchased in 2013, police said. Police sources told NBC that Crooks purchased 50 rounds of ammunition hours before the shooting.</p>

<p>When police searched Crooks' home in Bethel Park, some 85 km from the Trump rally, over a dozen firearms were found inside. As per Pennsylvania law, gun owners do not have to store their firearms in a lock box or other locked storage, but they are encouraged to do so.</p>

<p>Police also found that ahead of the attack, the 20-year-old made several online searches related to Trump as well as his rival US President Biden. He also searched "major depressive disorder" as well as the Democratic National Convention to be held for August.</p>

<p>Reports said police found that he had images of Trump, Biden, Attorney General Merrick Garland, FBI Director Chris Wray and a member of the British Royal Family.</p>

<p>The FBI also found a metal box of explosives in the car which Crooks drove to the rally.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Crooks' motive in the shooting remains unclear but the FBI and other law enforcement agencies have launched investigations. Currently, the FBI are were sifting through Crooks' phone and other electronic devices.</p>

<p>While the motive behind the attack is still unclear, preliminary investigation found that he climbed onto the roof of a nearby building outside the rally, some 300 metres away from where Trump was on stage.</p>

<p>The bullet missed Trump by a few inches but grazed the top of his right ear. Amid chaos and screams, Trump was ushered off stage by Secret Service agents with blood smeared on his face.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/bv51s1j_thomas-matthew-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks fired several rounds at the Trump campaign rally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/200-million-year-old-well-preserved-dinosaur-fossil-found-after-brazil-flood-6138583]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[200-Million-Year-Old "Well-Preserved" Dinosaur Fossil Found In Brazil Flood]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/200-million-year-old-well-preserved-dinosaur-fossil-found-after-brazil-flood-6138583]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 11:15:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Torrential rains causing historic flooding in southern Brazil have revealed a "very well-preserved" dinosaur fossil dating back some 200 million years, according to the research team who discovered it.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Torrential rains causing historic flooding in southern Brazil have revealed a "very well-preserved" dinosaur fossil dating back some 200 million years, according to the research team who discovered it.</p>

<p>The fossil was first identified in May near the city of Sao Joao do Polesine, some 280 kilometres (170 miles) west of Porto Alegre, in a part of the Brazilian pampas dubbed the country's 'El Dorado' of paleontology.</p>

<p>A team of paleontologists from the Federal University of Santa Maria spent four days excavating the fossil to remove the block of rock containing a "near complete" dinosaur fossil to take back to their research centre for the study.</p>

<p>Initial findings have determined the fossil was a specimen of the Herrerasauridae family, which were bipedal carnivores with long tails found in the area of modern-day Brazil and Argentina.</p>

<p>The fossil dates to the Triassic period, between 250 to 200 million years ago.</p>

<p>Rodrigo Temp Muller, who's leading the research effort, told AFP that the fossil is possibly the second most complete fossil of a Herrerasauridae specimen to date.</p>

<p>The most complete was found in the same part of Brazil in 2014, leading to the identification of a new species with hooked claws, dubbed gnathovorax cabreirai.</p>

<p>The fossil will undergo several rounds of analysis before researchers can determine whether the specimen is a member of the same species.</p>

<p>"We have to be very careful with this work, it's very meticulous, almost surgical," Muller said, adding the process could take "several months."</p>

<p>"Every little part that we might damage will be a bit of information that we might not be able to recover."</p>

<p>Once the analysis is done, Muller's team will publish the results in a scientific journal.</p>

<h3><strong>Erosion acceleration&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The heavy rains that affected the pampas in May killed more than 180 people in Brazil and caused major damage to infrastructure.</p>

<p>The floods revealed the fossil much earlier by "accelerating erosion," a silver lining to researchers, who would not have discovered it until much later, according to Muller.</p>

<p>The downpour is not without its drawbacks, however, as heavy rainfall "also destroys a lot of the material" from the fossils, especially small fragments.</p>

<p>Paleontologists maintain a close watch on the fossil deposit as a result, especially any fragments that may be exposed, and focus their efforts during excavations to recover these fossils in the best possible condition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/utj8rq2_brazil-dinosaur-fossil_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fossil was first identified in May near the city of Sao Joao do Polesine]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-hulk-hogan-tears-off-shirt-in-support-of-donald-trump-at-republican-event-6138573]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hulk Hogan Tears Off Shirt In Support Of Donald Trump At Republican Event]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-hulk-hogan-tears-off-shirt-in-support-of-donald-trump-at-republican-event-6138573]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 11:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hulk Hogan delivered a high-energy speech and ripped his shirt to reveal a Trump/Vance Red Hulk Hogan T-shirt. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wrestling legend Hulk Hogan made a fiery appearance at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee on Thursday night, endorsing Donald Trump for president. Mr Hogan, dressed in a navy blue suit, red bandanna, and his signature blond handlebar moustache, delivered a high-energy speech and ripped his shirt to reveal a Trump/Vance Red Hulk Hogan T-shirt.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Watch the video here:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I've seen it all now ????<a href="https://twitter.com/HulkHogan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HulkHogan</a> <a href="https://t.co/vy6ei4tAMO">pic.twitter.com/vy6ei4tAMO</a></p>
— Russell Brand (@rustyrockets) <a href="https://twitter.com/rustyrockets/status/1814113542775415272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Hogan, whose real name is Terry G Bollea, proclaimed, "I've seen the greatest tag team of my life!" The crowd erupted in cheers as the WWE Hall of Famer proclaimed Trump his "hero" and called for "Trump-O-Mania" to "make America great again."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Hogan's antics were met with chants of "USA, USA" from the audience.</p>

<p>One user on X commented, "It feels like we are living in a giant movie right now."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It really feels like we are living in a giant movie right now.</p>
— Klay Thompson (@Thompsonklay) <a href="https://twitter.com/Thompsonklay/status/1814113674182726104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another stated, "Sometimes I wonder if America is even a real country or just one big TV show."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sometimes I wonder if America is even a real country or just one big tv show ????</p>
— Layah Heilpern (@LayahHeilpern) <a href="https://twitter.com/LayahHeilpern/status/1814120566678257703?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"This video is the highlight of my year. I won't lie. This is FKN epic. I loved the Hulkster since I was a baby," a comment read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This video is the highlight of my year I won't lie. This is FkN epic. I loved the Hulkster since I was a baby.</p>
— ♱ Vicar Øf Christ ♱Fire-Breathing♱Dragon-Master♱ (@Vicar0fChrist) <a href="https://twitter.com/Vicar0fChrist/status/1814117212778586206?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone else quipped, "This took the energy to another level!"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This took the energy to another level!</p>
— Tom Young (@brui4ns1) <a href="https://twitter.com/brui4ns1/status/1814113767623385502?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The Republican nominee appeared at the RNC just days after an attempt on his life at a Pennsylvania rally. On July 13, 20-year-old Thomas Crooks opened fire on the former US President. The bullet whizzed past Trump's ear.</p>

<p>The Secret Service quickly came to his rescue and pulled him down behind the dais before Trump rose and pumped his fist in the air, shouting "fight! fight! fight!". Agents rushed to his side and escorted him to safety.</p>

<p>Undeterred by the close shave, Trump attended the convention and even announced his running mate, JD Vance, earlier this week. The pair are set to lock horns with Democratic nominee Joe Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris in the November 5 presidential elections.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/sk5i6cms_hulk-hogan_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-assassination-bid-felt-something-hit-me-really-really-hard-6138520]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I Wanted To": Trump On Why He Raised His Arm Seconds After Shooting]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-on-assassination-bid-felt-something-hit-me-really-really-hard-6138520]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 11:00:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump today addressed his first major public address since surviving an assassination attempt last week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>"I'm not supposed to be here tonight," Donald Trump said in his first speech since he was injured by a 20-year-old gunman at a rally in Pennsylvania on Saturday.</li>
	<li>He said he heard a "loud whizzing sound" and "felt something hit me really, really hard on my right ear". "I said to myself, 'Wow, what was that? It can only be a bullet,'" he said.</li>
	<li>Trump said he moved his hand to his ear and brought it down, and it "was covered with blood, just absolutely blood all over the place. I immediately knew it was very serious, that we were under attack."</li>
	<li>He also recalled how Secret Service agents rushed to the stage as bullets flew, pouncing on top of him to keep him safe.</li>
	<li>"The amazing thing is that prior to the shot, if I had not moved my head at that very last instant, the assassin's bullet would have perfectly hit its mark, and I would not be here tonight. We would not be together," he said.</li>
	<li>He also praised his supporters at the rally, saying they turned to look for the sniper instead of breaking into a stampede. "They knew I was in trouble. They didn't want to leave me. And you can see that love written all over their faces. Incredible people," Trump said.</li>
	<li>"I wanted to do something to let him know I was okay. I raised my right arm, looked at the thousands and thousands of people that were breathlessly waiting, and started shouting, 'Fight, fight, fight!," he said.</li>
	<li>"For the rest of my life, I will be grateful for the love shown by that giant audience of patriots that stood bravely on that fateful evening," he said.</li>
	<li>Trump insisted he would never recount the moment when he nearly lost his life again.</li>
	<li>"So many people have asked me, 'What happened? Tell us what happened, please," he said. But "you'll never hear it from me a second time, because it's actually too painful to tell."</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ojr3nf2_donald-trump_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump at the Republican National Convention]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-planet-on-edge-of-world-war-iii-will-end-all-international-crises-donald-trump-6138462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will End Every International Crisis": Trump Vows To End Wars If He Wins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-planet-on-edge-of-world-war-iii-will-end-all-international-crises-donald-trump-6138462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:56:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump, 78, began his keynote address at the 2024 GOP convention by describing how he narrowly survived an attempt on his life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump, who survived an assassination attempt last weekend, said that our planet is on the "edge of World War III." He then claimed he could end "every single international crisis," including the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict and Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p>At the Republican National Convention (RNC) 2024, which came to a close on Thursday night, Trump formally accepted the party's nomination.</p>

<p>"Our planet is teetering on the edge of World War III... this will be a war like no other," Trump said while addressing his supporters at the event.</p>

<p>"I will end every single international crisis that the current administration has created - including the horrible war with Russia and Ukraine, which would have never happened if I was president, and the war caused by the attack on Israel, which never would have happened if I were president," he added.</p>

<p>He also said he wanted Americans held abroad to be released -- or else.</p>

<p>"The entire world, I tell you this: we want our hostages back and they better be back before I assume office or you will be paying a very big price," said Trump -- again failing to give any specifics.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old started his keynote address at the 2024 GOP convention, describing how he narrowly survived an attempt on his life, noting he could only be there "by the grace of Almighty God."</p>

<p>He asserted that this was the only time he would recount the July 13 incident because it was too painful to recall.</p>

<p>Remembering the incident, he explained that he heard a "loud whizzing sound and felt something hit me really, really hard on my right ear".</p>

<p>"I said to myself, 'Wow, what was that? It can only be a bullet'," he added.</p>

<p>While Trump was speaking, a few photographs of the former president from the July 13 incident were displayed on screens behind him.</p>

<p>During his speech, he even lauded the Secret Service agents, who rushed to his side, and then paid tribute to the volunteer firefighter, Corey Comperatore, who was killed, reports said.</p>

<p>Trump also stressed that he was "running to be president for all of America, not half of America because there is no victory in winning for half of America".</p>

<p>The assassination attempt on Trump came just months ahead of the high-on-stakes US presidential elections slated for November 5, 2024.</p>

<p>The Democratic National Convention is expected to take place next month in Chicago, with US President Joe Biden, who tested positive for COVID-19 a few days ago, still the frontrunner to retain the nomination.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lvc49kcg_donald-trump-_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was speaking at the Republican National Convention]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-environmental-activist-sentenced-to-five-years-in-jail-for-blocking-highway-6138437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Activist Sentenced To Five Years In Jail For Blocking Highway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/british-environmental-activist-sentenced-to-five-years-in-jail-for-blocking-highway-6138437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:50:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The protest caused significant traffic delays and accidents, with costs exceeding 1.8 million pounds.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five environmental activists-including Roger Hallam and Daniel Shaw-have been convicted for their roles in the November 2022 M25 motorway disruption, according to <em>the BBC</em>. The protest, coordinated by Just Stop Oil, was intended to block the road and resulted in major traffic jams, accidents, and delays that lasted for almost four days. The financial costs of the event were estimated to be over 1.8 million pounds (Rs 19,47,28,935).</p>

<p>Hallam was sentenced to five years in prison, the other three to four years each. The protestors' "intricate planning and the level of sophistication involved" on climate change activism were highlighted by the court. With regard to the new rules intended to quell disruptive protests, this is the longest punishment.</p>

<p>As per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c880xjx54mpo"><em>news outlet</em></a>, in the M25 protest case, Whittaker De Abreu and Gethin were arrested near the motorway dressed for climbing, while Lancaster rented a safe house and bought climbing gear for the activists.</p>

<p>Lancaster defended her actions as necessary due to the perceived failure of democratic methods, calling the climate crisis a critical issue.</p>

<p>Gethin stated the disruption was intended to be minimal and blamed those in power for failing to address climate change seriously. Hallam, who had previously rejected direct action for conventional campaigning, was disruptive in court, leading to three arrests and encouraging supporters to protest outside the court.</p>

<p>This resulted in the arrest of 11 protesters for contempt, but charges were later dropped. Hallam claimed the judiciary was corrupt and manipulated, framing his actions as necessary for climate justice.</p>

<p>The new law under which the activists were sentenced, introduced in 2022, criminalises direct action causing serious public harm. The judge emphasised the law's intent to treat such actions severely, with sentences up to 10 years.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nbd3tq6_m25-uk_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court highlighted the "intricate planning" involved in the protest action.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/aerial-explosion-near-us-embassy-in-tel-aviv-kills-1-injures-2-6138414]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Aerial Explosion" Near US Embassy In Tel Aviv Kills 1, Injures 2]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/aerial-explosion-near-us-embassy-in-tel-aviv-kills-1-injures-2-6138414]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:47:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An explosion in Tel Aviv early Friday left one person dead, an Israeli emergency services spokesperson told AFP, with the army saying a falling "aerial target" caused the blast.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An explosion in Tel Aviv early Friday left one person dead, an Israeli emergency services spokesperson told AFP, with the army saying a falling "aerial target" caused the blast.</p>

<p>Emergency services said the explosion took place around 03:15 am (0015 GMT) in a building in the centre of the city. Two people were lightly injured, Zaki Heller of the Magen David Adom medical service said.</p>

<p>An earlier police report had said seven people were injured, but they were mainly in a state of shock, Heller added.</p>

<p>The army said an initial inquiry showed that the explosion was "caused by the falling of an aerial target".</p>

<p>"No sirens were activated," it said in a statement, adding that the air force had "increased its air patrols in order to protect Israeli airspace".</p>

<p>A resident of central Tel Aviv told AFP he had been woken by a loud explosion.</p>

<p>"Everything shook," he said.</p>

<p>Police found a body bearing injuries caused by shrapnel in the building, which is located on the corner of Ben-Yehuda Avenue and Shalom-Aleichem Street, not far from an annexe of the US Embassy in Israel, spokesperson Dean Elsdunne said.</p>

<p>"It may have been an aerial explosion... We were very lucky," said Peretz Amar, a Tel Aviv police commander at the scene, adding an investigation was "ongoing".</p>

<p>"The police, along with emergency and rescue forces, discovered a man in his 50s in a nearby building who was found dead in his apartment, with shrapnel wounds on his body," a police statement said.</p>

<p>Another 10 people with minor injuries were taken for medical treatment, it said.</p>

<p>Police and bomb disposal units were deployed to the scene and conducted searches for suspicious objects and additional threats, the statement added.</p>

<p>Residents were urged to "respect safety instructions and not to approach or touch debris or shrapnel that may contain explosives", it said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/d1pf0gp8_tel-aviv-blast-reuters-_625x300_19_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police found a body bearing injuries caused by shrapnel in a building.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/took-him-out-with-one-shot-trump-lauds-sniper-who-killed-thomas-crooks-6138349]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Praises Secret Service Agent Who Took Shooter Out With "One Shot"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/took-him-out-with-one-shot-trump-lauds-sniper-who-killed-thomas-crooks-6138349]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:36:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This statement came during the 78-year-old's speech at the Republican National Convention, his first public appearance since the assassination attempt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump has publicly appreciated the Secret Service agent who killed Thomas Crooks, the 20-year-old man behind the assassination attempt on the former US President at a rally in Pennsylvania. Trump praised the agent, stating the sniper "took him out with one shot."</p>

<p>His word of appreciation came during the 78-year-old's <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/politics/live-news/rnc-republican-national-convention-07-18-24/index.html">speech at the Republican National Convention</a> on Thursday night, his first public appearance since the assassination attempt. In the speech, Trump vowed to deliver "the four greatest years in the history of our country" and called for unity, stating "I'm running to be president for all of America." Trump also shared details about the recent attempt on his life, saying he was grateful for the "outpouring of love and support" from Americans.</p>

<p>The Republican nominee was shot at on July 13 by Thomas Crooks, who allegedly used a ladder to climb a nearby building before targeting Trump with an AR-style rifle from approximately 130 yards away. The attack occurred at 6:12 pm, resulting in chaos. Trump's ear was nicked, one rally attendee was killed, and two others were injured. The Secret Service immediately reacted, shooting and killing Crooks within 26 seconds.</p>

<p>In an <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-explains-why-he-asked-about-his-shoes-amid-shooting-chaos-6117844">earlier interview</a>, Donald Trump revealed that a slight turn of his head to read a chart likely saved him from the fatal bullet wound fired by Crooks, which just grazed his ear.</p>

<p>Trump vividly described the following moments, during which Secret Service agents sprang into action, yelling "Get down" and tackling him to the ground with force. He showed off a bruise on his arm he got when the agents grabbed him.</p>

<p>The Republican nominee was rushed to the hospital, where medical professionals told him that he was "supposed to be dead." The doctor described his survival as a "miracle," stating that he had never seen anyone survive an AR-15 rifle wound.</p>

<p>Trump praised the Secret Service for quickly taking down the shooter, describing his actions as "fantastic". He even pointed to his nose, indicating where the agents hit the shooter.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/eutnrp9_us-secret-service-in-trump-assassination-bid-afp_625x300_17_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>