<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:29:47 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-to-travel-to-pak-last-foreign-minister-visit-was-in-2015-6715527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar To Travel To Pak, Last Foreign Minister Visit Was In 2015]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-to-travel-to-pak-last-foreign-minister-visit-was-in-2015-6715527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:16:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Friday announced that External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will travel to Pakistan to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) in mid-October.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Friday announced that External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar will travel to Pakistan to attend a conclave of the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) in mid-October.</p>

<p>The announcement was made by external affairs ministry spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal.</p>

<p>The last Indian external affairs minister to visit Pakistan was Sushma Swaraj. She had travelled to Islamabad in December 2015 to attend a conference on Afghanistan.</p>

<p>Pakistan is hosting the SCO Council of Heads of Government (CHG) meeting on October 15 and 16.</p>

<p>"The external affairs minister will lead our delegation to Pakistan to participate in the SCO summit which will be held in Islamabad on October 15 and 16," Mr Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing.</p>

<p>The spokesperson clarified that the external affairs minister is travelling to Pakistan only to attend the SCO summit.</p>

<p>In August, Pakistan invited Prime Minister Narendra Modi to the SCO's summit.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's visit to Pakistan assumes significance as it is seen as a major decision on New Delhi's part.</p>

<p>The decision to send the senior minister is seen as a display of India's commitment to the SCO which has been playing a key role in boosting regional security cooperation.</p>

<p>The ties between India and Pakistan came under severe strain after India's warplanes pounded a Jaish-e-Mohammed terrorist training camp in Balakot in Pakistan in February 2019 in response to the Pulwama terror attack.</p>

<p>The relations further deteriorated after India on August 5, 2019 announced the withdrawal of special powers of Jammu and Kashmir and the bifurcation of the state into two union territories.</p>

<p>India has been maintaining that it desires normal neighbourly relations with Pakistan while insisting that the onus is on Islamabad to create an environment free of terror and hostility for such engagement.</p>

<p>The SCO council of heads of government conclave is the second-highest platform in the grouping.</p>

<p>The SCO heads of state summit is the top most forum in the grouping that is generally attended by the Indian prime minister.</p>

<p>The SCO, comprising India, China, Russia, Pakistan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan, is an influential economic and security bloc that has emerged as one of the largest transregional international organisations.</p>

<p>India was the chair of the SCO last year. It hosted the SCO summit in the virtual format in July last year.</p>

<p>India's association with the SCO began in 2005 as an observer country. It became a full member state of SCO at the Astana summit in 2017.</p>

<p>India has shown a keen interest in deepening its security-related cooperation with the SCO and its Regional Anti-Terrorism Structure (RATS), which specifically deals with issues relating to security and defence.</p>

<p>The SCO was founded at a summit in Shanghai in 2001 by the presidents of Russia, China, the Kyrgyz Republic, Kazakhstan, Tajikistan and Uzbekistan.</p>

<p>Pakistan became its permanent member along with India in 2017.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jvjnd69o_dr-s-jaishankar_625x300_17_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar will lead the Indian delegation to Pakistan. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-allies-in-the-region-would-keep-fighting-israel-irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-6715520]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Our Allies In The Region Would Keep Fighting Israel: Iran's Supreme Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/our-allies-in-the-region-would-keep-fighting-israel-irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-6715520]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:14:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader vowed in a rare address on Friday that his allies around the region would keep fighting Israel, as he defended his country's missile strike on its arch-foe.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's supreme leader vowed in a rare address on Friday that his allies around the region would keep fighting Israel, as he defended his country's missile strike on its arch-foe.</p>

<p>Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's address in Tehran was the first since Iran launched its second-ever attack on Israel, and also the first since exchanges of fire pitting Hezbollah fighters against Israeli troops escalated into full-blown war in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Nearly a year after the Palestinian militant group Hamas launched the deadliest attack on Israel in its history on October 7, Israel announced it was shifting its focus to securing its border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Israel says its objective is to allow 60,000 Israelis displaced by a year of cross-border rocket attacks launched by Hezbollah to return to their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's attacks on Hezbollah strongholds around Lebanon have killed more than 1,000 people since September 23, according to the Lebanese health ministry, and forced hundreds of thousands more to flee their homes in a country already mired in economic crisis.</p>

<p>They have also killed an Iranian general, a host of Hezbollah commanders and, in their biggest blow to the group in decades, assassinated its leader, Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Speaking to a crowd of thousands in Farsi-speaking Iran, he said in Arabic: "The resistance in the region will not back down with these martyrdoms, and will win."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The address comes as Israel weighs retaliation for Hezbollah backer Iran's missile attack which Tehran said was revenge for the killing of Nasrallah and other top figures.</p>

<p>Khamenei praised Hezbollah, saying that it was providing "a vital service to the entire region and the entire Islamic world".</p>

<p>The escalation has left people in Lebanon fearful that there will be no swift end to the violence engulfing their country.</p>

<p>In Beirut, 35-year-old displaced nurse Fatima Salah said people were "scared for our children, and this war is going to be long".</p>

<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant warned that "those who attack the state of Israel, pay a heavy price".</p>

<p>Iran said it would step up its response if Israel counterattacked.</p>

<p>Israel intercepted most of the 200 missiles launched by Iran, though the attack has sparked fear in Israel of more violence to come. In the West Bank, a Palestinian was killed by shrapnel.</p>

<p>Rony Eli-Ya, 37, an Israeli on a pilgrimage to Ukraine's Uman, said it was "a miracle, not a single rocket killed a single Jew" in the attack.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden said the United States was "discussing" possible Israeli strikes on Iranian oil facilities.</p>

<p><strong>- Border crossing closed -</strong></p>

<p>Lebanon said an Israeli strike on Friday cut off the main international road to Syria after Israel said Hezbollah was transporting weapons through the tiny Mediterranean country's principal land border crossing.</p>

<p>The strike comes after 310,000 people, mostly Syrians, have in recent days fled the war pitting Israel against Hezbollah in Lebanon for relative safety in neighbouring Syria.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its fighter jets struck Hezbollah targets near the border crossing overnight.</p>

<p>It said they included a 3.5 kilometre (two-mile) long tunnel that "enables the transfer and storage of large quantities of weapons underground".</p>

<p>The border with Syria is the only land route out of Lebanon and the strike could leave thousands who are unable to fly out trapped.</p>

<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi meanwhile landed in Beirut for talks with Lebanese officials, Lebanon's official National News Agency reported.</p>

<p>He arrived after an intense night of bombardment of Hezbollah's main bastion in the southern suburbs, with the US and an Israeli news website saying Israel targeted the militant group's potential successor just a week after it killed its Nasrallah.</p>

<p>The strikes destroyed at least five buildings and left a huge crater in the road, an AFP photographer said.</p>

<p>A target of one of Israel's recent Beirut strikes was Hashem Safieddine, a potential successor to Hezbollah chief Nasrallah, US news site Axios said, citing three Israeli officials it did not identify.</p>

<p>Israeli news website Ynet also reported Safieddine had been the target, while the Israeli military told AFP it was looking into the reports.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, a source close to Hezbollah said Nasrallah had been given a temporary burial in a secret location until a public funeral could be held.</p>

<p>Israel announced this week that its troops had started ground raids into parts of southern Lebanon, a stronghold of Hezbollah, after days of heavy bombardment of areas across the country where the group holds sway.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it shelled Israeli troops in a border area of south Lebanon Friday, in the latest such clash on the frontier.</p>

<p>The militant group also said it kept up its rocket fire, with sirens warning of incoming fire blaring in northern Israel Friday.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry said that 37 people were killed and 151 wounded by Israeli strikes over the previous 24 hours.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said nine of its soldiers have been killed in combat in Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>- Tulkarem strike -</strong></p>

<p>In the occupied West Bank, a source within the Palestinian security services told AFP that an air raid on the refugee camp of Tulkarem, which killed 18 people, was the deadliest in the territory since 2000.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its strike in the northern West Bank killed Hamas leader Zahi Yaser Abd al-Razeq Oufi, who it accused of participating in numerous attacks.</p>

<p>Calls for restraint have multiplied but months of similar calls to halt fighting in Gaza failed to bring a ceasefire.</p>

<p>Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The United Nations has described the figures as reliable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3h1k4qe_iran-supreme-leader_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran said it would step up its response if Israel counterattacked.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-must-convince-israel-irans-ambassador-to-ndtv-on-west-asia-crisis-6715420]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Must Convince Israel": Iran's Ambassador To NDTV On West Asia Crisis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-must-convince-israel-irans-ambassador-to-ndtv-on-west-asia-crisis-6715420]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 17:03:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the conflict in West Asia is poised to set off a series of dangerous escalations risking full-scale war between Iran and Israel, Iran's Ambassador to India Iraj Elahi today sought India's intevention to help bring stability to the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the conflict in West Asia is poised to set off a series of dangerous escalations risking full-scale war between Iran and Israel, Iran's Ambassador to India Iraj Elahi today sought India's intevention to help bring stability to the region.</p>

<p>"India must take this oportunity to convince Israel to stop its aggression in the reigon and help bring peace and stability," the Ambassador said, speaking to NDTV.</p>

<p>India, which has friendly ties with both Iran and Israel, has been urging all parties involved in the West Asia crisis to de-escalate tensions and resolve issues through diplomacy and dialogue.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi had even spoken to Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu after Tel Aviv opened a new front to the sconflict with its northern neighbour Lebanon, where it is targeting Hezbollah.</p>

<p>In an exclusive interview to NDTV, the Iranian Ambassador also said that "If Israel stops, we will stop," adding that "Iran does not want war. We want to have peace in the region, but if our national security is hit, then it leaves us with no other option than to retaliate, and that is precisely what we did."</p>

<p>He went on to explain that Iran's ballistic missile attack was "retaliatory move" and was done in response to the "assassination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh on Iranian soil. He was our state guest and was assassinated by Israel in our country. That is a national security issue, and according to our Constitution, we have to deal with such an issue with a retaliatory response."</p>

<p>The Ambassador also clarified that the missile attack was not for the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah. "The issue is getting mixed up here. Our retaliation to Israel was only for the killing of Ismail Haniyeh, not for the Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah. Hezbollah can take care of itself," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0h6ijblg_iran-ambassador-iraj-elahi-ndtv-intw_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's Ambassador Iraj Elahi sought India's intevention to help bring stability to the region.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/maldives-president-mohamed-muizzus-1st-bilateral-visit-to-india-from-sunday-6715087]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maldives President's 1st Bilateral Visit To India From Sunday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/maldives-president-mohamed-muizzus-1st-bilateral-visit-to-india-from-sunday-6715087]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:23:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu will be visiting India from October 6 to 10, the foreign ministry said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu will be visiting India from October 6 to 10, the foreign ministry said today. This will be his first bilateral visit to India. He had earlier travelled to India in June this year for the swearing-in ceremony of Prime Minister Narendra Modi and his council of ministers.</p>

<p>Mr Muizzu will meet President Droupadi Murmu and hold discussions with PM Modi on bilateral, regional, and international issues of mutual interest during his visit. He will also visit Mumbai and Bengaluru where he would be attending business events.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-meets-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-to-reset-bilateral-ties-6306626">Maldives is India's key maritime neighbour</a> in the Indian Ocean Region (IOR). The nation also found a special place in the Prime Minister's vision of 'SAGAR' (Security and Growth for All in the Region) and India's 'Neighbourhood First Policy'.</p>

<p>"The visit of President Mohamed Muizzu to India after the recent visit of the External Affairs Minister )S Jaishankar) to the Maldives is testimony to the importance that India attaches to its relations with the Maldives and is expected to lend further momentum to cooperation and robust people to people ties between the two countries," the Minister of External Affairs said in a statement.</p>

<p>S Jaishankar visited the Maldives in August - first high-level trip from New Delhi after the island nation's pro-China president, Muizzu, assumed office in November last year.</p>

<p>During his visit, he met the Maldives President and other top leaders and assured them that New Delhi attached top priority to its multifaceted relationship with Male and was determined to further its developmental cooperation with the country.</p>

<p>India's relationship with the Maldives was hurt after Muizzu, known for his pro-China leanings, took charge as the President late last year.</p>

<p>Within hours of his oath, he demanded India replace the defence personnel it had stationed in the Maldives with civilians.</p>

<p>He, however, visited India to attend PM Modi's oath-taking ceremony and recently reaffirmed his administration's full commitment to strengthening the historic and close connections between the Maldives and India.</p>

<p>He said that India has always been one of the closest allies and invaluable partners, facilitating and providing aid whenever Maldives has needed it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/fn3c9kgo_maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-ani_625x300_06_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mohamed Muizzu will also visit Mumbai and Bengaluru during his India visit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-decides-to-remove-taliban-from-terrorist-groups-list-report-6714937]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Decides To Remove Taliban From Terrorist Groups List: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-decides-to-remove-taliban-from-terrorist-groups-list-report-6714937]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 16:02:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's Foreign Ministry said on Friday that a decision to remove the Taliban from a list of terrorist organisations had been "taken at the highest level", the state TASS news agency reported on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's Foreign Ministry said on Friday that a decision to remove the Taliban from a list of terrorist organisations had been "taken at the highest level", the state TASS news agency reported on Friday.</p>

<p>The decision needs to be followed up with various legal procedures in order to make it a reality, President Vladimir Putin's special representative on Afghanistan Zamir Kabulov was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>Putin said in July that Russia considers Afghanistan's Taliban movement an ally in the fight against terrorism.</p>

<p>Russia has been slowly building ties with the Taliban since it seized power in Afghanistan in August 2021 as U.S.-led forces withdrew after 20 years of war but the movement is still officially outlawed in Russia.</p>

<p>Moscow formally labelled the Taliban a terrorist organisation in 2003.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-09/775ol53o_taliban-generic-afp_625x300_08_September_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Moscow formally labelled the Taliban a terrorist organisation in 2003.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/irans-resistance-axis-who-and-what-will-fill-the-vacuum-now-6714540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Who - And What - Will Fill The Vacuum In Iran's Resistance Axis?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/irans-resistance-axis-who-and-what-will-fill-the-vacuum-now-6714540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 15:11:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[History is littered with examples of how non-state militant actors, driven by ideology, are easily able to bulldoze their way to power before regional or international consensus-led political alternatives even start materialising.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/er5aoa7g_iran_625x300_04_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah in Israeli airstrikes on the Dahieh suburb of Beirut, a predominantly Shia stronghold, was a tectonic event both for the group and the region. Nasrallah had been the leader of Hezbollah for over three decades. The outfit itself was designated as a terror group by the US and others in 1997, two years before even Al Qaeda was labelled as such. In response to his death, Iran has launched a ballistic missile attack against Israel, upping the ante.</p>

<h2><strong>Hezbollah's Worst Crisis, Ever</strong></h2>

<p>The crisis today for Hezbollah, founded in 1982 from the ashes of the Lebanese Civil War, is more existential in nature than ever before. Along with Nasrallah, a majority of the group's military and political hierarchy has also been eliminated. While Israel's offensives against Hezbollah's leadership are not new, the 2006 Israel-Lebanon war, where Israel failed to deliver a thumping defeat, was a focal moment in its strategic thinking. The 2008 assassination in Syria of the group's second in command and founder of the Lebanese Islamic Jihad Organisation, Imad Mughniyeh, was a turning point, one that ultimately culminated in Israeli operations inside Lebanon over the past two months, such as targeting communication lines used via old pagers and walkie-talkies.</p>

<p>Moving forward, reconstructing Hezbollah in a post-Nasrallah era will not be easy. Israel, with these strikes, followed by a real threat of a region-wide escalation, may have found ample time for itself to hope for a political alternative emerging from within Lebanon, a country where Hezbollah was a state within a state and challenged the normal functioning of politics. Lebanon has had no president since 2022. Along with Nasrallah, the killing of senior Hezbollah commanders, such as the southern front chief Ali Karaki and Iranian commander Abbas Nilforoushan, amongst others, also significantly disrupts the chain of command. The Iranian retaliation against Israel in the form of ballistic missiles was explicitly highlighted as a response to these assassinations.</p>

<h2><strong>Who Will Lead Hezbollah?</strong></h2>

<p>The next leader of the group is widely expected to be Hashem Safieddine, a senior member and cousin of Nasrallah. Safieddine, by some accounts, is more radical and less politically astute than his predecessor. Sporting a black turban, he believes that he is a direct descendant of Prophet Mohammed. Safieddine has very close ties with Iran and is known to be married to the daughter of slain Iranian commander Qasseim Soleimani.&nbsp;</p>

<p>If he becomes the Hezbollah chief, Safieddine will have to contend with a mammoth reality. The degradation of his group's leadership is sure to have a significant impact. To date, Al Qaeda is reeling from the loss of its leaders Osama Bin Laden and Ayman Al Zawahiri; reconstruction efforts seem to be slow, and for the moment, invisible. Hamas, too, since the assassination of Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran this July (also purportedly by Israel), has seen little activity at the top. Its new chief, Yahya Sinwar, has largely maintained radio silence. Even so, it's important to acknowledge that every such group or movement has unique character traits in terms of both survivability and ideology, and both these traits are interlinked. Al Qaeda was largely based on the cult of personality, Hezbollah isn't.</p>

<h2><strong>What The Arab World Would Want</strong></h2>

<p>The fate and future of Hezbollah will also depend on regional dynamics. Iran is not only a principal support pillar for the 'Axis of Resistance' built around the Palestine issue, but Hezbollah itself is also much more institutionally attached to Tehran's constructs. While Hamas is a Sunni movement, Hezbollah is a quintessential representation of Shia power and influence in the region, and hence is also much more critical towards Iranian thinking. While powers in the Arab world have tried to maintain a level of neutrality, pitching the ongoing fallout as an 'Iran-vs-Israel' crisis, the dissolution of both Hamas and Hezbollah would in all probability be a welcome step, specifically as much of the dirty work would land on Israeli shoulders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moving forward, the main question is who and what would replace the political vacuum left behind. History is littered with examples of how non-state militant actors, driven by ideology, are easily able to bulldoze their way to power before regional or international consensus-led political alternatives even start materialising.</p>

<h2><strong>Can Iran Cross The Nuclear Threshold?</strong></h2>

<p>Notably, Israel's kinetic pushback is not just a symptom of the audacity of an existential state. The biggest and yet the least talked about military operations that afforded Israel - especially after 2006 - the space to build capacities to take on Hezbollah, Hamas, and others, were its attempts to make sure that arch-foes in Iran and Syria would be unable to attain nuclear capabilities. The Israeli airstrike in 2007 decommissioned Syria's suspected nuclear programme in the Deir Ez-Zor region. Protracted and clandestine operations against Iran's nuclear programme have also inflicted on Tehran critical setbacks. It is considered a threshold nuclear state now, but if the current trajectory continues, it may even sprint towards weaponisation.</p>

<p>The next few months will continue to be unpredictable for West Asia, bringing it back to the core of international geopolitics, big power competition, nuclear brinkmanship and potential re-drawing of traditional influence architectures. After all, all these factors work in tandem.</p>

<p><em>(The author is&nbsp;Deputy Director and Fellow, Strategic Studies Programme, Observer Research Foundation)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mp60vmkg_iran_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-court-orders-elon-musks-x-to-pay-418-000-for-child-abuse-probe-6714366]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Court Orders Musk's X To Pay $418,000 Fine In Child Abuse Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-court-orders-elon-musks-x-to-pay-418-000-for-child-abuse-probe-6714366]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:45:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian court upheld an order on Friday for Elon Musk's X to pay a fine of A$610,500 ($418,000) for failing to cooperate with a regulator's request for information about anti-child-abuse practices.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian court upheld an order on Friday for Elon Musk's X to pay a fine of A$610,500 ($418,000) for failing to cooperate with a regulator's request for information about anti-child-abuse practices.</p>

<p>X had challenged the fine but the Federal Court of Australia ruled it was obliged to respond to a notice from the eSafety Commissioner, an internet safety regulator, seeking information about steps to address child sexual exploitation material on the platform.</p>

<p>Musk took X, then called Twitter, private in 2022. But the company had argued it was not bound to respond to the notice in early 2023 because it was folded into a new Musk-controlled corporate entity, removing liability.</p>

<p>"Had X Corp's argument been accepted by the Court it could have set the concerning precedent that a foreign company's merger with another foreign company might enable it to avoid regulatory obligations in Australia," eSafety Commissioner Julie Inman Grant said in a statement following the verdict.</p>

<p>eSafety has also started civil proceedings against X because of its non-compliance.</p>

<p>X did not immediately respond to a request for comment on Friday.</p>

<p>This is not the first conflict between Musk and the Australian internet safety regulator. The eSafety Commissioner earlier this year ordered X to remove posts showing a bishop in Australia being stabbed during a sermon.</p>

<p>X challenged the order in court on the grounds that a regulator in one country should not decide what internet users viewed around the world, and ultimately kept the posts up after the Australian regulator withdrew its case.</p>

<p>Musk said at the time the order was censorship and shared posts describing the order, which would have applied globally, as a plot by the World Economic Forum to impose eSafety rules on the world.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jhsp7d2_elon-musk_625x300_21_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is not the first conflict between Musk and the Australian internet safety regulator. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-hezbollah-not-terrorists-people-are-hezbollah-lebanons-envoy-to-ndtv-6714344]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hezbollah Not Terrorists, People Are Hezbollah": Lebanon's Envoy To NDTV]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-hezbollah-not-terrorists-people-are-hezbollah-lebanons-envoy-to-ndtv-6714344]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:42:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is the right of every nation which comes under occupation to resist the occupation, said Lebanon's Ambassador to India Rabie Narsh, speaking to NDTV about the ongoing and escalating conflict in West Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is the right of every nation which comes under occupation to resist the occupation, said Lebanon's Ambassador to India Rabie Narsh, speaking to NDTV about the ongoing and escalating conflict in West Asia.</p>

<p>"Lebanon's armed forces have not been pressed into action, because if we do that, then it officially becomes a war between two nations. It is currently the people who are resisting an occupation by Israel," the envoy said.</p>

<p>Explaining his remark, the Ambassador said, "Israel has been attacking us since its formation due to its policy of occupation and expansionism. Resistance groups like the Hezbollah and many others have always resisted this occupation."</p>

<p>Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon is widely considered a militant organisation by many countries in the West and even a terrorist organisation by some, including Israel and the United States. Members of the Hezbollah are part of the Parliament in Lebanon, but are not considered part of the government.</p>

<p>Speaking about "resistance group" Hezbollah, the Ambassador said clearly that Lebanon "does not consider Hezbollah a terrorist group. They are freedom fighters who are resisting an occupation. The are fighting for the freedom and liberty of the people of Lebanon, and their fight is against state terrorism being done by Israel, and against occupation. They are freedom fighters because they are fighting on their own land"</p>

<p>"As for the relationship between Hezbollah and the Lebanese government, it has always been there, and is a debatable issue," he said, adding that "When it comes to domestic issues, Hezbollah is a political party just like any other political party. They play by the same rules as every other political party."</p>

<h2><strong>ROCKETS FIRED AT ISRAEL</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has been targeted by Lebanon for the last 11 month, Tel Aviv has said. As recently as THursday, 230 rockets were fired by Hezbollah on to Israeli territory.</p>

<p>Responding to this, the Ambassador said, "It is not true that Hezbollah has been fighting Israel for the last 11 months. The fight has been on since the formation of Israel in 1947-48. The resistance to occupation has been on since then. The fight has been on since then. Even now Israel is encroaching Lebanese territory."</p>

<p>Pinning the blame on the international community, the envoy said, "It is expected of the international community to put a hold on this situation. Today, we are suffering because the international community has failed to stop Israel's war crimes."</p>

<p>Speaking about the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, the envoy said, "You can see the implications of assassinating him. You can see the fallout. The war is still on. Israel's strikes are even killing civilians in Lebanon. Hundreds of civilians have been killed so far. This is what terrorism really is. If what Israel is doing is not terrorism, then what is."</p>

<h3><strong>'THE PEOPLE ARE HEZBOLLAH'</strong></h3>

<p>Israel has been saying that Hezbollah militants have been taking shelter in civilian areas, residing and hiding in residential colonies and even hiding their weapons, arms and ammunition under civilian buildings.</p>

<p>The envoy however, rubbished these claims as "pure lies" by Israel. He said, "Israel's entire journey has been built up on lies. Their entire narrative is a lie, and these claims are lies," he said, adding that there has been a recent visit organised by Hezbollah for journalists, where they have shown that the areas targeted by Israel are pure civilian areas and no military installations were there."</p>

<p>He went on to say that, "As for Hezbollah members living there, well, the people are Hezbollah. Hezbollah is not an imaginary organisation. It is made of the people of Lebanon. Those who are resisting the occupation. So, yes, people are there. It may be Hezbollah or some other groups, but just because of that is it justified to kill their entire families and their children."</p>

<p>"As for the weapons, I do not know where they hide them," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>THE PRICE FOR THE HOLOCAUST</strong></h3>

<p>The Holocaust was the systematic state-sponsored killing of six million Jewish men, women, and children and several million others by Nazi Germany between 1941 and 1945 during World War-II.</p>

<p>Acknowledging the suffering of the Jewish people, the Ambassador said, "Of course, we do not deny that the Jewish people have suffered from the Holocaust and genocide, but on whose hand? Was it at the hands of the Arabs, or the Lebanese people? Or was it at the hands of the Europeans? So tell me, why should the people of Lebanon or Palestine pay the price for the crimes committed against Jews by another people."</p>

<h3><strong>THE TWO-STATE SOLUTION</strong></h3>

<p>Lebanon does not want war, the Ambassador told NDTV. "A military solution can not be achieved. We have sought for a political and a diplomatic solution. We have agreed that the only solution is a two-state solution. A state of Israel and a state for Palestine, each having defined territories and sovereign rights. But the only one who is opposed to this solution is Israel," he said.</p>

<p>Israel, he said, "seems to be above the international laws and the international community. It is always treated by the West as a spoilt child. This must end. Netanyahu's crazy campaign must stop, his criminal agendas should finish. So, yes, we can only move to peace when the UN resolution for a two-state policy is implemented and Palestine is given its due recognition as a country."</p>

<h3><strong>ANOTHER ISRAELI 'LIMITED INVASION' - HOW IS THIS DIFFERENT</strong></h3>

<p>Speaking about the "limited invasion" by Israel this time - as it has done in 1982 and 2006 - the Ambassador said, "It is the same, nothing&nbsp; will change. It is the mentality of war that Israel has always had."</p>

<p>He went on to say that "The entire foundation of Israel is based on a lie... and what makes it dangerous is that they justify their acts and agendas based on religious doctrines. 'The Promised Land', 'The Chosen People'. It is very dangerous when one builds their entire strategy on a twisted religious doctrine."</p>

<p>"Israel today occupies territories in Palestinian West Bank, they have occupied the Gaza strip, they have occupied Golan Heights in Syria and have also occupied lands in Lebanon. It is very clear who the aggressor is," the Ambassador said.</p>

<p>On Iran's ballistic missile attack on Israel, the envoy told NDTV that "What Iran does is up to them. How I see this is that Israel is left with no friends in the region. They are the aggressor. Be it Iran or Iraq or Yemen, or Lebanon - Israel has no good ties with anyone around it."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q645efp_lebanon-ambassador-rabie-narsh-ndtv-intw_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lebanon's Ambassador Rabie Narsh spoke to NDTV about Hezbollah and Israel's offensive against Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-turnout-as-khamenei-delivers-rare-friday-sermon-amid-israel-crisis-6714056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel Won't Last Long": Iran's Khamenei's First Public Sermon In 5 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massive-turnout-as-khamenei-delivers-rare-friday-sermon-amid-israel-crisis-6714056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 14:00:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said Israel "won't last long" as he backed the Palestinian and Lebanese movements against Israelin his rare Friday sermon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei said Israel "won't last long" as he backed the Palestinian and Lebanese movements against Israel&nbsp;in his rare Friday sermon. Addressing tens of thousands of supporters at a mosque in Tehran, Khamenei justified its missile strikes on Israel as a "public service".</p>

<p>A gun kept by his side, the Iran leader declared that Israel would not prevail against Hamas or Hezbollah as chants of "we are with you" from the crowd echoed in the vast mosque grounds.</p>

<p>Khamenei's first Friday sermon in five years marks a crucial show of defiance amid threats to the supreme leader's life. He remains a top target for Israel, which has vowed to retaliate after Tuesday's missile attacks.</p>

<p>In his speech, he also praised Hassan Nasrallah, the former chief of the Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah who was killed in an Israeli airstrike in Beirut last week.</p>

<p>"Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah is no longer with us, but his spirit and his path will continue to inspire us forever. He was the high-standing flag against the Zionist enemy. His martyrdom will further increase this influence. The loss of Nasrallah is not in vain. We must stand up against the enemy while strengthening our unwavering faith," Khamenei told the gathering.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-israel-might-strike-back-at-iran-6713700">Explained: How Israel Might Strike Back At Iran</a></p>

<p>Khamenei also called Hezbollah a "blessed tree" that grew steadily under the leadership of Nasrallah.</p>

<p>"It is the duty and responsibility of all Muslims to help the blooded people of Lebanon and to support Lebanon's jihad and the battle for al-Aqsa mosque," he declared.</p>

<p>Iran's supreme leader, who backs the Palestinian Hamas group, called their October 7 attacks on Israel the "correct move".</p>

<p>"No international law has the right to object and protest against the Lebanese and Palestinians for standing up for themselves against the occupation," he told the crowd.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who spoke after a prayer ceremony for Nasrallah, also called Israel a "tool" for the United States "to take control of all the lands and resources in the region."</p>

<p><b>Read |&nbsp;</b><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-iran-hamas-war-israel-targets-hassan-nasrallahs-likely-successor-hashem-safieddine-in-fresh-strikes-on-beirut-lebanon-6711918">Israeli Strikes Target Hezbollah Intel HQ, Nasrallah's Likely Successor</a></p>

<p>"There is no doubt that the Zionists and the Americans are dreaming - the Zionist entity will be uprooted from the ground, it has no roots, it is fake, unstable, and exists only because of American support," said Khamenei.</p>

<p>Khamenei, the supreme leader who holds the highest authority in Iran, had last delivered a Friday sermon five years ago. His sermon comes just three days after Iran launched 180 missiles targeting crucial infrastructure in Israel and three days before the first anniversary of the Israel-Gaza war.</p>

<p>The Iran leader had last led Friday prayers in January 2020 after a missile attack on a US army base in Iraq in response to the killing of top Revolutionary Guards commander Qasem Soleimani.</p>

<p>Iran supports both Hamas and Hezbollah, who are fighting Israel on its southern and northern fronts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6ti55sgo_khamenei_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's Ayatollah Ali Khamenei delivers his first public sermon in five years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/second-asteroid-impact-may-have-contributed-to-dinosaur-extinction-research-6713947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Reveal It Wasn't Just One Asteroid That Wiped Out Dinosaurs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/second-asteroid-impact-may-have-contributed-to-dinosaur-extinction-research-6713947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:44:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The massive asteroid that ended the dinosaurs 66 million years ago was not an isolated event, new research has revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The massive asteroid that ended the dinosaurs 66 million years ago was not an isolated event, new research has revealed. The study, published in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-024-01700-4#:~:text=The%203D%20data%20reveal%20more,both%20sides%20of%20the%20crater ">Nature</a>, detailed scans of an underwater crater off the coast of Guinea. It revealed that another large asteroid struck Earth around the same time, potentially contributing to the cataclysmic conditions that led to the dinosaurs' extinction.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scientists recently mapped the Nadir crater, spanning over 8 km in diameter, and revealed that it was created by an asteroid measuring 400 metres wide. This asteroid struck the planet at nearly 72,000 kmph&nbsp;between 65 million and 67 million years ago. While it was smaller than the asteroid linked to the mass extinction, it was still powerful enough to leave a significant mark on Earth.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“The new images paint a picture of the catastrophic event,” said Dr Uisdean Nicholson, a marine geologist at Heriot-Watt University in Edinburgh. He discovered the <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abn3096 ">Nadir crater in 2022</a>, but the impact details were unclear until now.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Using advanced 3D seismic imaging, researchers managed to explore the crater's rim and the geological features lying 300 metres beneath the ocean floor. Dr Nicholson called it “exquisite,” saying, “There are around 20 confirmed marine craters worldwide, and none of them has been captured in anything close to this level of detail.”</p>

<p>The findings suggest the impact triggered intense tremors that liquefied sediments beneath the sea bed, resulting in faults and landslides that left traces of damage visible for thousands of square miles beyond the crater's edge. Furthermore, the collision unleashed a massive tsunami, estimated to have exceeded 800 metres in height, which would have surged across the Atlantic Ocean.</p>

<p>Although the exact timing of this asteroid's impact remains uncertain, its discovery raises intriguing possibilities about a cluster of impacts occurring at the end of the Cretaceous period – 145 million years ago to 66 million years ago. The asteroid responsible for the extinction of the dinosaurs created a much larger crater – 160 km wide – at Chicxulub on the Yucatan Peninsula in Mexico.</p>

<p>Dr Nicholson said the “closest humans have come to seeing something like this is the 1908 Tunguska event”, when a 50-metre asteroid entered Earth's atmosphere and exploded in the skies above Siberia. He pointed out that the new 3D seismic data across the Nadir crater provides an unrivalled opportunity to test impact crater hypotheses and develop new models of crater formation in marine environments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7hfg98pg_asteroid-generic-_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Timing of this asteroid's impact remains uncertain, but new study shows it added to dinosaur extinction.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-approves-first-diagnostic-test-for-mpox-amid-rising-outbreaks-in-africa-6713877]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Approves First Diagnostic Test For Mpox Amid Rising Outbreaks In Africa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-approves-first-diagnostic-test-for-mpox-amid-rising-outbreaks-in-africa-6713877]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:32:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UN health agency said on Friday that it had approved the use of the first diagnostic test for mpox, a key tool in countries battling outbreaks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UN health agency said on Friday that it had approved the use of the first diagnostic test for mpox, a key tool in countries battling outbreaks.</p>

<p>More than 800 people have died across Africa from mpox, where the disease has been officially detected in 16 countries, according to the African Union's disease control centre.</p>

<p>"The approval for emergency use" of the test "will be pivotal in expanding diagnostic capacity in countries facing mpox outbreaks, where the need for quick and accurate testing has risen sharply", the World Health Organization said in a statement.</p>

<p>The test, called the Alinity m MPXV assay and manufactured by Abbott Molecular Inc., enables the detection of the mpox virus from swabs taken from human lesions.</p>

<p>"By detecting DNA from pustular or vesicular rash samples, laboratory and health workers can confirm suspected mpox cases efficiently and effectively", the WHO said.</p>

<p>"Limited testing capacity and delays in confirming mpox cases persist in Africa, contributing to the continued spread of the virus", it said.</p>

<p>The approval of the test "represents a significant milestone in expanding testing availability in affected countries," the statement quoted Yukiko Nakatani, an assistant director-general of WHO, as saying.</p>

<p>"Increasing access to quality-assured medical products is central to our efforts in assisting countries to contain the spread of the virus and protect their people, especially in underserved regions", Nakatani said.</p>

<p>Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.</p>

<p>It causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions, and can be deadly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1n5d9p5_mpox-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 800 people have died across Africa from Mpox. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-us-election-broken-down-by-numbers-6713752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris vs Donald Trump: US Election Broken Down By Numbers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-us-election-broken-down-by-numbers-6713752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:17:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: here is the US election, broken down by numbers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swing states, electoral college votes, candidates up and down the ballot, and millions of potential voters: here is the US election, broken down by numbers.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Two&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Several independents ran -- and at least one, Robert F. Kennedy Jr, stumbled into a number of eyebrow-raising headlines.</p>

<p>But in the end, the presidential race comes down to a binary choice, with the two candidates from the major parties -- Democrat Kamala Harris and Republican Donald Trump -- seeking to lead a polarized America.</p>

<h3><strong>Five&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>November 5 -- Election Day, traditionally held on the Tuesday following the first Monday in November.</p>

<h3><strong>Seven&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The number of swing states -- states which don't clearly favour one party over the other, meaning they are up for grabs.</p>

<p>Harris and Trump are courting voters in Arizona, Georgia, Michigan, Nevada, North Carolina, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin, concentrating their campaign efforts there in an effort to ensure victory.</p>

<p>In a razor-tight election, just a handful of votes in any of those states could decide the outcome.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>34 and 435&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Voters won't just decide the White House occupant on Election Day -- they will also hit refresh on the US Congress.</p>

<p>Thirty-four Senate seats and all 435 spots in the House of Representatives are up for grabs.</p>

<p>In the House, members serve a two-year term. Republicans currently have the majority, and Harris's Democrats will be hoping for a turnaround.</p>

<p>In the Senate, 34 seats out of 100 are available, for a six-year term. Republicans are hoping to overturn the narrow Democratic majority.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>538</strong></h3>

<p>Welcome to the Electoral College, the indirect system of universal suffrage that governs presidential elections in the United States.</p>

<p>Each state has a different number of electors -- calculated by adding the number of their elected representatives in the House, which varies according to population, to the number of senators (two per state).</p>

<p>Rural Vermont, for example, has just three electoral votes. Giant California, meanwhile, has 54.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are 538 electors in total scattered across the 50 states and the District of Columbia. To take the White House, a candidate must win 270 votes.</p>

<h3><strong>774,000&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The number of poll workers who volunteered to make sure the 2020 election ran smoothly, according to the Pew Research Center.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are three types of election staff in the United States.</p>

<p>Poll workers -- recruited to do things like greet voters, help with languages, set up voting equipment, and verify voter IDs and registrations -- account for the majority of them.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Election officials are elected, hired or appointed to carry out more specialized duties such as training poll workers, according to Pew.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Poll watchers are usually appointed by political parties to observe the ballot count -- expected to be particularly contentious this year, thanks to Trump's refusal to agree to unconditionally accept the result.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Many election workers have already spoken to AFP about the pressure and threats they are receiving ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<h3><strong>244 million&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The number of Americans who will be eligible to vote in 2024, according to the Bipartisan Policy Center.&nbsp;</p>

<p>How many of those will actually cast their ballot remains to be seen, of course. But the Pew Research Center says that the midterm elections of 2018 and 2022, and the presidential vote of 2020, produced three of the highest turnouts of their kind seen in the United States in decades.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"About two-thirds (66%) of the voting-eligible population turned out for the 2020 presidential election - the highest rate for any national election since 1900," Pew says on its website.</p>

<p>That translated to nearly 155 million voters, according to the Census Bureau.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The presidential race comes down to a binary choice for US Polls: Kamala Harris vs Donald Trump. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-israel-might-strike-back-at-iran-6713700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How Israel Might Strike Back At Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-israel-might-strike-back-at-iran-6713700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 13:07:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has sworn it will retaliate for Iran's missile barrage on Tuesday, which involved more than 180 ballistic missiles and was largely thwarted by Israel's air defense systems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has sworn it will retaliate for Iran's missile barrage on Tuesday, which involved more than 180 ballistic missiles and was largely thwarted by Israel's air defense systems. Below are some ways Israel, backed by the United States, could strike back.</p>

<p><strong>Go After Iran's Military Installations</strong></p>

<p>Some analysts believe Israel is most likely to respond by targeting Iranian military installations, especially those that produce ballistic missiles like the ones used in Tuesday's attacks. It could also take out Iranian air defense systems and missile-launching facilities.</p>

<p>Washington has accused Tehran of supplying short-range ballistic missiles to Russia for use against Ukraine. Both countries deny that allegation.</p>

<p>Analysts said that would be seen as the most in-kind response to Iran's attack.</p>

<p><strong>Attack Iran's Nuclear Facilities</strong></p>

<p>Strikes against Iran's nuclear facilities could delay Tehran's ability to produce a nuclear weapon. Iran's nuclear program is spread over many locations, only some of which are built underground.</p>

<p>However, a major attack on its nuclear infrastructure would likely provoke serious consequences, potentially including a sprint by Iran to build a nuclear weapon. Washington has said it would not support such an action by Israel.</p>

<p>Richard Hooker, a retired US Army officer who served in the US National Security Council under Republican and Democratic presidents, said it was a "distinct possibility" that Israel could strike Iran's nuclear facilities but not a probability "because when you do something like that you put the Iranian leadership in a position to do something pretty dramatic in response."</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic denies ever having had a nuclear weapons program or planning to have one.</p>

<p>The UN nuclear watchdog, the IAEA, and the US intelligence community concluded that Iran pursued a coordinated nuclear weapons program until 2003, and experts say that with the collapse of the 2015 nuclear deal, it could produce enough weapons-grade uranium for a bomb in a matter of weeks.</p>

<p><strong>Attack Iran's Petroleum Production Infrastructure</strong></p>

<p>Israel could also hit Iran's petroleum industry, which would hurt its economy. Such an attack could provoke Iran in turn to strike oil production facilities in Saudi Arabia and other Gulf Arab states. That could send the price of fuel, always a major US campaign issue, soaring before Americans pick a new president and Congress in the November 5 elections.</p>

<p>"I'm not sure that (a hike in world oil prices) would restrain the Israelis," said David Des Roches, a former Department of Defense official involved in Gulf policy now with the US National Defense University's Near East-South Asia Centre. Israel, he added, might view a hike in world oil prices as a benefit for former President Donald Trump's re-election campaign.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu recently has been more aligned with Trump's Republicans than with Democrats.</p>

<p><strong>Economic, Cyber Options</strong></p>

<p>A military response is considered the most likely, but there are options that do not involve missile strikes or commando raids.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden has said he would impose more sanctions on Iran. Washington's sanctions on Iran already ban nearly all US trade with the country, block its government's assets in the US and prohibit US foreign assistance and arms sales.</p>

<p>Analysts said Israel could also use its cyber warfare abilities to respond to the Iranian strikes.</p>

<p>Israel's recent mass pager attack against Hezbollah in Lebanon turned the spotlight on its secretive Unit 8200, the Israel Defense Forces' specialist cyber warfare and intelligence unit, which Western security sources said was involved in planning the operation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f82nfiv_israels-iron-dome-antimissile-system-intercepts-rockets-reuters_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel could target Iranian air defense systems and missile-launching facilities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-the-implications-of-irans-military-barrage-on-israel-6713596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Implications of Iran's Military Barrage On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-the-implications-of-irans-military-barrage-on-israel-6713596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:51:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has sworn it will retaliate for Iran's missile barrage on Tuesday, which involved more than 180 ballistic missiles and was largely thwarted by Israel's air defense systems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has sworn it will retaliate for Iran's missile barrage on Tuesday, which involved more than 180 ballistic missiles and was largely thwarted by Israel's air defence systems.</p>

<p>Below are some ways Israel, backed by the United States, could strike back.</p>

<h3><strong>GO AFTER IRAN'S MILITARY INSTALLATIONS</strong></h3>

<p>Some analysts believe Israel is most likely to respond by targeting Iranian military installations, especially those that produce ballistic missiles like the ones used in Tuesday's attacks. It could also take out Iranian air defence systems and missile-launching facilities.</p>

<p>Washington has accused Tehran of supplying short-range ballistic missiles to Russia for use against Ukraine. Both countries deny that allegation.</p>

<p>Analysts said that would be seen as the most in-kind response to Iran's attack.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>ATTACK IRAN'S NUCLEAR FACILITIES</strong></h3>

<p>Strikes against Iran's nuclear facilities could delay Tehran's ability to produce a nuclear weapon. Iran's nuclear program is spread over many locations, only some of which are built underground.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, a major attack on its nuclear infrastructure would likely provoke serious consequences, potentially including a sprint by Iran to build a nuclear weapon. Washington has said it would not support such an action by Israel.</p>

<p>Richard Hooker, a retired US Army officer who served in the US National Security Council under Republican and Democratic presidents, said it was a "distinct possibility" that Israel could strike Iran's nuclear facilities but not a probability "because when you do something like that you put the Iranian leadership in a position to do something pretty dramatic in response."</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic denies ever having had a nuclear weapons program or planning to have one.</p>

<p>The UN nuclear watchdog, the IAEA, and the US intelligence community concluded that Iran pursued a coordinated nuclear weapons program until 2003, and experts say that with the collapse of the 2015 nuclear deal, it could produce enough weapons-grade uranium for a bomb in a matter of weeks. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>ATTACK IRAN'S PETROLEUM PRODUCTION INFRASTRUCTURE</strong></h3>

<p>Israel could also hit Iran's petroleum industry, which would hurt its economy. Such an attack could provoke Iran in turn to strike oil production facilities in Saudi Arabia and other Gulf Arab states. That could send the price of fuel, always a major US campaign issue, soaring before Americans pick a new president and Congress in the Nov. 5 elections.</p>

<p>"I'm not sure that (a hike in world oil prices) would restrain the Israelis," said David Des Roches, a former Department of Defense official involved in Gulf policy now with the US National Defense University's Near East-South Asia Center. Israel, he added, might view a hike in world oil prices as a benefit for former President Donald Trump's re-election campaign.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu recently has been more aligned with Trump's Republicans than with Democrats.</p>

<h3><strong>ECONOMIC, CYBER OPTIONS</strong></h3>

<p>A military response is considered the most likely, but there are options that do not involve missile strikes or commando raids.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden has said he would impose more sanctions on Iran. Washington's sanctions on Iran already ban nearly all US trade with the country, block its government's assets in the US and prohibit US. foreign assistance and arms sales.</p>

<p>Analysts said Israel could also use its cyber warfare abilities to respond to the Iranian strikes.</p>

<p>Israel's recent mass pager attack against Hezbollah in Lebanon turned the spotlight on its secretive Unit 8200, the Israel Defense Forces' specialist cyber warfare and intelligence unit, which Western security sources said was involved in planning the operation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/phn98hb8_israel-iran-conflict-generic-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Strikes against Iran's nuclear facilities could delay Tehran's ability to produce a nuclear weapon (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bibi-bugged-my-bathroom-boris-johnsons-big-claim-against-benjamin-netanyahu-6713494]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Bibi Bugged My Bathroom": Boris Johnson's Big Claim Against Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bibi-bugged-my-bathroom-boris-johnsons-big-claim-against-benjamin-netanyahu-6713494]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:40:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson claimed that a listening device was found in his bathroom after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu used the facility during their meeting in 2017.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson has claimed that a listening device was found in his bathroom after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu used the facility during their meeting in 2017, The Telegraph reported.</p>

<p>Johnson's new book ‘Unleashed', scheduled for release on October 10, claims the incident took place in the British Foreign Office when Johnson was serving as UK's foreign secretary.</p>

<p>During their meeting, Netanyahu – for whom he uses the nickname Bibi - excused himself to go to the bathroom, which Johnson describes as similar to “the gents in a posh London club” which exists within a “secret annexe”.</p>

<p>Mr Johnson writes: “Thither Bibi repaired for a while, and it may or may not be a coincidence but I am told that later, when they (security) were doing a regular sweep for bugs, they found a listening device in the thunderbox.”</p>

<p>When asked for more details on the incident, Johnson told The Telegraph, “I think everything you need to know about that episode is in the book.”</p>

<p>According to the reports, around the same time, Israel was accused of planting listening devices in the White House.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0vsjij4g_boris-johnson-and-benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A bugging device was found in Boris Johnson's bathroom after Benjamin Netanyahu's visit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-kenyas-dj-boboss-whose-music-is-crafted-with-household-items-6713426]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Kenya's DJ Boboss, Whose Music Is Crafted With Household Items]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-kenyas-dj-boboss-whose-music-is-crafted-with-household-items-6713426]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:29:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A spoon, some towel hooks, a piece of kettle and a plastic cap -- that's all you'll need to make a mixing deck if you have the technical and musical skills of DJ Boboss.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A spoon, some towel hooks, a piece of kettle and a plastic cap -- that's all you'll need to make a mixing deck if you have the technical and musical skills of DJ Boboss.</p>

<p>The 27-year-old -- real name Paul Mwangi -- has been building up a fanbase online and on the streets of Kenya with the one-of-a-kind deck that he put together himself.</p>

<p>It has even earned him slots at Uganda's Nyege Nyege festival, the largest in East Africa, and on the world-renowned club website Boiler Room.</p>

<p>But his favourite venue is Nairobi's bustling business district, where he set up on a recent Saturday among the stands of miraa (khat) vendors, the smell of grilled corn and the horns of matatus, the colourful minibuses of the Kenyan capital.</p>

<p>In a few minutes, dozens of curious onlookers had gathered, taking out their phones to film the amazing machine that spits out reggae hits.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j9pnm0ro_dj-boboss-kenya-afp-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The mixing desk consists of a spray-painted wooden board on which are screwed towel racks, switches and printed circuits connected in a tangle of cables -- all connected to an amp, speaker, and car battery.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He scratches using a slider made from a magnetised spoon between two towel hooks, and his fader is cobbled together from a plastic bottle cap.</p>

<p>Fixes are done without breaking the flow -- at one point, DJ Boboss whips out a screwdriver, strips a wire with his teeth and repairs a fault while the music keeps playing.</p>

<h3><strong>'Make my own'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"I've never seen anything like that in the world," smiled David Meshack, who works in a nearby electronics store that sells professional turntables.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"One day, a customer came in with a photo of it. He wanted the same one but I didn't know what it was," he said. "Today, I see it!"&nbsp;</p>

<p>Boboss is an acronym for "Be your own boss" and Mwangi got his start repairing radios.</p>

<p>"My dad bought me a radio. After some time it stopped 'talking' and he said he wouldn't buy another one. I was stressed because I was addicted to music and listening to radio, so I just opened it using a knife," he said.</p>

<p>Soon he was repairing electronic devices in his village near Meru in central Kenya.</p>

<p>Then one day he saw a DJ in a bar and was inspired.</p>

<p>"I loved how he played music and the way the crowd reacted. I didn't have the money to buy real equipment but I said I could make my own with the available resources."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mwangi moved to the capital and now makes a living from his DJing and occasionally selling specially commissioned turntables.</p>

<p>His favourite venue is the street, especially in the business district or at Gikomba, the largest second-hand clothing market in the country.</p>

<p>"Street shows is a special feeling, you have contact with the people. Many people have never seen a DJ mixing live," he said.</p>

<p>Among the onlookers, 48-year-old ex-soldier Zachary Mibei said he loved how Mwangi illustrates the situation for young people in Kenya.</p>

<p>"He has no training, it's all homemade, he is showing that he has something in him. He is telling us: 'I can do it by myself'," said Mibei.</p>

<p>Boboss admits it is probably time for a more advanced turntable with a few extra functions, but does not plan to part with the one which has made him famous.</p>

<p>"We could combine both and see what we can do with them," he smiled.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sm9hdu0g_dj-boboss_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Paul Mwangi's self-made DJ deck has a spoon, towel hooks, a piece of kettle and a plastic cap.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yazidi-woman-taken-as-isis-slave-at-age-11-rescued-after-10-years-6713291]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yazidi Woman Taken As ISIS Slave At Age 11 Rescued After 10 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yazidi-woman-taken-as-isis-slave-at-age-11-rescued-after-10-years-6713291]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:08:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Yazidi woman who was kidnapped by ISIS terrorists at age 11 and then held by Hamas for a decade has been rescued by Israeli forces in Gaza after a months-long operation led by the US, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Yazidi woman who was kidnapped by ISIS terrorists at age 11 and then held by Hamas for a decade has been rescued by Israeli forces in Gaza after a months-long operation led by the US, officials said.</p>

<p>Fawzia Amin Sido, 21, was rescued earlier this week. A footage of her being embraced tightly by her family soon after reaching Iraq was released by officials.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Ms Sido was freed after an operation coordinated between Israel, the United States, and other international actors.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Fawzia, a Yazidi girl kidnapped by ISIS from Iraq and brought to Gaza at just 11 years old, has finally been rescued by the Israeli security forces.<br />
<br />
For years, she was held captive by a Palestinian Hamas-ISIS member.<br />
<br />
She has now been reunited with her family. Her story is a... <a href="https://t.co/nkVotqYdov">pic.twitter.com/nkVotqYdov</a></p>
— David Saranga (@DavidSaranga) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidSaranga/status/1841684995301097932?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>When she was 11, Fawzia was trafficked by ISIS to a Hamas terrorist in Gaza, who was presumably killed during IDF strikes, the officials said in a statement. She fled to a hideout in which she was rescued in a secret mission through the Kerem Shalom Crossing, the official release mentioned.</p>

<p>David Saranga, Head of Digital Diplomacy Bureau in the Foreign Ministry of Israel, said her story is a reminder of the brutality faced by Yazidi children.</p>

<p>"Her story is a reminder of the brutality faced by Yazidi children, taken without a choice. Remember, there are still 101 Israelis being held hostage in Gaza," he tweeted.</p>

<p>After the 2014 massacres, some 1,00,000 Yazidis fled to Europe, the United States, Australia and Canada, according to the United Nations.</p>

<p>The Israeli military has been fighting against Hamas in Gaza since its unprecedented attack on Israel almost a year ago which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, according to an AFP tally.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,788 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qhrqunno_yazidi-woman-rescued-twitter_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fawzia Amin Sido, 21, was rescued earlier this week.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newly-elected-japan-pm-shigeru-ishiba-says-todays-ukraine-could-be-tomorrows-east-asia-6713272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Today's Ukraine Could Be Tomorrow's East Asia": Newly Elected Japan PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newly-elected-japan-pm-shigeru-ishiba-says-todays-ukraine-could-be-tomorrows-east-asia-6713272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:03:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's new Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba warned in his first policy speech Friday that "today's Ukraine could be tomorrow's East Asia" while also dubbing the country's low birth rate a "quiet emergency".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's new Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba warned in his first policy speech Friday that "today's Ukraine could be tomorrow's East Asia" while also dubbing the country's low birth rate a "quiet emergency".</p>

<p>"Many fear that today's Ukraine could be tomorrow's East Asia. Why did deterrence not work in Ukraine?" Ishiba told parliament.</p>

<p>"Combined with the situation in the Middle East, the international community is becoming increasingly divided and confrontational," the 67-year-old former defence minister said.</p>

<p>Ishiba made no direct reference to China but his country's relations with Beijing have deteriorated in recent years as it asserts its military presence around disputed territories in the region.</p>

<p>Of particular concern is Taiwan. Beijing claims the democratic island as part of its territory and has never renounced the use of force to bring the self-ruled island under its control.</p>

<p>Japan has also irked China with plans for a major increase in defence spending and by boosting security ties with the United States and its allies including the Philippines and South Korea.</p>

<p>In August, a Chinese military aircraft staged the first confirmed incursion by China into Japanese airspace, followed weeks later by a Japanese warship sailing through the Taiwan Strait for the first time.</p>

<p>Ishiba has backed the creation of a regional military alliance along the lines of NATO, saying on Tuesday that the security environment in Asia was "the most severe since the end of World War II".</p>

<h3><strong>Falling population&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Japan, like many developed countries, is facing a looming demographic crisis as its population ages and the birth rate stays stubbornly low.</p>

<p>The country has the world's oldest population after tiny Monaco, according to the World Bank.</p>

<p>Last year, its birth rate -- the average number of children a woman is expected to have in her life -- stood at 1.2, well below the 2.1 needed to maintain the population.</p>

<p>On Friday, Ishiba called the birth rate situation a "quiet emergency", adding the government would promote measures to support families such as flexible working hours.</p>

<h3><strong>Minimum wage</strong></h3>

<p>Kishida was unpopular with voters because of a string of scandals and inflation squeezing earnings in the world's fourth-biggest economy.</p>

<p>Ishiba wants to boost incomes through a new monetary stimulus package as well as support for local governments and low-income households.</p>

<p>Within this decade, he said Friday he wants to hike the average national minimum wage to 1,500 yen ($10.20) per hour, up nearly 43 per cent from the current 1,050 yen.</p>

<p>The yen surged last Friday after the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) voted Ishiba its new leader because he had broadly backed the Bank of Japan's exit from its ultra-loose policies.</p>

<p>But Ishiba told reporters late Wednesday he did not think the environment was right for further interest rate hikes, sending the Japanese currency south again.</p>

<p>On Friday afternoon, one dollar bought 146.02 yen, having slightly recovered from levels past 147 earlier this week.</p>

<h3><strong>Succession&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Ishiba also weighed in on the dearth of eligible male heirs to the imperial throne.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Male-only succession rules mean the imperial family is facing extinction, with only one young heir: Emperor Naruhito's 18-year-old nephew Prince Hisahito.</p>

<p>The emperor's daughter Princess Aiko, 22, is barred from the throne under the Imperial Household Law, in place since 1947.</p>

<p>Royal women must leave the family when they wed a commoner -- as in 2021, when former princess Mako Komuro, Naruhito's niece, married her university sweetheart.</p>

<p>Lawmakers in May began discussing a possible relaxation of the strict succession rules, and a recent Kyodo News poll found 90 per cent public support for female succession.</p>

<p>"Stable royal succession is extremely important. Stabilising the number of members of the Imperial Family is a particularly urgent issue," Ishiba told parliament, calling for active debate on the issue.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qoleve08_japan-pm-shigeru-ishiba-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The new Japan PM Shigeru Ishiba wants to boost incomes through a new monetary stimulus package. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-must-stop-fantasising-about-a-regime-change-in-iran-6713234]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Israel Should Stop Fantasising About A 'Regime Change' In Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-must-stop-fantasising-about-a-regime-change-in-iran-6713234]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:58:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Iranian regime is not going anywhere in a hurry, nor is its worldview going to change. The only change that might come would be in the shape of its capabilities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9ig7sbbg_israel_625x300_04_October_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The world had been for months expecting the conflict in the Middle East to blow up. That escalation has happened finally. It has been a remarkable turnaround for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who was under siege from within and under pressure from the outside. After Iran launched almost 200 missiles towards Israel, most of which were intercepted, Netanyahu has made it clear that Iran had made a "big mistake" and that it would "pay for it". The US is reportedly "discussing" the possibility of Israel striking Iranian oil sites and warnings continue to emanate from Iran that more is coming.</p>

<p>Diplomacy is no longer even in discussion, and like many times in the past, battlefield realities are dictating the behaviour of key protagonists in the never-ending Middle Eastern saga. This time, Israel and Iran are face to face. After an Israeli air strike killed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, Netanyahu warned Iran - Hezbollah's patron - that it could also become a target, underlining that "those who strike at us [Israel], we will strike at them", and that "there is nowhere in Iran or the Middle East beyond the reach of the long arm of Israel". Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, for his part, responded to the killing of Nasrallah by suggesting that it would be avenged and that his path in fighting Israel would be continued by other militants.</p>

<h2><strong>Israel Is Going For The Jugular</strong></h2>

<p>Israel's ground invasion of southern Lebanon that began last week shows no signs of relenting, with Israel warning more people to evacuate their homes, saying strikes would continue. For many in Israel, like the former prime minister Naftali Bennett, this was "the greatest opportunity in 50 years to change the face of the Middle East", with suggestions that Israel should go after Iran's nuclear facilities in order to "fatally cripple this terrorist regime". Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has also reached out directly to the Iranians, with the message that regime change was around the corner. "When Iran is finally free, and that moment will come a lot sooner than people think - everything will be different," Netanyahu said in a video statement addressed to Iranians, adding that "our two ancient peoples, the Jewish people and the Persian people, will finally be at peace".</p>

<p>At the moment, however, no one is planning for peace. Buoyed by its battlefield successes, Israel is keen to go for the jugular. It has had some stunning successes with the decapitation of Hezbollah's top leadership and the destruction of its weapons stockpile. The invasion of Lebanon is aimed at cleaning up the remnants of Hezbollah and its supporters. The veneer of the Iranian deterrent has been blown into smithereens. Iran is feeling the heat, and thus, unlike the very choreographed missile attack on Israel in April, Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps made a public display of their recent retaliation by announcing their intent. But with Israel continuing to push through southern Lebanon and Washington moving another carrier battle group to the Mediterranean, difficult decisions await Iran. Much as it would like to draw a line under this, Tehran's entire regional strategy, which till some time back looked like a winning one, suddenly has no legs to stand.</p>

<h2><strong>Iranian Regime Is In A Bind, But Not Going Anywhere</strong></h2>

<p>But it is exactly this which makes this a perilous moment in regional evolution. With its deterrence posture based on regional proxies now lacking credibility, Tehran has all the incentive to accelerate the development of its nuclear weapons capability, a move that will reshape the strategic contours of the Middle East. For all the bombast emanating from Israel about redrawing the political map of the region, a regime change in Iran remains in the realm of fantasy. The Iranian regime is not going anywhere in a hurry, nor is its worldview going to change. The only change that might come would be in the shape of its capabilities.</p>

<p>Even as the region struggles to come to terms with the escalation of violence, India's equities in the region have also come under stress. New Delhi's strong ties with both Israel and Iran will put pressure on Indian diplomacy. But its key priorities will remain ensuring energy security and the safety of its citizens in the region. India's entreaties for restraint, however, are unlikely to have much of an impact on the key players in this conflict, which remain intent on using the present escalation to seek long-term strategic gains. But the Middle East is a curious region where victories and defeats are never permanent and the end of every war spawns a new one.</p>

<p><em>(Harsh V. Pant is Vice President – Studies and Foreign Policy, at Observer Research Foundation, and Professor of International Relations at King's College London.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pvo1i0t8_israel_625x300_04_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-days-get-longer-in-summer-and-shorter-in-winter-6713207]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Days Get Longer In Summer And Shorter In Winter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-days-get-longer-in-summer-and-shorter-in-winter-6713207]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:50:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The days are getting longer and in Australia, the switch to daylight saving time is almost upon us (for about 70% of the population, anyway).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The days are getting longer and in Australia, the switch to daylight saving time is almost upon us (for about 70% of the population, anyway).</p>

<p>But why do we have longer days in summer and shorter days in winter?</p>

<h3><strong>It's all about the tilt</strong></h3>

<p>Earth goes around the Sun in an almost circular orbit. But not everything is lined up perfectly. Earth's axis is tilted by 23.44 degrees relative to its orbit around the Sun.</p>

<p>Imagine Earth's orbit as a flat frisbee with the Sun in the middle and Earth as a ball on a stick going around the edge.</p>

<p>If Earth's axis wasn't tilted (if its tilt was zero degrees) the stick would be exactly perpendicular to the frisbee. If you grab that perpendicular stick and tip it 23.44 degrees sideways, that's what Earth's tilt looks like now.</p>

<p>As Earth orbits the Sun, the tilt of the stick does not rotate relative to the Sun. If you were in outer space looking at the Sun and you watched from the exact same position for a whole year, you would see Earth go around the Sun while the stick stayed tilted in the same direction.</p>

<p>In other words, if the top of the stick was pointing to the right when you started watching Earth go around the Sun, it would stay pointing to the right the whole way around.</p>

<p>This tilt gives us longer days in summer and shorter days in winter. Let's set up the scenario so the Northern Hemisphere is the top of the planet and the Southern Hemisphere is the bottom of the planet.</p>

<p>When Earth is on one side of the Sun, the top of the stick is pointed towards the Sun. This is summer in the Northern Hemisphere and winter in the Southern Hemisphere. Six months later, when Earth is on the other side of the Sun, the bottom of the stick is pointed towards the Sun - and the seasons are reversed.</p>

<h3><strong>Solstices and equinoxes</strong></h3>

<p>Those two points, when the top of the stick is pointing directly towards the Sun or directly away from the Sun, are the solstices. They are the longest and shortest days of the year, depending on your hemisphere.</p>

<p>The shortest day of 2024 in Australia was June 21. Looking forward to sunnier times, the longest day of the year in 2024 will be December 21.</p>

<p>In between the summer and winter solstice, we have the equinoxes - when days and nights are almost exactly the same length. Those are the days when the stick through Earth is "side-on" to the Sun. The equinox is also the day when the Sun passes directly over Earth's equator. In 2024 this happened on March 20 at 2:06 pm AEDT and September 22 at 10:43 pm AEST.</p>

<p>That means that since September 22, days have been getting longer than nights in the Southern Hemisphere.</p>

<h3><strong>What does daylight saving do?</strong></h3>

<p>Earth's tilt means the Sun both rises earlier and sets later as we head towards summer. When the clocks (in some states) switch to daylight saving time, people in these states all get one hour less of sleep. However, the total length of the day doesn't change just because we changed our clocks.</p>

<p>For me, daylight saving means I need an extra cup of coffee in the morning for about a week before I adjust to the daylight saving lag (like jet lag, but without the fun of travel).</p>

<p>What it really gives us is more daylight in the evening, instead of more daylight in the morning. If you're already a morning person, this isn't the way to go. But if you prefer to have a long dinner in the summer sun it's ideal.</p>

<h3><strong>Has it always been this way?</strong></h3>

<p>Earth's axis hasn't always been tilted at 23.44 degrees. It cycles from a minimum 22.1-degree tilt to a maximum 24.5-degree tilt and back again once every approximately 41,000 years.</p>

<p>Earth's axis also "precesses", where the stick through it draws a circle once every approximately 26,000 years. You can see this in the animation below.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="A gif of the Earth wobbling in a circle on its axis." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=600&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=600&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=600&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=754&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=754&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/622704/original/file-20241001-16-lh8pl9.gif?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=754&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Demonstration of the precession of Earth's axis.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://science.nasa.gov/resource/axial-precession-wobble/">NASA/JPL-Caltech</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The length of a day on Earth hasn't always been the same, either.</p>

<p>At the moment, the length of a day is nearly exactly 24 hours. But it's shifting all the time by tiny amounts. This is tracked very closely by a system of telescopes and satellites. These systems measure "Earth orientation parameters" that describe Earth's exact orientation compared to the position of stars in the sky.</p>

<p>These are important to astronomers because the exact location of our telescopes is important for creating accurate maps of the sky. On top of all of this, the gravitational drag from the Moon causes days to become longer by around 2.3 milliseconds every 100 years. A few billion years ago, Earth's day was a lot shorter - only 19 hours long.</p>

<p>Even though some of us are losing an hour of sleep this weekend, at least we get to enjoy 2.3 milliseconds longer every day than our great - and great-great-grandparents did.</p>

<p><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/laura-nicole-driessen-892965">Laura Nicole Driessen</a>, Postdoctoral researcher in radio astronomy, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-sydney-841">University of Sydney</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/daylight-saving-is-about-to-start-but-why-do-the-days-get-longer-240221">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/cqi3c0n_the-sun-generic_625x300_13_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As Earth orbits the Sun, the tilt of the stick does not rotate relative to the Sun. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>