<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:59:01 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigeria-at-least-27-dead-several-missing-after-boat-capsizes-in-niger-river-7139254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nigeria: At Least 27 Dead After Boat Capsizes In Niger River]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nigeria-at-least-27-dead-several-missing-after-boat-capsizes-in-niger-river-7139254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:52:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Nigerian river ferry capsized Friday killing at least 27 people and leaving many missing, officials told AFP of the latest in a series of mass drownings on the country's busy waterways.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Nigerian river ferry capsized Friday killing at least 27 people and leaving many missing, officials told AFP of the latest in a series of mass drownings on the country's busy waterways.</p>

<p>The disaster happened on the Niger, near Dambo in Kogi state, at a point where West Africa's mightiest river can be more than 600 metres (yards) across.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's unclear how many people were on board, people don't usually keep a record of passengers," said Sandra Musa, of the state emergency management agency. "Search and rescue is still ongoing for survivors and possible bodies."</p>

<p>Musa said 27 bodies had been recovered. Kogi State Red Cross spokesman Abubakar Abullahi said the boat reportedly had more than 50 people on board.</p>

<p>Villagers and volunteers downstream of the accident have been urged to be on the lookout for bodies.</p>

<p>"It's not clear what caused the accident," Musa said. "It could be from turbulence or from the boat hitting a snag. Boat operators don't usually have life jackets, so none of the bodies recovered had life jackets on.</p>

<p>"The age of the boat might have played a role. Usually the lifespan of boat is between five and ten years, but you see boats aged 20 years. We will have a better idea of the situation tomorrow."</p>

<p>Kogi State Governor Ahmed Usman Ododo's office issued a statement lamenting the casualties and urging private boat operators and local authorities to ensure safety improvements.</p>

<p>Ododo, it said, "was particularly concerned that most of the victims were women, petty traders and artisans who are involved in legitimate business activities to earn a living and contribute to the economy of the state."</p>

<p>Friday's tragedy was the latest in a series of boat disasters on this stretch of the Niger flowing from the northeastern border towards central Nigeria and the Gulf of Guinea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Last month, around a 100 people were feared dead after a boat carrying 300 passengers, many of them women and children, to a Muslim festival in Niger State flipped over in the river.</p>

<p>In September, an overloaded boat sank while carrying more than 50 farmers across the Gummi River in Zamfara state. More than 40 are believed to have died.</p>

<p>In June 2023, more than 100 people died when a river boat carrying around 250 passengers capsized in the north-central state of Kwara, one of the country's deadliest waterway accidents in years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1gk7o3h8_boat-capsized-istock-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The boat reportedly had more than 50 people on board]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-aleppo-explained-whats-happening-in-syria-how-it-could-affect-middle-east-7139248]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What's Happening in Syria, How It Could Affect Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syria-bashar-al-assad-aleppo-explained-whats-happening-in-syria-how-it-could-affect-middle-east-7139248]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:50:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The civil war in Syria had thawed. But 13 years since the beginning of one of the worst humanitarian crises of the 21st century, a new surge in violence has reignited attention on a conflict that had faded from the world's headlines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The civil war in Syria had thawed. But 13 years since the beginning of one of the worst humanitarian crises of the 21st century, a new surge in violence has reignited attention on a conflict that had faded from the world's headlines. Syrian rebel forces have launched a major offensive on Aleppo, Syria's once-thriving commercial hub, marking the first challenge to President Bashar al-Assad's regime in years, potentially destabilising an already destabilised Middle East.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why Aleppo Matters</strong></h2>

<p>Aleppo, roughly 350 km north of the capital Damascus, has been a critical battleground in the Syrian civil war. Before the conflict, it was one of Syria's largest cities, home to 2.3 million people.</p>

<p>In 2012, rebel forces seized the eastern half of Aleppo, making it a stronghold of the rebellion against President Assad. However, the balance shifted in 2016 when Syrian government forces, backed by a brutal Russian aerial campaign, recaptured the city. The siege of Aleppo became symbolic, marked by indiscriminate bombings, starvation tactics, and massive displacement. By retaking Aleppo, Assad solidified his hold over key territories, bolstered by Russian and Iranian support.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0ck731bg_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The rebel offensive has targeted areas surrounding Aleppo and advanced toward its outskirts. If rebels succeed in breaking through, it could put a spanner in Assad's control over the crisis-hit country and reignite intense urban warfare.</p>

<h2><strong>The Actors Behind The Offensive</strong></h2>

<p>The primary force leading the charge is Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS). Once affiliated with terror group al-Qaida, HTS has rebranded itself over the years, claiming to focus on governance and military strategy in opposition-held territories. While the United States and the United Nations continue to designate HTS as a terrorist organisation, its leader, Abu Mohammed al-Golani, has sought to distance the group from its extremist roots.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u3ptikeg_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>

<p>HTS's transformation includes efforts to promote civilian governance in areas it controls, as well as limited outreach to religious minorities. Despite these changes, the group maintains a controversial reputation, accused of harbouring extremist elements and tolerating militant activities within its territory.</p>

<p>HTS is joined by several Turkish-backed factions, operating under the umbrella of the Syrian National Army. These groups have long had a complex relationship, often fighting among themselves despite their shared opposition to Assad.</p>

<h2><strong>Objectives Of The Rebel Offensive</strong></h2>

<p>In a video statement announcing the campaign, rebel military commander Lt. Col. Hassan Abdulghany described the operation as a defensive necessity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"To push back their fire from our people, this operation is not a choice. It is an obligation to defend our people and their land," he said, according to the New York Times. "It has become clear to everyone that the regime militias and their allies, including the Iranian mercenaries, have declared an open war on the Syrian people."</p>

<p>The rebels' immediate goals include halting airstrikes on civilian areas, reclaiming territory, and cutting off critical supply routes for government forces. Their progress so far has been rapid, capturing several villages, strategic highway interchanges, and military bases in Aleppo province.</p>

<h2><strong>The Assad Regime's Response</strong></h2>

<p>Syrian state media has reported fierce resistance by government forces, claiming to have inflicted losses on rebel fighters. The Syrian military, bolstered by Russian air support, has launched intense airstrikes on opposition-held areas, including the cities of Idlib and Atareb. Civilian casualties have mounted, with rescue groups like the White Helmets reporting dozens of deaths.</p>

<p>Iran, a key ally of Assad, has also suffered losses in the offensive. Among the casualties is a senior commander of Iran's Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>The Assad family, a Shia offshoot, has long relied on its alliance with Iran to stay in power. This alliance has been especially beneficial since 2011, when President Assad first faced an anti-government uprising.</p>

<p>After Syria plummetted into chaos in 2011, Iran has been accused of providing around 80,000 fighting personnel to Assad's army while Russia provided air support.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Regional Dynamics</strong></h2>

<p>The timing of this offensive comes at a time when Iran and its proxies, including Hamas and Hezbollah, are engaged in conflicts elsewhere. Israel's military campaign against Hezbollah in Lebanon and Hamas in Gaza has strained their resources. Additionally, Russia's focus on its war in Ukraine limits its capacity to provide substantial reinforcements in Syria.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ui9lsju_syria-reuters-_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters </span></p>
</div>

<p>Turkey, a key player in Syria, backs some of the rebel factions involved in the offensive. Israel continues its airstrikes on Iranian-linked targets within Syria, seeking to disrupt arms shipments to Hezbollah. This creates a volatile mix of overlapping conflicts.</p>

<p>The renewed fighting has had devastating consequences for Syrian civilians, particularly in opposition-held areas. The International Rescue Committee estimates that nearly 7,000 families have been displaced recently.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Northwestern Syria is home to approximately 4 million people, most of whom have been displaced multiple times during the conflict. Many live in overcrowded camps with limited access to food, water, and medical care. The resurgence of violence threatens to worsen these conditions and trigger another wave of mass displacement.</p>

<h2><strong>Implications For The Assad Regime</strong></h2>

<p>While his regime controls about 70 per cent of Syrian territory, much of this control relies on the backing of external allies like Russia and Iran.</p>

<p>Additionally, the offensive risks reigniting broader conflicts within Syria. The Islamic State, though largely defeated, still operates in the region through sleeper cells. A weakening of government control could create openings for these extremist groups to regroup and expand their activities.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/71csl97o_syria-bashar-al-assad-afp-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The primary force leading the charge is Hayat Tahrir al-Sham (HTS).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-320-billion-f-16-fighter-planes-radar-systems-to-taiwan-7139155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Approves $320 Billion F-16 Fighter Planes, Radar Systems To Taiwan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-approves-320-billion-f-16-fighter-planes-radar-systems-to-taiwan-7139155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:34:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States on Friday said it had approved the possible sale of spare parts for F-16 fighter planes and radar systems to Taiwan, in a deal valued at $320 million.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States on Friday said it had approved the possible sale of spare parts for F-16 fighter planes and radar systems to Taiwan, in a deal valued at $320 million.</p>

<p>The proposed sale consists of equipment in existing US military stocks, the Defense Security Cooperation Agency said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This proposed sale serves US national, economic and security interests by supporting the recipient's continuing efforts to modernize its armed forces and to maintain a credible defensive capability," the DSCA said.</p>

<p>"The proposed sale will improve the recipient's ability to meet current and future threats by maintaining the operational readiness of the recipient's fleet of F-16 aircraft."</p>

<p>China insists self-ruled Taiwan is part of its territory and opposes any international recognition of the island and its claim to be a sovereign nation.</p>

<p>The United States, while not recognising Taiwan diplomatically, is a major international backer.</p>

<p>The proposed sale includes "spare parts and support for F-16 aircraft" and "Active Electronically Scanned Array (AESA) radar spare parts and support," DSCA said.</p>

<p>The Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States requested the purchase and deliveries were estimated to begin next year, it added.</p>

<p>The deal was approved by the State Department, with the DSCA providing the required notification to Congress on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/oqvbsjto_taiwan-f16-fighter-l-chinese-h6-bomber-afp_625x300_22_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US, while not recognising Taiwan diplomatically, is a major international backer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-must-protect-minorities-ensure-fair-trial-for-hindu-monk-jaishankar-7139093]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Must Ensure Fair Trial For Hindu Monk: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-must-protect-minorities-ensure-fair-trial-for-hindu-monk-jaishankar-7139093]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:21:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as we]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Friday said the interim government in Bangladesh must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities as it expressed serious concern over the "surge" of extremist rhetoric and increasing incidents of violence against Hindus as well as attacks on temples in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>New Delhi also hoped that the case relating to Hindu monk Chinmoy Krishna Das, arrested in Bangladesh on sedition charge, will be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told Parliament that India has taken a serious note of incidents of violence against minorities in Bangladesh and that it is the primary responsibility of Dhaka to protect the life and liberty of all the citizens, including minorities.</p>

<p>The relations between India and Bangladesh have come under strain after the interim government headed by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus came to power following the resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina in August amid unrest.</p>

<p>India has been expressing concern over attacks on minorities, especially Hindus, in that country.<br />
"The primary responsibility for the protection of life and liberty of all citizens of Bangladesh, including minorities, rests with the government of Bangladesh," Jaishankar said, adding that the Indian high commission in Dhaka continues to monitor the situation related to minorities in that country "closely".</p>

<p>Separately, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) called upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities and hoped that the case involving arrested Chinmoy Krishna Das will be dealt with in a just, fair and transparent manner.</p>

<p>MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said India has consistently and strongly raised with the Bangladeshi government the threats and targeted attacks on Hindus and other minorities. "Our position on the matter is very clear -- the interim government must live up to its responsibility of protecting all minorities," Jaiswal said at his weekly media briefing.</p>

<p>"We are concerned at the surge of extremist rhetoric, increasing incidents of violence and provocation. These developments cannot be dismissed only as media exaggeration. We once again call upon Bangladesh to take all steps for the protection of minorities," he added.</p>

<p>Responding to a question in the Lok Sabha, Jaishankar said India is concerned over incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities, their homes and business establishments and attacks on temples and religious places.</p>

<p>"The government has taken a serious note of these incidents and shared its concerns with the government of Bangladesh." "Reports of attacks on temples and puja mandaps also came to light during the recent Durga Puja festival in Bangladesh. The government had expressed its serious concerns regarding the attack on a puja mandap in Tantibazar, Dhaka and theft at the Jeshoreshwari Kali temple at Satkhira during Durga Puja 2024," Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>Jaishankar said that following these attacks the Bangladeshi government had issued instructions for providing special security including deployment of Army and border guards to ensure a peaceful Durga Puja celebrations.</p>

<p>On the arrest of Das, who was associated with the ISKCON (International Society for Krishna Consciousness), Jaiswal said it is India's expectation that a fair and transparent trial will be ensured in the case. "We see ISKCON as a globally well-regarded organisation with a strong record of social service," he added.</p>

<p>Jaiswal said India has also noted that the legal processes in the case are underway. "We hope and expect that these processes will deal with the case in a just, fair and transparent manner, ensuring full respect for the legal rights of all concerned." Das was arrested at Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday in connection with a sedition case.</p>

<p>"It is our expectation that he will get a fair and transparent trial and his legal rights will be respected," Jaiswal said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s43j36bc_s-jaishankar-brics-summit-pti_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jaishankar said India is concerned over incidents of violence against Hindus and other minorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/prince-harry-meghan-markle-leading-isolated-life-in-us-reveals-documentary-director-7139013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harry and Meghan Leading 'Isolated' Life In US, Reveals Documentary Director]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/prince-harry-meghan-markle-leading-isolated-life-in-us-reveals-documentary-director-7139013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 11:05:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The documentary intends to examine whether the couple had achieved "freedom" and financial independence since stepping back from royal duties.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid reports about the alleged rift between Prince Harry and Harry Meghan, a documentary, based on the couple's life away from the spotlight of the royal family in the UK, is set to release in Germany next month. Award-winning filmmaker Ulrike Grunewald who travelled to the Californian town of Montecito to record the couple's experiences, said they had been leading a very 'isolated' life in what was a lively setting for socialising and mingling in the who's who of America.</p>

<p>"Harry and Meghan have set the bar very high. They want to be global benefactors who bring about tangible change. So far, they have not lived up to this image at all," Ms Grunewald, who has been a royal correspondent since 1987, told <em>The Mail.</em></p>

<p>“The cultural life here is very lively but often happens in closed circles, and Harry and Meghan rarely participate. They seem to have isolated themselves a lot.”</p>

<p>A similar version was echoed by one of the neighbours named Richard Mineards who said the Sussexes were seldom seen in the town.</p>

<p>"Sometimes you see her at the farmers' market or walking a dog, but generally, you don't see much of her or him. It's a shame. This is a lovely place," Mr Mineards said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/prince-harrys-friend-james-haskell-talks-about-dysfunctional-royal-family-7115521" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | Prince Harry's Friend Talks About "Dysfunctional" Royal Family</strong></a></p>

<p>Notably, the film intends to examine whether the couple had achieved "freedom" and financial independence since stepping back from royal duties.</p>

<p>"During the year that we worked on this film, a change of strategy was recognisable in Harry and Meghan. They started out as a power duo in their new life in California," said Ms Grunewald.</p>

<p>Now they mainly appear separately, as they were unable to create a functioning image together. They have come down to earth. I was interested in whether Harry and Meghan's strategies for an independent life are working. After four years, the results are very mixed," she added.</p>

<h3><strong>Professional separation?</strong></h3>

<p>In the last week, multiple reports have claimed that the couple was exploring separate career paths, in what experts have described as 'professional separation'. While Ms Markle is reportedly aiming to launch American Riviera Orchard next year, Mr Harry is planning the second iteration of Invictus Games in Canada. The first installment took place in Dusseldorf, Germany in 2023 and invited positive reviews. However, reports suggest that it cost German taxpayers 40 million euros (Rs 357 crore), undermining the goodwill.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eevn588_prince-harry-meghan-markle_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prince Harry and Meghan Markle during an event.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-was-muhammad-yunus-daughter-arrested-for-drunk-driving-7138962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Was Muhammad Yunus' Daughter Arrested For Drunk Driving?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fact-check-was-muhammad-yunus-daughter-arrested-for-drunk-driving-7138962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:56:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus, the Nobel Laureate and chief adviser of the interim government of Bangladesh, has often been in the spotlight, not just for his achievements but also for his contentious relationship with the US president-elect Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Claim</strong>: The video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken driving.</p>

<p><strong>Fact</strong>: The claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p><strong>Hyderabad:</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/nobel-laureate-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-as-head-of-bangladeshs-interim-government/article68502489.ece" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank"> Muhammad Yunus</a>, the Nobel Laureate and chief adviser of the interim government of Bangladesh, has often been in the spotlight, not just for his achievements but also for his contentious relationship with the US president-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The friction between the two dates to 2016 when Yunus made a significant donation to Hillary Clinton's foundation, an act that<br />
reportedly upset Trump. With Trump set to return to the White House after defeating Kamala Harris, political analysts predict that Yunus may face further challenges given his past remarks and actions.</p>

<p>Amid these ongoing developments, a set of photographs and a video have gone viral on social media, claiming to show <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.weforum.org/people/monica-yunus/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Monica Yunus</a>, the American-Bangladeshi music performer and daughter of Muhammad Yunus, being arrested for drunken driving.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@omkararoots/post/DC1GlW7TJBm?xmt=AQGzXuWbmENY-m2VIX0-aXXR6-JGt1vcCaEv7IJks-c_hA" target="_blank">A user on Threads</a> shared the images and the video with the caption, "He failed to raise his own kids n people think he is guiding muslim youth???? Trump-hater Muhammad Yunus supports gay rights. His daughter #MonicaYunus is a lesbian. She was arrested by cops in drunken state. Now can we ask those Islamists in Bangladesh to see the real identity of their 'leader'? (sic)"</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/q8sg1k08_yunus_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>&nbsp;The text on the images claimed that Monica Yunus is a lesbian and was arrested for driving under the influence. The video, captioned with inflammatory remarks about Muhammad Yunus and his family, shows a woman reportedly identifying herself as 'Monica Younus' during a police interaction.</p>
</div>

<p>Similar claims can be seen <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.threads.net/@shahadatali3870/post/DCiMQJ-P6L9?xmt=AQGzsgVioYeEP50NwERADhIfv5I7HDv82jl9mHcfaldxjA" target="_blank">here</a> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/kolappan1947/posts/pfbid02ohstXB3j7gQbgQBsziH1Rd72fqaBcb2z8V17u2B3fDKxeUrG3aRqyVRjQnsdUeY1l?rdid=dGXGbq6vQLzuv7ds" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<h3><strong>Fact Check</strong></h3>

<p>NewsMeter found that the claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p>Monica Yunus is an internationally renowned soprano, celebrated for her artistry and contributions to arts and culture.</p>

<p>A keyword search led us to Monica Yunus' official profiles, including her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.monicayunus.com/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">website</a> and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.facebook.com/YunusMonica" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Facebook account</a>, confirming her professional identity as an opera singer and social entrepreneur.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jhatoi88_yunuss_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>We found an article published in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2009/06/14/fashion/weddings/14YUNUS.html" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">The New York Times</a> titled ‘Monica Yunus, Brandon McReynolds' dated July 13, 2009. According to the article, Monica Yunus has been married to Brandon McReynolds since 2009.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u8jcrcgo_bangla_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;We couldn't find any reports of Monica Yunus being arrested or being known to have been seen driving under the influence of alcohol.</p>

<p></p>

<p>To verify if the person in the video is Monica Yunus, we compared the individual's face in the viral video with publicly available photos of Monica Yunus. The comparison confirmed that the two women are different individuals.</p>

<p>Here is a comparison of images.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d81kcu8_monica_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p>&nbsp;A reverse image search of the viral video led to a 1:14-hour-long <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sKLYf-cPNKE" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">YouTube video</a> titled, 'Drunk Woman Crashes her Car After a Breakup in Verona, New Jersey'. The thumbnail is the same as the images in the claim. The viral portion can be seen at the begin of the video, starting at 0:45 seconds.</p>
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sKLYf-cPNKE?si=HBqJ8G1ggLMouxI7" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe>

<p>The video under investigation is the bodycam footage taken from this video.</p>
</div>
</div>

<p>According to the video caption, the incident took place on April 16, 2022, when a woman named Monica was involved in a car accident in Verona, New Jersey. The video shows the driver admitting to consuming alcohol after breaking up with her girlfriend.</p>

<p>While the woman in the video shares the name "Monica," her identity is entirely unrelated to Monica Yunus.</p>

<p>Monica Yunus's most recent <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBgy92SJ2Yk/?igsh=Z2txYTZzNDc0andn&amp;img_index=1" target="_blank">Instagram post</a>, dated October 24, 2024, was about the celebration of "Sing for Hope." This is non-profit organization, co-founded by her and Camille Zamora, both opera singers, focuses on spreading hope through music.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vf7f0kio_yunusd_625x300_30_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Hence, the viral claim that a set of photos and a video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken driving is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus, as verified through image comparisons, official profiles and reports.</p>

<p><strong>Claim Review</strong>: The video shows Monica Yunus, daughter of Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus, getting arrested for drunken<br />
driving.</p>

<p><strong>Claimed By</strong>: Social Media Users</p>

<p><strong>Claim Reviewed By</strong>: NewsMeter</p>

<p><strong>Claim Source</strong>: Threads and Facebook users</p>

<p><strong>Claim Fact Check</strong>: False</p>

<p><strong>Fact</strong>: The claim is false. The woman in the video is not Monica Yunus.</p>

<p><em>(This story was originally published by&nbsp;<a href="https://newsmeter.in/fact-check/nehru-slapped-for-calling-arya-samaj-members-refugees-no-picture-is-from-a-patna-party-meeting-739748">NewsMeter</a>, and republished by NDTV as part of the Shakti Collective)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/agjfk0ag_yunus_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Monica Yunus is an internationally renowned soprano.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/foul-smell-at-international-space-station-how-the-situation-was-handled-7138857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Toxic' Odour At International Space Station Detected. What Happened Next?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/foul-smell-at-international-space-station-how-the-situation-was-handled-7138857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:33:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cosmonauts detected a strange odour emanating from a Russian spacecraft after it docked at the International Space Station (ISS) last weekend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cosmonauts detected a strange odour emanating from a Russian spacecraft after it docked at the International Space Station (ISS) last weekend. The Progress supply mission, carrying various supplies for the crew onboard the space station, was launched from Kazakhstan's Baikonur Cosmodrome on November 21, NASA said in a statement.</p>

<p>After the hatch to the Russian spacecraft was opened, they noticed an "unexpected odour and observed small droplets," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxweather.com/earth-space/cosmonauts-russian-progess-cargo-delivery-iss-unwelcome-smell" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Fox Weather</a> reported. The crew shut the hatch and sealed the rest of the Russian segment.</p>

<p>"The unpiloted Progress 90 spacecraft arrived at the space-facing port of the International Space Station's Poisk module at 9:31 a.m. EST, Saturday, November 23. The spacecraft launched at 7:22 a.m. (5:22 p.m. Baikonur time) Nov. 21, on a Soyuz rocket from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan," the US space agency said.</p>

<p>On Monday, Roscosmos cosmonauts Ivan Vagner and Aleksandr Gorbunov re-opened the hatch to unpack the supplies, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/spacestation/2024/11/23/space-delivery-arrives-at-station-aboard-progress-cargo-craft/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NASA</a> said in another update about the mission.</p>

<p>"Flight controllers on the ground activated air scrubbing equipment as part of normal procedures, indicating that the odor likely was outgassing from materials inside the cargo spacecraft," the US space agency said, adding the crew reported the odour dissipated quickly. The cargo transfer operations proceeded as per the schedule.</p>

<p>According to NASA, the Roscosmos spacecraft delivered nearly three tons of food, fuel, and supplies for the Expedition 72 crew onboard the space station.</p>

<p>It is scheduled to remain docked at ISS for approximately six months and will depart into the Earth's atmosphere to dispose of trash loaded by the crew.</p>

<p>Along with the air scrubbing, Ivan Vagner also cleaned the ventilation system and photographed the inside of the Progress spacecraft.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qbabbl48_russian-spacecraft-at-iss_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Roscosmos cosmonauts re-opened the hatch to unpack the supplies.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luciana-curtis-us-model-family-kidnapped-at-gunpoint-in-brazil-kept-in-remote-shack-7138758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Model, Family Ambushed By Gunmen At Brazil Restaurant, Held Hostage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luciana-curtis-us-model-family-kidnapped-at-gunpoint-in-brazil-kept-in-remote-shack-7138758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:18:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A New York-based model, her husband and their 11-year-old child were abducted at gunpoint and held captive in a remote shack in Sao Paulo, Brazil, for 12 hours.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York-based model, her husband and their 11-year-old child were abducted at gunpoint and held captive in a remote shack in Sao Paulo, Brazil, for 12 hours. The incident occurred on November 27. Luciana Curtis and her photographer husband, Henrique Gendre, were ambushed by armed men when they left a local restaurant. The gang forced them into their own car at gunpoint and took them to a wooden shack, according to a local Sao Paulo outlet, Gazeta. The shack, described as rudimentary, reportedly contained only a mattress, a toilet and a sink.</p>

<p>“The armed criminals approached the victims outside a restaurant and took them captive,” police stated in an official release, as per the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/29/world-news/new-york-based-model-and-her-family-kidnapped-held-hostage-in-brazil/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">NY Post</a>. During their captivity, the gang reportedly coerced the couple into transferring money from their bank accounts. On November 28, the family was abandoned by their captors as police search teams closed in on the area.</p>

<p>According to the report in <a href="https://www.gazetasp.com.br/cotidiano/bandidos-sequestram-familia-apos-jantar-na-zona-oeste-de-sao-paulo/1147097/" rel="nofollow,noindex" target="_blank">Gazeta</a>, the couple's eldest daughter, noticing no one returned home for a long time, alerted her uncle, who immediately contacted the police.</p>

<p>“During the search by specialist police teams, the gang abandoned the family and fled,” police added.</p>

<p>Seeking help, the family flagged down locals in a passing truck, who escorted them to the nearest police station. There, officers from the anti-kidnapping division recorded their statements and launched an investigation. Acting on the information, they tracked down the hideout, only to discover it had already been abandoned.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for the model confirmed their safety, stating, “The family has been released and they are safe and well.”</p>

<p>Curtis, a native of Sao Paulo and daughter of British businessman Malcolm Leo Curtis, divides her time between New York, Sao Paulo and London. She gained fame in 1993 after winning the Brazilian final of the Supermodel of the World competition.</p>

<p>The 47-year-old has graced the covers of renowned fashion magazines such as Marie Claire and Cosmopolitan. Her career includes collaborations with global icons such as Beyonce and leading brands, including Harrods, H&amp;M and Victoria's Secret.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hfhig2l8_luciana-curtis-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 47-year-old has graced the covers of fashion magazines such as Marie Claire and Cosmopolitan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydney-woman-kills-husband-with-drop-saw-disposes-of-body-in-30-plastic-bags-7138774]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sydney Woman Kills Husband With Drop Saw, Disposes Of Body In 30 Bags]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sydney-woman-kills-husband-with-drop-saw-disposes-of-body-in-30-plastic-bags-7138774]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:18:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police allege she killed him on May 3 last year using knives and a power saw, and disposed of his body in plastic bags across several suburbs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New South Wales Supreme Court has refused bail to Nirmeen Noufl, a 53-year-old Australian woman accused of killing her 62-year-old husband, Mamdouh "Emad" Noufl. After taking control of certain finances, Noufl, who appeared in court with the help of family and friends, allegedly killed and mutilated her husband.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.smh.com.au/politics/nsw/wife-dismembered-husband-with-drop-saw-to-escape-abusive-marriage-20241128-p5ku7f.html"><em>the Sydney Morning Herald,</em></a> police allege that on May 3 last year, Noufl acted alone in the killing, using knives and a power saw at their Greenacre home in western Sydney. The body parts were reportedly placed in up to 30 plastic bags and discarded in bins across multiple suburbs. Noufl was arrested last month after checking herself into a mental health hospital, where police gathered what they believed to be strong circumstantial evidence against her. Her husband's remains have yet to be found.</p>

<p>"The Crown would submit that there was a personal motive for the applicant [Ms Noufl] to act on the night of the alleged offence, and that was to escape a relationship she was not happy with, that she felt trapped with," the Crown prosecutor said. The Crown submitted that when Mr Noufl gave his wife legal authority of his properties in Egypt in May, it "presented an opportunity" for her to "get out of the relationship".</p>

<p>During the court hearing, it was revealed that a witness, known as "Witness A," claimed to have seen Noufl's actions on the night of the alleged murder. Another witness testified that Noufl made statements that could be seen as admissions of guilt. The police fact sheet indicated Noufl was motivated by abuse she suffered and her husband's relationship with a woman in Egypt, to whom he had become engaged while remaining married to her.</p>

<p>A witness, identified as "Witness A," said at the court hearing that he saw Noufl's behaviour the night of the suspected murder. According to the testimony of another witness, Noufl made remarks that can be interpreted as confessions of guilt. According to the police fact sheet, Noufl was driven by the abuse she experienced and her husband's affair with a lady in Egypt, with whom he had become engaged while still being married.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/rk3a5gro_-nirmeen-noufl_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police searched the Greenacre home of Nirmeen Noufl.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-wifi-router-overheating-set-her-home-on-fire-7138729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Claims WiFi Router 'Overheating' Set Her Home On Fire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-claims-wifi-router-overheating-set-her-home-on-fire-7138729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:08:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Florida resident Keona Huntley said she had been experiencing issues with the WiFi router for some time.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in the US state of Florida has claimed that her home was destroyed in a fire that was caused by her WiFi router overheating, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/28/us-news/homeowner-issues-warning-after-wi-fi-router-sparks-fire/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>NY Post</em></a>. Keona Huntley, who goes by the handle @yeahthatskeeee on TikTok, shared the now-viral video in the aftermath of the fire, stating that the blaze started in her bedroom where the router was kept. According to Ms Huntley, she had been experiencing issues with the device for some time and that a technician from the company responsible for it, Quantum Fibre, had visited her home on multiple occasions to sort out the problem.</p>

<p>Although the router had been replaced with a new one, the problems persisted as internet issues forced her to call the experts yet again. In the video, Ms Huntley also shared the aftermath of the fire that spread throughout the house, leaving almost everything charred. Starting in the kitchen, Ms Huntley showed the blackened walls with debris littered across the surface.</p>

<p>"We literally lost everything today. My bathroom is over there. it doesn't even look like a bathroom," said Ms Huntley. Her bedroom had been reduced to nothing but spring coils after the mattress was burned up.</p>

<p>Ms Huntley's problems have been expedited as she did not have renters insurance which means she has no way of covering the damage to her personal items.</p>

<p>“I didn't have renters insurance, and that was on me. I have to live with that guilt now that my kids don't have a home. I can't even replace their stuff," she said.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | UK Woman Fined For Littering Cigarette In Village She Hadn't Visited For Decades</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Investigation underway</strong></h3>

<p>"Our family's world was turned upside down when we lost our home to a devastating fire. In a matter of moments, the place where we built memories, shared laughter and found comfort was reduced to ashes," Ms Huntley wrote on her GoFundMe page.</p>

<p>Ms Huntley and her family are now seeking temporary housing and essential items as the house is rebuilt. "We never imagined finding ourselves in this position, but now we are reaching out to our community, friends, and kind-hearted strangers for help," she added.</p>

<p>Although Ms Huntley is of the view that the Quantum Wi-Fi router caused the fire, the authorities have launched an investigation to confirm whether the device was defective or if it was external factors that caused the incident.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mmfkb2j_fire_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keona Huntley's charred house after the fire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-highest-deflation-in-61-years-7138722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash-Strapped Sri Lanka Records Highest Deflation In 61 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-sri-lanka-records-highest-deflation-in-61-years-7138722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:04:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's consumer prices fell by 2.1 percent in November, the highest deflation rate recorded by the economically fragile island nation since 1961, official data showed Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka's consumer prices fell by 2.1 percent in November, the highest deflation rate recorded by the economically fragile island nation since 1961, official data showed Saturday.</p>

<p>An unprecedented financial crash in 2022 brought months of consumer goods shortages, with inflation peaking at nearly 70 percent that year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since then, a $2.9 billion bailout loan from the International Monetary Fund, tax hikes and other austerity measures have slowly made headway in repairing the island's economy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Headline inflation will remain negative in the next few months, deeper than previously projected, mainly due to larger downward adjustments in energy prices and reduction in volatile food prices," Sri Lanka's central bank said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The bank said inflation was likely to return to its target level of five percent in the coming months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sri Lanka had already seen deflation of 0.8 percent in October and 0.5 percent in September.</p>

<p>President Anura Kumara Dissanayake, who was elected in September, has vowed to maintain the IMF bailout programme negotiated by his predecessor that includes higher taxes and cuts to state spending.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/pqpaltag_sri-lanka-generic_625x300_13_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka had already seen deflation of 0.8 percent in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bank-accounts-of-hindu-leader-16-iskcon-members-frozen-in-bangladesh-7138607]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Hindu Leader's Arrest, 17 ISKCON Bank Accounts Frozen In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bank-accounts-of-hindu-leader-16-iskcon-members-frozen-in-bangladesh-7138607]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:33:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's authorities have ordered freezing for 30 days the bank accounts of 17 people associated with ISKCON, including its former member Chinmoy Krishna Das arrested this week on sedition charges, media reports said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's authorities have ordered freezing for 30 days the bank accounts of 17 people associated with ISKCON, including its former member Chinmoy Krishna Das arrested this week on sedition charges, media reports said Friday.</p>

<p>The move comes after the Bangladesh High Court rejected a petition seeking a ban on International Society for Krishna Consciousness (ISKCON), following the killing of a lawyer in a clash between the Hindu leader's supporters and security personnel.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) sent these directives to different banks and financial institutions on Thursday, suspending all types of transactions related to these accounts for a month, newspaper Prothom Alo said.</p>

<p>The financial intelligence agency under the central Bangladesh Bank asked the banks and financial institutions to send information, including updated transaction statements of accounts related all businesses owned by these 17 individuals, within the next three working days, it said.</p>

<p>On October 30, a sedition case was filed against 19 people, including Das, at Chattogram's Kotwali Police Station, accusing them of disrespecting Bangladesh's national flag in Chattogram's New Market area during a rally of the Hindu community.</p>

<p>Das, a spokesperson for the Bangladesh Sammilita Sanatani Jagran Jote, was arrested from Dhaka's Hazrat Shahjalal International Airport on Monday for alleged sedition. He was denied bail and sent to jail by a Chattogram court on Tuesday, triggering protests by his supporters.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, New Delhi expressed concern over the leader's arrest and denial of bail, and asked Bangladesh to ensure the safety of Hindus and other minorities.</p>

<p>Ousted Bangladesh prime minister Sheikh Hasina too has sought the priest's release. She also condemned the killing of the lawyer during the protests over his arrest.</p>

<p>ISKCON Bangladesh refuted allegations linking it to the lawyer's killing, saying the claims were baseless and part of a malicious campaign.</p>

<p>A spokesman of the attorney general's office said a two-member High Court bench that declined to ban the ISKCON activities in Bangladesh also said the situation did not warrant the intervention of the (High) court "at this time" as the State is carrying out its job. The Bench hoped that the government would remain cautious about protecting the law and order situation and the lives and properties of the people of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Hindus --- the community constituted about 22 per cent of Bangladesh's population during the 1971 Liberation War, now make up roughly 8 per cent - have been frequently reporting atrocities against their community members in different parts of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>There are also reports of the rise of extremist groups such as the Jamaat-e-Islami and similar ideological extremist wings.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ninval3k_isckon-priest-hindu-priest-chinmoy-krishna-das_625x300_26_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Bangladesh Financial Intelligence Unit (BFIU) sent these directives to different banks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Fined For Littering In Village She Hadn't Visited For Decades]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/uk-woman-fined-for-littering-cigarette-in-village-she-hadnt-visited-for-decades-7138440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:54:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Natalie Walton claimed that she could not have been the accused as she is a non-smoker and has not visited the place where the offence took place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Natalie Walton has been left confused ever since she received a fine for dropping a cigarette in a village, nearly 300 kilometres from her home -- a place she had not visited in over a decade. The fixed penalty notice (FPN), addressed to Ms Walton, was sent to her parent's house in Gravesend, Kent, accusing her of littering in nearby Swanscombe. The notice, dated November 12, stated a Dartford council officer witnessed her "committing an offence" which was also recorded on a body-worn camera, on October 29 and that she needed to pay a £75 (Rs 8,082) fine or appeal it.</p>

<p>The notice added that Ms Walton could be taken to court and if convicted, she may have to pay a fine "up to &amp; £2,500 (Rs 2,69,410) for littering".</p>

<p>"As neither the payment nor the written challenge has been received, you remain liable for the offence and prosecution proceedings in the magistrates' court may begin immediately against you," the notice added.</p>

<p>Ms Walton claimed that she could not have been the accused as she is a non-smoker and has not visited the place where the offence took place, since she was a kid. Ms Walton added she had an alibi which proved she was not even in Kent at the time of the supposed offence.</p>

<p>"I had not been to Kent for months. Dartford council were trying to fine me &amp;#163;75 for something I was not even there to do. It is just a bit bizarre. I was accused of littering a cigarette in Swanscombe which is honestly more absurd, as I do not smoke and have never been to the address they have claimed I was at," she was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.kentonline.co.uk/dartford/news/i-was-fined-for-dropping-a-cigarette-in-a-town-i-ve-never-b-316541/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>KentOnline</em></a>.</p>

<p>"I feel like a complete victim of fraud. Someone must have stolen my identity or the council's security measures are so broken they will take a name and address with no proof."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-man-eats-banana-artwork-he-bought-for-rs-52-crore-in-auction-7138037" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Watch: Man Eats Banana Artwork He Bought For Rs 52 Crore In Auction</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Evidence presented</strong></h3>

<p>As the controversy snowballed, Ms Walton produced her bank transactions, proving she was shopping in B&amp;M and Tesco in Staffordshire at the time of the littering incident. After her protest and examination of the evidence, the Dartford Council said Ms Walton's FPN was cancelled.</p>

<p>"When I saw the email, I was relieved and felt so much less stressed but I still have no idea how they thought it was me," she said.</p>

<p>The council, meanwhile, said the real accused had given the wrong address to the officers and pointed them towards Ms Walton.</p>

<p>"Our enforcement team requested a current photo of Ms Walton and upon receiving it was compared to the person in the footage. It was found it was not Ms Walton and the FPN has now been cancelled."</p>

<p>The council is still investigating who the real offender is but was unable to provide a photo.</p>

<p>Despite the fine being revoked, Ms Walton said the entire ordeal had left her stressed, especially when she is getting married in two weeks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e3kqje8o_cigarette_625x300_28_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Natalie Walton has been fined for dropping a cigarette in a town she has never been to.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/black-friday-fbi-issues-urgent-warning-for-chrome-safari-and-edge-users-scammers-are-targeting-you-7138228]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Issues Urgent Warning For Chrome, Safari And Edge Users]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/black-friday-fbi-issues-urgent-warning-for-chrome-safari-and-edge-users-scammers-are-targeting-you-7138228]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 07:57:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The FBI has issued a warning to online shoppers as holiday season scams surge, with an 89% increase in fraudulent websites reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the holiday shopping rush begins with Black Friday, online scammers are ramping up their efforts to target shoppers. A<em> Forbes report</em> has revealed that 89% spike in fraudulent websites compared to last year, with nearly 80% of shopping-related emails flagged as scams. Even trusted Google search results are being manipulated to direct users to harmful sites.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.fbi.gov/how-we-can-help-you/scams-and-safety/common-frauds-and-scams/holiday-scams"><em>Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)</em></a> has issued a warning to online shoppers, highlighting steps to protect themselves from these scams during Black Friday, Cyber Monday, and the rest of the holiday season. The alert is particularly crucial for users of popular web browsers like Chrome, Safari, and Edge, which dominate 95% of the US market. Shoppers are urged to stay vigilant and follow safety tips to avoid falling victim to these threats.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/black-friday-celebration-in-india-here-are-the-current-offers-7131718">Also Read | Black Friday 2024 Celebration In India: Here Are The Current Offers</a></p>

<p>The investigation agency has warned that "When shopping online during the holiday season-or any time of year-always be wary of deals that seem too good to be true. Don't become a scammer's next victim. Every year, thousands of people become victims of holiday scams. Scammers can rob you of hard-earned money, personal information, and, at the very least, a festive mood."</p>

<p>As per the precautionary measures mentioned in the statement released on the FBI's official website, the cyber scams include:</p>

<ul>
	<li>Non-delivery scams, where you pay for goods or services you find online, but you never receive your items</li>
	<li>Non-payment scams, where you ship purchased goods or services, but you never receive payment for them</li>
	<li>Auction fraud, where a product you purchase was misrepresented on an auction site</li>
	<li>Gift card fraud, where a seller asks you to pay with a pre-paid card</li>
</ul>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ic3.gov/AnnualReport/Reports/2023_IC3Report.pdf">Internet Crime Complaint Center's (IC3) 2023 report,</a> non-payment and non-delivery scams cost people more than $309 million that year. Credit card fraud accounted for another $173 million in losses. The IC3 receives a large volume of complaints in the early months of each year, suggesting a correlation with the previous holiday season's shopping scams.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4o7gddfo_black-friday-scams_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Popular browsers like Chrome, Safari, and Edge are being targeted.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/s-korean-train-conductors-4-minute-toilet-break-delays-commute-for-125-trains-7138198]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Korean Train Conductor's Toilet Break Disrupts Commute For 125 Trains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/s-korean-train-conductors-4-minute-toilet-break-delays-commute-for-125-trains-7138198]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 07:43:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Due to the toilet being on another floor, the train operator took 4 minutes 16 seconds to return to his cabin which led to a domino effect.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As many as 125 trains were delayed in the South Korean capital of Seoul, earlier this week, after a train operator took a four-minute toilet break -- leaving hundreds of passengers late for their destinations, according to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20241127050117" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Korean Herald</em></a>. The incident took place on Monday at around 8 am local time on Seoul's Line 2 when the train conductor, operating on the outer loop, made an urgent stop at a station and hurried away to relieve himself.</p>

<p>An engineer kept an eye on the proceedings as the operator ran down the platform to reach the restroom. Due to the toilet being on another floor, the train operator took 4 minutes 16 seconds to return to his cabin which led to a domino effect. 125 trains following the stationary train were rescheduled with many of them delayed by 20 minutes or more from their original scheduled arrival times, as per Seoul Metro.</p>

<p>Usually, conductors on the circular lines typically operate for two to three hours without breaks. Though portable toilets are available for emergencies, the staff members are sometimes compelled to go to restrooms, far from the platforms.</p>

<p>Despite the delay in services, Seoul Metro said the disruption was largely mitigated as the passengers reached their destination with minimal inconvenience.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-scrambles-jets-as-chinese-russian-warplanes-approach-7134563" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | South Korea Scrambles Jets As Chinese, Russian Warplanes Approach</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Social media users react</strong></h3>

<p>As the news went viral, social media users expressed concerns about labour rights in the Asian country where train operators remained under constant stress due to the policies.</p>

<p>"Train punctuality should be prioritised but not at the cost of a single person who cannot even take a few minute break," said one user, while another wrote: "This incident shows the realistic limitations of a one-man system."</p>

<p>A third demanded that better labour laws be in place to protect the rights of the workers: "If we hire enough people so that there are no delays when going to the bathroom and protect workers' rights, the system will run smoothly without any problems."</p>

<p>Nearly 70,000 railway, subway and education service workers, affiliated with the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions (KCTU) are expected to go on a general strike next month, demanding improved working conditions whilst condemning alleged workplace discrimination. regular train operators such as Korea Railroad (KORAIL), Seoul Metro (operator of subway lines 1-8) and Seoul Subway Line 9 will be part of the strike.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dgoft3_south-korea-rail_625x300_30_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Train conductor's toilet break leads to chaos.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-man-eats-banana-artwork-he-bought-for-rs-52-crore-in-auction-7138037]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Man Eats Banana Artwork He Bought For Rs 52 Crore In Auction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/watch-man-eats-banana-artwork-he-bought-for-rs-52-crore-in-auction-7138037]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 06:51:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Sun devoured the pricey banana after giving a speech and calling the artwork, curated by Italian artist Maurizio Cattelan "iconic".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Justin Sun, a Chinese-born cryptocurrency founder who spent $6.2 million (Rs 52.4 crore) on buying an artwork featuring a banana duct-taped to a wall, has eaten the fruit. Standing in front of journalists and influencers gathered at a luxury Hong Kong hotel on Friday (Nov 29), Mr Sun devoured the pricey banana after giving a speech and calling the artwork, curated by Italian artist Maurizio Cattelan “iconic”. He also drew parallels between the art and cryptocurrency, whilst describing the taste of the fruit.</p>

<p>“It's much better than other bananas. It's really quite good," said Mr Sun after eating the banana. Notably, each attendee at Friday's event was given a banana and a roll of duct tape as a souvenir.</p>

<p>Mr Sun competed with six others but emerged victorious in the auction, which was held at Sotheby's auction house in New York. The banana has been eaten twice before, first by a performance artist in 2019 and again by a South Korean student in 2023. However, none of them shelled any money, let alone $6.2 million.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zh">许多朋友问我这根香蕉的味道如何。老实说，对于一根有如此故事的香蕉，味道自然和普通香蕉不一样。我品尝出了一种100年前大麦克香蕉的味道。? <a href="https://t.co/ddo8pEjatx">pic.twitter.com/ddo8pEjatx</a></p>
— H.E. Justin Sun ? (@justinsuntron) <a href="https://twitter.com/justinsuntron/status/1862513736801808497?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Notably, immediately after winning the auction last week, Mr Sun had announced his plan to eat the fruit to make it a part of the history of the artwork.</p>

<p>"In the coming days, I will personally eat the banana as part of this unique artistic experience, honoring its place in both art history and popular culture," he said at the time.</p>

<p>"This is not just an artwork. It represents a cultural phenomenon that bridges the worlds of art, memes, and the cryptocurrency community," he added.</p>

<h3><strong>Comedian - a satirical art</strong></h3>

<p>Titled "Comedian", the banana artwork is a satirical conceptual piece that first debuted at Art Basel Miami Beach in 2019. It offers a commentary on how ridiculous the art world is where the meaning of a piece is tied to the money it attracts.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comedian-banana-taped-to-a-wall-sells-for-6-2-million-in-new-york-7068764" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also Read | "Comedian", Banana Taped To A Wall, Sells For $6.2 Million In New York</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Vendor in shock</strong></h3>

<p>While Mr Sun gulped down millions of dollars in a few seconds, the vendor who sold the banana for the auction expressed despair at not having received anything substantial sum of money from the viral gig. According to a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/27/nyregion/banana-auction-sothebys.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Times</em></a>, the banana was sold by Shah Alam, a 74-year-old fruit seller to the artist. Mr Alam, working outside Sotheby's in the Upper East Side said he was not aware that a piece of fruit he sold for only 35 cents would end up fetching the monstrous amount.</p>

<p>Though the banana art was satirical in nature, Mr Alam fails to understand how someone bought it for such an exorbitant price.</p>

<p>“Those who bought it, what kind of people are they? Do they not know what a banana is?” he questioned.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/8ma4nkc_justin-sun_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Justin Sun eating the $6.2 million banana.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-aleppo-airport-closed-as-rebel-group-reaches-heart-of-city-7137866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Syria's Aleppo Airport Closed As Rebel Group Reaches Heart Of City]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/syrias-aleppo-airport-closed-as-rebel-group-reaches-heart-of-city-7137866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 05:57:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Syrian authorities closed Aleppo airport and cancelled all flights on Saturday, three military sources told Reuters, as rebels opposed to President Bashar al-Assad said they had reached the heart of the city.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Syrian authorities closed Aleppo airport and cancelled all flights on Saturday, three military sources told Reuters, as rebels opposed to President Bashar al-Assad said they had reached the heart of the city.</p>

<p>The opposition fighters, led by the Islamist militant group Hayat Tahrir al-Sham, carried out a surprise sweep through government-held towns this week and reached Aleppo nearly a decade after having been forced out of the northern Syrian city.</p>

<p>Russia, a key ally of Assad, has promised Damascus extra military aid to thwart the rebels, two military sources said, adding new hardware would start arriving in the next 72 hours.</p>

<p>The rebels began their incursion on Wednesday and by late Friday an operations room representing the offensive said they were sweeping through various neighbourhoods of Aleppo.</p>

<p>They are returning to the city for the first time since 2016, when Assad and his allies Russia, Iran, and regional Shi'ite militias retook it, with the insurgents agreeing to withdraw after months of bombardment and siege.</p>

<p>Mustafa Abdul Jaber, a commander in the Jaish al-Izza rebel brigade, said their speedy advance this week had been helped by a lack of Iran-backed manpower in the broader Aleppo province. Iran's allies in the region have suffered a series of blows at the hands of Israel as the Gaza war has expanded through the Middle East.</p>

<p>Opposition sources in touch with Turkish intelligence said Turkey had given a green light to the offensive.</p>

<p>But Turkish foreign ministry spokesperson Oncu Keceli said Turkey sought to avoid greater instability in the region and had warned recent attacks undermined de-escalation agreements.</p>

<p>The attack is the biggest since March 2020, when Russia and Turkey agreed to a deal to de-escalate the conflict.</p>

<p>CIVILIANS KILLED IN FIGHTING</p>

<p>On Friday, Syrian state television denied rebels had reached the city and said Russia was providing Syria's military with air support.</p>

<p>The Syrian military said it was fighting back against the attack and had inflicted heavy losses on the insurgents in the countryside of Aleppo and Idlib.</p>

<p>David Carden, U.N. Deputy Regional Humanitarian Coordinator for the Syria Crisis, said: "We're deeply alarmed by the situation unfolding in northwest Syria."</p>

<p>"Relentless attacks over the past three days have claimed the lives of at least 27 civilians, including children as young as 8 years old."</p>

<p>Syrian state news agency SANA said four civilians including two students were killed on Friday in Aleppo by insurgent shelling of university student dormitories. It was not clear if they were among the 27 dead reported by the U.N. official.</p>

<p>Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said on Friday that Moscow regarded the rebel attack as a violation of Syria's sovereignty.</p>

<p>"We are in favour of the Syrian authorities bringing order to the area and restoring constitutional order as soon as possible," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0nsffsvs_syria-jihadists-_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti government armed group is returning to the city for the first time since 2016.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-pm-justin-trudeau-arrives-in-florida-to-meet-donald-trump-amid-tariff-threats-7137838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada's Trudeau Arrives In Florida To Meet Trump Amid Tariff Threats]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-pm-justin-trudeau-arrives-in-florida-to-meet-donald-trump-amid-tariff-threats-7137838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 05:43:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau arrived in Palm Beach, Florida, on Friday for what Canadian and American media said was a meeting with US President-elect Donald Trump at his Mar-a-Lago luxury estate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau arrived in Palm Beach, Florida, on Friday for what Canadian and American media said was a meeting with US President-elect Donald Trump at his Mar-a-Lago luxury estate.</p>

<p>Flight trackers first spotted a jet broadcasting the prime minister's callsign en route to the southern US state, in a visit that comes days after Trump threatened the United States' northern neighbor with import tariffs once he takes office.</p>

<p>According to the website Flightradar, the Canadian leader's plane landed at Palm Beach International Airport late in the afternoon.</p>

<p>Canadian public broadcaster CBC said Trudeau would be dining with Trump, and that his public safety minister, Dominic LeBlanc was accompanying him on the trip.</p>

<p>The prime minister's office did not immediately confirm the unannounced trip.</p>

<p>Trump sent shockwaves across Canada when he announced pending import tariffs against neighbors Canada and Mexico and also rival China in social media posts on Monday.</p>

<p>More than three-quarters of Canadian exports, or Can$592.7 billion ($423 billion), went to the United States last year, and nearly two million Canadian jobs are dependent on trade.</p>

<p>A government source told AFP that Canada is considering possible retaliatory tariffs against the United States.</p>

<p>Some have suggested Trump's tariff threat may be bluster, or an opening salvo in future trade negotiations. But Trudeau rejected those views when he spoke with reporters earlier in Prince Edward Island province.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump, when he makes statements like that, he plans on carrying them out," Trudeau said. "There's no question about it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/giln20ik_justin-trudeau-pti_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to reports, Trudeau would be dining with Trump today.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-delegation-to-hold-gaza-ceasefire-talks-today-in-egypt-official-7137670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Delegation To Hold Gaza Ceasefire Talks Today In Egypt: Official]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-delegation-to-hold-gaza-ceasefire-talks-today-in-egypt-official-7137670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 04:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas representatives will go to Cairo on Saturday for talks on a possible ceasefire in Gaza, an official in the Palestinian militant group told AFP on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas representatives will go to Cairo on Saturday for talks on a possible ceasefire in Gaza, an official in the Palestinian militant group told AFP on Friday.</p>

<p>"A Hamas delegation will go to Cairo tomorrow for several meetings with Egyptian officials to discuss ideas for a ceasefire and a prisoner accord in the Gaza Strip," the official said, speaking on condition of anonymity because of the sensitivity of the topic.</p>

<p>The announcement came two days after a ceasefire went into effect between Israel and the Lebanese group Hezbollah, a Hamas ally.</p>

<p>The United States has also announced a new diplomatic effort with Qatar, Turkey and Egypt to reach a Gaza ceasefire and the release of hostages taken during Hamas's October 7, 2023, attacks on Israel that set off the current fighting.</p>

<p>That attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,207 people, most of them civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed 44,363 people in Gaza, according to figures from the territory's health ministry, which the United Nations considers reliable.</p>

<p>Some 251 hostages were also taken on October 7, and 97 are believed still in Gaza, including 34 people who the Israeli army says are dead.</p>

<p>The only ceasefire so far, in November 2023, saw the release of about 100 hostages by Hamas and its allies in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners held by Israel.</p>

<p>The United States, Qatar and Egypt have led multiple failed efforts since the start of the year to reach a new ceasefire and hostage release.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rngv1mh8_israel-hamas-war_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed 44,363 people in Gaza since war began.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-are-bomb-cyclones-and-how-do-they-form-7137498]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Are Bomb Cyclones And How Do They Form?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-are-bomb-cyclones-and-how-do-they-form-7137498]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Nov 2024 03:45:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A dangerous weather phenomenon called a bomb cyclone that occurs in mid-latitudes - between Earth's tropics and the polar regions - can bring strong and damaging winds, torrential rains, heavy snowfall, flooding and frigid temperatures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>WHAT IS A BOMB CYCLONE?</strong></big> A bomb cyclone, also referred to as explosive cyclogenesis or bombogenesis, is a mid-latitude cyclone that has rapidly intensified. A cyclone is a low-pressure weather system - one where the atmospheric pressure is lower at its center than in surrounding areas - with winds rotating inward. It circulates in a counterclockwise direction in the northern hemisphere and a clockwise direction in the southern hemisphere. A bomb cyclone's winds can reach hurricane force - 74 miles (119 km) per hour - and stronger. These storms tend to form during winter and can spawn copious amounts of precipitation. They have life spans of about a week during which they grow to peak intensity over roughly four to five days and then dissipate over the last two, according to Jon Martin, a professor of meteorology at the University of Wisconsin at Madison.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>HOW DOES A BOMB CYCLONE FORM? </strong></big>Bomb cyclones form when the conditions at the surface and at the jet stream level are ideal for the storm to intensify. The jet stream is a narrow band of strong winds in the upper atmosphere. A variety of atmospheric processes combine to produce these storms. Almost all bomb cyclones have a precursor disturbance in the winds in the middle part of the troposphere - the lowest region of Earth's atmosphere - about 3-5 miles (5-8 km) above the planet's surface, Martin said. Another important feature common to many, but not all, explosive cyclogenesis events is a warm ocean surface. Many of the most intense bomb cyclones form over oceans. Precipitation can be prodigious. When water vapor changes into liquid and ice, as it does in these storms, enormous amounts of energy - called latent heat energy - are released. Some of that energy further intensifies the storm. By virtue of the atmospheric pressure getting so low, differences in pressure across the storm can become very large, powering strong winds that can have devastating effects.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>WHEN AND WHERE ARE THEY MOST LIKELY TO FORM?</strong></big> Explosive cyclogenesis occurs mostly over oceans and most commonly during the cold season in both hemispheres - roughly November to March for the northern hemisphere and roughly May through August in the southern hemisphere, though these storms can be earlier or later than that. Areas particularly prone are situated in so-called storm tracks along the east coast of continents because this is where the warmest ocean currents exist, such as the Kuroshio off Japan and the Gulf Stream off North America, Martin said. Bomb cyclones can be very destructive and pose particular danger to shipping interests, since many of them occur over the oceans, according to John Knox, an atmospheric scientist and professor of geography at the University of Georgia. Some bomb cyclones have occurred on the Great Lakes of North America and caused shipwrecks there, too, Knox said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>WHAT HAPPENS TO THE ATMOSPHERIC PRESSURE?</strong></big> The average sea-level atmospheric pressure at middle latitudes is about 1012 millibars, or mb. In cyclones, this gets down to as low as 980 mb with regularity. With bomb cyclones, it can drop to 950 mb or lower, and the rate at which they intensify is at least 24 mb in 24 hours.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>WHY CAN WE NOT CALL IT A HURRICANE?</strong></big> While bomb cyclones can unleash hurricane-force winds and sometimes display characteristics of a hurricane, they are not hurricanes. They form from different physical processes and do not have the symmetry of hurricanes, which also are low-pressure systems. Bomb cyclones occasionally develop "eyes" resembling those at the center of a hurricane, Knox said. But a bomb cyclone has its origins in the mid-latitudes and is associated with weather fronts - a boundary between two air masses with different characteristics such as temperature - and a strong jet stream, Knox said. A hurricane originates in the tropics and is not associated with either weather fronts or a strong jet stream, Knox said.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li"><big><strong>ARE BOMB CYCLONES BECOMING MORE COMMON?</strong></big> Global climate change, according to experts, is causing more frequent and more extreme weather events around the world. But are bomb cyclones becoming more common or more intense? Martin said it is not clear whether that is the case. The fact that Earth is warming has ramifications for cyclone dynamics that scientists are currently trying to figure out, Martin said. A warmer planet means more water vapor in the air and that would tend to make at least the latent heat portion of the empowerment of these storms stronger, Martin said. However, the warming is not uniform, Martin said. Since observations suggest more warming at high latitudes, Martin said, this could render the bomb cyclones weaker in general.</li>
</ol>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/thda9r8s_bomb-cyclone-reuters_625x300_30_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A low pressure storm system known as a "bomb cyclone" forms off the coast of US Pacific Northwest]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>