<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 18:08:51 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ayatollah-ali-khamenei-israel-hezbollah-hassan-nasrallah-cant-weaken-dismantle-iran-supreme-leader-after-hezbollah-chiefs-death-6670570]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Learnt No Lessons": Iran Supreme Leader After Hezbollah Chief's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ayatollah-ali-khamenei-israel-hezbollah-hassan-nasrallah-cant-weaken-dismantle-iran-supreme-leader-after-hezbollah-chiefs-death-6670570]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 17:36:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lashing out after the death of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and civilians in strikes on Lebanon's Beirut, Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has said the savage nature of the "rabid Zionist regime" has been revealed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lashing out after the death of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and civilians in strikes on Lebanon's Beirut, Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has said the savage nature of the "rabid Zionist regime" has been revealed. Mr Khamenei's statement came on Saturday, amid reports that he had been moved to a secure location after Nasrallah's killing and at a time when the world's eyes are on Iran to see what steps it takes after the attacks on one of its closest allies.</p>

<p>The Iranian Supreme Leader also called Israel's war against Hamas - another partner in Iran's 'Axis of Resistance' against the Jewish country - &nbsp;in Gaza a "criminal" one and called upon all Muslims to stand with Hezbollah and the people of Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The massacre of defenceless people in Lebanon has once again revealed the savage nature of the rabid Zionist regime, and at the same time, it has proven the short-sightedness and foolish policies of the heads of the usurping regime. The terror group ruling the Zionist regime has failed to learn a lesson from its year-long criminal war in Gaza. They have not understood that the mass killing of women, children, and civilians cannot weaken or dismantle the strong structure of the resistance organisation," Mr Khamenei said in a statement, which did not mention what were, until then, Israel's claims of killing the Hezbollah chief.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Accusing the Israeli government of testing the "same foolish policies" in Lebanon, Mr Khamenei said it is "too insignificant" to inflict any significant damage to Hezbollah's foundation in Lebanon.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"All the resistance forces in the region stand beside and support Hezbollah. The destiny of this region will be shaped by the forces of resistance, with the proud Hezbollah at the forefront. The people of Lebanon have not forgotten the days when the military of the usurping regime marched to Beirut. It was Hezbollah that cut off their advance and brought dignity and pride to Lebanon. Today, with God's strength, Lebanon will again force the vile, malevolent enemy to regret its actions," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Giving a call for Muslims to stand with Lebanon and Hezbollah, he added, "It is incumbent upon all Muslims to stand with the people of Lebanon and the proud Hezbollah with all their resources and support them in their confrontation with the usurping, oppressive, and malicious regime."</p>

<p>News agency Reuters reported that, after Nasrallah's death, Mr Khamenei has been moved to a secure location. Sources told the agency that Iran is in touch with Hezbollah and other groups in the region to assess what the country's next steps can be.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has, over the past few days, shifted the focus of its operation from Gaza to Lebanon and its heavy bombing has killed more than 700 people and displaced over 1 lakh. Its operations have continued despite growing international calls for a ceasefire, including from the US.</p>

<p>Israel's army chief Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi on Saturday said: "The message is simple, anyone who threatens the citizens of Israel: we will know how to reach them."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/b3d2u2tg_ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_01_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iranian Supreme Leader also called Israel's war against Hamas a "criminal" one.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-leader-hassan-nasrallahs-death-after-israeli-strike-6670568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Confirms Leader Hassan Nasrallah's Death After Israeli Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-confirms-leader-hassan-nasrallahs-death-after-israeli-strike-6670568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 17:35:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been killed, the Iran-backed group said on Saturday, confirming his death after the Israeli military said it had eliminated him in an airstrike in Beirut the day before.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah has been killed, the Iran-backed group said on Saturday, confirming his death after the Israeli military said it had eliminated him in an airstrike in Beirut the day before.</p>

<p>His death marks a devastating blow to Hezbollah as it reels from an escalating campaign of Israeli attacks. It is also a huge blow to Iran, given the major role he has played in the Tehran-backed regional "Axis of Resistance".</p>

<p>Hezbollah said in a statement that it would continue its battle against Israel "in support of Gaza and Palestine, and in defence of Lebanon and its steadfast and honourable people". It did not say how Nasrallah was killed.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said earlier that Nasrallah was eliminated in a "targeted strike" on Friday on the group's underground headquarters beneath a residential building in Dahiyeh - a Hezbollah-controlled southern suburb of Beirut.</p>

<p>It said he was killed along with another top Hezbollah leader, Ali Karaki, and other commanders.</p>

<p>"The strike was conducted while Hezbollah's senior chain of command were operating from the headquarters and advancing terrorist activities against the citizens of the State of Israel," it said.</p>

<p>Friday's airstrike on Dahiyeh shook Beirut. A security source in Lebanon said the attack - a quick succession of massively powerful blasts - had left a crater at least 20 metres (65 feet) deep.</p>

<p>It was followed on Saturday by further airstrikes on Dahiyeh and other parts of Lebanon. Huge explosions lit up the night sky, and more strikes hit the area in the morning. Smoke rose over the city.</p>

<p>Residents have fled Dahiyeh, seeking shelter in downtown Beirut and other parts of the city.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ev0ik0d8_hassan-nasrallah_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah said in a statement that it would continue its battle against Israel. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/colonialism-turned-tigers-to-trophies-how-india-relocated-thousands-of-humans-to-save-them-6670491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Colonialism Turned Tigers To Trophies. How India Moved Humans To Save Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/colonialism-turned-tigers-to-trophies-how-india-relocated-thousands-of-humans-to-save-them-6670491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 17:24:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British colonialism turned Indias tigers into trophies. Between 1860 and 1950, more than 65,000 were shot for their skins. The fortunes of the Bengal tiger, one of Earths biggest species of big cat, did not markedly improve post-independence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British colonialism turned India's tigers into trophies. Between 1860 and 1950, more than 65,000 were shot for their <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/epdf/10.1177/025764309801400206">skins</a>. The fortunes of the Bengal tiger, one of Earth's biggest species of big cat, did not markedly improve post-independence. The hunting of tigers – and the animals they eat, like deer and wild pigs – continued, while large tracts of their forest habitat became farmland.</p>

<p>India established Project Tiger in 1972 when there were <a href="https://ntca.gov.in/assets/uploads/Reports/Joining_the_dot.pdf">fewer than 2,000 tigers</a> remaining; it is now one of the world's longest-running conservation programmes. The project aimed to protect and increase tiger numbers by creating reserves from existing protected areas like national parks and wildlife sanctuaries. Part of that process has involved forcing people to relocate.</p>

<p>In protected areas globally, nature conservationists can find themselves at odds with the needs of <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/abs/10.1073/pnas.1525003113">local communities</a>. Some scientists have argued that, in order for them to thrive, tigers need forests that are completely free of people who might otherwise graze livestock or collect firewood. In a few documented cases, the tiger population has indeed recovered once people were <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10344-008-0219-2">removed from tiger reserves</a>.</p>

<p>But in pitting people against wildlife, relocations foster bigger problems that do not serve the long-term interests of conservation.</p>

<h2>India's Relocation Policy</h2>

<p>Under Project Tiger, 27 tiger reserves were established by 2005, each spanning somewhere between 500 and 2,500 square kilometres. Tiger reserves have a core in which people are prevented from grazing livestock, hunting wildlife and collecting wood, leaves and flowers. A buffer zone encircles this. Here, such activities are allowed, but regulated.</p>

<p>About 3,000 families were <a href="https://ntca.gov.in/assets/uploads/Reports/Joining_the_dot.pdf">relocated</a> from these core zones in the first three decades of the project, and from 2005 until 2023, about 22,000 families were moved. Most relocations were involuntary and some plunged those ousted into deeper poverty.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A house surrounded by grassland." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617216/original/file-20240904-16-izbkoa.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">A village inside the core of Sariska tiger reserve.</span> <span class="attribution"><span class="source">Ghazala Shahabuddin</span></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>In Sariska tiger reserve in Rajasthan, northwestern India, the first relocation was made during 1976-77. Some of the families returned to the reserve after being given land unsuitable for farming as compensation. This was a poor advertisement for relocation which few other communities <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/262127259_Creation_of_'Inviolate_Space'_Lives_Livelihoods_and_Conflict_in_Sariska_Tiger_Reserve">opted for voluntarily</a>.</p>

<p>After they were moved from Rajaji tiger reserve in 2012, Gujjar pastoralists who make their living grazing buffalo were prompted to take up farming on new land. With little experience in agriculture, and having been denied their traditional source of income, many struggled to adjust.</p>

<p>The Gujjar did at least gain access to <a href="https://india.mongabay.com/2023/06/commentary-a-decade-after-relocation-the-lives-of-van-gujjars-still-lack-stability-and-security/">water pumps and electricity</a>. In one case, in the Bhadra tiger reserve in Karnataka, southwestern India, relocation was less painful as people were offered quality agricultural land who already had <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S000632070700273X">prior farming experience</a>.</p>

<p>Most people who lost their right to graze livestock or collect forest produce in newly established tiger reserves went on to labour in tea and coffee plantations or factories.</p>

<p>Despite widespread relocations, the tiger population in India continued to plummet, reaching an all-time low of fewer than 1,500 in 2006. Tigers <a href="https://ntca.gov.in/assets/uploads/Reports/Joining_the_dot.pdf">became extinct</a> in Sariska and Panna tiger reserves in 2004 and 2007 respectively.</p>

<p>Local extinction in Sariska prompted the government to enlist the help of tiger biologists and social scientists in 2005. This task force found that illegal hunting of tigers was still happening, their claws, teeth, bones and skin harvested <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/business/environment/india-says-chinese-medicine-fuels-tiger-poaching-idUSTRE58G4XQ/">for use in Chinese medicine</a>. Mining and grazing had also continued within many reserves.</p>

<h2>Corridors Of Power</h2>

<p>The tiger task force acknowledged that having the local community onside helped prevent illegal hunting and forest fires. The Soliga tribes of Biligiri Rangananthaswamy temple tiger reserve in Karnataka decided not to relocate when offered compensation, but instead took up work rooting out invasive plants like lantana and <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320720309460">curbing illegal hunting and timber felling</a>. The Soliga are among the very few communities who have been rewarded with rights in tiger reserves.</p>

<p>Similarly, in Parambikulam tiger reserve in Kerala, a state on India's tropical Malabar coast, communities that were not relocated found work as tour guides and forest guards. People here have supplemented their income by collecting and selling honey, wild gooseberry and medicinal spices, under the joint supervision of the community and forest department officials. Many families have been able to give up cattle rearing as a result, <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666719320300145#:%7E:text=The%2520conversion%2520of%2520Parambikulam%2520Wildlife,cattle%2520in%2520the%2520Tiger%2520Reserve.">reducing grazing pressure</a> on the forest.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A woman carrying a bundle fodder on her head." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=544&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=544&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=544&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=684&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=684&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/617218/original/file-20240904-16-fixjgc.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=684&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Residents in tiger reserves depend on fodder, fuel and other forest produce.</span> <span class="attribution"><span class="source">Ghazala Shahabuddin</span></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Despite these successes, the government's policy of relocation remains.</p>

<p>Tiger numbers have recovered to more than 3,000 as of 2022, but Project Tiger shows that relocation alone cannot conserve tigers indefinitely.</p>

<p>A great opportunity awaits. Over 38 million hectares of forest, <a href="https://ntca.gov.in/assets/uploads/Reports/AITM/Tiger_Status_Report_2018.pdf">suitable tiger habitat</a>, lies outside tiger reserves. Declaring these forests “corridors” that allow tigers to move between reserves could <a href="https://besjournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/pan3.10177">reduce the risk</a> of inbreeding and local extinction and reinforce the recovery of India's tigers.</p>

<p>Studies in certain tiger reserves show that large numbers of villagers would <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0264837718312900">support further relocations</a> if it meant gaining access to drinking water, schools, healthcare and jobs in resettlement sites. A portion of the US$30 million (£22.7 million) <a href="https://www.pib.gov.in/PressReleasePage.aspx?PRID=1810562">spent annually</a> by Project Tiger should be used to make relocations fair. Or better yet, promote the kind of community-based conservation nurtured in the Biligiri Ranganathaswamy temple and Parambikulam tiger reserves.</p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/dhanapal-govindarajulu-1444876">Dhanapal Govindarajulu</a>, Postgraduate Researcher, Global Development Institute, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-manchester-1204">University of Manchester</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/divya-gupta-1646792">Divya Gupta</a>, Assistant Professor, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/binghamton-university-state-university-of-new-york-2252">Binghamton University, State University of New York</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/ghazala-shahabuddin-1646933">Ghazala Shahabuddin</a>, Visiting Professor of Environmental Studies, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/ashoka-university-5186">Ashoka University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>The authors do not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and have disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/to-save-its-tigers-india-has-relocated-thousands-of-people-it-could-enlist-their-help-instead-238109">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cg17u9kk_tiger-generic-pixabay_625x300_28_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has one of the worlds longest-running tiger conservation programmes. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-of-hezbollahs-senior-leaders-eliminated-says-israeli-army-6670338]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Most Of Hezbollah's Senior Leaders "Eliminated," Says Israeli Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/most-of-hezbollahs-senior-leaders-eliminated-says-israeli-army-6670338]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 17:00:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's military said Saturday that "most" senior leaders of Hezbollah had been killed, after it announced the death of Hassan Nasrallah, the head of the group, which has not provided confirmation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's military said Saturday that "most" senior leaders of Hezbollah had been killed, after it announced the death of Hassan Nasrallah, the head of the group, which has not provided confirmation.</p>

<p>"Most of the senior leaders of Hezbollah have been eliminated," military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani told an online press briefing.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/cih1ee1_hassan-nasrallah_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's statement came after it announced the death of Hassan Nasrallah. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-indians-than-ever-are-holidaying-abroad-where-are-they-heading-and-why-6670239]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[More Indians Than Ever Holidaying Abroad - Where Are They Heading And Why?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-indians-than-ever-are-holidaying-abroad-where-are-they-heading-and-why-6670239]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:46:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Travel is on the rise again. According to the UN's tourism agency, international travel for all purposes reached 97% of its pre-pandemic level in the first quarter of 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Travel is on the rise again. According to the UN's tourism agency, international travel for all purposes <a href="https://www.unwto.org/un-tourism-world-tourism-barometer-data">reached 97%</a> of its pre-pandemic level in the first quarter of 2024. In some regions such as Africa and Europe, arrivals are already surpassing these levels.</p>

<p>Indian travellers, in particular, are adding to this growing trend – no nation's <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/article/india-outbound-tourism-intl-hnk/index.html">outbound tourism market</a> is growing faster. In response to this rapidly expanding travel boom, Indian airlines ordered <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/record-plane-orders-raise-stakes-indias-aviation-boom-2023-06-20/">record numbers</a> of new planes in 2024.</p>

<p>The Indian travel market is gigantic, with its middle class now representing <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/economy/indicators/how-the-middle-class-will-play-the-hero-in-indias-rise-as-world-power/articleshow/101608682.cms?from=mdr">31% of the country's population</a>. This figure is expected to increase to 60% by 2047, meaning there will be more than 1 billion middle-class Indians by the middle of the century.</p>

<p>For budding Indian tourists, the future of travel looks exciting. But for the many destinations already besieged by <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2023/aug/17/wish-you-werent-here-how-tourists-are-ruining-the-worlds-greatest-destinations">overtourism</a>, this new market may be viewed through a more <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cl55vdjv2j3o">sceptical lense</a>.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, Indian tourists spent <a href="https://www.visitbritain.org/research-insights/inbound-markets/india">US$33.3 billion</a> (£25.3 billion) in 2023, and many destinations are recognising their potential. In April, for example, Japan introduced a new e-visa system for Indian tourists in the <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/visa-updates-for-indian-travellers-2024-9250412/">hopes of increasing arrivals</a>.</p>

<p>Two months earlier, Dubai created a five-year, multiple-entry tourist visa tailored to Indian visitors. South Africa's <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/finance/personal-finance/south-africa-to-offer-90-day-visa-waiver-for-indian-tourists-from-jan-2025-124090500183_1.html">simplified visa scheme</a> will also start in 2025, while other nations including <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/malaysia-allow-visa-free-entry-china-india-citizens-dec-1-pm-2023-11-27/">Malaysia</a>, <a href="https://skift.com/2024/03/05/kenya-offers-incentives-to-indian-travel-agents-plus-new-metro-route-to-the-taj-mahal-india-report/">Kenya</a>, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-05-07/thailand-extends-visa-waiver-plan-for-indian-taiwanese-tourists">Thailand</a> and <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/visit/iran-scraps-visa-requirement-for-indian-tourists-but-theres-a-catch/articleshow/107462794.cms?from=mdr">Iran</a> have scrapped visa requirements for Indian tourists entirely.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/co7un408_passport_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em>India's outbound tourism market is growing rapidly. (Representational image)</em></p>

<p>The evidence suggests these schemes work. Tour operator Thomas Cook reported in May that Indian demand for holidays in Georgia has <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/visit/delays-in-schengen-visa-appointment-prompt-indians-to-change-course-to-georgia-japan/articleshow/110216573.cms?from=mdr">surged</a> by a staggering 600% year-on-year since the country launched its e-visa system for Indian tourists in 2015.</p>

<p>Other European markets have been slower to adjust. Europe's border-free Schengen zone has <a href="https://www.euronews.com/travel/2024/05/01/the-eus-new-multiple-entry-visa-scheme-is-making-it-easier-for-indians-to-travel-to-europe">introduced</a> a new “cascade” system, which will allow Indian visitors who have used a short-stay visa twice in the last three years to now apply for a two-year, multiple-entry tourist visa.</p>

<p>But, while this is a positive step towards easier travel for some Indian tourists, it will have no effect on new travellers. The Schengen visa process can also still take months, requires significant paperwork, and appointments are <a href="https://schengen.news/indians-opting-for-alternative-destinations-due-to-limited-schengen-visa-appointments/">notoriously difficult</a> to find.</p>

<p>The story is similar for British visas. Many people in India, as well as <a href="https://inkyfada.com/en/2023/06/22/getting-schengen-visa-humiliating-journey/">other applicants</a>, feel the process is too harsh and can be <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/hey-west-can-we-get-visas-minus-the-pain-and-humiliation-please/articleshow/99873252.cms">humiliating</a>. Endless amounts of paperwork are required, including bank statements and invitation letters, and rejections are often not explained.</p>

<p>In a study of travel trends in India, online travel platform <a href="https://online.fliphtml5.com/nmyfd/fqhe/#p=1">Booking.com</a> also found that Indian tourists typically book their trip at the last minute. They spend just 30 days planning a holiday on average, compared with 63 days for Americans and 90 days for Brits. Many simply cannot be bothered with time-consuming visa requirements, and are opting for easier and more welcoming destinations instead.</p>

<h2>So, where are they going?</h2>

<p>Budget airlines flying to relatively nearby destinations have contributed to India's tourism rush, with south-east Asia increasingly popular. According to <a href="https://hanoitimes.vn/vietnam-becomes-no1-interest-among-indian-travelers-325803.html">Google Trends</a>, Vietnam was the most-researched destination by Indians in 2023.</p>

<p>That year, the Vietnam National Authority of Tourism <a href="https://vir.com.vn/indian-tourists-can-be-gold-mine-for-vietnam-114122-114122.html#:%7E:text=India%20is%20considered%20a%20promising,cent%20increase%20compared%20to%202019.">reported</a> a 231% increase in visitors from India compared with 2019. Other south-east Asian countries such as Thailand, Singapore and Indonesia are seeing similarly <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/article/india-outbound-tourism-intl-hnk/index.html">huge jumps in arrivals</a>.</p>

<p>Indian travellers are hugely influenced by television and movies, often opting to visit the places they have seen in Bollywood. Despite visa restrictions, the number of Indian tourists <a href="https://cultureandhistory.revistas.csic.es/index.php/cultureandhistory/article/view/250">visiting Spain</a> jumped by 40% in 2011 after the <em>La Tomatina</em> festival – where participants throw tomatoes at each other – was featured in the popular Hindi movie <em>Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara</em>.</p>

<p>It has been a similar story for Switzerland. Several Bollywood movies filmed there over the past 50 years have resulted in an Indian tourism <a href="https://houseofswitzerland.org/swissstories/history/bollywoods-long-standing-love-affair-switzerland">love affair</a> with the country. The Swiss tourist board even offers <a href="https://www.myswitzerland.com/en-gb/experiences/bollywood-tour/">Bollywood tours</a> to the various sites featured in Indian cinema.</p>

<p>While only 9% of Indian travellers focus on long-haul destinations in western Europe, Switzerland has been a <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/travel-logistics-and-infrastructure/our-insights/from-india-to-the-world-unleashing-the-potential-of-indias-tourists">top-20 destination</a> for Indian tourists for over a decade.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UNOvmdTYPP4?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="650"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Hundreds of Indian movies and music videos have been filmed in Switzerland.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Other destinations have started using Bollywood actors in their promotional campaigns. Dubai, for example, is promoted by the Indian acting superstar and film producer <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fuSpjxrdhTw">Shah Rukh Khan</a>. And the heartthrob actor <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/services/travel/tourism-new-zealand-ropes-in-sidharth-malhotra-as-brand-ambassador-for-india/articleshow/49270237.cms?from=mdr">Siddharth Malhotra</a> has been New Zealand's brand ambassador since 2015.</p>

<p>By 2040, the number of international tourist departures from India could hit <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/travel-logistics-and-infrastructure/our-insights/from-india-to-the-world-unleashing-the-potential-of-indias-tourists">90 million</a>, not far from the 104 million Chinese tourists who <a href="https://www.economist.com/international/2024/08/20/indian-tourists-are-conquering-the-world">travelled in 2019</a>. However, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/breakingviews/chinese-tourists-return-with-lighter-wallets-2023-05-03/">research</a> suggests that Chinese holidaymakers are increasingly deciding to travel at home, meaning Indian tourists may soon overtake them.</p>

<p>As more people in India flock to airport departure lounges, tourist destinations around the world are jostling for position in the race to take their share.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/237837/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/ross-bennett-cook-1301368">Ross Bennett-Cook</a>, Visiting Lecturer, School of Architecture + Cities, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-westminster-916">University of Westminster</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Ross Bennett-Cook does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/more-indians-than-ever-are-going-on-holiday-abroad-so-where-are-they-heading-and-why-237837">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-05/c15ktq2o_airport-generic_625x300_10_May_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Indian travel market is gigantic, with its middle class now representing 31% of the population]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-rescue-mission-spacex-launch-today-to-bring-home-two-astronauts-stuck-on-iss-6670100]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA To Launch Rescue Mission To Bring Home Sunita Williams, Barry Wilmore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sunita-williams-rescue-mission-spacex-launch-today-to-bring-home-two-astronauts-stuck-on-iss-6670100]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:22:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The National Aeronautics Space Agency (NASA) is all set to launch a mission on September 28 to facilitate the return of astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blogs.nasa.gov/crew-9/2024/09/24/nasa-spacex-shift-crew-9-launch-to-net-sept-28-over-weather-concerns/">The National Aeronautics Space Agency (NASA)</a> is all set to launch a mission on September 28 to facilitate the return of astronauts Sunita Williams and Barry Wilmore. SpaceX is preparing to send a two-person crew to the International Space Station (ISS) where the two astronauts have been stranded since June.</p>

<p>The Crew-9 mission, which marks the ninth operational flight for SpaceX under NASA's Commercial Crew Programme, is scheduled to lift off from Cape Canaveral Space Force Station in Florida at 1:17 PM EDT 1:17 PM EDT (10.47 pm IST).<br />
<br />
Onboard the Crew-9 mission are NASA's Nick Hague, who serves as the commander, and mission specialist Aleksandr Gorbunov from Russia's Roscosmos space agency. If all goes according to plan, the crew is expected to dock with the ISS on September 29, at 5:30 pm EDT (3 am IST on Monday, September 30).<br />
<br />
Usually, <a href="https://www.space.com/spacex-nasa-go-crew-9-astronaut-launch-florida-pad">SpaceX</a>'s Crew Dragon capsules carry four astronauts to the ISS. However, for this mission, two seats will remain unoccupied to facilitate the return of Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams, who have been on the ISS since June 6. They reached the ISS aboard Boeing's Starliner spacecraft, which encountered multiple helium leaks and thruster failures during its docking process.<br />
<br />
After extensive analysis and testing, NASA determined that bringing the astronauts home on the Starliner posed too great a risk. So, on September 6, the agency decided to return the spacecraft uncrewed. On September 28, the <a href="http://https://www.space.com/spacex-crew-9-launch-preview">SpaceX </a>Dragon spacecraft will transport Hague and Gorbunov to the orbiting laboratory for an estimated five-month science mission.<br />
<br />
In the unlikely event that an emergency evacuation of the ISS becomes necessary before Crew-9 arrives, a contingency plan is in place. Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams will use the Crew-8 Dragon capsule, currently docked on the ISS, and are scheduled to depart shortly after Crew-9's arrival. Since Crew-8 already has four assigned astronauts, Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams will utilise temporary seats in the cargo area of the capsule, should an emergency situation arise.<br />
<br />
Once Crew-9 docks, the emergency evacuation plans for Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams will shift to using their newly arrived spacecraft.<br />
<br />
“We're going to find spots for them to fly,” said Ken Bowersox, NASA's Associate Administrator for Space Operations, during a press conference. “We really appreciate how hard it is to give up a mission and wait a little bit longer.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hpp478o8_sunita-williams_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barry Wilmore and Sunita Williams have been on the ISS since June 6. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/came-to-class-to-hurt-somebody-arizona-teenager-stabs-classmate-6668563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Came To Class To Hurt Somebody": Arizona Teenager Stabs Classmate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/came-to-class-to-hurt-somebody-arizona-teenager-stabs-classmate-6668563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:07:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A student at the Arizona State University was hospitalised after being stabbed several times by a classmate. Mara Daffron, 19, was attacked by Kaci Sloan, also 19, who reportedly chose her as an "easier target," reported The New York Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A student at the Arizona State University was hospitalised after being stabbed several times by a classmate. Mara Daffron, 19, was attacked by Kaci Sloan, also 19, who reportedly chose her as an "easier target," reported The New York Post.</p>

<p>This occurred last week, when Sloan, seated in the classroom, suddenly lunged at Daffron and stabbed her twice. Sloan selected Daffron from among two potential victims, believing her to be an easier attack, according to 12 News.</p>

<p>"Kaci Sloan was immediately detained and arrested on suspicion of first-degree attempted murder; aggravated assault with a deadly weapon; interfering with an educational institution; and disorderly conduct. She is being held on a $250,000 cash-only bond," PEOPLE magazine quoted an ASU spokesperson as saying.</p>

<p>Daffron was rushed to hospital, where she underwent surgery for non-life-threatening injuries, said police. She is now recovering, with her family sharing updates about her condition.</p>

<p>Sloan has admitted that she "came to class to hurt somebody" and had been planning the attack since the previous night prior, court documents revealed. The planning included placing the knife that she used in her backpack.</p>

<p>She told the cops she knew the victim's first name and had shared only one class with her this semester.</p>

<p>Daffron reportedly had no idea why she was targeted, nor did she know her attacker prior to the incident.</p>

<p>Her family and neighbours have organised a GoFundMe campaign to assist them during this challenging time.</p>

<p>"We know Mara will come out stronger than ever from this unimaginable attack. We thank everyone who is able to contribute! We will share more updates as we receive them from their family," the GoFundMe campaign states.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/tudnbh9o_mara-daffron-kaci-sloan_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mara Daffron (L) was attacked by Kaci Sloan (R) at Arizona University.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/getting-shorter-going-hungrier-children-in-the-uk-are-living-in-poverty-6669972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Getting Shorter, Going Hungrier": Children In The UK Are Living In Poverty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/getting-shorter-going-hungrier-children-in-the-uk-are-living-in-poverty-6669972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:05:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Children's lives in the UK are changing. They are becoming shorter in height. More of them are going hungry than they were a few years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Children's lives in the UK are changing.</p>

<p>They are <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/children-vitamins-diet-food-poverty-babies-b2564470.html">becoming shorter</a> in height. More of them are <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-9209/">going hungry</a> than they were a few years ago. Recently, more <a href="https://www.nrscotland.gov.uk/news/2024/number-of-births-continues-to-fall#:%7E:text=The%20infant%20death%20rate%20was,the%20final%20quarter%20of%202023.">have died</a> <a href="https://www.ncmd.info/publications/child-death-data-2023/">each year</a> than they did a few years ago. Increased poverty, more destitution and the <a href="https://www.bma.org.uk/what-we-do/population-health/addressing-social-determinants-that-influence-health/cutting-away-at-our-children-s-futures-how-austerity-is-affecting-the-health-of-children-young-people-and-families">effects of ongoing austerity</a> are the clear culprits.</p>

<p>But why did this happen to our children? This rise in child poverty is a change that has not been found to have occurred to the same extent anywhere else in the world, among all the places that the United Nations measures in the same way.<br />
<br />
<strong>Change in child poverty, 2012–14 to 2019–21</strong></p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="Bar chart" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=821&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=821&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=821&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1031&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1031&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618148/original/file-20240909-16-6q8ze4.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=1031&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.unicef.org/globalinsight/media/3291/file/UNICEF-Innocenti-Report-Card-18-Child-Poverty-Amidst-Wealth-2023.pdf">UNICEF Innocenti—Global Office of Research and Foresight (2023) ‘Innocenti Report Card 18: Child poverty in the midst of wealth'</a>, <a class="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">CC BY-NC-ND</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><br />
This graph tells a story of hope and success. In much of Eastern Europe, child poverty has fallen by between as much as a third – and often at least a quarter – in a mere seven years.</p>

<p>But it also shows that child poverty has risen the most in the UK. The poorest fifth of households in the UK are <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/shatterednation/slides_all_files/page5-1053-full.html">poorer than the poorest fifth</a> in most of Eastern Europe. For many people in the UK, this will come as a surprise. Some will refuse to believe it can be this bad.</p>

<p>The evidence for this poverty is seen in the declining heights of five-year-olds since 2010.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Average height of five-year-old boys, 1985–2020</strong></p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="Line graph" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=456&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=456&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=456&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=574&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=574&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618155/original/file-20240909-15-3rxmt6.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=574&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Average height of 5-year-old boys, 1985–2020.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.itv.com/news/2023–06–21/british-children-shorter-thanother-five-year-olds-in-europe">Redrawn by the author from data in Press Association (2023) ‘British children shorter than other five-year-olds in Europe', ITV News, 21 June.</a>, <a class="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">CC BY-NC-ND</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><br />
A 5-year-old in 1990 would have been born in 1985 and their height influenced mostly by nutrition in the years 1985–1990. Those were hard years for the UK: mass poverty resulting from <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/onthisday/hi/dates/stories/january/26/newsid_2506000/2506335.stm">over three million people being out of work</a> in the early 1980s. But the average height of children was still increasing.</p>

<p>It was not until 2010, for those children who had lived between 2005 and 2010, that we first saw heights plateau and then fall, coinciding with the post-2010 austerity years.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/33rn1ngpFIQ?wmode=transparent&amp;start=2" width="650"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">Seven Children: Inequality and Britain's next generation.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>My <a href="http://dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">forthcoming book</a> attempts to make sense of what has happened to the UK: why, in 2024, it is not merely one of the countries in Europe with a high rate of child poverty, but the one country above all others that the UN has singled out as having had the greatest rises in child poverty among all those it surveyed.</p>

<h2>Seven children</h2>

<p>To try to understand more about children's lives in the UK, I constructed <a href="http://dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">seven typical children</a>. I divided all 14 million children living in the UK into seven groups of 2 million, according to the income of their families in 2018 and 2019. I then chose the middle child of each 2 million. I next looked at what had happened to those families between 2018 and 2024.</p>

<p>The graph below shows the annual income of each of <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">the seven households the children were drawn from</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Annual household incomes after tax, benefits and housing costs in the UK, families with children 2019/20</strong></p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=726&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=726&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=726&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=912&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=912&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/618200/original/file-20240909-18-o5cuxv.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=912&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Annual household incomes after tax, benefits and housing costs in the UK, families with children 2019/20: seven typical children marked in colour.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="http://dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">Danny Dorling</a>, <a class="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">CC BY-NC-ND</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><br />
The first thing to note is just how incredibly well-off the children are who are better-off than our <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">seven typical children</a>.</p>

<p>Some 6% of all children in the UK live in households richer than the best-off typical child <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren/page-7/statistics.html">in my analysis</a>. Those 6% of children, the best-off children of all, live in families that each year receive and spend <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren/page-7/statistics.html">a third of all the income</a> in the UK.</p>

<p>These 6% are not typical, and neither are the 6% poorest: those most destitute, those whose families are most likely to use food banks. If you pick seven typical children, equally spaced out across the income scale, then these extremes are not part of what you see.</p>

<p>But four of our <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">typical seven children</a> now live lives that most better-off people would consider to be in poverty. The other three are hardly well-off.</p>

<p>The least well-off are in families struggling to pay bills and making sacrifices others do not have to think about. For instance, whether to save £10 a month, or have insurance against the effects of flood, fire or theft. Increasingly often they cannot afford both.</p>

<p>But even the most well-off of our seven children lives in a family that worries about paying for an annual holiday. That is rare among the most affluent two million families, but possible.</p>

<p>The UK in 2024 demonstrates to the world what living with high inequality means in a once affluent country. It means a few using up far more resources than the vast majority of other children, such as having access to many more school teachers – per child – as compared to the rest, better food, better shelter, more warmth, more toys, better material everything; often more than you might think any child needed.</p>

<p>In future, almost all our children will tell <a href="https://www.dannydorling.org/books/sevenchildren">their stories of growing up in the UK</a> of the 2020s and – hopefully – what changed to make things better. It is hard to imagine them becoming much worse.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238364/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/danny-dorling-113761">Danny Dorling</a>, Halford Mackinder Professor of Geography, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-oxford-1260">University of Oxford</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Danny Dorling does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/getting-shorter-and-going-hungrier-how-children-in-the-uk-live-today-238364">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r2pm0aa8_poverty-generic-child-poverty-generic-pixabay_625x300_28_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An increasing number of children are going hungry in recent years across the UK. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-lebanon-why-is-netanyahu-playing-with-fire-because-he-has-understood-he-can-6669955]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Why Is Israel Playing With Fire? Because It Has Understood It Can]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/israel-lebanon-why-is-netanyahu-playing-with-fire-because-he-has-understood-he-can-6669955]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 16:01:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Already, Israel has demonstrated that in spite of widespread condemnation of its use of disproportionate force in the Gaza Strip, it has been able to stay intent on its course, with the international community incapable of or unwilling to halt its as]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/o5nhgdbo_israel_625x300_28_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Middle East is once again on a boil. Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah has been killed in a strike on Beirut, the Israeli military said today. The flare-up this time is truly alarming and could be apocalyptic in its potential.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Beginning Of The Recent Strikes</strong></h2>

<p>On September 17-18, the world was astonished by what seemed to be back-to-back attacks in Lebanon involving exploding pagers and walkie-talkies belonging mostly to the Iran-backed Hezbollah. The attacks were allegedly an Israeli operation. &nbsp;Almost 30 people lost their lives, with thousands reported injured. Soon after, Israel launched airstrikes on settlements in southern and eastern Lebanon in what it called 'targeted assassinations' to eliminate Hezbollah leaders and operatives. According to estimates from the Lebanese health ministry, more than 1,000 people have died in these strikes, with more than 5,000 injured. Many of them are civilians given how Hezbollah is well-integrated into the local population. A number of other Hezbollah leaders, like Ibrahim Aqil, have been confirmed dead.</p>

<p>To be fair, it was Hezbollah that had begun the attacks on northern &nbsp;Israel in response to Hamas's multipronged strikes in Israel on October 7 last year. Hezbollah's rationale was to open a second front against Israel and force it to declare a ceasefire with Hamas in Gaza.&nbsp;Hundreds of thousands of Israelis in the north of the country have been displaced by Hezbollah's assault.</p>

<h2><strong>The Destruction In Gaza</strong></h2>

<p>Almost a year has passed since the war in Gaza started. Large parts of the enclave have been flattened, much of Hamas degraded, and many of its leaders killed. The overall death toll stands at 40,000; at least a third of them are women and children. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In May this year, Israel launched relentless air strikes in Rafah and followed it up with a ground incursion. Yet, it has not been able to realise its objective of freeing all hostages taken captive by Hamas on October 7. While some have been released, others have died in captivity, and many others continue to be held hostage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>For a large part, Israel's retaliation against Hezbollah had been calculated as it wanted to preempt any large-scale conflagration. However, since July end, when Hezbollah strikes on Israel killed 12 children, its attacks have steadily intensified. Israel's ambassador to the United Nations, Danny Danon, has said that what Israel was doing was conducting "precise strikes" in Lebanon against Hezbollah command centres, weapons stores and leadership.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Why Is Israel Feeling So Confident?</strong></h2>

<p>Hezbollah, after all, is not Hamas. It is entirely dependent on Iran and has a larger, more professional and sophisticated army. It even has seats in the Lebanese parliament. It is battle-hardened and has fought wars with Israel earlier. In 2000, it managed to drive the Israeli Defense Forces out of Southern Lebanon, and in 2006, the group forced it to retreat. The organisation has often been called "a state within a state". &nbsp;While many Lebanese despise the Shiite group - and many would be happy with Nasrallah's elimination as he has brought to Lebanon one disaster after the other while carrying out what they say was the 'Iranian' agenda - within the community, it is admired and has contributed to keeping Syrian President Bashar Al Assad in power in Syria.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In spite of all this, Israel's actions betray a belief that perhaps it can now do to Lebanon what it did to Gaza. After all, Lebanon is a politically dysfunctional state; its currency has collapsed, its economy is in tatters and as per World Bank data, 44% of its population is living in poverty. A war will be catastrophic for the country. Already, Israel has demonstrated that in spite of widespread condemnation of its use of disproportionate force in the Gaza Strip - where it seems Israel is now winding down operations - it has been able to stay intent on its course, with the international community incapable of or unwilling to halt its assault.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Iran Is On The Fence</strong></h2>

<p>Next, Hezbollah's mentor, Iran, is not in a comfortable position either. It's facing both internal and external challenges. In fact, with its direct strikes on Israel in April, Tehran in a way demonstrated that it did not have the appetite for a direct war with Israel, which has both a superior economy and military. Thus, while Iran might not throw its favourite protege under the bus, it may also not be in a position to shore up Hezbollah's arsenal. Also, the numerous recent assassinations - Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh included - point to a breach within the ranks of both Iran and Hezbollah. This is sure to lead to further internal rupture and dissonance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The fact that Iran's new president Masoud Pezeshkian has also declared his intention to cooperate with the West over the nuclear deal is also added motivation for Israel. Pezeshkian perhaps sees a window of opportunity while the Democrats still hold power in Washington. He may not wish to jeopardise this opportunity by rushing to aid Hezbollah.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yet another factor for Israel's emboldening may be the looming US presidential elections. &nbsp;In case of a war breaking out in the region that pits Israel against one or other of its adversaries, there is sure to be bipartisan support for Israel in America. The US has stationed 12 warships in the region, and the IDF just this week announced that the US was disbursing another $8.7 billion in military aid. It's doubtful whether such similar aid will be forthcoming for Iran from any of its friends.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Israel's Actions Have A Cost</strong></h2>

<p>All these factors may have spurred Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, but his actions come at a great cost for Israel too. The Israeli economy is suffering. Foreign investments have dropped, tourism, one of the country's mainstays, has waned, about 46,000 businesses have gone bankrupt, and the country's credit rating has dwindled. On the military front as well, while Israelis still continue to be held captive by Hamas, the IDF has suffered serious losses too. Reports say that around 10,000 reservists have sought mental health support and a significant number failed to show up when called up a second or third time, citing "burnout". Israel's own resources are depleting fast and will need time to be replenished. Nevertheless, the public approval for a war with Lebanon seems much higher than that for its actions in Gaza.&nbsp;Nasrallah's assassination will go a long way in shoring up support for the Netanyahu government.</p>

<p>Beyond all this, however, the bottom line is that there are no permanent military solutions to the conflict in the region because the problem is essentially a political one. Israel may flatten Gaza and it may even go on to repeat that repertoire in Lebanon. It may destroy Hamas and Hezbollah. But the hatred will live on. With time, new avatars of Hamas and Hezbollah will continue to spring up.</p>

<p><em>(Aditi Bhaduri is a journalist and political analyst)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author&nbsp;</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hbkau1l_israel_625x300_28_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-nation-on-alert-after-claiming-it-killed-hezbollah-chief-6669724]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Army Says Nation On Alert After Claiming It Killed Hezbollah Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-army-says-nation-on-alert-after-claiming-it-killed-hezbollah-chief-6669724]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 15:28:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said on Saturday Israel is on high alert for a broader conflict after it claimed to have killed Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah in Beirut, and also said it hoped his reported death will cause the group to change course.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said on Saturday Israel is on high alert for a broader conflict after it claimed to have killed Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah in Beirut, and also said it hoped his reported death will cause the group to change course.</p>

<p>"We hope this will change Hezbollah's actions," Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani said in a media briefing after the military said it had killed Nasrallah.</p>

<p>But he said it would still take time to degrade the Iran-backed Hezbollah's capabilities.</p>

<p>"We've seen Hezbollah carry out attacks against us for a year. It's safe to assume that they are going to continue carrying out their attacks against us or try to," he said.</p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani said that there had been no new instructions given to Israeli civilians regarding home front readiness, as current guidelines already put much of the country on high alert.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vk0hi838_israel-army-afp_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We've seen Hezbollah carry out attacks against us for a year," said Nadav Shoshani. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-moved-to-secure-location-after-israel-says-it-killed-hezbollah-chief-news-agency-reuters-6669649]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader Moved After Israel Claims Hezbollah Chief Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-moved-to-secure-location-after-israel-says-it-killed-hezbollah-chief-news-agency-reuters-6669649]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 15:14:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been transferred to a secure location inside the country with heightened security measures in place, two regional officials briefed by Tehran told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has been transferred to a secure location inside the country with heightened security measures in place, two regional officials briefed by Tehran told Reuters.</p>

<p>The sources said Iran was in constant contact with Lebanon's Hezbollah and other regional proxy groups to determine the next step after Israel announced that it had killed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah in a strike on south Beirut on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/55cn059o_-ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The sources said Iran was in constant contact with Lebanon's Hezbollah. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-the-end-israeli-army-chief-after-hezbollah-chiefs-reported-death-6669645]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Not The End": Israeli Army After Announcing Hezbollah Chief's Death]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-the-end-israeli-army-chief-after-hezbollah-chiefs-reported-death-6669645]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 15:12:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's army chief has vowed to target anyone who poses a threat to Israel after the Israeli Defence Force reported the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's army chief has vowed to target anyone who poses a threat to the country after the Israeli Defence Force said Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah was killed today in a strike.</p>

<p>"This is not the end of our toolbox. The message is simple, anyone&nbsp;who threatens the citizens of Israel -- we will know how to reach them," said Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi in a statement after Israel reported the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-killed-in-strikes-on-beirut-says-israel-army-6669105" target="_blank">killing of Hassan Nasrallah</a>.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hassan Nasrallah will no longer be able to terrorize the world.<br />
<br />
? <a href="https://twitter.com/IAFsite?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IAFsite</a> <a href="https://t.co/6ExxS7ZTK3">pic.twitter.com/6ExxS7ZTK3</a></p>
— Israel Foreign Ministry (@IsraelMFA) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraelMFA/status/1839952354537267511?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hassan-nasrallah-is-dead-this-cleric-is-now-tipped-to-lead-hezbollah-6669637" target="_blank">The 64-year-old Hezbollah chief </a>was killed in a strike on Lebanon's Beirut, claimed Israeli forces. "Nasrallah will no longer be able to terrorize the world,"&nbsp;the Israeli Foreign Ministry said in a post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"The Israeli Defence Force confirms that Hassan Nasrallah, the leader of the Hezbollah terrorist organization and one of its founders, was eliminated yesterday, together with Ali Karki, the Commander of Hezbollah's Southern Front, and additional Hezbollah commanders," the Israeli Foreign Ministry wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Israeli <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IDF</a> confirms that Hassan Nasrallah, the leader of the Hezbollah terrorist organization and one of its founders, was eliminated yesterday, together with Ali Karki, the Commander of Hezbollah's Southern Front, and additional Hezbollah commanders.<br />
<br />
Nasrallah will no… <a href="https://t.co/1ovmoTh183">pic.twitter.com/1ovmoTh183</a></p>
— Israel Foreign Ministry (@IsraelMFA) <a href="https://twitter.com/IsraelMFA/status/1839940751997743150?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The attack on Hassan Nasrallah&nbsp;"was prepared for a long time, executed at the right moment with great precision, and now we are moving forward with careful preparation for the next steps," General Herzi Halevi said.</p>

<p>"Ultimately, I want to emphasise again that we are at full readiness in all of our fronts. All forces, including coordination with other organisations, must ensure very good synchronization and readiness," he added.</p>

<p>Ali Karake, identified by Israel as the commander of Hezbollah's southern front was also killed along with other Hezbollah commanders in the strike, according to a statement by the Israeli army.</p>

<p>The strike was conducted when Hezbollah's senior chain of command was operating from the headquarters and advancing terrorist activities against the citizens of the State of Israel, said the&nbsp;Israeli army.</p>

<p>"During Hassan Nasrallah's 32-year reign as the Secretary-General of Hezbollah, he was responsible for the murder of many Israeli civilians and soldiers, and the planning and execution of thousands of terrorist activities," the Israeli army added.</p>

<p>In recent days, Israel has shifted its military focus from Gaza to Lebanon, where intense bombing has resulted in over 700 deaths and displaced approximately 118,000 people.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/v503gejg_hassan-nasrallah_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In recent days, Israel has shifted its military focus from Gaza to Lebanon. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hassan-nasrallah-is-dead-this-cleric-is-now-tipped-to-lead-hezbollah-6669637]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hassan Nasrallah Is Dead. This Cleric Is Now Tipped To Lead Hezbollah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hassan-nasrallah-is-dead-this-cleric-is-now-tipped-to-lead-hezbollah-6669637]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 15:10:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hassan Nasrallah is dead. The Hezbollah chief's death has now been confirmed by the Iran-backed, Lebanon-based group.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hassan Nasrallah is dead. The Hezbollah chief's death has now been confirmed by the Iran-backed, Lebanon-based group.</p>

<p>This development has sparked significant concern and speculation regarding the future of the militant group. Killing Nasrallah, who has led Hezbollah for 32 years, would deliver a substantial blow to the organisation.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-killed-in-strikes-on-beirut-says-israel-army-6669105#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll">Israel Says Hezbollah Chief Dead: "Will No Longer Terrorise The World"</a></p>

<p>Now that he is out of the picture, who will lead Hezbollah's charge against Israel and what does it mean for the armed group's future?&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Nasrallah's Legacy</strong></h2>

<p>"Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah does not hold any public office, but he is the de facto ruler of Lebanon. He rules by televised speech. The rest of the state (even when there was a president and prime minister), learn the fate of their country and tailor their policies in accordance with what they hear Nasrallah saying," Hussain Abdul-Hussain, veteran journalist, Middle East expert and research fellow at the Foundation For Defense of Democracy in Washington DC, told NDTV.</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-inside-lebanon-politics-hezbollah-iran-and-a-larger-battle-for-hegemony-6588884">Inside Lebanon Politics: Hezbollah, Iran And A Larger Battle For Hegemony</a></p>

<p>Born in 1960 in East Beirut, Hassan Nasrallah's early life was shaped by the Lebanese Civil War, which prompted his family to return to their ancestral village. At 15, he joined the Amal movement, a Shia political and paramilitary group. His educational journey took him to Iraq for Quranic studies, but he returned to Lebanon in 1978 due to government pressures against Shia radicals.</p>

<p>In 1982, following the Israeli invasion, he transitioned from Amal to join Hezbollah, which was formed by Iran's Revolutionary Guards. His leadership began in earnest after the assassination of his predecessor, Abbas al-Musawi, in 1992. Under Nasrallah, Hezbollah transformed from a militia focused on resistance to Israeli occupation into a political force in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Hezbollah's operations in southern Lebanon contributed to Israel's withdrawal in 2000, a momentous event that significantly bolstered Nasrallah's reputation. His opposition to Israel remained a cornerstone of his leadership, as he famously stated, "I don't believe in the state of Israel as a legal state because it was founded on occupation."</p>

<h2><strong>Implications of Nasrallah's Death</strong></h2>

<p>Replacing Nasrallah would present an unprecedented challenge, especially given Israeli military successes that have already decimated Hezbollah's leadership structure. The loss of Nasrallah would compound these issues, as the group faces questions about its internal security following the assassination of several key commanders and the recent pager blast attacks the shook the group across Lebanon. While Hezbollah is not expected to collapse entirely if Nasrallah were to die, his removal would undoubtedly damage the group's morale and serve as a potent symbol of Israel's military dominance.</p>

<p>"Hezbollah will not collapse if Nasrallah is killed or incapacitated, but this will be a major blow to the group's morale. It would also underline Israel's security and military superiority and access," Analyst Lina Khatib of the Chatham House Policy Institute said as quoted by news agency Reuters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The potential ramifications extend beyond morale; they may also affect Hezbollah's military capabilities.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has engaged in a year-long exchange of fire with Israel across the Lebanese border, which has escalated into its worst conflict since 2006. Hezbollah increased its rocket fire into Israel since the October 7 attack on Israel by the Palestinian group Hamas. In the aftermath of the recent Beirut airstrike, Hezbollah launched several attacks on Israeli positions, indicating an effort to demonstrate its operational capacity despite the ongoing Israeli offensive.</p>

<h2><strong>A Leadership Vacuum</strong></h2>

<p>The question of succession looms large. Any new leader would need to be acceptable to both Hezbollah's internal factions and its Iranian backers. Currently, Hashem Safieddine is viewed as the likely heir to Nasrallah.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Safieddine, who oversees Hezbollah's political affairs and is a member of the group's Jihad Council, is also Nasrallah's cousin and shares a clerical background. The US State Department designated him a terrorist in 2017.</p>

<p>Nasrallah had been grooming Safieddine for leadership through various positions within the organisation. His familial ties, physical resemblance to Nasrallah, and religious status would all contribute to his potential leadership.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0hj10n6g_hassan-nasrallah-getty-_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hassan Nasrallah's political career began at the age of 15.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-killed-in-strikes-on-beirut-says-israel-army-6669105]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Chief Killed In Israel Strike: "Will No Longer Terrorise The World"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-chief-hassan-nasrallah-killed-in-strikes-on-beirut-says-israel-army-6669105]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 13:41:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah was killed in a strike on Beirut, the Israeli military said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah was killed in a strike on Beirut, the Israeli military said today.&nbsp;A source close to Hezbollah told news agency AFP that communication with the 64-year-old Nasrallah was lost since Friday night.</p>

<p>"Hassan Nasrallah is dead," military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Nadav Shoshani announced on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="in">Hassan Nasrallah is dead.</p>
— LTC Nadav Shoshani (@LTC_Shoshani) <a href="https://twitter.com/LTC_Shoshani/status/1839938066653364274?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Israeli strikes targeted dozens of Hezbollah sites in eastern and southern Lebanon following intense rocket fire by the group into northern Israel. Israeli jets bombarded Hezbollah strongholds in southern Beirut overnight, flattening several residential buildings.</p>

<p>"Hassan Nasrallah will no longer be able to terrorise the world," the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) said in a statement.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Hassan Nasrallah will no longer be able to terrorize the world.</p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1839937408587968917?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 28, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"This is not the end of our toolbox. The message is simple, anyone who threatens the citizens of Israel -- we will know how to reach them," Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said in a statement.</p>

<p>This wave of retaliatory strikes occurred just hours after Hezbollah claimed responsibility for launching rockets into northern Israel. One such attack targeted the kibbutz Kabri using Fadi-1 rockets, which Hezbollah stated was in defence of Lebanon against Israeli "barbaric" aggression.</p>

<p>Nasrallah, who holds immense power in Lebanon, particularly among his Shiite supporters, is widely seen as the only figure capable of waging war or brokering peace.</p>

<p>The 64-year-old's daughter Zainab was killed in one of the airstrikes targeting Hezbollah strongholds in southern Beirut, Israel's Channel 12 reported, however, there has been no confirmation from Hezbollah or Lebanese media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nasrallah was rumoured to have been killed in 2006 following Israel's invasion of Lebanon. However, the Shiite leader reemerged days later unhurt. The Israeli strikes also killed Ali Karake, commander of Hezbollah's southern front, and other Hezbollah members.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"During Hassan Nasrallah's 32-year reign as the Secretary-General of Hezbollah, he was responsible for the murder of many Israeli civilians and soldiers, and the planning and execution of thousands of terrorist activities," an Israeli statement read. &nbsp;"He was responsible for directing and executing terrorist attacks around the world in which civilians of various nationalities were murdered. Nasrallah was the central decision-maker and the strategic leader of the organisation."</p>

<p>Air raid sirens were heard across northern Israel, signalling an imminent threat from rockets launched across the Lebanese border. According to Israeli military reports, two surface-to-surface missiles were fired from Lebanon, one falling in an open area, while the other was intercepted.</p>

<p>Lebanon's health ministry ordered the evacuation of hospitals in Beirut's southern suburbs, bracing for further escalation. The ministry urged unaffected hospitals to stop admitting non-emergency patients to make room for those being relocated from the conflict-hit areas.</p>

<p>The Israeli bombing of Lebanon has killed more than 700 people and displaced around 118,000.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hc62ic48_hassan-nasrallah-getty-_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-couple-kicked-off-plane-for-indulging-in-sexual-activity-6668932]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Couple Kicked Off Plane For Indulging In "Sexual Activity"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-couple-kicked-off-plane-for-indulging-in-sexual-activity-6668932]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 13:10:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Both Bradley, 22, and Antonia, 20, pleaded guilty this week to a charge of outraging public decency by committing a sexual act in a public place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British couple recently had their court hearing after being kicked off from an EasyJet flight in March for a lewd act. Bradley Smith and Antonia Sullivan were caught in the act while engaging in a sexual act in public view, leading to their escort of the flight.</p>

<p>The couple was returning to Bristol from a holiday in Tenerife, Spain, on March 3 when multiple witnesses reported their inappropriate behaviour to the crew. During the 7 a.m. flight, Bradley sat in seat 16A while Antonia occupied 16B.</p>

<p>According to reports from British newspaper <em>The Sun</em>, a fellow passenger in seat 16C was among three witnesses to their NSFW act, along with a mother and daughter sitting in the row behind them.</p>

<p>Witnesses stated that shortly after takeoff, Bradley asked Antonia to perform a sexual act. They then draped clothing over Bradley's lap and began their explicit actions on the crowded flight.</p>

<p>"After a few minutes, the witness noticed that the couple had rearranged some coats over Smith's lap, followed by vigorous hand movements beneath the coat," prosecutor Maree Doyle told Bristol magistrates' court.</p>

<p>"The witness next to them could see what was happening, as could a mother and teenage daughter seated behind the couple," the prosecutor added.</p>

<p>When the angry mother alerted the cabin crew, Antonia initially claimed she was merely rubbing her boyfriend's leg. However, the couple was eventually escorted off the plane by police for questioning.</p>

<p>Both Bradley, 22, and Antonia, 20, pleaded guilty this week to a charge of outraging public decency by committing a sexual act in a public place.</p>

<p>They were ordered to pay 100 pounds (approximately Rs 11,000) as compensation to each of the three witnesses. Additionally, Bradley was sentenced to complete 300 hours of community service, while Antonia received 270 hours.</p>

<p>Judge Lynne Matthews chastised the couple for their explicit behaviour in public, stating, "You showed no regard for the feelings of other passengers. There was a child sitting behind you who was able to see what was happening.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Who do you think you are, and what right do you believe you have to behave in such a way in full view of people on that flight?" the judge questioned.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cu8hkg8o_airplane-generic_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple was eventually escorted off the plane by police for questioning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-in-russian-attacks-on-medical-centre-says-ukraine-6668898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Killed In Russian Attacks On Medical Centre, Says Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-killed-in-russian-attacks-on-medical-centre-says-ukraine-6668898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 13:02:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two consecutive Russian attacks on a medical centre in Sumy in northeastern Ukraine on Saturday morning killed six people, Ukraine's interior minister said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two consecutive Russian attacks on a medical centre in Sumy in northeastern Ukraine on Saturday morning killed six people, Ukraine's interior minister said.</p>

<p>"The first attack killed 1 person and damaged the ceilings of several floors of the hospital. The evacuation of patients and staff began," Ihor Klymenko said on Telegram.</p>

<p>As people were being evacuated, the Russians struck again, killing a further five people, he said.</p>

<p>Attacks on Sumy city and the Sumy region have become much more frequent since Ukrainian forces launched an operation in Russia's neighbouring Kursk region in August and captured dozens of settlements.</p>

<p>Sumy city is located just 32 km (20 miles) from the Russian border and Russian forces have been attacking the region and the city with drones and guided bombs.</p>

<p>Klymenko did not specify what weapons were used in Saturday's attacks but the regional administration said the strike was carried out by drones.</p>

<p>Ukrainian air forces earlier on Saturday said its troops shot down 69 of 73 drones during an overnight Russian attack that included two ballistic and two cruise missiles.</p>

<p>About 15 Russian attack drones were destroyed by air defences on the outskirts and in the capital Kyiv, the military administration there said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukrainian air forces earlier on Saturday said its troops shot down 69 of 73 drones. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-revelations-about-princess-diana-rumours-on-harrys-biological-father-6668803]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Revelations About Princess Diana, Rumours On Harry's "Biological Father"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-revelations-about-princess-diana-rumours-on-harrys-biological-father-6668803]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 12:49:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Princess Diana's hairdresser has weighed in on the controversy surrounding Prince Harry and her riding instructor James Hewitt.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After years of rumours and speculations that Princess Diana's riding instructor James Hewitt, and not King Charles, is the biological father of Prince Harry, a new memoir has shed some light on the nature of their relationship. For years, a few similarities between Hewitt and Harry -- ginger hair and freckles -- led to such rumours.<br />
<br />
Richard Dalton, Diana's hairdresser, has now weighed in on the controversy and even detailed his friendship with the late Princess in a new memoir, “It's All About the Hair”.<br />
<br />
“It's not possible,” Dalton told <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/entertainment/princess-dianas-friend-devastating-prince-harry-paternity-rumors-not-possible">Fox News Digital</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“It was tough... Harry was already born a while before her relationship with Hewitt. And I don't think it's possible.” To support his statement, Dalton claimed even Princess Diana's brother and sister had "bright red hair".<br />
<br />
“Harry and the Spencer family have red hair. Charles, Diana's brother, had bright red hair when he was (in) college,” he said, adding he used to cut his hair back then.<br />
<br />
He added that Sarah, Diana's sister, also has bright red hair, while her other sister Jane was "more or less the same colouring as Diana."<br />
<br />
In his book, Dalton said that Diana “used to get very upset” over the reports of Hewitt being called Harry's father, adding that the "red hair was a trait from the Spencer family".<br />
<br />
Diana and Hewitt met each other for the first time in 1986, two years after Harry's birth in 1984, according to reports.<br />
<br />
Harry was born “long before Diana even met James Hewitt,” Dalton wrote in his book, adding the two had a "love affair," which lasted three years between 1989 and 1991.&nbsp;Both Harry and Hewitt have addressed the rumour in the past.<br />
<br />
Last year, Harry sued an outlet for apparently using unlawful techniques "on an industrial scale" to score on his life.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"Numerous newspapers had reported a rumour that my biological father was James Hewitt, a man my mother had a relationship with after I was born," Harry said in a written statement.<br />
<br />
"At the time of this article and others similar to it, I wasn't actually aware that my mother hadn't met Major Hewitt until after I was born," he added.<br />
<br />
In 2002, Hewitt himself addressed the gossip and said, "There really is no possibility whatsoever that I am Harry's father. I can understand the interest, but Harry was already walking by the time my relationship with Diana began."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ik2s9afo_princess-diana-prince-harry_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-downed-69-drones-2-missiles-in-overnight-russian-attack-6668506]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Says Downed 69 Drones, 2 Missiles In Overnight Russian Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-says-downed-69-drones-2-missiles-in-overnight-russian-attack-6668506]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 11:56:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine shot down 69 of 73 drones during an overnight Russian attack that included two ballistic and two cruise missiles, the Ukrainian air force said on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine shot down 69 of 73 drones during an overnight Russian attack that included two ballistic and two cruise missiles, the Ukrainian air force said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Ukrainian forces downed the two cruise missiles, the air force said in a statement on the Telegram messaging app.</p>

<p>About 15 Russian attack drones were destroyed by air defence forces on the outskirts and in the capital Kyiv, the military administration there said.</p>

<p>It said debris was reported falling in one district of the city.</p>

<p>"As a result, a non-residential building was damaged. No information on casualties was received," the administration said on Telegram.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[No information on casualties was received, Ukraine said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-estimates-damages-of-3-31-billion-from-typhoon-yagi-report-6668447]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vietnam Estimates Damages Of $3.31 Billion From Typhoon Yagi: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-estimates-damages-of-3-31-billion-from-typhoon-yagi-report-6668447]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 11:43:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Asia's strongest storm this year, Typhoon Yagi, caused damages estimated at 81.5 trillion dong ($3.31 billion) across northern Vietnam, or twice as much as previous estimates, state media said on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asia's strongest storm this year, Typhoon Yagi, caused damages estimated at 81.5 trillion dong ($3.31 billion) across northern Vietnam, or twice as much as previous estimates, state media said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The typhoon, which killed 299 with 34 missing, devastated export-oriented industrial hubs, destroying factories and facilities, besides flooding farmland, damaging homes, and tearing up a bridge.</p>

<p>"The total economic damage is initially estimated at over 81.5 trillion dong, with most damage triggered by landslides and flash floods," state-run Vietnam News Agency quoted Agriculture Minister Le Minh Hoan as saying.</p>

<p>The figure exceeds a preliminary estimate of $1.6 billion made this month by the planning ministry that threatened to chip 0.15 percentage point from a forecast for economic growth of 6.8% to 7% this year.</p>

<p>Hoan urged authorities to help people resume production while ensuring supplies and holding down prices, as farm and agricultural land were among the areas hit hardest.</p>

<p>Live pig prices in Vietnam have risen steadily since Typhoon Yagi and subsequent flooding affected several pig farms, Reuters has reported.</p>

<p>On Thursday, rating agency S&amp;P Global said Vietnamese banks' profitability would be hit because of typhoon debt relief measures ordered by the central bank.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f15fbpp8_vietnam-floods_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Live pig prices in Vietnam have risen steadily since Typhoon Yagi. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vows-to-fix-us-immigration-system-donald-trump-says-this-is-bad-timing-6667904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Vows To Fix US Immigration System, Trump Says "This Is Bad Timing"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vows-to-fix-us-immigration-system-donald-trump-says-this-is-bad-timing-6667904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 28 Sep 2024 10:06:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has vowed to impose tougher security measures at the border and fix America's broken immigration system]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has vowed to impose tougher security measures at the border and fix America's broken immigration system, as she sought to counter frequent political attacks on the issue from her Republican rival Donald Trump ahead of the November election.</p>

<p>Vice President Harris' comments came during her visit to the US-Mexico border in Douglas, Arizona, on Friday.</p>

<p>Despite taking a hardline stance on border security, Harris said she also supports a "pathway to citizenship" for undocumented migrants currently in the US.</p>

<p>"As President, I will work with Congress to create, at long last, a pathway to citizenship for hardworking immigrants who have been here for years," Harris said.</p>

<p>Harris was in Arizona to get a first-hand assessment of the security situation at the southern borders.</p>

<p>Slamming former President Trump, she said politicians have refused to come together and fix the broken immigration system.</p>

<p>Illegal immigration is an issue that Americans have grown increasingly worried about in recent years amid record levels of migrant crossings at the southern border.</p>

<p>"Well, as President, I will put politics aside to fix our immigration system and find solutions to problems which have persisted for far too long...These issues are highly consequential for our nation," she said.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, will take on Trump, 78, in the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>Observing that the contrast in the 2024 election is clear, Harris said it is a choice between common sense solutions and the same old political games.</p>

<p>"In the four years that Donald Trump was President, he did nothing to fix our broken immigration system. He did not solve the shortage of immigration judges and border agents or create lawful pathways into our nation. He did nothing to address our outdated asylum system. And did not work with other governments in our hemisphere to deal with what is clearly a regional challenge," she alleged.</p>

<p>Harris slammed Trump for wanting to run on a problem instead of fix a problem.</p>

<p>"The American people deserve a President who cares more about border security than playing political games," she said.</p>

<p>As a former border state Attorney General, Harris noted that she understands what security and enforcing the law at the border means, prosecuting transnational criminal organizations for the trafficking of guns, drugs, and human beings.</p>

<p>As such she unveiled her approach to "target the entire global fentanyl supply chain" to "significantly reduce the flow of precursor chemicals from China" and protect Americans from the "unimaginable destruction" it is causing.</p>

<p>"On behalf of all communities across our nation that want to see these problems solved I say: We cannot accept Donald Trump's failure to lead. We should not permit scapegoating instead of solutions. Or rhetoric instead of results," she said.</p>

<p>In his remarks earlier in the day, Trump hammered Harris for having an unsecured border.</p>

<p>"This is bad timing for Kamala to show up today at the border. She didn't go there for four years. Today, she shows up," Trump said.</p>

<p>Trump said Harris had betrayed her oath.</p>

<p>"She let our cities fail violent gangs. She let our American sons and daughters be raped and murdered at the hands of vicious monsters. She let American communities be conquered. You go out to Aurora in Colorado, where they're taking over with AK-47s. They're taking over real estate. Kamala turned cherished small towns into blighted refugee camps," he said.</p>

<p>"What Kamala Harris has done is unforgivable. It's a crime what she did. It's got to be criminal. There's no greater act of disloyalty than to extinguish the sovereignty of your own nation, and that's what she's done. She's ruined our nation. She's ruined our nation," Trump alleged.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a34kj30g_kamala-harris-donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris was in Arizona to get a first-hand assessment of the security situation at the borders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>