<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:51:11 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrian-billionaire-richard-lugner-dies-at-91-2-months-after-marrying-sixth-time-6328654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Austrian Billionaire Dies At 91, 2 Months After Marrying Sixth Time]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrian-billionaire-richard-lugner-dies-at-91-2-months-after-marrying-sixth-time-6328654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:07:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Lugner was a successful entrepreneur who built his fortune in construction and real estate and was also known for his flashy lifestyle and celebrity connections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Richard Lugner, an Austrian billionaire known for bringing celebrities like Kim Kardashian and Pamela Anderson to the Vienna Opera Ball, has died at 91. According to<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/billionaire-richard-lugner-dead-91-months-after-marrying-sixth-wife-8693930"> People,</a></em>&nbsp;he died at his villa in Vienna on Monday, just two months after marrying his sixth wife, Simone Reilander.&nbsp;Emergency services rushed to his home but were unable to revive him.</p>

<p>As per AFP, Mr Lugner had been battling various health issues and underwent surgery in recent months. Despite his health challenges, he still managed to attend the prestigious Vienna Opera Ball in February with&nbsp;Priscilla Presley,&nbsp;ex-wife of Elvis Presley.</p>

<p>Austrian chancellor Karl Nehammer paid a touching tribute to him on X and wrote, ''Richard Lugner was a successful entrepreneur and a dazzling personality. An Austrian original who never lost his way. May he rest in peace!''</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="de">Richard Lugner war ein erfolgreicher Unternehmer und eine schillernde Persönlichkeit. Ein österreichisches Original, das sich nie verbogen hat. Er ruhe in Frieden! <a href="https://t.co/tqp6Zau9fJ">pic.twitter.com/tqp6Zau9fJ</a></p>
— Karl Nehammer (@karlnehammer) <a href="https://twitter.com/karlnehammer/status/1822909532558835724?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><strong>Who was Richard Lugner?</strong></p>

<p>Mr Lugner was a successful Austrian entrepreneur who built his fortune in construction and real estate and was also known for his flashy lifestyle and celebrity connections.&nbsp;Mr Lugner's celebrity guests included the likes of Joan Collins, Jane Fonda, Pamela Anderson, Kim Kardashian and Paris Hilton, among others.</p>

<p>One of his most enduring legacies is the iconic Lugner City shopping centre in Vienna, which he built in 1990.&nbsp;The complex shared a touching tribute to its founder on Facebook, referring to him as ''our mortar and above all our beloved boss.''&nbsp;</p>

<p>The billionaire also harboured political ambitions and ran twice in the Austrian presidential elections as an independent candidate, once in 1998 and again in 2016, as per<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.euronews.com/2024/08/12/austrian-entrepreneur-richard-lugner-dies-at-the-age-of-91"> Euro News.&nbsp;</a></em></p>

<p>Notably, his&nbsp;death came just two months after his marriage to Simone Reilander, 42. The couple exchanged vows in an intimate ceremony at Vienna City Hall on June 1, surrounded by close friends and family. At the wedding, Mr Lugner declared, "It will be the last marriage,''&nbsp;People reported, quoting a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.rnd.de/promis/richard-lugner-heiratet-simone-reilaender-KJNCTMGNCVLUNOI37RUEOHT5EQ.html">local media report.</a></p>

<p>He was previously married to Christine Gmeiner (​1961-1978), Cornelia Laufersweiler​​ (​1979-1983), Susanne Dietrich (1984-1989), Christina Lugner (1990-2007), as well as&nbsp;Playboy&nbsp;model and actress Cathy Schmitz (2014-2016).</p>

<p>He leaves behind four children from his previous marriages. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7lj8j81o_richard-lugner_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Lugner was a successful entrepreneur who built his fortune in construction and real estate]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-opens-murder-case-against-ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-6327917]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Court Opens Murder Case Against Ex-PM Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-opens-murder-case-against-ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-6327917]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:20:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Bangladesh opened a murder investigation into ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina and six top figures in her administration Tuesday over the police killing of a man during civil unrest last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in Bangladesh opened a murder investigation into ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina and six top figures in her administration Tuesday over the police killing of a man during civil unrest last month.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, fled by helicopter to neighbouring India a week ago, where she remains, as protesters flooded Dhaka's streets in a dramatic end to her iron-fisted tenure.</p>

<p>More than 450 people were killed during the weeks of unrest leading up to her toppling.</p>

<p>"A case has been filed against Sheikh Hasina and six more," said Mamun Mia, a lawyer who brought the case on behalf of a private citizen.</p>

<p>He added that the Dhaka Metropolitan Court had ordered police to accept "the murder case against the accused persons", the first step in a criminal investigation under Bangladeshi law.</p>

<p>Mia's filing with the court also named Hasina's former home minister Asaduzzaman Khan and Obaidul Quader, the general secretary of Hasina's Awami League party.</p>

<p>It also names four top police officers appointed by Hasina's government who have since vacated their posts.</p>

<p>The case accuses the seven of responsibility for the death of a grocery store owner who was shot dead on July 19 by police violently suppressing protests.</p>

<p>The Daily Star newspaper reported that the case was brought on behalf of Amir Hamza Shatil, a resident of the neighbourhood where the shooting happened and a "well-wisher" of the victim.</p>

<p><strong>- 'We don't deny this' -</strong></p>

<p>Hasina's government was accused of widespread human rights abuses, including the extrajudicial killing of thousands of her political opponents.</p>

<p>Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus returned from Europe three days after Hasina's ouster to head a temporary administration facing the monumental challenge of steering democratic reforms.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for his pioneering work in microfinance, and is credited with helping millions of Bangladeshis out of grinding poverty.</p>

<p>He took office as "chief adviser" to a caretaker administration -- all fellow civilians bar home minister Sakhawat Hossain, a retired brigadier general -- and has said he wants to hold elections "within a few months".</p>

<p>Hossain said on Monday that the government had no intention of banning Hasina's Awami League, which played a pivotal role in the country's independence movement.</p>

<p>"The party has made many contributions to Bangladesh -- we don't deny this," he told reporters on Monday.</p>

<p>"When the election comes, (they should) contest the elections."</p>

<p>AFP has contacted the caretaker administration for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/es5ieto_sheikh-hasina_625x300_11_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina's government was accused of widespread human rights abuses. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-very-grim-5-year-forecast-very-grim-s-jaishankars-forecast-amid-global-military-economic-tension-6327873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar's 5-Year Prediction Amid West Asia War Fears, US Election]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/s-jaishankar-very-grim-5-year-forecast-very-grim-s-jaishankars-forecast-amid-global-military-economic-tension-6327873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:15:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar has painted a bleak picture of where the world might be in five years, warning of a "very grim forecast" given military tension in West Asia, between Ukraine and Russia, and in Southeast Asia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/s-jaishankar" target="_blank">S Jaishankar</a> has painted a bleak picture of where the world might be in five years, warning of a "very grim forecast" given military tension in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/middle-east" target="_blank">West Asia</a>, between <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/russia-ukraine-war" target="_blank">Ukraine and Russia</a>, and in Southeast Asia, as well as economic challenges and the spectre of climate change.</p>

<p>The possibility of such a future "makes the case" for a stronger relationship between India and the United States, Mr Jaishankar said as much, if not all, of the world waits on the outcome of November's US presidential election many believe will be the second coming of Donald Trump.</p>

<p>"I am an optimistic person and generally tend to think of solutions to problems rather than the problems that come out of solutions. But I would say, with a great deal of sobriety, that we are going through an exceptionally difficult period," Mr Jaishankar said Tuesday at an event in Delhi.</p>

<p>"... (and) I have a very grim forecast for the next five years... you see happening in the Middle East, in Ukraine, in Southeast and East Asia, and the continued impact of COVID, which those of us who have come out of it take for granted... but many have not come out of it," Mr Jaishankar said.</p>

<p>The reference to tension in the Middle East, or West Asia, was underlined Monday by the United States and its European allies calling on Iran to "stand down" as fears mount of yet another a full-scale war.</p>

<p><strong>READ |</strong>&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/west-tells-iran-to-stand-down-israel-attacks-threats-as-war-fears-mount-6324363" target="_blank">US, European Allies Tell Iran To "Stand Down" Israel Attack Threats</a></p>

<p>This follows Israel's attack on the Gaza. Iran and its Lebanese ally, Hezbollah, have vowed revenge for the killing of the Hamas' political leader and a Hezbollah commander.</p>

<p>India - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/explained-indias-stand-amid-threat-of-open-war-between-iran-israel-5440444" target="_blank">caught in a tight spot between two friendly nations</a> - has advised both sides to exercise restraint and resolved all issues with "dialogue and diplomacy", Mr Jaishankar's office said in April.</p>

<p>In today's comments Mr Jaishankar built on the threats posed by military conflict to the world and warned this would spill over into economic challenges, such as rising fuel and fertiliser prices precipitated last year by Russia's invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>"The kind of economic challenges you see in the world... you see more and more countries struggling. Trade is getting difficult, there are forex shortages... so, you know, disruptions of various kinds," he said, also referring to concerns over increased pirate attacks in the Red Sea by Iran-aligned Houthi militia targeting commercial ships in a 'show of solidarity' with Palestinians in Gaza.</p>

<p>"What was happening in the Red Sea (and) climate events... are no longer just news... they have globally disruptive consequences and sometimes entire regions are basically made dysfunctional."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Delhi | On being asked how he sees the world today, EAM Dr S Jaishankar says, "...We are going through an exceptionally difficult period. If I were to say give a 5-year forecast, then it would be a grim forecast. And I think the answers are there, you see what is… <a href="https://t.co/JVgWwetsco">pic.twitter.com/JVgWwetsco</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1823237137271054837?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"This makes the case for India-US ties... not just about treaties (but) much more..." he said.</p>

<p>However, Mr Jaishankar refused to get drawn into a discussion on the US election.</p>

<p>"We don't comment on other countries' elections. The US will give its verdict (and) we have every confidence, based on the past 20 years, we can work with the President... whoever he or she will be."</p>

<p>The 2024 US presidential election will see Vice President Kamala Harris, a late pick for the Democrats after President Joe Biden, the first (and contentious) choice, stood down. Ms Harris faces the returning and twice-impeached Donald Trump, the Republican candidate bidding for a second term.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k2g94n8_jaishankar_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar was speaking at an event in Delhi (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-opens-murder-case-against-sheikh-hasina-6327648]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Court Opens Murder Case Against Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-opens-murder-case-against-sheikh-hasina-6327648]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:47:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A court in Bangladesh opened a murder investigation into ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina and six top figures in the previous government over the police killing of a man during civil unrest last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A court in Bangladesh opened a murder investigation into ousted ex-premier Sheikh Hasina and six top figures in the previous government over the police killing of a man during civil unrest last month.</p>

<p>Mamun Mia, a lawyer who brought the case on behalf of a private citizen, said the court in Dhaka had ordered police to accept "the murder case against the accused persons", the first step in a criminal investigation under Bangladeshi law.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina and six top figures in the previous government face murder case. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attack-on-israel-imminent-us-intelligence-issues-big-warning-6327647]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Attack On Israel Imminent? US Intelligence Issues Big Warning]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attack-on-israel-imminent-us-intelligence-issues-big-warning-6327647]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:47:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran or its proxies are "increasingly likely" to launch an attack on Israel in the upcoming days, the White House warned, citing intelligence.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran or its proxies are "increasingly likely" to launch an attack on Israel in the upcoming days, the White House <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/08/12/world/israel-iran-hamas-gaza-war ">warned</a>, citing intelligence. The potential attack could "happen as soon as this week," spokesperson John F Kirby announced. The warning comes despite the Israeli military's reported "peak readiness" in anticipation of a retaliatory attack.</p>

<p>The Middle East is on high alert after Iran pledged to retaliate against Israel for two recent strikes. On July 31, Israel assassinated Hamas leader Ismael Haniyeh in Tehran, followed by an airstrike on Hezbollah's senior commander, Fuad Shukr, in Lebanon.</p>

<p>As tensions simmer, five world leaders, including US President Joe Biden, urged Iran to "stand down", issuing a joint statement supporting ceasefire efforts between Israel and Hamas. The US, UK, France, Germany and Italy are working to de-escalate tensions and prevent further violence.</p>

<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz took direct steps to address the crisis, each contacting Iran's newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian to control this military escalation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Discussions on a ceasefire, mediated by Egypt and Qatar, are expected to resume on Thursday. However, the White House spokesperson stated that if Iran were to launch an attack, these discussions might face delays.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Israeli military has increased patrols over neighbouring Lebanon and continued to strike targets daily. Military spokesperson Daniel Hagari announced increased air patrols over Lebanon, home to Hezbollah, and ongoing strikes on targets to "remove threats".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) Chief of Staff, Herzi Halevi, conducted a situational assessment with top military leaders, focusing on maintaining a high level of readiness for both "offence and defence."</p>

<p>The US Pentagon has also reinforced its commitment to the region. Pentagon spokesman General Patrick Ryder confirmed that Secretary of Defense Lloyd J Austin III ordered the deployment of the guided-missile submarine USS Georgia to the Middle East, alongside additional combat aircraft and missile-defence ships.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j630f33g_israeliran-conflict_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkish-woman-arrested-for-criticising-instagram-ban-insulting-tayyip-erdogan-6327379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turkish Woman Arrested For Criticising Instagram Ban, Insulting Erdogan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkish-woman-arrested-for-criticising-instagram-ban-insulting-tayyip-erdogan-6327379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:09:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Turkish court on Monday ordered the arrest of a woman on charges of inciting hatred and insulting the president after she criticised a ban on social media platform Instagram, broadcaster Haberturk and other media said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Turkish court on Monday ordered the arrest of a woman on charges of inciting hatred and insulting the president after she criticised a ban on the social media platform Instagram, broadcaster Haberturk and other media said.</p>

<p>Turkey blocked access to Instagram on August 2 for failing to comply with its "laws and rules" and public sensitivities. It removed the ban on Saturday, after it said the Meta Platforms-owned app agreed to cooperate with the authorities to address the government's concerns.</p>

<p>In an interview posted on a YouTube channel last week, when the app was still blocked, the woman was one of several passers-by who were asked what they thought about the ban.</p>

<p>"This is wrong. The president cannot ban Instagram as he wishes," the woman said. She also criticised President Tayyip Erdogan and those who supported the ban.</p>

<p>Meta did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the arrest.</p>

<p>Monday's arrest, ordered by a local court in the western city of Izmir, came after the head of Turkey's broadcasting watchdog RTUK criticised street interviews aired on social media, saying they "manipulate public opinion".</p>

<p>The Instagram access ban came after a top Turkish official accused the social media platform of blocking posts expressing condolences over the assassination of Ismail Haniyeh, a leader of the Palestinian operative group Hamas.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestinian-freed-during-truce-killed-by-israeli-forces-in-west-bank-6327360]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Freed During Gaza Ceasefire Killed By Israeli Forces In West Bank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/palestinian-freed-during-truce-killed-by-israeli-forces-in-west-bank-6327360]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 14:04:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Palestinian prisoners watchdog said Tuesday that a man shot dead by Israeli forces in the occupied West Bank the previous day had been freed during the November truce in the Gaza war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Palestinian prisoners watchdog said Tuesday that a man shot dead by Israeli forces in the occupied West Bank the previous day had been freed during the November truce in the Gaza war.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Prisoners' Club said the 18-year-old had been released on November 25 during the one-week truce that saw scores of Palestinian prisoners exchanged for dozens of Israeli hostages held in Gaza since October 7.</p>

<p>The Palestinian health ministry in Ramallah said Tariq Ziad Abdul Rahim Daoud was killed "by the occupation forces' bullets near the town of Azzun, east of Qalqilya", in the northern West Bank, on Monday.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the alleged attacker had "fired at an Israeli civilian who was in the city" of Qalqilya, despite Israel forbidding its citizens from visiting Palestinian built-up areas.</p>

<p>The Israeli civilian was wounded along with two Palestinians, the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Hamas later issued a statement mourning the death of Tariq Daoud and claiming he was a member of its armed wing.</p>

<p>Violence has surged in the West Bank since Hamas's unprecedented October 7 attack on Israel triggered war in Gaza. At least 619 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli troops or settlers, according to an AFP tally based on Palestinian official figures.</p>

<p>During the same period, at least 18 Israelis, including soldiers, have been killed in Palestinian attacks in the territory, according to Israeli official figures.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/dl1tdeb_israel-palestine-war_625x300_08_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[At least 619 Palestinians have been killed by Israeli troops or settlers. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-algorithm-analyses-tongue-to-predict-diabetes-stroke-with-98-accuracy-6327124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Algorithm Analyses Tongue To Predict Diabetes, Stroke With 98% Accuracy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-algorithm-analyses-tongue-to-predict-diabetes-stroke-with-98-accuracy-6327124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:37:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers have developed a novel computer algorithm that can predict various diseases like diabetes or stroke, just by analysing the colour of the human tongue with 98 per cent accuracy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Researchers have developed a novel computer algorithm that can predict various diseases like diabetes or stroke, just by analysing the colour of the human tongue with 98 per cent accuracy.</p>

<p>The imaging system developed by Middle Technical University (MTU) and the University of South Australia (UniSA) in Australia can diagnose conditions such as diabetes, stroke, anaemia, asthma, liver and gallbladder issues, Covid-19, and other vascular and gastrointestinal diseases.</p>

<p>"The colour, shape, and thickness of the tongue can reveal a litany of health conditions," said Ali Al-Naji, adjunct Associate Professor at MTU and UniSA.</p>

<p>"Typically, people with diabetes have a yellow tongue; cancer patients a purple tongue with a thick greasy coating; and acute stroke patients present with an unusually shaped red tongue," he added.</p>

<p>The breakthrough was achieved through a series of experiments using 5,260 images to train machine-learning algorithms to detect tongue colour.</p>

<p>Researchers received 60 tongue images from two teaching hospitals in the Middle East, representing patients with diverse health conditions. The AI model matched tongue colour with the correct disease in nearly all cases.</p>

<p>The paper published in Technologies describes how the system analyses tongue colour to provide real-time diagnoses, demonstrating that AI can advance medical practices significantly.</p>

<p>Al-Naji explained that AI is replicating a 2,000-year-old technique from traditional Chinese medicine, where the tongue's colour, shape, and thickness are used to diagnose health issues.</p>

<p>For example, people with diabetes typically have a yellow tongue, while cancer patients show a purple tongue with a thick greasy coating. Stroke patients often present with an unusually shaped red tongue. A white tongue can indicate anaemia, severe Covid-19 cases are associated with a deep red tongue, and an indigo or violet tongue suggests vascular or gastrointestinal problems or asthma.</p>

<p>The study used cameras placed 20 centimetres from a patient to capture tongue colour, and the imaging system predicted health conditions in real time.</p>

<p>Co-author UniSA Professor Javaan Chahl noted that this technology could eventually be adapted for use with smartphones, making disease screening more accessible.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nfc01ads_human-tongue-generic-pixabay_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The colour, shape, thickness of the tongue can reveal a litany of health conditions. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-harbours-oceans-of-life-giving-water-deep-beneath-surface-study-6327101]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Water 20 km Below Mars Surface? What Study Shows And What It Means]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mars-harbours-oceans-of-life-giving-water-deep-beneath-surface-study-6327101]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:21:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Water is considered essential for life, and geological studies show the planet's surface had lakes, rivers and oceans more than 3 billion years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A study released Monday using data from NASA's Mars InSight lander shows evidence of liquid water far below the surface of the fourth planet, advancing the search for life there and showing what might have happened to Mars' ancient oceans.</p>

<p>The lander, which has been on the Red Planet since 2018, measured seismic data over four years, examining how quakes shook the ground and determining what materials or substances were beneath the surface.</p>

<p>Based on that data, the researchers found liquid water was most likely present deep beneath the lander. Water is considered essential for life, and geological studies show the planet's surface had lakes, rivers and oceans more than 3 billion years ago.</p>

<p>"On Earth what we know is where it is wet enough and there are enough sources of energy, there is microbial life very deep in Earth's subsurface," said one of the authors, Vashan Wright of the University of California San Diego's Scripps Institution of Oceanography. "The ingredients for life as we know it exist in the Martian subsurface if these interpretations are correct."</p>

<p>The study found that large reservoirs of liquid water in fractures 11.5 kilometres (7.15 miles) to 20km beneath the surface best explained the InSight measurements.</p>

<p>It notes that the volume of liquid water predicted beneath the surface is "more than the water volumes proposed to have filled hypothesised ancient Martian oceans".</p>

<p>"On Earth, groundwater infiltrated from the surface" to deep underground, Wright said. "We expect this process to have occurred on Mars as well when the upper crust was warmer than it is today."</p>

<p>There is no way to directly study water that deep beneath the surface of Mars, but the authors said the results "have implications for understanding Mars' water cycle, determining the fates of past surface water, searching for past or extant life, and assessing in situ resource utilization for future missions".</p>

<p>The study, whose other authors are Matthias Morzfeld of the Scripps Institution of Oceanography and Michael Manga of the University of California Berkeley, was published the week of Aug. 12 in the journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.</p>

<p>"I'm inspired and I hope the public is also inspired," Wright said. "Humans can work together to put instruments on a planet... and try to understand what's going on there."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h34a0a8_mars_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lander has been on the Red Planet since 2018 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-student-gets-21-months-in-prison-for-threatening-jewish-classmates-6326954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Student Gets 21 Months In Prison For Threatening Jewish Classmates]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-student-gets-21-months-in-prison-for-threatening-jewish-classmates-6326954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 13:01:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former Cornell University student was sentenced to 21 months in prison on Monday for threatening Jewish classmates. Patrick Dai posted the threats anonymously on an online campus bulletin board three weeks after the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former Cornell University student was sentenced to 21 months in prison on Monday for threatening Jewish classmates.</p>

<p>Patrick Dai, who was suspended by the Ivy League school in Ithaca, New York, posted the threats anonymously on an online campus bulletin board three weeks after the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel.</p>

<p>Dai pleaded guilty to one felony count of making threats and was sentenced to 21 months in prison and three years of supervised release by District Judge Brenda Sannes in Syracuse, New York.</p>

<p>"The defendant terrorized a campus community for days and horrified the nation at a very volatile time," prosecutors said in their sentencing memo.</p>

<p>Lisa Peebles, Dai's lawyer, told the court her 22-year-old client is "autistic" and is actually "pro-Israel."</p>

<p>"In a misguided attempt to highlight Hamas's genocidal beliefs and garner support for Israel," Peebles said, he "made several posts on a campus-related website in the guise of an anti-Semite Hamas extremist.</p>

<p>"He believed, wrongly, that the posts would prompt a 'blowback' against what he perceived as anti-Israel media coverage and pro-Hamas sentiment on campus," she said.</p>

<p>According to the Justice Department, Dai said he was "gonna shoot up 104 west," a dining hall that mostly caters to Jewish students, and "stab" and "slit the throat" of any Jewish males he saw on campus.</p>

<p>Cornell canceled classes for a day in November following the threats.</p>

<p>Attorney General Merrick Garland highlighted the case at the time of Dai's arrest as part of "a significant increase in the volume and frequency of threats against Jewish, Muslim and Arab communities across our country."</p>

<p>Colleges across the United States were rocked for months by protests over Israel's war in Gaza.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/74omjuc8_college-lecture_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Patrick Dai's lawyer, told the court that her client is "autistic" and "pro-Israel" (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-airport-runway-shut-after-us-cargo-plane-makes-emergency-landing-6326873]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Airport Runway Shut After US Cargo Plane Makes Emergency Landing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-airport-runway-shut-after-us-cargo-plane-makes-emergency-landing-6326873]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:52:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One of the two runways at Japan's Narita Airport was closed on Tuesday after an American cargo plane made an emergency landing due to an issue with its hydraulic system, officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the two runways at Japan's Narita Airport was closed on Tuesday after an American cargo plane made an emergency landing due to an issue with its hydraulic system, officials said.</p>

<p>An Atlas Air Boeing 747 cargo jet en route to Los Angeles turned back to Narita for an emergency landing after the problem became apparent at 1:10 am (1610 GMT), a transport ministry spokesman said.</p>

<p>"The seven crew members of the Boeing 747 were not injured, but tyres were found ruptured and the wheels damaged," the spokesman told AFP.</p>

<p>Narita's runway A was closed for at least seven hours, but the "tyres were changed and the operation of the runway is expected to resume at 8:30 am," he said.</p>

<p>The closure's impact on other flights had been minimal, he added.</p>

<p>No further details of the mechanical issue were immediately available.</p>

<p>The incident comes after a brake glitch on a Singapore Airlines plane forced a runway closure at Narita on Monday.</p>

<p>Fire engines and ambulances rushed to the scene after smoke was reported as coming from the arriving Singapore Airlines plane, though responders found no signs of fire and no one was injured.</p>

<p>The company later clarified that the flight had "experienced a technical issue with its brakes upon landing".</p>

<p>Narita's runway B was closed for just under an hour after the flight landed around 7:40 am, airport and fire officials said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1e14hbmo_airplane-runway_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Crew members were not injured, but tyres were found ruptured and the wheels damaged (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-it-killed-an-israeli-hostage-injured-2-others-in-gaza-israel-responds-6326758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Says It Killed A Hostage, Injured 2 Others In Gaza, Israel Responds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-says-it-killed-an-israeli-hostage-injured-2-others-in-gaza-israel-responds-6326758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:32:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The armed wing of Palestinian group Hamas said Monday its operatives had shot and killed an Israeli hostage and wounded two others, both women, "in two separate incidents" in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The armed wing of Palestinian group Hamas said Monday its operatives had shot and killed an Israeli hostage and wounded two others, both women, "in two separate incidents" in Gaza.</p>

<p>Palestinian operatives seized 251 hostages during their October 7 attack on Israel that triggered the ongoing war, with 111 of them still held in Gaza including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Abu Obeida, spokesman for the Ezzedine Al-Qassam Brigades, said in a statement: "In two separate incidents, two recruits assigned to guard enemy prisoners fired at a Zionist prisoner, killing him immediately, and also injured two female prisoners critically".</p>

<p>The statement, posted on Telegram, did not identify the hostages or say when or where the incidents occurred, but noted "attempts are being made to save the lives" of the two women.</p>

<p>Abu Obeida said Hamas had formed a committee to investigate the shootings.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said in a statement that it does "not have any intelligence information that allows us to refute or confirm Hamas claims".</p>

<p>"We will continue to examine and verify the credibility of the message", the statement added.</p>

<p>Israeli military spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari, in a televised briefing earlier on Monday, said: "We do not forget for a moment the hostages being cruelly held by Hamas in Gaza".</p>

<p>"We are deeply concerned about their physical and mental condition, given the prolonged time that has passed and the harsh conditions of their captivity."</p>

<p>The October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in the Gaza Strip since then has killed at least 39,897 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/ubk0a3i8_israel-hostages_625x300_22_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The statement, posted on Telegram, did not identify the hostages (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/body-found-inside-burned-out-athens-factory-as-wildfire-continues-to-spread-6326733]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Body Found Inside Burned-Out Athens Factory As Wildfire Continues To Spread]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/body-found-inside-burned-out-athens-factory-as-wildfire-continues-to-spread-6326733]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:30:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A woman's body was found early Tuesday inside a burned-out Athens factory, state news agency ANA said, in what is believed to be the first reported death from a disastrous wildfire that has scorched the city's northeastern suburbs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman's body was found early Tuesday inside a burned-out Athens factory, state news agency ANA said, in what is believed to be the first reported death from a disastrous wildfire that has scorched the city's northeastern suburbs.</p>

<p>The woman, believed to be around 60 years old, was found inside the factory building in Patima Halandriou, part of a municipality of over 70,000 people that was partly evacuated on Monday.</p>

<p>Hundreds of firefighters continued to battle for a third day the fire that broke out Sunday afternoon in the town of Varnavas, some 35 kilometres (22 miles) northeast of Athens.</p>

<p>Aided by strong winds, it grew to a 30-kilometre-long front line of flames more than 25 metres (80 feet) high in places, according to state TV ERT.</p>

<p>At least one firefighter has suffered serious burns battling the blaze, while another was hospitalised with breathing trouble, fire brigade spokesman Vassilis Vathrakogiannis said Monday.</p>

<p>According to the health ministry, 66 people have been treated for injuries related to the fire since Sunday.</p>

<p>Reinforcements from several EU states as well as Serbia and Turkey are expected on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/tcmhmpa_athens-fire_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hundreds of firefighters continued to battle for a third day the fire that broke out in Varnavas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-vladimir-putin-palestines-mahmoud-abbas-to-address-middle-east-crisis-6326627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vladimir Putin To Discuss Middle East Situation With Palestinian President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russias-vladimir-putin-palestines-mahmoud-abbas-to-address-middle-east-crisis-6326627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's President Vladimir Putin will discuss the situation in the Middle East with Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas in Moscow on Tuesday, the Kremlin said late on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's President Vladimir Putin will discuss the situation in the Middle East with Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas in Moscow on Tuesday, the Kremlin said late on Monday.</p>

<p>"It is expected that an exchange of views will be held on the situation in the Middle East in light of the current aggravation of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict and the unprecedented humanitarian catastrophe in the Gaza Strip," the Kremlin said in a post on the Telegram messaging app.</p>

<p>Abbas is in Moscow on a long-expected visit until Wednesday and is to travel to Turkey for talks with President Tayyip Erdogan afterwards.</p>

<p>Russia, which has forged close ties both with Iranian Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei and Arab leaders including Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, has condemned the recent killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh, calling on all parties to refrain from further destabilisation of the Middle East.</p>

<p>It has also repeatedly scolded the West for ignoring the need for an independent Palestinian state within 1967 borders.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/etden2mo_vladimir-putin_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has called on all parties to refrain from further destabilisation of the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-his-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-clash-over-gaza-hostage-deal-report-6326517]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu, His Defence Minister Clash Over Gaza Hostage Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-his-defence-minister-yoav-gallant-clash-over-gaza-hostage-deal-report-6326517]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 12:00:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant exchanged criticism on Monday over stalled talks for a ceasefire deal that would free hostages held in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yoav Gallant exchanged criticism on Monday over stalled talks for a ceasefire deal that would free hostages held in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The reason a hostage deal is stalling is in part because of Israel", Israeli media, including television channel Kan, reported Gallant saying in a private briefing for a parliamentary committee on Monday.</p>

<p>Gallant was discussing the choice Israel faced between a ceasefire deal that could end the conflicts in the north with Lebanese Hezbollah and in Gaza, and escalating the war, Kan reported.</p>

<p>"I and the defence establishment support the first option," he said, rather than talk of "'total victory' and all that nonsense", a phrase frequently used by Netanyahu in his communications.</p>

<p>Within hours of Gallant's words leaking to the media, Netanyahu hit back in a statement issued by his office, in which he accused Gallant of jeopardising a deal to secure the release of hostages.</p>

<p>"When Gallant adopts the anti-Israel narrative, he harms the chances of reaching a hostage release deal," Netanyahu said, adding that Hamas supremo Yahya Sinwar is the one "who has been and remains the only obstacle to a hostage deal."</p>

<p>He concluded by saying that Israel's only choice was "to achieve total victory", which "obligates everyone - including Gallant".</p>

<p>Gallant defended himself in a post on X stating that during the briefing he had "emphasised that (he is) determined to meet the goals of the war and continue the fighting".</p>

<p>He also blasted what he called "incessant leaks" since the beginning of the war, including the one on Monday.</p>

<p>Hamas commented on the row between the two politicians, with one of its leaders, Izzat al-Rishq saying in a statement that "Gallant's admission (...) confirms what we have always said."</p>

<p>"Netanyahu is lying to the world and to hostage families, he doesn't care about the hostages' lives and doesn't want to reach an agreement", he added.</p>

<p>Hamas officials, some analysts and critics in Israel have said Netanyahu has sought to prolong the fighting for political gain.</p>

<p>In late July, Israeli media reported that Gallant was criticising the lack of a deal to guarantee the return of the hostages held in Gaza since Hamas's unprecedented attack on October 7.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Islamist movement's attack on Israel resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has since then killed at least 39,897 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory, which does not provide details on civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/07ni27d_benjamin-netanyahu-yoav-gallant_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory military offensive in Gaza has so far killed nearly 40,000 people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/environment/julys-scorching-heat-breaks-records-raises-climate-alarm-6326482]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth Witnesses Hottest July Ever, 14th Straight Record-Breaking Month]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/environment/julys-scorching-heat-breaks-records-raises-climate-alarm-6326482]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 11:53:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Last month was the hottest July on record, making it the fourteenth straight record-breaking month, a US environmental agency reported Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month was the hottest July on record, making it the fourteenth straight record-breaking month, a US environmental agency reported Monday.</p>

<p>The monthly report from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) also said that 2024 now has a 77 percent chance of being the warmest year on record.</p>

<p>The July calculation by NOAA contradicted the EU's Copernicus climate monitor, which -- using a different dataset -- calculated last month's average temperature as being slightly lower than July 2023.</p>

<p>However, both agencies agree on the alarming trend of record-breaking heat, with the past year seeing month after month of new highs.</p>

<p>According to NOAA, whose historical data goes back 175 years, 2024 will definitely be one of the five hottest years on record.</p>

<p>In July, the global temperature was 2.18 degrees Fahrenheit (1.21 degrees Celsius) above the 20th century average of 60.4F (15.8C), the US agency said.</p>

<p>The month saw a series of heat waves across Mediterranean and Gulf countries, NOAA said.</p>

<p>Africa, Europe and Asia recorded their hottest July on record, while North America was the second hottest.</p>

<p>Ocean temperatures were their second warmest ever in July, according to NOAA -- the same reading as Copernicus.</p>

<p>Scientists at Copernicus noted last week that "air temperatures over the ocean remained unusually high over many regions" despite a swing from the El Nino weather pattern that helped fuel a spike in global temperatures to its opposite La Nina, which has a cooling effect.</p>

<p>Last year was also the warmest year on record.</p>

<p>"The devastating effects of climate change started well before 2023 and will continue until global greenhouse gas emissions reach net zero," said Samantha Burgess, deputy director of Copernicus.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m6dirrcg_climate-change_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The month saw a series of heat waves across Mediterranean and Gulf countries. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salvatore-strazzullo-dies-new-york-notorious-night-life-lawyer-found-dead-in-car-outside-parents-home-6326474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New York's Notorious 'Night-Life' Lawyer Found Dead Outside Parents' Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salvatore-strazzullo-dies-new-york-notorious-night-life-lawyer-found-dead-in-car-outside-parents-home-6326474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 11:51:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Salvatore Strazzullo, the New York City lawyer notorious for his colourful client roster and personal scandals, was found dead in his car outside his parents' Brooklyn home on Saturday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Salvatore Strazzullo, the New York City lawyer notorious for his colourful client roster and personal scandals, was found dead in his car outside his parents' Brooklyn home on Saturday. He was 52. The circumstances surrounding his death remain unclear, with his cause of death not yet determined, reported the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/12/us-news/sal-strazzullo-found-dead-night-life-lawyer-repped-strippers-celebs/ ">NY Post</a>. &nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Night-Life Lawyer'</strong></p>

<p>Strazzullo, who earned the nickname "Night-Life Lawyer" given his penchant for taking on cases involving celebrities and embarrassing circumstances, was facing multiple ongoing criminal cases for allegedly exploiting elderly clients out of millions of dollars.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Famous Clientele&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>In 2011, Strazzullo defended rapper Foxy Brown in a case where she was accused of flashing a neighbour she had been feuding with. Strazzullo was prepared to invoke "the underwear defence" if the case went to trial, arguing that his client had simply not worn underwear that day. The case, however, ended up getting dismissed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In another case, Strazzullo represented Milana Dravnel, an exotic dancer who sued Oscar de la Hoya for $100 million in 2007. The case involved racy photos of the boxing legend in his underwear, which Ms Dravnel sold to a West Coast photo agency for $70,000. Mr De la Hoya's team claimed the photos were doctored.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Personal Scandals</strong></p>

<p>The infamous lawyer faced numerous legal troubles, including allegations of sexual harassment and criminal charges for theft and fraud, throughout his career.</p>

<p>In 2011, Desiree DeMartino, a former paralegal and employee, pressed charges against Strazzullo for sexual harassment in Brooklyn Federal Court. The suit alleged that Strazzullo trapped Ms DeMartino in a conference room, pleasured himself in front of her, and committed other inappropriate acts, including forcibly kissing her and touching her breasts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More recently, Strazzullo faced criminal charges for theft and fraud, accused of misusing his escrow account to fund a lavish lifestyle. In April, Brooklyn District Attorney Eric Gonzalez alleged that Strazzullo operated a Ponzi scheme, using funds from one client to pay off another while accumulating tens of thousands of dollars in charges at upscale restaurants and hotels. Prosecutors also alleged he spent the stolen funds on luxuries like a $100,000 BMW and a $13,000-per-month apartment.</p>

<p>Strazzullo pleaded not guilty to multiple counts of grand larceny and scheme to defraud, but the evidence against him was substantial. Brooklyn District Attorney Eric Gonzalez condemned Strazzullo's actions, stating he stole the "nest eggs" of senior citizens who trusted him.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the time of his death, two criminal cases, including another alleged theft of $1.5 million from three clients, against Strazzullo were still pending.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/le7h778o_salvatore-strazzullo_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vowed-to-never-to-do-this-again-but-did-it-during-musk-interview-6326362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Vowed To Never To Do This Again, But Did It During Musk Interview]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-vowed-to-never-to-do-this-again-but-did-it-during-musk-interview-6326362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 11:36:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump today spent nearly an hour discussing the recent assassination attempt, something he had promised never to talk about again.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump today spent nearly an hour discussing the recent assassination attempt, something he had promised never to talk about again. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-ddos-attack-flagged-by-elon-musk-that-hit-donald-trump-interview-6324982">Trump and Musk discussed at length</a> how a bullet narrowly missed the former US President during a rally at Pennsylvania's Butler.</p>

<p>At the Republican national convention last month, Trump had told the crowd about the close call and what he went through - but said he would do so only that one time. During the speech, his first following the assassination attempt, he promised never to narrate the ordeal.</p>

<p>But Trump went back on his word during the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-donald-trump-interview-live-updates-x-owner-to-interview-republican-2024-us-elections-presidential-candidate-6324927">conversation with Musk</a>, saying "It was a miracle. If I hadn't turned my head, I would not be talking to you right now, as much as I like you."</p>

<p>"It was a hard hit. It was very, I guess you would say, surreal, but it wasn't surreal. You know, I was telling somebody, you have instances like this... where you feel it's a surreal situation. And I never felt that way. I knew immediately that it was a bullet," Trump said before elaborating the entire incident.</p>

<p>The start of the much-awaited interview though was delayed due to techinical glitches, which Musk claimed were caused due to a targeted cyber attack on the platform.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-interview-crashed-unable-to-fetch-spaces-trend-on-x-as-musk-interviews-trump-6324955">glitches prevented people from listening to the event</a> and led to widespread frustration among users. Many were met with error messages and resulted in 'crashed' and 'unable to fetch spaces' being the top trending hashtags on X.</p>

<p>The conversation was intended to help reinvigorate <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-interviews-donald-trump-on-x-6323844">Donald Trump's</a> stuttering campaign, which has flagged since Biden dropped out of the race, to be replaced by a surging Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Musk, who has said he previously voted Democrat, has thrown his weight -- and his wealth -- behind Trump since a gunman tried to assassinate the Republican at a rally last month.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/da04e9s4_donald-trump_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump spoke at length about the assassination attempt during his conversation with Musk.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earth-hit-by-intense-geomagnetic-solar-storm-likely-to-trigger-more-northern-lights-6326291]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Earth Hit By "Intense" Solar Storm, Likely To Trigger More Northern Lights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earth-hit-by-intense-geomagnetic-solar-storm-likely-to-trigger-more-northern-lights-6326291]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 11:21:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The new solar storm is caused by coronal mass ejections (CMEs), which are explosions of particles leaving the Sun. When these particles arrive on Earth, they disrupt its magnetic field.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Earth was hit Monday by an intense solar storm that could bring the northern lights to night skies further south than normal, a US agency announced.</p>

<p>Conditions of a level-four geomagnetic storm -- on a scale of five -- were observed Monday from 1500 GMT, according to a specialized center at the US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).</p>

<p>These conditions may persist for several hours, but were not expected to increase further in intensity, NOAA added in a statement.</p>

<p>"A severe geomagnetic storm includes the potential for aurora to be seen faintly as far south as Alabama and northern California," NOAA said in a statement, referring to US states.</p>

<p>The new solar storm is caused by coronal mass ejections (CMEs), which are explosions of particles leaving the Sun. When these particles arrive on Earth, they disrupt its magnetic field.</p>

<p>"There are a lot of auroras now... If it lasts until nightfall here, we might be able to see some," Eric Lagadec, an astrophysicist at the Cote d'Azur Observatory in France, said on X.</p>

<p>On Sunday, NASA astronaut Matthew Dominick published on X a superb photo of the aurora borealis -- or Northern Lights -- taken from the International Space Station, where he is currently stationed.</p>

<p>But solar or geomagnetic storms can also trigger undesirable effects.</p>

<p>For example, they can degrade high-frequency communications, disrupt satellites, and cause overloads on the electricity grid. Operators of sensitive infrastructure have been notified to put in place measures to limit these effects, NOAA said.</p>

<p>In May, the planet went through the most powerful geomagnetic storms recorded in 20 years. They caused auroras to light up the night sky in the United States, Europe, and Australia, at much lower latitudes than usual.</p>

<p>This type of event has increased recently because the Sun is currently close to its peak activity, as per its 11-year cycle.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/t40ihdf8_solar-storm-colorful-lights_625x300_11_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In May, the planet went through the most powerful geomagnetic storms recorded in 20 years (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-donald-trump-elon-musk-happy-to-host-kamala-harris-ahead-of-us-polls-6326134]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Trump, Elon Musk "Happy To Host" Kamala Harris Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-donald-trump-elon-musk-happy-to-host-kamala-harris-ahead-of-us-polls-6326134]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 10:59:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump said that the country "will go out of business," if Kamala Harris wins US elections 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former United States President Donald Trump was interviewed by billionaire Elon Musk on his social media platform X (formerly Twitter) today. The interview had a rocky start and was delayed by 40 minutes after the Tesla Chief announced that there was a cyber attack on his social media platform. The two businessmen discussed a variety of topics ahead of US polls including immigration, layoffs, the assassination attempt on Mr Trump and climate change. Amid this, Mr Musk has now invited US Vice President Kamala Harris for a chat on X Spaces.</p>

<p>He took to the microblogging platform and wrote, "Happy to host Kamala on an X Spaces too."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Happy to host Kamala on an ? Spaces too</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1823217769229566251?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 13, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Since being shared, his post has amassed a variety of reactions online.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign reacted to the post with a folded hands emoji.</p>

<p>A person joked, "Same chance of her agreeing to come on as me meeting Abraham Lincoln tomorrow morning."</p>

<p>"It would be really smart of her to do this. Significantly simpler logistics than doing a rally, with a far larger potential impact. I'm sure you'd be a fair interviewer," said a person.</p>

<p>A user stated, "Free Speech! @VP should 100% do this. The American people deserve to hear your thoughts on the issues!"</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Republican candidate slammed Ms Harris and said, "The number of illegals Kamala (Harris) has welcomed into our communities is much bigger than we think." He told Elon Musk, "Countries are emptying their prisons - and sending them to our country. They're bringing crime and violence to our backyards," he said.</p>

<p>In a separate comment, he also said that the country "will go out of business," if she wins US elections 2024. "We don't have a president right now - and Kamala is even worse. She's a San Francisco liberal who destroyed that city, destroyed California, and will destroy our country if she's elected," Donald Trump said.</p>

<p>Reacting to the same, Ms Harris' presidential campaign<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1823194536983556377"> issued a statement on X</a>. They said, "Donald Trump's extremism and dangerous Project 2025 agenda is a feature not a glitch of his campaign, which was on full display for those unlucky enough to listen in tonight during whatever that was on X.com."</p>

<p>They added, "Trump's entire campaign is in service of people like Elon Musk and himself - self-obsessed rich guys who will sell out the middle class and who cannot run a livestream in the year 2024."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/p0bt00l8_elon-musk-kamala-harris_625x300_02_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Trump campaign reacted to the post with a folded hands emoji.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>