<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:32:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-kamala-harris-trailblazer-eying-americas-last-glass-ceiling-6156986]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Trailblazer Eying America's Last Glass Ceiling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-kamala-harris-trailblazer-eying-americas-last-glass-ceiling-6156986]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:31:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For years Kamala Harris faced criticism that she was not up to the job of being a heartbeat away from the presidency. Now, she finds herself feted by Democrats as their best hope to stop Donald Trump's comeback.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For years Kamala Harris faced criticism that she was not up to the job of being a heartbeat away from the presidency. Now, she finds herself feted by Democrats as their best hope to stop Donald Trump's comeback.</p>

<p>Despite blazing a trail as the first woman, Black and South Asian vice president in US history, the 59-year-old Democrat long struggled with approval ratings as bad or worse than President Joe Biden's.</p>

<p>The last 12 months, however, have revealed a transformed Harris.</p>

<p>And with Biden's endorsement of Harris after stunning the world by dropping his own reelection bid Sunday, she's suddenly on the cusp of history.</p>

<p>Harris will hope she has done the hard work to earn her full party's backing in the midst of the crisis.</p>

<p>As the ageing Biden faded over the last year, his "veep" emerged as a force on the campaign trail, pushing for abortion rights and reaching out to core voters, including suburban women and Black men.</p>

<p>With a fondness for the f-bomb and her family nickname of "Momala" going viral, she has also finally started to cut through the noise to voters who previously barely paid attention.</p>

<p>She has also won plaudits in party circles by staying loyal to the 81-year-old president during the last few weeks, even as political vultures circled over his candidacy.</p>

<p>She now is likely to face Trump -- a brutal battle against a candidate who defeated Hillary Clinton in her bid become the first female commander in chief in 2016.</p>

<p>The fact that Harris has blamed much of the criticism of her by Republicans on racism and sexism would likely make a win feel even more vindicating for her.</p>

<p>Trump and other Republicans have notably stepped up their attacks on her as Biden's position weakened and polls showed Harris would fare better against him than Biden.</p>

<h3><strong>'Ready to serve'</strong></h3>

<p>A child of immigrant parents -- her father was from Jamaica and her mother from India -- Harris grew up in Oakland, California, in an activist household that saw her attend her first rallies in a stroller.</p>

<p>Her focus on rights and justice saw her build an impressive CV, becoming California's first Black attorney general and the first woman of South Asian heritage elected to the US Senate.</p>

<p>Harris then went up against Biden in the 2020 primaries. In one stinging attack, she criticized him for allegedly opposing the bussing of students to segregated schools.</p>

<p>"There was a little girl in California who was part of the second class to integrate her public schools, and she was bussed to school every day. And that little girl was me," she said in a barbed attack on her future boss.</p>

<p>But as his running mate, she consolidated the coalition that helped defeat the incumbent Trump in 2020.</p>

<p>Her transition to the White House, however, proved difficult.</p>

<p>Critics said she was underwhelming and gaffe-prone in a job that has been known to flummox many officeholders.</p>

<p>Struggling to carve out a role, she was tasked by Biden with getting to the roots of the illegal migration problem, but fumbled and then got defensive in response to a question during a visit to the Mexican border.</p>

<p>Unusually high staff turnover fed rumors of discontent in the vice presidential office.</p>

<p>And Republicans relentlessly targeted her as being unfit to take over should the worst happen to America's oldest-ever president, often resorting to stereotypes her supporters branded as sexist and racist.</p>

<p>Harris told the Wall Street Journal in February: "I am ready to serve. There's no question about that."</p>

<h3><strong>'Momala'</strong></h3>

<p>Things began to change as the 2024 race got underway.</p>

<p>The Biden campaign repeatedly deployed her to battleground states to hammer home the party's message on abortion rights, with Harris becoming the first vice president to visit an abortion clinic.</p>

<p>Gradually, she began to draw warm and fired-up crowds.</p>

<p>Some of the outreach was, however, cringe-inducing. Earlier this year, she was mocked after she told chat show host Drew Barrymore her family sometimes called her "Momala," and Barrymore replied: "We need you to be Momala of the country."</p>

<p>But voters seemed to be switching on.</p>

<p>A clip of her quoting her mother as often saying "You think you just fell out of a coconut tree?" became a meme, with a rising sense among supporters that now could be her time.</p>

<p>If elected, Harris would break one of the highest glass ceilings left for women in the United States -- that of occupying the country's top office.</p>

<p>Her husband, Douglas Emhoff, would also be breaking new ground, moving from being the current Second Gentleman to the country's first First Gentleman.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1810n4to_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The last 12 months, however, have revealed a transformed Harris (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-biden-bombshell-a-plot-twist-that-roils-trump-too-6156958]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Biden Bombshell: A Plot Twist That Roils Trump Too]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-biden-bombshell-a-plot-twist-that-roils-trump-too-6156958]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:25:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden's withdrawal upends what was already a White House race for the ages, but it will rattle Donald Trump, too -- forcing him to recalibrate a campaign that was focused almost entirely on his former opponent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden's withdrawal upends what was already a White House race for the ages, but it will rattle Donald Trump, too -- forcing him to recalibrate a campaign that was focused almost entirely on his former opponent.</p>

<p>For months Trump and his allies have been playing on concerns that the 81-year-old Biden may no longer be fit for office, gleefully sharing video clips of every stammer, rhetorical gaffe and red carpet stumble.</p>

<p>He was frequently a target of Republican mockery and scorn at the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, where Trump's newly announced running mate J.D. Vance called him "Fake Scranton Joe."</p>

<p>But with the Democrat no longer in the race, the Trump operation finds itself pushed into a strategic pivot, forced now to shift its messaging to fit a contest with no incumbent and a yet-to-be-confirmed opponent, although Biden did endorse Vice President Kamala Harris on Sunday as he pulled out of the race.</p>

<p>"Biden withdrawing is bad news for Trump," Henry Olsen, a senior fellow at the conservative Ethics and Public Policy Center think tank, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Biden has the lowest job approval of any first-term president at this stage of his presidency in polling history and is also irretrievably burdened by his age. It's much better for Trump to run against him than any conceivable opponent."</p>

<p>Trumpworld had been playing down the chances of Biden withdrawing, but behind the scenes aides have been consumed by the contingencies, preparing a brutal assault on the veteran Democrat's heir apparent, Harris.</p>

<p>"Nothing fundamentally changes" Jason Miller, one of Trump's closest advisors, told AFP during the Republican convention, saying that any "radical liberal" Democratic opponent, Harris or otherwise, shares "the responsibility for the failure of destroying our economy."</p>

<p>Harris, a 59-year-old former California senator is not a shoo-in, and could face competition from multiple leading Democrats in Congress and the nation's 23 Democratic governors.</p>

<p>"I'm going to show up and I'm going to campaign -- whether it's him or somebody else," Trump told a radio network in Virginia before Biden's announcement, pointing to polls showing him doing as well or better against other Democrats.</p>

<p>- Clash of cultures -</p>

<p>Voters have been telling pollsters for months they want younger political leaders, and a ticket topped by a relatively youthful swing state governor, for example, would be a threat to Trump, who would be 82 at the end of a second term.</p>

<p>A campaign led by Harris and backed up by a moderate midwestern running mate could present the biggest danger though, helping turn out more women, who historically vote in greater numbers than men and are a weakness for Trump.</p>

<p>Harris would also give Democrats a chance to redefine the race at their convention in Chicago in August as a clash of cultures between a former prosecutor and a convicted felon.</p>

<p>And Harris ensures that abortion rights -- one of her biggest domestic priorities and another vulnerability for Trump and the Republicans -- remains a crucial election issue.</p>

<p>Trump's new, serious focus on the vice president was demonstrated by his bestowal on her of one of his famous nicknames, referring to her on social media recently as "Laffin' Kamala Harris."</p>

<p>- 'Destruction and chaos' -</p>

<p>It is the disastrous June presidential debate in Atlanta that proved the catalyst for Biden's withdrawal.</p>

<p>A new survey from Democratic polling form Public Policy Polling released Thursday found that Harris -- with the right running mate -- likely can defeat Trump and Vance in Pennsylvania and Michigan, two of the three "Blue Wall" states seen as critical to electing a Democratic president.</p>

<p>The vice president has the disadvantage of incumbency, though, meaning Trump can pin on her anything that was considered a weakness for Biden -- including the border crisis, on which Harris led the administration's early efforts.</p>

<p>Several Democratic rising stars have been floated as alternatives, including governors Josh Shapiro, Gretchen Whitmer and Gavin Newsom.</p>

<p>Newsom, of California -- who has demonstrated a willingness to go toe-to-toe with top Republicans -- would be unlikely to be intimidated by Trump's broadsides.</p>

<p>Whitmer was considered for the Biden ticket in 2020 and has since spearheaded a Democratic resurgence in Michigan, while Pennsylvania's Shapiro is another serious contender as chief executive of a critical swing state.</p>

<p>Whoever becomes the nominee, Trump will likely spend the rest of the campaign pushing them on their past defenses of Biden, accusing them of covering up the president's decline.</p>

<p>"The destruction and chaos created by the Biden administration isn't just on Crooked Joe -- it's on the entire Democrat Party," the Trump team said in a recent edition of its daily circular.</p>

<p>"None have been worse than Kamala Harris, who has lied repeatedly -- presumably putting her own position above the security of the American people."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/r5eouhrg_joe-biden-new_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trumpworld had been playing down the chances of Biden withdrawing (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pendulum-swung-to-republican-party-jab-from-elon-musk-after-joe-biden-decision-6156955]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pendulum Swung To Republican Party: Elon Musk's Jab After Biden Announcement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pendulum-swung-to-republican-party-jab-from-elon-musk-after-joe-biden-decision-6156955]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:22:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, the CEO of Tesla and SpaceX, has tweeted his disapproval of US President Biden's move to end his reelection campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk, the CEO of Tesla and SpaceX, has tweeted his disapproval of US President Biden's move to end his reelection campaign.</p>

<p>"I believe in an America that maximizes individual freedom and merit. That used to be the Democratic Party, but now the pendulum has swung to the Republican Party,"read his post on X, formerly Twitter.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I believe in an America that maximizes individual freedom and merit.<br />
<br />
That used to be the Democratic Party, but now the pendulum has swung to the Republican Party.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1815092002083471731?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>US President Joe Biden ended his reelection campaign on Sunday after fellow Democrats lost faith in his mental acuity and ability to beat Republican candidate Donald Trump.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ldckr8sg_elon-musk_625x300_18_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jill-bidens-heart-response-to-husband-joe-bidens-move-to-quit-us-presidential-race-6156954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jill Biden's 'Heart' Response To Husband's Move To Quit Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jill-bidens-heart-response-to-husband-joe-bidens-move-to-quit-us-presidential-race-6156954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:22:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden has announced that he is stepping out of the pesidential race slated for later this year. To this announcement, Joe Biden's wife Jill Biden had a no-word response, just a heart emoji.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden has announced that he is stepping out of the presidential race slated for later this year. Joe Biden made the big announcement through a statement on social media platform X (formerly twitter). To this announcement, Joe Biden's wife Jill Biden had a no-word response, just a heart emoji.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The First Lady of the United States, Jill Biden, reshared Joe Biden's letter on X from her personal account and captioned the post with a heart emoji.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="art">? <a href="https://t.co/VN2rZpyhVX">https://t.co/VN2rZpyhVX</a></p>
— Dr. Jill Biden (@DrBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrBiden/status/1815083964207358095?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Joe Biden's surprise announcement has come after he repeatedly affirmed over the last few weeks that he is going to contest the presidential polls. He has now endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as the democrat candidate to face Donald Trump in the US presidential polls.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/qs48mbso_joe-biden-jill-biden_625x300_28_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris to contest US presidential polls (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-joe-biden-will-step-aside-in-2024-us-presidential-race-what-happens-next-6156924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Joe Biden Won't Run For Re-Election. What Happens Next?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-joe-biden-will-step-aside-in-2024-us-presidential-race-what-happens-next-6156924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:19:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden announced on Sunday that he was withdrawing from the presidential race against challenger Donald Trump, following a dismal debate performance and flagging polling numbers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden announced on Sunday that he was withdrawing from the presidential race against challenger Donald Trump, following a dismal debate performance and flagging polling numbers.</p>

<p>The stepping down of the Democratic party's flag bearer at the last minute is unprecedented in modern US electoral history, and a high-risk move.</p>

<p>Here's a look at how replacing the 81-year-old could work.</p>

<h3><strong>Chaotic convention?</strong></h3>

<p>To designate a formal nominee, delegates from all 50 states attend their party's summer nominating convention to officially anoint a candidate based on primary voting.</p>

<p>Biden overwhelmingly won the primary votes, and the party's roughly 3,900 delegates heading to the convention in Chicago this August are beholden to him.</p>

<p>With Biden exiting, the delegates have to find a replacement. That brings US politics back to the old days, when party bosses jostled to pick a nominee through deal-making in smoke-filled back rooms and endless rounds of voting.</p>

<p>On March 31, 1968, then-president Lyndon Johnson made the shock announcement in the middle of the Vietnam War that he would not seek reelection.</p>

<p>The move turned that year's convention, also in Chicago, into a political crisis with protesters in the streets and left-leaning delegates angry at the pro-war stance of party-picked candidate Hubert Humphrey.</p>

<p>Following that debacle, states more widely embraced the primary process and conventions have become well-oiled affairs whose outcomes are known in advance since they are determined by the primaries.</p>

<h3><strong>Who might fill in?</strong></h3>

<p>Immediately after the debate, Democrats had circled their wagons around Biden, at least when speaking on the record.</p>

<p>All of that dissolved as time went on, with increasingly senior party leaders publicly questioning the viability of the incumbent's candidacy.</p>

<p>A natural -- but not automatic -- pick to take Biden's place would be his running mate on the 2020 ticket, Vice President Kamala Harris. Biden endorsed her Sunday as he announced he is pulling out.</p>

<p>Sent in to put out the fire after the Democratic president's lackluster performance at the debate, the 59-year-old conceded Biden had been "slow to start" against Trump but had "finished strong."</p>

<p>Otherwise, any of a number of strong Democratic politicians -- Governors Gavin Newsom of California, Gretchen Whitmer of Michigan and Josh Shapiro of Pennsylvania have been mentioned -- might be called on.</p>

<h3><strong>Third-party chances?</strong></h3>

<p>With Biden dropping out, could a strong third-party hopeful emerge? So far, no independent candidate is posing any danger to the United States's dominant two-party system.</p>

<p>In 1992, Texas billionaire Ross Perot, running as an independent, managed to win nearly 19 percent of the popular vote.</p>

<p>But in the end, because of the way the country's electoral system works, he did not receive a single one of the votes that matter most: those of the 538 members of the Electoral College that ultimately decide the winner.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/5t1qk6f8_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_11_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-joe-biden-abruptly-changed-his-mind-about-2024-race-over-weekend-report-6156886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Abruptly Changed His Mind About 2024 Race Over Weekend: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-joe-biden-abruptly-changed-his-mind-about-2024-race-over-weekend-report-6156886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:07:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden as of Saturday night had planned to stay in the 2024 presidential race, but told senior staff on Sunday afternoon that he was withdrawing, a source familiar with the matter said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden as of Saturday night had planned to stay in the 2024 presidential race, but told senior staff on Sunday afternoon that he was withdrawing, a source familiar with the matter told Reuters.</p>

<p>"Last night the message was to proceed with everything, full speed ahead," the source told Reuters, speaking on condition of anonymity. "At around 1:45 p.m. today: the president told his senior team that he had changed his mind."</p>

<p>The decision caught many White House staff off guard, with several expressing shock that the president had made the announcement while recuperating from a bout of COVID-19 at his home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.</p>

<p>Nursing a cough, the 81-year-old Biden had spent the weekend stewing over Democratic pressure to force him to leave the race.</p>

<p>He had been particularly irked at former House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi, whom Biden advisers believed was orchestrating a pressure campaign to get him to stand down.</p>

<p>Hours before the shock announcement, the Biden campaign denied reports that he was planning to drop out.</p>

<p>"It is false. And I think that it is false to continue to try to gin up this narrative," deputy campaign manager Quentin Fulks told MSNBC's "The Weekend” on Sunday morning.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/368soaeo_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hours before the announcement, the Biden campaign denied reports that he was planning to drop out.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-kamala-harris-will-be-easier-to-defeat-after-joe-biden-quits-us-presidential-race-6156880]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Says Kamala Harris Will Be Easier To Defeat, After Joe Biden Quits]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-says-kamala-harris-will-be-easier-to-defeat-after-joe-biden-quits-us-presidential-race-6156880]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:02:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told CNN on Sunday that he thinks Vice President Kamala Harris will be easier to defeat in November's election than Democratic President Joe Biden who stepped aside as his party's candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump told CNN on Sunday that he thinks Vice President Kamala Harris will be easier to defeat in November's election than Democratic President Joe Biden who stepped aside as his party's candidate.</p>

<p>A CNN reporter said on X that Trump made the comments to the network shortly after Biden announced his decision.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/itte998_trump-assassination_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-endorses-kamala-harris-as-democratic-partys-presidential-nominee-6156798]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Endorses Kamala Harris As Democratic Party's Presidential Nominee]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-endorses-kamala-harris-as-democratic-partys-presidential-nominee-6156798]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 23:49:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden endorses Kamala Harris as Democratic Party's presidential nominee]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden ended his reelection campaign on Sunday after fellow Democrats lost faith in his mental acuity and ability to beat Donald Trump while endorsing Vice President Kamala Harris to replace him as the party's candidate.</p>

<p>Biden, 81, in a post on X, said he will remain in his role as president and commander-in-chief until his term ends in January 2025 and will address the nation this week.</p>

<p>"It has been the greatest honor of my life to serve as your President. And while it has been my intention to seek reelection, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and to focus solely on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term," Biden wrote.</p>

<p>His initial statement had not included an endorsement of Harris, but he followed up a few minutes later with an expression of support.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">My fellow Democrats, I have decided not to accept the nomination and to focus all my energies on my duties as President for the remainder of my term. My very first decision as the party nominee in 2020 was to pick Kamala Harris as my Vice President. And it's been the best… <a href="https://t.co/x8DnvuImJV">pic.twitter.com/x8DnvuImJV</a></p>
— Joe Biden (@JoeBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Harris, 59, would become the first Black woman to do run at the top of a major-party ticket in the country's history.</p>

<p>It was unclear whether other senior Democrats would challenge Harris for the party's nomination - she was widely seen as the pick for many party officials - or whether the party itself would choose to open the field for nominations.</p>

<p>Biden's announcement follows a wave of public and private pressure from Democratic lawmakers and party officials to quit the race after his shockingly poor performance in a June 27 televised debate last month against Republican rival Trump, 78.</p>

<p>Biden's failure at times to complete clear sentences took the public spotlight away from Trump's performance, in which he made a string of false statements, and trained it instead on questions surrounding Biden's fitness for another 4-year term.</p>

<p>Days later he raised fresh concerns in an interview, shrugging off Democrats' worries and a widening gap in opinion polls, and saying he would be fine losing to Trump if he knew he'd "gave it my all."</p>

<p>His gaffes at a NATO summit - invoking Russian President Vladimir Putin's name when he meant Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy and calling Harris "Vice President Trump" -further stoked anxieties.</p>

<p>Only four days before Sunday's announcement, Biden was diagnosed with COVID-19 for a third time, forcing him to cut short a campaign trip to Las Vegas. More than one in 10 congressional Democrats had called publicly for him to quit the race.</p>

<p>Biden's historic move - the first sitting president to give up his party's nomination for reelection since President Lyndon Johnson in March 1968 - leaves his replacement with less than four months to wage a campaign.</p>

<p>If Harris emerges as the nominee, the move would represent an unprecedented gamble by the Democratic Party: its first Black and Asian American woman to run for the White House in a country that has elected one Black president and never a woman president in more than two centuries of democracy.</p>

<p>Biden was the oldest U.S. president ever elected when he beat Trump in 2020. During that campaign, Biden described himself as a bridge to the next generation of Democratic leaders. Some interpreted that to mean he would serve one term, a transitional figure who beat Trump and brought his party back to power.</p>

<p>But he set his sights on a second term in the belief that he was the only Democrat who could beat Trump again amid questions about Harris's experience and popularity. In recent times, though, his advanced age began to show through more. His gait became stilted and his childhood stutter occasionally returned.</p>

<p>His team had hoped a strong performance at the June 27 debate would ease concerns over his age. It did the opposite: a Reuters/Ipsos poll after the debate showed that about 40% of Democrats thought he should quit the race.</p>

<p>Donors began to revolt and supporters of Harris began to coalesce around her. Top Democrats, including former House of Representatives Speaker Nancy Pelosi, a longtime ally, told Biden he cannot win the election.</p>

<p>Biden initially resisted pressure to step aside. He held damage-control calls and meetings with lawmakers and state governors, and sat for rare television interviews. But it was not enough. Polls showed Trump's lead in key battleground states widening, and Democrats began to fear a wipeout in the House and Senate. On July 17, California's Rep. Adam Schiff called on him to exit the race.</p>

<p>Biden's departure sets up a stark new contrast, between the Democrats' presumptive new nominee, Harris, a former prosecutor, and Trump who at 78 is two decades her senior and faces two outstanding criminal prosecutions related to his attempts to overturn the 2020 election result. He is due to be sentenced in New York in September on a conviction for trying to cover up a hush-money payment to a porn star.</p>

<p>BIDEN STRUGGLED BEFORE DEBATE</p>

<p>Earlier this year, facing little opposition, Biden easily won the Democratic Party's primary race to pick its presidential candidate, despite voter concerns about his age.</p>

<p>However, his staunch support for Israel's military campaign in Gaza eroded support among some in his own party, particularly young, progressive Democrats and voters of color.</p>

<p>Many Black voters say Biden has not done enough for them, and enthusiasm among Democrats overall for a second Biden term had been low. Even before the debate with Trump, Biden was trailing the Republican in some national polls and in the battleground states he would have needed to win to prevail on Nov. 5.</p>

<p>Harris was tasked with reaching out to those voters in recent months.</p>

<p>During the primary race, Biden accumulated more than 3,600 delegates to the Democratic National Convention to be held in Chicago in August. That was almost double the 1,976 needed to win the party's nomination.</p>

<p>Unless the Democratic Party changes the rules, delegates pledged to Biden would enter the convention "uncommitted," leaving them to vote on his successor.</p>

<p>Democrats also have a system of "superdelegates," unpledged senior party officials and elected leaders whose support is limited on the first ballot but who could play a decisive role in subsequent rounds.</p>

<p>Biden beat Trump in 2020 by winning in the key battleground states, including tight races in Pennsylvania and Georgia. At a national level, he bested Trump by more than 7 million votes, capturing 51.3% of the popular vote to Trump's 46.8%.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nb3f6m5o_kamala-biden_625x300_21_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-the-final-days-how-joe-biden-and-his-inner-circle-blew-it-6156790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Final Days: How Biden And His Inner Circle Blew It]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-race-the-final-days-how-joe-biden-and-his-inner-circle-blew-it-6156790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 23:46:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden's decision to end his reelection campaign on Sunday followed a series of strategic missteps by his campaign team and White House aides that amplified concerns that the 81-year-old president wouldn't be able to win in November's election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden's decision to end his reelection campaign on Sunday followed a series of strategic missteps by his campaign team and White House aides that amplified concerns that the 81-year-old president wouldn't be able to win in November's election, or run the country for another four years.</p>

<p>Biden's halting performance at the June 27 presidential debate against Republican candidate Donald Trump, pushed even some of his closest allies to question whether he could endure a full campaign, and added gasoline to a smoldering Democratic party movement questioning the wisdom of his second term.</p>

<p>Within days, Biden went from the party's figurehead to a liability. He became the first sitting president to stand down from a possible reelection since Lyndon B Johnson in 1968.</p>

<p>These were some of the key moments that led to Biden's downfall.</p>

<p><strong>THE DEBATE COUP: April to June</strong></p>

<p>Biden himself set the debate in motion, after he told radio show host Howard Stern in April that he'd debate Trump, despite worries from some of his Democratic allies that a debate might do little to improve his chances or even cast an unflattering light on him.</p>

<p>Some Biden aides thought they had scored a coup in agreeing to a June debate. They worked with broadcaster CNN to shape the rules in what they thought was their favor and agreed on May 15 to two debates, including the first on June 27.</p>

<p>An earlier debate would serve Biden well, some aides thought, convincing voters that there was no other anti-Trump option in the race, but also cushioning the blow of any mediocre performance by the president.</p>

<p>The format - no audience to pump up Trump's punchlines, no third-party candidates, moderators they could trust and a mute button on the microphones- would, they thought, favor Biden's style.</p>

<p><strong>JET LAG - JUNE 4 TO 27</strong></p>

<p>Biden flew to Europe twice and to the West Coast over a 14-day period before taking just a few days to rest at his vacation home in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden was tired and dragging by the end of the travel, according to several people who observed him during this period.</p>

<p>He and his aides headed to Camp David for focused prep sessions on June 21, where they peppered Biden with details, then followed up with mock debates for the better part of seven days.</p>

<p><strong>A BAD NIGHT - JUNE 27</strong></p>

<p>In CNN's Atlanta studios, Biden stumbled over his words and lost his train of thought. His delivery, appearance and voice drew the immediate attention of reporters, who asked his aides for an explanation.</p>

<p>Officials told reporters as the debate was underway some new information: Biden was sick with a cold, they said.</p>

<p>Biden's hoarseness would improve as the debate went on but his disjointed answers took voters, donors and Democratic officials by surprise. One Democratic strategist called it "a disaster."</p>

<p>Trump, 78, repeated a series of well-worn, glaring falsehoods during the 90-minute debate, including claims that he actually had won the 2020 election. Biden failed to refute them, leaving sentences and thoughts unfinished.</p>

<p>Trump jabbed Biden for being incoherent: "I really don't know what he said at the end of that sentence. I don't think he knows what he said."</p>

<p><strong>FALLOUT - JUNE 27 TO JULY 2</strong></p>

<p>"I know I'm not a young man, to state the obvious," Biden said the day after the debate, admitting a poor performance. "Nearly fell asleep on stage," he said on July 2.</p>

<p>Calls for Biden to step down would start in the hours after the debate. Calls from Biden aides to worried Democrats facing reelection campaigns who saw their political futures flashing before their eyes, wouldn't start until days later.</p>

<p>Some lawmakers started to break ranks, starting with US Representative Lloyd Doggett on July 2, and then gathering steam.</p>

<p>Angry donors told Biden's aides they would need to see a turnaround in the candidate's performance. Senior Democrats and Biden allies also began to hint at changes to the ticket.</p>

<p>House of Representatives Democrat Jim Clyburn - a kingmaker of sorts within the Democratic Party who was instrumental in Biden's 2020 win - said on July 2 that he would back Vice President Kamala Harris if Biden did depart and suggested the idea of a "mini-primary" if Biden stepped aside.</p>

<p>Former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi, a longtime Biden ally, said it was legitimate to ask whether Biden's performance in Atlanta was an "episode" or a condition. She also hinted that Biden would need to examine his choice to say in the race.</p>

<p><strong>THE DAM BREAKS - JULY 5 TO 8</strong></p>

<p>Biden would fail to quiet the chorus of dissent.</p>

<p>In his first major interview after the debate, on July 5, Biden told ABC News anchor George Stephanopoulos that only the "Lord Almighty" could cast him from the race.</p>

<p>More worrying to some Democrats, Biden said he could accept remaining in the race and losing to Trump "as long as I gave it my all and I did as good a job as I know I can do."</p>

<p>Thirty-six Democratic U.S. lawmakers and one independent who caucuses with the Democrats would ultimately call for Biden to step off the ticket over the 24 days that followed the debate.</p>

<p><strong>NATO, POLLS - JULY 9 TO 12</strong></p>

<p>Biden tried to move on. He gave interviews, held a press conference and gave stern speeches on the campaign trail as well as at the NATO summit of US allies.</p>

<p>But the events sometimes raised more concerns than they quieted.</p>

<p>At the NATO summit during the second week of July, Biden mixed up the names of his vice president Harris and his Republican rival Trump, and those of Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky and Russian President Vladimir Putin, whose countries are at war with each other.</p>

<p>Polls showed Biden trailing other Democrats in many of the key states and districts Democrats need to win in November, though polls nationwide continued to point to a close race.</p>

<p>Biden was unmoved, still believing he was the best candidate to face Trump, that he could rebound from this setback as he has so many times before, a view reinforced by a close circle of aides.</p>

<p><strong>TRUMP RALLY SHOOTING - JULY 13</strong></p>

<p>Trump was shot while giving a speech in Pennsylvania. The bullet grazed his ear, bloodied his face, and photos of the former president holding up his fist in defiance were shown widely.</p>

<p>Republicans spoke of divine providence, unifying around their candidate. Democrats worried if their own chances were cursed, seeing only a narrower path to any victory in November.</p>

<p>Days later, Biden got COVID while campaigning in Nevada. Recuperating at his Rehoboth Beach, Delaware, home, he would be left with time, alone and in isolation, to decide whether and how to end his campaign.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/klbdjneg_joe-biden-reuters_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden went from the party's figurehead to a liability.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-quits-us-presidential-race-full-text-of-announcement-6156766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Won't Contest US Presidential Polls: Full Text Of Announcement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-quits-us-presidential-race-full-text-of-announcement-6156766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 23:41:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden ended his re-election campaign on Sunday after fellow Democrats lost faith in his mental acuity and ability to beat Donald Trump, leaving the presidential race in uncharted territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden ended his re-election campaign on Sunday after fellow Democrats lost faith in his mental acuity and ability to beat Donald Trump, leaving the presidential race in uncharted territory.</p>

<p>Here's the full text of his announcement to quit the race:</p>

<p>My Fellow Americans,</p>

<p>Over the past three and a half years, we have made great progress as a Nation. Today, America has the strongest economy in the world. We've made historic investments in rebuilding our Nation, in lowering prescription drug costs for seniors, and in expanding affordable health care to a record number of Americans. We've provided critically needed care to a million veterans exposed to toxic substances. Passed the first gun safety law in 30 years. Appointed the first African American woman to the Supreme Court. And passed the most significant climate legislation in the history of the world. America has never been better positioned to lead than we are today.</p>

<p>I know none of this could have been done without you, the American people. Together, we overcame a once in a century pandemic and the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression. We've protected and preserved our Democracy. And we've revitalized and strengthened our alliances around the world.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/RMIRvlSOYw">pic.twitter.com/RMIRvlSOYw</a></p>
— Joe Biden (@JoeBiden) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeBiden/status/1815080881981190320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 21, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>It has been the greatest honour of my life to serve as your President. And while it has been my intention to seek reelection, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and to focus solely on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term.</p>

<p>I will speak to the Nation later this week in more detail about my decision.</p>

<p>For now, let me express my deepest gratitude to all those who have worked so hard to see me reelected. I want to thank Vice President Kamala Harris for being an extraordinary partner in all this work. And let me express my heartfelt appreciation to the American people for the faith and trust you have placed in me.</p>

<p>I believe today what I always have: that there is nothing America can't do - when we do it together. We just have to remember we are the United States of America.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6v5grhls_joe-biden_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden has quit from the US presidential race]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In Best Interest...": Biden Bows Out Of US Presidential Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-drops-out-of-us-presidential-election-race-says-it-is-in-best-interest-of-country-for-me-to-stand-down-6156671]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 23:24:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden announced Sunday that he was dropping out of his reelection battle with Donald Trump, in a historic move that plunges the already turbulent 2024 White House race into uncharted territory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden announced Sunday that he was dropping out of his reelection battle with Donald Trump, in a historic move that plunges the already turbulent 2024 White House race into uncharted territory. He endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris to replace him as the party's candidate.</p>

<p>"It has been the greatest honor of my life to serve you as president," the 81-year-old Democrat said in a letter in X, posted while he was recovering from Covid at his beach house in Delaware.</p>

<p>"While it has been my intention to seek reelection, I believe it is in the best interest of my party and the country for me to stand down and focus solely on fulfilling my duties as President for the remainder of my term."</p>

<p>Biden said he would "speak to the nation later this week in more detail about my decision."</p>

<p>The Democratic Party is now plunged into chaos and needs to find a new candidate by November's election, with Vice President Kamala Harris the frontrunner.</p>

<p>The stunning move makes Biden the first president in US history to pull out so late in an election race, and the first to bow out because of concerns over his mental acuity and health.</p>

<p>Biden spent more than three weeks resisting calls to step down following the shock of the June 27 debate, at one point insisting that only the "Lord Almighty" could convince him to back out.</p>

<p>In a bid to show he was up to the job, he gave a number of interviews and what was billed as a "big boy" press conference in which he took numerous questions, but made further gaffes including calling Kamala Harris "Vice President Trump."</p>

<p>A tide of voices within his own party calling on him to go, starting with donor and actor George Clooney and ending with former president Barack Obama, sealed his fate.</p>

<p>The end finally came shortly after Biden had been diagnosed with Covid, forcing him off the campaign trail and into isolation.</p>

<p>Biden's decision to pull out also caps a tense and chaotic period in the US election, with Trump having survived an assassination attempt at a campaign rally on July 13.</p>

<p>He joins a small club of US presidents who have decided to throw in the towel after just one term, with the last being Lyndon Johnson in 1968 -- a year also marked by political turmoil and violence.</p>

<p>Johnson's replacement as nominee, then-vice president Hubert Humphrey, went on to lose heavily to Richard Nixon.</p>

<p>But Democrats are counting on Harris to fare better, and hoping that she can prevent convicted felon Trump from making a sensational comeback to the Oval Office.</p>

<p>In recent weeks, the Biden campaign has reportedly been quietly carrying out a head-to-head survey of voters measuring how she matched up against Trump.</p>

<p>While Harris struggled to make an impact in her first years in the White House, she has emerged in the last year as a strong performer on the campaign trail on key messages such as abortion rights.</p>

<p>The former prosecutor has also made much of her life story as the first woman in US history to hold the vice presidency, as well as the first person of Black and South Asian origin.</p>

<p>Biden took office in January 2021 pledging to heal the "soul of America" after four turbulent years under Trump and the shock of the January 6, 2021 Capitol assault by his supporters.</p>

<p>Overcoming a reputation for verbal flubs, Barack Obama's former vice president pushed through a massive Covid recovery plan and a green industry scheme.</p>

<p>US allies welcomed his pledge that "America is back" following Trump's trampling on international alliances, and his strong support for Ukraine as it battled Russia's 2022 invasion.</p>

<p>But he faced criticism over the catastrophic US withdrawal from Afghanistan and inflation that meant overstretched Americans ignored otherwise positive economic numbers.</p>

<p>Behind it all were the ongoing concerns about his age with a series of senior moments, including tripping up the stairs to Air Force One and falling off his bike, contributing to the doddery image played up by Republicans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/pn27j9kg_joe-biden-_625x300_12_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said he would "speak to the nation later this week".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-why-did-my-father-have-to-die-relatives-mourn-bangladesh-unrest-victims-6156478]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Why Did My Father Have To Die": Relatives Mourn Bangladesh Unrest Victims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protests-why-did-my-father-have-to-die-relatives-mourn-bangladesh-unrest-victims-6156478]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:45:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Grief-stricken widow Fatema Begum wept when hospital staff said her husband had been killed in the unrest that has roiled Bangladesh for nearly a week. She wept again when they refused to hand over his body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Grief-stricken widow Fatema Begum wept when hospital staff said her husband had been killed in the unrest that has roiled Bangladesh for nearly a week. She wept again when they refused to hand over his body.</p>

<p>Islam is the majority religion in the south Asian country, where 155 people have died since Tuesday in clashes between student protesters and police over contentious civil service hiring rules.</p>

<p>The faith's customs dictate that anyone who dies must be given a prompt burial.</p>

<p>But staff at one of the biggest hospitals in the capital Dhaka has a longstanding requirement to only release bodies to relatives with police permission, and that is no longer easily forthcoming.</p>

<p>"Where is my husband?" Begum, 40, shouted at staffers outside the hospital's morgue, tears streaming down her cheeks. "Give me his body."</p>

<p>Begum's husband Kamal Mia, 45, eked out a tough living as a pedal-rickshaw driver, transporting people around the sprawling megacity of 20 million people for the equivalent of a dollar per fare.</p>

<p>The family says he was not taking part in any of the clashes that have wrought widespread destruction around the city, but was killed by stray police fire.</p>

<p>Begum and her two daughters were told to go to a nearby police station for clearance. When her eldest daughter Anika went there, it was barricaded shut.</p>

<p>Officers had closed the station after arson attacks on dozens of police posts by protesters.</p>

<p>Anika was then sent to another police station farther away - a 10-kilometre (six-mile) round trip from the hospital - despite a nationwide government-imposed curfew.</p>

<p>Police there refused to give the necessary permission for the release of the body.</p>

<p>"My father was not a protester," Anika said. "Why did my father have to die?"</p>

<p><strong>Tested to the limits</strong></p>

<p>Mia was among more than 60 people whose deaths in the unrest were recorded at Dhaka Medical College Hospital, the country's largest healthcare facility in the heart of the capital.</p>

<p>The relentless influx of patients since the start of the police crackdown on protesters has stretched the hospital to its limits.</p>

<p>Ambulances, private cars and rickshaws carrying the wounded were at one point arriving an average of once per minute, an AFP correspondent at the scene saw.</p>

<p>The entry gate of the emergency department, guarded by paramilitary Ansar forces, was blood-stained.</p>

<p>As soon as casualties arrive, staff rush with stretchers and trolleys. Some wounded people were given first aid for a rubber bullet, while others who were hit by injuries had to wait -- sometimes for hours -- for the doctors on duty.</p>

<p>Some are brought in already dead. Loved ones burst into tears as soon as a doctor or nurse makes it official.</p>

<p>A group of volunteers stood by the emergency department using loudhailers to call for blood donors after the hospital's stocks were depleted.</p>

<p>Among the dozens of grieving relatives at the hospital, the steps the police took to quell the student demonstrations have prompted untempered fury against Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's government.</p>

<p>"Hasina's police have killed my son to keep her in power," the father of a 30-year-old mobile phone shop owner shot dead in the capital, who asked not to be identified, told AFP.</p>

<p>"God will punish her for this unjust torture."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/p2p0h4m8_bangladesh-protests-afp_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Protesters throw stones as they clash with police during the ongoing anti-quota protest in Dhaka.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israelis-not-welcome-at-paris-olympic-games-says-french-mp-sparks-row-6156170]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israelis "Not Welcome At Paris Olympic Games", Says French MP, Sparks Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israelis-not-welcome-at-paris-olympic-games-says-french-mp-sparks-row-6156170]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 21:45:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major French Jewish group on Sunday slammed a hard-left MP for saying Israeli athletes were not welcome at the Paris Olympics from next week because of the war in Gaza, calling the comments "irresponsible".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major French Jewish group on Sunday slammed a hard-left MP for saying Israeli athletes were not welcome at the Paris Olympics from next week because of the war in Gaza, calling the comments "irresponsible".</p>

<p>France Unbowed (LFI) lawmaker Thomas Portes was "putting a target on the backs of Israeli athletes," said Yonathan Arfi, head of the Representative Council of Jewish Institutions in France, on X.</p>

<p>Portes had said at a rally in support of Palestinians that "the Israeli delegation is not welcome in Paris. Israeli sportspeople are not welcome at the Paris Olympic Games" and called for "mobilisation" around the event.</p>

<p>He later told the Parisien newspaper that "France's diplomats should pressure the International Olympic Committee to bar the Israeli flag and anthem, as is done for Russia".</p>

<p>"It's time to end the double standard," Portes added.</p>

<p>Opposition to Israel's campaign in Gaza was a centrepiece of LFI's campaign ahead of European elections last month.</p>

<p>The territory's Hamas-run health ministry said Sunday that almost 39,000 people had been killed in the fighting, which was sparked by the bloody October 7 attacks by Hamas.</p>

<p>Perceived ambiguity in LFI's response to the October massacre broke apart an alliance of left-wing parties, which grudgingly reformed for this month's parliamentary polls but has since struggled to find common ground despite coming first.</p>

<p>Crif head Arfi said Israeli athletes were "already the most in danger at the Olympic Games", recalling the 11 "murdered by Palestinian terrorists" in 1972 at the Munich Games.</p>

<p>Beyond the Jewish group, Portes also came under attack from nominal parliamentary allies in the Socialist party and conservatives.</p>

<p>"Of course Israeli athletes are welcome, like all sportspeople from all over the world. Not for who they are but for what they do," Socialist MP Jerome Guedj posted.</p>

<p>Some LFI lawmakers came out in support of Portes.</p>

<p>"The Israeli flag, stained with the blood of Gaza's innocents, should not fly in Paris this summer," MP Aymeric Caron wrote.</p>

<p>Israel's football team is set to play its first Olympic match against Mali in Paris' Parc des Prince stadium on Wednesday, two days before the opening ceremony.</p>

<p>Israeli President Isaac Herzog's office said Sunday that he would attend Friday's boat parade on the river Seine and a commemoration for the Israelis killed in Munich in 1972.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o4fkva7o_thomas-portes_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-bangladesh-students-are-protesting-against-job-quotas-6156152]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Bangladesh Students Are Protesting Against Job Quotas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-bangladesh-students-are-protesting-against-job-quotas-6156152]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 21:42:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Supreme Court on Sunday scrapped most of the quotas on government jobs that had sparked nationwide protests by students that have killed at least 139 people in recent days.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Supreme Court on Sunday scrapped most of the quotas on government jobs that had sparked nationwide protests by students that have killed at least 139 people in recent days.</p>

<p>Here are details of the protests and their history:</p>

<p><strong>WHAT TRIGGERED THE PROTESTS?</strong></p>

<p>The demonstrations started last month after the High Court reinstated a quota system for government jobs, overturning a 2018 decision by Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's government to scrap it.</p>

<p>That move, which covered the 30% of jobs reserved for family members of freedom fighters in the 1971 war for independence from Pakistan, followed similar student protests.</p>

<p>But the Supreme Court suspended the high court order after the government's appeal. On Sunday it dismissed the lower court order and directed that 93% of jobs should be open to candidates on merit.</p>

<p>The court reserved 5% of jobs for family members of independence fighters and 2% for people from so-called backward groups and the disabled.</p>

<p>The students had stepped up their protest when Hasina refused to meet their demands, citing the court proceedings.</p>

<p>She called the protesters "razakar", an offensive term for those accused of collaborating with Pakistan's army in 1971 to betray the country.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT IS THE QUOTA SYSTEM?</strong></p>

<p>Introduced in 1972, Bangladesh's quota system has gone through several changes since. When it was abolished in 2018, 56% of government jobs were blocked under various quotas.</p>

<p>The bulk covered groups such as freedom fighters' families, with women and those from underdeveloped districts receiving a share of a tenth each, with 5% allotted to indigenous communities, and 1% for the disabled.</p>

<p>The protesting students want all categories abolished, except the last two.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT SPARKED THE VIOLENCE?</strong></p>

<p>The protests turned violent last week following clashes between thousands of anti-quota demonstrators and members of the student wing of Hasina's Awami League party. Police fired rubber bullets and hurled sound grenades and tear gas to scatter protesters who also blocked railway tracks and major roads.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT DO THE STUDENTS FEAR?</strong></p>

<p>Hasina is the daughter of Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, the founding father of Bangladesh, who led its freedom movement. Protesters and critics say the 30% quota for families of freedom fighters favours Awami League supporters, which led the independence fight.</p>

<p>Experts also attribute the unrest to stagnant job growth in the private sector, making public sector jobs, with their accompanying regular wage hikes and privileges, very attractive.</p>

<p>The quotas shrink the number of government jobs open for all, hurting aspirants who want them filled on the basis of merit.</p>

<p>They have sparked anger among students grappling with high youth unemployment, as nearly 32 million young people are out of work or education in a population of 170 million.</p>

<p>The economy, once among the world's fastest-growing, has stagnated, inflation hovers around 10% and dollar reserves are shrinking.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT HAS HASINA SAID?</strong></p>

<p>The protests are the first challenge to Hasina's government since she won a fourth consecutive term in January in elections boycotted by the main opposition. She has condemned the loss of lives and called for patience ahead of the Supreme Court's verdict.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/h16elgdo_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke rises as anti-quota supporters clash with police and Awami League supporters in Dhaka.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/caged-like-terrorist-in-jail-being-denied-basic-human-rights-imran-khan-6155904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Caged Like "Terrorist" In Jail, Being Denied Basic Human Rights: Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/caged-like-terrorist-in-jail-being-denied-basic-human-rights-imran-khan-6155904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 20:52:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former premier Imran Khan has claimed that he is being caged like a "terrorist", and was denied basic prisoner and human rights in a "death cell" at a high-security jail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's jailed former premier Imran Khan has claimed that he is being caged like a "terrorist", and was denied basic prisoner and human rights in a "death cell" at a high-security jail.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old Pakistan-Tehreek-e-Insaf party founder made these claims in a rare interview from behind bars with British publication 'The Sunday Times', the Dawn newspaper reported on Sunday.</p>

<p>"I am confined in a 7ft by 8ft death cell, typically reserved for terrorists to ensure they have no contact with anyone," he told the newspaper.</p>

<p>"It is solitary confinement with barely any space to move. I am under constant surveillance by the agencies, being recorded 24/7, and I am denied basic prisoner and human rights such as visitation," he said.</p>

<p>The interview was conducted via his lawyers, as - according to the article - he is not allowed a pencil and paper.</p>

<p>Imran Khan has been imprisoned at the high-security Adiala Jail in Rawalpindi for almost a year upon his conviction in three cases - the Toshakhana corruption case, the cipher case, and the un-Islamic marriage case -- in which his wife, Bushra Bibi, is also jailed.</p>

<p>He faces over 200 cases and has been convicted in a few of them.</p>

<p>Though the former-cricketer-turned-politician had secured bail or his conviction was set aside, he has not been released.</p>

<p>Imran Khan was arrested on August 5 last year after his conviction in the first Toshakhana corruption case filed by the Election Commission of Pakistan.</p>

<p>Since then, he has been kept in jail in various cases.</p>

<p>After setting aside Imran Khan's conviction in the Iddat (un-Islamic marriage) case earlier this month, the court ruled that he should be released from jail if he is not wanted in another case.</p>

<p>But within hours, he was arrested in another Toshakhana case along with his 49-year-old wife Bushra, and both are still in jail.</p>

<p>He frequently alleges about not being treated well in jail, but authorities so far have been rejecting his claims and allegations.</p>

<p>Responding to reports about Imran Khan's imprisonment conditions, Information Minister Atta Tarar denied he was being held in a death row cell.</p>

<p>"The Sharif family endured harsh conditions, but Imran Khan enjoys presidential suites at Adiala Jail, with access to a gym, kitchen, walking gallery, and luxurious meals," he said at a press conference.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Imran Khan's wife, Bushra also expressed grave concerns about her husband's safety in the Adiala Jail, alleging that he was kept in inhumane conditions and given contaminated food.</p>

<p>According to Bushra, Imran Khan's life is in danger, keeping in view the past incidents where he was allegedly poisoned and shot at.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/t32m7b7o_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imran Khan faces over 200 cases and has been convicted in a few of them. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-shoots-down-missile-fired-from-yemen-after-striking-houthis-6155762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Shoots Down Missile Fired From Yemen After Striking Houthis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-shoots-down-missile-fired-from-yemen-after-striking-houthis-6155762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 20:33:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel said it shot down a missile launched from Yemen on Sunday and the Yemeni Houthi movement said it had fired several missiles at the Israeli city of Eilat after Israel's first public strike against the Iran-aligned group a day earlier.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel said it shot down a missile launched from Yemen on Sunday and the Yemeni Houthi movement said it had fired several missiles at the Israeli city of Eilat after Israel's first public strike against the Iran-aligned group a day earlier.</p>

<p>The Houthis have launched missiles and drones at Israel and disrupted global trade through the Red Sea in response to Israel's assault on Gaza, further destabilising the Middle East as war in the Palestinian enclave rages on after nine months.</p>

<p>Israel says the Houthis have launched 200 attacks against it since the Gaza war began, many of them intercepted and most of them not deadly.</p>

<p>But a rare Houthi drone strike on Friday hit Tel Aviv and killed one person, prompting Israel to announce its first strikes against the group on Saturday. The strikes by warplanes hit near the Yemeni port of Hodeidah and killed six people, local medics said.</p>

<p>The Houthi movement, known formally as Ansar Allah, said on Sunday it would continue to attack Israel in response.</p>

<p>Houthi spokesperson Mohammed Abdulsalam told Qatar's Al Jazeera TV there would be "no red lines ... all sensitive institutions ... will be a target for us."</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its Arrow 3 missile defence system had shot down a surface-to-surface missile projectile launched from Yemen on Sunday before it crossed into Israeli territory.</p>

<p>Before the interception, air raid sirens sounded in the Red Sea port city of Eilat, sending residents running for shelter.</p>

<p>Sunday's attack prolonged an escalation of violence between Israel and the Houthis that began with the Houthi drone strike that hit the centre of Tel Aviv on Friday. One man was killed and four other people were wounded, officials said.</p>

<p>The Israeli warplanes' air raid on Hodeidah on Saturday killed six people and wounded more than 80, medical sources in Yemen told Reuters, describing all as civilians.</p>

<p>Images from the scene showed a fiery blaze and dense smoke rising from the site of the strike. A Houthi-run TV channel said the strikes had hit an oil facility and power station.</p>

<p>Israeli officials say Hodeidah port has been used by the Houthis to receive weapons shipments from Iran.</p>

<p>PROXY BATTLE</p>

<p>The exchanges are part of a spillover from the Gaza war that has drawn in regional and world powers.</p>

<p>Iran-aligned groups including the Houthis have fired rockets and missiles at Israel saying they are doing so in support of Palestinians and the Islamist militant group Hamas that governs Gaza. The United States and its allies back Israel and provide weapons to it.</p>

<p>The war began on Oct. 7 after a Hamas-led attack on southern Israel in which about 1,200 people were killed and over 250 taken hostage back to Gaza, according to Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>Israel has since bombed and invaded Gaza as part of what it says is a campaign to eliminate Hamas, killing nearly 39,000 people, according to health officials in the enclave.</p>

<p>The Houthis, who control much of the north of Yemen and other large population centres, have previously claimed targeting Eilat and other attacks directed at Israel, saying they are acting in retaliation for Israel's war on Gaza.</p>

<p>The group has also attacked Red Sea shipping routes for months.</p>

<p>Hamas' allies include Iran-backed groups such as the Houthis, Hezbollah in Lebanon and Iraqi paramilitaries.</p>

<p>The Houthi movement consists primarily of members a minority Shi'ite Muslim group in Yemen and has controlled the country's capital, Sanaa, for years.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3rualgd_yemen-strike-reuters_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli strikes by warplanes hit near the Yemeni port of Hodeidah. (FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-historic-relationship-with-russia-not-going-to-cut-it-off-us-6155703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Has Historic Relationship With Russia, Not Going To Cut It Off: US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-has-historic-relationship-with-russia-not-going-to-cut-it-off-us-6155703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There is no tangible evidence of India deepening its military and technology relationship with Russia, US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan has said, asserting that Moscow has become a "junior partner" to China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no tangible evidence of India deepening its military and technology relationship with Russia, US National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan has said, asserting that Moscow, which has become a "junior partner" to China, is not necessarily going to be a "great and reliable friend" to India in a future contingency.</p>

<p>Mr Sullivan made remarks at the Aspen Security Forum in Colorado while responding to questions about the recent visit of Prime Minister Narendra Modi to Russia for bilateral talks with President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>"I think the biggest question is: Do we see tangible evidence that India is deepening its military and technology relationship with Russia? And I did not see tangible evidence out of that visit that it was deepening; I didn't see deliverables in that space," Mr Sullivan said.</p>

<p>"How concerned were you when Prime Minister Modi met President Putin, essentially at the same time that President Joe Biden was hosting the NATO leaders in Washington?" he was asked.</p>

<p>"Don't you think the bear hug was significant then?" he was asked. "Well, Modi has a certain way, of course, of greeting world leaders. I've seen it up close and personal, actually,'' Mr Sullivan said.</p>

<p>The Biden Administration, he said, never wants to see countries that the US cares about, who are its partners and friends, show up in Moscow and hug Putin. "Of course, we don't. I'm not going to sit here and tell people otherwise," he said.</p>

<p>''But in terms of our relationship with India, you know, we see enormous opportunities in technology, in economics, and in the statecraft and geopolitics of the wider Indo-Pacific region. And we want to deepen that relationship as equals, as two sovereign countries who also have relationships with other countries. And India has a historic relationship with Russia that they're not going to cut off,'' Mr Sullivan said.</p>

<p>"But we do believe that we want to continue to have a deep dialogue with India about the specifics and the nature of that relationship and whether it evolves, particularly, Demetri, because Russia is getting closer and closer to China, and as the junior partner to China, is not necessarily going to be a great and reliable friend to India in a future contingency or crisis."</p>

<p>"That's not something India needs to hear from Jake Sullivan, but it is a fact in the world. And it's something that we take into account as we have our strategic dialogue with India,'' said the US National Security Advisor, who was in New Delhi last month and met Prime Minister Modi and his counterpart Ajit Doval.</p>

<p>Mr Ajit Doval and Mr Sullivan also held a telephone conversation on July 12, days after PM Modi visited Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/vlvc0v3o_jake-sullivan-reuters_625x300_18_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ajit Doval and Mr Sullivan held a conversation days after PM Modi visited Russia (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-kamala-harris-democrats-would-bet-against-us-history-of-sexism-racism-6155543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Quits Presidential Race. Will Kamala Harris Take On Trump Now?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-kamala-harris-democrats-would-bet-against-us-history-of-sexism-racism-6155543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 19:57:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Democratic party will be taking a historic gamble if it turns to Vice President Kamala Harris to become its presidential candidate, betting that a]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Democratic party will be taking a historic gamble if it turns to Vice President Kamala Harris to become its presidential candidate, betting that a Black woman can overcome racism, sexism and her own missteps as a politician to defeat Republican Donald Trump.</p>

<p>In more than two centuries of democracy, American voters have elected only one Black president and never a woman, a record that makes even some Black voters wonder if Harris can crash through the hardest ceiling in US politics.</p>

<p>"Will her race and gender be an issue? Absolutely," said LaTosha Brown, a political strategist and co-founder of the Black Lives Matter Fund.</p>

<p>Harris would face other big challenges: if promoted to the top of the ticket, she would have barely three months to campaign and unite the party and donors behind her.</p>

<p>Yet many Democrats are excited about her chances.</p>

<p>Some three dozen Democratic lawmakers have voiced fears that President Joe Biden, 81, will lose an election that the party has cast as a battle for the future of US democracy because he lacks the mental and physical stamina to win and serve four more years.</p>

<p>Many fear Trump and the Republicans could not only take the White House, but both houses of Congress.</p>

<p>Biden ended his reelection campaign on Sunday. He said, in a post on X, he will remain in his role as president and commander-in-chief until his term ends in January 2025 and will address the nation this week.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, is two decades younger than Trump and a leader in the party on abortion rights, an issue which resonates with younger voters and Democrats' progressive base. Proponents argue she would energize those voters, consolidate Black support, and bring sharp debating skills to prosecute the political case against the former president.</p>

<p>Her candidacy would offer a contrast with Trump and his vice presidential running mate, Senator J.D. Vance, the two white men on the Republican ticket, Brown said.</p>

<p>"That to me is reflective of America's past. She is reflective of America's now and future," Brown said.</p>

<p>But despite earning praise in the last few weeks for her strong defense of Biden, some Democrats remain concerned about Harris' shaky first two years in office, short-lived campaign for the 2020 Democratic nomination, and - perhaps most of all - the weight of a long history of racial and gender discrimination in the United States.</p>

<p>In a hypothetical head-to-head matchup, Harris and Trump were tied with 44% support each in a July 15-16 Reuters/Ipsos poll, conducted immediately after the assassination attempt against Trump. Trump led Biden 43% to 41% in that same poll, though the 2 percentage point difference was within the poll's 3 percentage point margin of error.</p>

<p>Harris's approval ratings, while low, are a tick higher than Biden's. According to polling outfit Five Thirty Eight, 38.6 percent of Americans approve of Harris while 50.4 percent disapprove. Biden has 38.5 percent approval and 56.2 percent disapproval.</p>

<p>'NO SAFE OPTION'</p>

<p>"If you think that there is consensus among the people who want Joe Biden to leave that they will support Kamala - Vice President Harris - you would be mistaken," Representative Alexandra Ocasio-Cortez, a Biden supporter, said on Instagram. "There's no safe option."</p>

<p>The United States elected Barack Obama, the first and only Black president in 2008. The only woman to head a presidential ticket of a major party, Hillary Clinton, lost to Trump in 2016.</p>

<p>Supporters of Harris, the first woman and first Black and South Asian person to serve as vice president, argue she has already weathered unfair attacks related to her race and gender and is prepared for more.</p>

<p>"America has a history of racism, sexism, so I'm sure that will factor into this conversation, factor into her campaign," said Jamal Simmons, a former Harris aide.</p>

<p>But he said there is a flip side: Black voters could be galvanized if Harris is put at the top of the ticket, and women, including some who regret not voting for Clinton in 2016, would back her as well.</p>

<p>"It's also true that she will benefit from her race and her gender, that many African Americans may rally to her candidacy," he said.</p>

<p>Harris benefits from greater name recognition than the other Democratic leaders who have been floated as potential presidential candidates, he said. California Governor Gavin Newsom and Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer are among those talked about in Democratic circles as possible replacements.</p>

<p>"While she has flaws and faults like everyone, we know those flaws and faults, so you can build a campaign with clarity. Any other candidates are complete unknowns," Simmons said.</p>

<p>One former Democratic lawmaker, speaking on condition of anonymity, said he thought Harris was a bigger risk because of her record than her race.</p>

<p>Harris was plagued by staff turnover at the beginning of her vice presidency and showed little progress on her portfolios of protecting voting rights and stemming migration from Central America.</p>

<p>"I think the race thing is just a compounding factor or an exacerbating factor," the former lawmaker said. "Any of it's going to be a gamble, but I like the odds with another candidate, even if that means Kamala at the top of the ticket."</p>

<p>'PATRIARCHY IS A HELL OF A DRUG'</p>

<p>Trump has used racist and sexist language, explicitly and in code. In 2020 he said he had "heard" Harris, a US citizen born in California, did not qualify to be a candidate for vice president.</p>

<p>At a rally in Michigan on Saturday, Trump piled on Harris for the way she laughs.</p>

<p>"I call her Laughing Kamala," Trump said. "You ever watch her laugh? She's crazy."</p>

<p>Trump's campaign said Democrats were deploying "classic disinformation" about his language and noted Harris's dispute with Biden in a 2019 debate about school busing and her criticism of Biden for working with segregationists in the Senate.</p>

<p>"In contrast, President Trump is polling at record-high levels with African Americans," Trump campaign senior adviser Jason Miller said in a statement.</p>

<p>Trump made false "birtherism" claims against Obama, who was born in Hawaii. Those falsehoods gained traction among far-right activists and his nationalist base, prompting an exasperated Obama, blasting "carnival barkers," to release a longer version of his birth certificate from the White House.</p>

<p>Polling at the time showed a quarter of all Americans - and 45 percent of Republicans - believed Obama had not been born in the country.</p>

<p>"You've got birtherism 2.0," said Cliff Albright, co-founder and CEO of Black Voters Matter Fund, an Atlanta-based non-profit, referring to Harris.</p>

<p>Nadia Brown, director of the women's and gender studies program at Georgetown University, said despite the rise of Black political leaders, there remains a notable reluctance to accept women in key leadership roles.</p>

<p>"Patriarchy is a hell of a drug," Brown said. "With racism, we know it, we can call it out. The mood that we're not seeing as articulately expressed is a real reticence to have a Black woman in particular as a leader."</p>

<p>Harris's standing in the party has improved with her aggressive advocacy for reproductive rights after the Supreme Court in 2022 struck down Roe v Wade, which protected women's right to abortion.</p>

<p>Biden credited her with helping to prevent a "red wave" of Republican victories in that year's midterm elections, and Harris has crisscrossed the country as a top campaign spokesperson on abortion rights.</p>

<p>Harris could also inherit Biden's strong support among Black voters, who helped propel him to the 2020 Democratic nomination.</p>

<p>But Black women have not entirely given up on Biden.</p>

<p>Donna Brazile, a political strategist and former chair of the Democratic National Committee, said on Friday she had joined 1,400 Black women in a letter of support for a Biden-Harris ticket and in condemnation of disunity within the party.</p>

<p>And if the party ends up coalescing around Harris, she could receive some of the blame from voters who say Democratic leaders covered up his frailties.</p>

<p>"I'm kind of done with the Democrats. So many knew about Biden's condition and hid it. Kamala was part of that," said Gina Gannon, 65, a retiree in the battleground state of Georgia, who voted for Trump in 2016 and Biden in 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1810n4to_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris would face big challenges, if promoted to the top of the ticket.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israel-after-strike-on-lebanon-6155385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Fires Rockets At Israel After Strike On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-fires-rockets-at-israel-after-strike-on-lebanon-6155385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 19:24:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Hezbollah on Sunday said it fired Katyusha rockets at northern Israel in response to an overnight Israeli strike that, according to state media, hit a weapons depot and wounded six people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Hezbollah on Sunday said it fired Katyusha rockets at northern Israel in response to an overnight Israeli strike that, according to state media, hit a weapons depot and wounded six people.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has traded near-daily cross-border fire with Israeli forces in support of Hamas since the Palestinian militant group's October 7 attack on southern Israel triggered war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed Hezbollah said it targeted northern Israel's Dafna area with Katyusha rockets "in response to the Israeli enemy's attacks that targeted civilians in the town of Adloun, injuring several of them".</p>

<p>This comes after the Israeli military said its air force "struck two Hezbollah weapons storage facilities in southern Lebanon, containing rockets and additional weaponry".</p>

<p>Late on Saturday, Lebanon's state-run National News Agency said "the Israeli enemy launched a raid" on the town of Adloun, about 30 kilometres (19 miles) from the border with Israel, later saying the target was "an ammunition depot".</p>

<p>"Six civilians sustained moderate injuries," the NNA said on Sunday, revising the figure up from three the night before.</p>

<p>Rockets were still exploding about an hour after the strike was first reported, the NNA said, with videos circulating online showing several large explosions in Adloun.</p>

<p>"Shrapnel from the explosions flew to surrounding villages," the NNA said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah on Sunday said in separate statements that three of its fighters were killed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier on Saturday, Hezbollah and its Palestinian ally Hamas had fired rocket salvos and explosive-laden drones at Israeli positions.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said it had launched "dozens of Katyusha rockets" towards northern Israel "in response" to a strike blamed on Israel that injured civilians.</p>

<p>Hamas's armed wing, the Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, said they also fired a rocket salvo from south Lebanon towards an Israeli military position in the Upper Galilee.</p>

<p>The violence since October has killed at least 518 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally. Most of the dead have been fighters, but they have included at least 104 civilians.</p>

<p>On the Israeli side, 18 soldiers and 13 civilians have been killed, according to Israeli authorities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/6om8qmno_hezbollah_625x300_05_March_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-pledge-huge-response-to-israel-strike-as-gaza-violence-spreads-6154876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthis Pledge "Huge" Response to Israel Strike As Gaza Violence Spreads]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthis-pledge-huge-response-to-israel-strike-as-gaza-violence-spreads-6154876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 21 Jul 2024 17:54:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthi rebels promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel on Sunday following a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as violence sparked by the Gaza war gripped the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Houthi rebels promised a "huge" retaliation against Israel on Sunday following a deadly strike on the port of Hodeida, as violence sparked by the Gaza war gripped the region.</p>

<p>Israel bombed the Palestinian territory, Lebanon and Yemen in quick succession this week in response to attacks from Iran-backed militant groups.</p>

<p>Despite Washington asserting that a deal to end more than nine months of devastating war between Israel and Gaza rulers Hamas was near the "goal line", the Israeli military said it intercepted a missile fired from Yemen as it pressed on with its offensive in the besieged Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Dozens have been killed since Saturday across Gaza, the civil defence agency said, including in strikes on homes in the central Nuseirat and Bureij areas and displaced people near southern Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>Residents said a major operation was underway in the Saudi district west of Rafah in the south, reporting heavy artillery and clashes.</p>

<p>The deadly strikes in Gaza came hours after Hezbollah and its ally Hamas said they fired at Israeli positions from south Lebanon, while Yemen's Houthi rebels vowed to respond to Israeli warplanes hitting a key port.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree said the rebel's &nbsp;"response to the Israeli aggression against our country is inevitably coming and will be huge."</p>

<h2>Fire still raging</h2>

<p>The fire left raging by the strikes on rebel-held Hodeida port "is seen across the Middle East and the significance is clear," Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The Houthis control swathes of Yemen, including much of its Red Sea coast, while the internationally recognised government has withdrawn to Aden on the south coast.</p>

<p>Detailing the first strikes claimed by Israel in Yemen, Gallant warned of further operations if the Houthis "dare to attack us" after a rebel drone strike killed one in Tel Aviv on Friday.</p>

<p>In Hodeida, three people were killed and 87 wounded, health officials said in a statement carried by Houthi media.</p>

<p>Firefighters struggled to contain the massive blaze caused by the strike on Hodeida, with a port employee saying fuel storage tanks and a power plant were still on fire on Sunday.</p>

<p>Following the strikes, the Israeli military said on Sunday it had intercepted a missile fired from Yemen towards the Red Sea resort town of Eilat. Saree said the rebels had fired ballistic missiles towards the port city.</p>

<h2>Netanyahu travels to Washington</h2>

<p>The trio of militant groups has vowed to keep up attacks on Israel until a truce ends the violence in Gaza, which lies in ruins, with most residents forced to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The Gaza war was triggered by Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The militants also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom are still in Gaza, including 42 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military retaliation to wipe out Hamas has killed at least 38,983 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-ruled Gaza.</p>

<p>The war has also unleashed hunger and health crises in Gaza, with Israel and the United Nations trading blame for vital aid supplies failing to reach those in need.</p>

<p>After the detection of poliovirus in Gaza sewage, though no individual cases, the World Health Organization said there were "monumental" constraints to mounting a timely response.</p>

<p>WHO spokesman Christian Lindmeier said Friday the agency believes many more diseases are "spreading out of control" inside Gaza.</p>

<p>The months-long war has also brought Israelis to the streets, sometimes in their tens of thousands, focused on securing the release of the remaining hostages.</p>

<p>"Bring them home," demonstrator Ofira Azrieli said Saturday in Tel Aviv, appealing to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<p>The premier is due to address US lawmakers Wednesday in Washington, where he will be under pressure to reach a ceasefire with Hamas.</p>

<p>His office announced that he will meet US President Joe Biden on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/6l5ssuro_houthi-rebels-_625x300_30_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>