<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:50:12 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-long-would-it-take-to-reach-elon-musk-levels-of-wealth-the-answer-is-7009592]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Long Would It Take A Salaried Person To Reach Musk Levels Of Wealth?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-long-would-it-take-to-reach-elon-musk-levels-of-wealth-the-answer-is-7009592]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:36:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In terms of his earnings from assets, Mr Musk's wealth primarily comes from his stakes in various companies like Tesla, SpaceX, X (formerly Twitter) and The Boring Company.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk is a billionaire with the highest net worth in the world, according to Bloomberg Index. And after Donald Trump's win in the US presidential election, the tech tycoon is close to breaking his wealth record (of $340 billion in 2021) following the rally of Tesla's shares. The world's richest person gained almost $21 billion on Monday as Tesla stock jumped 9 per cent, boosting his net worth to $335 billion, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. So how long would it take for a salaried person to reach Musk levels of wealth?</p>

<p><strong>Also Read | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-ndtv-analysis-elon-musk-donald-trump-and-worlds-largest-maga-megaphone-6938456">Elon Musk, Donald Trump And World's Largest MAGA Megaphone</a></strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/business/average-salary-by-state/" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>Forbes</em></a>, the average annual salary in US is $59,428. It would take more than three million years for an average US resident to amass Mr Musk's wealth by working a regular job, as per Statista.</p>

<p>A study on UK's working population claimed that it would take the average person 17 weeks and one hour to earn what Tesla's founder and CEO does in five minutes. The research was done by mathematical modelling tool Gigacalculator.com that studied the earnings of the 10 highest paid bosses according to Bloomberg's CEO pay index, and compared them to the average Briton's full-time salary of 35,423 pounds.</p>

<p>In June, shareholders of Tesla approved in favour of restoring Mr Musk's 10-year pay plan of $45 billion. As per current exchange rate, this comes to about Rs 3.80 lakh crore in a year or Rs 1,040 crore per day.</p>

<p>In September, a new report from Informa Connect Academy, a group that tracks wealth, said that Mr Musk is on track to become the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/article/2024/sep/07/elon-musk-first-trillionaire-2027">world's first trillionaire</a> by 2027. The report further said that the billionaire's wealth has been growing at an average annual rate of 110 per cent.</p>

<p>In terms of his earnings from assets, Mr Musk's wealth primarily comes from his stakes in various companies like Tesla, SpaceX, X (formerly Twitter) and The Boring Company.</p>

<p>Mr Musk was born in Pretoria, South Africa, in 1971 and showed his talents for entrepreneurship early, going door-do-door with his brother selling homemade chocolate Easter Eggs. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-61234231" rel="noindex,nofollow"><em>BBC</em></a>, he developed his first computer game at the age of 12.</p>

<p>Mr Musk dropped out of Stanford University and founded two technology start-ups during the "dotcom boom" of the 1990s. An online banking company that was bought by PayPal for $1.5 billion in 2002.</p>

<p>He bought X two years ago and since then, influence on the platform has skyrocketed with followers nearly doubling to 194 million.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gniajb58_elon-musk-wealth_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's wealth increased at a rapid pace after Donald Trump's election win.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newlywed-in-brazil-strangled-after-she-slapped-co-worker-who-asked-for-a-kiss-7009502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Newlywed In Brazil Strangled After Slapping Co-Worker Who Asked For A Kiss]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/newlywed-in-brazil-strangled-after-she-slapped-co-worker-who-asked-for-a-kiss-7009502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:22:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police investigations revealed that Bastos Santos confessed to the heinous crime, stating that he strangled Ms Barbosa after she rejected his romantic advances.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking crime that has shaken the community, a 38-year-old caregiver in Brazil was allegedly murdered by her co-worker. Notably,&nbsp;Cintia Ribeiro Barbosa&nbsp;and Marcelo Junior Bastos Santos worked as caregivers for the elderly in a home in the Cidade Jardim neighbourhood.&nbsp;According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/newlywed-allegedly-strangled-death-coworker-rejected-kiss-days-after-wedding-8743768">People</a></em>, Ms Barbosa's body was found on a property next to the house where she worked in Goiania, Brazil, on Tuesday, November 5, a day after she was killed.&nbsp;Police investigations revealed that Bastos Santos confessed to the heinous crime, stating that he strangled Ms Barbosa after she rejected his romantic advances. The newlywed mother of four reportedly slapped Santos after he asked her to kiss him, prompting a violent response.</p>

<p>As reported by<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://g1.globo.com/go/goias/noticia/2024/11/08/colega-confessa-como-matou-cuidadora-de-idosos-estrangulada-apos-ela-negar-beijo-video.ghtml"> g1</a></em>, Bastos Santos allegedly placed Barbosa in a deadly chokehold. Following the strangulation, he reportedly used diaper tape to restrain her hands.&nbsp;Afterwards, he allegedly disposed of&nbsp;Ms Barbosa's body by throwing it over the wall and hiding it in an unoccupied adjacent property, where it was later discovered.</p>

<p>Authorities launched an investigation into Ms Barbosa's&nbsp;disappearance after her husband, whom she had married just eight days prior, reported her missing.&nbsp;The man stated that he took his wife to work, but that she had not returned home and was not answering her cell phone.</p>

<p>Police chief Carlos Alfama explained, ''He thought the victim had died and went to another room. Suddenly, he realised that she had regained consciousness and was trying to run away. The suspect then grabbed Cintia and allegedly strangled her again with masking tape.&nbsp;He strangled the victim with this masking tape to ensure she would die.''</p>

<p>During the investigation, he noted that there was disturbed earth in the backyard of the residence where the woman worked and that the house's electric fence had been pulled.&nbsp;Initially, investigators suspected that Santos may have had an accomplice to dispose of Cintia Ribeiro Barbosa's body over the wall into the neighbouring property. However, a review of security camera footage revealed no evidence of anyone else entering the premises.</p>

<p>Mr Alfama said that the only others present were the bedridden elderly couple, who required assistance to move, making it impossible for them to be involved. ''He confessed to the crime in detail and confirmed what the security cameras also showed us. He acted alone,'' Mr&nbsp;Alfama added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A friend of the caregiver, who preferred to remain anonymous, said that the woman was very dear to the elderly couple, with whom she had worked for about 6 years.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7k8gi30o_cintia-ribeiro-barbosa_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[She had gotten married eight days before the crime.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youtuber-buys-39k-amazon-home-proves-too-good-to-be-true-7008632]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[YouTuber Buys "Ready-Made House" For $39,000. It Turned Into A Nightmare]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youtuber-buys-39k-amazon-home-proves-too-good-to-be-true-7008632]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:07:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From a place to buy books, Amazon has now evolved into a place you can buy anything from. Even a home, yes. But is it liveable and does it even make sense to buy one from the e-commerce giant?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From a place to buy books, Amazon has now evolved into a place you can buy anything from. Even a home, yes. But is it liveable and does it even make sense to buy one from the e-commerce giant? Well, a group of YouTubers took on the challenge and answered some of our questions. And not reading the fine print of the product landed them in huge trouble.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nathan Graham, the man behind the YouTube channel Unspeakable, bought the ready-made house from Amazon for $38,999. Upon arrival, the house had to be unwrapped from its Amazon-branded box. Nathan pointed out that while the house came complete with windows and a bathroom, no instructions were included with the ready-made home. On further examination, Nathan discovered the 19-by-20-foot Chery Industrial expandable house lacked electricity outlets. “I'm trying to find somewhere to plug in the fridge, but there are no electrical outlets,” the Youtuber said in the <a href="https://youtu.be/53vIAXNBc6g?si=XRBueyLc52N6ioR3">unboxing video.&nbsp;</a><br />
<br />
His friend asked, “Did you not order the electrical package?”. After this, Nathan realised that he hadn't read the full product description while ordering, which said, “Reminder: Mobile Prefab House is not wired. Please hire an electrician for American standard wiring. Stay safe!”<br />
<br />
But Nathan was prepared with a generator to connect some of his essentials, such as an 80-inch TV and refrigerator. Additionally, the Youtuber bought food, kitchenware, games, a couch, tables, a vacuum, and a bunk bed. Apart from electrical outlets, the home was also devoid of furniture, appliances, running water, and connections for drain and sewer pipes.<br />
<br />
The house, however, had built-in kitchen cupboards, a bathroom, and a shower. Nathan Graham and his team learnt that although you may get nearly anything from Amazon, it's crucial to read the fine print to be aware of the details of the purchase.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3eeudl5o_youtuber-house-_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insane-video-captures-speeding-motorcyclist-landing-on-car-roof-after-collision-7008435]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On Camera, Biker Lands On Car Roof After High-Speed Collision]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insane-video-captures-speeding-motorcyclist-landing-on-car-roof-after-collision-7008435]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:01:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A motorcyclist flying onto the roof of a car after a high-speed collision on a freeway in Melbourne has been caught on camera.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A motorcyclist flying onto the roof of a car after a high-speed collision on a freeway in Melbourne has been caught on camera.&nbsp;The motorcyclist sped through heavy traffic on the Princes Freeway near Altona on October 8, before the collision, according to 7 News. Victoria Police confirmed the incident was not reported to the authorities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incident, captured on dashcam, shows the biker weaving through traffic before ramming a black SUV, which abruptly changed lanes. In the footage, shared by DashCamOwners Australia on its social media handles, the rider, after slamming the car, flung on the top of the vehicle. The impact was so intense that he was left perched atop the SUV for a while. Just before the crash, a silver car signalled to merge lanes when the motorbike sped past, narrowly avoiding a collision with its rear.</p>

<p>Following the collision, traffic slowed, and the driver pulled over to the side. The driver, seemingly agitated, appeared to yell and gesture at the motorcyclist, who was on the side of the freeway, presumably recovering from the shock of the accident.</p>

<p>Another motorcyclist, witnessing the crash, stopped to offer assistance. DashCamOwners Australia uploaded the video to their social media platforms, and it went viral.<br />
<br />
<strong>Watch the footage here:</strong><br />
<iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="314" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FDashCamOwnersAustralia%2Fvideos%2F1259202398534411%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="560"></iframe><br />
Reckless driving incidents often grab attention due to their dangerous nature. A few months ago, one such case involved influencer Rajat Dalal, currently a participant in Bigg Boss 18. A viral video from Haryana showed him speeding at 140 km/h despite his co-passengers urging him to slow down. His car then collided with a motorcycle, causing the rider to fall. The driver's dismissive remark, saying it was no big deal and a daily occurrence, showed a complete lack of concern.<br />
<br />
In another incident earlier this year, a truck driver in Hyderabad was arrested after a video showing a speeding truck dragging a motorcycle along a busy road, with the rider hanging from the side of the truck, went viral.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7daadeg8_bike-accident-dash-cam-_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident, captured on dashcam, shows the biker weaving through traffic before ramming a black SUV.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/amazon-offers-free-computing-power-to-ai-researchers-aiming-to-challenge-nvidia-7009124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Offers Free Computing Power To AI Researchers To Challenge Nvidia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/amazon-offers-free-computing-power-to-ai-researchers-aiming-to-challenge-nvidia-7009124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:40:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amazon Web Services (AWS) said it will offer credits to use its cloud data centers that it values at $110 million to researchers who want to tap its AI chips]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon.com's cloud computing unit on Tuesday said it will offer free computing power to researchers who want to use its custom artificial intelligence chips, aiming to challenge Nvidia's popularity among those researchers.</p>

<p>Amazon Web Services (AWS) said it will offer credits to use its cloud data centers that it values at $110 million to researchers who want to tap Trainium, its chip for developing artificial intelligence models that competes with chips from Nvidia, as well as Advanced Micro Devices and Alphabet's cloud division.</p>

<p>AWS said researchers from Carnegie Mellon University and the University of California, Berkeley, are taking part in the program. The company plans to make 40,000 of the first-generation Trainium chips available for the program.</p>

<p>The move comes as AWS, still the largest cloud computing company by sales, has seen a sharp challenge from Microsoft as software developers look to harness new types of chips for AI work. AWS is hoping to gain attention for its own AI chips by taking a different strategy than Nvidia, said Gadi Hutt, who leads business development for the AI chips at AWS.</p>

<p>To program Nvidia's chips, most AI developers use what is called Cuda, Nvidia's flagship software, rather than programming the chip directly. AWS instead plans to publish documentation about the most fundamental part of its chip - what is called the instruction set architecture - and let customers program the chip directly.</p>

<p>Hutt said the approach is aimed at luring large customers who might want to make small tweaks that could add up to big gains when using tens of thousands of chips at a time.</p>

<p>"Think about folks that are using infrastructure and putting hundreds of millions of dollars, if not more" toward rented computing power, Hutt said. "They would take any opportunity possible to increase performance and reduce the cost."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lf2og7bo_amazon-ai-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company plans to make 40,000 of the first-generation Trainium chips available for the program]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/rome-didnt-fall-in-a-daythat-could-be-true-for-america-too-7009108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Just Like Rome, The American Empire Is Crumbling From Within]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/rome-didnt-fall-in-a-daythat-could-be-true-for-america-too-7009108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:36:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Washington's influence, for instance, extends to every corner of the glob-ejust as Rome's once did across the Mediterranean and beyond. But beneath the surface, familiar cracks are beginning to show.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k63mrvao_america_625x300_13_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>When Donald Trump clinched the US Presidency last week, world leaders practically stumbled over each other in a frenzied dash to congratulate him. Clearly the idea was that an extra flourish or two might win them favour with this new emperor of a modern empire. This reinforces the notion that America, even though in slow but steady decline, still reigns as the preeminent superpower, wielding a global influence that would be as familiar to a Roman emperor as it is to the President-elect.</p>

<h2><strong>Washington DC – America's Rome?</strong></h2>

<p>The parallels between Washington DC. and Rome—in terms of trappings of power, grandeur and diplomacy—are unmistakable. Much like ancient Rome, Washington is a beacon of authority where world leaders arrive to pay respects and seek influence. From the remote reaches of Britannia to the deserts of Egypt, emissaries once travelled to Rome to bask in its glory and secure the emperor's favour. In its own way, Washington DC appears to be the heir to this imperial aura, with diplomats, heads of state and dignitaries flocking to its corridors to align themselves with American power.</p>

<p>In fact, it is not lost on us that several federal buildings in Washington DC were heavily modelled on Roman architecture to convey the ideals of democracy, liberty and grandeur. It was Thomas Jefferson, one of America's founding fathers, who drew inspiration from the republican ideals and aesthetics of the Roman Republic, which he admired for its principles of civic virtue, republicanism, and enduring architecture. Jefferson influenced the classical architectural style that defined some DC buildings, such as the US Capitol and Supreme Court, infusing the cityscape with a Roman grandeur that embodied the principles of America's founding vision. Surely, early American Presidents positioned themselves in the tradition of ancient Greeks and Romans whose vibrant societies and polity stood out for holding public debates and developing principles, such as the rule of law, liberty and justice.</p>

<h2><strong>Emperors And Presidents</strong></h2>

<p>Roman emperors were renowned for their ability to project power, both militarily and culturally, across continents—a legacy with undeniable resonance in today's American presidency. Consider Augustus, Rome's first emperor, who established stability throughout the empire and transformed the city into a symbol of imperial order. We can see his legacy reflected in George Washington, whose leadership cemented stability in the fledgling United States of America, laying the groundwork for a powerful nation. Trajan, another Roman giant, oversaw Rome's greatest territorial expansion and initiated significant infrastructure projects. Theodore Roosevelt, who extended American influence and launched major national initiatives, had that same vision for America. We had Constantine the Great who was credited to have unified the empire's geographic and cultural landscape. His counterpart might be Abraham Lincoln, who, amid deep national division, unified the Union and redefined America's moral core—a persona with an almost imperial legacy within the democratic fabric of the US.</p>

<h2><strong>Donald Trump And The Ghosts Of Rome</strong></h2>

<p>Historians would bear me out when I say that when it comes to Donald Trump, his 'America First' rhetoric and highly publicised misconduct align him most closely with Nero, Rome's infamous emperor known for his ambition, controversies and self-promotion. Like Trump, Nero enjoyed a fiercely loyal support base, even as his reign sparked debates and divisions among elites and the general public. Nero's self-assured style, combined with frequent scandals, drew fascination and criticism alike, mirroring Trump's own complex legacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Yet, Trump also shares similarities with the lesser-known Caligula, a Roman emperor infamous for his audacity and unconventional approach. Caligula challenged norms, defied Rome's elite, and pursued his vision regardless of tradition—traits that mirror Trump's own disregard for Washington conventions, deep state and norms. Both figures embody a “disruptor” quality that simultaneously captivated and unsettled their societies.</p>

<h2><strong>The Enduring Influence Of Empire</strong></h2>

<p>It is quite fascinating to see that the Roman Empire and the United States of America stand as the titans of their eras, each unmatched in their influence and power over politics, culture, and ideals. Rome's dominance shaped law and governance for centuries, creating ripples that still echo in Western civilisation. Likewise, America's cultural and economic reach extends across the globe, from Hollywood films to Silicon Valley innovations, projecting an influence that binds distant nations in a shared sphere.</p>

<h2><strong>Signs Of Decline Of US Hegemony</strong></h2>

<p>Just like Rome was not built in a day, the Roman Empire did not crumble overnight. It was a long drawn-out affair marked by overreach, moral decadence, corruption and a heavy reliance on military might to hold off the inevitable. It took centuries, but Rome's end serves as a cautionary tale, not least for the United States today.</p>

<p>Like Rome, the US has positioned itself as a global power for decades, flexing its muscles economically, militarily and culturally. Washington's influence, for instance, extends to every corner of the globe—just as Rome's once did across the Mediterranean and beyond. But beneath the surface, familiar cracks are beginning to show.</p>

<p>First, there's the cost of military dominance. Rome poured unimaginable resources into its legions, eventually stretching its borders too far and thin. The US has similarly extended itself, from NATO bases in Europe to military bases in over 700 locations worldwide, spending 40% of its total defence budget, a whopping $916 billion as of 2023. To put this into perspective, the US defence budget exceeded the combined defence spending of the next nine countries, including China, Russia and India. While this has maintained a semblance of control, the long-term view is that America's relentless drive to police the world is not sustainable. Businessman Trump knows it better than Bush and Bill Clinton.</p>

<h2><strong>The Political Splintering</strong></h2>

<p>Then there's the political strain. Rome was rife with infighting, corruption and self-serving elites. The late-stage empire saw more emperors assassinated or overthrown than crowned naturally. America isn't facing quite that level of chaos, but the increasing polarisation and deadlock in Washington feel ominously familiar. The US society is divided vertically, with the middle ground shrinking very fast. It's crying out for national unity. Rome, too, fell prey to this kind of division, with competing interests ultimately undermining the empire's stability.</p>

<p>Economically, both empires grapple with inequality. Rome's wealth disparity led to an unhappy, disenfranchised underclass, one that had little stake in the empire's survival. The US also faces stark inequalities, with wealth concentrated in the hands of a few. As Rome's elite thrived on the backs of the masses, America's billionaire class has seen its fortunes soar even as many Americans grapple with stagnant wages and dwindling social mobility. An empire is, after all, only as strong as the support it commands from its people.</p>

<p>Finally, there's the cultural decay. Rome, in its twilight years, grew obsessed with decadence—it indulged in lavish parties, games, and luxury while the world around it burned. America, for its part, many would argue, is captivated by consumerism and political spectacle today.</p>

<p>As I said earlier, Rome's fall wasn't a single, dramatic event. In the same way, American hegemony isn't likely to collapse in one generation. But the echoes are there—a military stretched too thin, political divisions, economic inequality, and a distracted public. In a few words, the parallels between the two entities are hard to ignore.</p>

<h2><strong>What Is Trump's Legacy?</strong></h2>

<p>The President-elect, with his chest puffed up with pride for winning the election so handsomely, must also be feeling invincible. The White House, Congress (now in Republican hands) and the Capitol Hill, all in Trump's control now, will echo the grandeur of Rome's Forum. As Trump returns to power this January, the world will once again watch, captivated by a mix of admiration, fear, apprehension and awe.</p>

<p>Generations from now, with time lending a certain distance, Trump might be remembered as one of America's enigmatic leaders, and perhaps even evoke comparisons with some Roman emperor. But his legacy will depend on his choices: will he be the leader who brokered peace, halting wars and fostering global stability? Or will he be seen as one who rolled back rights, limiting freedoms for women and others? Will he hasten the fall of the American empire, or will he turn the tide?</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the authors</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5got8gng_america_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/apple-to-announce-ai-wall-tablet-as-soon-as-march-7009023]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Apple To Announce AI Wall Tablet As Soon As March]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/apple-to-announce-ai-wall-tablet-as-soon-as-march-7009023]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:24:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The product, code-named J490, could be announced as early as March]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Apple is planning on launching a wall-mounted display that can control appliances, handle video conferencing and use artificial intelligence to navigate apps, Bloomberg News reported on Tuesday, citing people with knowledge of the effort.</p>

<p>The product, code-named J490, could be announced as early as March, the report said, adding that it will spotlight the new AI platform, Apple Intelligence.</p>

<p>Apple did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>The higher-end device could be priced as much as $1,000 depending upon the components being used, the report said, but the display-only device would be far less than that.</p>

<p>The potential device launch would come as the tech behemoth looks to compete with rivals in the smart home market, including Google's Nest Hub and Amazon's Echo Show and Echo Hub smart displays.</p>

<p>The AI wall tablet, which looks like a square iPad and is about the size of two iPhones side by side, has a roughly 6-inch screen and will be offered in silver and black colours, Bloomberg News said.</p>

<p>The product will be a standalone device, but it will require an iPhone for some tasks, the report said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/886jqpb_apple_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-goes-to-snap-polls-tomorrow-how-new-parliament-is-elected-7008947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Goes To Snap Polls Tomorrow: How New Parliament Is Elected]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-goes-to-snap-polls-tomorrow-how-new-parliament-is-elected-7008947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:14:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka President Anura Kumara Dissanayake dissolved parliament on September 24 to clear the way for the general election, days after the Marxist-leaning leader was elected president on a platform for change.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lanka will vote in a snap general election on Thursday, called by new President Anura Kumara Dissanayake to secure a majority in parliament to back his policies in the island nation struggling to recover from a crushing financial crisis.</p>

<p>Here are the key steps in the process in which 17.1 million Sri Lankans are eligible to elect lawmakers to the 225-member parliament for a five-year term:</p>

<h3><strong>Snap election</strong></h3>

<p>Dissanayake dissolved parliament on September 24 to clear the way for the general election, days after the Marxist-leaning leader was elected president on a platform for change. The election became necessary as Dissanayake had just three lawmakers in the outgoing parliament - whose five-year term was due to end in Aug. 2025 - and needed a fresh mandate to push his policies.</p>

<p>Campaigning ended at midnight on Monday, 48 hours before election day.</p>

<h3><strong>Number of eligible voters</strong></h3>

<p>Sri Lanka has 17.1 million voters who are eligible to participate in the election. About 1 million of them are first-time voters.</p>

<h3><strong>Election process</strong></h3>

<p>Voters directly elect 196 members to parliament from 22 constituencies under a proportional representation system. The remaining 29 seats will be allocated according to the island-wide proportional vote obtained by each party. A voter can cast up to three preferential votes for candidates contesting from their party of choice.</p>

<h3><strong>Voting and counting</strong></h3>

<p>Votes are cast at thousands of polling stations amid tight security. They will be counted by government employees after polling ends, supervised by Election Commission officials, election monitors, and representatives of candidates.</p>

<p>Voting begins at 7 a.m. local time (0130 GMT) and ends at 4 p.m. (1030 GMT), with counting scheduled to start shortly after.</p>

<h3><strong>Declaration of results</strong></h3>

<p>The Election Commission will formally announce the winning party, likely on Friday. A cabinet is expected to be formed immediately afterwards and the new parliament will convene on Nov. 21 to elect a speaker. President Dissanayake will also present a throne speech outlining his key policy priorities to the new parliament on the same day.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mtpl92o8_sri-lanka_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lanka has 17.1 million voters who are eligible to participate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cruise-line-introduces-4-year-trip-for-americans-who-want-to-skip-trumps-second-term-7008487]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cruise Line Offers 4-Year Trip For Americans Who Want To Skip Trump's Term]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cruise-line-introduces-4-year-trip-for-americans-who-want-to-skip-trumps-second-term-7008487]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 13:11:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Passengers will have the opportunity to explore international destinations at sea, with the cruise line promising an easy, carefree experience.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A luxury cruise line has introduced a unique, four-year voyage designed for travellers interested in "skipping ahead" in time, especially those looking to sit out a second Trump term.&nbsp;According to<em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/11/11/villa-vie-residences-4-year-skip-ahead-cruise-second-trump-term/" rel="nofollow, noindex"> Fortune,&nbsp;</a></em>Florida-based<em>&nbsp;</em>Villa Vie Residences is offering a 4-year "Skip Forward" voyage for Americans looking to escape the country following Donald Trump's re-election. This unique package allows passengers to travel the world in style, visiting iconic destinations, and essentially "skipping" the next presidential term.</p>

<p>According to a press release from Villa Vie Residences, residents have the flexibility to join their customised journey at any port during the continuous global adventure for up to 4 years. The package is available for a one-time payment of $159,999 for double-occupancy rooms or $255,999 for single-occupancy cabins.&nbsp;Passengers will have the opportunity to explore international destinations at sea, with the cruise line promising an easy, carefree experience.</p>

<p>Villa Vie Residences stressed that its "Skip Forward" package is designed for travellers of all backgrounds and political affiliations. Although launched following the 2024 US presidential election, the package's purpose is to provide a unique travel experience, not to promote any political agenda.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Villa Vie CEO Mikael Petterson told&nbsp;<i>Fox News</i>, ''Although the campaign was put together before the results of the election, we feel we have a perfect product for those who said they'd leave the country if XYZ wins the election. We may have differing political views, but our community comes together through our passion for exploring the world in a very real way that goes far beyond politics.''</p>

<p>He also explained to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-cruise-world-travel-retire-digital-nomad-1984726">Newsweek</a></em> that the marketing campaign was conceived before the election results were known, anticipating that half of the population might feel dissatisfied regardless of the outcome. He emphasised that the company holds no political stance and simply wanted to offer an option for those feeling unsettled to have a way to get away.</p>

<p>For those hesitant to commit to a four-year cruise, Villa Vie Residences also offers alternative options. Travellers can choose from a one-year "Escape from Reality" journey, a two-year "Mid-Term Selection" voyage, or a three-year "Everywhere but Home" cruise.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''Villa Vie offers a unique one-of-a-kind way to see the whole world at a slow pace where you have enough time to experience the cultural vibe of every port. Your villa is your bedroom, and the ship is your home, she'll take you across the globe to endless horizons,''&nbsp;said Anne Alms, head of sales for <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/villa-vie-residences-releases-tour-la-vie--the-4-year-world-cruise-302298810.html">Villa Vie Residences in a statement.&nbsp;</a></p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3ojhmvm_cruise-line_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The program allows travelers to join a trip around the world for one to four years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-influencer-imsha-rehman-deactivates-social-media-accounts-after-private-video-leaks-7008463]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Influencer Deactivates Social Media Accounts After Private Video Leaks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-influencer-imsha-rehman-deactivates-social-media-accounts-after-private-video-leaks-7008463]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 13:10:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Before deactivating her account, Imsha Rehman talked about dealing with negative comments, according to local media. She called the backlash "overwhelming".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan TikTok star Imsha Rehman has deactivated her social media accounts after her private video went viral. She faced a lot of backlash from social media users, who accused her of intentionally making the video public to gain attention online. She, however, appears to be a victim of data breach. This is the second such case after Minahil Malik whose private video with her boyfriend recently surfaced online. Her followers too had accused it a publicity stunt. Malik had reportedly quit Instagram after the controversy.</p>

<h3><strong>Imsha Rehman's response to the controversy</strong></h3>

<p>Before deactivating her account, the young influencer talked about dealing with negative comments, according to local media. She called the backlash "overwhelming".</p>

<p>Several screenshots from her private video have been circulating on social media, and even turned into memes.</p>

<p>Another screenshot, reportedly from Rehman's TikTok account, is making rounds on the internet in which quotes her as saying "<em>Jab tak video viral hai maine ne ID off kar di hai</em> (Till the time video is viral, I have deactivated my account)."</p>

<h3><strong>Who is Imsha Rehman?</strong></h3>

<p>She is very famous in Pakistan and is known for her peppy and engaging content. Apart from TikTok, Rehman has presence on other social media platforms too.</p>

<p>In interviews to local channels, Rehman has said that she was born on October 7, 2002. She was born and brought up in Lahore.</p>

<h3><strong>What happened with Minahil Malik?</strong></h3>

<p>Malik also faced a similar controversy after a video showing her in an intimate moment with her partner went viral on social media in October. She claimed the video was "fake" and lodged a complaint with Federal Investigation Agency (FIA).</p>

<p>However, Malik faced intense trolling since social media users accused her of intentionally leaking the video. Pakistani actress Mishi Khan released a video in which she criticised influencers "stooping to the lowest level" for fame. She did not directly name Malik, but the references were said to be directed towards her.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ijuvlnso_imsha-rehman_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Imsha Rehman, 22, is a Pakistan-based influencer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-net-worth-falls-by-300-million-as-truth-social-parent-s-shares-decline-7007827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Net Worth Dips $300 Million As Truth Social Parent's Stocks Stumble]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-s-net-worth-falls-by-300-million-as-truth-social-parent-s-shares-decline-7007827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 13:05:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's net worth has taken a $300 million hit following a dip in the shares of Trump Media & Technology Group, the parent company of Truth Social.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's net worth has taken a $300 million hit following a dip in the shares of Trump Media &amp; Technology Group, the parent company of Truth Social. The company's stock saw a decline of 8% on November 12, continuing a downtrend that began after an initial post-election surge, according to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tylerroush/2024/11/12/donald-trumps-net-worth-sheds-300-million-as-truth-social-parents-shares-slide/">Forbes</a>.<br />
<br />
By 2:40 pm EST on November 12, Trump Media's stock fell below $31, down from a high of $33.41 on November 11. This drop comes after a two-day rally that saw the stock rise by 20.6%. As a result, Trump's 57% ownership stake in Trump Media — equating to 114.75 million shares — has seen its value decrease from just over $3.8 billion on November 11 to around $3.5 billion. This represents a significant fall from a peak of $5.2 billion when the stock reached $45.77 on November 6, reported Forbes.</p>

<p>The initial rally in the company's stock price followed a statement from Trump on Truth Social last week. He dismissed rumours of his intention to sell his stake in Trump Media, describing them as “fake, untrue and probably illegal claims,” although it remains unclear what specific allegations he was referring to.</p>

<p>According to the latest Forbes estimates, Trump's current net worth is valued at $5.6 billion, making him the 591st wealthiest individual globally. His fortune has experienced fluctuations due to the volatility of Trump Media's stock. A surge in October briefly pushed his net worth above $8 billion for the first time since the company went public earlier this year.</p>

<p>Although Trump has repeatedly stated he would not sell his stake in Trump Media, other company executives have made plans to sell shares. Earlier this month, Trump Media CFO, Phillip Juhan, announced intentions to sell shares worth around $13.4 million by December 2025, according to a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission.<br />
<br />
Trump Media has faced significant volatility since its public listing in March 2024 through a reverse merger with Digital World Acquisition Corp. The company's stock has been subject to fluctuations linked to both Trump's political campaign and the financial performance of the business itself.<br />
<br />
According to Forbes, in its third-quarter earnings report, Trump Media revealed a net loss of $19 million, citing legal expenses and costs associated with its TV streaming services. The stock spiked following Trump's debate with President Joe Biden and an attempt on his life in July but it dropped sharply after his debate with Vice President Kamala Harris in September.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/leckf9eo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump Media has faced significant volatility since its public listing in March 2024.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-draws-a-pak-parallel-to-answer-question-on-india-russia-ties-7008394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In This Day And Age...": S Jaishankar's Sharp Take On Russia Ties Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-draws-a-pak-parallel-to-answer-question-on-india-russia-ties-7008394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:58:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Known for his no-nonsense articulation of India's position on geopolitical issues, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar had a sharp response when an Australian journalist asked him if New Delhi recognises Canberra's "angst" over ties with Russia]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Known for his no-nonsense articulation of India's position on geopolitical issues, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar had a sharp response when an Australian journalist asked him if New Delhi recognises Canberra's "angst" over its ties with Russia.</p>

<p>Dr Jaishankar was speaking to Sky News Australia's Sharri Markson in an interview during his recent visit. When Ms Markson asked him if India recognises the "angst" its relationship with Russia causes Australia, he replied, "I don't think we have given cause for any angst. In this day and age, countries don't have exclusive relationships."</p>

<p>The minister then drew a Pakistan parallel. "If I were to use that logic, I would say so many countries have relationship with Pak. Look at the angst it should cause me," he said.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Tl0Y1Gyy2c8?si=CdhuQD_zlgbzJFDK" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>Dr Jaishankar then proceeded to explain how India's close ties with Russia is in the interest of the international community. Referring to Delhi's decision to buy Russian oil despite the West and other counties sanctioning Moscow after the Ukraine war broke out, the minister said,</p>

<p>"If we had not made the moves we had, the energy markets would have taken a completely different turn and precipitated a global energy crisis, it would have caused inflation across the world."</p>

<p>He said India's ties with Russia enables it to play a role in bringing the conflict to the talks table. "The fact that we have a good relationship with Russia allows us to be a country in between which has the ability to talk to both Russia and Ukraine and try to find some intersection in those conversations. i think the world, including Australia, needs such a country that will help bring this conflict back to the conference table," he said, adding, "Conflicts rarely end on battlefield, mostly they end in negotiations."</p>

<p>Australia has backed Ukraine in its conflict with Russia and supplied Kyiv with weapons. When the conflict began in 2022, then Australian Prime Minister Scott Morrison had said Russia should be seen as a "pariah state" and no country should have anything to do with them.</p>

<p>As the West imposed sanctions on Russia, India decided to continue buying oil from Moscow. This raised eyebrows and Dr Jaishankar countered the West's questions regarding India's decision. The former diplomat had then sharply said that Europe needs to grow out of the mindset that Europe's problems are the world's problems but the world's problems are not Europe's problems. He had said India has a right to prioritise its energy needs. Later, speaking at NDTV World Summit, Dr Jaishankar had underlined that Moscow never done anything to impact India's interests negatively.</p>

<p>On the Ukraine conflict, the Narendra Modi government has refused to take sides, with the Prime Minister stressing that this is not an era of war. The Prime Minister recently travelled to both Ukraine and Russia. India, he has said, is not neutral, but on the side of peace.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ja8he14o_s-jaishankar_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr S Jaishankar has sharply articulated India's position on the Russia-Ukraine conflict]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/byjus-us-units-wrongly-stripped-of-education-app-court-rules-7008359]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Byju's US Units Wrongly Stripped Of Education App, Court Rules]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/byjus-us-units-wrongly-stripped-of-education-app-court-rules-7008359]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:52:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two money-making education apps that are part of the troubled Byju's software empire were wrongly transferred away from US lenders and must be returned to a court-supervised bankruptcy trustee, a federal judge ruled Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two money-making education apps that are part of the troubled Byju's software empire were wrongly transferred away from US lenders and must be returned to a court-supervised bankruptcy trustee, a federal judge ruled Tuesday.</p>

<p>A "rogue officer" manipulated Apple Inc. into changing the ownership - and the revenue stream - of two apps that bring in about $1 million a month, according to the trustee, who controls three of Byju's US units.</p>

<p>The apps are used by parents to download education materials for their children, Catherine Steege, a lawyer for the US units said Tuesday during a virtual hearing. The transfer happened shortly after the trustee took control of the bankrupt units: Epic! Creations, Neuron Fuel, and Tangible Play.</p>

<p>Since the trustee, Claudia Springer, was given control of the three units by a federal judge, unknown people directed by Byju's, which is based in India, have been grabbing cash, moving source code away from cloud systems managed by Apple and Alphabet Inc.'s Google and changing the names of various online accounts, Steege said.</p>

<p>"These bad actors began a game of 'catch me if you can'," Steege told US Bankruptcy Judge John Dorsey in Wilmington, Delaware. They are "trying to stay one step ahead of the trustee."</p>

<p>Dorsey ordered Apple to return ownership of the apps to the US units. A lawyer for an Indian firm that had been wrongly given ownership of the apps unsuccessfully tried to persuade Dorsey to delay making any ruling.</p>

<p>The dispute is the latest clash between Byju's and its US lenders. After Byju's, whose formal name is Think &amp; Learn Private Ltd., defaulted on more than $1.2 billion in debt, US lenders took control of one Byju's shell company and forced three smaller, US subsidiaries into bankruptcy.</p>

<p>A representative for Byju's did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>Byju's bought the firms just a few years ago for $820 million according to court records. Springer is preparing to hold an auction for at least two of the unit in order to raise money to repay Byju's creditors, including the US lenders.</p>

<p>Lenders have been fighting Byju's in state and federal courts in the US for more than a year. Byju's is facing an insolvency proceeding in India, where a court-appointed professional has been tasked with raising money to repay creditors. That professional, Pankaj Srivastava has asked the US court to take no action related to the three US units because they are owned by Byju's and could be used to repay creditors in India.</p>

<p>Dorsey has rejected those requests, saying the units are US-incorporated entities that are subject to American bankruptcy courts.</p>

<p>Company founder Byju Raveendran has denied wrongdoing, saying his actions were justified in response to overly aggressive tactics used by lenders who specialize in squeezing money out of distressed companies.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rvvruu_byjus-generic-bloomberg-_625x300_04_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-albania-s-communist-era-bunkers-became-part-of-modern-day-tourism-7007809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In This Country, Cold War Relics Are Coming Back To Life. Here's How]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-albania-s-communist-era-bunkers-became-part-of-modern-day-tourism-7007809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:38:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Albania is seeing a rebirth of its communist-era military structures. No, not to prepare for a war. The country has turned old bunkers and barracks into tourist destinations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Albania is seeing a rebirth of its communist-era military structures. No, not to prepare for a war. The country has turned old bunkers and barracks into tourist destinations. Once symbols of isolation and fear under the iron grip of dictator Enver Hoxha, these buildings are now being repurposed by entrepreneurs and returning émigrés, offering a glimpse into Albania's complex past while helping the country embrace a more prosperous future.</p>

<p>For decades, Albania's legacy of over 220,000 bunkers — built to fortify the country against potential invasions during Hoxha's regime — served as grim reminders of a nation consumed by fear. During the height of his rule, Hoxha's government shut off the country from the outside world, creating an atmosphere of surveillance, paranoia and control. Thousands were imprisoned or executed for attempting to flee, while the population was subjected to a brutal, Stalinist regime.<br />
<br />
But today, this dark history is being revisited through a new lens. Instead of remaining relics of a repressive past, many of these structures are now thriving as part of Albania's tourism boom, which has gained momentum in recent years. Many of the country's former military outposts have been transformed into art galleries, hotels, and restaurants, offering visitors a unique opportunity to connect with Albania's history unexpectedly.</p>

<p>One such transformation is found just outside Tirana, where the former military barracks of Kazerma e Cerenit have been reborn as a popular restaurant and agritourism destination, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/albania-communism-bunkers-cold-war/index.html">CNN</a>. The idea came from Ismet Shehu, a chef who trained in the UK and worked with royalty before returning to Albania to open a series of restaurants. His latest venture, Kazerma, opened its doors just a year and a half ago. The building, once used for housing military trucks and equipment, now serves as a farm-to-table dining experience.</p>

<p>Shehu said, “When people come here, they say, ‘Wow!', this place used to be for soldiers, it used to be for tanks, TNT and grenades.”</p>

<p>At Kazerma, guests enjoy traditional Albanian dishes served in military-style canteens, with waiters dressed in military uniforms. The restaurant's decor features original memorabilia, including trays and pans from military field kits used to serve duck, alongside former military bunkers now repurposed for wine and cheese tastings.</p>

<p>Just a short drive away, another reminder of the past is Bunk'Art 2, a nuclear-grade bunker now serving as one of Albania's most important museums. Bunk'Art 2 chronicles the political atrocities of Hoxha's rule, housing exhibitions on the Sigurimi — Albania's local surveillance police. Among the objects on display is a wooden broomstick that has a listening device covertly placed in its head, allowing neighbours to spy on one another.</p>

<p>Eni Koco, a local tour guide who lived through the years of communist control, recalls how Albania was effectively cut off from the rest of the world, with borders sealed tight to prevent any form of escape. “We became compared with North Korea because the government created a cult of personality, telling us they were gods and we needed to worship them, creating a system to control the borders and killing anyone trying to escape or enter the country,” said Koco.</p>

<p>The Ottoman-era town of Gjirokaster, Hoxha's birthplace, offers another layer to the country's history. While the building where Hoxha was born is now the Ethnographic Museum, efforts are also underway to preserve the history of Albania's communist period. Then in the farming village of Fishte, agritourism has breathed new life into another former communist-era site. The Mrizi i Zanave restaurant, set in a compound that was once a prison, now serves as a hub for local traditions and food.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0oemoeao_albania-generic_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Today, Albania's dark history is being revisited through a new lens. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-tourism-finds-new-destination-in-los-angeles-murder-mansion-7008226]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Dark Tourism" Finds New Destination In Los Angeles Murder Mansion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dark-tourism-finds-new-destination-in-los-angeles-murder-mansion-7008226]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:34:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Exactly 28 years after the jury convicted the Menendez brothers, the house was sold for $17 million in March 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the Hindenburg crash site in New Jersey to the spooky hiking trails in Colorado, a lot of places historically associated with death and tragedy have now become popular spots for "dark tourism" in the United States. A new addition to the list is a Beverly Hills mansion in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>The house came into the spotlight after the release of Netflix's popular show Monsters and the documentary <em>The Menendez Brothers</em>. Now, the mansion has been transformed into a huge tourist destination, with tour buses and rental vehicles continuously stopping by to catch a sight of the place, reported <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/travel/travel-news-mendendez-brothers-mansion-beverly-hills/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN</a>.</p>

<p>Netflix's true crime anthology series Monsters: The Lyle and Erik Menendez Story, based on the Menendez brothers case, was released in September. A month later, the streaming giant released a two-hour documentary called The Menendez Brothers, which included fresh audio conversations with the siblings. A new generation was exposed to a case that had their parents and grandparents glued to television screens during the trials in 1993.</p>

<p>The trial was one of the first of its kind to be televised. The country was captivated by the story of two charming but disturbed young men who appeared to have it all before they suddenly snapped and killed their parents with shotguns.</p>

<p>Since the release of the Netflix series and documentary, TikTokers have turned the house's resurrected celebrity status into a treasure trove of viral material, filming the mansion and replaying the graphic details of the murder scene for viewers online. In recent months, tourists have begun pouring onto the crime scene.</p>

<p>CNN interviewed visitors who travelled from near and far to see the house. Toni Ricci, who owns a dance class in the area, claimed she came with her five coworkers who followed the case. But the neighbours aren't as thrilled with the influx of people.</p>

<p>A local, who spoke to CNN, is eager for the hype to subside but is aware that it won't happen anytime soon. He said, "We're probably now going to have to wait another decade or two for it to calm down again, and hopefully there won't be another documentary in 20 years' time."</p>

<p>The Menendez family no longer owns the mansion. Exactly 28 years after the jury convicted the brothers, the house was sold for $17 million in March 2024, according to the Realtor. The names of buyers have not been disclosed.</p>

<p>Currently unoccupied, the mansion is being renovated. However, that hasn't hindered its appeal at home or abroad.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vnvpaloo_murder-mansion_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Menendez family no longer owns the mansion. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mackenzie-scott-s-net-worth-drops-to-30-billion-after-latest-amazon-share-sale-7008222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jeff Bezos' Ex-Wife Mackenzie Scott Slashes Amazon Stake By Another $8 Billion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mackenzie-scott-s-net-worth-drops-to-30-billion-after-latest-amazon-share-sale-7008222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:32:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[MacKenzie Scott, the ex-wife of Amazon founder Jeff Bezos, received around 400 million Amazon shares as part of her divorce settlement in 2019.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MacKenzie Scott, billionaire philanthropist and ex-wife of Amazon founder Jeff Bezos, has further cut down her Amazon stake. A November 8 filing revealed that Scott sold 11 per cent of her Amazon shares valued at over $8 billion on September 30.</p>

<p>The latest transaction brings her total Amazon share sales and gifts to 255 million shares, amounting to around $37 billion at the time of the disposals. With this, Scott, who received around 400 million Amazon shares as part of her divorce settlement with Bezos in 2019, has sold or donated two-thirds of those holdings in less than six years.</p>

<p>This makes her one of the five most generous living donors in the US, with at least $17.3 billion donated to non-profit organisations, according to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/phoebeliu/2024/11/11/billionaire-philanthropist-mackenzie-scott-sold-donated-more-amazon-shares/">Forbes</a>.</p>

<p>Currently, Forbes estimates Scott's net worth at $30 billion, a drop from $38 billion just a week ago, and significantly down from her peak of $59 billion in 2021. Had she not given away her Amazon shares, her wealth would have been closer to $82 billion, placing her among the top 20 richest people globally and making her the second richest woman.</p>

<p>While Scott has never publicly discussed her philanthropic efforts in great detail, she regularly updates her <a href="https://yieldgiving.com/essays/bridges-and-barriers">Yield Giving website</a> and lists grants made to various causes. In one of her essays in December 2022, Scott wrote, “Information from other people – other givers, my team, the non-profit teams I've been giving to – has been enormously helpful to me.” She also reflected on the challenges of creating a platform that properly conveys her philanthropic intentions.</p>

<p>Scott has recently given $1.5 million to the Mni Sota Fund, a non-profit organisation that builds wealth for urban Native people in Minnesota. Then Access to Capital for Entrepreneurs in Georgia received $10 million in August from her. Additionally, Coastal Enterprises, an organisation focused on rural economic development in Maine, was given $15 million in October 2024, marking a rare second donation to the same organisation from Scott, according to Forbes.</p>

<p>Scott often opts not to publicise her donations unless requested by the recipients. Each year, Scott unveils new grants through her Yield Giving platform, usually at the end of the calendar year. It's likely that some of the Amazon shares sold in this recent filing were directed to non-profit groups as part of her ongoing charitable commitments.</p>

<p>Of the $37 billion in Amazon shares Scott has offloaded so far, she has announced donations of $17.3 billion to more than 2,300 organisations. The remaining value from the sales is likely held in donor-advised funds or other charitable accounts, with some funds possibly already being sold.</p>

<p>Scott's unique approach to philanthropy has garnered attention for its simplicity and effectiveness. She does not actively solicit requests for grants, except for her Open Call initiative, which awarded $640 million to 361 organisations earlier this year. Her unrestricted cash grants, which are often larger than an organisation's annual budget, have made a significant impact on many smaller charities. For instance, Dianne Calvi, CEO of Village Enterprises, a non-profit tackling poverty in rural Africa, noted that Scott's $7 million donation last year significantly boosted the organisation's reputation, leading to additional funding.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u42n69_mackenzie-scott_625x300_13_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Scott's unique approach to philanthropy has garnered attention for its simplicity and effectiveness.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-dead-as-bus-with-wedding-guests-falls-into-river-in-pak-bride-survives-7008148]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[14 Dead As Bus With Wedding Guests Falls Into River In Pak, Bride Survives]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/14-dead-as-bus-with-wedding-guests-falls-into-river-in-pak-bride-survives-7008148]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:21:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bus carrying 25 passengers returning from a wedding plunged into a river late Tuesday in Gilgit-Baltistan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A bus carrying guests home from a wedding plunged into a river in northern Pakistan killing at least 14 people, officials said Wednesday, with the bride so far the only known survivor.</p>

<p>"There were 25 people on the bus and so far 14 dead bodies have been recovered while 10 are still missing," said Wazir Asad Ali, a rescue official in Gilgit-Baltistan.</p>

<p>"The bride is out of danger and she is being treated in a Gilgit hospital," Ali added. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Naik Alam, a senior police official from the area, told AFP the driver appeared to have been speeding when he lost control at a curve. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The groom's family had travelled from Punjab, more than 500 kilometres (300 miles) away, for the wedding and were returning home when the accident happened.</p>

<p>Road accidents with high fatalities are common in Pakistan, where safety measures are lax, driver training is poor, and transport infrastructure is often decrepit.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Balochistan in August, 12 men died when their bus crashed into a ravine on the Makran Coastal Highway. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In another accident that month, 24 people on board a bus were killed when it plunged into a ravine near the town of Azad Pattan on the border between Punjab province and Pakistan-administered Kashmir. &nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/gep9jf6g_pakistan-police-_625x300_06_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The driver appeared to have been speeding when incident took place. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/peanut-the-famous-squirrel-euthanised-in-us-didnt-have-rabies-report-7008113]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Peanut, The Famous Squirrel Euthanised In US, Didn't Have Rabies: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/peanut-the-famous-squirrel-euthanised-in-us-didnt-have-rabies-report-7008113]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:19:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Peanut was taken by the state agents in a raid on October 30, sparking major outrage over social media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media sensations Peanut, the squirrel, and Fred, the raccoon, were marked for death and decapitation days before they were seized from their owner in New York, a county official has confirmed. The two pets also tested negative for rabies, the official added.<br />
<br />
The state agents picked them up from their owner in a raid on October 30, sparking major outrage on social media and accusations of government overreach.<br />
<br />
The state officials advised the county to euthanise <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-york-authorities-euthanise-instagram-squirrel-star-6927159">Peanut</a> and Fred seven days before they were taken into custody by the authorities from their 'unofficial' caretaker Mark Longo.</p>

<p>The Department of Environmental Conservation said the squirrel bit an agent at the time of the raid, sparking the need for a rabies test.<br />
<br />
“Wildlife cannot be confined like domestic animals, and if there was an exposure, the animals would need to be tested for rabies,” the State Department of Health wrote to the county on October 23.<br />
<br />
The message sealed Peanut and Fred's fates as the rabies test required decapitation so that their heads could be opened for their brain samples.<br />
<br />
The timeline shows that after a few days on October 29, the Department of Environmental Conservation came up with plans to raid Longo's residents. At the same time, it was coordinating the animals' euthanisations with Elmira Animal Control.<br />
<br />
This contradicts the earlier claim that the squirrel prompted his own euthanisation.<br />
<br />
When shown the timeline, Longo told The New York Post, "I'm in utter shock... I'd like to give you a proper statement, but for now, I'll just say ‘Wow.'”<br />
<br />
Longo, who earlier claimed the two animals were rabies-free, said he was yet to receive any word from the officials about them. The operation by DEC was set in motion when it got four complaints about Longo keeping two animals without a license.<br />
<br />
“DEC is aware of an individual in Chemung County who is known to illegally possess an adult grey squirrel and at least four young raccoons. They may also be in possession of other illegal wildlife species,” the DEC earlier said.</p>

<p>With more than five lakh followers on Instagram, the domesticated black squirrel had fans around the world.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s6u5nnk_peanut-squirrel_625x300_02_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Peanut had more than 5 lakh followers on Instagram]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-cancel-flights-after-volcanic-eruptions-why-thats-a-good-thing-7008097]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airlines Cancel Flights After Volcanic Eruptions. Why That's A Good Thing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/airlines-cancel-flights-after-volcanic-eruptions-why-thats-a-good-thing-7008097]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:14:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least three airlines cancelled flights between Australia and Bali this week after a volcano eruption in eastern Indonesia spewed a vast plume of volcanic ash into the air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">At least three airlines <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-11-13/flights-to-and-from-bali-cancelled-due-to-volcanic-ash/104593698">cancelled flights between Australia and Bali</a> this week after a volcano eruption in eastern Indonesia spewed a vast plume of volcanic ash into the air.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>But while would-be holiday makers are naturally <a href="https://7news.com.au/sunrise/volcanic-eruption-in-indonesia-forces-airlines-to-cancel-flights-to-bali-stranding-frustrated-passengers-c-16732486">upset</a> at having their plans disrupted, it's worth remembering it's not safe to fly planes through volcanic ash.</p>

<p>So, how do airlines decide it's not safe to fly when a volcano erupts? And why is volcanic ash so dangerous for aircraft, anyway?</p>

<h3><strong>What does volcanic ash do to a plane?</strong></h3>

<p>Volcanic ash particles are very, very abrasive. They can cause permanent damage to windscreens in the aircraft and can even make windscreens look opaque – like someone has gone over them with sandpaper.</p>

<p>Imagine getting spectacles and scraping them over and over with sandpaper – that's what you'd see if you were sitting in the cockpit.</p>

<p>Volcanic ash can also clog or damage external sensors, leading to erroneous readings, and can infiltrate an aircraft's ventilation system. This can affect cabin air quality and lead to potential respiratory issues.</p>

<p>But the main issue, in fact, is the impact volcanic ash has on engines.</p>

<p>A jet engine works by drawing in air, compressing it, mixing it with fuel and igniting it. This creates high-pressure exhaust gases that are expelled backward, which pushes the engine (and the aircraft) forward.</p>

<p>The correct balance of fuel and airflow is crucial. When you disrupt airflow, it can cause the engine to stall.</p>

<p>Ash particles that get inside the engines will melt and build up, causing disruption of the airflow. This could cause the engine to “flame out” or stall.</p>

<p>Volcanic ash has a lot of silica in it, so when it melts it turns into something similar to glass. It won't melt unless exposed to very high temperatures – but inside a jet engine, you do get very high temperatures.</p>

<p>There was a famous incident in 1982 where a <a href="https://theaviationgeekclub.com/the-story-of-british-airways-flight-9-the-boeing-747-that-lost-all-four-engines-due-to-volcanic-ash-yet-it-landed-safely/">British Airways Boeing 747 plane</a> was flying in the vicinity of Indonesia and lost all four engines after it encountered volcanic ash spewing from Java's Mount Galunggung.</p>

<p>Fortunately, the pilot was able to <a href="https://simpleflying.com/gallunggung-glider-the-story-of-british-airways-flight-9/">restart the engines and land safely</a>, although the pilots were unable to see through the front windscreens.</p>

<h3><strong>How do airlines decide it's not safe to fly when a volcano erupts?</strong></h3>

<p>The decision is made by each airline's operational staff. Each airline's operational team would be looking at the situation in real time today and making the decision based on their risk assessment.</p>

<p>Every airline has a process of risk management, which is required by Australia's Civil Aviation Safety Authority.</p>

<p>Different airlines may tackle risk management in slightly different ways; you might have some cancelling flights earlier than others. But, in broad terms, the more sophisticated airlines would come to similar conclusions and they are likely all communicating with each other.</p>

<p>Mostly, they make the call based on the extent of the plume – how big the cloud of ash is and where it's going, bearing in mind that winds vary with altitude. As you get stronger winds with altitude, the ash can drift quite far from the source.</p>

<p>There is also a United Nations agency called the <a href="https://www.icao.int/Pages/default.aspx">International Civil Aviation Organization</a>, which issues guidance on volcanic ash hazards. Various meteorological agencies around the world work together and liaise with aviation authorities to spread the word quickly if there is an eruption.</p>

<p>For airlines to resume flights, the ash needs to clear and there needs to be a low probability of further eruptions.</p>

<h3><strong>Passenger safety is the priority</strong></h3>

<p>The underpinning reason behind these flight cancellations is safety. If you lose engines and you can't see out the window, the risk to passenger safety is obvious.</p>

<p>Naturally, people are upset about their holiday plans being held up. But it's actually in passengers' best interests to not fly through volcanic ash.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243576/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><strong><em><span>(<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/patrick-murray-2027113">Patrick Murray</a>, Emeritus Professor of Aviation, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-southern-queensland-1069">University of Southern Queensland</a></span></em></strong></p>

<p><strong><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/airlines-cancel-flights-after-volcanic-eruptions-an-aviation-expert-explains-why-thats-a-good-thing-243576">original article</a>.)</em></strong></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-12/203ma0hg_volcano-generic_625x300_09_December_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volcanic ash particles are very, very abrasive.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18th-century-scottish-sculpture-used-as-doorstop-could-fetch-over-rs-2-68-crore-at-auction-7007628]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[18th Century Sculpture Bought For Rs 540 Could Sell For Over Rs 2.68 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18th-century-scottish-sculpture-used-as-doorstop-could-fetch-over-rs-2-68-crore-at-auction-7007628]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:05:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A marble bust bought for &#163;5 (around Rs 540) and long used as a doorstop may soon fetch over &#163;2.5 million (Rs 2.68 crore).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A marble bust bought for £5 (around Rs 540) and long used as a doorstop may soon fetch over £2.5 million (Rs 2.68 crore). The sculpture, known as the Bouchardon Bust, was made in the early 18th century by renowned French sculptor Edmé Bouchardon and depicts the late Scottish landowner and politician John Gordon. Acquired by Invergordon Town Council in 1930 to honour Gordon, considered the town's founder, the bust was meant to be displayed in the local town hall. But after surviving a fire at a 19th-century castle, the sculpture was misplaced. It ended up being used to open a shed door in an industrial park until its rediscovery in 1998.</p>

<p>After the local government that owns the bust requested permission from Tain Sheriff Court in the Scottish Highlands to sell it, no objections were raised during the hearing, a spokeswoman for the Highland Council told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/12/style/marble-bust-doorstop-auction-intl-scli/index.html" rel="nofollow noindex">CNN.</a></p>

<p>This decision allows the council to proceed with the sale, which had been recommended by a council committee following a public consultation earlier this year. By June, the full council agreed to move forward with the sale.</p>

<p>The bust has attracted interest from a private overseas buyer, who has offered more than £2.5 million through Sotheby's, a renowned auction house. The buyer also pledged to fund a museum-quality replica of the bust for local display.</p>

<p>The sculpture's high value has kept it out of local exhibitions, though it has made appearances abroad, including at the Louvre in Paris in 2016 and the Getty Museum in Los Angeles in 2017.</p>

<p>The spokeswoman told CNN that following court approval last week, a legal review to determine if the bust qualifies as a “national treasure” — under the Waverley Criteria, which restricts certain items from being exported overseas — will “almost certainly be triggered.” When asked by CNN whether an auction would be held, the spokeswoman did not give any confirmation.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bqsf8eqg_bouchardon-bust-_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bust has attracted interest from a private overseas buyer.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>