<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:25:10 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-had-emergency-surgery-to-remove-lump-as-a-teen-reveals-new-book-6236131]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kate Middleton Had Emergency Surgery To Remove Lump As A Teen, Says New Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kate-middleton-had-emergency-surgery-to-remove-lump-as-a-teen-reveals-new-book-6236131]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:24:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The surgery left a three-inch scar which several people noticed on Ms Middleton's first solo engagement over two decades ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kate Middleton, Princess of Wales, revealed in March that she has been diagnosed with cancer. Amid this, a new royal biography has revealed that she had an emergency surgery as a teenager to remove a lump from her head, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/kate-middleton-cancer-lump-removal-princess-wales-b2588167.html"><em>Independent</em></a>. This was shared by royal author Rob Jobson in his upcoming book, 'Catherine, the Princess of Wales'.</p>

<p>"Apart from debilitating bouts of morning sickness and, of course, stays in the Lindo Wing at St Mary's Hospital to deliver her babies, Catherine has fortunately avoided hospital for most of her life," Mr Jobson explained. "As a teenager, however, when at Marlborough College she discovered a lump on the left side of her head, just under her hairline," he added.</p>

<p>The author added that her mother took her to the hospital where the doctors removed it. "The school notified her parents immediately and her mother Carole took her to hospital, where she had surgery to remove it," he wrote in the book.</p>

<p>However, the operation left a three-inch scar which several people noticed on Ms Middleton's first solo engagement over two decades ago. The Buckingham Palace shared a brief statement that read, "'The scar is related to a childhood operation."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Princess said in June that she was making good progress as she was undergoing preventative chemotherapy. However, she was "not out of the woods".</p>

<p>In a personal written message, Ms Middleton said she had been "blown away" by the thousands of kind messages from across the globe which followed her cancer announcement in March. "I am making good progress, but as anyone going through chemotherapy will know, there are good days and bad days," her statement said.</p>

<p>She added, "On those bad days you feel weak, tired and you have to give in to your body resting. But on the good days, when you feel stronger, you want to make the most of feeling well." She said they had made a world of difference to her and her husband, heir-to-the-throne Prince William.</p>

<p>"My treatment is ongoing and will be for a few more months," she said. "I'm looking forward to attending The King's Birthday Parade this weekend with my family and hope to join a few public engagements over the summer, but equally knowing I am not out of the woods yet," she said on June 14.</p>

<p>The Princess of Wales was recently seen at the Wimbledon Men's final in London as she walked onto the court to present the trophy to winner Carlos Alcaraz. A passionate tennis fan and player herself, Kate was greeted with a thunderous ovation as she entered the Royal Box at Centre Court, accompanied by her daughter Princess Charlotte and sister Pippa Matthews.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/f5dovut8_kate-middleton-reuters_625x300_23_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Princess said in June that she was making good progress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comic-con-undercover-agents-at-comic-con-rescue-10-sex-trafficking-victims-6236130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Undercover Agents Posed As Sex Buyers At Comic Con To Rescue Victims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/comic-con-undercover-agents-at-comic-con-rescue-10-sex-trafficking-victims-6236130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 07:22:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Undercover officers posing as sex buyers at last week's Comic-Con event in California rescued human trafficking victims, including a 16-year-old girl, and made multiple arrests, prosecutors said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Undercover officers posing as sex buyers at last week's Comic-Con event in California rescued human trafficking victims, including a 16-year-old girl, and made multiple arrests, prosecutors said Wednesday.</p>

<p>A task force involving local San Diego police, federal officers and naval intelligence arrested 14 people who were attempting to buy sex at the giant pop culture gathering.</p>

<p>Ten victims were rescued, nine of them adults, said California Attorney General Rob Bonta.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, sex traffickers capitalize on large-scale events such as Comic-Con to exploit their victims for profit," said Bonta, in a statement.</p>

<p>San Diego Comic-Con is one of the world's largest pop culture events.</p>

<p>Around 135,000 people were expected to attend the convention, which lasted from Thursday to Sunday.</p>

<p>"Obviously we find this very disturbing and, while we were not made aware of this operation, it is our understanding that the arrests were made outside of the event," a spokesperson for Comic-Con said in a statement to AFP.</p>

<p>"We work closely with a variety of law enforcement entities throughout the year and stand ready to assist in any way we can."</p>

<p>Originally a grassroots event for comic book fans to meet, Comic-Con has grown exponentially and is today used by giant Hollywood studios and A-list stars to launch their latest blockbuster movies and TV shows.</p>

<p>Christopher Davis, acting special agent in charge of Homeland Security Investigations in San Diego, said "highly attended events" like Comic-Con are often seen by criminals as "an opportunity to prey upon minors."</p>

<p>"Working together, teams identified and arrested more than a dozen individuals participating in these illegal acts in our city over the weekend," said San Diego Police Chief Scott Wahl.</p>

<p>Law enforcement personnel placed undercover advertisements soliciting sex in order to arrest sex buyers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nial63jo_comic-con-afp-_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[San Diego Comic-Con is one of the world's largest pop culture events.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-accepts-dare-to-fight-venezuela-president-whats-at-stake-6236030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If I Win, He Resigns. If He Wins...": Elon Musk Dares Venezuela President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-accepts-dare-to-fight-venezuela-president-whats-at-stake-6236030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 06:50:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk has accepted a challenge to fight Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on national television. The SpaceX and Tesla chief, and the owner of the social network X, took to his platform to respond to Maduro's challenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has accepted a challenge to fight Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro on national television. The SpaceX and Tesla chief, and the owner of the social network X, took to his platform to respond to Maduro's challenge. "I accept," he tweeted, sparking a flurry of reactions online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The animosity between Musk and Maduro has been brewing for some time amidst political turmoil in Caracas. Maduro, whose victory in the recent elections has been widely contested, has found a foe in Musk, a staunch ultra-capitalist and supporter of Donald Trump. This ideological clash pits billionaire Musk against Maduro, a socialist leader who rose from humble beginnings as a bus driver to preside over the oil-rich yet economically struggling nation.</p>

<p>Maduro has accused Musk of orchestrating attacks against Venezuela, alleging that the tech mogul is behind a supposed "computer hacking" at the National Electoral Council (CNE). The CNE controversially declared Maduro the winner of the latest vote without providing detailed data, a move that has led to allegations of foul play.</p>

<p>Following Musk's public comments against him, Maduro responded by saying, "Social media creates a virtual reality, and who controls the virtual reality? Our new archenemy, the famous Elon Musk," he began his speech. Do you want to fight? Let's do it. Elon Musk, I'm ready," Maduro said. I'm not afraid of you Elon Musk. Let's fight, wherever you want."</p>

<p>Musk took to X and replied to a lot of people reacting to the development. In one particular post Musk referred to Maduro as a "big guy", while taking a sly dig at Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg by terming him a "little fella".</p>

<p>"Maduro is a big guy himself and probably knows how to fight, so this would be a real fight. Zuck is a little fella, so that would be a short fight lol," he posted.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Maduro is a big guy himself and probably knows how to fight, so this would be a real fight.<br />
<br />
Zuck is a little fella, so that would be a short fight lol.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1818700101520703898?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"If I win, he resigns as dictator of Venezuela. If he wins, I give him a free ride to Mars," Musk wagered.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">If I win, he resigns as dictator of Venezuela.<br />
<br />
If he wins, I give him a free ride to Mars.</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1818699112134721953?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 31, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Following the Venezuelan election results, Musk expressed his disapproval, calling Maduro a "dictator" and describing the election as a "travesty." He even posted a 2020 announcement from the US Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) about criminal charges against Maduro for drug trafficking, which includes a $15 million reward for information leading to his arrest.</p>

<p>Maduro's response was fiery. "He wants to come here with his guns and an army to invade Venezuela. Elon Musk, good thing you showed your face because we knew you were behind it all! With your money and your satellites," Maduro claimed.</p>

<p>Musk's retort was sharp and in Spanish: "An ass knows more than Maduro." He later apologised, albeit sarcastically, adding, "Sorry to have compared the poor ass to Maduro. That was an insult to the animal kingdom."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5v31kjn8_maduro-musk-_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maduro has accused Musk of orchestrating attacks against Venezuela.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-male-charged-with-murder-of-3-girls-in-uk-knife-attack-6235857]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17-Year-Old Male Charged With Murder Of 3 Girls In UK Knife Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-year-old-male-charged-with-murder-of-3-girls-in-uk-knife-attack-6235857]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 05:58:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls and the attempted murder of 10 more people in a knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance class, UK prosecutors said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls and the attempted murder of 10 more people in a knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance class, UK prosecutors said.</p>

<p>"The Crown Prosecution Service (CPS) has authorised Merseyside Police to charge a 17-year-old male of Banks, Lancashire, with three counts of murder and ten counts of attempted murder, following the tragic incident that took place in Southport this week," prosecutors said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/2hmhj068_uk-police_625x300_12_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 17-year-old male was charged on Thursday with the murder of three girls.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-wants-to-restart-nuclear-talks-if-donald-trump-wins-says-ex-diplomat-6235708]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Wants To Restart Nuclear Talks If Trump Wins, Says Ex-Diplomat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-wants-to-restart-nuclear-talks-if-donald-trump-wins-says-ex-diplomat-6235708]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 05:06:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea wants to reopen nuclear talks with the United States if Donald Trump is re-elected as president and is working to devise a new negotiating strategy, a senior North Korean diplomat who recently defected to South Korea told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea wants to reopen nuclear talks with the United States if Donald Trump is re-elected as president and is working to devise a new negotiating strategy, a senior North Korean diplomat who recently defected to South Korea told Reuters.</p>

<p>The escape of Ri Il Gyu from Cuba made headlines globally last month. He was the highest-ranking North Korean diplomat to defect to the South since 2016.</p>

<p>In his first interview with international media, Ri said North Korea has set Russia, the U.S. and Japan as its top foreign policy priorities for this year and beyond.</p>

<p>While bolstering relations with Russia, Pyongyang was keen to reopen nuclear negotiations if Trump - who engaged in both fiery brinkmanship and unprecedented diplomacy with North Korea during his previous term - won re-election in November, Ri said.</p>

<p>Pyongyang's diplomats were mapping out a strategy for that scenario, with the goal of lifting of sanctions on its weapons programmes, removing its designation as a state sponsor of terrorism and eliciting economic aid, said Ri.</p>

<p>His comments signal a potential about-face from the North's current stance after recent statements ditching the possibility of dialogue with the U.S. and warning of armed confrontation.</p>

<p>A summit between North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Trump in Vietnam in 2019 collapsed over sanctions, for which Ri partly blamed Kim's decision to entrust "inexperienced, clueless" military commanders with nuclear diplomacy.</p>

<p>"Kim Jong Un doesn't know much about international relations and diplomacy, or how to make strategic judgment," he said.</p>

<p>"This time, the foreign ministry would definitely gain power and take charge, and it won't be so easy for Trump to tie North Korea's hands and feet again for four years without giving anything."</p>

<p><strong>RUSSIAN TIES, JAPAN AID</strong></p>

<p>By forging closer ties with Russia, North Korea received help with its missile technology and economy. But a bigger benefit could be to block additional sanctions and undercut existing ones, Ri said, adding it would raise Pyongyang's bargaining power against Washington.</p>

<p>"The Russians got their own hands dirty by engaging in illicit transactions and, thanks to that, North Korea no longer needs to rely on the U.S. to lift sanctions, which essentially means they stripped the U.S. of one key bargaining chip," he said.</p>

<p>In Tokyo, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida has said he wants to meet Kim, but the issue of Japanese nationals abducted by North Korea in the 1970s and 80s has long been a stumbling block.</p>

<p>According to Ri, Kim would seek to hold a summit with Japan, aiming to get economic assistance in return for concessions on the abductee issue.</p>

<p>Tokyo believes 17 of its citizens were abducted, five of whom returned to Japan in 2002. Pyongyang sees the issue as settled, having admitted to kidnapping 13 Japanese nationals and saying those unaccounted for had either died or their whereabouts were unknown.</p>

<p>Ri said Kim would be willing to change that position, established under his father Kim Jong Il, in order to obtain economic support.</p>

<p>"They're saying that the issue was resolved, but that's just to boost negotiating power until he makes concessions at a summit," he said.</p>

<p><strong>RESENTMENT AND DEFECTION</strong></p>

<p>Having studied at a French school in Algeria and lived in Cuba alongside his late father, who was a state media reporter, Ri says he had imagined a life in South Korea since his childhood, but never acted to flee until he was bullied by a diplomatic colleague for refusing his demand for bribes.</p>

<p>Then the defining moment came when Pyongyang instantly refused his request to get medical treatment in Mexico, at his own expense, for a ruptured disc in his neck.</p>

<p>"That exploded all the resentment I had been harbouring towards the regime," he said.</p>

<p>The COVID-19 lockdown deepened hardships at home and for those stationed overseas, with most telephone lines to Pyongyang cut to prevent any information from spreading in the outside world, Ri said.</p>

<p>Financial troubles have also forced North Korea to shut down a dozen of its 54 diplomatic missions.</p>

<p>"When they began reopening and summoning those working abroad in early 2023, they asked to bring everything from used toothbrushes to spoons back home, saying there's nothing there," he said.</p>

<p>Ri had also witnessed - and in his job tried to impede - the launch of diplomatic relations between South Korea and Cuba, a Cold War-era ally of North Korea.</p>

<p>"I had done everything to block that from happening, but establishing relations with Cuba was the best thing South Korea had done since last year," he said. "It was a model example of how the tides of history have turned, and where a normal civilisation of the international community is headed."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/gm98ccao_donald-trump-kim-jong-un-reuters_625x300_12_June_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The historic talk between Donald Trump and Kim Jong Un was held in Singapore in June 2018.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-plea-deal-reached-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6235674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Plea Deal Reached With 9/11 Mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-plea-deal-reached-with-9-11-mastermind-khalid-sheikh-mohammed-6235674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:52:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US prosecutors have reached a deal with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, the Pentagon said Wednesday, reportedly involving a guilty plea in exchange for avoiding a death penalty trial.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US prosecutors have reached a deal with 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed, the Pentagon said Wednesday, reportedly involving a guilty plea in exchange for avoiding a death penalty trial.</p>

<p>The agreements with Mohammed and two other accused moves their long-running cases toward resolution. These have been bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings for years while the defendants remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>A Pentagon statement said no details of the deal would be immediately made public at this time, but the New York Times reported that Mohammed, Walid bin Attash and Mustafa al-Hawsawi had agreed to plead guilty to conspiracy in exchange for a life sentence instead of a trial after they could get the death penalty.</p>

<p>Such a proposal was detailed by prosecutors in a letter last year but divided the families of the nearly 3,000 people killed in the September 11, 2001 attacks, with some still wanting the defendants to face the ultimate penalty.</p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone methodical torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11 -- a thorny question that the plea deals help avoid.</p>

<p>Mohammed was regarded as one of Al-Qaeda chief Osama bin Laden's most trusted and intelligent lieutenants before his March 2003 capture in Pakistan. He then spent three years in secret CIA prisons before arriving in Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The trained engineer -- who has said he masterminded the 9/11 attacks "from A to Z" -- was involved in a string of major plots against the United States, where he had attended university.</p>

<p>In addition to planning the operation to bring down the Twin Towers, Mohammed claims to have personally beheaded US journalist Daniel Pearl in 2002 with his "blessed right hand," and to have helped in the 1993 World Trade Center bombing that killed six people.</p>

<p>- 'War on Terror' prison -<br />
Bin Attash, a Saudi of Yemeni origin, allegedly trained two of the hijackers who carried out the September 11 attacks, and his US interrogators also said he confessed to buying the explosives and recruiting members of the team that killed 17 sailors in an attack on the USS Cole.</p>

<p>He took refuge in neighboring Pakistan after the US invasion of Afghanistan in 2001 and was captured there in 2003, and was then held in a network of secret CIA prisons.</p>

<p>Hawsawi is suspected of managing the finance for the 9/11 attacks. He was arrested in Pakistan on March 1, 2003, was also held in secret prisons before being transferred to Guantanamo in 2006.</p>

<p>The United States used Guantanamo, an isolated naval base, to hold militants captured during the "War on Terror" that followed the September 11 attacks in a bid to keep the defendants from claiming rights under US law.</p>

<p>The facility held 800 prisoners at its peak, but they have since slowly been repatriated to other countries. President Joe Biden pledged before his election to try and shut down Guantanamo, but it &nbsp;remains open.</p>

<p>In another 9/11-related case, the Justice Department denied a request by Zacarias Moussaoui, the so-called "20th hijacker," to serve the remainder of his life sentence in France.</p>

<p>In a hand-written letter to District Judge Leonie Brinkema obtained by the website Legal Insurrection, Moussaoui -- the only person convicted in the United States in connection with the September 11 attacks -- expressed fears he would be executed if Donald Trump regains the presidency in November.</p>

<p>A Justice Department spokeswoman said the department does not discuss prisoner transfer requests but noted that Moussaoui is "serving a life sentence following conviction for terrorism offenses."</p>

<p>"The Department of Justice plans to enforce this life sentence in US custody," the spokeswoman added.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/60bhh5ro_us-guantanamo-naval-base_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US used Guantanamo, an isolated naval base, to hold militants captured during the "War on Terror".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-orders-attack-on-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killing-report-6235614]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Leader Orders Attack On Israel For Ismail Haniyeh Killing: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/irans-supreme-leader-ayatollah-ali-khamenei-orders-attack-on-israel-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killing-report-6235614]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 04:36:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has ordered Iran to strike Israel directly, in retaliation for the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, New York Times reported, citing three Iranian officials, briefed on the order.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Iran's supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, has ordered Iran to strike Israel directly, in retaliation for the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, New York Times reported, citing three Iranian officials, briefed on the order, including two members of the Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>Khamenei gave the order at an emergency meeting of Iran's Supreme National Security Council on Wednesday morning, shortly after Iran announced that Haniyeh had been killed.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas have accused Israel of the assassination. Israel, which is at war with Hamas in the Gaza Strip, has neither acknowledged nor denied killing Haniyeh, who was in Tehran for the inauguration of Iran's new president.</p>

<p>Notably, Israel has a long history of killing enemies abroad, including Iranian nuclear scientists and military commanders, according to the NYT.</p>

<p>Through almost 10 months of war in Gaza, Iran has tried to strike a balance, putting pressure on Israel with sharply increased attacks by its allies and proxy forces in the region, while avoiding an all-out war between the two nations.</p>

<p>In its biggest and most overt attack on Israel, Iran launched hundreds of missiles and drones in April in retaliation for an Israeli strike on its embassy compound that killed several Iranian military commanders in the Syrian capital of Damascus.</p>

<p>"Now it is unclear how forcefully Iran will respond, and whether it will once again calibrate its attack to steer clear of escalation. Iranian military commanders are considering another combination attack of drones and missiles on military targets in the vicinity of Tel Aviv and Haifa, but would make a point of avoiding strikes on civilian targets," the Iranian officials said.</p>

<p>One option under consideration is a coordinated attack from Iran and other fronts where it has allied forces, including Yemen, Syria and Iraq, for maximum effect, they added.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who has the last word on all state matters and is also the commander in chief of the armed forces, instructed military commanders from the Revolutionary Guards and the army to prepare plans for both an attack and a defence in case the war expands and Israel or the US strike Iran, the officials said.</p>

<p>In his public statement about Haniyeh's death, Khamenei signalled that Iran would retaliate directly, saying, "we see avenging his blood our duty," because it happened on the territory of the Islamic Republic. He said Israel had set the stage for receiving "a severe punishment," New York Times reported.</p>

<p>Other Iranian officials, including the newly elected president, Masoud Pezeshkian, the foreign ministry, the Guards and Iran's mission to the UN, also said openly that Iran would retaliate against Israel and that it had a right to defend itself against a transgression on its sovereignty.</p>

<p>Iran and the regional forces it backs -- Hamas, Hezbollah in Lebanon, the Houthis in Yemen and multiple militias in Iraq -- form what they call the "axis of resistance."</p>

<p>Leaders of those groups were in Tehran for the inauguration of Pezeshkian on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Haniyeh was assassinated at about 2 am (local time), after attending the ceremony and meeting with Khamenei. The killing shocked Iranian officials, who described it as crossing red lines.</p>

<p>According to the NYT, it was a humiliating security breach for Iran, which is eager to project strength but has been unable to prevent Israel from carrying out covert operations on its soil. The embarrassment was compounded by Haniyeh's prominence, the presence of other allies, and that he was attacked at a highly secure Revolutionary Guards guesthouse on a day of heightened security in the capital.</p>

<p>It further reported citing analysts that Tehran sees retaliation as necessary for both avenging the killing of Haniyeh but also as deterrence against Israel killing other powerful enemies, like Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, or General Ismail Qaani, the commander of the Quds Forces who oversees the militant groups outside Iran.</p>

<p>"Iran likely believes it has no choice other than retaliating to deter further Israeli attacks, defend its sovereignty, and preserve its credibility in the eyes of its regional partners," said Ali Vaez, the Iran director of the International Crisis Group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/b3d2u2tg_ayatollah-ali-khamenei_625x300_01_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran's Supreme Leader gave the order to attack on Israel at an emergency meeting on Wednesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-elon-musk-battle-it-out-online-6235466]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Venezuela's Nicolas Maduro, Elon Musk Battle It Out Online]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-elon-musk-battle-it-out-online-6235466]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:46:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, whose claim to victory at the polls has been widely contested, is no friend of billionaire Elon Musk, and the feeling is clearly mutual, with their war of words escalating amid the political crisis in Caracas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro, whose claim to victory at the polls has been widely contested, is no friend of billionaire Elon Musk, and the feeling is clearly mutual, with their war of words escalating amid the political crisis in Caracas.</p>

<p>Musk -- who leads SpaceX and Tesla, and owns the social network X -- is an ultra-capitalist who backs Donald Trump, meaning he is everything that the socialist Maduro despises.</p>

<p>But in recent days, the bus driver-turned-leader of oil-rich, cash-poor Venezuela has Musk -- who he calls his "arch-enemy" -- in his sights.</p>

<p>Maduro has accused Musk of being behind "attacks against Venezuela" and possibly the mastermind of an alleged "computer hacking" at the National Electoral Council (CNE), which declared Maduro the winner of Sunday's vote without providing detailed data.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, following a meeting of Maduro's top political and military advisors, he announced the creation of a special committee, aided by Russian and Chinese experts, to evaluate the nation's biosecurity and an attack on the CNE's communications systems.</p>

<p>"The attacks, I am sure, were directed by the power of Elon Musk," he said.</p>

<p>Opposition figures and observers do not believe there was actually a hack, but that authorities self-sabotaged the system so they would not have to provide the real election results.</p>

<p>Before voters cast their ballots, the 61-year-old Maduro was running well behind opposition candidate Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia in independent opinion polls.</p>

<p>Late Tuesday, Maduro addressed hundreds of supporters from his balcony -- and once again attacked the 53-year-old Musk.</p>

<p>"Venezuela, as I said yesterday and today, is facing domestic and international aggression from world powers, and now it is evident that Elon Musk is obsessed with the idea of taking over Venezuela and ruling it from abroad," Maduro said.</p>

<p>"He is largely responsible for these attacks and acts of aggression," he added, suggesting the existence of a "global alliance of the far right, the fascist far right, drug traffickers, Elon Musk and the imperialist US government."</p>

<p>"All those who come after Venezuela, we will eliminate them."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Shame on Dictator Maduro' -</strong><br />
Musk has regularly slammed Maduro's policies on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When asked about the criticisms, a senior Venezuelan foreign ministry official said on condition of anonymity: "We know who Musk is. He's on the far right and supports (Argentine President Javier) Milei... So we take all these remarks as compliments."</p>

<p>Before Sunday's election, Musk posted: "It is time for the people of Venezuela to have the chance for a better future. Support Maria Corina!"</p>

<p>He was referring to the wildly popular opposition leader Maria Corina Machado, who was barred from running against Maduro.</p>

<p>After the vote, and the announcement of the results, Musk said Sunday: "Shame on Dictator Maduro" and "What a travesty."</p>

<p>He also posted a 2020 announcement from the US Drug Enforcement Administration of criminal charges against Maduro for drug trafficking and a $15 million reward for information leading to his arrest.</p>

<p>The posts sparked outrage from Maduro.</p>

<p>"He wants to come here with his guns and an army to invade Venezuela. Elon Musk, good thing you showed your face because we knew you were behind it all! With your money and your satellites," Maduro said.</p>

<p>"He wants to control the world, he already controls Argentina... You want to fight? Elon Musk, I am ready. I am the son of Bolivar and Chavez, I'm not afraid of you, Elon Musk... The people defeated Elon Musk's bots, we defeated Elon Musk's bots!"</p>

<p>Musk's retort came in Spanish: "An ass knows more than Maduro."</p>

<p>Later on, the billionaire added: "Sorry to have compared the poor ass to Maduro. That was an insult to the animal kingdom."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/do8o3bco_elon-musk-reuters-_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nicolas Maduro has accused Musk of being behind "attacks against Venezuela".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-expresses-concern-over-escalating-middle-east-conflict-risk-6235408]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Expresses Concern Over Escalating Middle East Conflict Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-expresses-concern-over-escalating-middle-east-conflict-risk-6235408]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:21:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The White House on Wednesday voiced concern about the increased risk of an escalation into a broader Middle East war after the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran drew threats of retaliation against Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The White House on Wednesday voiced concern about the increased risk of an escalation into a broader Middle East war after the assassination of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran drew threats of retaliation against Israel.</p>

<p>Speaking to reporters at a daily briefing, White House national security spokesperson John Kirby said, however, that Washington did not see an all-out conflict in the region as imminent or inevitable and that it was working to prevent that from happening.</p>

<p>He said the U.S. still believed there was a "viable" process to reach a ceasefire deal to end more than nine months of fighting between Israel and Hamas in the Gaza Strip, despite concerns that effort had been dealt a serious blow.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Islamist militant group Hamas and Iran's Revolutionary Guards confirmed the death of Haniyeh, who had participated in internationally-brokered indirect talks on reaching a ceasefire in the Palestinian enclave. The Guards said it took place hours after he attended a swearing-in ceremony for Iran's new president.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government made no mention of Haniyeh's killing in a televised statement on Wednesday evening but said Israel had delivered crushing blows to Iran's proxies of late, including Hamas and Hezbollah, and would respond forcefully to any attack.</p>

<p>The assassination occurred less than 24 hours after Israel claimed to have killed Hezbollah's most senior military commander in the Lebanese capital Beirut in retaliation for a deadly rocket strike in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights.</p>

<p><strong>CONCERNS OF ESCALATION</strong></p>

<p>"We don't want to see an escalation," Kirby told reporters. "Those risks go up and down every day. They are certainly up right now. They don't make the task of de-escalation, deterrence and dissuasion - which is the goal - any less complicated."</p>

<p>Kirby referred, however, to comments by Iran's Ayatollah Ali Khamenei. The Supreme Leader said Israel had provided the grounds for "harsh punishment for itself" and it was Tehran's duty to avenge Haniyeh's death.</p>

<p>Iranian forces had already made strikes directly on Israel earlier in the Gaza war, which was triggered by a Hamas-led cross-border attack on Israel on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>Kirby declined to say whether the U.S. was urging restraint by Israel, except to say: "We have been working hard to keep this war from escalating."</p>

<p>While the latest events appear to set back any prospects for an imminent ceasefire agreement in Gaza, Kirby said: "We haven't seen any indications ... that the process has been completely torpedoed."</p>

<p>"We still believe the deal on the table is worth pursuing," he added.</p>

<p>U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken, at an event in Singapore, sidestepped a question on Haniyeh's killing, saying a ceasefire deal in Gaza was key to avoiding wider regional conflict. He told Channel News Asia that the U.S. had neither been aware of nor involved in the killing.</p>

<p>Blinken spoke by phone to Jordanian and Qatari leaders, and the State Department said they discussed regional tensions and efforts to reach a Gaza ceasefire.</p>

<p>The United States will take every possible measure to protect its personnel and interests in the Middle East after recent attacks there, U.S. State Department Deputy spokesperson Vedant Patel told reporters.</p>

<p>The U.S. also urged its citizens to not travel to Lebanon, citing rising tensions between Israel and the Lebanon-based Hezbollah group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/lha87bsg_john-kirby_625x300_16_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The White House official declined to say whether the U.S. was urging restraint by Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-she-indian-or-black-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-6234983]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Is She Indian Or Black?": Donald Trump On Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/is-she-indian-or-black-donald-trump-on-kamala-harris-6234983]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 01:17:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump questioned Wednesday whether Democrat Kamala Harris is really Black or is using race as a political convenience in an interview that sent shockwaves through the 2024 presidential contest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump questioned Wednesday whether Democrat Kamala Harris is really Black or is using race as a political convenience in an interview that sent shockwaves through the 2024 presidential contest.</p>

<p>"She was always of Indian heritage, and she was only promoting Indian heritage. I didn't know she was Black until a number of years ago when she happened to turn Black," Trump told a panel of interviewers at the National Association of Black Journalists conference in Chicago.</p>

<p>"And now she wants to be known as Black. So I don't know, is she Indian or is she Black?" he said of Harris, who is the first Black, female, and South-Asian-heritage vice president in US history.</p>

<p>"I respect either one but she obviously doesn't, because she was Indian all the way and then all of a sudden she made a turn, and she became a Black person."</p>

<p>The provocative comments by the Republican presidential nominee were the latest in a stream of ratcheted up personal attacks by the 78-year-old on Harris, and follow his multiple remarks this week in which he accused Harris -- who is married to a Jewish-American -- of being anti-Semitic.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden's White House swiftly responded to Trump's comments, calling them "insulting."</p>

<p>"No one has any right to tell someone who they are, how they identify," White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, the first black woman to hold the position, told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7s3biquo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_30_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump said that Kamala Harris was only promoting Indian heritage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-chief-antonio-guterres-calls-killing-of-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-dangerous-escalation-6234836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Chief Calls Killing Of Hamas, Hezbollah Leaders "Dangerous Escalation"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-chief-antonio-guterres-calls-killing-of-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-dangerous-escalation-6234836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:39:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Calling the twin strikes by Israel killing senior leaders of Hamas and Hezbollah during a 24-hour period a "dangerous escalation", UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has called for an international diplomatic push to prevent the conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling the twin strikes by Israel killing senior leaders of Hamas and Hezbollah during a 24-hour period a "dangerous escalation", UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has called for an international diplomatic push to prevent a broader regional conflict.</p>

<p>"The international community must work together to urgently prevent any actions that could push the entire Middle East over the edge, with a devastating impact on civilians," the UN chief's Spokesperson Stephane Dujarric said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was killed in an audacious strike inside Iran on Wednesday during his visit for the swearing-in of newly-elected Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian, according to Hamas.</p>

<p>A short while earlier, Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr was killed in an air strike in Beirut.</p>

<p>"The Secretary-General believes that the attacks we have seen in South Beirut and Tehran represent a dangerous escalation at a moment in which all efforts should instead be leading to a ceasefire in Gaza, the release of all Israeli hostages, a massive increase of humanitarian aid for Palestinians in Gaza and a return to calm in Lebanon and across the Blue Line that separates Lebanon from Israel," Dujarric said.</p>

<p>While Guterres has been calling for maximum restraint, it alone is not enough "at this extremely sensitive time" and he "urges all to vigorously work towards regional de-escalation", the spokesperson added.</p>

<p>Iran's UN Mission warned of an escalation, saying in an X post: "The response to an assassination will indeed be special operations -- harder and intended to instill deep regret in the perpetrator."</p>

<p>While Israel military confirmed it had taken out Shukr, Israel was silent on the killing of Haniyeh, a serious setback to ceasefire efforts in Gaza because the Qatar-based leader was a key negotiator with Israel for a ceasefire and the return of hostages taken by Hamas during the October 7 attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/otldtf18_antonio-guterres_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Antonio Guterres has called for an international diplomatic push to prevent a broader regional conflict.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-al-jazeera-journalists-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-gaza-report-6234787]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Al Jazeera Journalists Killed In Israeli Strike On Gaza: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-al-jazeera-journalists-killed-in-israeli-strike-on-gaza-report-6234787]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:24:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two Al Jazeera journalists were killed on Wednesday in an Israeli strike in Gaza, the Qatar-based channel reported as war rages in the Palestinian territory between Israel and Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Two Al Jazeera journalists were killed on Wednesday in an Israeli strike in Gaza, the Qatar-based channel reported as war rages in the Palestinian territory between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>"Al Jazeera Arabic journalist Ismail al-Ghoul and his cameraman Rami al-Refee have been killed in an Israeli attack on the Gaza Strip," the network reported adding the strike "targeted a car near the Aidia area, west of Gaza City".</p>

<p>Since the start of the war in Gaza on October 7, Al Jazeera has aired continuous on-the-ground reporting on the effects of Israel's campaign.</p>

<p>The network's office in Gaza has already been bombed in the conflict and two other correspondents killed.</p>

<p>In a statement, Hamas condemned the killings as a "heinous crime" which it said was "aimed at terrorising and silencing" Palestinian journalists as they reported "the ongoing genocide against our people in the Gaza Strip for nearly ten months".</p>

<p>Al Jazeera has been the focus of months of criticism from Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and his government.</p>

<p>Last month, an Israeli court confirmed it had extended a ban on the network, which broadcasts in Arabic and English, initially placed on Al Jazeera in early May.</p>

<p>In January, Israel said an Al Jazeera staff journalist and a freelancer killed in an air strike in Gaza were "terror operatives".</p>

<p>The following month, it accused another journalist with the channel who was wounded in a separate strike of being a "deputy company commander" with Hamas.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera has fiercely denied Israel's allegations and accused it of systematically targeting Al Jazeera employees in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>Its bureau chief in Gaza, Wael al-Dahdouh, was wounded in an Israeli strike in December that killed the network's cameraman.</p>

<p>His wife, two of their children and a grandson were killed in the October bombardment of central Gaza's Nuseirat refugee camp.</p>

<p>His eldest son was the Al Jazeera staff journalist killed in January when a strike targeted a car in Rafah.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, an Israeli court confirmed it had extended a ban on the network. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-names-ex-aerospace-veteran-robert-kelly-ortberg-as-new-ceo-6234702]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Boeing Names Ex Aerospace Veteran Robert "Kelly" Ortberg As New CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boeing-names-ex-aerospace-veteran-robert-kelly-ortberg-as-new-ceo-6234702]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:04:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Boeing on Wednesday named former aerospace veteran Robert "Kelly" Ortberg its next CEO, as the aviation giant reported a hefty loss on continued operational problems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boeing on Wednesday named former aerospace veteran Robert "Kelly" Ortberg its next CEO, as the aviation giant reported a hefty loss on continued operational problems.</p>

<p>Ortberg, 64, helped lead aviation communications and electronics supplier Rockwell Collins and integrate it into United Technologies, which then merged with Raytheon to become RTX. He retired from RTX in 2021.</p>

<p>He is an engineer and is an outsider to Boeing, fulfilling key CEO requirements in the eyes of some aviation insiders.</p>

<p>His appointment, which will take effect August 8, comes as Boeing attempts to rebound from a series of safety and quality control problems that have sharpened scrutiny on the company.</p>

<p>Those difficulties were immediately visible in Boeing's second-quarter results released Wednesday, a loss of $1.4 billion, compared with a loss of $149 million in the year-ago period.</p>

<p>Revenues fell 14.6 percent to $16.9 billion.</p>

<p>The quarterly results reflected a continued drag from Boeing's commercial division, where it has lowered production while upgrading safety and quality control practices under the close watch of regulators.</p>

<p>The latest results also showed significant weakness in its defense business due to a number of fixed price contracts where it has experienced deep losses due to supply chain problems, as well as higher engineering costs and technical issues.</p>

<p>Boeing listed four defense contracts behind an operating loss of $913 million in the quarter.</p>

<p>- Leadership shake-up -</p>

<p>Boeing has been in the hot seat since a January incident in which a 737 MAX operated by Alaska Airlines made an emergency landing after a fuselage panel blew out mid-flight.</p>

<p>That incident raised fresh scrutiny on Boeing and the MAX following two fatal crashes in 2018 and 2019 that led to a lengthy grounding of the plane.</p>

<p>Outgoing leader Dave Calhoun ascended to CEO in January 2020 unexpectedly following the ouster of predecessor Dennis Muilenburg amid fallout from the MAX crashes.</p>

<p>Calhoun appeared poised to stay on as CEO to 2028 until the Alaska Airlines incident sparked outrage on Capitol Hill and concern among Boeing's airline customers. Calhoun announced on March 25 that he would step down by the end of this year.</p>

<p>Aviation experts had hoped the next Boeing CEO would ideally have an aerospace background, experience managing big manufacturing projects, strategic smarts, a hands-on approach to safety and the ability to navigate congressional hearings.</p>

<p>In Wednesday's statement, Boeing Chairman Steve Mollenkopf described Ortberg as "an experienced leader who is deeply respected in the aerospace industry."</p>

<p>Ortberg said he was "extremely honored and humbled to join this iconic company," adding: "There is much work to be done, and I'm looking forward to getting started."</p>

<p>Some analysts have suggested that Boeing's next CEO could remake the company's executive ranks.</p>

<p>But Calhoun indicated he does not expect significant personnel changes, saying, "I don't think this is intended to be a large leadership overhaul."</p>

<p>Ortberg "knows full well that we're in a recovery mode," said Calhoun, adding that he was not deeply involved in the CEO selection process.</p>

<p>- 'Very challenging job' -</p>

<p>Immediate priorities facing Ortberg include negotiations with a machinists' and aerospace union amid a potential September strike threat; and restoring production levels on the MAX and 787 Dreamliner to meet Boeing's targets by late 2024.</p>

<p>Analysts at JPMorgan Chase praised the appointment, while noting the CEO post "remains a very challenging job," according to a note.</p>

<p>"We believe he is highly respected in the industry, he has important operational and engineering experience, and we think he has the potential to do some of the things Boeing needs most, including restoring relationships with customers, suppliers, regulators, and legislators," said the JPMorgan note.</p>

<p>Third Bridge analyst Peter McNally said Ortberg's aviation experience will help at Boeing, but said "he and the organization face a long road ahead."</p>

<p>Ortberg is set to take office just after a two-day hearing organized by the National Transportation Safety Board in Washington on the Alaska Airlines incident.</p>

<p>Boeing has agreed to plead guilty to a fraud charge as part of a plea deal with the US Department of Justice over the two fatal MAX crashes, according to a court filing last week.</p>

<p>The deal must be approved by a federal judge.</p>

<p>Shares of Boeing rose 3.0 percent near midday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c0onvjs8_robert-kelly_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shares of Boeing rose 3.0 percent near midday. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/top-hezbollah-commanders-body-recovered-from-israeli-strike-rubble-report-6234666]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Top Hezbollah Commander's Body Recovered From Israeli Strike Rubble: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/top-hezbollah-commanders-body-recovered-from-israeli-strike-rubble-report-6234666]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 23:57:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The body of top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr was recovered Wednesday from the rubble of an Israeli strike in south Beirut a source close to the group said, as fears mounted of a wider war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>The body of top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr was recovered Wednesday from the rubble of an Israeli strike in south Beirut a source close to the group said, as fears mounted of a wider war.</p>

<p>The raid on the Beirut suburb, an overcrowded residential area that is also a Hezbollah bastion, killed five civilians -- three women and two children, according to Lebanon's health ministry.</p>

<p>It was followed by another strike, hours later, which killed Hezbollah ally Hamas's political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, further stoking fears that the Gaza war could spill over.</p>

<p>UN Secrertary-General Antonio Guterres denounced the two strikes as a "dangerous escalation at a moment in which all efforts should instead be leading to a ceasefire in Gaza" and "the release of all Israeli hostages", his spokesman Stephane Dujarric said in a statement.</p>

<p>Lina Khatib, an associate fellow and Middle East expert at Chatham House, told AFP: "Even if the actors involved do not intend for all-out war to break out, every escalation increases the risk of things spiralling out of control."</p>

<p>The source, who requested anonymity due to the sensitivity of the matter, said "Shukr's body has been found under the rubble of the targeted building," after Israel's military said it had killed the commander on Tuesday.</p>

<p>AFP photographers saw rescuers combing through the rubble almost immediately after explosions rocked the Lebanese capital on Tuesday evening.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its strike had "eliminated" Shukr, who it blamed for carrying out a weekend rocket attack on the annexed Golan Heights that killed 12 children in a Druze Arab town.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has denied responsibility for Saturday's deadly rocket strike on the Druze Arab town of Majdal Shams in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights, though the Iran-backed group claimed multiple strikes on Israeli military positions that day.</p>

<p>The Israeli army has described Shukr as Hezbollah's "most senior military commander" and "right-hand man" to the group's chief Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Army chief Herzi Halevi said on Wednesday that Israel would "not let the situation return to having (Hezbollah) present on the border" where there have been near-daily exchanges of fire between the group and Israel.</p>

<p>Ahead of the strike, Hezbollah evacuated some of its positions in southern and eastern Lebanon in anticipation of Israeli retaliation.</p>

<p><strong>'I could lose my children'</strong></p>

<p>Earlier on Wednesday, Hezbollah confirmed Shukr was inside the targeted building but said his fate was still unknown.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said in a statement that "the great jihadist commander brother Fuad Shukr (Hajj Mohsen) was present" in the targeted building with rescue teams "working... to remove the rubble... and we are still waiting for the results of this operation regarding the fate of the great commander".</p>

<p>Hundreds of mourners on Wednesday chanted "death to Israel" and "America is the Great Satan" at the funeral of siblings Amira and Hassan Fadlallah, the two children killed in the raid.</p>

<p>At the procession in southern Beirut, some carried photographs of the two dead siblings while others held up Hezbollah's flag.</p>

<p>"I feel very angry because the... lives of our children are becoming very cheap," said Aya Ahmed, 38, a friend of the two killed children's mother.</p>

<p>"Every mother now is thinking: I could lose my children at any moment because the Israelis have a license to kill," said Ahmed.</p>

<p>In 2017, the US Treasury offered $5 million for information on Shukr, in his early sixties, describing him as "a senior adviser" to Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>The Treasury said he had "a central role" in the deadly 1983 bombing of the US Marine Corps barracks in Beirut.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military said its strike had "eliminated" Fuad Shukr,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-case-of-virgin-birth-in-italy-female-sharks-make-babies-alone-report-6234646]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[First Case Of "Virgin Birth" In Italy, Female Sharks Make Babies: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/first-case-of-virgin-birth-in-italy-female-sharks-make-babies-alone-report-6234646]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 23:51:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Italian researchers have noted the first case of "virgin birth", or reproduction without fertilisation, in an endangered shark species, a scientific journal reported this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Italian researchers have noted the first case of "virgin birth", or reproduction without fertilisation, in an endangered shark species, a scientific journal reported this week.</p>

<p>The findings published in Scientific Reports concern the first case of the phenomenon in the common smooth-hound shark, Mustelus mustelus, a species threatened by illegal fishing that inhabits the Mediterranean and other warm waters.</p>

<p>Researchers from the Experimental Zooprophylactic Institute of Piedmont, Liguria and the Aosta Valley found that two female M. mustelus sharks under observation in captivity had exhibited parthenogenesis -- in which a female can reproduce asexually without the need of sperm to fertilise the egg -- each year since 2020.</p>

<p>The two 18-year-old sharks have been at the Cala Gonone Aquarium in Sardinia since 2010.</p>

<p>"Remarkably, this finding reveals that parthenogenesis can occur annually in these sharks, alternating between two females, and conclusively excludes long-term sperm storage as a cause," the study's authors wrote.</p>

<p>Cycling parthenogenesis, in which progeny can be born either from fertilised eggs or asexually with unfertilised eggs, occurs in over 15,000 species, yet is not fully understood.</p>

<p>Parthenogenesis, which is more common in invertebrates than vertebrates, has not yet been seen in mammals.</p>

<p>Reptiles and some sharks, rays and skates are able to "modify their adaptive strategy according to the surrounding circumstances", the authors wrote.</p>

<p>"Although the mechanisms driving parthenogenesis remain unclear, it is suggested that male population reduction could be a pivotal factor," they said.</p>

<p>Sharks in the wild pose challenges to understanding the phenomenon, but conditions in captivity are ideal for long-term monitoring, they noted.</p>

<p>Aquariums in the United States, United Arab Emirates and Australia have documented the phenomenon in other shark species in the past two decades.</p>

<p>M. mustelus, a midsize shark found in shallower waters that can potentially live up to 25 years, is classified as endangered, with estimates showing the population could decline by as much as a half in the next several decades, according to the study.</p>

<p>The study tracked two 18-year-old female sharks in the aquarium for 13 years, without the presence of males.</p>

<p>"Nonetheless, a nearly annual production of young was observed in the absence of males," the authors wrote.</p>

<p>The researchers studied the DNA of the offspring to exclude the possibility they were conceived because of long-term storage of sperm by the mothers.</p>

<p>The authors also noted that only one of the sharks born from parthenogenesis at the aquarium is still alive today. The two adults "are in good health", sharing their large exhibition tank with other Mediterranean marine species.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8t9uqjs_shark_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two sharks have been at the Cala Gonone Aquarium in Sardinia since 2010. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-smacked-a-spacecraft-into-an-asteroid-what-it-learnt-from-the-mission-6233683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA Smacked A Spacecraft Into An Asteroid - What It Learnt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-smacked-a-spacecraft-into-an-asteroid-what-it-learnt-from-the-mission-6233683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 21:16:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NASA's DART mission  Double Asteroid Redirection Test  was humanitys first real-world planetary defence mission.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA's DART mission – <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/dart">Double Asteroid Redirection Test</a> – was humanity's first real-world planetary defence mission.</p>

<p>In September 2022, the DART spacecraft smashed into the companion “moon” of a small asteroid 11 million kilometres from Earth. One goal was to find out if we can <a href="https://theconversation.com/new-results-from-nasas-dart-planetary-defence-mission-confirm-we-could-deflect-deadly-asteroids-200835">give such things a shove</a> if one were headed our way.</p>

<p>By gathering lots of data on approach and after the impact, we would also get a better idea of what we'd be in for if such an asteroid were to hit Earth.</p>

<p>Five new studies <a href="https://www.nature.com/ncomms/">published in Nature Communications</a> today have used the images sent back from DART and its travel buddy <a href="https://www.asi.it/en/planets-stars-universe/solar-system-and-beyond/liciacube/">LICIACube</a> to unravel the origins of the Didymos-Dimorphos dual asteroid system. They've also put that data in context for other asteroids out there.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="A slightly blurry image of a grey rock that looks a bit like a potato on a black background." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=450&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609842/original/file-20240729-19-r8fu36.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=566&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">DART's last complete image of Dimorphos, about 12km from the asteroid and 2 seconds before impact.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://science.nasa.gov/solar-system/asteroids/didymos/">NASA/Johns Hopkins APL</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2>Asteroids are natural hazards</h2>

<p>Our Solar System is full of small asteroids – debris that never made it into planets. Those that come close to Earth's orbit around the Sun are called Near Earth Objects (NEOs). These pose the biggest risk to us, but are also the most accessible.</p>

<p>Planetary defence from these natural hazards really depends on knowing their composition – not just what they're made of, but how they're put together. Are they solid objects that will punch through our atmosphere if given the chance, or are they <a href="https://theconversation.com/our-solar-system-is-filled-with-asteroids-that-are-particularly-hard-to-destroy-new-study-finds-197413">more like rubble piles</a>, barely held together?</p>

<p>The Didymos asteroid, and its tiny moon Dimorphos, are what's known as a binary asteroid system. They were the perfect target for the DART mission, because the effects of the impact could be easily measured in changes to Dimorphos' orbit.</p>

<p>They are also close(ish) to Earth, or are at least NEOs. And they're a very common type of asteroid we haven't had a good look at before. The chance to also learn how binary asteroids form was the icing on the cake.</p>

<p>Quite a few binary asteroid systems have been discovered, but planetary scientists don't exactly know how they form. In one of the new studies, a team <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50146-x">led by Olivier Barnouin</a> from Johns Hopkins University in the United States used images from DART and LICIACube to estimate the age of the system by looking at surface roughness and crater records.</p>

<p>They found Didymos is roughly 12.5 million years old, while its moon Dimorphos formed less than 300,000 years ago. That may still sound like a lot, but it's much younger than was expected.</p>

<h2>A pile of boulders</h2>

<p>Dimorphos is also not a solid rock as we'd typically imagine. It is a rubble pile of boulders that are barely held together. Along with its young age, it shows there can be multiple “generations” of these rubble pile asteroids in the wake of larger asteroid collisions.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2213133716301330">Sunlight actually causes</a> small bodies like asteroids to spin. As Didymos started to spin like a top, its shape became squashed and bulged in the middle. This was enough to cause large pieces to just roll off the main body, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50149-8">with some even leaving tracks</a>.</p>

<p>These pieces slowly created a ring of debris around Didymos. Over time, as the debris started sticking together, it formed the smaller moon Dimorphos.</p>

<figure><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2c4iMI-V2Iw?wmode=transparent&amp;start=0" width="650"></iframe>

<figcaption><span class="caption">How the spin of Didymos could have produced its tiny moon Dimorphos. Video by Yun Zhang.</span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Another study, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50148-9">led by Maurizio Pajola</a> from Auburn University in the US used boulder distributions to confirm this. The team also discovered there were significantly more (up to five times) large boulders than have been observed on other non-binary asteroids humans have visited.</p>

<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50147-w">Another of the new studies</a> shows us that boulders on all asteroids space missions have visited so far (Itokawa, Ryugu and Bennu) were likely shaped the same way. But this excess of larger boulders on the Didymos system could be a unique feature of binaries.</p>

<figure class="align-center zoomable"><a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"><img alt="" sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=392&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=392&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=392&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=493&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=493&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/609848/original/file-20240729-21-wu5ham.png?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=493&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" /></a>

<figcaption><span class="caption">The locations of 15 suspected boulder tracks on the surface of Didymos.</span> <span class="attribution"><span class="source">Bigot, Lombardo et al., (2024)/Image taken by DRACO/DART (NASA)</span></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Lastly, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50145-y">another paper shows</a> this type of asteroid appears to be more susceptible to cracking. This happens due to the heating–cooling cycles between day and night: like a freeze–thaw cycle but without the water.</p>

<p>This means if something (such as a spacecraft) were to impact it, there would be much more debris thrown up into space. It would even increase the amount of “shove” it could have. But there is a good chance that what lies underneath is much stronger than what we're seeing on the surface.</p>

<p>This is where the European Space Agency's <a href="https://www.esa.int/Space_Safety/Hera">Hera mission</a> will step in. It will not only be able to provide higher-resolution images of the DART impact sites, but will also be able to probe the asteroids' interiors using low-frequency radar.</p>

<p>The DART mission not only tested our ability to protect ourselves from future asteroid impacts, but also enlightened us on the formation and evolution of rubble pile and binary asteroids near Earth.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/235684/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/eleanor-k-sansom-1067191">Eleanor K. Sansom</a>, Research Associate, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/curtin-university-873">Curtin University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> </span>Eleanor K. Sansom receives funding from the International Centre for Radio Astronomy Research and is supported by the Australian Research Council)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/nasa-smacked-a-spacecraft-into-an-asteroid-and-learned-details-about-its-12-million-year-history-235684">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v0s313k_artist-impression-of-esas-hera-mission-to-didymos-dimorpho_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Artist impression of ESA's Hera mission to Didymos and Dimorphos. ESA/Science Office.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-3rd-stage-of-non-strategic-nuclear-exercises-6233484]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Begins 3rd Stage Of Non-Strategic Nuclear Exercises]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-3rd-stage-of-non-strategic-nuclear-exercises-6233484]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 20:54:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The third stage of Russia's non-strategic nuclear exercises has begun, which focuses on the preparation of units for the combat use of non-strategic nuclear weapons, the Russian Ministry of Defense said on Wednesday on its Telegram channel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The third stage of Russia's non-strategic nuclear exercises has begun, which focuses on the preparation of units for the combat use of non-strategic nuclear weapons, the Russian Ministry of Defense said on Wednesday on its Telegram channel.</p>

<p>It said that the exercises involve the central and southern military districts as well as the Aerospace Forces, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"As part of this stage, personnel from the missile formations of the central and southern military districts will work on training and combat tasks, including receiving special training munitions for the Iskander-M operational-tactical missile systems, equipping missile carriers, and covertly moving to designated positional areas to prepare for electronic launches," said the ministry.</p>

<p>It added that personnel from the aviation units of the Aerospace Forces involved in the exercise would practice equipping aviation strike assets with special warheads and flying to designated patrol areas.</p>

<p>Earlier, as part of the first and second stages of the exercise of non-strategic nuclear forces, issues of preparing units of the southern and Leningrad military districts, units of the Aerospace Forces and the navy for the combat use of non-strategic nuclear weapons were worked out.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-09/90j02klo_russia-army_625x300_23_September_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As part of 3rd stage, army will work on training and combat tasks: Russian Ministry (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-kremlin-critic-vladimir-kara-murzas-location-unknown-says-lawyer-6233302]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jailed Kremlin Critic Vladimir Kara-Murza's Location "Unknown," Says Lawyer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jailed-kremlin-critic-vladimir-kara-murzas-location-unknown-says-lawyer-6233302]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 20:29:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lawyers representing jailed Kremlin critic Vladimir Kara-Murza said Wednesday that they did not know the dissident's exact location after twice being denied access to the facility where he was supposed to be held.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Lawyers representing jailed Kremlin critic Vladimir Kara-Murza said Wednesday that they did not know the dissident's exact location after twice being denied access to the facility where he was supposed to be held.</p>

<p>Rumours are swirling of an upcoming prisoner swap involving Russia and Western countries as numerous high-profile prisoners, including foreigners, have gone missing from Russian prisons where they are serving long terms, in recent days.</p>

<p>"Today a lawyer for Vladimir Kara-Murza for a second day running was not allowed to visit him in a prison hospital. The exact location of the political prisoner is unknown," his lawyer Vadim Prokhorov wrote on Facebook.</p>

<p>Kara-Murza, a 42-year-old joint Russian and British citizen, is serving a 25-year sentence in Siberia for treason and other charges.</p>

<p>He suffers from a nerve disease and was moved to a prison hospital earlier this month for medical checks.</p>

<p>The dissident is being represented by a local lawyer in the Siberian city of Omsk, where he has been imprisoned.</p>

<p>On Tuesday and Wednesday, the lawyer was told he could not visit his client because he was having a medical examination, Prokhorov said.</p>

<p>Such a refusal of access is a "gross violation", Prokhorov said.</p>

<p>Kara-Murza is due to have a public court hearing Thursday in Omsk over a legal appeal. His defence team are demanding he be allowed to participate via video link.</p>

<p>"Court staff and the administration of the prison hospital have already expressed doubts that tomorrow there will be stable video link with Vladimir Kara-Murza," Prokhorov wrote.</p>

<p>"But at the same time, so far they deny that he has been moved from the hospital," Prokhorov wrote.</p>

<p>AFP contacted the Federal Prison Service, who said they could not provide information on a prisoner without an official request to the penal colony.</p>

<p>At least seven Russian political prisoners have been moved from their penal colonies or jails in recent days, according to lawyers and families.</p>

<p>A lawyer for jailed former US marine Paul Whelan, charged with espionage, was also unsure of his location on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Moscow and Washington have both confirmed there are ongoing negotiations over a swap involving US reporter Evan Gershkovich, sentenced to 16 years for espionage earlier this month in a fast-track trial slammed as a "sham" by the White House.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7d2u3s28_jail-generic_625x300_10_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kara-Murz is serving a 25-year sentence in Siberia for treason and other charges. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/slovakias-bratislava-airport-evacuated-after-bomb-threat-report-6232362]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Slovakia's Bratislava Airport Evacuated After Bomb Threat: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/slovakias-bratislava-airport-evacuated-after-bomb-threat-report-6232362]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 18:23:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Slovakia's Bratislava Airport was being evacuated due to a bomb alert, local police said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Slovakia's Bratislava Airport was being evacuated due to a bomb alert, local police said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Based on an anonymous announcement regarding the placement of an explosive device on the premises of M.R. Stefanik Airport in Bratislava, the police are currently taking the necessary steps, including evacuating people," the police said in a Facebook post, the News Agency of the Slovak Republic reported.</p>

<p>Arrivals at the airport have not been suspended, but passengers on such flights have to remain on the planes and wait for further instructions, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>"A pyrotechnic inspection is being carried out at the site," it added.</p>

<p>The airport said on its website that the airport building has been evacuated since 8:40 a.m. local time, and departures are not being carried out "until further instructions from the police."</p>

<p>Bratislava Airport, or M.R. Stefanik Airport in Bratislava, is the biggest international airport of the Slovak Republic. It is located 9 km from the city centre and handled over 1.8 million passengers last year, according to the airport website.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/4oqnp1cg_airport-generic_625x300_16_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["A pyrotechnic inspection is being carried out at the site", according to reports. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/polio-detected-in-gaza-says-who-chief-calling-for-preventative-measures-6232283]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Polio Detected In Gaza, Says WHO Chief Calling For Preventative Measures]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/polio-detected-in-gaza-says-who-chief-calling-for-preventative-measures-6232283]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 31 Jul 2024 18:13:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The head of the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Wednesday that polio had been detected in Gaza and warned that children in the war-ravaged enclave would soon be infected by the disease if preventative measures were not quickly taken.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The head of the World Health Organization (WHO) said on Wednesday that polio had been detected in Gaza and warned that children in the war-ravaged enclave would soon be infected by the disease if preventative measures were not quickly taken.</p>

<p>A day after the WHO said there were "very likely" polio cases among Gaza's population, Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus took to social media platform X to flag concern about the human cost of the conflict between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>"The detection of polio in Gaza is another reminder of the dire conditions the population is facing," Tedros wrote on X. "The persistence of the conflict hampers efforts to identify and respond to preventable threats such as polio."</p>

<p>Tedros linked his post to an article he had written in French newspaper Le Monde, published late on Tuesday, in which he said poliovirus has been detected in sewage samples in Gaza.</p>

<p>In the article, the WHO chief wrote that although no cases of polio had yet been recorded, "unless immediate action is taken, it is only a matter of time before the disease reaches the thousands of unprotected children" there.</p>

<p>Poliomyelitis, which is spread mainly through the faecal-oral route, is a highly infectious virus that can invade the nervous system and cause paralysis and death in young children.</p>

<p>Polio cases have declined by 99% worldwide since 1988 thanks to mass vaccination campaigns and efforts to eradicate it.</p>

<p>The WHO is sending more than a million polio vaccines to Gaza to be administered in the coming weeks to prevent children from becoming infected with the disease, Tedros said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/4odvh4lg_gaza-children_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Polio cases have declined by 99% worldwide since 1988 thanks to mass vaccination campaigns. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>