<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:37:25 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-what-are-countries-doing-to-rescue-nationals-out-of-lebanon-amid-conflict-6699382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Are Countries Doing To Rescue Nationals Out Of Lebanon Amid Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-what-are-countries-doing-to-rescue-nationals-out-of-lebanon-amid-conflict-6699382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:40:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Western nations are ramping up contingency plans to evacuate citizens from Lebanon after a sharp escalation in the conflict between Israel and the Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah, coupled with Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Western nations are ramping up contingency plans to evacuate citizens from Lebanon after a sharp escalation in the conflict between Israel and the Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah, coupled with Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday.</p>

<p>No country has launched a large-scale military evacuation yet, though some are chartering aircraft as Beirut airport stays open. Plans to evacuate to Cyprus by sea will enable the movement of larger groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here are details on contingency planning:</p>

<h3><strong>AUSTRALIA</strong></h3>

<p>Its contingency plans could include evacuation by sea, though authorities have urged an estimated 15,000 citizens in Lebanon to leave while Beirut airport remains open.</p>

<h3><strong>BELGIUM</strong></h3>

<p>Belgium's foreign ministry has advised citizens to leave as soon as possible, the Belga news agency said.</p>

<h3><strong>CANADA</strong></h3>

<p>News reports from Canada suggest it will cooperate with Australia in evacuating nationals by sea. The plan involves contracting a commercial vessel to ferry out 1,000 people a day, the Toronto Star newspaper said.</p>

<h3><strong>CYPRUS</strong></h3>

<p>The European Union member state closest to the Middle East is a likely hub for evacuations, having processed about 60,000 people fleeing the Hezbollah-Israel war in 2006. Neighbouring Turkey has offered facilities as well.</p>

<p>Cyprus has asked Greece to provide an aircraft that could be used to evacuate its nationals who wish to leave. There are an estimated 1,500 Cypriots in Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>FRANCE</strong></h3>

<p>France has not issued an evacuation order, despite having had plans for several months. Present contingency plans centre on Cyprus and Beirut airport, while it is also discussing evacuations via Turkey. France has a warship in the region, while a French helicopter carrier will arrive in the eastern Mediterranean in the coming days and take up position in case a decision is taken to evacuate foreign nationals from Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>GERMANY</strong></h3>

<p>Germany has evacuated non-essential staff, families of embassy workers and German nationals who are medically vulnerable from Lebanon and will support others trying to leave, the foreign and defence ministries said in a joint statement on Monday.</p>

<h3><strong>GREECE</strong></h3>

<p>The Greek foreign ministry has urged its citizens to leave Lebanon and avoid any travel there, with a frigate on standby in case assistance is needed.</p>

<h3><strong>ITALY</strong></h3>

<p>Italy has cut diplomatic staff and beefed up security personnel at its Beirut embassy. Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani has repeatedly urged nationals to leave the country and sought assurances from Israel over the safety of Italian peacekeepers in the area.</p>

<h3><strong>THE NETHERLANDS</strong></h3>

<p>The Netherlands will repatriate its citizens from Lebanon, Dutch news agency ANP said on Tuesday.</p>

<h3><strong>POLAND</strong></h3>

<p>Poland will limit staff numbers at its Beirut embassy, a foreign ministry spokesperson said on Tuesday, adding that Warsaw would organise transport for citizens wanting to leave Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>PORTUGAL</strong></h3>

<p>Prime Minister Luis Montenegro has advised against travel to Lebanon, which assisted in the evacuation of a small number of Portuguese citizens living there.</p>

<h3><strong>TURKEY</strong></h3>

<p>Turkey is ready for a possible evacuation of Turks from Lebanon via air and sea and is working with about 20 countries to ready its ports and airports for a possible evacuation of foreign nationals via Turkey. About 14,000 Turkish citizens were registered at the consulate in Lebanon, but the number was not definitive.</p>

<h3><strong>UNITED KINGDOM</strong></h3>

<p>Britain has urged nationals to leave immediately. It has moved about 700 troops to Cyprus, bolstering its military assets, including two Royal Navy ships. It also has two military bases on the island. Britain has chartered a flight to help meet any additional demand from Britons wishing to leave on Wednesday and will fly them directly back to London.</p>

<h3><strong>UNITED STATES</strong></h3>

<p>The United States has ordered dozens of troops deployed to Cyprus to help prepare for scenarios such as an evacuation of Americans from Lebanon. It is working with airlines to add flights out of Lebanon, with more seats for Americans, the State Department said on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8t455i7_beirut-airport-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-tim-walz-vice-presidential-debate-us-elections-2024-fact-checking-who-said-what-in-the-vance-walz-veep-debate-ahead-of-us-polls-6699277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Checking Who Said What In The Vance-Walz Veep Debate Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-tim-walz-vice-presidential-debate-us-elections-2024-fact-checking-who-said-what-in-the-vance-walz-veep-debate-ahead-of-us-polls-6699277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:28:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Tim Walz and Republican JD Vance faced off in New York City on Tuesday night for their one and only vice-presidential debate, hosted by CBS News.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Tim Walz and Republican JD Vance faced off in New York City on Tuesday night for their one and only vice-presidential debate, hosted by CBS News.</p>

<p>Reuters examined 12 statements made by the two running mates.</p>

<p>While Reuters monitored the entire debate, this fact check did not examine every statement. It focuses on topics and narratives that are part of broader public discourse and can be assessed with credible evidence.</p>

<h3><strong>STATEMENTS BY WALZ</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Walz said that the US is producing more natural gas and more oil than ever before. (Timestamp 9:15 p.m. ET)</p>

<h4><strong>&nbsp;WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is mostly true. In March 2024, the government Energy Information Administration said in a release that the US had produced "more crude oil than any nation at any time" for a sixth straight year. The report added that it is unlikely the record for 2023 will be broken by another country in the "near term," as none have a production capacity of 13.0 million barrels per day. The US averaged 12.9 million barrels per day that year.</p>

<p>Monthly production of dry natural gas in the US reached a record high in December 2023, having steadily increased through most of the past decade. However, production is forecast to decline in 2024, which would mark the first time output declined since 2020.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>"Donald Trump hasn't paid any federal tax in 10 of the last 15 years, and the last year as president." (9:35 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>This is mostly true based on the information available. In 2020, the New York Times reported, based on an analysis of tax return data from 2017, that Trump had paid no income taxes in 10 of the previous 15 years. This was "largely because he reported losing much more money than he made," the Times said. Trump did pay $750 the year he won the 2020 election, the paper added, as well as in his first year in the White House. Trump had dismissed the report as "fake news."</p>

<p>In 2022, the US House Ways and Means Committee released Trump's tax returns for 2015 through 2020, which showed that Trump paid no income tax during the final full year of his presidency. "Trump and his wife, Melania, paid some form of tax during all four years, the documents showed, but were able to minimize their income taxes in several years as income from Trump's businesses was more than offset by deductions and losses," Reuters reported.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Minnesota's child tax credit "reduces childhood poverty by a third." (9:30 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is unknown. The 2023 child tax credit program for low- and middle-income families was projected to cut child poverty in Minnesota by one-third based on an analysis by Columbia University's Center on Poverty &amp; Social Policy. &nbsp;</p>

<p>No report examining whether the child tax credit program did result in a one-third reduction in child poverty in the state has been published.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An August 2024 press release by the governor noted figures from the state's Department of Revenue that said the program "put over $545 million into the budgets of more than 215,000 Minnesota families" between 2023 and 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Minnesota is ranked first in healthcare (9:46 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This depends on who you ask. It is true based on data published in July 2024 by the financial information site WalletHub, which Walz has previously cited as governor of Minnesota.</p>

<p>The site ranked Minnesota as the state with the best healthcare system that provides low healthcare costs, a high number of convenient care clinics per capita, a high-quality public hospital system and low emergency room wait times.</p>

<p>Minnesota also topped the chart in a Forbes analysis, but other rankings with different methodologies rate the states differently.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<h4>"Minneapolis is the one city where we've seen the lowest inflation rates," the Minnesota governor said. (10:07 p.m.)</h4>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW </strong>&nbsp;</h4>

<p>This is mostly true during certain periods in the past 1.5 years. Data from the US Bureau of Labor Statistics on the 12-month percentage change in the Consumer Price Index, which measures inflation across metropolitan areas, found that the Minneapolis-Saint Paul area recorded the lowest inflation rate in the country in May and July 2023, and again in March 2024.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Walz said Trump created the largest trade deficit in American history with China. (9:34 p.m. ET)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is true. The US trade deficit in goods with China reached a record high during Trump's second year in the White House. The trade gap rose by 11.6% to $419.2 billion in 2018, from the previous record of $375.5 billion in 2017, a Commerce Department report showed in 2019. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2018 under Trump, the US imposed tariffs on $250 billion worth of goods imported from China, with Beijing then retaliating with duties on $110 billion worth of American products, including soybeans and other commodities.</p>

<h3><strong>STATEMENTS BY VANCE</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said Iran "received over $100 billion in unfrozen assets thanks to the Kamala Harris administration." (Timestamp 9:06 p.m.)&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is mixed. In August 2023, US President Joe Biden approved a prisoner swap deal between the US and Iran that involved the unfreezing of $6 billion in Iranian funds that were frozen in South Korea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the Iranian-backed Palestinian group Hamas attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, the U.S. said five days later that Iran would not gain access to the funds, parked in a Qatari bank, anytime soon and that Washington retained the right to freeze the funds.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, Biden had previously sought to revive a 2015 nuclear deal with Iran, which had been abandoned by Donald Trump. The talks stalled in September 2022.</p>

<p>In 2015, US officials said that the deal would give Iran access to $100 billion in frozen assets if implemented. Former Israeli Prime Minister Yair Lapid said in 2022 that the deal would give Tehran $100 billion a year to destabilize the Middle East, but did not provide details for the calculation.&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>"When was the last time that an American president did not have a major conflict break out? The only answer is during the four years Donald Trump was president," Vance said. (9:10 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This needs more context. Trump joins other presidents such as Barack Obama, Bill Clinton, Ronald Reagan, Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford, Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy and Dwight D. Eisenhower in not officially bringing the US into a new war since 1945.</p>

<p>Trump's presidency, however, involved military hostilities and the risk of new wars. Trump ordered in 2020 a drone strike that killed Iranian General Qassem Soleimani, and launched in 2017 an attack on a Syrian army base, a move that marked an escalation of the US military's role in Syria.</p>

<p>The former president also said in 2017 during a speech to the United Nations General Assembly that he would "totally destroy" North Korea.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said the US is "the cleanest economy in the entire world." (9:12 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>This is false. According to the EU's Emissions Database for Global Atmospheric Research 2024 report, the US was second only to China as the highest emitter of greenhouse gas emissions globally last year.</p>

<p>The US accounted for 11.25% of global greenhouse gas emissions, while China represented 30.1%.</p>

<p>Per capita, greenhouse gas emissions in 2023 for the US stood at 17.61 tons of CO2 equivalent, higher than China's 11.11, the UK's 5.55, and Mexico's 5.15, but lower than Canada's 19.39 and Russia's 18.66.</p>

<p>In a 2024 World Economic Forum report on the Global Average Energy Transition Index, a measure of performance and readiness for clean energy transition, the US ranked 19th. Sweden tops the list, followed by Denmark, Finland, Switzerland and France.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to this year's Environmental Performance Index - a project by Yale and Columbia universities that evaluates countries based on indicators like climate change mitigation, air pollution, deforestation and biodiversity protection - the rankings put Estonia in pole position, followed by Luxembourg, and Germany. The US ranks 34th.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>When discussing ways to address carbon emissions, Vance said Kamala Harris' policies have led to "more energy production in China, more manufacturing overseas" (9:13 pm)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>Vance could be referring to the 2022 Inflation Reduction Act that provides incentives to boost domestic energy production and manufacturing investment, including support for clean energy jobs and the sale of new and used electric vehicles.</p>

<p>The impact of the IRA on the US manufacturing sector is still too early to tell, but some research has found it has benefited domestic clean energy manufacturing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The IRA provides billions of dollars in tax credits to help consumers buy EVs and firms to produce renewable energy as part of the Biden administration's plan to decarbonize the U.S. power sector. China, which dominates the global battery supply chain, is among the four countries excluded from the subsidy available to firms looking to invest in the US EV supply chain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China has since requested the World Trade Organization set up a panel to help settle the dispute over what it describes as "discriminatory subsidies."</p>

<p>Another area of the global supply chain that China dominates is solar panel production. Some Chinese-backed companies with factories in the US are claiming those subsidies for clean energy manufacturing under the IRA, and a bipartisan group of US lawmakers introduced a bill in July that would block them from claiming subsidies for their American factories. &nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM &nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said Donald Trump's economic policies delivered the highest take-home pay in a generation. (9:33 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is true. US median household income reached a record high of $68,703 during the Trump administration in 2019, a 6.8% increase from 2018 - the highest the country had seen since the U.S. Census Bureau started tracking the data in 1967.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The White House Council of Economic Advisers at the time said an increase in the number of workers in the country drove the income increase. "There were 2.2 million more people working at some point in 2019 compared with 2018, and 1.2 million more people working full-time year-round," the council added. &nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>"The gross majority, close to 90% in some of the statistics I've seen, of the gun violence in this country is committed with illegally obtained firearms." (10:00 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is misleading. Most public mass shootings - a shooting that kills four or more people - between 1966 and 2019 were carried out by legally obtained handguns, according to research funded by the National Institute of Justice.</p>

<p>The data showed "77% of those who engaged in mass shootings purchased at least some of their guns legally," an article on the 2021 study said, while 13% of the mass shootings involved illegally purchased firearms.</p>

<p>The report also noted that over 80% of individuals involved in K-12 school shootings had stolen guns from family members.</p>

<p>Between 2017 and 2021, over 1.4 million crime guns were traced to a known purchaser with a Federal Firearms License, of which 99% were acquired from a dealer, pawnbroker or manufacturer, according to a 2023 report (page 7) by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</p>

<p>These crime guns, however, "may change hands a number of times after that first retail sale, and some of those transactions may be a theft or violate one or more regulations on firearm commerce," the report adds.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9b77t7e8_walz-vance-debate-reuters-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance faced off Tim Walz in their first Vice Presidential debate almost a month before US Elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-missile-attack-iron-dome-video-israel-shoots-down-irans-onslaught-but-some-missiles-sneak-past-6699211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Shows Iran Launching Hundreds Of Ballistic Missiles At Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-missile-attack-iron-dome-video-israel-shoots-down-irans-onslaught-but-some-missiles-sneak-past-6699211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:18:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran launched a large-scale missile offensive against Israel - its second in the past seven months - Tuesday, targeting military bases in a strike dubbed 'Operation True Promise II'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/iran" target="_blank">Iran</a> launched a large-scale missile offensive against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/israel" target="_blank">Israel</a> - its second in the past seven months - Tuesday, targeting military bases in a strike dubbed '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Operation True Promise II</a>'. Iran's Revolutionary Guards said the attack - which sharply escalates military tension in West Asia - was in response to the killing last week of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>A chilling video shared on X by Iranian news outlet Press TV shows multiple rockets being fired and arcing into the night sky, filling it with a deafening roar. As the video plays out, and pans to show more of the sky, more and more burning orange spots appear on the horizon.</p>

<p>The final 25 seconds of the clip show dozens of what look like burning balls dropping over an urban centre; many of them explode mid-air, having been successfully intercepted.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Op. True Promise II: Iran launches hundreds of missiles at Zionist entity, 90% hit targets<br />
<br />
Follow Press TV on Telegram: <a href="https://t.co/B3zXG73Jym">https://t.co/B3zXG73Jym</a> <a href="https://t.co/IxJfhOOZyE">pic.twitter.com/IxJfhOOZyE</a></p>
— Press TV ? (@PressTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/PressTV/status/1841351956738011398?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Several, though, seem to break through and hit the ground.</p>

<p>Another video shared online shows a massive crater near the Mossad HQ in Tel Aviv. The video was geolocated by American news outlet CNN to establish it was shot from a high-rise apartment building in Herzliya, less than 3 km from the Mossad headquarters.</p>

<p>The barrage of 180+ projectiles included, for the first time, the Fattah hypersonic missiles. The missiles' flight path meant it streaked over Jordan too, prompting Amman to announce a suspension of air traffic.</p>

<p>However, Israel's formidable multi-layered aerial defence system, at the core of which is the Iron Dome, was in action to intercept the missiles.</p>

<p><strong>VIDEO |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israels-air-defence-system-in-action-to-intercept-iranian-missiles-6695307" target="_blank">Israel's Air Defence System In Action To Intercept Iranian Missiles</a></p>

<p>As with the April attack, Iran and Israel have squabbled over the strike rate of these missiles, with Tehran claiming a 90 per cent success rate but Tel Aviv insisting most were tracked and destroyed by the Iron Dome and Arrow systems.</p>

<p>No injuries were reported in Israel, but one man was killed in occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>The April strike was retaliation for what Iran said was an Israeli air strike on its consulate in Syria's Damascus, in which seven Guards officers, including two commanders, were killed.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Inside 'True Promise II': What Changed In Iran's Latest Israel Attack</a></p>

<p>Then, for 'Operation True Promise I', Tehran fired nearly 200 ballistic missiles and older models of explosive drones, a staggering 99 per cent of which, Tel Aviv claimed, had been intercepted.</p>

<p>Ballistic missiles are an important part of Tehran's arsenal; Iran says these are a key deterrent and retaliatory force against the United States, Israel and other potential regional targets. According to the United States, Iran has the most numbers of such weapons in the region.</p>

<p>Iran is also believed to have cruise missiles like the Kh-55, an air-launched nuclear-capable weapon with a range up to 3,000 km, and the advanced anti-ship missile the Khalid Farzh, which has a smaller range - around 300 km. Both, however, can carry a 1,000-kg warhead.</p>

<p>Early this morning Iran said its attack had been completed and no further military action is expected, barring further provocation. Israel and the US, however, have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-it-has-finished-attack-on-israel-amid-fears-of-spreading-conflict-in-middle-east-6696722" target="_blank">Iran Says Attack On Israel Over Amid Fears Of Spreading Conflict</a></p>

<p>The US said it would work with Israel to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-lebanon-hezbollah-after-irans-missile-attack-on-israel-us-severe-consequences-warning-6696958#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">make sure Iran faced "severe consequences"</a>. Israel, meanwhile, has again bombed Lebanon, targeting Beirut's southern suburbs - a Hezbollah stronghold.</p>

<p>Guy Nir, spokesperson for the Israeli embassy in India, told NDTV Tehran would get an appropriate response. "If he (Iran leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them. Israel's response is going to be strategic and pin-pointed... not a full-scale war."</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6581g6mo_iran-missile-attack-on-israel-video-press-tv_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/escalating-tensions-in-west-asia-india-calls-for-restraint-by-all-sides-6699055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Escalating Tensions In West Asia: India Calls For Restraint By All Sides]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/escalating-tensions-in-west-asia-india-calls-for-restraint-by-all-sides-6699055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:51:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In its first reaction to fresh escalation of tensions in West Asia, India on Wednesday called for restraint by all sides and said the conflict must not take a wider regional dimension.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In its first reaction to fresh escalation of tensions in West Asia, India on Wednesday called for restraint by all sides and said the conflict must not take a wider regional dimension.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India's comments came a day after Iran fired around 200 missiles into Israel in response to Israel's killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and other commanders of the militant outfit.</p>

<p>New Delhi said it is deeply concerned over the escalating security situation in West Asia and called for addressing all issues through "dialogue and diplomacy".</p>

<p>"We are deeply concerned at the escalation of the security situation in West Asia and reiterate our call for restraint by all concerned and protection of civilians," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said.</p>

<p>"It is important that the conflict doesn't take a wider regional dimension and we urge that all issues be addressed through dialogue and diplomacy," it said in a statement.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/12pq7qro_israel-iran-war_625x300_14_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's comments came a day after Iran fired around 200 missiles into Israel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Did Netanyahu Run Into A Bunker During Iran's Missile Attack?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:21:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following Iran's massive rocket attack on Israel Tuesday night, video clips circulating on social media showed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu allegedly running for cover inside a bunker.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Iran's massive rocket attack on Israel Tuesday night, video clips circulating on social media showed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu allegedly running for cover inside a bunker. As Iran's missiles, some of which were hypersonic, entered Israeli airspace, sirens were sounded across the country, prompting thousands to seek safety.</p>

<p>Pro-Iranian social media handles shared a video clip that allegedly showed Benjamin Netanyahu running across the hallways of an alleged bunker. "Moments in which the Prime Minister of Israel, Benjamin Netanyahu, flees to a bunker in the face of the Iranian response," claimed one post.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Someone please give Benjamin Netanyahu a place to hide. The poor guy is not even running away. After all, he saved his life by hiding in a bunker. He ran away and hid, leaving his countrymen to fend for themselves," claimed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-iraq-the-year-is-1980-and-iran-has-a-new-best-friend-in-middle-east-its-israel-6697695#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">When Israel And Iran Joined Hands To Fight A Common Enemy</a></p>

<p>However, the purported video is at least three years old, a fact corroborated by posts on Facebook that shared the same video in 2021. The original video allegedly shows Benjamin Netanyahu rushing through the corridors of the Knesset, the Israeli parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Original video:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="476" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fm.magadli%2Fvideos%2F3099680666968955%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=267&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="267"></iframe></p>

<p><strong>Screengrab of 2021 post:</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fvqh2oq8_netanyahu-viral-post-_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Netanyahu termed Iran's missile attack "a big mistake" and vowed to make Tehran "pay for it".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Iran made a big mistake tonight and will pay for it," he said. "Whoever attacks us, we attack them."</p>

<p>The missile salvo is the second direct attack by Iran on Israel this year, following a similar offensive in April, which was quickly subdued by Israeli and allied defences. Tuesday's strikes, according to Iranian officials, were in retaliation for the recent killing of senior Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Israeli military operations.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel</a></p>

<p>Guy Nir, spokesperson of the Israeli embassy in India, speaking exclusively to NDTV, said an appropriate response will be given to Tehran. "If he (Ayatollah Ali Khamenei) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them (Iran)," Mr Nir told NDTV. "Israel's response is going to be something strategic and pin-pointed, and not a full-scale war. I don't think any side wants that."</p>

<p>Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) claimed that 90 per cent of its missiles successfully hit their targets, despite Israel's advanced defence systems.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j3i153uo_netanyahu-viral-post-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu termed Iran's missile attack "a big mistake" and vowed to make Tehran "pay for it".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-people-to-sue-us-rapper-sean-diddy-combs-in-sex-assault-case-6698693]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 100 People To Sue US Rapper Sean 'Diddy' Combs In Sex Assault Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-people-to-sue-us-rapper-sean-diddy-combs-in-sex-assault-case-6698693]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:59:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 100 people, including dozens of children, who say they were victims of rape, sexual assault and sexual exploitation at the hands of Sean "Diddy" Combs are to sue the US rap star, a lawyer said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 100 people, including dozens of children, who say they were victims of rape, sexual assault and sexual exploitation at the hands of Sean "Diddy" Combs are to sue the US rap star, a lawyer said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The latest legal action will heap further pressure on a man who once bestrode American pop culture, but who has long been dogged by accusations of violent abuse of women, and who is now sitting in jail on criminal charges.</p>

<p>"The biggest secret in the entertainment industry, that really wasn't a secret at all, has finally been revealed to the world," Texas-based attorney Tony Buzbee said as he announced plans by 120 people, including 25 minors, to take civil action.</p>

<p>"The wall of silence has now been broken, and victims are coming forward."</p>

<p>Combs was indicted last month on three criminal counts that allege he sexually abused women and coerced them into drug-fueled sex parties using threats and violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Allegations have been building against the Grammy Award-winner since last year, when singer Cassie, whose real name is Casandra Ventura, alleged Combs subjected her to more than a decade of coercion by physical force and drugs as well as a 2018 rape.</p>

<p>A spate of similarly lurid lawsuits since have painted a picture of Combs as a violent man who used his celebrity status to prey on women.</p>

<p>Combs has pleaded not guilty to the criminal charges. He has been jailed awaiting trial.</p>

<h3><strong>Pattern of abuse&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>At a press conference in Houston, Buzbee said more than 3,000 people had come forward with allegations against Combs, and he appealed for anyone else who might have been a victim to come forward.</p>

<p>He said much of the abuse Combs and members of his entourage are alleged to have carried out followed a pattern.</p>

<p>"I would say 90 per cent of the cases, these individuals were drugged," he told reporters.</p>

<p>"One individual who was 22 years old at the time she was assaulted, said that... when you were handed a drink -- and now we know that the drink is laced with something -- if you refused to drink it, you were kicked out of the party."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Buzbee described instances of repeated rape of teenagers, allegedly carried out by Combs and his associates.</p>

<p>He said alleged abuse of minors often took place in the context of a promise of fame and fortune in the music industry.</p>

<h3><strong>Fears of retribution&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>One boy, who was just nine years old at the time, was taken to New York to audition for Combs' label Bad Boy Records.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This individual was sexually abused, allegedly by Sean Combs and several other people at the studio, in the promise to both his parents and to himself of getting a record deal," Buzbee said.</p>

<p>"Another incident, an individual, 15 years old at the time, flown to New York City to attend a party, was drugged and then taken into a private room, allegedly in the presence of Mr Combs, where this female individual, a minor, was raped, and then other individuals took turns raping her."</p>

<p>Buzbee praised the courage of those who had come forward despite fears of retribution or backlash from their own communities.</p>

<p>"I expect that through this process, many powerful people, many dirty secrets will be revealed.</p>

<p>"We know what we are potentially up against, and as is always the case in situations like this, when a celebrity is involved, people can be downright mean and nasty."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/amruf0fg_sean-diddy-combs_625x300_17_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sean "Diddy" Combs has pleaded not guilty to the criminal charges. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-how-successful-were-missile-attacks-what-iran-and-israel-said-6698674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Successful Were Missile Attacks? What Iran And Israel Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-how-successful-were-missile-attacks-what-iran-and-israel-said-6698674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:53:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran launched a wave of missiles into Israel last evening to avenge the killing of top Hezbollah and Hamas leaders as the war in Middle East threatens to snowball into a larger regional conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran launched a wave of missiles into Israel last evening to avenge the killing of top Hezbollah and Hamas leaders as the war in Middle East threatens to snowball into a larger regional conflict. Israelis scrambled for bomb shelters as sirens sounded across the nation and orange streaks lit up the night sky, showed visuals. Israel said they had intercepted most of the missiles and vowed to make Iran "pay" for the attack. Amid claims and counterclaims by Iran and Israel, it is hard to figure out how successful Tuesday's attacks were and whether Israel will launch an immediate retaliation.</p>

<p>Here's what Israel and Iran said about Tuesday's attacks:</p>

<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">There were reports yesterday of up to 400 missiles being fired at Israel from Iran. But Iran confirmed this morning it had fired 200 missiles while&nbsp;Israel gave a count of 180. Sirens were sounded across the country and&nbsp;most of the missiles were intercepted by Israeli air defences or allied air forces before they reached their territory.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">State media footage showed Iranian missiles being launched at Israel. The missiles targeted "three military bases" around Tel Aviv and other bases, The Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) said, adding that 90% of those "hit their targets". Israel denied this claim and said only 20 missiles landed while the rest were intercepted.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran has claimed to have hit the headquarters of Mossad, Israel's premier intelligence agency. Israel, however, has denied it and said some missiles landed on an empty ground. A video showing a massive crater near the Mossad headquarters has emerged on the social media - probably due to a missile strike.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran said yesterday they used hypersonic Fattah missiles to target military facilities in Israel, which were successful. This claim was opposed by Israel as they claimed to have intercepted most of the missiles. Israel said the attacks resulted in only two injuries.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran warned it would carry out "crushing attacks" against Israel if it retaliates to the Iranian missile attack. But Israel termed the missile attack as the "biggest mistake by Iran" and vowed retaliation at a time and place of its choosing. "This attack will have consequences. We have plans, and we will operate at the place and time we decide," said IDF spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/78bfinkg_iran-israel-missiles_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/avoid-non-essential-travel-indias-advisory-amid-iran-israel-conflict-6698662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Avoid Non-Essential Travel": India's Advisory Amid Iran-Israel Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/avoid-non-essential-travel-indias-advisory-amid-iran-israel-conflict-6698662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:51:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indians have been asked to avoid travelling to Iran after they launched a massive missile attack on Israel while those already present in the country have been asked to stay vigilant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indians have been asked to avoid travelling to Iran after they launched a massive missile attack on Israel. The government said Indian nationals who are already present in the country must stay vigilant and stay in touch with its embassy in Tehran.</p>

<p>The war situation in the Middle East saw a sharp escalation yesterday after a barrage of hypersonic missiles lit up the night sky above Israel - an offensive that Iran said was to avenge the recent killings of top Hamas and Hezbollah leaders.</p>

<p>The Indian government is closely monitoring the recent escalation in security situation in the region, the foreign ministry said in a statement shared online by spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Travel advisory for Indian nationals regarding Iran:<a href="https://t.co/FhUhy3fA5k">https://t.co/FhUhy3fA5k</a> <a href="https://t.co/tPFJXl6tQy">pic.twitter.com/tPFJXl6tQy</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1841372293064261752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Indian nationals are advised to avoid all non-essential travel to Iran. Those currently residing in Iran are requested to remain vigilant and stay in contact with the Indian Embassy in Tehran," the travel advisory read.</p>

<p>The Indian embassy in Tel Aviv had yesterday asked Indians in the country to excise caution, avoid unnecessary travel and stay close to the safety shelters.</p>

<p><strong>Read | </strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655">Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel</a></p>

<p>"The Embassy is closely monitoring the situation and remains in regular touch with the Israeli authorities to ensure the safety of all our nationals," the embassy said in its advisory.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday expressed concern at the possibility of the Middle East crisis growing into a larger regional conflict. "We are very much concerned at the possibility of a broadening of the conflict, not just what happened in Lebanon, but also, you know, I referred earlier to the Houthis and the Red Sea, and, you know, to some extent, everything that happens between Iran and Israel," he said.</p>

<p>Tuesday's attack marked a massive escalation in the Israel-Iran ties that had worsened after the October 7 Hamas attacks. Iran backs the Hamas and the Palestinian cause. Israel is also fighting the Iran-backed Hezbollah, which runs Lebanon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r95f3jc8_iran-missile-attack-afp-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:50:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) launched its second missile attack against Israel in less than six months, targeting military bases on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) launched its second missile attack against Israel in less than six months, targeting military bases on Tuesday. Dubbed Operation True Promise II, this attack differed from Iran's earlier strike in April, showcasing a higher degree of technological sophistication and strategic ambition.</p>

<p>Iran deployed hypersonic missiles for the first time in this operation, marking a technological advancement over the older drones and ballistic missiles used in April's Operation True Promise. The IRGC claimed that 90 per cent of its missiles successfully hit their targets, despite Israel's advanced defence systems.</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-iraq-the-year-is-1980-and-iran-has-a-new-best-friend-in-middle-east-its-israel-6697695">When Israel And Iran Joined Hands To Fight A Common Enemy</a></p>

<p>Unlike April's attack, which primarily targeted isolated military sites, this assault appeared to target more densely populated urban centres near Tel Aviv. Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian framed the missile strikes as a proportional response to Israeli "aggression," warning Israel not to provoke further escalation.</p>

<p><strong>Key Differences Between April And October Attacks:</strong></p>

<p>Iran used hypersonic missiles for the first time in Operation True Promise II, marking a shift from the older technology drones and ballistic missiles used in the April attack. This latest attack involved a broader array of advanced weaponry.</p>

<p><strong>Fact Check </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839">Did Benjamin Netanyahu Run Into A Bunker During Iran's Missile Attack</a></p>

<p>In April, Iran targeted military bases in remote areas, while this time, urban centres near Tel Aviv were in the crosshairs. Iran claimed a 90 per cent success rate in hitting its targets in this latest attack, despite Israel's sophisticated defence systems, compared to the high interception rate of missiles in April.</p>

<p>One Palestinian man died after being hit by debris from an Iranian missile in West Bank. Despite no casualties reported on Israel's side, the proximity of the attack to populated areas signals that Israel's next response may be far more comprehensive and severe.</p>

<p>With Israeli citizens under direct threat, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is expected to take a stronger stance than after the April attack, potentially heightening the conflict with Iran. Resistance groups across the Middle East praised Iran's operation, raising the potential for further involvement from Hezbollah, Hamas, and other allied factions in the region.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/48gmq8co_israel-bunker-reuters-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran used hypersonic missiles for the first time in Operation True Promise II.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-6698529]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Analysis: Yes, Calling Someone Mentally Disabled Causes Real Harm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-6698529]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a recent speech, Donald Trump used the language of intelligence, or intellectual impairment, as a weapon against Kamala Harris. And he used similar language about Vice presidential candidate Tim Walz in a TV appearance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">In <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/09/28/trump-harris-attacks-mentally-impaired-criticism/">a recent speech</a>, Donald Trump used the language of intelligence, or intellectual impairment, as a weapon against Kamala Harris. And he used <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/10/01/us/walz-vance-vp-debate/d5878199-2d8d-5282-9922-47316fd56f9f?smid=url-share">similar language about Vice presidential candidate Tim Walz</a> in a TV appearance.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>In a rally on Sept. 29, 2024, in Prairie du Chien, Wisconsin, <a href="https://www.wpr.org/news/trump-harris-mentally-disabled-wisconsin-speech-immigration">Trump told supporters</a> that “Joe Biden became mentally impaired. Kamala was born that way. She was born that way. And if you think about it, only a mentally disabled person could have allowed this to happen to our country.” He <a href="https://whyy.org/articles/donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-mentally-impaired-erie-pennsylvania-rally/">made similar comments</a> at a rally in Erie, Pennsylvania, over the same weekend.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.aapd.com/ableist-trump-comments-september-24/">Disability rights advocates</a> were quick to point out that Trump's language is what is called “ableist,” meaning that it assumes people with disabilities are somehow less valuable than those without.</p>

<p>In an attempt to fire back, “Saturday Night Live” Weekend Update host Colin Jost <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y2tOpMV6T0I">quipped </a>“I cannot</p>

<p>Special education classrooms are disproportionately filled with students of colour, <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED610548.pdf">most often diagnosed with behavioral disabilities</a>. These students often end up in the <a href="https://inclusivity.consulting/2017/12/08/school-prison-pipeline-intersection-race-disability/">school-to-prison pipeline</a>. These classrooms show how something as “simple” as an IQ test – something as innocuous as a label – can end up sentencing the country's children to lives of segregation and social oppression.</p>

<h3><strong>Not just Trump's words</strong></h3>

<p>Temperatures are running high during this presidential election. Yet Trump's words about Harris, while extraordinarily coarse and ugly for a presidential candidate, are often found among disparaging descriptions used by both sides. These phrases are part of a culture that uses measures of intelligence as a way to measure the worth of a human being.</p>

<p>Words are powerful: They can either, like the literature I teach, broaden perspectives of the world, or they can serve to reinforce limiting ideologies that perpetuate oppression.</p>

<p>Terms such as “low IQ,” “idiot” and “mentally impaired” have a traumatic history, one that many cognitively disabled, lower-class and minority people continue to live with today. I believe politicians and their constituents should understand the destructive history of these terms – and think twice before using words like these as an easy means to attack one another.<br />
<!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/kathleen-beres-rogers-1641673">Kathleen Béres Rogers</a>, Professor of English and Director, Program in Medical Humanities, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/college-of-charleston-734">College of Charleston</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-239659">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b64vd7go_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Disability rights advocates have said that Donald Trumps language against Kamala Harris is ableist.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/did-trump-lose-2020-election-his-veep-pick-jd-vance-refuses-to-say-6698437]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Did Trump Lose 2020 Election? His Veep Pick JD Vance Refuses To Say]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/did-trump-lose-2020-election-his-veep-pick-jd-vance-refuses-to-say-6698437]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:14:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance has refused to acknowledge that Donald Trump lost the 2020 elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican vice presidential candidate JD Vance has refused to acknowledge that Donald Trump lost the 2020 elections, as he evaded a direct reply on whether the former president would seek to challenge this year's election results even if these were certified in every state.</p>

<p>Senator Vance of Ohio came face to face with his Democratic rival Minnesota Governor Tim Walz on Tuesday in the only vice presidential debate of this election cycle.</p>

<p>The debate comes just over a month before the crucial US presidential elections when the country will choose between Democratic Presidential nominee Kamala Harris and Republican candidate Trump as the next leader.</p>

<p>In reference to the January 6, 2021 insurrection, Vance did not give a clear answer when asked if Trump would again challenge election results this year even if every governor certifies the results.</p>

<p>"Look, what President Trump has said is that there were problems in 2020, and my own belief is that we should fight about those issues, debate those issues peacefully in the public square. And that's all I've said, and that's all that Donald Trump has said," Vance said.</p>

<p>He added that Trump asked the protesters on January 6 to "protest peacefully", and the former president "left the White House" on January 20 when Joe Biden became president. "...now, of course, unfortunately, we have all of the negative policies that have come from the Harris-Biden administration," he said.</p>

<p>Trump has denied wrongdoing regarding the attack on the US Capitol in January 2021 in an attempt to overturn the 2020 election won by Biden, a Democrat. The Republican presidential candidate has repeatedly claimed that he won the 2020 elections.</p>

<p>During the debate, the Democratic vice presidential candidate Walz also questioned Vance about Trump losing the 2020 election, NBC News reported.</p>

<p>"Did he (Trump) lose the 2020 election?" Walz asked.</p>

<p>"Tim, I'm focused on the future," Vance was quoted as saying in the report.</p>

<p>Calling it a "non-answer", Walz said, "I'm pretty shocked by this. He lost the election. This is not a debate, it's not anything anywhere other than in Donald Trump's world." In the debate hosted by CBS News here, the two vice presidential candidates also sparred over issues ranging from immigration, gun policy, climate change, abortion and the economy.</p>

<p>Calling censorship a "threat" to democracy in the US, Vance alleged that Harris has engaged in it at an "industrial scale".</p>

<p>"She did it during Covid. She's done it over a number of other issues, and that, to me, is a much bigger threat to democracy than what Donald Trump said when he said the protesters should peacefully protest on January the sixth," he said.</p>

<p>On immigration, Walz referred to false claims by Vance about Haitian immigrants eating the pets of residents in Springfield, Ohio.</p>

<p>"There are consequences for this," Walz said. To this, Vance replied, "The people I care most about in Springfield are the American citizens." &nbsp;Vance added that because of an influx of migrants, "you've got schools that are overwhelmed, you've got hospitals that are overwhelmed, you've got housing that is totally unaffordable." On the issue of abortion, Walz was asked by the moderators to respond to an assertion from Trump that he supports abortion in the ninth month. "In Minnesota, what we did was restore Roe v. Wade," Walz said. "We made sure that we put women in charge of their health care." "The states will decide what's right for Texas might not be right for Washington. That's not how this works," Walz was quoted as saying by CNN.</p>

<p>"This is basic human rights. We have seen maternal mortality skyrocket in Texas (since its restrictions went into effect), outpacing many accounts in the world," he added.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Vance said Republicans need to "do so much better of a job at earning the American people's trust back on this issue, where they, frankly, just don't trust us."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/50sh69ag_tim-walz-jd-vance-veep-debate-us-afp-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the debate, Tim Walz questioned JD Vance about Donald Trump losing the 2020 elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-profile-all-about-the-republican-vice-presidential-candidate-6698381]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who is JD Vance, The Republican Vice-Presidential Pick?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-profile-all-about-the-republican-vice-presidential-candidate-6698381]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:03:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[JD Vance is a politician, an author and a Marine veteran who has been serving as junior senator from Ohio.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Senator JD Vance and Minnesota Governor Tim Walz are readying for the big electoral battle in the United States that will choose the next Vice President of the country. One of them will be part of the long list of political leaders who have been the integral part of a President's administration. Democrat Walz and Republican Vance are reinforcing their running mates' messages to voters, just weeks before the November 5 election. While Mr Vance is Vice Presidential pick of Donald Trump, Mr Walz has been chosen by Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Here's a look at the life and political career of 2024 US election Republican vice presidential nominee JD Vance:</p>

<p>Mr Vance is a politician, an author and a Marine veteran who has been serving as junior senator from Ohio. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/J-D-Vance">Encyclopaedia Britannica</a>, he was born James Donald Bowman in Middletown, in the Rust Belt region of Ohio to Don and Bev Bowman who had Scottish ancestry.</p>

<p>James' parents divorced when he was young and his mother changed his middle name to David. He eventually took his mother's middle name Vance as his surname.</p>

<p>Mr Vance was raised mostly by his maternal grandparents as his mother struggle with drug and alcohol abuse disorders.</p>

<h3><strong>His military background</strong></h3>

<p>It has happened for the first time since 1996 that both political parties in the US have picked a veteran as Vice President nominee. Mr Vance enlisted in the United States Marine Corps after graduating from Middletown High School in 2003. He spent four years in USMC, including six-month deployment to Iraq.</p>

<p>After his military service, Mr Vance attended the Ohio State University where he received a bachelor's degree in political science and philosophy in 2009. He later studied in Yale University, earning a law degree in 2013.</p>

<h3><strong>National fame</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Vance gained national recognition with his memoir '<em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>', which was published in 2016. It became a bestseller and was later adapted into a Netflix movie. The book tells Mr Vance's personal story against the backdrop of his struggles.</p>

<p>The book carries an excerpt about how the Marine Corps taught Mr Vance adulthood. "The day I graduated from boot camp was the proudest of my life," he wrote in the book, as per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/30/nx-s1-5134005/vance-walz-veteran-election-2024-vice-president"><em>NPR</em></a>.</p>

<p>Mr Trump also wrote about the book on his Truth Social platform while announcing Mr Vance's name as his running mate. "JD's book, 'Hillbilly Elegy,' became a Major Best Seller and Movie, as it championed the hardworking men and women of our Country," said Mr Trump.</p>

<h3><strong>JD Vance's family</strong></h3>

<p>While studying at Yale, Mr Vance met Usha Chilukuri and they got married in 2014. Her parents moved to the US in the late 1970s and now teach engineering and molecular biology in San Diego.</p>

<p>While Usha Vance studied at Yale and Cambridge, her father and grandfather both taught or studied at the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), India's premier engineering college. Her younger sister is a mechanical engineer with a semiconductor company in San Diego and an aunt a medical professional in the southern Indian city of Chennai.</p>

<p>In his memoir '<em>Hillbilly Elegy</em>', Mr Vance calls his wife a "supersmart daughter of Indian immigrants". The couple have three children.</p>

<h3><strong>JD Vance was once critical of Trump</strong></h3>

<p>In the lead-up to the 2016 US presidential election, Mr Vance was a bitter critic of Donald Trump. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5y5g2k2yp3o">The <em>BBC</em></a> carried his two quotes about Mr Trump - "My god, what an idiot" and "I find him reprehensible" - that resurfaced in July. He had also compared Mr Trump to Hitler, as per a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/10/01/jd-vance-trump-americas-hitler-republican-vice-president/"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>.</p>

<p>But when Mr Trump narrowed his search and announced Mr Vance as his running mate in July this year, the Ohio native became one of his most ardent defenders.</p>

<p>By the time Mr Vance ran for Senate in 2022, his demonstrations of loyalty, which included downplaying the January 6, 2021 attack on the US Capitol by Mr Trump's supporters, were sufficient to score the former president's coveted endorsement. Mr Trump's support helped put him over the top in a competitive primary.</p>

<h3><strong>Relationship with Donald Trump</strong></h3>

<p>Before Mr Vance developed a relationship with the former president, he grew close with Trump's eldest son, Donald Trump Jr, according to news agency Reuters. He attracted the attention of Mr Trump's son by opposing aid to Ukraine during the Ohio Senate primary in 2022.</p>

<p>In February 2023, Mr Trump and Mr Vance visited East Palestine, Ohio, the site of a toxic train derailment, a trip that raised Mr Vance's national profile.</p>

<p>Behind the scenes, Mr Vance has helped convince wealthy donors to open their wallets to Mr Trump, Reuters said quoting people with knowledge of the Republican leader's fundraising operations. Mr Vance helped put together a Bay Area fundraiser in June hosted by venture capitalists David Sacks and Chamath Palihapitiya.</p>

<p>Vance's scepticism of corporate America, support for tariffs, weariness of foreign entanglements and his youth make him a leading voice of a new Republican Party that is more focused on the working class than big business in the eyes of supporters.</p>

<h3><strong>How the Vice President is elected in the US?</strong></h3>

<p>The Vice President is the second-highest office in the executive branch of the US government, after the President. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/about-the-white-house/our-government/the-executive-branch/">White House</a>, the Vice President is elected along with the President by the Electoral College. Each elector casts one vote for President and another for Vice President. Before the ratification of the 12th Amendment in 1804, electors only voted for President, and the person who received the second greatest number of votes became Vice President.</p>

<p>The primary responsibility of the Vice President of the United States is to be ready at a moment's notice to assume the Presidency if the President is unable to perform his or her duties. This can be because of the President's death, resignation, or temporary incapacitation, or if the Vice President and a majority of the Cabinet judge that the President is no longer able to discharge the duties of the presidency.</p>

<p>The Vice President also serves as the President of the United States Senate, where he or she casts the deciding vote in the case of a tie.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/psoqm5n4_jd-vance-reuters_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance gained national recognition with his memoir 'Hillbilly Elegy'.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-the-iron-dome-israels-anti-missile-cover-since-2011-6698342]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: What Is The Iron Dome, Israel's Anti-Missile Cover Since 2011]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-what-is-the-iron-dome-israels-anti-missile-cover-since-2011-6698342]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:58:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Iron Dome air defence system has intercepted thousands of rockets since it went into operation in 2011, providing the country with crucial cover during times of conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Iron Dome air defence system has intercepted thousands of rockets since it went into operation in 2011, providing the country with crucial cover during times of conflict.</p>

<p>It has been heavily relied upon to protect military and civilian sites from frequent barrages of rockets fired from Gaza and Lebanon in the ongoing war between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>Israel's air defences were in operation on Tuesday night when Iran fired missiles at Israel in what it said was a response to Israel's killing of Tehran-backed militant leaders.</p>

<p>Israel's military chief Herzi Halevi said Tuesday that the Iranian barrage had been blunted partly by "a very strong aerial defence array".</p>

<p>The system had also intercepted more than 200 drones and missiles launched by Iran on April 13.</p>

<p>Israel initially developed the Iron Dome alone after the 2006 Lebanon War and was later joined by the United States, which has provided its defence know-how and billions of dollars in financial support for the program.</p>

<p>The system has an interception rate of around 90 per cent, according to Israeli defence firm Rafael, which helped design it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here's how it works:</p>

<h3><strong>Three-part system</strong></h3>

<p>The Iron Dome is one part of Israel's multi-tiered missile defence systems and is designed to intercept short-range rockets at a distance of up to 70 kilometres (43 miles).&nbsp;</p>

<p>Each Iron Dome battery is made up of three main sections: a radar detection system, a computer to calculate the incoming rocket's trajectory, and a launcher that fires interceptors if the rocket is deemed likely to hit a built-up or strategic area.</p>

<p>It sits alongside other missile defence systems like the Arrow, which counters ballistic missiles, and David's Sling, for medium-range rocket or missile attacks.</p>

<h3><strong>How much does it cost?</strong></h3>

<p>Each Iron Dome interceptor costs $40,000 to $50,000 to produce, according to the Washington-based Center for Strategic and International Studies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The think tank estimated that a complete system, including the radar, computer and three to four launchers -- each containing up to 20 interceptors -- costs around $100 million to produce.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has 10 such systems in operation, according to Raytheon, which helps manufacture the Iron Dome. Other estimates have put the figure slightly higher.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Bipartisan US support</strong></h3>

<p>The Iron Dome is one of the strategic pillars of the US-Israeli alliance that has been followed by successive Democratic and Republican administrations.</p>

<p>In August 2019 the US Army signed a contract to purchase two Iron Dome batteries to enhance its own short-range missile defence capabilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/67gmuofg_israel-iron-dome-afp_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iron Dome is one part of Israel's multi-tiered missile defence systems.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-says-india-very-much-concerned-about-middle-east-tensions-6695358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India "Very Much" Concerned About Middle East Tensions: S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-says-india-very-much-concerned-about-middle-east-tensions-6695358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:51:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Tuesday that India is "very much" concerned at the possibility of broadening of the conflict in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said on Tuesday that India is "very much" concerned at the possibility of broadening of the conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Speaking at the conversation at the Carnegie Endowment in the US, he called Hamas' attack on Israel a "terrorist attack," and added that Israel had a need to respond and added that India believes that any response by any country has to take into account international humanitarian law.</p>

<p>Asked about the escalating violence in the Middle East and India's approach towards Israel's policy and wider conflict possibilities, Mr Jaishankar said, " If one looks at the current situation, I think it would be right to start off with October 7th. We regard October 7th as a terrorist attack. We understand that Israel had a need to respond, but we also believe that any response by any country has to take into account international humanitarian law, that it must be careful about any damage or any implications for civilian populations. And that given what has happened in Gaza, it is important to have some kind of international humanitarian effort out there."</p>

<p>"And we are very much concerned at the possibility of a broadening of the conflict, not just what happened in Lebanon, but also, you know, I referred earlier to the Houthis and the Red Sea, and, you know, to some extent, everything that happens between Iran and Israel. So again, it's one thing to be concerned. I'm sure you can say that for a lot of countries. If as part of that concern, we can end up doing something about it, you know, then don't underestimate the importance of communication in difficult times. If there are things to be said and passed on and passed back, I think those are all contributions that we can make and we do," he added.</p>

<p>Notably, India has backed a two-state solution to the Israel-Palestine conflict. PM Narendra Modi was one of the first global leaders to condemn the terror attack on Israel by Hamas on October 7.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, India has repeatedly expressed concerns over the deteriorating situation in Gaza.</p>

<p>In October last year, Israel launched a counter-offensive against Hamas after hundreds of Hamas terrorists burst into Israeli borders, killing over 1200 people and taking over 250 hostages, out of which 100 continue to be in captivity.</p>

<p>The war has spiralled into the region lately, with Houthi rebels in Yemen also targeting Israel and other countries in the Red Sea. Israel has also continued striking Hezbollah in Lebanon. As the conflict heads towards escalation, all major countries have called for a ceasefire and hostage deal, while also stressing for a two-state solution as a means to achieve durable and sustainable peace in the region.</p>

<p>In a major escalation in the raging conflict in the Middle East, Iran on Tuesday launched a missile attack on Israel on Tuesday. In a statement, the IDF said all Israeli civilians are in bomb shelters as rockets from Iran are fired at Israel.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is upset that the IDF exposed their plans to massacre Israelis, so they decided to target innocent civilians by firing a barrage of rockets, the IDF further said.</p>

<p>102 missiles have been launched towards Israel, according to the Jerusalem Post. Sirens continue to sound across Israel amid the attack, the Times of Israel reported. According to the IDF, around 10 million civilians are the targets of Iranian projectiles. Iran's state media has also confirmed the Iranian attack towards Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iltj1phg_s-jaishankar-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has backed a two-state solution to the Israel-Palestine conflict.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-man-held-for-distributing-app-that-was-whatsapp-for-criminals-6698197]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Man Held For Distributing App That Was 'Whatsapp For Criminals']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-man-held-for-distributing-app-that-was-whatsapp-for-criminals-6698197]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:37:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian man has been charged with distributing the encrypted messaging app known as "Ghost", allegedly used by criminals across the globe to arrange drug deals and violence, police said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian man has been charged with distributing the encrypted messaging app known as "Ghost", allegedly used by criminals across the globe to arrange drug deals and violence, police said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The Ghost app was marketed to underworld figures as "unhackable" and used by hundreds of suspected criminals from Europe, the Middle East, Australia and Asia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It was allegedly designed by a 32-year-old Australian computer whiz living with his parents in suburban Sydney.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Australian Federal Police said Wednesday they had arrested a 47-year-old man "alleged to be a distributor" of the app.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Encrypted phones were pre-loaded with Ghost before the man stashed them at "dead drops", or pre-arranged hiding places for collection, police said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Global policing authorities managed to infiltrate the network, watching as criminals discussed illicit drug trafficking, money laundering, homicides and serious violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Police swooped in September, arresting criminals from Italy, Ireland, Sweden, Canada and Australia -- including Jay Je Yoon Jung, the alleged "mastermind".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ghost, a kind of WhatsApp for criminals, was created nine years ago and could only be accessed via modified smartphones that sold for about US $1,590.</p>

<p>French police traced the creator's location to Australia and joined forces with local police to target the platform.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Several thousand people worldwide used Ghost and around 1,000 messages were exchanged on it every day, according to Europol.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There were 376 phones with the Ghost app installed in Australia alone.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7emhd6j8_cyber-crime-generic_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ghost app was created nine years ago. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-irans-missile-capabilities-explained-6698182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran's Missile Capabilities Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-war-irans-missile-capabilities-explained-6698182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:34:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran fired a salvo of ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday in retaliation for Israel's campaign against Tehran's Hezbollah allies in Lebanon, drawing on an array of weapons that has long worried the West.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran fired a salvo of ballistic missiles at Israel on Tuesday in retaliation for Israel's campaign against Tehran's Hezbollah allies in Lebanon, drawing on an array of weapons that has long worried the West.</p>

<p>The attack came five months after a strike in April that was the first ever direct Iranian strike on Israel.</p>

<p>Ballistic missiles are an important part of the arsenal at Tehran's disposal. According to the U.S. Office of the Director of National Intelligence, Iran is armed with the largest number of ballistic missiles in the region.</p>

<p>Here are some details:</p>

<p>The semi-official Iranian news outlet ISNA published a graphic in April showing nine Iranian missiles it said could reach Israel. These included the 'Sejil', capable of flying at more than 17,000 km (10,500 miles) per hour and with a range of 2,500 km (1,550 miles), the 'Kheibar' with a range of 2,000 km (1,240 miles), and the 'Haj Qasem', which has a range of 1,400 km (870 miles), ISNA said.</p>

<p>The Arms Control Association, a Washington-based non-governmental organization, says Iran's ballistic missiles include 'Shahab-1', with an estimated range of 300 km (190 miles); the 'Zolfaghar', with 700 km (435 miles); 'Shahab-3', with 800-1,000 km (500 to 620 miles); 'Emad-1', a missile under development with a range up to 2,000 km (1,240 miles) and 'Sejil', under development, with 1,500-2,500 km (930 to 1,550 miles).</p>

<p>Fabian Hinz, a Berlin-based expert on Iran's missile arsenal with the International Institute for Strategic Studies, said that based on the locations of videos of launches posted on social media and the ranges to Israel, he assessed that Iran fired a combination of solid- and liquid-fueled missiles.</p>

<p>The former category of missile, which is more advanced, is fired from angled mobile launchers and the latter from vertical launchers, he said.</p>

<p>He said three solid-propellent missiles fired on Tuesday could be the 'Haj Qasem', 'Kheibar Shekan' and 'Fattah 1'. Liquid propellant missiles reported as being launched from Isfahan might potentially be the 'Emad', 'Badr' and 'Khorramshahr', he said.</p>

<p>Iran says its ballistic missiles are an important deterrent and retaliatory force against the U.S., Israel and other potential regional targets. It denies seeking nuclear weapons. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>According to a 2023 report by Behnam Ben Taleblu, a Senior Fellow at the U.S.-based Foundation for Defense of Democracies, Iran continues to develop underground missile depots complete with transport and firing systems, and subterranean missile production and storage centers. In June 2020, Iran fired its first ever ballistic missile from underground, it said.</p>

<p>"Years of reverse-engineering missiles and producing various missile classes have also taught Iran about stretching airframes and building them with lighter composite materials to increase missile range," the report said.</p>

<p>In June 2023, Iran presented what officials described as its first domestically made hypersonic ballistic missile, the official IRNA news agency reported. Hypersonic missiles can fly at least five times faster than the speed of sound and on a complex trajectory, which makes them difficult to intercept.</p>

<p>The Arms Control Association says Iran's missile programme is largely based on North Korean and Russian designs and has benefited from Chinese assistance.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran also has cruise missiles such as Kh-55, an air-launched nuclear-capable weapon with a range up to 3,000 km (1,860 miles), and the advanced anti-ship missile the Khalid Farzh, with about 300 km (186 miles), capable of carrying a 1,000-kg (1.1-ton) warhead.</p>

<p><strong>Regional Attacks</strong></p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards used missiles in January 2024 when they said they attacked the spy headquarters of Israel in Iraq's semi-autonomous Kurdistan region, and said they fired at Islamic State militants in Syria. Iran also announced firing missiles at two bases of a Baluchi militant group in neighbouring Pakistan. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Saudi Arabia and the U.S. have said they believe Iran was behind a drone and missile attack on Saudi Arabia's prized oil facilities in 2019. Tehran denied the allegation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2020, Iran launched missile attacks on U.S.-led forces in Iraq, including the al-Asad air base, in retaliation for a U.S. drone strike on an Iranian commander.</p>

<p><strong>Backing For Yemen's Houthis</strong></p>

<p>The United States accuses Iran of arming the Houthis of Yemen, who have been firing on Red Sea shipping and Israel itself during the Gaza war, in a campaign they say is aimed at supporting the Palestinians. Tehran denies arming the Houthis.</p>

<p>On Sept. 24, Reuters reported Iran had brokered secret talks between Russia and the Houthis to transfer anti-ship missiles to the armed group, citing Western and regional sources.</p>

<p>In 2022, the Houthis said they fired ballistic missiles and drones at the United Arab Emirates. This included a missile attack targeting a base hosting the U.S. military in the UAE, which was thwarted by U.S.-built Patriot interceptor missiles.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Support For Hezbollah</strong></p>

<p>Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah group has said it has the ability within Lebanon to convert thousands of rockets into precision missiles and to produce drones. Last year, the late Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah said the group was able to transform standard rockets into precision missiles with the cooperation of Iranian experts.</p>

<p><strong>Syria</strong></p>

<p>Iran has transferred indigenous precision-guided missiles to Syria to support President Bashar al-Assad's fight against rebels, according to Israeli and Western intelligence officials.</p>

<p>It has moved some production capacity to underground compounds in Syria, where Assad's military and other pro-Tehran forces have learned to build their own missiles, those sources say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5igooq6_iran-missile-reuters_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ballistic missiles are an important part of the arsenal at Tehran's disposal]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Solar Eclipse On October 2: How Fast It Will Travel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/solar-eclipse-on-october-2-how-fast-it-will-travel-6683968]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:33:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The much-anticipated annular solar eclipse is set to grace the skies on October 2. The eclipse will begin at 9:13 pm IST on October 2 and conclude at 3:17 pm IST the next day. During this time, the Moon will appear smaller than the Sun, creating a brilliant <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/ring-of-fire-solar-eclipse-2024-check-timing-visibility-in-india-and-other-details-6671693 ">“ring of fire”</a> effect – a halo of sunlight visible around the darkened centre.</p>

<p><strong>How fast the eclipse will travel</strong></p>

<p>During the upcoming annular solar eclipse, the speed of the Moon's shadow across Earth will vary significantly depending on location. In some areas, it will travel faster than 10 million kmph, while in others, it will slow to about 2,057 kmph, roughly the speed of a fighter jet, reported <a href="https://www.space.com/how-fast-will-the-annular-solar-eclipse-october-2-travel ">Space.com</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Path of the eclipse</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will move from northwest to southeast, and due to Earth's curvature and the Moon's changing distance and orbital speed, the shadow's velocity will fluctuate dramatically across different regions. The eclipse will start with an eclipsed sunrise, peak at midday and end with an eclipsed sunset.</p>

<p><strong>Where the eclipse will touch and leave Earth</strong></p>

<p>The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean, moving at 8.55 million kmph. When it leaves Earth near the island of South Georgia, it will travel at 10 million km/h. However, these extreme speeds occur as the shadow touches and leaves Earth, rendering them less meaningful.</p>

<p><strong>Where can you view the eclipse?</strong></p>

<p>The shadow's speed will be slower when the eclipse is visible at the horizon, around 8,258 kmph at sunrise and 14,312 kmph at sunset. The slowest speed of 2,057 kmph will be observed in the Pacific Ocean northwest of Easter Island, where the ‘ring of fire' will last for 7 minutes and 25 seconds. This slower speed is due to the Moon's shadow being nearly perpendicular to Earth at local midday – the longest duration of the eclipse.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/hii8n5ng_ring-of-fire-annual-solar-eclipse_625x300_08_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Solar Eclipse: The Moon's shadow will first strike south of Hawaii in the Pacific Ocean (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-missile-attack-israel-naftali-bennett-israels-chance-to-change-face-of-middle-east-ex-pm-after-iran-offensive-6698069]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Israel's Chance To Change Face Of Middle East': Ex PM After Iran Offensive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-missile-attack-israel-naftali-bennett-israels-chance-to-change-face-of-middle-east-ex-pm-after-iran-offensive-6698069]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:18:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's missile offensive against Israel was a "terrible mistake" and Tel Aviv has its greatest opportunity in 50 years to change the face of the Middle East, former Israel Prime Minister Naftali Bennett has said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's missile offensive against Israel was a "terrible mistake" and Tel Aviv has its greatest opportunity in 50 years to change the face of the Middle East, former Israel Prime Minister Naftali Bennett has said.&nbsp;In a post on X after Tehran fired 108 ballistic missiles targeting Israel last night, the former Prime Minister said Israel must act now and destroy Iran's nuclear programme and energy facilities.</p>

<p>"Israel has now its greatest opportunity in 50 years, to change the face of the Middle East. The leadership of Iran, which used to be good at chess, made a terrible mistake this evening. We must act *now* to destroy Iran's nuclear program, its central energy facilities, and to fatally cripple this terrorist regime," Mr Bennett wrote.</p>

<p>A former commando in Israel's elite Sayeret Matkal unit, Mr Bennett leads the New Right party and served as Prime Minister from June 2021 to June 2022. He succeeded Benjamin Netanyahu after he was ousted as Prime Minister in 2021.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Israel has now its greatest opportunity in 50 years, to change the face of the Middle East.<br />
<br />
The leadership of Iran, which used to be good at chess, made a terrible mistake this evening.<br />
<br />
We must act *now* to destroy Iran's nuclear program, its central energy facilities, and to…</p>
— Naftali Bennett נפתלי בנט (@naftalibennett) <a href="https://twitter.com/naftalibennett/status/1841222685638177225?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Mr Bennett described Iran as the head of the octopus of terror. "To strike the head of the octopus of terror, that, in its cowardice, sent its tentacles (Hamas, Hezbollah, the Houthis, etc.) to murder us, while the Ayatollahs sat safely in their palaces in Tehran. The octopus's tentacles are temporarily paralysed - now comes the head. We must remove this terrible threat to our children's future," he said in the post. "We can grant the Iranian people an opportunity to rise up and shake off the regime that tyrannizes its women and daughters," the former Prime Minister added.</p>

<p>Iran's missile offensive against Israel followed the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Israeli military operations. While Tel Aviv's advanced defence systems intercepted many of the missiles launched by Tehran, many others landed. There have been no casualties in Israel though.</p>

<p>The Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps said the attack was "in accordance with the United Nations Charter" and followed "a period of restraint" following an "attack on the sovereignty" of Iran -- a reference to the killing of Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in late July. The IRGC said the missiles targeted "three military bases" around Tel Aviv as well as air and radar bases.</p>

<p>Israel Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has said Iran made a "big mistake" and warned that it "will pay for it".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-06/p8dl40a8_naftali-bennett-650_625x300_03_June_21.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>In his post on X, Mr Bennett said, "We have the justification. We have the tools. Now that Hezbollah and Hamas are paralyzed, Iran stands exposed. Over this last terrible year, Iranian tentacles murdered our families. Raped our daughters. Kidnapped our children. Ransacked our towns. Burned our fields. Fired on our ships. Terrorized children in Kiryat Shmona, Kfar Aza, and Sderot. Emptied out whole regions of our land. Humiliated us."</p>

<p>"Now is the moment. A Nation of Lions has united and proven its strength over the last year. It has yearned for a change, for action, for so very long. There are times when history knocks at our door, and we must open it. This opportunity must not be missed," the former Prime Minister added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/30q5lnho_israel-crater_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The missiles landed at several locations in Israel and craters were formed. AFP]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-study-shows-music-can-boost-plant-growth-6697988]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Study Shows Music Can Boost Plant Growth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-study-shows-music-can-boost-plant-growth-6697988]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 11:02:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Playing a monotonous sound stimulates the activity of a fungus that promotes plant growth, a study suggested on Wednesday, raising the potential that playing music could be good for crops and gardens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Playing a monotonous sound stimulates the activity of a fungus that promotes plant growth, a study suggested on Wednesday, raising the potential that playing music could be good for crops and gardens.</p>

<p>Whether or not blasting Mozart could help plants grow has long been a matter of scientific debate. The US TV show "MythBusters" even tested it out, finding that plants exposed to death metal and classical music grew a little better than those left in silence, but deeming the results inconclusive.</p>

<p>However, with the plant world facing a raft of human-driven challenges -- including erosion, deforestation, pollution and a burgeoning extinction crisis -- the future of the world's biodiversity and crops are increasingly feared to be under threat.</p>

<p>According to a new study in the journal Biology Letters, "the role of acoustic stimulation in fostering ecosystem recovery and sustainable food systems remains under-explored".</p>

<p>Based on previous work that exposed E. coli bacteria to sound waves, the team of Australian researchers set out to assess the effect sound has on the growth rate and spore production of the fungus Trichoderma harzianum.</p>

<p>This fungus is often used in organic farming for its ability to protect plants from pathogens, improve nutrients in the soil and promote growth.</p>

<p>The researchers built little sound booths to house Petri dishes full of fungi.</p>

<p>Instead of pop bangers, they were played "Tinnitus Flosser Masker at 8 kHz". This was the audio from one of many white noise videos on YouTube which are intended to relieve tinnitus or help babies fall asleep.</p>

<p>"Think of the sound of an old-school radio in between channels," lead study author Jake Robinson of Flinders University told AFP.</p>

<p>"We chose this monotone for controlled, experimental reasons, but it might be that a more diverse or natural soundscape is better," he said.</p>

<p>"This needs further research."</p>

<h3><strong>Sound garden&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The petri dishes were played with this sound at a level of 80 decibels for half an hour a day.</p>

<p>After five days, the growth and spore production were higher in the fungi that were played the sound, compared to those that sat in silence.</p>

<p>While far from definitive, the researchers suggested some potential reasons this could happen.</p>

<p>The acoustic wave could be converted into a fungi-stimulating electrical charge under what is known as the piezoelectric effect.</p>

<p>Another theory involves tiny receptors on the membranes of the fungi called mechanoreceptors.</p>

<p>These are comparable to the thousands of mechanoreceptors on human skin that play a role in our sense of touch -- which involves reacting to pressure or vibration.</p>

<p>"It might be that sound waves stimulate these mechanoreceptors in the fungi, which then trigger a cascade of biochemical events that lead to genes being switched on or off -- for instance, the kind of genes responsible for growth," Robinson said.</p>

<p>"Our preliminary research suggests the fungi respond to the sound, but we don't know yet if this benefits the plants. So, this is the next step," he added.</p>

<p>"Can we influence soil or plant microbial communities as a whole? Can we speed up the soil restoration process by stimulating the earth with natural soundscapes? What impact might this have on the soil fauna?" he asked.</p>

<p>"There are many important questions to keep us busy."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1uttmp7_plant-generic_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plant world is facing a raft of human-driven challenges such as erosion, deforestation, and pollution]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-destabilizing-dangerous-force-in-middle-east-kamala-harris-on-missile-attacks-on-israel-6697940]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Iran Destabilizing Force In Middle East": Kamala Harris On Missile Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-destabilizing-dangerous-force-in-middle-east-kamala-harris-on-missile-attacks-on-israel-6697940]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 10:58:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential candidate, said on Tuesday that Iran was a "dangerous" and "destabilizing" force in the Middle East and Washington was committed to Israel's security.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential candidate, said on Tuesday that Iran was a "dangerous" and "destabilizing" force in the Middle East and Washington was committed to Israel's security.</p>

<h2><strong>Why It's Important</strong></h2>

<p>The comments from Harris, who faces Republican former President Donald Trump in the November 5 US election, came hours after Iran fired ballistic missiles at Israel in retaliation for Israel's military campaign in Lebanon, drawing vows of a sharp response from Israel and the US.</p>

<p>No injuries were reported in Israel and Washington called Iran's attack ineffective.</p>

<h2><strong>Key Quotes</strong></h2>

<p>"I'm clear-eyed Iran is a destabilizing, dangerous force in the Middle East," Harris said. "I will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist militias."</p>

<p>"I fully support President (Joe) Biden's order for the U.S. military to shoot down Iranian missiles targeting Israel," Harris said. "Initial indications are that Israel, with our assistance, was able to defeat this attack."</p>

<p>Harris added that Washington will work with its allies to disrupt what she called Iran's "aggressive behavior."</p>

<h2><strong>Context</strong></h2>

<p>Israel has escalated its military campaign in Lebanon in recent days, killing hundreds and displacing more than a million due to operations that Israel says are targeting Lebanese Iran-backed Hezbollah operatives.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign in Lebanon is in addition to its war in Gaza that followed a deadly October 7 attack on Israel by Palestinian Hamas operatives. Israeli's military assault on Gaza has killed tens of thousands according to Palestinian health authorities, displaced nearly everyone there, caused a hunger crisis and prompted genocide allegations that Israel denies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Washington is committed to Israel's security, said Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>