<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 01:49:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-ukraine-incursion-real-dilemma-for-putin-6331784]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says Ukraine Incursion "Real Dilemma For Putin"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-ukraine-incursion-real-dilemma-for-putin-6331784]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 01:27:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine's cross-border incursion into Russia is giving President Vladimir Putin a "real dilemma," US President Joe Biden said Tuesday in his first comments on Kyiv's surprise attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine's cross-border incursion into Russia is giving President Vladimir Putin a "real dilemma," US President Joe Biden said Tuesday in his first comments on Kyiv's surprise attack.</p>

<p>"It's creating a real dilemma for Putin, and we've been in direct contact, constant contact, with the Ukrainians. That's all I'm going to say about it while it's active," Biden told reporters in the southern US city of New Orleans.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/o44j52qo_joe-biden_625x300_03_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said that US has been in constant touch with Ukrainians amid rising tensions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/case-filed-against-teacher-maid-over-blasphemy-allegations-in-pakistan-6331694]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Case Filed Against School Owner, Maid Over Blasphemy Charges In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/case-filed-against-teacher-maid-over-blasphemy-allegations-in-pakistan-6331694]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:58:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police registered a blasphemy case against a private school owner and her maid in Rai Kalan village in the Kasur district of Punjab after accusations emerged that they had desecrated pages of the Quran, Dawn News reported on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police registered a blasphemy case against a private school owner and her maid in Rai Kalan village in the Kasur district of Punjab after accusations emerged that they had desecrated pages of the Quran, Dawn News reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The incident, which occurred on Friday, was captured in a video that quickly went viral on social media the following day.</p>

<p>As a result, large crowds from neighbouring villages gathered outside the school and police arrived in a substantial number.</p>

<p>According to the FIR, the school's driver and gardener recorded the video of the burned pages and reported it to the complainant. The allegations suggest that the maid burned the pages under the direction of the school owner. The police have stated that the situation is under control and that arrests will be made soon.</p>

<p>Blasphemy is a highly sensitive and contentious issue in Pakistan, where allegations of insulting religion or religious texts can result in severe legal repercussions and societal backlash.</p>

<p>In Pakistan, false allegations of blasphemy have led to severe consequences for many individuals, often driven by personal grievances or social tensions.</p>

<p>One prominent case is that of Asia Bibi, a Christian woman who was falsely accused of blasphemy in 2009. Despite her eventual acquittal by the Supreme Court in 2018, her case drew significant international attention and highlighted the dangers of false accusations, as Dawn News reported.</p>

<p>Similarly, Mashal Khan, a university student, was brutally lynched in 2017 after being wrongfully accused of blasphemy, a situation exacerbated by personal vendettas.</p>

<p>The case of Sawan Masih, a Christian man accused in 2013, resulted in violent attacks on Christian communities and was criticized for its lack of credible evidence.</p>

<p>Additionally, Rimsha Masih, a young Christian girl with learning disabilities, faced accusations in 2012 that were later shown to be fabricated, underscoring the vulnerability of those targeted by false claims. These cases illustrate the severe impact and risks associated with false blasphemy allegations in Pakistan, reported Dawn News.</p>

<p>The blasphemy laws in Pakistan have been criticized for being frequently misused to settle personal scores, target minority communities, or incite violence. False accusations can lead to severe social and legal repercussions, including mob violence and extrajudicial killing.</p>

<p>The enforcement of blasphemy laws has faced criticism for lack of due process, with many cases resulting in lengthy legal battles and significant social unrest.</p>

<p>Moreover, the judicial process is often influenced by public opinion and pressure from extremist groups. Human rights organizations and international bodies have condemned the blasphemy laws for their potential to infringe on fundamental rights and freedoms.</p>

<p>Critics argue that the laws violate principles of free speech and are used to persecute religious minorities and dissenters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-08/pakistan-flag_650x400_41440732057.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Blasphemy is a highly sensitive and contentious issue in Pakistan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-plans-1st-manned-space-mission-over-earths-poles-6331411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Plans 1st Manned Space Mission Over Earth's Poles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-plans-1st-manned-space-mission-over-earths-poles-6331411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 23:47:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX is aiming to break new barriers in polar exploration with the first manned space mission over the Earth's poles -- a private flight commanded by a crypto entrepreneur later this year, the company said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX is aiming to break new barriers in polar exploration with the first manned space mission over the Earth's poles -- a private flight commanded by a crypto entrepreneur later this year, the company said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The mission, dubbed "Fram2" after a 19th century polar expedition schooner, is due to last between three to five days, and was purchased by Chun Wang, a wealthy bitcoin pioneer who founded f2pool and stakefish, for an undisclosed amount.</p>

<p>He will be joined by three polar experts: Norwegian filmmaker Jannicke Mikkelsen, German robotics researcher Rabea Rogge, and Australian polar adventurer Eric Philips.</p>

<p>It is the latest foray by the aerospace industry into private space tourism, growing fast in the United States in recent years.</p>

<p>"From mission proposal, planning, trajectory design, to crew selection, everything has been done by the customer," Mr Wang, reportedly born and raised in China but now a Maltese citizen, said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"A new chapter in space exploration is unfolding before our eyes," he said.</p>

<p>Satellites have flown over the poles, but due to the Earth's rotation, reaching them can take more power, while radiation can also be an issue, astrophysicist Jonathan McDowell told AFP.</p>

<p>"To date, the highest inclination achieved by human spaceflight has been the Soviet Vostok 6 mission, at 65 degrees," according to the mission website.</p>

<p>The poles are not visible from the International Space Station (ISS).</p>

<p>The mission will use a SpaceX Dragon capsule equipped with an observation dome. The craft will fly at an altitude of between 265 and 280 miles (425 and 450 kilometers), according to SpaceX, owned by mercurial billionaire Elon Musk.</p>

<p>The crew plans to conduct research including taking the first X-ray images in space and studying an aurora-like light phenomenon, according to SpaceX.</p>

<p>SpaceX has flown 13 manned missions in the last four years. It carries Nasa astronauts to the ISS, but has also carried out several space tourism missions, including the first in 2021, named Inspiration4, financed by American billionaire Jared Isaacman.</p>

<p>"Until 2021, space missions were solely the privilege of governments," Mr Wang wrote, adding: "Then @inspiration4x came along and changed everything."</p>

<p>SpaceX is set to launch another private mission, Polaris Dawn on August 26, carrying four crew members including Isaacman.</p>

<p>It is scheduled to include the first private spacewalk.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5kba7v_earth-from-space-_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mission will use a SpaceX Dragon capsule equipped with an observation dome. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrest-of-ex-isi-chief-faiz-hameed-internal-issue-of-pak-army-imran-khan-6331247]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Arrest Of Ex ISI Chief Faiz Hameed "Internal Issue" Of Pak Army: Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/arrest-of-ex-isi-chief-faiz-hameed-internal-issue-of-pak-army-imran-khan-6331247]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 23:16:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former premier on Tuesday termed the arrest of former ISI chief Faiz Hameed as an "internal issue" of the military and said that the army's action against the former general has nothing to do with his party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's jailed former premier on Tuesday termed the arrest of former ISI chief Faiz Hameed as an "internal issue" of the military and said that the army's action against the former general has nothing to do with his party.</p>

<p>Mr Hameed served as the director general of Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) from 2019 to 2021, when Mr Khan was prime minister and was accused of meddling in political affairs at his behest.</p>

<p>"Imran Khan sahib said just this that 'it is the army's internal matter' and that whatever action the army has taken has nothing to do with the PTI or Khan sahib," Mr Khan's legal representative Intezar Panjutha said.</p>

<p>Mr Panjutha made these remarks following a meeting of Mr Khan with his senior lawyers at Adiala Jail in Rawalpindi.</p>

<p>Mr Panjutha quoted Mr Khan as saying it was purely a military matter, with no links to PTI. He further clarified that there had been no political connection between Mr Khan and Gen Faiz.</p>

<p>Mr Khan also claimed that former army chief General Qamar Javed Bajwa had replaced Gen Faiz after making a deal with Nawaz Sharif, according to the lawyer.</p>

<p>Mr Khan also suggested that if General Faiz's arrest was related to the events of May 9, it would be an opportune moment to form a judicial commission and bring the CCTV footage of the day to light, Panjutha noted.</p>

<p>He also stated that the former premier urged his followers to peacefully protest tonight for the sake of freedom, stressing the importance of taking to the streets for the country.</p>

<p>Mr Panjutha also highlighted Mr Khan's concerns over the mounting pressure on the Supreme Court, the disillusionment among the youth, and the deteriorating conditions in Pakistan, comparing them with those in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>He stated that Mr Khan believed it was time for Chief Justice Qazi Faez Isa to step back, highlighting that PTI's three seats were allegedly taken away the previous day.</p>

<p>Earlier, in an unprecedented move, Mr Hameed was detained by military authorities and court martial proceedings were initiated against him on charges of corruption, misuse of authority and violating the Pakistan Army Act.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j1tbgt1o_faiz-hameed_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-1-000-arrested-following-uk-riots-police-6331240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 1,000 Arrested In UK After Days Of Rioting And Racist Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/more-than-1-000-arrested-following-uk-riots-police-6331240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 23:13:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British authorities have now arrested more than 1,000 people following days of rioting involving violence, arson and looting as well as racist attacks targeting Muslims and migrants, a national policing body said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British authorities have now arrested more than 1,000 people following days of rioting involving violence, arson and looting as well as racist attacks targeting Muslims and migrants, a national policing body said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The riots, which followed the killings of three young girls in the northern English town of Southport, began after the July 29 attack was wrongly blamed on an Islamist migrant based on online misinformation.</p>

<p>Violence broke out in cities across England and also in Northern Ireland, but there have been fewer instances of unrest since last week after efforts to identify those involved were ramped up.</p>

<p>Many have been swiftly jailed, with some receiving long sentences</p>

<p>The National Police Chiefs' Council said in its latest update that 1,024 had been arrested and 575 charged across the UK.</p>

<p>Those arrested include a 69-year-old accused of vandalism in Liverpool and a 11-year-old boy in Belfast.</p>

<p>A 13-year-old girl pleaded guilty to violent disorder at Basingstoke Magistrates' Court, prosecutors said, having been seen on July 31 punching and kicking the entrance to a hotel for asylum seekers.</p>

<p>"This alarming incident will have caused genuine fear amongst people who were being targeted by these thugs - and it is particularly distressing to learn that such a young girl participated in this violent disorder," prosecutor Thomas Power said.</p>

<p>The last time Britain witnessed widespread rioting was in 2011, when the fatal shooting of a Black man by police triggered several days of street violence.</p>

<p>Fast and tough judicial action was viewed as helping quell the unrest in 2011, when around 4,000 people were arrested over several weeks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/em13t2vo_uk-riots-arrest-reuters_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[An anti-immigration protester detained by police officers in Newcastle, Britain. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctica-experiences-exceptionally-long-heatwave-researcher-says-6331192]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Antarctica Experiences Exceptionally Long Heatwave, Says Research Body]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctica-experiences-exceptionally-long-heatwave-researcher-says-6331192]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 23:03:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Antarctica, the world's coldest continent, is experiencing an exceptionally long heatwave during its winter, according to Britain's national polar research institute.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Antarctica, the world's coldest continent, is experiencing an exceptionally long heatwave during its winter, according to Britain's national polar research institute.</p>

<p>Temperature anomalies are not unusual on the continent known as "The Ice" but "the longevity of the warm period is unusual", Thomas Caton Harrison, Polar Climate Scientist at British Antarctic Survey, said to AFP this week.</p>

<p>Provisional figures indicate the Antarctic-wide July 2024 average near-surface temperature was 3.1 degrees Celsius above normal for the month.</p>

<p>Calculated over land and land ice, this makes it the second warmest July in Antarctica since records began in 1979 -- the warmest was in July 1981.</p>

<p>Average daily temperatures ranged from -34.68C on July 15 to -28.12C on July 31, according to data posted online by the University of Maine.</p>

<p>It was -26.6C on average on the continent on August 7, the latest date available.</p>

<p>The July average temperature anomaly even reached 9-10C over limited parts of Dronning Maud Land and part of the eastern Weddell Sea offshore.</p>

<p>Daily temperature anomalies often occur during the Antarctica's winter, but "what is remarkable is prolonged high temperatures", said Caton Harrison.</p>

<p>"Very early figures suggest it could be on track to be an exceptionally warm Antarctic winter," he added.</p>

<p>"The Ice" is the coldest, windiest, and least populated continent on the planet, but it too is impacted by global warming.</p>

<p>Extreme heat on the continent has high stakes, notably as a trigger for greater ice loss.</p>

<p>According to a study published in June in the journal Nature Geoscience, scientists have discovered a new tipping point toward "runaway melting" of Antarctic ice sheets, caused by warm ocean water intruding between the ice and the land it sits on.</p>

<p>With the rise of ocean temperatures due to human-caused global warming, Antarctic ice sheets are melting, threatening a rise in global sea levels and putting coastal communities at risk.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/tgsd9118_antarctica_625x300_10_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is the second warmest July in Antarctica since records began in 1979]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-want-friendly-relationship-with-india-key-bangladesh-leader-6331155]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Want Friendly Relationship With India": Key Bangladesh Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-want-friendly-relationship-with-india-key-bangladesh-leader-6331155]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:58:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[General Secretary of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Mirza Islam Alamgir, has expressed his party's desire to strengthen ties with India and emphasized that India is considered a neighbour and friend, but also called for a resolution of sever]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>General Secretary of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), Mirza Islam Alamgir, has expressed his party's desire to strengthen ties with India and emphasized that India is considered a neighbour and friend, but also called for a resolution of several key issues.</p>

<p>While speaking to news agency ANI, Mr Alamgir said that the BNP wants a friendly relationship with India, and is seeking solutions to these issues to move forward.</p>

<p>"It will be definitely strengthened further because we as a political party, always consider India to be our neighbour and friend. But we also invite India to come to a solution on certain issues," said Mr Alamgir</p>

<p>"We want a good friendly relationship with India," he added.</p>

<p>Further, Mr Alamgir has denied reports of communal atrocities against Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Mr Alamgir claimed that the issues are "totally political" and not communal or religious. He invited Indian media to visit Dhaka to assess the situation themselves.</p>

<p>"There is a sort of misunderstanding and very unfortunate propaganda being made by different media nationally and globally and especially from your country. The media is peddling that communal atrocities are going on in Bangladesh which is not true at all. This is not communal, not religious, this is totally political to some extent. I invite you, the media of India to come to Dhaka and see themselves, what has happened in Bangladesh," said Mr Alamgir while referring to the attacks on Hindus in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>Further, Mr Alamgir accused the government of perpetuating a "political conspiracy" against the interim government and the people.</p>

<p>"Some people say that the people of Bangladesh are creating some communal problems. No not at all. They are safe in the hands of the Bangladeshi government, Bangladeshi people, they're always safe. This is again a political conspiracy going on against the interim government and the people because the people do not want anymore the government of Sheikh Hasina who has killed so many people in these few years and destroyed the constitution. They have violated human rights and corruption was rampant and unprecedented," the General Secretary of BNP said to ANI.</p>

<p>Mr Alamgir also spoke about the situation when Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled from the country and stated that she fled to Delhi, India, under "special circumstances" following a student and citizen uprising.</p>

<p>"Former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina has resigned and fled from the country abandoning her party and the people. She was supposed to be with the people always but she left the country. As far as our knowledge goes, she has landed in Delhi. She had to leave under special circumstances," he said.</p>

<p>"There was a student and citizen uprising. It was a revolution and before that, almost 1,000 students were killed by Sheikh Hasina's police and almost 12,000 people were arrested... Millions of people were on the streets and they were heading towards the official residence of the Prime Minister and then she left the country with her helicopter," he added.</p>

<p>Bangladesh is experiencing a volatile political situation, with Sheikh Hasina resigning from the post of Prime Minister on August 5 amid mounting protests. The protests, led mainly by students demanding an end to a quota system for government jobs, evolved into anti-government demonstrations.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/p9rd735_bangladesh-protest_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh is experiencing a volatile political situation (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/banksy-unveils-ninth-animal-theme-mural-outside-london-zoo-6331085]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Street Artist Banksy Unveils 9th Animal Theme Mural Outside London Zoo]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/banksy-unveils-ninth-animal-theme-mural-outside-london-zoo-6331085]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:46:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elusive street artist Banksy's ninth animal-themed mural in nine days, unveiled on Tuesday on a shutter outside London Zoo, depicted a gorilla releasing animals from the zoo, tying together the series of artworks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elusive street artist Banksy's ninth animal-themed mural in nine days, unveiled on Tuesday on a shutter outside London Zoo, depicted a gorilla releasing animals from the zoo, tying together the series of artworks.</p>

<p>Claimed by the artist on Instagram, the mural outside London Zoo showed a gorilla lifting the shutter to free birds and a seal, with some animals staring out from the inside.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-mm6DzMmZc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-mm6DzMmZc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-mm6DzMmZc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-mm6DzMmZc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Banksy (@banksy)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>It is the latest in Banksy's series populating the British capital with animals, starting with a goat revealed last week Monday, followed by two elephants the next day and then monkeys, a wolf, pelicans, a cat, piranhas and a rhinoceros in subsequent days.</p>

<p>The frequency of artworks is unusual for Banksy -- whose identity is publicly unknown -- and who usually spaces out his pieces over months, leaving fans speculating about the meaning of the different animals and awaiting a "big" reveal.</p>

<p>The latest mural was "an absolute shock and surprise to all of us here at London Zoo", Karl Penman, commercial operations manager at the zoo said.</p>

<p>"If it is the full stop, what a great full stop to end on," Penman told AFP.</p>

<p>The BBC reported the that piece was the last in the series.</p>

<p>"You can see the watchful eyes, which to me look a little bit uncertain about whether they want to be free," said doctor Sharmela Darne about the eyes of animals staring from behind the shutter in the latest artwork.</p>

<p>"But the seal's clearly going away and so are the birds flying free... so maybe it's about freedom and being unsure about freedom," Darne told AFP.</p>

<p>For many, the animal safari has added some positivity to their week, as the country reeled following the death of three girls in a stabbing and ensuing violent riots.</p>

<p>Speaking in front of two pelicans painted over a fish shop in Walthamstow, northeast London, Peter McCarthy said it had been "very nice to have it in this particular week".</p>

<p>"Very nice that he's been around the country when there's been such trouble. Doing these wonderful things."</p>

<p><strong>Removed</strong></p>

<p>For others, the choice of animals has meaning, with some finding the goat similar to a Palestinian mountain gazelle and others pointing out the artist's previous work on the climate crisis.</p>

<p>Three of the artworks have already been removed or stolen, and the rhino revealed on Monday was defaced the same day.</p>

<p>A satellite dish painted with the wolf was stolen within hours of being claimed by Banksy, with the cat on a billboard removed by contractors and a police box painted with swimming piranhas removed by the local authority to ensure it was "properly protected".</p>

<p>Speaking in front of the cat on Saturday before it was removed, dentist Mitul Patel said he wished "people would leave his work alone so that other people could enjoy it as well".</p>

<p>Locals and tourists alike have been enjoying the artworks that are still up.</p>

<p>Taking a brief pause from his job, construction worker Owen said the three monkeys in east London's Shoreditch area were "very exciting" and a "big talking point".</p>

<p>Kevin Mazur, a photographer visiting from the US, said he had been "running around photographing all" the artworks, and was "bummed" about having to return to New York.</p>

<p>Retiree Don Gould lives around the corner from the goat in southwest London's Kew Green, and saw the artwork after it was revealed online last week. "It's very good excuse for a stroll on the green and a pint, isn't it?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/90r8isao_banksy-zoo-mural_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The latest mural depicted a gorilla releasing animals from the zoo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-chief-on-giving-shelter-to-some-leaders-of-sheikh-hasinas-party-6331016]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Army Chief On "Giving Shelter" To Some Leaders Of Awami League]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-army-chief-on-giving-shelter-to-some-leaders-of-sheikh-hasinas-party-6331016]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Army Chief Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman on Tuesday disclosed that they have given shelter to some influential people of the ousted Awami League government to prevent any attack or extrajudicial action against them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Army Chief Gen Waker-Uz-Zaman on Tuesday disclosed that they have given shelter to some influential people of the ousted Awami League government to prevent any attack or extrajudicial action against them.</p>

<p>Speaking at Rajshahi Cantonment, where he met with officials of the army, police, and administration, Gen Zaman said they gave shelter to those people irrespective of their party affiliation, opinion and religion, the Daily Star newspaper reported.</p>

<p>"If there is any allegation against them, any case is filed, they will be punished. But of course, we don't want any attack or extrajudicial action (against them). We have given them shelter because of the threat to their lives," he said in response to a query.</p>

<p>His comments came on a day when former law minister Anisul Huq and Salman F Rahman, private industry and investment affairs adviser to the former prime minister Sheikh Hasina, were arrested in Dhaka.</p>

<p>Former foreign minister Hassan Mahmud and ex-state minister Zunaid Ahmed Palak were arrested last week at the Dhaka airport while attempting to flee the country after Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resigned and fled the country following deadly protests against her government.</p>

<p>According to reports, several top leaders and lawmakers of Hasina's Awami League and cabinet ministers have left the country. Several other ministers left their official or private residences and are believed to be hiding in safe places.</p>

<p>Asked about any possibility of a counter-revolution, the army chief said he had no knowledge of it.</p>

<p>Asked about any pressure from foreign nations regarding the situation, he replied in the negative. "... this is a unique situation. Everyone understands it. There has been some discussion over the minority issue. A total of 30 minority-related attacks have taken place in 20 districts," he said.</p>

<p>"We are looking into the incidents. We will bring the criminals to book," he added.</p>

<p>"The situation has become normal. But the police are still in trauma. Once it's over, the police will be able to perform their duties properly again," the army chief said.</p>

<p>"Police have already started working in different police stations. We are giving protection to the police. When they start functioning fully, the situation will become normal. Then we will return to the cantonment," he added.</p>

<p>"We will provide all-out help to the government. The government wants some reform, and to hold a free and fair election. We will provide all sorts of assistance in this regard," he said replying to another query.</p>

<p>The army chief said many looted arms of police have already been recovered. More will be recovered soon more in the days ahead.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ivpbh1rg_bangladesh-police-afp_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-scraps-august-15-national-holiday-marking-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-assassination-6331009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Scraps Aug 15 Holiday Marking Mujibur Rahman's Assassination]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-scraps-august-15-national-holiday-marking-sheikh-mujibur-rahmans-assassination-6331009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:34:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday cancelled a national holiday on August 15, marking the assassination of the country's founder and deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina's father Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's interim government on Tuesday cancelled a national holiday on August 15, marking the assassination of the country's founder and deposed prime minister Sheikh Hasina's father Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman.</p>

<p>According to the press release issued by the Chief Advisor's Office, the cancellation of the August 15 holiday was approved in today's meeting of the Advisory Council.</p>

<p>This decision was announced on Tuesday through an official notification.</p>

<p>The sources said the decision came a day after Mr Yunus met with different political parties, excluding the Awami League. Some of them were in favour of keeping the day as a national holiday and some others were opposed to it.</p>

<p>Soon after Sheikh Hasina resigned and left the country, an angry mob virtually set a museum dedicated to Bangabandhu on fire.</p>

<p>The museum was originally Bangbandhu's private residence, where he was killed along with his family members in a military coup staged by a group of junior officers on August 15, 1975, while Sheikh Hasina, her two minor children, and her younger sister Sheikh Rehana were in Germany on a short visit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/v93gtcog_sheikh-mujibur-rahman_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This decision was announced on Tuesday through an official notification.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norway-man-boards-plane-without-ticket-in-germany-two-days-in-a-row-6331004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Norway Man Boards Plane Without Ticket In Germany For Two Days In A Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/norway-man-boards-plane-without-ticket-in-germany-two-days-in-a-row-6331004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:33:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Norwegian traveller managed to board a plane at Munich airport without a ticket two days in a row -- and even flew to Sweden on the second occasion, police said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Norwegian traveller managed to board a plane at Munich airport without a ticket two days in a row -- and even flew to Sweden on the second occasion, police said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The 39-year-old sneaked past security at Germany's second-busiest airport for the first time on August 4.</p>

<p>Passengers are supposed to scan boarding passes at an automatic gate but he stood close to another traveller and got through without one, the Bild daily reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He then snuck past airline staff at the gate and boarded the plane.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But the aircraft was fully booked and his deception was discovered as he did not have a seat. The man was handed over to police, who charged him but let him go, the paper said.</p>

<p>Undeterred, the Norwegian returned a day later, used the same technique, and boarded a flight to Sweden that was not fully booked, said police spokesman Sebastian Pinta.</p>

<p>However on arrival in Stockholm, he attracted the attention of airport staff as he wanted to return to Munich immediately, and he was handed over to the police.</p>

<p>Pinta insisted the man did not pose any danger.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He is under investigation for unlawful entry and transport fraud, he added.</p>

<p>Munich airport said it was investigating how the man had bypassed security checks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/52gfm0no_airport-passenger-generic_625x300_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man stood close to another traveller to get through without a boarding pass]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-sees-bluetongue-virus-outbreak-with-over-1-800-cases-this-year-6330954]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany Sees Bluetongue Virus Outbreak With Over 1,800 Cases This Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-sees-bluetongue-virus-outbreak-with-over-1-800-cases-this-year-6330954]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 22:23:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany has seen an explosion of cases of bluetongue virus this year, authorities said Tuesday as fears increase across Europe about the disease affecting sheep and cattle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany has seen an explosion of cases of bluetongue virus this year, authorities said Tuesday as fears increase across Europe about the disease affecting sheep and cattle.</p>

<p>The country has registered 1,885 outbreaks of bluetongue virus serotype 3 (BTV-3) since the start of 2024, according to the Friedrich Loeffler Institute, Germany's top animal disease research centre.</p>

<p>During the whole of 2023, there were just 23 outbreaks.</p>

<p>"There has been a real wave since the beginning of July in farms with susceptible animals," a spokeswoman for the institute told AFP.</p>

<p>New cases are being added every day and the number of outbreaks could exceed 2,000 by as soon as Thursday, the spokeswoman said.</p>

<p>The institute was unable to provide information on mortality rates.</p>

<p>Bluetongue is a non-contagious, insect-borne viral disease that affects ruminants such as cows and sheep but not pigs or horses. It is difficult to control once it takes hold.</p>

<p>It is not a risk to humans, but in animals it causes high fevers, mouth ulcers and swollen heads.</p>

<p>Support for farmers in tackling the disease through vaccinations is patchy in Germany as the responsibility falls to local authorities in the country's 16 states.</p>

<p>The first outbreak of BTV-3 was registered in Germany on October 12, 2023, according to the institute.</p>

<p>Since then, other outbreaks have been concentrated in the west and centre of the country, in North Rhine-Westphalia, Rhineland-Palatinate, Hesse and Lower Saxony states.</p>

<p>The government has issued an emergency order to temporarily authorise three BTV-3 vaccines, pending official authorisation from the EU.</p>

<p>Since October 2023, cases of bluetongue have also appeared in other countries including the Netherlands and Belgium.</p>

<p>The disease has also recently hit France, causing alarm among farmers.</p>

<p>BTV-3 is particularly deadly for sheep but can also cause a significant drop in milk production in cows, according to the German institute.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/acum4cvg_bluetongue-virus-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A sheep suffering from bluetongue virus (serotype 8) on a farm in France. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-uses-sniffer-dogs-to-search-for-bedbugs-after-paris-olympics-6330776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Uses Sniffer Dog To Search For Bedbugs After Paris Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-uses-sniffer-dogs-to-search-for-bedbugs-after-paris-olympics-6330776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 21:57:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea said on Tuesday it had deployed its first sniffer dog trained to detect bedbugs to prevent a possible infestation as athletes return from the Paris Olympics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea said on Tuesday it had deployed its first sniffer dog trained to detect bedbugs to prevent a possible infestation as athletes return from the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>South Korea won 32 medals, including 13 golds, to finish eighth overall in the medal standings, and around 140 of its athletes have returned to Seoul over the past week.</p>

<p>The sniffer dog, named Ceco, was deployed at the main airport in Seoul as part of an initiative between the government and South Korea's largest pest control company, Cesco.</p>

<p>Ceco, a two-year-old beagle, is trained to detect the smell of pheromones unique to bedbugs and can locate the blood-sucking pests within two minutes with an accuracy rate of 95 percent, Cesco said in a statement.</p>

<p>"From August 9 to September 8 -- the day the Paralympics concludes -- bedbug detection dog services will be available at Incheon Airport for those who wish to utilise them," said a spokesperson for the Korea Disease Control and Prevention Agency.</p>

<p>The initiative also includes bedbug control experts with more than 10 years experience to help search luggage. Aircraft disinfection has also been increased from once a month to once a week, focusing on the Paris-Incheon route.</p>

<p>South Korea had been largely bedbug-free for years but infestations rose as travel rebounded after the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>More than 950 cases were reported between November and February, official statistics show.</p>

<p>Paris struggled with a bedbug outbreak last year, with a surge of reported sightings sending a shudder through France during the summer and autumn and prompting several school closures.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/04n50c88_south-korea-sniffer-dog-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ceco, a two-year-old beagle, is trained to detect the smell of pheromones unique to bedbugs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-in-first-comments-after-ouster-says-those-involved-in-bangladesh-violence-should-be-investigated-6330434]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Dance Of Destruction In Name Of Protest": Sheikh Hasina Breaks Silence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-in-first-comments-after-ouster-says-those-involved-in-bangladesh-violence-should-be-investigated-6330434]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 21:02:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Hasina, in first comments after ouster, says those involved in Bangladesh violence should be investigated]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ousted Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, in first comments after leaving Dhaka, has sought that rioters in the country be punished. She has also sought justice for the vandalism to the statue of her father, Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, who was also the Founding Father of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>In a three-page emotive statement posted on X by her son Sajeeb Wazed, Sheikh Hasina spoke of the family members she lost when her father was assassinated on August 15, 1975. Mujibur Rahman's sons and their wives, his brother's family, close colleagues and associates, were wiped out the same night by the army as part of a coup. &nbsp;</p>

<p>After paying her respects to them, she turned to the present day, saying the dance of destruction across the country in the name of protest, has also led to many deaths -- of "students teachers, police, journalists, social workers, common people, leaders and workers of the Awami League, pedestrians and office workers".</p>

<p>"For those who have lost their loved ones like me, i extend my deepest sympathy. And for those involved in this slaughter, this destruction, I demand that investigations be held and they be caught and given appropriate punishment," read a rough translation of her statement in Bengali.</p>

<p>The protesters had not only targeted her, they had also targeted the house she grew up in, one that was turned into a museum and was visited by eminent personalities from foreign shores.</p>

<p>"That is now dust... And the memories we had -- that have been reduced to ashes with the disrespect shown to Mujibur Rahman, under whose leadership we got our freedom, recognition, self-respect... the blood shed by thousands of freedom fighters has been desecrated... I demand justice for this from my countrymen," she added.</p>

<p>She added that the coming August 15 be marked as a day of mourning, passed in showing respects and praying for martyrs at "Bangabandhu Bhavan".&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, only 28 when Mujibur Rahman was assassinated, remained in exile from 1975 to late 1980s. While in exile, she rose through the ranks to head the Awami League, the party her father founded, and dived into politics. In 1996, she steered Awami League to victory in the national election, becoming the first woman Prime Minister of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>The wave of student protests that saw her out of office had started weeks ago over quota in government jobs for the families of freedom fighters. But the government's resistance had turned it into demands for Sheikh Hasina's resignation.</p>

<p>As the violence spiked, the army took action, and Sheikh Hasina had to hand in her resignation under a 45-minute ultimatum.</p>

<p>She is currently in India, the next part of her journey still un-announced. But the 76-year-old intends to go back to Bangladesh whenever the elections are held, her son has said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-offers-to-stop-incursion-if-russia-accepts-just-peace-6330383]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Offers To Stop Incursion If Russia Accepts "Just Peace"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-offers-to-stop-incursion-if-russia-accepts-just-peace-6330383]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:59:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine said Tuesday it would not hold on to Russian territory captured in its surprise cross-border incursion and offered to stop raids if Moscow agreed a "just peace".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine said Tuesday it would not hold on to Russian territory captured in its surprise cross-border incursion and offered to stop raids if Moscow agreed a "just peace".</p>

<p>Ukrainian forces entered Russia's Kursk region last Tuesday, taking over two dozen settlements in the biggest attack by a foreign army on Russian soil since World War II. Russia said Tuesday it had fended off new attacks in Kursk.</p>

<p>More than 120,000 people have fled the area and Ukraine's military chief Oleksandr Syrsky said Monday that his troops controlled about 1,000 square kilometres of Russian territory.</p>

<p>At least 800 square kilometres was under Ukrainian control as of Monday, according to an AFP analysis of data from the US-based Institute for the Study of War.</p>

<p>Foreign ministry spokesman Georgiy Tykhy on Tuesday said Kyiv was not interested in "taking over" Russian territory and defended Ukraine's actions as "absolutely legitimate".</p>

<p>"The sooner Russia agrees to restore a just peace... the sooner the raids by the Ukrainian defences forces into Russia will stop," he told reporters.</p>

<p>Ukraine meanwhile said it was imposing movement restrictions in a 20-kilometre zone in Sumy region along the border with Kursk region due to an "increase in the intensity of hostilities" and "sabotage" activities.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said it had "foiled" new Ukrainian attacks in Kursk by "enemy mobile groups in armoured vehicles to break through deep into Russian territory".</p>

<p>Alexander Bortnikov, head of Russia's FSB security service, also said in a statement that Ukraine had carried out the attack "with the support of the collective West".</p>

<p><strong>'I saw a lot of death'</strong></p>

<p>Since launching its invasion in February 2022, Russia has captured territory in southern and eastern Ukraine and subjected Ukrainian cities to missile and drone barrages.</p>

<p>Ukraine's offensive was the biggest cross-border action since the invasion and it caught Russia off guard.</p>

<p>"They didn't protect the border," a Ukrainian serviceman who took part in the offensive and identified himself as Ruzhyk told AFP in Sumy region.</p>

<p>"They only had anti-personnel mines scattered around trees at the side of the road and a few mines that they managed to quickly throw along the highways," he said.</p>

<p>A 27-year-old squad leader, who identified himself as Faraon, was sparing but direct in his description of battles in Kursk.</p>

<p>"I saw a lot of death in the first few days. It was terrifying at first but then we got used to it," he told AFP.</p>

<p>"There have been many deaths," he repeated stood next to a forest road leading to the frontier, without elaborating.</p>

<p>Ukrainian military analyst Mykola Bielieskov told AFP: "Russian complacency prevailed".</p>

<p>"Russia assumed that since it had initiative elsewhere, Ukraine wouldn't dare to do things we've seen," he said, referring to months of Russian advances along the front.</p>

<p>ISW figures also showed that Russian troops had captured 1,360 square kilometres of Ukrainian territory since the start of 2024.</p>

<p><strong>'Sow discord'&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has vowed to "dislodge" Ukrainian troops.</p>

<p>Putin told a televised meeting with officials on Monday that "one of the obvious goals of the enemy is to sow discord" and "destroy the unity and cohesion of Russian society".</p>

<p>Putin also said Ukraine wanted to "improve its negotiating position" for any future talks with Moscow.</p>

<p>Regional governor Alexei Smirnov told the same meeting that Ukrainian forces had entered at least 12 kilometres into the region and the new front was now 40 kilometres wide.</p>

<p>Russia had conceded earlier that Ukrainian forces had penetrated up to 30 kilometres (20 miles) into Russian territory in places.</p>

<p>A Ukrainian security official told AFP, on condition of anonymity, at the weekend, that Ukraine sought to "stretch the positions of the enemy, to inflict maximum losses and to destabilise the situation in Russia as they are unable to protect their own border".</p>

<p>The Ukrainian official said thousands of Ukrainian troops were involved in the operation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a23pp28o_ukraine-army-enters-russia-afp_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Ukrainian military vehicle drives from the direction of the border with people blindfolded.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/auto-workers-body-files-charges-against-trump-musk-heres-why-6330288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Auto Workers' Body Files Charges Against Trump, Musk. Here's Why]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/auto-workers-body-files-charges-against-trump-musk-heres-why-6330288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:42:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Auto Workers Union said on Tuesday it has filed federal labour charges against Donald Trump and Tesla CEO Elon Musk over attempts to threaten and intimidate workers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Auto Workers Union said on Tuesday it has filed federal labour charges against Donald Trump and Tesla CEO Elon Musk over attempts to threaten and intimidate workers.</p>

<p>The action came after Musk and Trump held a two-hour conversation on social media platform X Monday night, during which the two discussed workers walking off the job to go on strike.</p>

<p>"You're the greatest cutter," Trump said during the conversation. "I mean, I look at what you do. You walk in, you just say: 'You want to quit?' They go on strike - I won't mention the name of the company - but they go on strike. And you say: 'That's okay, you're all gone.'"</p>

<p>Under federal law, workers cannot be fired for going on strike, and threatening to do so is illegal under the National Labor Relations Act, the UAW said in its statement.</p>

<p>The UAW has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris in her bid for U.S. president. She met with union officials and workers last week near Detroit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/map7l9ho_trump-musk_650x400_13_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UAW has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris in her bid for U.S. president.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rocket-fired-from-gaza-fell-in-sea-off-tel-aviv-israel-army-6330136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rocket Fired From Gaza Fell In Sea Off Tel Aviv: Israel Army]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rocket-fired-from-gaza-fell-in-sea-off-tel-aviv-israel-army-6330136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:20:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A rocket fired from the war-torn Gaza Strip fell in the sea off Israel's Tel Aviv on Tuesday, Israel's army said, as Hamas militants announced their first attack on the city in months.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rocket fired from the war-torn Gaza Strip fell in the sea off Israel's Tel Aviv on Tuesday, Israel's army said, as Hamas militants announced their first attack on the city in months.</p>

<p>"A short while ago, a projectile that was identified crossing from the Gaza Strip fell in the maritime space in central Israel," an army statement said, as an AFP journalist reported hearing a boom in the city at the same time.</p>

<p>The army added that "simultaneously, an additional projectile that did not cross into Israeli territory was identified".</p>

<p>Hamas armed wing, the Ezzedine Al-Qassam Brigades, said it fired two M90 rockets at Tel Aviv, their first attack on the Israeli commercial hub since May.</p>

<p>"Al-Qassam Brigades bombarded the city of Tel Aviv and its suburbs with two M90 missiles in response to the Zionist massacres against civilians and the deliberate displacement of our people," a statement by the group said.</p>

<p>The attack came with Israel on high alert for an attack by Iran and its proxies following the killings of senior figures from Hamas and Hezbollah, the Lebanese armed group.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/udjca7ho_hamas-attack-on-israel_625x300_26_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack came with Israel on high alert. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthi-rebels-take-over-human-rights-offices-in-yemen-says-un-6330019]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Houthi Rebels Take Over Human Rights Offices In Yemen, Says UN]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/houthi-rebels-take-over-human-rights-offices-in-yemen-says-un-6330019]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 20:09:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations said Tuesday their human rights offices in Sanaa had been taken over by Yemen's Houthi rebels, with the UN's rights chief demanding they leave immediately and return all seized assets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Nations said Tuesday their human rights offices in Sanaa had been taken over by Yemen's Houthi rebels, with the UN's rights chief demanding they leave immediately and return all seized assets.</p>

<p>On August 3, the Iran-backed Houthis sent a delegation to the UN Human Rights Office's premises in Sanaa and forced staff to hand over the keys. They are still in control of the premises, the Geneva-based office said.</p>

<p>"Entering a UN office without permission and seizing documents and property by force are wholly inconsistent with the privileges and immunities of the United Nations," UN rights chief Volker Turk said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This is also a serious attack on the ability of the UN to perform its mandate, including with respect to the promotion and protection of human rights, which my office is there to defend.</p>

<p>"Ansar Allah forces must leave the premises and return all assets and belongings immediately."</p>

<p>The Houthis are engaged in a long-running civil war that has triggered one of the world's worst humanitarian crises. More than half of the population is dependent on aid in the Arabian Peninsula's poorest country.</p>

<p>The rebels seized control of the capital Sanaa in September 2014, prompting a Saudi-led military intervention on behalf of the government the following March.</p>

<p>In June this year, the Houthis detained 13 UN staff, including six employees of the Human Rights Office, plus more than 50 staff from non-governmental organisations, plus an embassy staff member.</p>

<p>The Houthis claimed they had arrested "an American-Israeli spy network" operating under the cover of humanitarian organisations -- allegations emphatically rejected by the UN Human Rights Office.</p>

<p>Two other UN Human Rights staff had already been detained since November 2021 and August 2023 respectively. They are all being held incommunicado.</p>

<p>"I appeal again, with a heavy heart, for their immediate and unconditional release," said Turk.</p>

<p>"It is crucial that the de facto authorities respect the United Nations and its independence, release all detained UN staff immediately, and create conditions in which my office and other UN agencies can continue their critical work for people of Yemen without threats or hinderance."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/7m2ae1j8_huthi-yemen-afp_625x300_19_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Houthis seized control of the capital Sanaa in September 2014. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-declared-public-health-emergency-by-africa-after-massive-outbreak-6329875]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mpox Declared Public Health Emergency By Africa After Massive Outbreak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mpox-declared-public-health-emergency-by-africa-after-massive-outbreak-6329875]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:48:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Africa's top public health body declared what it termed a "public health emergency of continental security" on Tuesday over an outbreak of mpox that spread from the Democratic Republic of Congo to neighbouring countries.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Africa's top public health body declared what it termed a "public health emergency of continental security" on Tuesday over an outbreak of mpox that spread from the Democratic Republic of Congo to neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>Mpox is transmitted through close contact and causes flu-like symptoms and pus-filled lesions. Most cases are mild but it can kill.</p>

<p>The outbreak in Congo began with the spread of an endemic strain, known as Clade I. But the new variant, known as Clade Ib, appears to spread more easily through routine close contact, particularly among children.</p>

<p>The Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) warned last week that the viral infection's rate of spread was alarming.</p>

<p>It said that over 15,000 mpox cases and 461 deaths were reported on the continent this year so far, representing a 160% increase from the same period last year.</p>

<p>Mpox has been endemic in parts of Africa for decades after it was first detected in human in the Democratic Republic of Congo in 1970.</p>

<p>A milder version of the virus spread to over a hundred countries in 2022, largely through sexual contact, prompting the World Health Organization (WHO) to declare a public health emergency of international concern, its highest level of alert.</p>

<p>The WHO ended the emergency 10 months later, saying the health crisis had come under control.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7cp24dfg_mpox-africa-reuters_625x300_13_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The outbreak has swept through several African countries, particularly the Democratic Republic of Congo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laxman-narasimhan-steps-down-as-starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-to-replace-him-6329855]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Laxman Narasimhan Steps Down As Starbucks CEO, Brian Niccol To Replace Him]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/laxman-narasimhan-steps-down-as-starbucks-ceo-brian-niccol-to-replace-him-6329855]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 13 Aug 2024 19:42:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Starbucks said Tuesday that Brian Niccol, chief executive at Chipotle, would be the coffee chain's new CEO -- just over a year after current boss Laxman Narasimhan took over the role.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Starbucks said Tuesday that Brian Niccol, chief executive at Chipotle, would be the coffee chain's new CEO -- just over a year after current boss Laxman Narasimhan took over the role.</p>

<p>Mr Narasimhan steps down as chief executive and as a member of the Starbucks board "with immediate effect," said the company in a statement.</p>

<p>The leadership shifts come as Starbucks pushes to turn around its business, while contending with broad-based sales declines in its most recent financial results.</p>

<p>Starbucks has cited weakening consumer sentiment and difficult market conditions in China as factors in its troubles.</p>

<p>"Brian is a culture carrier who brings a wealth of experience and a proven track record of driving innovation and growth," said Starbucks board chair Mellody Hobson in a statement as the comapny announced the leadership changes.</p>

<p>Niccol has served as Chipotle's CEO since 2018.</p>

<p>In naming him Starbucks' new CEO, the company noted that his work at Chipotle had "driven significant growth and value creation," citing revenue that has nearly doubled and rising profit.</p>

<p>Narasimhan, a veteran of PepsiCo and other consumer brands, had taken over the top spot in 2023 after a period working with longtime Starbucks CEO and interim boss Howard Schultz.</p>

<p>The statement noted that Narasimhan, during his tenure, drove innovation in the brand's supply chains and boosted its store operations.</p>

<p>Niccol will start in his new role on September 9, with Starbucks chief financial officer Rachel Ruggeri serving as interim CEO until then.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-03/esjbkhqo_laxman-narasimhan-starbuckscom_625x300_24_March_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narasimhan, a veteran of PepsiCo and other consumer brands, had taken over the top spot in 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>