<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:09:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-journalist-thrown-off-screen-as-israeli-missile-strikes-during-live-interview-6645562]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Israeli Missile Hits Lebanon Journalist's Home During Live Interview]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-journalist-thrown-off-screen-as-israeli-missile-strikes-during-live-interview-6645562]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:09:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Lebanese journalist sustained injuries when an Israeli missile struck his home while he was conducting a live TV interview. Fadi Boudaya, the editor-in-chief of Miraya International Network, was seen losing his balance and thrown off-screen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Lebanese journalist sustained injuries when an Israeli missile struck his home while he was conducting a live TV interview. Fadi Boudaya, the editor-in-chief of Miraya International Network, was seen losing his balance and thrown off-screen the moment the missile hit his home.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The footage, now viral on social media, showed Boudaya mid-sentence, which quickly turned into a scream when the explosion occurred. Fortunately, he sustained only minor injuries in the incident.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WINDOWS AND WALLS SHATTER AND COLLAPSE ON A JOURNALIST, NEARLY KILLING HIM<br />
<br />
Fadi Boudia,editor of the Maraya International News Network,nearly dies live as IDF missiles attack his home in Beqaa,eastern ????????,just as he begins a Skype interview for a live program in the video above. <a href="https://t.co/ucJls46IGC">pic.twitter.com/ucJls46IGC</a></p>
— Malcolm X (@malcolmx653459) <a href="https://twitter.com/malcolmx653459/status/1838307199073800563?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The journalist, reportedly considered sympathetic towards Hezbollah, later reassured his followers through X. “Thank you to everyone who called, texted, checked in and to everyone who felt any emotion,” he wrote. “Thank God, I am fine, thanks to God and His blessings upon us, and we return to continue our media duty in support of the resistance. Thank you from the bottom of my heart.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="ar">شكراً لكل من اتصل وراسل واطمأنّ، وشكراً لكل من شعر بأية عاطفة.<br />
الحمدلله انا بخير بفضل الله ونعمته علينا، ونعود لمتابعة واجبنا الإعلامي سنداً للمقاومة.<br />
شكراً لكم من القلب</p>
— Fadi Boudaya (@Fadi_Boudaya) <a href="https://twitter.com/Fadi_Boudaya/status/1838523270083010630?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The attack on Fadi Boudaya comes amid escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah, the Iran-backed militant group. Since the Gaza war erupted last October, both sides have been involved in intense cross-border conflict, with recent hostilities reaching new heights.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The situation worsened following a cyber attack on Hezbollah members, during which their communication devices – pagers and walkie-talkies – were targeted. Hezbollah accused Israel of orchestrating the attacks.</p>

<p>On Monday, Israeli airstrikes in Lebanon killed more than 550 people, including 50 children. That evening, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu released a video message, urging Lebanese citizens to evacuate their homes. “Once the operation is finished, they can return to their homes,” he said.&nbsp;<br />
<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OspjXp19h8M?si=gjRJ7KBwAY-6SOPb" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
On Tuesday, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300">Israeli airstrikes in Beirut</a> killed Ibrahim Qubaisi, the head of Hezbollah's missile division. The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) confirmed Qubaisi's death, saying he was a key figure in Hezbollah's missile operations. Alongside Qubaisi, at least two other high-ranking commanders were reportedly killed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The strikes, targeting the Dahiyeh suburb, came amid intense cross-border clashes, with Hezbollah firing over 300 rockets at northern Israeli cities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/19p4cnc8_lebanon-journalist-bomb-during-live-interview-_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack on Fadi Boudaya comes amid escalating tensions between Israel and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-new-zealand-on-chinas-rare-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-test-serious-concern-6645603]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Serious Concern": Japan, New Zealand As China Conducts Rare Missile Test]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-new-zealand-on-chinas-rare-intercontinental-ballistic-missile-test-serious-concern-6645603]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 14:02:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China test-launched an intercontinental ballistic missile on Wednesday, firing it into the Pacific Ocean in its first such exercise in decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China said it test-launched an intercontinental ballistic missile on Wednesday, firing it into the Pacific Ocean in its first such exercise in decades. The launch sparked protests from other countries in the region, with China's neighbour Japan saying it had not been given advance notice and expressing "serious concern" about Beijing's military build-up.</p>

<p>Beijing has stepped up its nuclear development and boosted defence spending in recent years, with the Pentagon last October warning China was developing its arsenal more quickly than the United States had anticipated.</p>

<p>China held more than 500 operational nuclear warheads as of May 2023 and is likely to have more than 1,000 by 2030, it said.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, the Chinese military's Rocket Force "launched an ICBM... carrying a dummy warhead to the high seas in the Pacific Ocean at 08:44 on September 25, and the missile fell into expected sea areas", the defence ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>An analyst told AFP such tests were very rare.</p>

<p>"This is extremely unusual and likely the first time in decades that we've seen a test like this," said Ankit Panda, Stanton Senior Fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.</p>

<p>"(The test) likely speaks to China's ongoing nuclear modernisation manifesting in new requirements for testing," he added.</p>

<h3>'Serious concern'</h3>

<p>China's defence ministry, however, called the firing a "routine arrangement in our annual training plan".</p>

<p>"It is in line with international law and international practice and is not directed against any country or target," it said.</p>

<p>Japan, however, said it was given "no notice from the Chinese side in advance", with a government spokesman adding that Beijing's military build-up was a "serious concern".</p>

<p>New Zealand also said the launch of the missile, which landed in the South Pacific, was "an unwelcome and concerning development".</p>

<p>A spokesman for Wellington's foreign minister vowed to consult with Pacific allies further as details become clear.</p>

<p>Beijing first test-fired an ICBM into the South Pacific in the 1980s.</p>

<p>But since then, Panda told AFP, it has typically conducted such tests in its own airspace.</p>

<p>In 2021, the United States said it was "very concerned" about reported hypersonic missile testing by China.</p>

<h3><strong>Third-largest stockpile</strong></h3>

<p>The United States and China in November held rare talks on nuclear arms control, part of a bid to ease mistrust ahead of a summit between leaders Joe Biden and Xi Jinping.</p>

<p>But in July, Beijing said it had suspended negotiations with the United States on nuclear non-proliferation and arms control in response to Washington's weapons sales to Taiwan.</p>

<p>In an annual report, the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI) listed China as having the world's third-largest stockpile of nuclear warheads, after Russia and the United States.</p>

<p>This year, Beijing announced it would increase its defence budget -- the world's second-largest -- by 7.2 percent.</p>

<p>The boost comes as China increasingly squares off with the United States and its regional partners from the South China Sea to Taiwan.</p>

<p>This month, senior military officials from China and the United States held "in-depth" talks as part of a bid by the powers to avoid wider tensions escalating into conflict.</p>

<p>Since its first atomic test in 1964, China has been content to maintain a comparatively modest arsenal and has maintained that it would never be the first to use nuclear weapons in a conflict.</p>

<p>In recent years, under President Xi, it has begun a massive military modernisation drive that includes upgrading its nuclear weapons to not only deter foes but also be able to counter-attack.</p>

<p>But Beijing's secretive Rocket Force, which carried out Wednesday's test and oversees the country's nuclear arsenal, has also been the target of an aggressive, wide-ranging anti-graft campaign.</p>

<p>In July, Beijing announced that Sun Jinming, the former chief of staff of the force, had been placed under investigation for corruption.</p>

<p>Its head, Li Yuchao, was replaced last July.</p>

<p>And Li Shangfu was ousted last year after only seven months as defence minister following a lengthy absence from public view.</p>

<p>Other disgraced generals include Wei Fenghe, who once headed the Rocket Force and who later became China's defence minister from 2018 to 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9glcm1n_china-missile_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sandwiched-between-india-and-china-6645383]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Don't Want To Be Sandwiched...": New Lanka President's India-China Plans]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sandwiched-between-india-and-china-6645383]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:34:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake - Sri Lanka's new Marxist President - has said he wants to avoid being "sandwiched" between India and China but recognises each as a "valued partner", as he tries to resolve a financial crisis roiling his country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/anura-kumara-dissanayake" target="_blank">Anura Kumara Dissanayake</a> - Sri Lanka's new Marxist President - has said he wants to avoid being "sandwiched" between India and China but recognises each as a "valued partner", as he tries to resolve a financial crisis that has roiled his country since 2019 and led to a sovereign default in April 2022.</p>

<p>The former grassroots leader made it clear he intends to steer clear of geopolitical rumblings in South Asia or the Indian Ocean region. He acknowledged that each can provide much-needed financial aid but said he also wanted closer ties with the West, the Middle East, and even Africa.</p>

<p>The remarks were made in an interview with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://monocle.com/shop/product/2546171/issue-176/" target="_blank">The Monocle</a>, a global affairs and lifestyle magazine, in early September (before his election win was confirmed), in which he spoke about his foreign policy.</p>

<p>"There are many power camps within a multipolar system... but we won't be part of that geopolitical fight, nor will we be aligned with any party. We also don't want to be sandwiched, especially between China and India. Both are valued friends and we expect them to become closer partners."</p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake, 55, a previously fringe Left leader, was catapulted into the limelight after winning the presidential election; he pulled over 42 per cent of the votes.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-elections-marxist-leader-anura-kumara-dissanayaka-wins-sri-lankas-presidential-elections-6625013" target="_blank">Marxist Leader Anura Dissanayake Wins Sri Lanka's Prez Polls</a></p>

<p>Rumoured close ties to China raised eyebrows, particularly in Delhi, which expressed concerns over Beijing's growing influence on Sri Lanka, which sits on key shipping lanes in the Indian Ocean. Added to that, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/diplomacy/article/3279800/sri-lanka-seek-maximum-support-china-under-new-leader-dissanayake-analysts-say" target="_blank">South China Morning Post</a> claimed Beijing expects Dissanayake will seek "maximum support" via foreign direct investment.</p>

<p>That report cited an economics professor from the University of Colombo as saying it is "highly probable" Mr Dissanayake would prefer to work with Beijing over Delhi.</p>

<p>However, Mr Dissanayake has, publicly at least, sought to reassure both Delhi and the United States, which too is wary of China's growing influence.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-rise-of-anura-kumara-dissanayake-sri-lankas-new-president-6628769" target="_blank">The Rise Of Lanka's Anura Dissanayake From Grassroots To President</a></p>

<p>Speaking to an Indian publication on voting day (on Saturday), Mr Dissanayake said India is "crucial" to his country's hopes for economic stability and regional security.</p>

<p>"We will consider how our economic measures impact our country (while) recognising the importance of India's support in our development efforts," he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theweek.in/news/world/2024/09/24/dont-want-to-be-sandwiched-between-india-china-sri-lankan-president-anura-on-his-foreign-policy.html" target="_blank">The Week</a>.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi has spoken to Mr Dissanayake, stating he looks forward to working closely with him to further strengthen the Indo-Lanka multifaceted cooperation. Mr Modi's post on X also contained a reference to Colombo's "special place" in Delhi's Neighbourhood First policy.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-congratulates-anura-dissanayake-for-victory-in-sri-lankan-presidential-poll-6626358" target="_blank">PM Congratulates Dissanayake For Victory In Sri Lankan Polls</a></p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake responded, "I share your commitment... Together, we can work towards enhancing cooperation for the benefit of our peoples and the entire region."</p>

<p>The Sri Lankan leader also played down fears - expressed by both Delhi and Washington - his country would become a military base for Beijing; as recently as last month three Chinese Navy ships were berthed at Colombo Port, at the same time as India's front-line warship, INS Mumbai, docked.</p>

<p>"We are committed to maintaining our sovereignty and will not become subordinate to any power in this geopolitical race..." Mr Dissanayake said this month.</p>

<p>Delhi has played a key role - recognised by the International Monetary Fund, which has provided a $3 billion bailout programme - in guiding Colombo through the ongoing financial crisis, having provided aid - food, medicines, fuel, etc., - worth nearly $4 billion since the storm broke.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/imf-to-work-with-sri-lankas-new-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-on-3-billion-loan-6635752" target="_blank">IMF To Work With Sri Lanka's New President On $3 Billion Loan</a></p>

<p>Mr Dissanayake, however, has said he will try to renegotiate the IMF's loan conditions, some of which led to tax hikes and spending cuts, which many in Colombo said actually exacerbated the cost-of-living crisis that sparked the violent protests of 2019 and 2020. Reviewing the debt plan, though, risks delaying additional loans he needs to meet fiscal criteria before more funds are released.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b7jfm6hs_sri-lankan-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-reuters_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake won Sri Lanka's first presidential polls since the financial crisis (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-117-freed-70-dead-but-fate-of-64-hostages-still-held-in-gaza-unknown-6645229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[117 Freed, 70 Dead, But Fate Of 64 Hostages Still Held In Gaza Unknown]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-117-freed-70-dead-but-fate-of-64-hostages-still-held-in-gaza-unknown-6645229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:12:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For Hamas, the hostages are key bargaining chips to negotiate a truce with Israel and seek the release of Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Hamas militants staged the worst-ever attack on Israel, they took back into the Gaza Strip 251 hostages, some of them already dead. A year later, 64 people, including two children, are still in captivity and Israel believes they are alive.</p>

<p>For the Palestinian militant group that rules the Gaza Strip, the hostages are key bargaining chips to negotiate a truce with Israel and seek the release of Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Here is what we know about the hostages still held in Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>52 men, 10 women, two children</strong></h3>

<p>Of the 251 hostages seized by militants on October 7, 2023, 117 have been freed, most of them women, children and foreign workers.</p>

<p>Most were released during a week-long truce in late November in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners held in Israeli jails.</p>

<p>Nearly a year later, Israel believes 64 hostages still held in Gaza are alive.</p>

<p>The army has confirmed 70 others are dead, 33 of whose bodies are still in Gaza.</p>

<p>The military has repatriated the bodies of 37 hostages who either died in Gaza or were killed on October 7 and taken to the territory.</p>

<p>Of the 64 thought to be alive, 57 are Israelis, though some of them have more than one nationality. Another six are Thai nationals and one is Nepalese.</p>

<p>Fifty-two are men and 10 are women. Eleven are military personnel.</p>

<p>Two are children.</p>

<p>The youngest hostage, Kfir, was just eight-and-a-half months old when he was kidnapped. The other is his brother Ariel, who was only four years old when he was taken to Gaza.</p>

<p>Hamas has said the two children are dead, but Israel has not confirmed this.</p>

<h3><strong>No proof of life</strong></h3>

<p>Since the truce ended on December 1, only seven other hostages have been freed alive, all during Israeli military operations.</p>

<p>With no proof of life, uncertainty remains over whether the 64 are still alive.</p>

<p>The armed wing of Hamas said on August 12 that its fighters had shot and killed an Israeli hostage and injured two others.</p>

<p>Hamas has announced on several occasions deaths of hostages that have not been confirmed by Israel, leaving families in agonising limbo.</p>

<h3><strong>Bodies taken to Gaza</strong></h3>

<p>On October 7, Hamas militants took several dead back into Gaza with them, including 10 Israeli soldiers' bodies.</p>

<p>At least 28 other hostages have died in the territory since the start of the war.</p>

<p>Three were killed in error by the Israeli army on December 15, 2023. They were Yotam Haim, 28, Samer El-Talalqa and Alon Shamriz, 26.</p>

<p>The Israeli army accuses Hamas of executing six others in August: Hersh Goldberg-Polin, Carmel Gat, Eden Yerushalmi, Alexander Lobonov, Almog Sarusi and Ori Danino.</p>

<p>They were found dead by soldiers in a tunnel in Rafah, in southern Gaza.</p>

<h3><strong>Festival, kibbutz survivors</strong></h3>

<p>Most of the hostages were taken during the attack on the Nir Oz kibbutz and on the Nova music festival.</p>

<p>At Nir Oz kibbutz, of the at least 76 hostages taken on October 7, 40 were released alive. Another 20 are still in Gaza and believed to be alive. The remaining 16 are dead.</p>

<p>Only 17 people abducted from the festival are thought to be alive and still being held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Only nine of at least 43 hostages taken from Nova have been released, while 17 others have died.</p>

<h3><strong>Whole families</strong></h3>

<p>On October 7, whole families were taken to Gaza. For them, the November 2023 truce brought relief but also the heartache of leaving loved ones behind.</p>

<p>French-Israeli children Eitan, Erez and Sahar were freed but their fathers Ohad Yahalomi and Ofer Kalderon are still being held.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nutnuvbg_israel-hamas-war_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmers-faux-pas-goes-viral-i-call-for-return-of-sausages-6645103]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['I Call For Return Of Sausages From Gaza': UK PM's Faux Pas Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmers-faux-pas-goes-viral-i-call-for-return-of-sausages-6645103]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:54:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[UK PM Keir Starmer's slip of the tongue came while he was speaking at the Labour Party conference in Liverpool, as he meant to say "hostages".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video of UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer calling on Hamas to return "the sausages" as he urged a peaceful solution to the Gaza war with Israel went viral on Tuesday. Starmer's slip of the tongue came while he was speaking at the Labour Party conference in Liverpool, northwest England, as he meant to say "hostages".</p>

<p>Having first called for "restraint and de-escalation at the border between Lebanon and Israel", Starmer moved on to the Gaza conflict.</p>

<p>"I call again for an immediate ceasefire in Gaza, the return of the sausages," he said, before quickly correcting himself with "the hostages" as applause rang out around the conference hall.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">? NEW: Keir Starmer calls for the ‘return of the sausages' in Gaza, before correcting to ‘hostages'<a href="https://t.co/T71PHGKh6m">pic.twitter.com/T71PHGKh6m</a></p>
— Politics UK (@PolitlcsUK) <a href="https://twitter.com/PolitlcsUK/status/1838572221461062107?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"And a recommitment to the two-state solution, a recognised Palestinian state alongside a safe and secure Israel," he continued.</p>

<p>Almost as soon as the words had left Starmer's mouth, the video went viral on X and by Tuesday evening it was the second most shared content.</p>

<p>British media were quick to jump on Starmer's mistake, with the left-wing Guardian calling it a "gaffe" and the right-wing Daily Mail noting a "faux-pas".</p>

<p>Starmer was referring to the nearly year-long war that broke out after the attack by Hamas militants on Israel on October 7 last year and the Israeli ground invasion of Gaza that followed.</p>

<p>Recent escalation has seen Israel and the Lebanese militant group Hezbollah move to the brink of all-out war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r20darb8_keir-starmer_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer during his speech on the third day of the annual Labour Party conference in Liverpool]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran-moves-were-already-made-6644974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Moves Were Already Made": Trump Claims "Big Threats" On His Life By Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran-moves-were-already-made-6644974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:35:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Trump's campaign team said in a statement Tuesday that US intelligence had warned the former president of "real and specific" threats from Iran to assassinate him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump said Wednesday there were "big threats" on his life posed by Iran after the Republican presidential candidate's campaign team said US intelligence warned him of "real and specific" threats from Tehran.</p>

<p>"Big threats on my life by Iran. The entire US Military is watching and waiting," Trump wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p>

<p>"Moves were already made by Iran that didn't work out, but they will try again. I am surrounded by more men, guns, and weapons than I have ever seen before," he said, following increased scrutiny of the US Secret Service since two attempts on Trump's life this year.</p>

<p>Trump's campaign team said in a statement Tuesday that US intelligence had warned the former president of "real and specific" threats from Iran to assassinate him.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear if the threats referred to by the campaign and Trump himself were new or threats that have previously been reported.</p>

<p>"President Trump was briefed earlier today by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence regarding real and specific threats from Iran to assassinate him in an effort to destabilize and sow chaos in the United States," campaign communications director Steven Cheung said in the statement.</p>

<p>"Intelligence officials have identified that these continued and coordinated attacks have heightened in the past few months, and law enforcement officials across all agencies are working to ensure President Trump is protected and the election is free from interference," he added.</p>

<p>The campaign did not elaborate on the claims, which come as world leaders scramble to try to avert hostilities between Iran-backed Hezbollah and Israel escalating into a wider regional war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Iran has rejected accusations that it is trying to kill Trump this summer, shortly after a gunman opened fire at a rally in Pennsylvania, killing one person and wounding the presidential candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Days after the July 13 assassination attempt, US media reported that authorities had received intelligence on an alleged Iranian plot against the Republican, prompting his protection to be boosted. Iran rejected the "malicious" accusations.</p>

<p>"If they do 'assassinate President Trump,' which is always a possibility, I hope that America obliterates Iran, wipes it off the face of the Earth -- If that does not happen, American Leaders will be considered 'gutless' cowards!" Trump wrote on his social media platform, Truth Social, at the time.</p>

<h3><strong>Iranian cyberattackers</strong></h3>

<p>US intelligence agencies have also accused Iran of a hack targeting Trump's campaign, alleging Tehran is seeking to influence the 2024 election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A joint statement from the US Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency this month said Iranian cyberattackers had offered "stolen, non-public" material from Trump's campaign to staff for his then-White House rival, President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>"Foreign actors are increasing their election influence activities" as Election Day in November approaches, the statement said, singling out Russia, Iran and China as "trying by some measure to exacerbate divisions in US society for their own benefit."</p>

<p>The US agencies said the Iranian cyberattackers had also attempted to share the information stolen from the Trump campaign with US media organizations. It did not name the outlets.</p>

<p>Iran has also vehemently denied those accusations.</p>

<p>The campaign of Trump's presidential election rival, Democrat Kamala Harris, said on August 13 that it too had been targeted by foreign hackers, but did not give an indication of which country was believed to be behind the attempt.</p>

<p>Americans cast their ballots on November 5. Polls show Trump and Harris, who launched her campaign after Biden dropped out earlier this summer, are neck and neck.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6amhn82_moves-were-already-made-trump-claims-big-threats-on-his-life-by-iran_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunshots-fired-at-harris-campaign-office-in-arizona-2nd-time-in-two-weeks-6644963]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunshots Fired At Harris' Campaign Office In Arizona, 2nd Time In Two Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunshots-fired-at-harris-campaign-office-in-arizona-2nd-time-in-two-weeks-6644963]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:32:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At the time of the incident, the Democratic campaign office in Tempe, located just east of Phoenix in Arizona, was unoccupied and nobody was injured in the attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Multiple gunshots were fired at a campaign office of US Vice President Kamala Harris in Arizona, police said. The gunshot damage from several bullets, believed to have been fired sometime after midnight on Monday, was discovered at the Democratic campaign office near Southern Avenue and Priest Drive in Tempe, the city police told The New York Post.<br />
<br />
“No one was inside the office during the overnight hours, but this raises concerns about the safety of those who work in that building, as well as those nearby,” Public Information Officer Ryan Cook said.<br />
<br />
According to the Tempe Police Department, the matter is currently being looked upon as a potential property crime. In footage aired by the local TV stations, two bullet holes were seen in a door, while two others were in windows of the office.<br />
<br />
Currently, the investigators are analysing the evidence collected from the party office, while additional measures have been taken to tighten the security of the staff members and others in the area, police said.<br />
Shockingly, this was the second time criminal damage was reported at the property in as many weeks.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Earlier, the front windows of the office were shot by what appeared to be a BB gun or pellet gun, just after midnight on September 16. So far, no arrests have been made in either incident, while the authorities investigate all possible angles and motives.<br />
<br />
In a statement, Sean McEnerney, the Arizona Democratic Party coordinated campaign manager, thanked the city police for swiftly taking action on the matter.<br />
<br />
“We are grateful to Tempe Police for coming quickly to the scene and are fortunate no one was present or injured,” McEnerney said.</p>

<h3><strong>Kamala Harris' Arizona visit</strong></h3>

<p>The twin shootings at the local campaign office of the party took place days before US Vice President Kamala Harris was scheduled to touch down in Arizona, a key battleground state in the November 5 presidential election in the US.<br />
<br />
As per reports, Harris will campaign across the Grand Canyon State during her visit.<br />
<br />
Further, sources told The New York Times that Harris plans to visit the US-Mexico border on Friday, seeking to counter Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump's advantage with voters on the immigration issue.</p>

<h3><strong>Assassination attempt on Trump</strong></h3>

<p>The alleged attack on the local campaign office in Arizona comes on the heels of the second assassination attempt on former US president Donald Trump at his West Palm Beach golf course on September 15.<br />
<br />
Ryan Routh, the gunman, was uncovered by a Secret Service agent, who spotted the muzzle of a rifle sticking out of the bushes. The agent fired before Routh had the chance to fire a single shot. Soon after, Routh allegedly dropped his rifle and fled in a car, but was arrested in 40 minutes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/if09613_kamala-harris_625x300_25_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/naomi-seibt-best-ride-of-my-life-influencer-praises-self-driving-tesla-cab-elon-musk-reacts-6644904]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Best Ride": Influencer Praises Self- Driving Tesla Cab, Elon Musk Reacts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/naomi-seibt-best-ride-of-my-life-influencer-praises-self-driving-tesla-cab-elon-musk-reacts-6644904]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:25:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The video, which has taken social media by storm with over 86,000 views, caught the eye of Tesla CEO Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>German YouTuber Naomi Seibt has shared on microblogging website x (formerly known as Twitter) that she had experienced a truly unforgettable Uber ride when her Tesla car arrived to pick her up. The experience, which Naomi described in words as the "best of her life," was made special by having a chance to ride in the self-driving car mode.</p>

<p>According to Seibt, it felt surreal and revolutionary to be riding in such advanced technology. She went so far as to predict that self-driving technology will dramatically change the future of driving.</p>

<p>She shared her excitement on X in a video clip, detailing the conversation with the driver about the car's progress and her awe at the futuristic technology.</p>

<p>"Self-driving Tesla first experience. Best Uber ride of my life: I got to witness first-hand how the new Tesla manages to manoeuvre around obstacles and steer the wheel automatically. This technology will revolutionise the market; no one can come close. Respect, Elon Musk," she captioned the video.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:&nbsp;</strong><br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">SELF-DRIVING TESLA FIRST EXPERIENCE❗️<br />
<br />
Best Uber ride of my life: I got to witness first-hand how the new Tesla manages to maneuver around obstacles and steer the wheel automatically.<br />
<br />
This technology will revolutionize the market, no one can come close. Respect, <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@elonmusk</a>! <a href="https://t.co/CuMJtdsVbU">pic.twitter.com/CuMJtdsVbU</a></p>
— Naomi Seibt (@SeibtNaomi) <a href="https://twitter.com/SeibtNaomi/status/1838452360839942397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The video, which has garnered over 86,000 views and gone viral on social media, even caught the attention of Tesla CEO Elon Musk. He responded to Seibt's post with one word, "Yup," seemingly agreeing with her prediction of self-driving technology revolutionizing the future of driving.</p>

<p>"Glad you never gave up. Inspired me to fight through hard times myself instead of choosing the safe route," she said in a reply to Tesla chief Elon Musk.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/8modlhmo_naomi-seibt_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The German YouTuber looked fascinated with Tesla's ability to manoeuvre through traffic.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-conflict-hezbollah-fires-ballistic-missile-at-mossad-base-near-tel-aviv-6644843]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Fires Ballistic Missile Targeting Mossad Base Near Tel Aviv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-israel-conflict-hezbollah-fires-ballistic-missile-at-mossad-base-near-tel-aviv-6644843]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:15:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is the first time the group has claimed a ballistic missile strike since its nearly year-long battle with Israel began after Hamas carried out its October 7 attack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah said Wednesday it had fired a ballistic missile targeting Israeli spy agency Mossad's headquarters near Tel Aviv, saying that recent attacks on the militant group had been planned there. It is the first time the group has claimed a ballistic missile strike since its nearly year-long battle with Israel began after Hamas carried out its October 7 attack.</p>

<p>Earlier Wednesday, Israel's military had said it intercepted a missile fired from Lebanon after sirens sounded in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"The Islamic Resistance launched a 'Qader 1' ballistic missile at 6:30 am (0330 GMT) on Wednesday, 25-9-2024, targeting the Mossad headquarters in the outskirts of Tel Aviv," Hezbollah said in a statement.</p>

<p>"This headquarters is responsible for the assassination of leaders and the explosion of pagers and wireless devices," it added, referring to attacks last week that killed scores in Lebanon including a top commander.</p>

<p>It also said the strike was carried out in support of the people of Gaza and "in defence of Lebanon and its people".</p>

<p>Longtime foes Hezbollah and Israel have been locked in near-daily exchanges of cross-border fire since Palestinian militant group Hamas launched an unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7.</p>

<p>The Hamas attack sparked a war in Gaza that has drawn in Hezbollah and other Iran-backed militants from across the Middle East.</p>

<p>The focus of Israel's firepower has shifted sharply from Gaza to Lebanon in recent days.</p>

<p>The Lebanese health ministry said Israeli strikes killed at least 558 people on Monday -- the deadliest day of violence in the country since its 1975-90 civil war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mlvgfkqo_israel-hezbollah_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's military said it intercepted a missile fired from Lebanon]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indian-origin-founder-unveils-wearable-device-that-records-every-moment-of-your-life-6644793]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Founder Unveils Wearable Device That Records Your Entire Life]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/indian-origin-founder-unveils-wearable-device-that-records-every-moment-of-your-life-6644793]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:07:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Paliwal explained that Iris not only organises the photos into a timeline but also uses AI to generate captions and help users recall forgotten details.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Advait Paliwal, an Indian-origin entrepreneur, has recently introduced a wearable AI device called Iris, designed to provide users with "infinite memory." According to Paliwal, the device captures "pictures every minute," which are stored either on the device or in the cloud, allowing users to preserve life's small moments and recognize patterns often overlooked.</p>

<p>In a series of tweets, Mr Paliwal, who is based in San Francisco, explained that Iris not only organises the photos into a timeline but also uses AI to generate captions and help users recall forgotten details. Additionally, the device features a "focus mode," which detects when the wearer is distracted and offers reminders to refocus.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I built Iris, a wearable that gives you infinite memory of your life.<br />
<br />
It takes a picture every minute, captions and organizes them into a timeline, and uses AI to help you remember forgotten details.<br />
<br />
Iris also has a focus mode. It notices when you get distracted and proactively… <a href="https://t.co/fQxzpBRmIA">pic.twitter.com/fQxzpBRmIA</a></p>
— Advait Paliwal (@advaitpaliwal) <a href="https://twitter.com/advaitpaliwal/status/1838621207882797501?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p><em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://advaitpaliwal.notion.site/Iris-d05b5e2cfe4b4314b8732c73d24e2397">Mr Paliwal</a></em> shared that the design of Iris is inspired by the evil eye symbol. He developed the device over the summer at the Augmentation Lab in Cambridge, part of a two-month AI and hardware talent accelerator program. After the program, Mr Paliwal presented Iris to over 250 attendees at the MIT Media Lab, where he received positive feedback, with many expressing interest in owning the device.</p>

<p>Highlighting its potential, Mr Paliwal suggested that Iris could offer safety and health benefits, such as aiding doctors in understanding patients' daily habits or ensuring workplace safety compliance. In elderly care, the device could help caregivers monitor patients without being intrusive.</p>

<p>However, after Mr Paliwal shared his post on X (formerly Twitter), reactions were mixed. While some users expressed excitement, others raised privacy concerns. One person commented, "It's an interesting concept, but I wouldn't want to interact with someone wearing this, taking a photo every minute." Paliwal responded by pointing out that people are already "constantly taking mental photos."</p>

<p>Others were more enthusiastic, with one user noting, "I've been searching for a device like this for years! A picture every minute should be enough if it archives, organizes, labels, and retrieves them." Another user praised the concept, saying, "Love the idea. The design and name are perfect. Great work!"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nmmiu87_advait-paliwal_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Paliwal shared that the design of Iris is inspired by the evil eye symbol.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-on-viral-picture-with-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-goes-viral-6644695]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Is Musk "Dating" Meloni? What He Said On Viral Pic With Italy PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-on-viral-picture-with-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-goes-viral-6644695]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:51:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk and Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni recently met at an event in New York.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A picture of billionaire Elon Musk with Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni at a recent event has gone viral, triggering social media reactions that the two were "dating".</p>

<p>At an award ceremony in New York on Tuesday, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-calls-italy-pm-giorgia-meloni-authentic-honest-at-awards-gala-6636979" target="_blank">Musk also praised Meloni</a>, calling her "authentic, honest and truthful".</p>

<p>Musk, while bestowing the Atlantic Council Global Citizen Award on Meloni, said it was an honour to present the accolade to "someone who is even more beautiful on the inside than she was on the outside."</p>

<p>"Giorgia Meloni is someone I admire, who has done an incredible job as the Prime Minister of Italy," he said.</p>

<p>"She's also someone who is authentic, honest, truthful - and that can't always be said about politicians," Musk added.</p>

<p>She also took to her official X account and thanked Musk for his remarks.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Grazie Elon <a href="https://t.co/NgHchWLUtB">pic.twitter.com/NgHchWLUtB</a></p>
— Giorgia Meloni (@GiorgiaMeloni) <a href="https://twitter.com/GiorgiaMeloni/status/1838555335356817836?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A Tesla fan club then posted a picture of Musk and Meloni and wrote, "Do you think they'll date?." The 53-year-old billionaire responded saying that they are "not dating".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are not dating</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1838727329180205304?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meloni received the award "for her strong support of the EU and becoming the first female prime minister of Italy," according to a media package distributed by the Atlantic Council.</p>

<p>She was in New York with leaders from more than 190 other nations for the annual high-level meeting of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-pleads-for-democracy-in-his-final-united-nations-speech-6642317">United Nations General Assembly</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9gva9p08_elon-musk-giorgia-meloni_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk with Giorgia Meloni at an event in New York.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-suspect-ryan-rouths-son-oran-alexander-routh-arrested-in-child-sex-abuse-case-6644049]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Assassination Suspect's Son Arrested In Child Sex Abuse Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-assassination-suspect-ryan-rouths-son-oran-alexander-routh-arrested-in-child-sex-abuse-case-6644049]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:42:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of Ryan Routh, who is accused of plotting to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump at his golf course, has been arrested on charges of possessing child pornography.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of Ryan Routh, who is accused of plotting to assassinate Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump at his golf course, has been arrested on charges of possessing child pornography. Oran Alexander Routh has been charged with one count of receipt of child pornography and another count of possession of child pornography, NBC News reported.</p>

<p>Records at a district court showed Oran Routh was arrested on Tuesday, while there was no attorney listed for him. As per public reports, Oran is the son of Ryan Routh, who is believed to have hatched the plot to target the former US president at his golf club in West Palm Beach, Florida, on September 15.</p>

<p><strong>'Hundreds' of files uncovered</strong></p>

<p>An FBI search was carried out at Oran's home in North Carolina on Saturday in connection with an unrelated case, as per the criminal complaint.&nbsp;An SD card found in a phone in his bedroom allegedly contained "hundreds" of files having child sex abuse images.</p>

<p>The files include videos from a "known" series. It includes videos of an adult man with a "prepubescent" girl, believed to be under the age of 10, the complaint states.</p>

<p>Another handset, recovered from Oran Routh's possession, had a downloaded folder with additional video files. A review of the device uncovered a video of an adult woman with a child, aged around 6-8 years.</p>

<p>Further, investigating officers also uncovered a messaging app on the smartphone which is "commonly used by individuals who distribute and receive child pornography."</p>

<p>According to the complaint, the individual, who sent the messages from the handset asked for a preview of digital content being sold. Later, two files were shared and both included adults engaging in sexual activities with minors.</p>

<p>The warrant for Oran's arrest was filed in the federal court on Monday, the NBC News report states.</p>

<p><strong>Cocaine, MDMA, Ketamine seized</strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Oran Routh has also been charged with drug possession as the law enforcement officers seized cocaine, Ketamine and MDMA along with gold and black trays having white powdery substance from his house.</p>

<p>It further prompted two felony and two misdemeanour charges for possession, records show.</p>

<p><strong>Case against Ryan Routh</strong></p>

<p>On Tuesday, US prosecutors charged Ryan Routh with the attempt to kill Donald Trump, according to the US Department of Justice. He has also been charged with possession of a firearm in furtherance of a crime of violence, assaulting a Secret Service agent among others.</p>

<p>He is currently in custody and faces a maximum of life in prison if found convicted in the case.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/iof8givc_arrest-generic_625x300_30_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Records at a district court showed Oran Routh was arrested on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/dr-jay-varma-fired-from-job-after-revelations-of-pandemic-era-sex-parties-6644220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin New York Health Adviser Fired Over Drug-Fuelled Sex Party]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/dr-jay-varma-fired-from-job-after-revelations-of-pandemic-era-sex-parties-6644220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:29:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[DrJay Varma, the former COVID-19 czar of New York City, has been fired from his position at SIGA Technologies following the revelation of his involvement in drug-fuelled sex parties during the pandemic.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dr Jay Varma, the former COVID-19 czar of New York City, has been fired from his position at SIGA Technologies following the revelation of his involvement in drug-fuelled sex parties during the pandemic. Dr Varma's NYC COVID policies drew national attention when Brooklyn Nets' Kyrie Irving was banned from playing for refusing vaccination.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Varma, who previously served as a senior health adviser under former Mayor Bill de Blasio, was reported to have boasted about attending underground raves and hosting parties while the city was under severe lockdowns. These admissions were made public through secretly recorded conversations.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING: Former NYC Covid Czar Held Secret Drug-Fueled Sex Parties During Global Pandemic; Says New Yorkers Would Have Been “Pissed” If They Found Out Because He Was Running Entire Covid Response For City<br />
<br />
Dr. Jay Varma, Former Senior Adviser for Public Health, NYC Mayor's… <a href="https://t.co/YrgniDUdFc">pic.twitter.com/YrgniDUdFc</a></p>
— Steven Crowder (@scrowder) <a href="https://twitter.com/scrowder/status/1836737026281836727?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>On September 23, SIGA Technologies issued a <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/23/us-news/ex-nyc-covid-czar-jay-varma-fired-from-job-after-sex-party-scandal/ ">statement</a> confirming Dr Varma's immediate termination, stating, “Pursuant to the terms of his employment agreement, Dr Varma's service on the Company's Board of Directors also automatically ended effective immediately”.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The scandal erupted last week when podcaster Steven Crowder released clips of Dr Varma's candid discussions, in which he said, “I did all this deviant, like sexual stuff,” and confessed to sneaking around due to his role in managing the city's COVID response.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In one recorded conversation, Dr Varma recounted hosting a party in August 2020 where attendees used MDMA: “So we rented a hotel … we all took, like, you know, molly and like it was like eight or nine or us, eight to 10 of us were in a room and everybody had a blast because everybody was like so pent up.”</p>

<p>Dr Varma also recalled attending a June 2021 rave with hundreds of attendees, and when asked if he regretted his actions, he replied, “No, actually, I'm like, I love being my authentic self.” A source revealed that Dr Varma hosted another gathering in November 2020.</p>

<p>City Councilwoman Inna Vernikov condemned Dr Varma's actions, stating, “While grandmothers took their last breaths alone on cold hospital beds, Dr Varma was fulfilling his sick fantasies with hundreds of sweaty strangers.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Michael Kane of Teachers for Choice said he was disgusted “hearing Varma say having drug-fuelled group sex orgies was necessary for him to be his ‘authentic self' because COVID had him ‘pent up.'”</p>

<p>Despite the uproar, a source close to Dr Varma defended him, claiming that “he technically didn't violate the mandate” and that his statements were taken out of context.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Varma himself issued a statement acknowledging his actions, saying, “In those private conversations that were secretly recorded, spliced, diced and taken out of context, I referred to events that transpired four years ago. Between April 2020 – May 2021, I participated in two private gatherings. I take responsibility for not using the best judgement at the time.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0bv3tafo_dr-jay-varma-_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Varma, who previously served as a senior health adviser under former Mayor Bill de Blasio]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/until-we-can-restore-peace-on-border-s-jaishankar-on-india-china-ties-6644490]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Until We Can Restore Peace On Border...": S Jaishankar On India-China Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/until-we-can-restore-peace-on-border-s-jaishankar-on-india-china-ties-6644490]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:20:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2020 clash between Indian and Chinese troops in Galwan Valley overshadowed the relations between the two countries and New Delhi's focus for the last four years has been disengagement on the border, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar said]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2020 clash between Indian and Chinese troops in Galwan Valley overshadowed the relations between the two countries and New Delhi's focus for the last four years has been disengagement on the border, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar has said.</p>

<p>Addressing an event titled 'India, Asia and the World' in New York yesterday, Dr Jaishankar said the India-China relationship is key to the future of Asia and would influence the entire world.</p>

<p>"I think the India-China relationship is key to the future of Asia. In a way, you can say that if the world is to be multi-polar, Asia has to be multi-polar. And therefore this relationship will influence not just the future of Asia, but in that way, perhaps the future of the world as well," Dr Jaishankar said, according to news agency PTI. The event was hosted by Asia Society and Asia Society Policy Institute.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Closing the day with an engaging conversation with <a href="https://twitter.com/dannyrrussel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@dannyrrussel</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/AsiaPolicy?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@AsiaPolicy</a> today on the theme ‘India, Asia &amp; the World'.<br />
<br />
As rebalancing, multipolarity and plurilateralism become key words of Asian and global geopolitics and a changing world tries to adjust to the shocks of… <a href="https://t.co/FcodPdlpA9">pic.twitter.com/FcodPdlpA9</a></p>
— Dr. S. Jaishankar (@DrSJaishankar) <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar/status/1838738414213971980?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 25, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The External Affairs Minister said India had a "difficult history" with China. "You have two countries who are neighbours, unique in the sense that they are the only two countries with over a billion people, both rising in the global order and who often have overlapping peripheries, including the fact that they have a common border. So it's really a very complicated issue. I think, if you look today in global politics, the parallel rises of India and China present a very, very unique problem," he said.</p>

<p>He referred to a recent remark that 75 per cent of the disengagement problems with China have been sorted out. "When I said 75 per cent of it has been sorted out - I was asked in a way to quantify - it's only of the disengagement. So that's one part of the problem. The main issue right now is the patrolling. You know, how do we, both of us, patrol up to the Line of Actual Control."</p>

<p>Dr Jaishankar said patrolling arrangements have been disturbed after 2020. "So we've been able to sort out much of the disengagement, the friction points, but some of the patrolling issues need to be resolved." He said that once the disengagement issue is dealt with, "there is the larger issue as both of us have brought a very large number of troops up to the border". "So there is what we call the de-escalation issue, and then there is the larger, the next step is really, how do you deal with the rest of the relationship?"</p>

<p>The minister said the "entire 3500 kilometre-border between India and China is disputed". "And so you make sure the border is peaceful so that other parts of the relationship can move."</p>

<p>Dr Jaishankar said several agreements between the two countries detailed how to ensure the border remained peaceful.</p>

<p>"Now the problem was in 2020, despite these very explicit agreements, we saw that the Chinese - we were all in the middle of Covid at that time - moved a large number of forces in violation of these agreements to the Line of Actual Control. And we responded in kind," he said. "Once troops were deployed very close up, which is 'very dangerous', it was likely a mishap could happen, and it did happen."</p>

<p>Referring to the 2020 Galwan clash, he said, "So there was a clash, and a number of troops died on either side, and that has since, in a sense, overshadowed the relationship. So until we can restore peace and tranquillity on the border and ensure the agreements signed up to are adhered to, it's obviously difficult to carry on with the rest of the relationship."</p>

<p>The External Affairs Minister said the focus for the last four years had been to at least disengage the troops, meaning that they go back to the camp, the military bases from which they traditionally operate.&nbsp;"Because right now, both sides have troops deployed forward," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/45o1tdjo_jaishankar_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar was addressing a gathering at New York]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mozilla-faces-privacy-complaint-over-firefox-user-tracking-6644422]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mozilla Faces Privacy Complaint Over Firefox User Tracking]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mozilla-faces-privacy-complaint-over-firefox-user-tracking-6644422]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:11:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The digital rights group NOYB (None Of Your Business) said Mozilla has enabled a feature that turned the browser into a tracking tool for websites without directly telling its users.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vienna-based advocacy group NOYB on Wednesday said it has filed a complaint with the Austrian data protection authority against Mozilla accusing the Firefox browser maker of tracking user behaviour on websites without consent. NOYB (None Of Your Business), the digital rights group founded by privacy activist Max Schrems, said Mozilla has enabled a so-called "privacy preserving attribution" feature that turned the browser into a tracking tool for websites without directly telling its users.</p>

<p>Mozilla had defended the feature, saying it wanted to help websites understand how their ads perform without collecting data about individual people. By offering what it called a non-invasive alternative to cross-site tracking, it hoped to significantly reduce collecting individual information.</p>

<p>While this may be less invasive than unlimited tracking, it still interferes with user rights under the EU's privacy laws, NOYB said, adding that Firefox has turned on the feature by default.</p>

<p>"It's a shame that an organisation like Mozilla believes that users are too dumb to say yes or no," said Felix Mikolasch, data protection lawyer at NOYB. "Users should be able to make a choice and the feature should have been turned off by default."</p>

<p>Open-source Firefox was once a top browser choice among users due to its privacy features but now lags market leader Google's Chrome, Apple's Safari and Microsoft's Edge with a low single-digit market share.</p>

<p>NOYB wants Mozilla to inform users about its data processing activities, switch to an opt-in system and delete all unlawfully processed data of millions of affected users.</p>

<p>NOYB, which in June filed a complaint against Alphabet for allegedly tracking users of its Chrome browser, had also filed hundreds of complaints against big tech companies, some leading to big fines.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h5qviuko_mozilla-firefox_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-you-want-to-die-chilling-message-us-woman-got-in-suicide-pod-6644385]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If You Want to Die...": Chilling Message US Woman Got In 'Suicide Pod']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/if-you-want-to-die-chilling-message-us-woman-got-in-suicide-pod-6644385]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:09:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a first, an American woman reportedly died by suicide inside a new 3D-printed "suicide pod", Sarco, in a forest cabin in Merishausen, Switzerland.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a first, an American woman reportedly died by suicide inside a new 3D-printed “suicide pod”, Sarco, in a forest cabin in Merishausen, Switzerland. The 64-year-old woman, who has not been publicly named, entered the Sarco pod on Monday. The machine allegedly encouraged her with a chilling message before her last moments, “If you want to die, press this button,” according to a report by AFP.</p>

<p>The Sarco pod, short for ‘sarcophagus', operates by flooding its chamber with nitrogen gas. That leads to a rapid decrease in oxygen levels due to which the person becomes unconscious within moments. Death typically occurs within ten minutes.</p>

<p>Florian Willet, co-president of the assisted suicide group Exit International's Swiss affiliate, the Last Resort, was the only witness present during the incident. He described the woman's death as “peaceful, fast and dignified,” as reported by the organisation. The woman suffered from “severe immune compromise,” the group said.</p>

<p>Dr Philip Nitschke, director of Exit International was “pleased” by the pod's performance. He stated, “I am pleased that the Sarco had performed exactly as it had been designed… to provide an elective, non-drug, peaceful death at the time of the person's choosing.”</p>

<p>Although the pod is designed with an emergency exit button, the device is not yet legally approved for use. Authorities have since arrested several individuals connected to the woman's death.</p>

<p>Switzerland allows assisted suicide, but individuals must do so without help from a doctor, meaning those who assist cannot act for selfish reasons. Unlike the Netherlands, where euthanasia with medical assistance is legal, Swiss law forbids euthanasia entirely.</p>

<p>Swiss Health Minister Elisabeth Baume-Schneider has voiced scepticism regarding the Sarco pod's potential approval, noting, “It does not fulfil the demands of the product safety law, and as such, must not be brought into circulation.” She added that the use of nitrogen is “not compatible with the article on purpose in the chemicals law.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ps1g567o_sarco-suicide-capsule-afp-_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-raids-lebanon-for-third-day-kills-hezbollah-members-sirens-sound-in-tel-aviv-as-tensions-surge-in-middle-east-6644364]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Raids Lebanon Again, Sirens Sound In Tel Aviv As Tensions Surge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-raids-lebanon-for-third-day-kills-hezbollah-members-sirens-sound-in-tel-aviv-as-tensions-surge-in-middle-east-6644364]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 11:03:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Longtime foes Hezbollah and Israel have been locked in near-daily exchanges of cross-border fire since Hamas launched an unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli warplanes pounded villages in south Lebanon for a third day, Lebanese media reported Wednesday, while Israel said it intercepted a missile fired after sirens sounded early morning in Tel Aviv. Lebanese officials said hundreds of thousands of civilians have fled their homes in the south this week to avoid <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decades-of-covert-conflict-the-israel-lebanon-shadow-war-6636815">fighting between Hezbollah and the Israeli military</a>.</p>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency said Israeli warplanes launched raids on multiple towns in the south from 5:00 am (0200 GMT), adding "casualties were reported" from other strikes overnight.</p>

<p>The United Nations Security Council said it will hold an emergency meeting on the crisis in New York Wednesday, while UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres warned the situation was critical.</p>

<p>Hundreds of thousands of people have been displaced since the latest round of fighting began Monday, officials said, some crossing the border to Syria to flee Israeli bombing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Thuraya Harb, a 41-year-old housewife at a makeshift centre for displaced families in Beirut, said her family fled "with nothing but the clothes on our backs".</p>

<p>"I didn't want to leave my home, but the children were scared," the mother of four said.</p>

<p>Longtime foes Hezbollah and Israel have been locked in near-daily exchanges of cross-border fire since Palestinian group Hamas launched an unprecedented attack on Israel on October 7.</p>

<p>The Hamas attack sparked a war in Gaza that has drawn in Hezbollah and other Iran-backed militants from across the Middle East, including Yemen and Iraq.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanese-take-refuge-in-shelters-after-long-trips-fleeing-israeli-bombing-6641864">Lebanon</a> said Israeli strikes killed at least 558 people on Monday -- the deadliest day of violence in the country since its 1975-90 civil war.</p>

<p>Lebanese Health Minister Firass Abiad said the "vast majority, if not all" of those killed were unarmed civilians in their homes.</p>

<p>Israel's military said Wednesday it intercepted a missile fired from Lebanon after sirens sounded in Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>"Following the sirens that sounded in the Tel Aviv and Netanya areas, one surface-to-surface missile was identified crossing from Lebanon and was intercepted," a military spokesman said.</p>

<h3><strong>Hezbollah's Rocket Commander Killed</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-faces-biggest-israeli-attack-in-4-decades-all-about-the-1982-lebanese-war-6636511">Hezbollah</a> claimed 18 attacks on Israel on Tuesday, while the Israeli military said the Iran-backed group fired about 300 rockets across the border.</p>

<p>Hezbollah also confirmed an Israeli claim that it had killed its rocket forces commander <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-lebanon-hezbollah-missile-chief-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-beirut-10-points-6643300#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Ibrahim Kobeissi</a> in the strike on the Lebanese capital.</p>

<p>Early Wednesday, a Lebanese security source said a new Israeli strike hit the Saadiyat area near Beirut, with a "warehouse" targeted.</p>

<p>At the UN General Assembly in New York, Secretary-General Guterres warned the situation in Lebanon was critical.</p>

<p>"We should all be alarmed by the escalation. Lebanon is at the brink," he said, while cautioning against "the possibility of transforming Lebanon (into) another Gaza".</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden warned against a full-blown war in Lebanon in his speech during the New York gathering.</p>

<p>"Full-scale war is not in anyone's interest. Even though the situation has escalated, a diplomatic solution is still possible," Biden said.</p>

<p>Lebanon's foreign minister, also at the UN assembly, said the number of displaced Lebanese had soared to nearly 500,000 since Israel ramped up its military campaign.</p>

<p>A security official in neighbouring Syria told AFP about 500 people had crossed the border to flee the bombing.</p>

<h3><strong>Defiant Netanyahu</strong></h3>

<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed to continue the withering air campaign.</p>

<p>"We will continue to hit Hezbollah... the one who has a missile in his living room and a rocket in his home will not have a home," he said.</p>

<p>Iran, Hezbollah's main backer, condemned the raids, with its president, Masoud Pezeshkian, saying its ally "cannot stand alone" against Israel.</p>

<p>"We must not allow Lebanon to become another Gaza at the hands of Israel," he said.</p>

<p>A US official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Washington opposed an Israeli ground invasion targeting Hezbollah and had "concrete ideas" on how to de-escalate the crisis.</p>

<p>Israel's ambassador to the UN, Danny Danon, said Israel was "not eager to start any ground invasion" in Lebanon.</p>

<p>Britain's foreign ministry said Tuesday that it was sending military teams to Cyprus as it prepares "contingency plans" for its citizens in Lebanon, who it urged to immediately leave the country.</p>

<h3><strong>'New phase'</strong></h3>

<p>The war in Gaza began with Hamas's October 7 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>Of the 251 hostages seized by militants, 97 are still held in Gaza, including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military offensive has killed at least 41,467 people in Gaza, most of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry. The UN has described the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>In a statement addressed to the UN chief, Hamas urged "immediate action" to stop the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Since the start of the Gaza war, clashes along the Lebanon-Israel border have forced tens of thousands of people on both sides to flee their homes.</p>

<p>The violence between Israel and Hezbollah escalated dramatically last week, when coordinated communications device blasts that the militants blamed on Israel killed 39 people and wounded almost 3,000.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/hpts2c1o_israel-hezbollah_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bright-space-rock-to-light-up-sky-this-week-comet-to-visit-after-80-000-years-6644305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bright Space Rock To Light Up Sky, Comet To Visit After 80,000 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/bright-space-rock-to-light-up-sky-this-week-comet-to-visit-after-80-000-years-6644305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:58:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Comet C/2023 A3 (Tsuchinshan-ATLAS) is set to make a dramatic appearance in our skies over the next few weeks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Comet C/2023 A3, also known as Tsuchinshan-ATLAS, is returning to Earth. Our ancestors last witnessed this uncommon sight about 80,000 years ago. This comet, which resembles a fuzzy star with a tail, can be seen in the early morning hours of the sky from Friday through Monday. Even a beautiful video of it was taken by NASA astronaut Matthew Dominick, who is presently stationed on the International Space Station.</p>

<p>"So far, Comet Tsuchinshan-ATLAS looks like a fuzzy star to the naked eye looking out the cupola windows. But with a 200mm f/2 lens at 1/8s exposure, you can really start to see it. This comet is going to make for some really cool images as it gets closer to the sun. For now a timelapse preview," Dominick captioned the video in his X post.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">So far Comet Tsuchinshan-ATLAS looks like a fuzzy star to the naked eye looking out the cupola windows. But with a 200mm, f2 lens at 1/8s exposure you can really start to see it. This comet is going to make for some really cool images as it gets closer to the sun. For now a… <a href="https://t.co/JstaSLJ4Ui">pic.twitter.com/JstaSLJ4Ui</a></p>
— Matthew Dominick (@dominickmatthew) <a href="https://twitter.com/dominickmatthew/status/1836916069870751825?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Stuart Atkinson, a space enthusiast and amateur astronomer based in Cumbria, said the comet will look like 'a fuzzy star with a misty tail'.</p>

<p>Cumbria-based space enthusiast and amateur astronomer Stuart Atkinson said in a social media post that "the comet will look like a fuzzy star with a misty tail, beneath the Moon, very low in the east. You might need binoculars to see it."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">You can use the Moon to find Comet A3 Tsuchinshan-ATLAS in the sky before sunrise later this week. The comet will look like a fuzzy star with a misty tail, beneath the Moon, v low in the east. You might need binoculars to see it. (Charts drawn for UK but visible elsewhere too) <a href="https://t.co/hUISrEqEoT">pic.twitter.com/hUISrEqEoT</a></p>
— Stuart Atkinson (@mars_stu) <a href="https://twitter.com/mars_stu/status/1838136319702102384?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.skyatnightmagazine.com/advice/comet-c-2023-a3-tsuchinshan-atlas"><em>BBC Sky at Night Magazine,</em></a> "Initial data seems to suggest that Comet C/2023 A3 completes an orbit every 80,000 years. By the end of September 2024, it will be a morning object, perhaps shining as brightly as mag. +0.6 but rising just before the sun. Comet C/2023 A3 will reach perihelion-the closest point to the Sun in its orbit-on 28 September 2024. Our best views of A3 will come when it moves up into the evening sky around 10 October. By then it will have faded slightly but is predicted to still be as bright as mag. +0.8, low in the west after sunset."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pka6v0oo_comet_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The comet will look like a faint star-like blob with a hazy tail.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sahara-desert-turns-green-nasa-shares-stunning-image-of-transformation-6644222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sahara Desert Turns Green, NASA Shares Stunning Image of Transformation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sahara-desert-turns-green-nasa-shares-stunning-image-of-transformation-6644222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:44:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Historically, the Sahara was once covered in vegetation and lakes between 11,000 and 5,000 years ago]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the driest places on Earth is seeing a surprising burst of greenery, as heavy rainfall has led to vegetation sprouting across the typically barren Sahara Desert.&nbsp;NASA's satellite images reveal patches of plant life emerging in the desert following an extratropical cyclone that drenched parts of northwestern Africa on September 7 and 8. Regions in Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, and Libya, which rarely receive rain, are now showing traces of green, according to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/images/153320/a-deluge-for-the-sahara" rel="nofollow, noindex">NASA's Earth Observatory</a></em>.</p>

<p>Shrubs and trees are growing in low-lying areas like riverbeds, explained Sylwia Trzaska, a climate variability researcher at the Columbia Climate School. Peter de Menocal, president of the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution, noted that while it's rare, plant life does respond quickly to heavy rain events in this part of Africa. When substantial rain falls, dunes transform into lush, green landscapes for a brief time as plants take full advantage of the moisture.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">An extratropical cyclone over the Sahara Desert drenched parts of Morocco and Algeria – bringing up to a year's worth of rain to some areas. ?️ <a href="https://twitter.com/NASA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@nasa</a>'s Terra satellite captured floodwaters and some Saharan lakes, usually dry, filled with water. <a href="https://t.co/cuS1c73RoA">https://t.co/cuS1c73RoA</a> <a href="https://t.co/m8Ga8G0FgO">pic.twitter.com/m8Ga8G0FgO</a></p>
— NASA Earth (@NASAEarth) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAEarth/status/1836071502384394313?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Historically, the Sahara was once covered in vegetation and lakes between 11,000 and 5,000 years ago, de Menocal's past research suggests. Now, even lakes that are typically dry are filling up due to this recent deluge, according to Moshe Armon, a lecturer at the Institute of Earth Sciences, Hebrew University of Jerusalem.</p>

<p>The unusual rainfall event was triggered by the northward movement of the tropical rain belt, known as the Intertropical Convergence Zone, reaching farther north than usual, bringing heavy rains typical of equatorial regions into the Sahara. Some areas saw over half a foot of rain, which far exceeds the typical annual precipitation of just a few inches.</p>

<p>While the rains largely affected sparsely populated areas, devastating floods have killed over 1,000 people and affected around 4 million across 14 African nations, according to the World Food Programme and the Associated Press.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Experts believe the shift in the rain belt is influenced by record-high ocean temperatures and climate change, which could lead to further changes in rainfall patterns across Africa. However, as ocean temperatures balance out globally, the rain belt is expected to shift back south, potentially crossing the equator, according to de Menocal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c2uglpr8_sahara-desert_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some areas saw over half a foot of rain]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-appoints-3-member-cabinet-6641518]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sri Lanka's President Appoints 3-Member Cabinet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-appoints-3-member-cabinet-6641518]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 25 Sep 2024 10:01:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers on Tuesday evening, with Prime Minister Harini Amarasuriya, lawmaker Vijitha Herath and himself taking on Cabinet portfolios.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers on Tuesday evening, with Prime Minister Harini Amarasuriya, lawmaker Vijitha Herath and himself taking on Cabinet portfolios.</p>

<p>Dissanayake will now oversee defence, finance, economic development, policy formulation, planning, tourism, energy, agriculture, lands, livestock, irrigation, fisheries and aquatic resources, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Dissanayake, 55, has taken the key finance portfolio himself as Sri Lanka looks to emerge from its most punishing economic crisis in 70 years and its first debt default, while keeping promises to aid the nation's poor.</p>

<p>The Marxist-leaning firebrand politician will also hold the economic development and tourism jobs in the cabinet.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's intentions to slash taxes and desire to revisit the terms of a $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund bailout have worried investors, who fear that it could delay a crucial $25 billion debt restructuring.</p>

<p>His comments during Monday's inauguration offered few clues as to how hardline his economic approach will be.</p>

<p>"Our politics needs to be cleaner, and the people have called for a different political culture," the 55-year-old said.</p>

<p>"I am ready to commit to that change."</p>

<p>Dissanayake ran in Saturday's presidential election as the candidate for the National People's Power coalition, which includes his Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna Party that traditionally championed Marxist economic policies centred on protectionism and state intervention. In recent years the party has taken more centrist positions.</p>

<p>Earlier, Amarasuriya was sworn in as the Prime Minister, and was appointed as the Minister of justice, public administration, provincial councils, local government, education, science and technology, labour, women, child and youth affairs, sports, trade, commerce, food security, co-operative development, industries and entrepreneur development, and health.</p>

<p>Herath was assigned the Minister of Buddhist affairs, religious and cultural affairs, national integration, social security, mass media, transport, highways, ports and civil aviation, public security, and foreign affairs, environment, wildlife, forest resources, water supply, plantation and community, infrastructure, rural and urban development, housing and construction.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b7jfm6hs_sri-lankan-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake-reuters_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anura Kumara Dissanayake appointed a new Cabinet of Ministers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>