<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 03:07:38 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-joe-biden-pledges-historic-4-billion-to-world-bank-fund-for-poor-nations-7051283]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Pledges "Historic" $4 Billion To World Bank Fund For Poor Nations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-joe-biden-pledges-historic-4-billion-to-world-bank-fund-for-poor-nations-7051283]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 03:07:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden announced a "historic" $4 billion pledge for a World Bank fund that helps the world's poorest countries, the White House said Monday, before Donald Trump takes office with a new cost-cutting agenda.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>US President Joe Biden announced a "historic" $4 billion pledge for a World Bank fund that helps the world's poorest countries, the White House said Monday, before Donald Trump takes office with a new cost-cutting agenda.</p>

<p>The outgoing leader unveiled the money for the International Development Association as he attends the G20 summit underway in Rio de Janeiro, his last time at the gathering of world leaders.</p>

<p>"The president announced today that the United States intends to pledge $4 billion over three years... which is really exciting," a senior US administration official told reporters on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The official said the pledge would not be binding on Trump's incoming administration but said previous Republican governments had also backed top-ups for the fund.</p>

<p>US Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer earlier called the pledge "historic" and said Biden would "rally other leaders to step up their contributions."</p>

<p>The International Development Association is the concessional lending arm of the World Bank and is used for some of the poorest countries in the globe, including for projects focused on climate.</p>

<p>During a six-day tour of South America, Biden has been trying to shore up his international legacy ahead of President-elect Trump's return to the White House on January 20.</p>

<p>On Sunday he visited the Amazon rainforest in Brazil to promote his record on climate change, saying that the United States had hit its target of increasing bilateral climate financing to $11 billion a year.</p>

<p>Billionaire Trump has pledged to take a wrecking ball to many of Biden's policies and has appointed tech tycoon Elon Musk as head of a commission to target what he calls federal government waste.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6n7bv69g_joe-biden-g20_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US official said the pledge would not be binding on Trump's incoming administration.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-sam-altman-joins-san-franciscos-transition-government-7051222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI CEO Sam Altman Joins San Francisco's Transition Government]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/openai-ceo-sam-altman-joins-san-franciscos-transition-government-7051222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 02:48:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI CEO Sam Altman has joined a growing list of former tech leaders taking roles in San Francisco's government following this month's election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI CEO Sam Altman has joined a growing list of former tech leaders taking roles in San Francisco's government following this month's election.</p>

<p>San Francisco Mayor-elect Daniel Lurie named Altman, the head of the artificial-intelligence company behind ChatGPT, as one of seven co-chairs of his transition team, the campaign announced on Monday. The tech industry concentrated in Silicon Valley, south of San Francisco, has increasingly moved into the city itself, creating tensions in a place once synonymous with hippies and counterculture.</p>

<p>At the same time, San Francisco's sluggish post-pandemic economic recovery and visible struggles with drugs and homelessness have fueled a shift towards centrist Democratic politics, driven by both disgruntled citizens and affluent tech executive donors.</p>

<p>Some Silicon Valley investors have backed Republican President-elect Donald Trump.</p>

<p>In San Francisco's election, WhatsApp co-founder and former CEO Jan Koum supported Lurie. Two former software entrepreneurs, Bilal Mahmood and Danny Sauter, were elected to the city's board of supervisors.</p>

<p>Lurie, a philanthropist and heir to the Levi Strauss fortune, will succeed London Breed, the city's first Black female mayor, who has led the city since 2018.</p>

<p>Upon taking office on January 8, Lurie, who has no experience at City Hall, will face the challenge of resolving San Francisco's public safety crisis, a pressing issue that has driven numerous tech leaders to relocate from the Bay Area.</p>

<p>Other tech executives embraced the chance to focus their industry's skills on San Francisco's problems.</p>

<p>"I'm excited to help the city I love, and where OpenAI was started," Altman said in a statement.</p>

<p>In an interview with Reuters, Mahmood said former business executives are experts in prioritization and metrics-driven governance, which can help the city "return to the basics".</p>

<p>"Democrats have been too focused on ideological battles rather than quality-of-life issues," he said.</p>

<p>Mahmood added that many of San Francisco's problems stem from its inefficient technical infrastructure, leading to delays in hiring and housing approvals, areas where tech executives are well-positioned to contribute.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/elqng2j_sam-altman_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I'm excited to help the city I love, and where OpenAI was started," Sam Altman said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-holds-bilateral-meeting-with-indonesia-portugal-at-g20-sidelines-7051191]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Holds Bilateral Meeting With Indonesia, Portugal At G20 Sidelines]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-holds-bilateral-meeting-with-indonesia-portugal-at-g20-sidelines-7051191]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 02:33:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi held bilateral meeting with Indonesia and Portugal at the sidelines of the G20 Leaders' Summit in Brazil.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi held bilateral meeting with Indonesia and Portugal at the sidelines of the G20 Leaders' Summit in Brazil.</p>

<p>PM Modi along with the Indian contingent, including External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar met with Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto and his contingent.</p>

<p>PM Modi highlighted that their talks were focused on improving ties in commerce, security, and more.</p>

<p>"Delighted to meet President Prabowo Subianto during the G20 Summit in Brazil. This year is special as we are marking 75 years of India-Indonesia diplomatic relations. Our talks focussed on improving ties in commerce, security, healthcare, pharmaceuticals and more," PM Modi said on X.</p>

<p>Minister of External Affairs official spokeperson Randhir Jaiswal, taking to X, said that PM Modi assured Mr Prabowo of expanding the India-Indonesia Comprehensive Strategic Partnership.</p>

<p>"India-Indonesia, Commemorating 75 years of warm and friendly ties! PM Narendra Modi met President Prabowo Subianto of Indonesia on the sidelines of the G20 Brazil Summit. PM congratulated President Prabowo and assured him of India-Indonesia Comprehensive Strategic Partnership, in existing domains as well as expand it to newer areas." Jaiswal wrote on X.</p>

<p>PM Modi also held a bilateral meeting with the PM of Portugal Luis Montenegro where they focused on strengthening economic partnership. PM Modi said that both countries explored opportunities for more collaboration in sectors like renewable energy and green hydrogen.</p>

<p>"Had a very good meeting with Prime Minister of Portugal, Mr. Luis Montenegro. India cherishes the long-standing ties with Portugal. Our talks focussed on adding more vigour to our economic linkages. Sectors like renewable energy and green hydrogen offer many opportunities for more collaboration. We also talked about strong defence relations, people-to-people linkages and other such subjects," PM Modi wrote on X.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, PM Modi met with President of Spain Pedro Sanchez on the sidelines of G20 summit.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Brazil's President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, China's President Xi Jinping, and other leaders posed for a family photo at the 19th G20 Leaders' Summit.</p>

<p>A photo was taken following the launch of the Global Alliance Against Hunger and Poverty.</p>

<p>The official spokesperson of the Ministry of External Affairs, Randhir Jaiswal, described it as "a photo for posterity."</p>

<p>"A photo for posterity! The #G20 leaders together for 'Building a Just World and a Sustainable Planet'," Jaiswal posted on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/94r14u28_pm-modi-g20_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi held a bilateral meeting with the PM of Portugal Luis Montenegro, focusing economic partnership.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-germany-to-send-4-000-ai-drones-to-ukraine-rejects-long-range-missiles-7051090]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany To Send 4,000 AI Drones To Ukraine, Rejects Long-Range Missiles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-germany-to-send-4-000-ai-drones-to-ukraine-rejects-long-range-missiles-7051090]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 02:09:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany on Monday said that it was delivering 4,000 AI-guided drones to Ukraine, as Chancellor Olaf Scholz stood by a decision not to send Kyiv long-range Taurus missiles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany on Monday said that it was delivering 4,000 AI-guided drones to Ukraine, as Chancellor Olaf Scholz stood by a decision not to send Kyiv long-range Taurus missiles.</p>

<p>Scholz has faced renewed pressure to hand the weapons system over to Ukraine, after US President Joe Biden gave Kyiv the green light to use US missiles against military targets in Russia itself.</p>

<p>Kyiv has repeatedly urged Germany to send it Taurus missiles, which have a reach of more than 500 kilometres (310 miles) -- a plea Berlin has steadfastly refused.</p>

<p>"I have explained very clearly why I do not think it is right to supply Taurus cruise missiles," Scholz said on the sidelines of the G20 summit in Brazil.</p>

<p>Scholz said it was important to support Ukraine's defence against Russia's full-scale invasion while acting "prudently".</p>

<p>The missiles could only be used if "responsibility for targeting" was shared, Scholz said, a move he has previously stressed would risk drawing Germany directly into the war.</p>

<p>"That is something that I cannot take responsibility for," Scholz said Monday in Rio de Janeiro.</p>

<p>"We have a clear understanding that the powerful weapons we have supplied so far, the long-range artillery, the rocket launchers, cannot be used to penetrate deep into the Russian hinterland."</p>

<p>But Britain's former defence minister Ben Wallace urged Scholz to "now reconsider his rather stubborn and clumsy opposition to using Taurus, which just makes him look odd compared to the French and British".</p>

<p>The German leader "clearly doesn't understand deterrence", Wallace told Britain's Times Radio.</p>

<p>The Conservative ex-minister added many will be relieved once Germany's elections are over -- the country will go to the polls in February after Scholz's coalition collapsed, with the chancellor's party trailing in opinion surveys.</p>

<p>"Olaf Scholz is probably better suited to running a subcommittee of a planning committee in a local council than one of the biggest nations in Europe," Wallace said.</p>

<p>Berlin has been the second-biggest supplier of military aid to Ukraine in its fight against Russia's invasion and said earlier Monday it would supply Kyiv with 4,000 AI-guided drones.</p>

<p>Defence Minister Boris Pistorius told reporters at an event in the German state of Bavaria that the drones being provided could "take out the enemy's electronic drone defences".</p>

<p>The drones "can be delivered very quickly" and could be "deployed 30-40 kilometres (19-25 miles) behind the front line and hit combat posts, logistics hubs among other targets", Pistorius said.</p>

<p>Along some parts of the front line in Ukraine, such a distance would reach into Russian territory.</p>

<p>Despite the unmanned aerial vehicles being nicknamed "mini-Taurus" by the German media, the government was careful to point out they do not have the same range.</p>

<p>"These are tactical drones with a restricted range," defence ministry spokesman Natalie Jenning told reporters at a press conference on Monday.</p>

<p>"There is no connection to the Taurus (system) as has been sketched out in some of the media coverage," she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/qkhj7ntg_olaf-scholz_625x300_05_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Olaf Scholz said it was important to support Ukraine's defence against Russia's invasion. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-highlights-4-key-aspects-of-climate-action-at-cop29-7051008]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Highlights 4 Key Aspects Of Climate Action At COP29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-highlights-4-key-aspects-of-climate-action-at-cop29-7051008]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:48:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India made a significant intervention on Monday during the '2024 Annual High-level Ministerial Roundtable on pre-2030 Ambition' at the COP29 UN Climate Change Summit in Baku, Azerbaijan, emphasising four critical aspects of global climate action.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India made a significant intervention on Monday during the '2024 Annual High-level Ministerial Roundtable on pre-2030 Ambition' at the COP29 UN Climate Change Summit in Baku, Azerbaijan, emphasising four critical aspects of global climate action.</p>

<p>India underscored the importance of addressing four key areas in global climate action: scaling up innovative actions and technology transfer, prioritising climate finance as central to implementing climate action, enhancing international cooperation, and fostering mutual trust among nations, according to a statement from the Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change.</p>

<p>Leena Nandan, Secretary of the Environment, Forest and Climate Change Ministry and Deputy Leader of the Indian Delegation, highlighted findings from the 2024 Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) Synthesis Report. She noted that cumulative CO2 emissions between 2020 and 2030 are projected to consume 86% of the remaining carbon budget, as per the ministry's statement.</p>

<p>"Our discussions and deliberations are taking place at a crucial time when decisive action is imperative. The pre-2030 period is an opportunity to enhance global climate action," the statement read.</p>

<p>India emphasised that this ambitious, action-oriented approach depends on bold commitments from parties responsible for leading economy-wide emission reductions. Developed nations achieving net-zero targets would lay the groundwork for a sustainable and resilient world in the current and future decades.</p>

<p>The statement also stressed the importance of equity and the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities (CBDR-RC), along with climate justice in science, policy, and practice. It highlighted the need to avoid burdening developing nations with the consequences of inadequate pre-2020 mitigation efforts and called for climate solutions that are both effective and equitable.</p>

<p>India further called for the scaling up of innovative actions through unrestricted technology transfer. "New technologies and solutions are critical for transitioning to a low-carbon economy, yet innovations in areas such as clean energy and carbon removal remain in their early stages, with significant barriers to scaling and transferring them to developing nations," the statement said.</p>

<p>The ministry also emphasised the importance of knowledge and technology transfer without Intellectual Property Rights (IPR) restrictions on green technologies, urging COP29 to deliver tangible outcomes on deploying technology in developing countries.</p>

<p>On climate finance, the statement highlighted a significant gap in funding for climate action, particularly in developing nations. "The first global stocktake of progress under the Paris Agreement shows a substantial shortfall in financing, which is essential for deploying clean energy, building disaster-resilient infrastructure, and implementing adaptation projects, requiring trillions of dollars," it stated.</p>

<p>India stressed that public climate finance from developed nations must fully cover the costs of deviations from least-cost development pathways for developing countries. "Failure to do so imposes additional burdens on people in developing nations, who already bear disproportionate impacts of climate change despite minimal contributions to the problem," the statement added.</p>

<p>India termed COP29 a "milestone" for climate finance, urging developed nations to fulfil long-standing commitments to provide substantial, equitable, and accessible financial resources.</p>

<p>On international cooperation, the statement noted that enhanced collaboration is essential for achieving measurable outcomes, including cost-effective and scalable mitigation solutions. However, it criticised the uneven nature of international cooperation, with some nations resorting to unilateral measures that transfer financial burdens to developing countries.</p>

<p>"There is a need to address the negative impacts of such unilateral trade measures on developing nations in the context of climate change," the statement said.</p>

<p>Highlighting mutual trust as a cornerstone in combating climate change, India asserted that COP29 offers developed nations a chance to build trust and achieve significant milestones in climate ambitions by 2030.</p>

<p>The ministry noted that while the 2024 NDC Synthesis Report raises concerns, it also provides hope. "195 parties have submitted their NDCs, with 180 updating them. Global greenhouse gas emissions in 2030 are estimated to be 2.6% lower than in 2019, suggesting a possible peak before 2030. With the next round of NDCs due next year, there is room for further improvement," India said at COP29.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jjlggl0c_cop29-climate-summit-reuters_625x300_12_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India underscored the importance of addressing four key areas in global climate action. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-you-going-joe-russian-state-media-mocks-joe-biden-for-avoiding-questions-on-ukraine-war-escalation-7050744]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wanders Off...": Russian Media Mocks Biden For Avoiding Ukraine Question]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/where-you-going-joe-russian-state-media-mocks-joe-biden-for-avoiding-questions-on-ukraine-war-escalation-7050744]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:43:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Biden held a press conference in the Amazon rainforest in Brazil's Manaus but took no questions about America's decision to clear Ukraine to use its long-range missiles to strike inside Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden, who is in Brazil to attend the G-20 Summit, announced a multimillion-dollar plan to "reforest the Amazon" on Sunday. Biden held a press conference in the Amazon rainforest in Brazil's Manaus, where he talked about conservation and the investments his administration has made in clean energy infrastructure. But, the US president took no questions about the United States's just-announced decision to clear Ukraine to use long-range American missiles to strike inside Russia in a major escalation of the conflict.</p>

<p>Following this, RT, the Russian state-controlled international news television network, posted a video of the US President appearing to "wander off" into the Amazon rainforest, on X (formally Twitter) and asked, "Where you going Joe?"</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Where you going Joe?<br />
<br />
Biden finishes press conference, answers no questions, wanders off into the Amazon Jungle <a href="https://t.co/r2Hl5NoUhi">pic.twitter.com/r2Hl5NoUhi</a></p>
— RT (@RT_com) <a href="https://twitter.com/RT_com/status/1858515504131944787?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 18, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The clip showed outgoing US president Biden standing at a podium in a loose-fitting blue outdoor shirt and sunglasses. He suddenly turns, waves, and appears to walk right into the forest, rather than following the path in front of him.</p>

<p>"Biden finishes press conference, answers no questions, wanders off into the Amazon Jungle," &nbsp;the Russian state media portal said in the post on X.</p>

<p>This was the second post on RT's X handle in the last 24 hours, which seemed to be mocking Mr Biden's decision, giving the green signal to Kyiv to use American missiles against military targets inside Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Earlier on Sunday, RT posted a screen grab of a media article on the Biden administration's big move. A graphics interchange format (gif) image of a smiling US President was superimposed on the article. Posting the graphic, RT wrote, "Joe Biden planning his final vacation as US president be like".&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Joe Biden planning his final vacation as US president be like <a href="https://t.co/alvs3Elz2R">pic.twitter.com/alvs3Elz2R</a></p>
— RT (@RT_com) <a href="https://twitter.com/RT_com/status/1858255489752355110?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 17, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h2><strong>US Clears Kyiv To Use ATACMS Missiles</strong></h2>

<p>Acting on Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky's long-standing demand for authorisation to use the powerful Army Tactical Missile System-known by its initials ATACMS-the Biden administration has lifted restrictions on Kyiv's use of long-range missiles, allowing it to hit targets inside Russia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The move, which came weeks before Mr Biden left office, has angered the Kremlin. Accusing the US of "throwing oil on the fire", Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the decision would mean Washington's direct involvement in the conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though there has been no official comment on the issue from the White House and incoming President Donald Trump, Mr Trump's eldest son, Donald Trump Jr, said: "The military-industrial complex seems to want to make sure they get World War III going before my father has a chance to create peace and save lives."</p>

<p>President-elect Trump, who is set to take office on January 20, repeatedly pledged during his election campaign to negotiate an end to the Ukraine war.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jaillkr_biden-amazon-afp_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden held a press conference in the Amazon rainforest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delhis-hazardous-air-quality-key-focus-at-cop29-7050979]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delhi's Hazardous Air Quality Key Focus At COP29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delhis-hazardous-air-quality-key-focus-at-cop29-7050979]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:35:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Delhi's hazardous air quality was a key focus at COP29, as experts warned about the health risks of air pollution and called for immediate global action.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Delhi's hazardous air quality was a key focus at COP29, as experts warned about the health risks of air pollution and called for immediate global action.</p>

<p>Aarti Khosla, Director of Climate Trends, says that Delhi's Air Quality Index (AQI) had reached dangerous levels, with some areas recording particulate pollution above 1,000 microgram per cubic metre. "Pollution comes from many sources like black carbon, ozone, burning fossil fuels, and farm fires. We need solutions that tackle all of these," she said.</p>

<p>Khosla also explained that low wind speeds during the La Nina weather pattern are trapping pollutants in the air, making the situation worse. "While we discuss major global issues, millions of people's health is at risk. We must act fast," she said.</p>

<p>Courtney Howard, Vice-Chair of the Global Climate and Health Alliance, shared her experience from Canada, where wildfires forced the evacuation of 70 per cent of her population in 2023. "This was expensive, even for a rich country like ours. Poorer nations need financial help to deal with such disasters," she said.</p>

<p>Howard also criticised the lack of funds for health care, despite massive subsidies given to large corporations. "We are giving USD 1 trillion to corporations making huge profits, but we say there's no money for health care. We must fund health to protect everyone," she said.</p>

<p>Enkhun Byambadorj, Co-Founder of Breathe Mongolia, highlighted the serious air pollution problem in his country. "Children in cities have 40 per cent lower lung capacity compared to those in rural areas. The air we breathe is a choice we make as a society, but it's hurting our children's future," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/27377ero_delhi-air-pollution_625x300_25_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Low wind speeds during the La Nina weather pattern are trapping pollutants in the air. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ecuador-declares-national-emergency-over-forest-fires-water-shortage-7050920]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ecuador Declares National Emergency Over Forest Fires, Water Shortage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ecuador-declares-national-emergency-over-forest-fires-water-shortage-7050920]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:16:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ecuador on Monday declared a national emergency due to water shortages, drought and forest fires that have razed more than 10,000 hectares in the south of the country so far this month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ecuador on Monday declared a national emergency due to water shortages, drought and forest fires that have razed more than 10,000 hectares in the south of the country so far this month.</p>

<p>The state of emergency, approved by the environment ministry, will be in place for 60 days, the country's SNGR emergency management secretariat said in a statement.</p>

<p>It will allow the freeing of funds to tackle the multi-faceted crisis, including fires concentrated in the Azuay and Loja provinces, with 17 blazes reported active on Monday.</p>

<p>Eight firefighting helicopters -- three of them sent by Peru and Italy -- were combating fires, said the SNGR.</p>

<p>One of the worst fires was in the Cajas national park.</p>

<p>The South American country has been rationing electricity for months due to the worst drought it has faced in six decades.</p>

<p>Last month, scheduled rationing was lengthened from eight to 14 hours per day.</p>

<p>Low water levels have caused the reservoirs of hydroelectric plants that cover 70 percent of national demand to fall to critical levels, leaving the country to face an "unprecedented crisis," according to Energy Minister Ines Manzano.</p>

<p>According to the SNGR, between January and November, Ecuador reported more than 5,100 forest fires that claimed six lives and injured 45 people.</p>

<p>Fires have consumed some 40,000 hectares of crops and killed more than 44,000 farm animals, according to the government.</p>

<p>Authorities suspect arson in some of the fires, with several suspects identified to date, Cristian Zamora, the mayor of the Azuay capital, Cuenca, told the Ecuavisa broadcaster.</p>

<p>He said the fires may have been set to clear forest area for agriculture.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3d6entg8_ecuador_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fires have consumed some 40,000 hectares of crops and killed more than 44,000 farm animals. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-44-injured-in-russian-missile-attack-says-ukraine-7050810]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Killed, 44 Injured In Russian Missile Attack, Says Ukraine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/10-killed-44-injured-in-russian-missile-attack-says-ukraine-7050810]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:42:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Russian missile attack killed 10 people and wounded 44 in Ukraine's Black Sea port of Odesa on Monday, local governor Oleh Kiper and national police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Russian missile attack killed 10 people and wounded 44 in Ukraine's Black Sea port of Odesa on Monday, local governor Oleh Kiper and national police said.</p>

<p>Four children were among the wounded while three people were in serious condition, Kiper said on the Telegram messenger.</p>

<p>President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Telegram that a Russian ballistic missile had hit a residential neighbourhood, and that an apartment building, a university building and an administrative building had been damaged.</p>

<p>"These are not random strikes - these are show strikes. After calls and meetings with Putin, after all the false gossip in the media about supposedly 'refraining' from strikes. Russia is showing what it is really interested in: only war," he said.</p>

<p>National police said that seven police officers, a medic and two residents had been killed, and 14 police officers were among the wounded.</p>

<p>Russia unleashed its largest overnight missile attack on Ukraine in almost three months on Sunday, killing seven people and further hobbling an already damaged energy system.</p>

<p>Later on, a Russian missile hit a residential building in the Sumy region, killing 11 including two children and wounding 89.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/mioag7lo_odesa-ukraine_625x300_19_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[National police said that seven police officers, a medic and two residents had been killed. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-confirms-military-plan-for-mass-deportation-of-undocumented-migrants-7050776]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Confirms Military Plan For Mass Deportation Of Undocumented Migrants]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-confirms-military-plan-for-mass-deportation-of-undocumented-migrants-7050776]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:32:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump confirmed Monday that he plans to declare a national emergency on border security and use the US military to carry out a mass deportation of undocumented migrants.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump confirmed Monday that he plans to declare a national emergency on border security and use the US military to carry out a mass deportation of undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>Immigration was a top issue in the election campaign, and Trump has promised to deport millions and stabilize the border with Mexico after record numbers of migrants crossed illegally during President Joe Biden's administration.</p>

<p>On his social media platform Truth Social, Trump amplified a recent post by a conservative activist that said the president-elect was "prepared to declare a national emergency and will use military assets to reverse the Biden invasion through a mass deportation program."</p>

<p>Alongside the repost, Trump commented, "True!"</p>

<p>Trump sealed a remarkable comeback to the presidency in his November 5 defeat of Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>He has been announcing a cabinet featuring immigration hardliners, naming former Immigration and Customs Enforcement acting chief Tom Homan as his "border czar."</p>

<p>Homan appeared at the Republican National Convention in July, telling supporters: "I got a message to the millions of illegal immigrants that Joe Biden's released in our country: You better start packing now."</p>

<p>Authorities estimate that some 11 million people are living in the United States illegally. Trump's deportation plan is expected directly to impact around 20 million families.</p>

<p>While the US government has struggled for years to manage its southern border with Mexico, Trump has super-charged concerns by claiming an "invasion" is underway by migrants he says will rape and murder Americans.</p>

<p>During his campaign, Trump repeatedly railed against undocumented immigrants, employing incendiary rhetoric about foreigners who "poison the blood" of the United States and misleading his audiences about immigration statistics and policy.</p>

<p>Trump has not elaborated on his immigration crackdown in any detail but during his election campaign repeatedly vowed to invoke the Alien Enemies Act of 1798 to speed up deportations.</p>

<p>Critics say the law is outdated and point to its most recent use during World War II to hold Japanese-Americans in internment camps without due process.</p>

<p>The number of US border patrol encounters with migrants crossing from Mexico illegally is now about the same as in 2020, the last year of Trump's first term, after peaking at a record 250,000 for the month of December 2023.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c31dbfe8_trump_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has not elaborated on his immigration crackdown in any detail. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-global-south-impacted-by-food-fuel-fertiliser-crisis-amid-ongoing-conflicts-says-pm-modi-7049946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Global South Impacted By Food, Fuel Crisis Amid Conflicts: PM Modi At G20]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/g20-summit-global-south-impacted-by-food-fuel-fertiliser-crisis-amid-ongoing-conflicts-says-pm-modi-7049946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:29:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts, and G20 must focus on addressing the challenges, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts, and G20 must focus on addressing the challenges, Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Monday.</p>

<p>In an address on the first day of the G20 summit, PM Modi said India's G20 theme of "One Earth, One Family, One Future" is as relevant at the ongoing summit as it was last year.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, PM Modi, Chinese President Xi Jinping and British Prime Minister Keir Starmer are among the leaders attending the two-day summit at Rio de Janeiro's Modern Art Museum.</p>

<p>The people-centric decisions taken at the G20 Summit in New Delhi last year have been taken forward during Brazil's presidency of the bloc, PM Modi said.</p>

<p>"I would like to say that countries of the Global South are most adversely impacted by the food, fuel and fertilizer crisis caused by global conflicts," he said.</p>

<p>"So our discussions can only be successful when we keep in mind the challenges and priorities of the Global South," he added.</p>

<p>The prime minister made the remarks at the G20 session on 'Social Inclusion and the Fight Against Hunger and Poverty'.</p>

<p>The opening day's highlight was the launch of a global alliance to combat poverty and hunger that has been supported by at least 80 nations.</p>

<p>In his comments, PM Modi also called for reform of the institutions of global governance.</p>

<p>"And just as we amplified the voice of the Global South by granting permanent membership of G20 to the African Union during the New Delhi summit, we will reform institutions of global governance," he said.</p>

<p>The prime minister said India supports Brazil's initiative for a 'global alliance against hunger and poverty'.</p>

<p>"The people-centric decisions taken at the G20 Summit in New Delhi have been taken forward during Brazil's Presidency," he said.</p>

<p>"It is a matter of great satisfaction that we prioritised SDG (sustainable development goals). We focused on inclusive development, women-led development, and youth power," he said.</p>

<p>"And gave wings to the hopes and aspirations of the Global South. It is clear that One Earth One Family One Future is as relevant at this summit as it was last year," he added.</p>

<p>The theme of India's G20 presidency is drawn from the ancient Sanskrit text of Maha Upanishad.</p>

<p>"Over the last 10 years, we have lifted 250 million people out of poverty," PM Modi said.</p>

<p>In line with the theme of the session, PM Modi also gave an overview of India's success in addressing hunger and poverty.</p>

<p>"Over 800 million people are being given food grains free of cost. 550 million people are benefiting from the world's biggest health insurance scheme," he said.</p>

<p>"Now, 60 million senior citizens, over the age of 70, will also be able to benefit from free health insurance," he said.</p>

<p>"Maintaining our focus on women-led development and social inclusion, over 300 million women micro-entrepreneurs have been linked to banks and given access to credit," PM Modi added.</p>

<p>The prime minister also spoke about India's crop insurance scheme.</p>

<p>"Under the world's largest crop insurance scheme, over 40 million farmers have received benefits worth 20 billion US dollars," he said.</p>

<p>"Under the farmers' scheme, assistance worth over 40 billion dollars has been given to 110 million farmers. Institutional credit worth 300 billion US dollars is being given to farmers," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi said India is not only ensuring food security but also focusing on nutrition. He said New Delhi is also contributing to global food security by sending food items to various countries.</p>

<p>"The main reason for our success is our approach: 'back to basics' and 'march to the future'," he said.</p>

<p>"We have focused not only on natural farming and organic farming but also on new technologies. We have focused on sustainable agriculture, protection of the environment, nutrition and food security by promoting Sri Ann or millets," he said.</p>

<p>The prime minister said India has developed over 2000 climate-resilient crop varieties and has started the 'Digital Agriculture Mission'.</p>

<p>"India's digital public Infrastructure enabled social and financial inclusion. With the aspirational districts and blocks project, we created a new model for inclusive development that strengthens the weakest link," he said.</p>

<p>PM Modi began his visit to Brazil after concluding a two-day trip to Nigeria.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/52294rv8_narendra-modi-g20-brazil-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi made the remarks at the G20 summit in Brazil.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trumps-cabinet-choices-are-giving-pakistan-sleepless-nights-7050704]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Donald Trump's Cabinet Choices Are Giving Pakistan Sleepless Nights]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-donald-trumps-cabinet-choices-are-giving-pakistan-sleepless-nights-7050704]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:16:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan is keeping a very close watch on how Donald Trump's cabinet is shaping up as Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery over the decisions being made so far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan is keeping a very close watch on how Donald Trump's cabinet is shaping up as Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery over the decisions being made so far.</p>

<p>President-elect Trump has already picked a sizeable team for his second term in office as President, and policy makers, think tanks, and most of all, the Pakistani military establishment is reportedly having sleepless nights over key nominations.</p>

<p>Islamabad finds itself on a sticky-wicket as Trump's picks for Secretary of State, Secretary of Defence, National Security Adviser, and spy agency CIA chief all having very critical views of Pakistan while being much more considerate to New Delhi.</p>

<p>Not finding a place in Washington's foreign policy, top government and military officials in Pakistan are reportedly in a huddle to re-strategise its approach towards the United States.</p>

<h2><strong>SECRETARY OF STATE MARCO RUBIO</strong></h2>

<p>Senator Marko Rubio, who has been nominated as the next US Secretary of State, had introduced a bill fully endorsing India's views and concerns against Pakistan - a move that rang alarm bells in Pakistan Army headquarters in Rawalpindi.</p>

<p>Mr Rubio's proposed bill had mentioned Pakistan's direct involvement in sponsoring terrorism against India through various state-sponsored proxy groups, suggesting that Islamabad should not be given any US security assistance whatsoever.</p>

<p>Besides Pakistan, the bill, named 'US-India Defense Cooperation Act' and introduced in the Senate by Mr Rubio, also called for an extended defence cooperation with India to tackle China's increasing influence in the region.</p>

<p>According to the bill, Washington is advised to treat India at par with top US allies, including Japan, Israel, South Korea and NATO, on technology transfers. It also suggested that New Delhi should be provided with full security assistance through collaboration in defence, technology, economic investments and civil space.</p>

<h3><strong>NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER MIKE WALTZ</strong></h3>

<p>Another key figure in Donald Trump's new administration is Mike Waltz - a staunch Pakistan critic, who has been nominated as the next US National Security Adviser.</p>

<p>Mr Waltz has been very critical of Pakistan in the past, telling Islamabad that "terrorism cannot be a tool of foreign policy. Be it the Lashkar-e-Taiba or other terrorist groups - it is simply unacceptable, and the Pakistani government, the Pakistani military and its intelligence service (ISI) have to move past that."</p>

<p>He has called for significantly higher pressure on Islamabad to be held accountable for terror financing and for the country to completely eliminate cross-border terrorism. Mr Waltz's views match that of New Delhi's.</p>

<h3><strong>US NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE DIRECTOR TULSI GABBARD</strong></h3>

<p>Tulsi Gabbard, who is set to be the US Director of Intelligence, a top post in the Trump administration has fully backed India's stand on cross-border terrorism from Pakistan. Ms Gabbard had extended her full support to New Delhi in its military escalation with Islamabad after the 2019 Pulwama terror attack.</p>

<p>She has also slammed Pakistan on multiple occasions for giving shelter to then Al Qaeda chief Osama Bin Laden, who was killed in a US Navy Seals operation in Abbottabad in Pakistan in 2011.</p>

<h3><strong>CIA CHIEF JOHN RATCLIFFE</strong></h3>

<p>The next CIA chief John Ratcliffe is also known for his hawkish view on China and Iran and someone who will keep a close watch on Islamabad's actions too - both overt and covert.</p>

<p>As Donald Trump's cabinet takes shape, analysts believe it is getting increasingly difficult for Islamabad to have the kind of relations it desires with Washington, and that Pak PM Shehbaz Sharif must walk the talk on action against terrorism and terror financing. It is also observed that Donald Trump's cabinet picks are a message that Islamabad is not on his priority list and certainly nowhere near the importance given to New Delhi.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/au3tdfno_shehbaz-sharif-reuters_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As Donald Trump picks his cabinet, Islamabad is getting increasingly jittery with his selections]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-israel-to-target-hezbollah-despite-potential-lebanon-ceasefire-benjamin-netanyahu-7050622]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel To Target Hezbollah Despite Potential Lebanon Ceasefire: Netanyahu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-israel-to-target-hezbollah-despite-potential-lebanon-ceasefire-benjamin-netanyahu-7050622]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 23:55:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that Israel will continue to operate militarily against the Iran-backed Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah even if a ceasefire deal is reached in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Monday that Israel will continue to operate militarily against the Iran-backed Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah even if a ceasefire deal is reached in Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The most important thing is not (the deal that) will be laid on paper... We will be forced to ensure our security in the north (of Israel) and to systematically carry out operations against Hezbollah's attacks... even after a ceasefire", to keep the group from rebuilding its forces, Netanyahu told the Israeli parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h903pudo_netanyahu_625x300_10_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fined-25-4-million-by-india-antitrust-body-whatsapp-data-sharing-blocked-for-5-years-7050158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Fined $25.4 Million By India, WhatsApp Data Sharing Blocked For 5 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-fined-25-4-million-by-india-antitrust-body-whatsapp-data-sharing-blocked-for-5-years-7050158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 22:37:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India's competition watchdog directed WhatsApp to refrain from sharing user data for advertising purposes with other applications owned by Meta for a period of five years and fined the U.S. tech giant $25.4 million on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India's competition watchdog directed WhatsApp to refrain from sharing user data for advertising purposes with other applications owned by Meta for a period of five years and fined the U.S. tech giant $25.4 million on Monday over antitrust violations related to the messaging application's 2021 privacy policy.</p>

<p>The Competition Commission of India (CCI) launched a probe in March 2021 into WhatsApp's privacy policy, which allowed data sharing with Facebook and its units, sparking global backlash.</p>

<p>"Sharing of user data collected on WhatsApp with other Meta companies... for purposes other than for providing WhatsApp service shall not be made a condition for users to access WhatsApp Service in India," the CCI said.</p>

<p>Meta did not immediately respond to Reuters' request for comment.</p>

<p>Tech giants, including Apple, Google and Meta face new regulatory challenges with India's proposed EU-like antitrust law.</p>

<p>The Indian government is currently examining a February report from a panel established by the corporate affairs ministry. The report proposed a new "Digital Competition Bill" to complement existing antitrust laws.</p>

<p>The U.S.-India Business Council, a key U.S. lobby group has already opposed the move, fearing its business impact.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dlcdtomo_meta-generic_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta faces new regulatory challenges with India's proposed EU-like antitrust law. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-peace-in-middle-east-might-be-beyond-donald-trumps-dealmaking-skills-7050063]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Peace In The Middle East Might Be Beyond Trump's Deal-Making Skills]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-peace-in-middle-east-might-be-beyond-donald-trumps-dealmaking-skills-7050063]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 22:27:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trumps re-election as the US president last week comes at a time of extreme volatility in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump's re-election as the US president last week comes at a time of extreme volatility in the Middle East.</p>

<p>The president-elect has promised to end all wars. In his usual impulsive and unpredictable manner, he has pledged to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-russia-ukraine-war-un-election-a78ecb843af452b8dda1d52d137ca893">resolve</a> the Ukraine war within 24 hours of taking office and help Israel <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-mideast-netanyahu-israel-gaza-iran-wars-2e37305522d19bdc34e956586cce99bd">finish</a> its Gaza and Lebanon operations quickly.</p>

<p>Yet the Middle East is a complex place. Trump will have much difficulty balancing his ardent support of Israel and his other ambitions in the region, especially given the changing dynamics between Iran and its rival, Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Here's what Trump can expect when he takes office in a few months.</p>

<h2>Collapse of talks between Israel and Hamas</h2>

<p>Overshadowed by the US election was Qatar's announcement that it has <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/09/politics/qatar-gaza-ceasefire-pause-mediator/index.html">paused</a> its role as a ceasefire mediator between Israel and Hamas.</p>

<p>The tiny, oil-rich emirate has worked hard over the past year to try to reach a deal to end the war. In the process, it made good use of its close relations with the United States, which has its largest Middle East military base in Qatar, and with Hamas, whose political leadership and office have been based in Doha. This, Qatar believed, would help it gain the confidence of the warring parties.</p>

<p>However, its efforts did not produce anything more than a <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2023/11/27/middleeast/israel-hamas-truce-extended-intl/index.html">brief ceasefire</a> last year, which resulted in the release of more than 100 Israeli hostages in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Lebanon Ceasefire: Israel and Lebanon are reportedly “in advanced stages” of reaching a ceasefire agreement. This deal appears to attempt to more successfully implement UNSCR 1701, which prohibits Lebanese Hezbollah military activity in southern Lebanon. <a href="https://t.co/lV2KCHvNcj">https://t.co/lV2KCHvNcj</a> <a href="https://t.co/Qq9Gb20icw">pic.twitter.com/Qq9Gb20icw</a></p>
— Institute for the Study of War (@TheStudyofWar) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheStudyofWar/status/1851452376185520352?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>There are several reasons for this.</p>

<p>For one, the two sides cannot get past a couple of main sticking points. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has resolved to eliminate Hamas completely, ruling out a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-news-06-24-2024-f5de2ed8288ac3cdb02c4e9e2fbaeda1">temporary truce</a>. Hamas is demanding a complete end to the fighting and total Israeli military withdrawal from Gaza.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Washington has failed to play a meaningful role in the talks. While repeatedly emphasising its desire for a ceasefire, the Biden administration did not at any point put tangible pressure on Israel beyond diplomatic rhetoric.</p>

<p>It has also refused to cut off military aid to Israel. Instead, it <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-gaza-20-billion-weapons-us-aid-b6a99129c88a5dcc4a4753e20b5e19ec">approved a US$20&nbsp;billion</a> (A$30&nbsp;billion) arms sale to Israel in August. This means Netanyahu has had no compelling reason to divert from his mission.</p>

<h2>A possible ceasefire in Lebanon</h2>

<p>As the chances of a Gaza ceasefire have faded, hopes have been raised about a Lebanon ceasefire.</p>

<p>Washington has reportedly <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o">engaged</a> in intensive diplomatic efforts to get Israel and Hezbollah to reach a common ground to end the fighting there.</p>

<p>Israel wants Hezbollah to be disarmed and pushed back at least beyond the Litani River in southern Lebanon – about 30km north of the Israeli border – with a security zone to be established between the two. Israel <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c14ln6kkkg7o">wants to maintain</a> the right to strike Hezbollah if necessary, which Lebanese authorities are likely to reject.</p>

<p>Israel has considerably weakened Hezbollah in its bombing and ground invasion of southern Lebanon at the expense of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-lebanon-hezbollah-news-10-16-2024-f18b2e0f5e05eb11a3c2ee29c16ed867">massive civilian casualties</a>.</p>

<p>However, just as Israel has not been able to wipe out Hamas, it has so far <a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/targeted-killings-wont-destroy-hezbollah">not succeeded in crippling Hezbollah</a> to the extent it would be forced to accept a ceasefire on Israel's terms. The militant group continues to possess sufficient political and military prowess to remain resilient.</p>

<h2>Changing regional dynamics</h2>

<p>Now, Trump re-enters the scene.</p>

<p>His electoral triumph has comforted Netanyahu's government to the extent that his finance minister, Bezalel Smotrich, has <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/smotrich-says-trumps-victory-an-opportunity-to-apply-sovereignty-in-the-west-bank/">asked</a> the relevant authorities to prepare for the formal annexation of Jewish settlements in the West Bank.</p>

<p>Trump has been a committed supporter of Israel for a long time. During his first presidency he <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/12/06/world/middleeast/trump-jerusalem-israel-capital.html">recognised</a> Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and ordered the US embassy to move there. He also <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-47697717">recognised</a> Israeli sovereignty over the Golan Heights, which Israel seized from Syria in 1967.</p>

<p>He castigated Iran as the real villain in the region and <a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/briefings-statements/president-donald-j-trump-ending-united-states-participation-unacceptable-iran-deal/">withdrew</a> the US from the multilateral Iran nuclear agreement. He also instigated the <a href="https://www.state.gov/the-abraham-accords/">Abraham Accords</a>, in which several Arab states normalised relations with Israel.</p>

<p>However, the Gaza and Lebanon wars, as well as the direct military exchanges between Israel and Iran over the past year, have changed the regional texture.</p>

<p>Trump has voiced unwavering backing of Israel against Hamas and Hezbollah, and is likely to resuscitate his “<a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/national-security-daily/2024/11/08/a-sneak-peak-on-trumps-iran-policy-00183727">maximum pressure</a>” campaign against Iran. This could involve strangling Tehran with stringent sanctions and blocking its oil exports, while seeking to isolate it internationally.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">President-elect Donald Trump plans to drastically increase sanctions on Iran and throttle its oil sales, according to people briefed on his early plans <a href="https://t.co/43wvCXt5NH">https://t.co/43wvCXt5NH</a></p>
— The Wall Street Journal (@WSJ) <a href="https://twitter.com/WSJ/status/1855081421129367813?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, as a transactional leader, Trump also wants to strengthen America's lucrative economic and trade ties with the Arab governments of the region.</p>

<p>However, these countries have been shaken by the scale of Israel's Gaza and Lebanon operations. Their populations are boiling over with frustration at their leaders' inability to counter Israel's actions. This is nowhere more evident than in <a href="https://www.barrons.com/news/jordanians-boiling-with-anger-at-gaza-spurring-israel-border-attacks-f09c55ae">Jordan</a>.</p>

<p>As a result, Saudi Arabia – America's richest and most consequential Arab ally in the region – has lately <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/11/11/israeli-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-on-arab-islamic-summit-agenda-in-saudi-arabia">taken the lead</a> in voicing strong opposition to Israel. Saudi Arabia's de facto ruler, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, has also made a path toward an independent Palestinian state a <a href="https://www.middleeasteye.net/news/saudi-crown-prince-says-no-normalisation-israel-without-palestinian-statehood">condition</a> of normalising relations with Israel.</p>

<p>Further, Riyadh is strengthening its more than year-long rapprochement with its arch rival, Iran. The two countries' defence ministers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-armed-forces-general-chief-staff-hold-talks-iran-2024-11-10/">met</a> last weekend, following a <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/iran-and-saudi-arabia-hold-joint-naval-exercise-in-sea-of-oman/">joint military exercise</a> involving their navies.</p>

<p>In addition, Bin Salman has just <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/12/middleeast/saudi-mbs-accuses-israel-genocide-gaza-intl/index.html">convened</a> a meeting of Arab and Muslim leaders in Riyadh to forge a consensual position in dealing with Israel and the incoming Trump administration.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Gulf states wary of return to Trump's ‘maximum pressure' against Iran <a href="https://t.co/CogsazuGbf">https://t.co/CogsazuGbf</a></p>
— Financial Times (@FT) <a href="https://twitter.com/FT/status/1856293825922138268?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h2>Where is it all heading?</h2>

<p>Trump will need to find a balance between his commitment to Israel and upholding America's close relations with its traditional Arab allies. This will be crucial to ending the Middle East wars and rebuffing Iran.</p>

<p>Tehran is no longer as vulnerable to Trump's venom as it may have been in the past. It is more powerful militarily and enjoys strong strategic relations with Russia, China and North Korea, as well as improved relations with regional Arab states.</p>

<p>Given the absence of a Gaza ceasefire, the thin hope of a halt to the Lebanon fighting, Netanyahu's intransigence and Trump's pursuance of an “Israel first” policy, the Middle East's volatility is likely to persist.</p>

<p>It may prove to be as much of a headache for Trump as it was for Joe Biden in a very polarised and unpredictable world.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/243570/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em>(<strong>Author:</strong> <span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amin-saikal-1413547">Amin Saikal</a>, Emeritus Professor of Middle Eastern and Central Asian Studies, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/australian-national-university-877">Australian National University</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:</strong> Amin Saikal does not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and has disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment.)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/donald-trump-fancies-himself-a-skilled-dealmaker-but-middle-east-peace-might-be-beyond-him-243570">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/48oemgp_israel-us-reuters_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has voiced unwavering backing of Israel against Hamas and Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-62-000-dead-in-sudans-civil-war-real-figure-might-be-far-higher-7049900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[At Least 62,000 Dead In Sudan's Civil War, Real Figure Might Be Far Higher]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-least-62-000-dead-in-sudans-civil-war-real-figure-might-be-far-higher-7049900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:59:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ongoing war in Sudan has often been overlooked amid higher-profile conflicts raging across multiple continents.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.cfr.org/global-conflict-tracker/conflict/power-struggle-sudan">ongoing war in Sudan</a> has often been overlooked amid higher-profile conflicts raging across multiple continents. Yet the lack of media and geopolitical attention to this 18-month-long conflict has not made its devastation in terms of human lives any less stark.</p>

<p>Since fighting broke out in April 2023 between the Sudanese Armed Forces and the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, both of which had been part of a power-sharing military government, the country has seen the displacement of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-war-refugees-displaced-un-8672055b2a23b019662e8005a8c54e77">more than 14 million people</a> and the carving up of the country by geography and ideology.</p>

<p>And while we may never know the exact death toll, the conflict in Sudan is certainly among the deadliest in the world today.</p>

<p>As scholars of <a href="https://pul.uclouvain.be/author/?person_id=5196">public health</a>, conflict and <a href="https://publichealth.berkeley.edu/people/rohini-haar">human rights</a> and <a href="https://sapa-usa.org/team/">Sudanese-American health workers</a>, we are keenly aware of how fraught it can be to estimate mortality in war for a slew of practical and political reasons. But such estimates are of critical importance: They allow us to understand and compare conflicts, target humanitarian aid for those still at risk, trigger investigations of war crimes, bear witness to conflict and compel states and armed groups to intervene or change.</p>

<h2>The difficult work of counting the dead</h2>

<p>A profound humanitarian crisis is occurring in Sudan, characterized by <a href="https://www.hrw.org/news/2024/05/09/sudan-ethnic-cleansing-west-darfur">ethnic cleansing</a>, <a href="https://dtm.iom.int/sudan">mass displacement</a>, <a href="https://www.wfp.org/countries/sudan">food scarcity</a> and the <a href="https://www.unicef.org/sudan/press-releases/over-three-million-children-heighted-risk-cholera-and-other-deadly-diseases-sudan">spread of disease</a>, complicated further by flooding in the northern states.</p>

<p>Considering a death toll in such a conflict includes counting not only those who are killed as a direct result of violence – itself a difficult thing to determine in real time – but also those who have died by conflict-exacerbated factors, such as the absence of emergency care, the breakdown of vaccination programs and a lack of essential food and medicine. Estimating this latter death toll, called indirect mortality, presents its own challenge, as the definition itself varies among researchers.</p>

<p>In congressional testimony, U.S. special envoy to Sudan Tom Perriello <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/05/28/sudan-war-genocide-el-fasher-humanitarian-aid-crisis/">recognized the estimation challenges</a> when noting there had been anywhere between 15,000 and 150,000 deaths in Sudan – an exceedingly wide range that was attributable, in part, to the complexity of determining indirect mortality.</p>

<p><a href="https://acleddata.com/">Armed Conflict Location and Event Data</a> (ACLED), a nonprofit specializing in conflict-related data collection, <a href="https://acleddata.com/">has recorded</a> an average of more than 1,200 direct conflict deaths per month in Sudan, with nearly 19,000 deaths in the first 15 months of the conflict. This figure is similar to the 20,000 deaths <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">estimated</a> by the Sudan Doctors Union and the 19,000 <a href="https://reliefweb.int/report/sudan/glance-protection-impacts-conflict-update-no-29-15-july-2024">figure used by</a> the Sudan Protection Cluster, a centralized group of U.N. agencies and NGOs that used World Health Organization data.</p>

<p>ACLED <a href="https://acleddata.com/knowledge-base/faqs-acled-sourcing-methodology/">sources its estimates</a> of deaths from traditional media, reports from international NGOs and local observers, supplemented by new media such as verified Telegram and WhatsApp accounts. The Sudan Doctors Union, on the other hand, gives on-the-ground estimates of conflict deaths.</p>

<p>When available, distinct data sources such as surveys, civil registers and official body counts can make an estimation more accurate. However, this data is often available only in retrospect, after the cessation of conflict. It is therefore critical to use both the available data and precedents from previous conflicts to capture a reasonable estimate of the human costs of an ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>A 2010 article in The Lancet estimated that there are <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20109956/">2.3 indirect deaths for every direct conflict death</a>, based on data from 24 small-scale surveys conducted in Darfur from 2003 to 2005. As such, using ACLED's data of 18,916 direct deaths, we estimate that in the current Sudan conflict, there are an additional 43,507 indirect deaths – or more than 62,000 total deaths.</p>

<p>We believe our estimate is very conservative. When estimating mortality in the ongoing conflict in Gaza, a different group of scholars, <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(24)01169-3/fulltext">also writing in The Lancet</a>, used a multiplier of four indirect deaths for every direct death to estimate the overall mortality there.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a <a href="https://www.refworld.org/reference/research/gds/2008/en/64390">report from the Geneva Declaration Secretariat</a> showed an average of 5.8 indirect deaths for every direct death across 13 armed conflicts from 1974 to 2007.</p>

<p>Using that latter multiplier, the number of indirect deaths in Sudan would jump to nearly 110,000 – meaning the total deaths in the region amount to 130,000 – double our estimate.</p>

<p>This range is wide, but it acknowledges how difficult it can be to estimate indirect deaths and how they can vary significantly with the shape of a conflict.</p>

<h2>The Sudanese conflict in context</h2>

<p>For all the tremendous loss of life these numbers reflect, they surely underestimate the true human costs of the conflict.</p>

<p>Sudan <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10928779/">already had a fragile</a> and <a href="https://doi.org//10.1007/s40475-021-00237-2">underfunded health system</a> before the fighting started. And compared with other ongoing conflicts such as in <a href="https://www.unicef.org/sop/what-we-do/health-and-nutrition">Gaza</a> and <a href="https://data.unicef.org/country/ukr/">Ukraine</a>, there was already a more precarious baseline, with <a href="https://data.unicef.org/country/sdn/">higher child mortality</a> and lower life expectancy.</p>

<p><iframe class="tc-infographic-datawrapper" frameborder="0" height="400px" id="w2RzA" scrolling="no" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/w2RzA/1/" style="border: 0;" width="100%"></iframe></p>

<p>Since the <a href="https://reliefweb.int/country/sdn">war in Sudan</a> began, there have been <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2023/08/sudan-war-crimes-rampant-as-civilians-killed-in-both-deliberate-and-indiscriminate-attacks-new-report/">consistent reports</a> of <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/11/10/corpses-on-streets-sudans-rsf-kills-1300-in-darfur-monitors-say">mass killings</a>, forced disappearances, <a href="https://www.un.org/africarenewal/magazine/july-2023/sudan-un-condemns-spike-violence-against-women-and-girls">sexual violence</a>, deliberate blocking of food and medicine, and other forms of <a href="https://www.hrw.org/report/2024/05/09/massalit-will-not-come-home/ethnic-cleansing-and-crimes-against-humanity-el">violence against civilians</a>.</p>

<p>Much of the violence is ethnically targeted, and the Darfur region – where a <a href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/famine-confirmed-sudans-north-darfur-confirming-un-agencies-worst-fears">full-scale famine has been declared</a> – has suffered disproportionately.</p>

<p>The destruction of civilian infrastructure and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-darfur-starvation-violence-united-nations-295c2bf7ac311313313dd44d021d8d11">interrupted aid mechanisms</a> are preventing medicine, food, clean water and vaccinations from getting to in-need populations.</p>

<p>Health care workers and facilities, not only in at-risk Darfur but also throughout the country, <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">have been the target of attacks</a>. Nearly 80% of medical facilities have been rendered inoperable. And at least 58 physicians <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/node/5034313">have been killed</a>, in addition to the many that were <a href="https://phr.org/our-work/resources/chaos-and-fire-an-analysis-of-sudans-june-3-2019-khartoum-massacre/">targeted in previous crises</a>.</p>

<p>Given the persistent targeting of health care systems and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/attack-icrc-convoy-sudans-south-darfur-kills-two-drivers-injures-three-2024-05-03/">restricted access to humanitarian corridors</a>, indirect deaths in Sudan are likely to grow as hospitals shut down, even in the capital Khartoum, due to bombardments, ground attacks and a lack of critical supplies.</p>

<p>The costs for Sudanese children are especially alarming. Thirteen children die per day in Zamzam camp in North Darfur, according to Doctors Without Borders, mostly due to <a href="https://www.msf.org/sudan-urgent-response-needed-amid-high-death-rates-and-malnutrition-crisis-north-darfur">undernutrition and food scarcity</a>.</p>

<p>And nearly 800,000 Sudanese children will <a href="https://www.unicef.org/press-releases/famine-confirmed-sudans-north-darfur-confirming-un-agencies-worst-fears">face severe, acute malnutrition</a> through 2024, a condition that requires intensive care and supplemental nutrition merely to prevent death. Even before the conflict, children were severely threatened <a href="https://data.who.int/countries/729">by a lack of access to care</a>, including basic preventive care such as early immunization.</p>

<p>Finally, the transmission of communicable diseases <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33692451/">thrives in conflicts like the one in Sudan</a>, where there has been widespread population displacement, malnutrition, limited water and sanitation, and lack of appropriate sheltering. In August, a <a href="https://www.care.org/news-and-stories/press-releases/care-statement-on-spread-of-cholera-in-sudan/">cholera outbreak</a> led to a <a href="https://www.aa.com.tr/en/africa/death-toll-from-cholera-outbreak-in-sudan-reaches-348/3335522">spiking death rate</a> of more than 31 deaths per 1,000 cholera cases. And instances of such disease effects are likely underestimates in a country lacking health care penetration and monitoring.</p>

<h2>The limitations of estimations</h2>

<p>The massive internal displacement of <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sudan-war-refugees-displaced-un-8672055b2a23b019662e8005a8c54e77">more than 14 million people</a> in Sudan complicates the estimation of death tolls, as shifting populations make establishing baselines nearly impossible.</p>

<p>Moreover, there is typically a <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37193053/">dearth of official information collected and released</a> during conflicts.</p>

<p>So establishing a concrete estimate of the true impact of armed conflict <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/stories/2022/11/forensic-investigators-bring-dr-congo-victims-closer-justice">often comes</a> after the cessation of hostilities, <a href="https://icmp.int/press-releases/icmp-assists-serbia-in-excavation-of-mass-grave-near-raska/">when expert teams</a> <a href="https://www.sapiens.org/archaeology/cyprus-war-missing/">are able</a> <a href="https://www.iclvr.ie/en/iclvr/pages/thedisappeared">to conduct</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.geoforum.2013.12.011">field studies</a>.</p>

<p>Even then, estimates will require assumptions about direct deaths, indirect-to-direct death ratio and the quality of existing data.</p>

<p>But as scholars working at the intersection of public health and human rights, we believe such work, however imperfect, is necessary for the documentation of conflict – and its future prevention. And while there are many current global conflicts that require our urgent attention, the conflict in Sudan must not be lost in the mix.</p>

<p>_Editor's note: Israa Hassan, a physical medicine and rehabilitation resident at Texas Rehabilitation Hospital-Fort Worth and <a href="https://sapa-usa.org/about-us/">advocacy director at the Sudanese American Physicians Association</a>, contributed to this article.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/242073/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Authors:</strong> <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/sarah-elizabeth-scales-2246791">Sarah Elizabeth Scales</a>, Post-Doctoral Researcher, Department of Environmental, Occupational, and Agricultural Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-nebraska-medical-center-5675">University of Nebraska Medical Center</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/blake-erhardt-ohren-2247945">Blake Erhardt-Ohren</a>, DrPH Candidate, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-california-berkeley-754">University of California, Berkeley</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/debarati-guha-sapir-2247595">Debarati Guha Sapir</a>, Professor of Public Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/universite-catholique-de-louvain-uclouvain-697">Université catholique de Louvain (UCLouvain)</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/khidir-dalouk-2247625">Khidir Dalouk</a>, Assistant Professor of Medicine, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/oregon-health-and-science-university-3386">Oregon Health &amp; Science University</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/rohini-j-haar-2241539">Rohini J Haar</a>, Faculty, Epidemiology Division, School of Public Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-california-berkeley-754">University of California, Berkeley</a>)</span></em></p>

<p><em><span>(<strong>Disclosure Statement:&nbsp;</strong></span>Rohini J Haar receives funding from FCDO. Blake Erhardt-Ohren, Debarati Guha Sapir, Khidir Dalouk, and Sarah Elizabeth Scales do not work for, consult, own shares in or receive funding from any company or organisation that would benefit from this article, and have disclosed no relevant affiliations beyond their academic appointment)</em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/sudans-civil-war-has-left-at-least-62-000-dead-by-our-estimate-but-the-true-figure-could-be-far-higher-242073">original article</a>.</em><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ehg8ip3s_sudan-civil-war-afp_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fighting broke out in April 2023 between the Sudanese Armed Forces and paramilitary Rapid Support Forces]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carrot-recall-announced-in-us-after-e-coli-outbreak-in-18-states-7049588]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Carrot Recall Announced Across US After E. Coli Outbreak In 18 States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/carrot-recall-announced-in-us-after-e-coli-outbreak-in-18-states-7049588]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:33:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Organic carrots and baby carrots sold in grocery stores across the United States are being recalled after an E. coli outbreak that has left at least one person dead and 15 others hospitalized.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Organic carrots and baby carrots sold in grocery stores across the United States are being recalled after an E. coli outbreak that has left at least one person dead and 15 others hospitalised. The move came after the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) on Sunday flagged the new E. coli outbreak linked to organic carrots sold by Grimmway Farms to big supermarkets-- including Trader Joe's, Whole Foods's 365, Walmart's Marketside, Target's Good &amp; Gather, among others</p>

<p>So far, 39 cases have been reported across 18 states tied the E. coli infections linked with fresh carrots, the CDC said in a statement.</p>

<h2><strong>Health Advisory</strong></h2>

<p>The CDC urged people to not eat any recalled carrots and to wash items and surfaces that may have touched the bagged organic root veggie using hot, soapy water or a dishwasher. The carrots are unlikely to still be on store shelves, but may still be in consumers' homes and should be thrown away, the agency said.</p>

<h3><strong>Carrots Recalled</strong></h3>

<p>As per the US Food and Drug Administration, Grimmway Farms had issued a voluntary recall of the carrots, which were also shipped to stores in Canada and Puerto Rico.</p>

<p>Notably, the recalled whole organic carrots had best-if-used-by dates ranging from August 14 through October 23, while the recalled baby carrots had dates from September 11 through November 12.</p>

<p>Grimmway Farms, which was located in California, said in a Saturday press release that the company is reviewing its growing, harvesting and processing practices and that it is working with suppliers and health authorities on the matter. The previously family-owned company was reportedly sold to private equity firm Teays River Investments in 2020.</p>

<h3><strong>E. coli Poisoning Symptoms</strong></h3>

<p>Most Escherichia coli (E. coli) bacteria reside harmlessly in the intestines of people and animals. But some can cause mild to life-threatening gastrointestinal illnesses if consumed, according to the CDC.</p>

<p>Symptoms of E. coli poisoning, including dehydration, bloody diarrhoea, vomiting, abdominal cramps and fever, appear between two to eight days after exposure.</p>

<p>Most people recover without treatment after five to seven days. In rare cases, especially seen among older adults and children under 5, people may develop a type of kidney failure called hemolytic uremic syndrome (HUS) which is marked by easy bruising, pallor, and decreased urine output. These people should seek emergency medical care immediately.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n7sih2e_carrots-pixabay_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Carrots recalled across the US after an E. Coli outbreak in more than a dozen states (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-bangladesh-ties-dhaka-islamabad-inch-closer-with-historic-sea-link-1st-since-1971-how-it-impacts-india-7048203]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dhaka, Islamabad Inch Closer With Historic Sea Link. How It Impacts India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-bangladesh-ties-dhaka-islamabad-inch-closer-with-historic-sea-link-1st-since-1971-how-it-impacts-india-7048203]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:14:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Pakistani cargo ship docked at Bangladeshs Chittagong port last week, marking the first-ever direct maritime contact between the two countries in over five decades. The vessel from Karachi has successfully unloaded its containers at the post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Pakistani cargo ship docked at Bangladesh's Chittagong port last week, marking the first-ever direct maritime contact between the two countries in over five decades. The vessel from Karachi has successfully unloaded its containers at Bangladesh's southeastern coast, port officials told news agency AFP on Sunday, as both sides seek to rebuild ties frosty since the 1971 Bangladesh Liberation War.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The direct maritime links between Pakistan and Bangladesh underscores a historic shift in the traditionally complex relationship between India's western and eastern neighbours. It also has implications on New Delhi's security establishment especially due to Bangladesh's proximity to India's northeastern states.</p>

<h2><strong>Docking Of Pakistani Vessel In Bangladesh</strong></h2>

<p>The Panama-flagged Yuan Xiang Fa Zhan, an 182-metre (597-foot) long container ship, had sailed from Pakistan's Karachi to Bangladesh's Chittagong. The ship had offloaded its cargo in Bangladesh on November 11 before leaving port, AFP reported quoting top Chittagong official Omar Faruq.</p>

<p>Chittagong port authorities reportedly said the ship brought goods from Pakistan and the United Arab Emirates, including raw materials for Bangladesh's key garment industry and basic food items.</p>

<p>Pakistani goods were previously transferred onto feeder vessels, usually in Sri Lanka, Malaysia or Singapore, before being transported to Bangladesh. However, in September, Bangladesh, under the new interim government led by Muhammad Yunus, eased import restrictions on Pakistani goods, which previously required a mandatory physical inspection on arrival resulting in long delays.</p>

<p>The opening of the direct maritime link is being seen as an attempt by Bangladesh's interim government to have robust ties with Pakistan.</p>

<p>There has been widespread discussion on social media in Bangladesh after a post by Pakistan's envoy to Dhaka, Syed Ahmed Maroof, about the direct shipping route being "a major step" in boosting trade between the two nations.</p>

<p>The route will "promote new opportunities for businesses on both sides", Mr Maroof wrote on Facebook.</p>

<h3><strong>Bangladesh-Pakistan Relations And Shadow Of 1971 Liberation War</strong></h3>

<p>Pakistan and Bangladesh - once one nation - split in 1971 following Mukti Juddho (Liberation War). The memory of the brutal war, which saw the killing of some 3 million people and the rape and torture of tens of thousands of others, remained deeply imprinted in Bangladesh's national psyche till recently.</p>

<p>Formerly known as East Pakistan, Bangladesh became an independent nation after a nine-month war with West Pakistan in 1971 in which India aided Bengali freedom fighters.</p>

<p>The bilateral ties between Pakistan and Bangladesh have remained sour since the Liberation War, more so under Sheikh Hasina's regime in Dhaka, whose central political agenda had been to seek justice for atrocities committed by Pakistan during the brutal war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Hasina, who ruled Bangladesh from 1996-2001 and 2009-2024, set up the International Crimes Tribunal in 2010 to prosecute war criminals or <em>razakars</em> for their war crimes in 1971. She also banned the historically pro-Pakistan Jamaat-e-Islami, whose leader Abdul Quader Mollah was convicted by the ICT in 2013 for war crimes. Mollah became the first of many <em>razakars</em> to be executed during Ms Hasina's reign.</p>

<h3><strong>India-Bangladesh Relation Post-1971</strong></h3>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Hasina kept bringing Bangladesh closer to India over the year. India already held a close bond with Bangladeshis, courtesy of New Delhi's assistance in the Bangladesh Liberation War.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ousted former Prime Minister and her family reportedly enjoyed a close personal relationship with the Nehru-Gandhi family, but her government's clampdown on terrorism and religious extremism proved to be a strategic glue that bound successive Indian governments to her regime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Her relationship with New Delhi helped her flee to India on August 5 after a student-led revolution against her regime escalated. But, Bangladesh's ties with New Delhi frayed after the toppling of her autocratic Hasina regime.</p>

<h3><strong>Hasina's Ouster</strong></h3>

<p>For years, Ms Hasina reaped political mileage from her party and family's contribution to Bangladesh's liberation, however, the recent protests across the nation seem to indicate that the sentiment does not echo many.</p>

<p>So, when Ms Hasina branded the protestors as <em>"razakars"</em> in July, it backfired, leading to outrage amidst real social and economic concerns plaguing the country.</p>

<p>Furthermore, there was reportedly resentment among Bangladeshis against Ms Hasina for “cozying up” to New Delhi. As per a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/pakistani-cargo-bangladesh-9671748/" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Indian Express</a>, many in Bangladesh felt that India was too involved in the country's matters. The growing “anti-India” sentiment in Bangladesh was on display when a mob in August vandalised and torched the Indira Gandhi Cultural Centre (IGCC), the hub of Indian cultural activity in the Bangladeshi capital for over five decades.</p>

<p>The Jamaat-e-Islami, which opposed the creation of Bangladesh, has a strong presence in the post-Hasina dispensation in Dhaka.</p>

<h3><strong>Growing Pakistan and Bangladesh Ties</strong></h3>

<p>After Ms Hasina's ouster, Mr Yunus' interim government has shown a shift towards closer ties with Pakistan. Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif of Pakistan and Mr Yunus discussed strengthening bilateral cooperation on the sidelines of the United Nations General Assembly in September this year.</p>

<p>“The maritime link is essential for reviving our relations,” Mr Yunus recently said, calling for a “new page” in Pakistan-Bangladesh ties to enhance cooperation in different sectors.</p>

<p>Bangladesh also seems to be going the Pakistan way with the country's Attorney General Md Asaduzzaman calling for removing the words “socialism” and “secularism” from Bangladesh's constitution. The proposal has sparked fears the predominantly Muslim nation could be shifting toward an Islamic state.</p>

<p>Moreover, Bangladesh is also seeking the extradition of ousted Ms Hasina, who remains in exile in India. Dhaka has already issued an arrest warrant for the 77-year-old and has summoned her to appear in court in Dhaka to face charges of "massacres, killings, and crimes against humanity".</p>

<p>Mr Yunus said his administration was focused on ensuring those guilty of cracking down on the protests to oust Ms Hasina faced justice.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old Nobel Peace Prize winner was appointed to lead the government as "chief advisor" on August 9, days after the end of Ms Hasina's 15 years of iron-fisted rule. Mr Yunus, in a speech to the nation marking 100 days in power since a student-led revolution, said he had spoken to Karim Khan, chief prosecutor of the International Criminal Court.</p>

<p>"We will seek the extradition of the ousted autocrat from India," Mr Yunus said, referring to Ms Hasina.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, Bangladesh said it would request an Interpol "red notice" alert for fugitive leaders of Ms Hasina's regime. Red notices issued by the global police body alert law enforcement agencies worldwide about fugitives.</p>

<p>India is a member of Interpol, but the red notice does not mean New Delhi must hand Ms Hasina over. Member countries can "apply their own laws in deciding whether to arrest a person", according to the group, which organises police cooperation between 196 member countries.</p>

<h3><strong>Impact On India</strong></h3>

<p>With increasing narcotics trade linked to Pakistan, growing ties between Islamabad and Dhaka could become a national security concern for India&nbsp; Another security concern for New Delhi is the involvement of Pakistan's spy agency ISI in activities that destabilise the region.</p>

<p>Over the years, India has used its relationship with Ms Hasina to keep an eye on the activities at Chittagong port, where in 2004, around 1,500 boxes of Chinese ammunitions were confiscated. The consignment, reportedly worth an estimated USD 4.5-7 million, was allegedly masterminded by Pakistan's intelligence agency, the Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI).</p>

<p>The consignment was allegedly meant to be delivered to banned terrorist outfit ULFA (United Liberation Front of Asom) in India.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus however, has assured that Dhaka-Delhi relations should be "very close" despite the recent regime change in the country, asserting that it is in the interest of both countries.</p>

<p>"Relations between the two countries must be very close. There can be no alternative to this. They need this, we need this. This is essential from any angle, whether it's about economics, security or water," he was quoted as saying by Bengali language daily <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/interview/ox81d7gkfs" rel="No Follow, No Index" target="_blank">Prothom Alo</a> in October.</p>

<p>When asked for his comments on recent tensions in bilateral ties, Mr Yunus said the recent incidents in Bangladesh might have "disheartened" India and "they were not pleased with the changes." He did not mention the incidents.</p>

<p>"It will be difficult for us to move along without each other. It is only natural that we have close ties and good relations in every sphere,” he said.</p>

<p>India has urged the interim Bangladesh government to ensure peaceful religious events for the Hindu community in the South Asian country. More than 600 persons, including Hindus, were killed during violent protests in Bangladesh following the ouster of Hasina-led government, according to a UN report.</p>

<p>"Things will be clear to them when they see that the entire world is accepting us, how can they not accept us?" he added.</p>

<p>He said as far as South Asian diplomacy was concerned, his interim government placed high importance on strengthening ties with India and "at the same time, strengthening SAARC (South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation".<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h818gimg_merchant-ship-yuan-xiang-fa-zhan_625x300_18_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cargo ship Yuan Xiang Fa Zhan, carring goods from Pak, docked at Bangladesh's Chittagong port]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-ready-to-deliver-on-common-understandings-between-pm-modi-xi-jinping-says-china-7049026]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Ready To Deliver On Common Understandings Between PM Modi-Xi": China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-china-ties-ready-to-deliver-on-common-understandings-between-pm-modi-xi-jinping-says-china-7049026]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 19:53:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China said it stands ready to deliver on important common understandings reached between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the recent BRICS summit leading to a thaw in the relations frozen for over four years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China on Monday said it stands ready to deliver on important common understandings reached between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping during the recent BRICS summit leading to a thaw in the relations frozen for over four years due to a military standoff in Eastern Ladakh.</p>

<p>“Recently, President Xi Jinping met with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi on the margins of the BRICS summit held in Kazan,” Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Lin Jian told a media briefing here while responding to a question on the likelihood of a meeting the two leaders on the sidelines of G20 summit in Brazil.</p>

<p>“China stands ready to work with India to deliver on the important common understandings between the leaders of the two countries, step up communication and cooperation and enhance strategic mutual trust,” he said, adding that he has no information on the specifics of the meeting of the leaders and officials.</p>

<p>At their Kazan meeting, the two leaders endorsed the India-China agreement on patrolling and disengagement along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh and issued directions to revive various bilateral dialogue mechanisms, signalling attempts to normalise ties that were hit by a deadly military clash in 2020.</p>

<p>In the nearly 50-minute meeting held on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit at Kazan, PM Modi underscored the importance of properly handling differences and disputes and not allowing them to disturb peace and tranquility in border areas and that mutual trust, mutual respect and mutual sensitivity should remain the basis of the relations.</p>

<p>Xi said China-India relations are essentially a question of how the two large developing countries and neighbours, each with a 1.4-billion-strong population, treat each other.</p>

<p>China and India should maintain a sound strategic perception of each other and work together to find the "right and bright path" for big, neighbouring countries to live in harmony and develop side by side, he said.</p>

<p>The ties between the two Asian giants nosedived significantly following the fierce clash in the Galwan Valley in June 2020 that marked the most serious military conflict between the two sides in decades.</p>

<p>On Oct 21, India and China firmed up an agreement on patrolling and disengagement of troops along the LAC in eastern Ladakh, in a breakthrough to end the over four-year standoff.</p>

<p>Both leaders also instructed the Special Representatives on the India-China boundary question to meet at an early date and to continue their efforts to address the issues related to the Line of Actual Control (LAC).</p>

<p>India's Special Representative for the dialogue is NSA Ajit Doval while the Chinese side is headed at the talks by Foreign Minister Wang Yi.</p>

<p>The Special Representatives mechanism was constituted in 2003. The two sides held 20 rounds of talks since then. The last meeting was held in 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mvn5qm1_modi-xi-jinping_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi-Xi had endorsed the agreement on patrolling and disengagement along the LAC.(FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-says-made-mistakes-on-immigration-plans-big-change-7048582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau Says 'Made Mistakes' On Immigration, Plans Big Change]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-says-made-mistakes-on-immigration-plans-big-change-7048582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:55:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a recent video message, Trudeau stated that Canada's population has grown rapidly over the past two years, but this growth has also been accompanied by exploitation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has acknowledged that his government's immigration policy has been exploited by "bad actors" such as “fake colleges” and large corporations, leading to a significant shift in the country's immigration strategy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This comes in amid Trudeau's descending popularity ahead of the General Elections in Canada next year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a recent video message, Trudeau stated that Canada's population has grown rapidly over the past two years, but this growth has also been accompanied by exploitation.</p>

<p>He said "In the last two years, our population has grown really fast, like a baby boom...Increasingly bad actors like fake colleges and big chain corporations have been exploiting our immigration system for their own interests."</p>

<p>The people of Canada have been accusing the Prime Minister and his party of bad management, housing shortages, inflation and the health and transport systems of the country. The opposition has also claimed that he does not prioritise the needs of the Canadian citizens.</p>

<p>"We made some mistakes and that's why we are taking this big turn," he said, giving grounds for the government's action.</p>

<p>To address these issues, Trudeau announced that Canada will reduce the number of immigrants entering the country over the next three years.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Immigration Minister Marc Miller outlined the government's plan, which includes admitting approximately 395,000 permanent residents in 2025, a 20% decrease from the previous year.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The number of temporary immigrants, including international students and foreign workers, will also decrease to around 446,000 in 2025 and 2026, down from 800,000 this year.</p>

<p>Canada's new immigration plan prioritises permanent residents with skills in healthcare and construction. Trudeau emphasised that the goal is to stabilise population growth while addressing housing shortages and cost-of-living issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Trudeau said Canada's immigration plan is very "straightforward -- lower the number of immigrants -- both permanent and temporary."</p>

<p>The government also ended the popular fast-track study visa program, SDS, which may impact international students, particularly those from India, who make up the largest group of foreign students in Canada.</p>

<p>The immigration system overhaul aims to prevent exploitation by fake colleges and corporations. Trudeau acknowledged that Canada's focus on permanent immigration led to neglect of temporary immigration pathways. The government now seeks to balance economic growth with community needs.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v170vjs8_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_18_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trudeau announced that Canada will reduce the number of immigrants entering the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>