<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:18:36 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teens-become-trans-to-get-into-ivy-leagues-jd-vance-triggers-row-joe-rogan-6919289]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Teens Become Trans To Get Into Ivy Leagues": JD Vance Triggers Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teens-become-trans-to-get-into-ivy-leagues-jd-vance-triggers-row-joe-rogan-6919289]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 10:18:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican Vice-Presidential nominee JD Vance recently triggered a row by making controversial remarks on transgender and nonbinary people.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican Vice-Presidential nominee JD Vance recently triggered a row by making controversial remarks on transgender and nonbinary people, suggesting that some white children are incentivised to "become" trans to get college admissions into Ivy Leagues.</p>

<p>Mr Vance made the statement during an interview podcast with Joe Rogan.</p>

<p>"If you are a middle-class or upper-middle-class white parent, and the only thing that you care about is whether your child goes into Harvard or Yale, obviously that pathway has become a lot harder for a lot of upper-middle class kids...The one way that those people can participate in the DEI (Diversity, equity, and inclusion) bureaucracy in this country is to be trans," he told Mr Rogan.</p>

<p>Mr <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-says-donald-trump-did-not-lose-2020-us-election-6806849">Vance</a> also had some outrageous views on transgender rights and whether they should be allowed to play on sports teams that match their gender identity.</p>

<p>"I'm the father of a two-year-old daughter. I don't want her going into athletic competitions where I'm terrified she's gonna get bludgeoned to death because we're allowing a six-foot-one male to compete with her in sports," he said.</p>

<p>According to Mr Vance, Republican Presidential candidate Donald Trump may get the "normal gay" vote.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
"I won't be surprised if Trump won the normal gay guy vote because again, they just wanted to be left alone," he said.</p>

<h3><strong>Abortion Rights</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Vance also touched upon abortion rights in the US and spoke dismissively of it. According to him, women are "publicly celebrating their abortions by baking birthday cakes and posting about it" - which Mr Rogan disagreed with.</p>

<p>"I think it's six weeks is a limit to when you can have an abortion, which a lot of people think then you can't even tell whether or not you are pregnant, and this puts a lot of women in very vulnerable positions. And then there is this thought that they could go to another state where it is legal and have an abortion, but they could be possibly prosecuted for that in their state. That's concerning to me," Mr Rogan said.</p>

<p>To this, Mr Vance said that he has "not heard of any women being arrested for traveling to have an abortion".</p>

<p>Mr Vance, in the three-hour episode of "The Joe Rogan Experience" podcast, also spoke on Mr Trump's assassination attempt and climate change. He also joked about recent US President Joe Biden's "garbage" comment against Mr Trump, saying that Mr Biden is helping the former US President win the election.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tf2b9g1g_jd-vance_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Vance made the statements during an interview podcast with Joe Rogan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-celebrates-diwali-with-wife-akshata-murty-after-resigning-as-opposition-leader-6919167]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak Celebrates Diwali After Resigning As Opposition Leader]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rishi-sunak-celebrates-diwali-with-wife-akshata-murty-after-resigning-as-opposition-leader-6919167]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 09:55:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak and Akshata Murty were seen serving prasadam to the revellers gathered for the Diwali festivities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former UK prime minister Rishi Sunak alongside his wife, Akshta Murthy celebrated Diwali on Thursday (Oct 31), a day after resigning as the Opposition leader. Sunak, who made history in 2022 by becoming the first British-Asian PM to celebrate Diwali at 10, Downing Street, seemed in festive spirit as the couple celebrated the festival of light in Leicester. Ms Murty took to Instagram to share pictures of the celebration, in which she and Rishi Sunak were seen serving prasadam to the revellers gathered for the Diwali festivities.</p>

<p>"Embracing new beginnings with joy and gratitude this Diwali. May this light bring blessings to all. Happy Diwali!" she captioned the post.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBzYOZrOy9H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBzYOZrOy9H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBzYOZrOy9H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBzYOZrOy9H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Akshata Murty (@akshatamurty_official)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<h2><strong>Sunak resigns as Opposition leader</strong></h2>

<p>On Wednesday (Oct 30), Mr Sunak resigned as the Opposition leader by making his final appearance at the House of Commons during Prime Minister's Questions (PMQs).</p>

<p>"I became leader of my party during Diwali, and I now stand down during that same festival," said Sunak in his parting speech.</p>

<p>"I am proud to have been the first British Asian Prime Minister, but I was even prouder that it was not that big a deal." Sunak added whilst extending wishes for a joyful Diwali to all celebrating in the UK and around the world.</p>

<p>In a display of mutual respect and admiration, Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer also thanked his predecessor for his service and extended the best wishes to his family.</p>

<p>"I wish everyone celebrating in the UK and around the world a joyful Diwali a time to come together to celebrate and focus on the brighter future," said Starmer.</p>

<p>"Last Diwali the leader of the opposition and his family uh lit the doors outside 10 Downing Street it was a significant moment in our national story the first British Asian prime minister is a reminder that this is a country where people of every background could fulfill their dreams and it makes us all proud to be British leader of the opposition," he added.</p>

<p>Rishi Sunak has been serving as interim leader of Conservatives until a new Tory leader is elected. The voting for the new leader took place on Thursday with the winner expected to be announced on Saturday, almost four months after the crushing general election defeat faced by the Tories.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/h2d9ekdo_rishi-sunak_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rishi Sunak, wife Akshata Murty celebrating Diwali]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cctv-shows-firing-outside-singer-ap-dhillons-house-in-canada-cars-on-fire-6918838]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Emerges Months After Firing Outside Singer AP Dhillon's Canada House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cctv-shows-firing-outside-singer-ap-dhillons-house-in-canada-cars-on-fire-6918838]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 08:44:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A video has emerged showing several rounds being fired at Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house in Canada. Two vehicles were also set on fire during the September 2 incident in Vancouver. The singer was not injured in the shooting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A video has emerged showing several rounds being fired at Punjabi singer AP Dhillon's house in Canada. It also shows two vehicles set on fire during the September 2 incident in Vancouver. The singer, who lives on Victoria Island in Vancouver, was not injured in the shooting.</p>

<p>The notorious Lawrence Bishnoi gang, which is being probed for the high-profile murders of Sidhu Moose Wala and Baba Siddique, had then claimed they carried out the firing since the singer featured actor Salman Khan in a music video.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/ap-dhillon-reacts-after-firing-outside-his-canada-house-by-lawrence-bishnoi-gang-member-6478052">"I'm Safe": Singer AP Dhillon After Firing Outside His Canada House</a></p>

<p>Canadian cops have arrested a suspect named Abhijeet Kingra, an Indian, from Ontario and issued an arrest warrant for a second suspect, Vikram Sharma.</p>

<p>Kingra, 25, has been charged with arson and discharge of a firearm with intent, said the Canadian Police in a statement posted on its website. He will appear in the Ontario court today.</p>

<p>The cops said they don't have a photo of Sharma, 23, but described him as a South Asian male who is 5 feet and 9 inches tall with black hair and brown eyes. They suspect he's currently in India.</p>

<p>AP Dhillon, known for blending the 80s-style synth-pop with Punjabi music, has seen a meteoric rise in the global canvas with hits that include 'Brown Munde', 'Dil Nu', and 'Insane'.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/firing-outside-ap-dhillons-canada-house-gangster-claims-responsibility-6473453">Firing Outside AP Dhillon's Canada House, Gangster Claims Responsibility</a></p>

<p>After the shooting incident in September, the Bishnoi gang issued death threats to Mr Dhillon in a social media post. Gangster Rohit Godara, who claims to be associated with Lawrence Bishnoi, had also said it was behind the firing at a jeweller's house in Canada.</p>

<p>Mr Dhillon later shared on Instagram that he was safe and thanked his fans for reaching out to him.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b4a72qr8_ap-dhillon-house-firing_625x300_01_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-over-400-alleged-sex-abuse-victims-of-ex-harrods-boss-come-forward-6918665]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 400 Alleged Sex Abuse Victims Of Ex Harrods Boss Come Forward]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mohamed-al-fayed-over-400-alleged-sex-abuse-victims-of-ex-harrods-boss-come-forward-6918665]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 08:00:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A BBC documentary in September revealed Al Fayed sexually abused female staff at his London department store Harrods.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 400 alleged victims have so far contacted the legal team working on a case against the late Egyptian billionaire Mohamed Al Fayed, who has been accused of sexual abuse and rape, lawyer Dean Armstrong said on Thursday.</p>

<p>A BBC documentary in September revealed Al Fayed, who died last year aged 94, sexually abused female staff at his London department store Harrods, forced them to have medical screenings and threatened consequences if they tried to complain.</p>

<p>"The sheer scale of abuse perpetrated by Al Fayed, and facilitated by those around him, sadly, continues to grow," Armstrong told a news conference in London.</p>

<p>Al Fayed always denied similar accusations raised by other reports before his death.</p>

<p>When asked for a response, Harrods pointed Reuters to its past statements on the allegations, in which it has apologised, said it was "appalled" by them and that it had launched a process for any current or former Harrods employees who wish to claim compensation.</p>

<p>Another lawyer, Bruce Drummond, said the more than 400 claims have been made by women from around the world, mostly from Britain but also from the United States, Australia, Malaysia, Spain, South Africa and other countries.</p>

<p>"That, in our opinion, is an industrial scale abuse," Drummond said, adding abuse took place "within the walls of Harrods" but also in other locations linked to Al Fayed's business empire, such as Fulham Football Club, the Ritz Paris and his estate in Surrey.</p>

<p>Victims include the daughter of a former U.S. ambassador to Britain and the daughter of a well-known soccer player, Drummond said, without giving any names.</p>

<p>The BBC documentary said Harrods had failed to intervene and helped to cover up abuse allegations during his ownership.</p>

<p>Lawyers have criticised the Harrods-run compensation scheme, saying some of the victims do not feel comfortable to reach out to Harrods directly for compensation as that is where the abuse unfolded.</p>

<p>Drummond said some senior members of staff from the Al Fayed era still worked at Harrods.</p>

<p>The Financial Times last week reported that four alleged victims had quit the Harrods compensation scheme due to their concerns over potential conflicts of interest and poor communication.</p>

<p>Several media organisations had reported allegations of sexual abuse against Al Fayed before the BBC documentary, including Vanity Fair in 1995, ITV in 1997 and Channel 4 in 2017. Lawyers said in September many of the women only felt able to speak publicly in the BBC report after he died last year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l43pehn_mohamed-alfayed_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Al Fayed died last year aged 94]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-followed-by-34-zeroes-why-russia-has-fined-google-20-decillion-6918636]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Russia Has Fined Google $20,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000,000]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-followed-by-34-zeroes-why-russia-has-fined-google-20-decillion-6918636]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 07:49:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The unprecedented penalty targets YouTube, owned by Google's parent company Alphabet, over the platform's decision to block Russian state-run media channels in response to Russia's invasion of Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia issued a fine against Google, estimated at an astronomical $20 decillion - a 2 followed by 34 zeroes. The unprecedented penalty targets YouTube, owned by Google's parent company Alphabet, over the platform's decision to block Russian state-run media channels in response to Russia's invasion of Ukraine. This sum far exceeds any reasonable financial scale, surpassing the entire global economy many times over.</p>

<p>The penalty arose after a Russian court ruled that Google violated national broadcasting rules by barring channels from Russian state-backed media outlets on YouTube. The fine is compounded by an additional ruling that demands the restoration of these channels, with the fines doubling each day if the platform fails to comply within a nine-month period.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The issue traces back to March 2022, when YouTube announced a global ban on several Russian state-operated channels, including RT and Sputnik. The platform justified its decision by pointing to content policies prohibiting material that denies, minimises, or trivialises violent events. YouTube has enforced such policies against channels supporting Russia's narratives around the Ukraine conflict, removing over 1,000 channels and more than 15,000 videos globally. In Europe, restrictions on Russian state media accounts were imposed before the ban expanded worldwide. This action led to backlash from Russia, which views the move as censorship and suppression of its state-sponsored media.</p>

<p>Since 2020, Google has faced ongoing penalties, starting with a daily fine of 100,000 rubles (approximately $1,028) over blocked Russian channels from Tsargrad and RIA FAN, two prominent Russian state-affiliated media outlets.</p>

<p>According to reports, 17 Russian broadcasters have joined the legal fray, filing suits against Google and demanding the reinstatement of their channels on the platform.</p>

<p>Following the onset of Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in early 2022, Google significantly curtailed its operations within Russia but stopped short of a complete exit. Services like YouTube and Google Search remain accessible within Russian borders. Unlike some American tech companies that fully withdrew, Google's partial operations in Russia continue, although its Russia subsidiary filed for bankruptcy several months into the conflict after the Russian government seized its bank accounts.</p>

<p>The Kremlin has called the fine a largely symbolic measure intended to compel Google to reconsider its stance on Russian broadcasters. Dmitry Peskov, spokesperson for the Kremlin, told Russian media that the monumental fine amount is intended to attract attention to the seriousness with which Russia views the issue of YouTube's bans on Russian media. "I can't even pronounce this figure right," Peskov said.</p>

<p>Since its invasion of Ukraine, Russia has leveraged a range of penalties against foreign tech platforms for hosting content deemed anti-Russian or pro-Ukrainian. Although YouTube remains accessible within Russia, authorities have threatened to block the platform outright if it continues to restrict Russian media channels.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/mg35f038_google-generic-file_625x300_20_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Kremlin has called the fine a largely symbolic measure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-150-dead-in-spains-worst-flood-related-disaster-6918634]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 150 Dead In Spain's Worst Flood-Related Disaster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-150-dead-in-spains-worst-flood-related-disaster-6918634]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 07:48:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The rescue teams are still searching for those missing in what could become Europe's worst storm-related disaster in over five decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death count from devastating flash floods in eastern Spain climbed to 158 on Thursday, with rescue teams still searching for those missing in what could become Europe's worst storm-related disaster in over five decades.</p>

<p>"There's a total of 158 people to which must be added dozens and dozens of missing," Angel Victor Torres, minister in charge of cooperation with Spain's regions, told a press conference.</p>

<p>A year's worth of rain fell in eight hours in parts of the Valencia region on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The tragedy is already Spain's worst flood-related disaster in modern history, and meteorologists say human-driven climate change is making such extreme weather events more frequent and destructive.</p>

<p>In 2021, at least 185 people died in heavy flooding in Germany. Prior to that, 209 people died in Romania in 1970 and floods in Portugal in 1967 killed nearly 500 people.</p>

<p>Rescue teams on Thursday discovered the bodies of eight people, including a local policeman, who had been trapped in a garage on the outskirts of the city of Valencia, Mayor Maria Jose Catala told reporters.</p>

<p>In the same neighbourhood of La Torre, she said, a 45-year-old woman was also found dead in her home.</p>

<p>Thousands of people carrying bags or pushing shopping trolleys could be seen on Thursday crossing a pedestrian bridge over the Turia River from La Torre into Valencia city centre to stock up on essential supplies such as toilet paper and water.</p>

<p>Opposition politicians accused the central government in Madrid of acting too slowly to warn residents and send in rescue teams, prompting the Interior Ministry to say regional authorities were responsible for civil protection measures.</p>

<p>"Those people wouldn't have died if they had been warned in time," Laura Villaescusa, a neighbour and manager of a local supermarket, told Reuters.</p>

<p>Maribel Albalat, mayor of the nearby town of Paiporta, said residents were not warned of the imminent danger of flooding. She said 62 people had died in her town.</p>

<p>"We found a lot of elderly people inside their homes and people who went to get their cars. It was a trap," she told TVE.</p>

<h3><strong>CLINGING TO PILLAR</strong></h3>

<p>In Godelleta, a town 37 km (23 miles) west of Valencia city, Antonio Molina, 52, described how he survived by clinging to a pillar on a neighbour's porch on Tuesday as water reached his neck.</p>

<p>Molina's home suffered two major floods in 2018 and 2020 and he blamed authorities for allowing construction of residential buildings in depressions where water accumulates.</p>

<p>"We don't want to live here anymore," he said, tearfully. "As soon as we get a couple of raindrops, we're already checking our phones."</p>

<p>The floods have battered Valencia's infrastructure, sweeping away bridges, roads and rail tracks, and submerged farmland in a region that produces about two-thirds of Spain's citrus crops like oranges, which the country exports globally.</p>

<p>About 80 km (50 miles) of roads in the eastern region were seriously damaged or impassable, said Transport Minister Oscar Puente. Many were blocked by abandoned cars.</p>

<p>"Unfortunately there are dead bodies in some vehicles," Puente told reporters, adding that it would take two to three weeks to re-establish the high-speed train connection between Valencia and Madrid.</p>

<p>Visiting a rescue coordination centre near Valencia city, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez urged people to stay at home due to the threat of more stormy weather.</p>

<p>"Right now the most important thing is to safeguard as many lives as possible," he told reporters.</p>

<p>In the hard-hit rural town of Utiel, some 85 km (53 miles) inland, the Magro River burst its banks, sending up to three metres (9.8 feet) of water into the mostly single-storey homes.</p>

<p>Utiel's mayor, Ricardo Gabaldon, said at least six people died in the town of about 12,000, most of them elderly or disabled people who were unable to clamber to safety.</p>

<p>Residents used water pumps carried on tractors as they started to clean up on Thursday, with children helping to sweep the sidewalks. Ruined household appliances and furniture were piled up in the middle of roads and elderly people struggled to walk in the slippery, mud-coated streets.</p>

<p>Pope Francis said he was praying for the people of the region. "I'm close to them in this moment of catastrophe," he said in a video posted on X.</p>

<p>Research group Climate Central said in a report on Thursday that a low-pressure system behind Spain's floods had tapped into an "atmospheric river" carrying excess moisture from the unusually warm Tropical Atlantic.</p>

<p>According to its Climate Shift Index: Ocean, human-caused climate change has made these elevated sea surface temperatures at least 50 to 300 times more likely.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dj4ptpj8_spain-floods_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many roads were blocked by abandoned cars.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-and-her-two-children-including-5-month-old-die-after-jumping-off-niagara-falls-cops-6918626]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman And Her Two Children Dead After Jumping Off Niagara Falls: Police]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-and-her-two-children-including-5-month-old-die-after-jumping-off-niagara-falls-cops-6918626]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 07:41:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US woman and her two children died after jumping off Niagara Falls on Monday night, the Independent reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US woman and her two children died after jumping off Niagara Falls on Monday night, the <em>Independent</em> reported. The woman, identified as 33-year-old Chianti Means climbed over a safety rail and intentionally went over the waterfall with her two children, a nine-year-old and a 5-month-old. Authorities reached the scene around 9 pm on Monday and determined that the family went over the rail on Luna Island, a popular sight-seeing point above the waterfall with a nearly 200-foot drop. Investigators also determined that the plunge was "intentional". "The circumstances remain under investigation," state troopers said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Investigation determined that three individuals, Chianti Means, 33 years old, Roman Rossman, 9 years old and Mecca Means, 5 months old all of Niagara Falls, NY crossed over safety guild rail and went over Niagara Falls on Luna Island (attached to Goat Island)," state police said in a news release, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/niagara-falls-death-chianti-means-b2638845.html" rel="noindex, nofollow">outlet</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The investigation has determined that this incident was intentional in nature, though the circumstances remain under investigation. New York State Park Police and State Police search/rescue efforts were conducted with negative results. This incident deems no public threat to safety," the department added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Chianti, a mother of two, was a resident of Niagara Falls, where she lived with her children. As of Wednesday, there is no news about the discovery of their bodies, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/30/us-news/new-york-mom-and-two-young-kids-including-5-month-old-baby-dead-after-jumping-off-niagara-falls/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stop-the-insanity-bolts-billionaire-ceo-cracks-down-on-remote-work-6913161">"Stop The Insanity...": Bolt's Billionaire CEO Cracks Down On Remote Work</a></strong></p>

<p>The 33-year-old worked as a domestic violence counsellor, according to her LinkedIn profile, and graduated from school in nearby Buffalo. Shortly after the news of her death broke, tributes from friends and family started pouring in. "I have been speechless and crying and couldn't sleep at all," wrote friend Kayshawna Morgane on Facebook, adding, "My heart is broken. Mental health is no joke."</p>

<p>"I can't even bear to write a post about her and share memories.I am literally sick to my stomach and I can't even deal with the emotions I am feeling. Just know her and her children are dearly loved by me and my children," said friend Mich Molina. "You really never know what anybody is going through," said another, Niesha Eukeya.</p>

<p>An investigation is ongoing. Authorities are reportedly using unmanned aircraft and underwater units in the investigation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/p19km6_chianti-means-_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-diwali-message-donald-trump-condemns-violence-against-hindus-in-bangladesh-6918589]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Kamala Ignored Hindus": In Diwali Message, Trump Condemns Bangladesh Unrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-diwali-message-donald-trump-condemns-violence-against-hindus-in-bangladesh-6918589]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 07:31:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump, in a Diwali message on Thursday, condemned the atrocities faced by Hindus in Bangladesh.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President Donald Trump, in a Diwali message on Thursday, condemned the atrocities faced by Hindus in Bangladesh, especially after the fall of the Sheikh Hasina government. He also vowed to protect the Hindu Americans against "anti-religion agendas" and fight for their freedom.</p>

<p>"I strongly condemn the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities who are getting attacked and looted by mobs in Bangladesh, which remains in a total state of chaos. It would have never happened on my watch," Mr Trump wrote in a post on X.</p>

<p>This is the first time Mr Trump has spoken on the issue of Bangladesh.</p>

<p>The US Presidential candidate hit out at his Democratic rival Kamala Harris, saying that she and US President Joe Biden have "ignored" Hindus across the world as well as in America.</p>

<p>"Kamala and Joe have ignored Hindus across the world and in America. They have been a disaster from Israel to Ukraine to our own Southern Border, but we will Make America Strong Again and bring back Peace through Strength!," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Trump, who extended his Diwali wishes to Indians, also vowed to strengthen his country's partnership with India and his "good friend" <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/140-crore-indians-worried-about-safety-of-hindus-in-bangladesh-pm-modi-6341273">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a>.</p>

<p>"Under my administration, we will also strengthen our great partnership with India and my good friend, Prime Minister Modi. Also, Happy Diwali to All. I hope the Festival of Lights leads to the Victory of Good over Evil," he wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I strongly condemn the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities who are getting attacked and looted by mobs in Bangladesh, which remains in a total state of chaos.<br />
<br />
It would have never happened on my watch. Kamala and Joe have ignored Hindus across the…</p>
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033622494105832?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>On August 5, former Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina fled the country, ending her 15-year rule as student protests against her government escalated. Following this, the minority Hindus in the country have been facing violence, and vandalism of temples and their businesses. According to the Bangladesh National Hindu Grand Alliance, attacks and threats against the minority community have taken place in over 200 locations across 48 districts. Hundreds of Hindus were also killed between July and August this year.</p>

<p>The minority Hindus constitute about eight percent of the population in Bangladesh.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hd7kpmco_donald-trump_625x300_30_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This is the first time Mr Trump has spoken on the issue of Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-why-us-votes-in-november-but-inaugurates-new-president-in-january-6914375]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why US Votes In November But Inaugurates New President In January]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-why-us-votes-in-november-but-inaugurates-new-president-in-january-6914375]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:54:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States has an electoral system and calendar unlike no other country. The nation votes in November but the new President is inaugurated in January.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States has an electoral system and calendar unlike no other country. The nation votes in November but the new President is inaugurated in January. While many countries swiftly usher in new leaders, the US takes a more measured approach with an 11-week transition period. Although this duration may seem lengthy, it is, in fact, shorter than the four months that the Constitution originally permitted for the transfer of power from an incumbent president to their successor.</p>

<p><strong>Historical context</strong></p>

<p>Federal elections in the US are held on the first Tuesday in November. Initially, states had different election days, but in 1845, a law established a uniform election day nationwide. At the time, the US was predominantly agricultural, and early November proved advantageous for farmers. The harvest would be complete, yet the weather remained good for travel. Certain days were ruled out for voting. Sunday was universally recognised as a day of worship for devout Christians, while Wednesday served as a market day for farmers to sell their produce. In addition, reaching polling places often required travel, even up to a day for those living in rural areas without modern transport. With Sunday and Wednesday unavailable, Monday and Thursday were also eliminated as potential election days. As such, Tuesday emerged as the most suitable choice.<br />
<br />
<strong>From four months to under three months</strong><br />
<br />
The challenges faced during the Great Depression prompted leaders to expedite the swearing-in process for newly elected presidents, reducing the lengthy four-month “lame duck” period to under three months. A “lame duck” refers to an elected official whose successor has already been chosen, leaving them politically weakened.<br />
<br />
The 20th Amendment, ratified in 1933, officially moved the inauguration date to January 20, while presidential elections continue to occur in early November.<br />
<br />
<strong>Logistical considerations</strong><br />
<br />
One of the main reasons for this gap is the need for a seamless transition of power. After the election, the president-elect and their team require time to prepare for governance. This includes assembling a cabinet, developing policies and addressing national issues. The time between the election and inauguration allows the incoming administration to lay the groundwork for their agenda.<br />
<br />
The extended transition period can also be attributed to the Electoral College system, which determines the president weeks after the popular vote, as opposed to a parliamentary system where the winning party directly assumes power. While this delay means that presidents cannot take office immediately, the winner is granted access to transition funding and can receive essential briefings from the outgoing administration to facilitate a smooth handover.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-11/us-voting_650x400_81478643267.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Federal elections in the US are held on the first Tuesday in November.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-donald-trump-may-challenge-results-if-he-loses-but-what-are-his-options-6915609]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump May Challenge Results If He Loses, But What Are His Options]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-donald-trump-may-challenge-results-if-he-loses-but-what-are-his-options-6915609]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 06:48:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the US presidential election nears, the two primary candidates -- Republican nominee Donald Trump and his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris -- are making their last pitch to the voters at multiple rallies in a day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the US presidential election nears, the two primary candidates &nbsp;-- Republican nominee Donald Trump and his Democratic counterpart Kamala Harris -- are making their last pitch to the voters at multiple rallies in a day. But there's another thing keeping the US electorate and political observers on their toes. What will unfold if Harris wins? The reason? Well, former President Donald Trump has routinely claimed that a loss for him will only be due to Democratic interference. This has raised concerns that he may again cast doubt on the results, as he did in 2020 when he sought to challenge Joe Biden's win.</p>

<p>During a Michigan rally in September, Trump said, “If I lose, I'll tell you what, it's possible. Because they cheat. That's the only way we're gonna lose because they cheat.”</p>

<p><strong>New safeguards for this election</strong></p>

<p>New safeguards introduced for this election aim to reduce the chances of any efforts to undermine the outcome from gaining traction.</p>

<p><strong>The new protections include:</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>An electoral law enacted by Congress following the January 6 insurrection.</li>
	<li>Recent court rulings reinforcing electoral integrity.</li>
	<li>Increased vigilance from state election officials.</li>
	<li>More aggressive action by law enforcement agencies.</li>
</ul>

<p>These measures have been put in place to prevent any recurrence of the violent Capitol scenes from four years ago.</p>

<p><strong>What happened in 2020?</strong></p>

<p>After his 2020 loss, Trump and his allies sought to challenge the election outcome through numerous lawsuits, all of which failed to alter or delay the results. He also pressured Georgia officials to "find" additional votes in his favour, and his supporters stormed the US Capitol on January 6, 2021, in an unsuccessful attempt to prevent Vice President Mike Pence from certifying Biden's victory. This election, however, Trump no longer has access to the presidential powers he wielded in 2020 -- a significant change in circumstances.</p>

<p><strong>Trump, allies may question Harris win</strong></p>

<p>Trump and his allies have been actively preparing to challenge the election outcome if he loses on November 5. In the event of a Harris win, he may pursue legal avenues or cast doubt on the legitimacy of her victory among his supporters, potentially leading to unforeseen reactions, reported Reuters.</p>

<p>Both Republicans and Democrats anticipate that counting could extend for several days post-election as mail-in and other ballots are processed and verified. If Trump appears to be trailing, the delay could prompt him to allege fraud and work to erode public confidence in election officials, potentially inciting protests.</p>

<p>He has also suggested punitive action against election workers and officials for “unscrupulous” behaviour, though he needs to secure a victory first to act on such threats.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/7m0a05lg_donald-trump-afp_625x300_14_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and his allies have been actively preparing to challenge the election outcome.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-test-fired-latest-icbm-hwasong-19-on-thursday-6917870]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Says It Test-Fired Latest ICBM Hwasong-19 On Thursday]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-says-it-test-fired-latest-icbm-hwasong-19-on-thursday-6917870]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 03:22:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea on Friday said it test-fired the latest intercontinental ballistic missile Hwasong-19 on Thursday, calling it a final and complete version, the Yonhap news agency reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea on Friday said it test-fired the latest intercontinental ballistic missile Hwasong-19 on Thursday, calling it a final and complete version, the Yonhap news agency reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/398hjiko_north-korea-flag-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-60-million-cast-early-votes-in-kamala-harris-trump-tight-race-6917811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Elections: 60 Million Cast Early Votes In Kamala Harris-Trump Tight Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-60-million-cast-early-votes-in-kamala-harris-trump-tight-race-6917811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 03:08:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With just a few days to go for the United States elections, a staggering 61.0 million Americans have already made their voices heard by casting their ballots in the November election, according to a report by CNN.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With just a few days to go for the United States elections, a staggering 61.0 million Americans have already made their voices heard by casting their ballots in the November election, according to a report by CNN.</p>

<p>Notably, voters have cast their ballots either by mail or through early in-person voting for the presidential elections between Vice President Kamala Harris, a Democrat and former President Donald Trump, a Republican.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, according to new CNN polls conducted by SSRS, the presidential race is heating up in Georgia and North Carolina, with the latest polls showing a neck-and-neck contest between Harris and Trump.</p>

<p>Likely voters in Georgia divide 48 per cent for Trump to 47 per cent for Harris, and in North Carolina, Harris stands at 48 per cent to Trump's 47 per cent, CNN reported.</p>

<p>These narrow margins are within the poll's margin of error, indicating no clear frontrunner in either state.</p>

<p>It is interesting to note that North Carolina, which supported former President Barack Obama in 2008, has voted Republican in the past three presidential elections. However, in 2020, Trump won against US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>Joe Biden made history in Georgia four years ago by defeating Donald Trump with a margin of less than 1 percentage point, becoming the first Democrat to win the state since Bill Clinton's victory in 1992.</p>

<p>In both states, Georgia and North Carolina, Harris is leading among the Black likely voters (84 per cent to 13 per cent in Georgia; 78 per cent to 19 per cent in North Carolina) and voters with college degrees (55 per cent to 39 per cent in Georgia; 53 per cent to 42 per cent in North Carolina).</p>

<p>On the other hand, white college graduates divide around evenly in both states (50 per cent Harris to 47 per cent Trump in North Carolina, 48 per cent Trump to 46 per cent Harris in Georgia). Trump holds a commanding lead, 81 per cent to 15 per cent, among White voters without college degrees in Georgia. He leads that group by a less overwhelming margin, 65 per cent to 31 per cent, in North Carolina, CNN reported.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oh3m2dlg_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Likely voters in Georgia divide 48 per cent for Trump to 47 per cent for Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-extends-diwali-greetings-vows-to-strengthen-partnership-with-india-and-pm-modi-6917641]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Extends Diwali Greetings, Vows To Strengthen Ties With India, PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-extends-diwali-greetings-vows-to-strengthen-partnership-with-india-and-pm-modi-6917641]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 02:03:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that the United States' "great partnership" with India and "my good friend Prime Minister (Narendra) Modi" will be strengthened under his administ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President and Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has said that the United States' "great partnership" with India and "my good friend Prime Minister (Narendra) Modi" will be strengthened under his administration.</p>

<p>In a post on X, Trump also extended his greetings on Diwali. "... Happy Diwali to All. I hope the Festival of Lights leads to the Victory of Good over Evil!," he posted.</p>

<p>In the same post, the former President condemned the violence against Hindus and other minorities in Bangladesh.</p>

<p>"I strongly condemn the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities who are getting attacked and looted by mobs in Bangladesh, which remains in a total state of chaos," he said, adding that it would have "never happened" on his watch.</p>

<p>Trump accused Vice President Kamala Harris and President Joe Biden of ignoring Hindus across the world and in America.</p>

<p>He also vowed to make "America Strong Again and bring back Peace through Strength".</p>

<p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I strongly condemn the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities who are getting attacked and looted by mobs in Bangladesh, which remains in a total state of chaos.<br><br>It would have never happened on my watch. Kamala and Joe have ignored Hindus across the…</p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033622494105832?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote></script></p>

<p>"We will also protect Hindu Americans against the anti-religion agenda of the radical left. We will fight for your freedom. Under my administration, we will also strengthen our great partnership with India and my good friend, Prime Minister Modi," he said.</p>

<p>The former President further said that Harris will "destroy your small businesses with more regulations and higher taxes".</p>

<p>"By contrast, I cut taxes, cut regulations, unleashed American energy, and built the greatest economy in history. We will do it again, bigger and better than ever before -- and we will Make America Great Again," he added.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/gfbm3a8_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_27_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former President Trump also condemned the violence against Hindus a minorities in Bangladesh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-000-north-korean-troops-deployed-in-kursk-region-says-blinken-6917568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Says 8,000 North Korean Troops Deployed In Russia's Kursk Region]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-000-north-korean-troops-deployed-in-kursk-region-says-blinken-6917568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:46:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on Thursday revealed that approximately 10,000 North Korean soldiers are currently in Russia, with around 8,000 deployed in the Kursk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Anthony Blinken on Thursday revealed that approximately 10,000 North Korean soldiers are currently in Russia, with around 8,000 deployed in the Kursk region.</p>

<p>He further said that while these troops have not yet been engaged in combat against Ukrainian forces, he anticipates their involvement in the coming days.</p>

<p>The remarks by Blinken came during a press conference with US Secretary of Defence Lloyd J. Austin III, Republic of Korea Minister of Foreign Affairs Cho Tae-yul, and Republic of Korea Minister of Defence Kim Yong-hyun on Thursday.</p>

<p>Blinken said, "We now assess that there are some 10,000 North Korean soldiers in total in Russia. And recent information indicates that as many as 8,000 of those North Korean forces have been deployed in the Kursk region. We have not yet seen these troops deployed in the combat against Ukrainian forces but we expect that to happen in the coming days."</p>

<p>He added, "Russia has been training Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK) soldiers in artillery, UAVs, and basic infantry operations, indicating that they fully intend to use these forces in front-line operations. Should these troops engage in combat or combat-support operations against Ukraine, they would become legitimate military."</p>

<p>The US Secretary of State sharply criticised Russia, stating that President Vladimir Putin is "throwing Russians in a meat grinder" and is now turning towards North Korea which is a "clear sign of weakness." He said, "One of the reasons that Russia is turning towards North Korean troops is that it is desperate. Putin has been throwing more and more Russians into a meat grinder of his own making in Ukraine and now he's turning to North Korean troops and that is a clear sign of weakness."</p>

<p>Blinken added, "Russia is suffering some 12,000 casualties a day and with the deployment of North Korean troops, this is the first time in 100 years that Russia has invited foreign troops into its country."</p>

<p>Notably, NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte on October 28 confirmed the deployment of North Korean troops to Russia, following reports from Ukrainian military intelligence that noted their presence in the Kursk border region, Al Jazeera had reported.</p>

<p>Blinken also condemned North Korea's latest intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) launch and said, "One of the things that we emphasise today is reaffirmation of the United States' ironclad commitment to security... That's important in light of ongoing provocations coming from North Korea, including another ICBM launch just yesterday. We condemn it in the strongest words..."</p>

<p>Notably, Japan's Defence Ministry reported that North Korea launched at least one ballistic missile on Thursday morning, suspected to be an ICBM-class weapon.</p>

<p>The missile, launched at 7:11 am local time, flew eastward from within North Korea's interior before landing outside Japan's Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ) in waters approximately 200 kilometres west of Hokkaido's Okushiri Island at 8:37 am, NHK World reported.</p>

<p>Japan's Defence Minister Nakatani Gen stated that the missile's flight duration of one hour and 26 minutes marks the longest-ever trajectory of a North Korean ballistic missile. He further noted that the missile travelled around 1,000 kilometres and reached a peak altitude of approximately 7,000 kilometres.</p>

<p>This launch marks North Korea's 12th ballistic missile or suspected ballistic missile launch this year, and the first ICBM-class missile launch since December 2023.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1c37bhlo_antony-blinken-afp-_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Blinken also condemned North Korea's latest intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) launch.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-strike-on-israel-from-iraqi-territory-within-days-reports-6917383]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Preparing Strike On Israel From Iraqi Territory Within Days: Reports]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-preparing-strike-on-israel-from-iraqi-territory-within-days-reports-6917383]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:41:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli intelligence suggests Iran is preparing to attack Israel from Iraqi territory in the coming days, possibly before the U.S. presidential election on Nov. 5, Axios reported on Thursday, citing two unidentified Israeli sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Israeli intelligence suggests Iran is preparing to attack Israel from Iraqi territory in the coming days, possibly before the U.S. presidential election on Nov. 5, Axios reported on Thursday, citing two unidentified Israeli sources.</p>

<p>The attack is expected to be carried out from Iraq using a large number of drones and ballistic missiles, the Axios report added.</p>

<p>The report said that carrying out the attack through pro-Iran militias in Iraq could be an attempt by Tehran to avoid another Israeli attack against strategic targets in Iran.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/phn98hb8_israel-iran-conflict-generic-_625x300_04_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli intelligence suggests Iran is preparing to attack Israel from Iraqi territory.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/israeli-foreign-minister-extends-diwali-greetings-to-indians-6916404]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Extends Diwali Greetings To Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/israeli-foreign-minister-extends-diwali-greetings-to-indians-6916404]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Oct 2024 20:38:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz Thursday extended greetings to Indians on Diwali, stressing that his country shares the values of democracy, freedom, and a vision of a brighter future like India.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz Thursday extended greetings to Indians on Diwali, stressing that his country shares the values of democracy, freedom, and a vision of a brighter future like India.</p>

<p>"My friend @DrSJaishankar, I wish you and the people of India a #HappyDiwali2024! Israel and India share the values of democracy, freedom, and a vision for a brighter future", Israel Katz said in a post on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"May this Festival of Light bring us all joy, prosperity, and peace," the Israeli foreign minister added. "Deepawali ki haardik shubhkamnayen," he further wrote in Hindi.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="und">My friend <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrSJaishankar</a>, I wish you and the people of India a <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HappyDiwali2024?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#HappyDiwali2024</a>! Israel and India share the values of democracy, freedom, and a vision for a brighter future. May this Festival of Light bring us all joy, prosperity, and peace ????.<br />
<br />
दीपावली की हार्दिक शुभकामनाएँ! <a href="https://t.co/ANiBGlcnbg">pic.twitter.com/ANiBGlcnbg</a></p>
— ישראל כ”ץ Israel Katz (@Israel_katz) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel_katz/status/1851914591078387794?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Academic institutions across Israel seem to be decked up for Diwali celebrations, with Indian researchers forming the bulk of the overseas student community in the country.</p>

<p>Some 18-20,000 Indians working in Israel are also celebrating the festival of lights.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/n6di67mg_israel-katz_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some 18-20,000 Indians working in Israel are also celebrating the festival of lights. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-trademark-lawsuit-over-youtube-shorts-court-rules-no-confusion-6916109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Google Wins Trademark Suit Over YouTube Shorts, Court Rules No Confusion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-wins-trademark-lawsuit-over-youtube-shorts-court-rules-no-confusion-6916109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:37:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Google on Thursday defeated a trademark lawsuit brought by a British short film company over YouTube's short video platform Shorts, with London's High Court ruling there was no risk of confusion for consumers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google on Thursday defeated a trademark lawsuit brought by a British short film company over YouTube's short video platform Shorts, with London's High Court ruling there was no risk of confusion for consumers.</p>

<p>Shorts International, which runs a television channel devoted to short films, sued the tech giant last year, accusing Google of infringing its trademark over the word "shorts".</p>

<p>Google-owned YouTube had launched Shorts, featuring minute-long videos, in late 2020 as it struggled to compete with TikTok.</p>

<p>Google's lawyer Lindsay Lane argued in court documents at a trial earlier this month that it was "abundantly clear" that the Shorts platform came from YouTube, not Shorts International.</p>

<p>Judge Michael Tappin said in a written ruling that none of Google's uses of the word "shorts" would lead to any likelihood of confusion as to the origin of the platform.</p>

<p>He also said that Google and YouTube's use of the word "will not cause damage to the distinctive character or repute of (Shorts International's) trade marks" and dismissed the lawsuit.</p>

<p>Google and Shorts International did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-09/0o8jdg68_youtube-generic_625x300_27_September_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Google-owned YouTube had launched Shorts, featuring minute-long videos, in late 2020. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-shut-down-iranian-consulates-over-execution-of-dual-national-6916065]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Germany To Shut Down Iranian Consulates Over Execution Of Dual National]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/germany-to-shut-down-iranian-consulates-over-execution-of-dual-national-6916065]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:28:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany will shut all Iranian consulates in Germany but allow the embassy to remain open in reaction to the execution of a German-Iranian national, the foreign ministry said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany will shut all Iranian consulates in Germany but allow the embassy to remain open in reaction to the execution of a German-Iranian national, the foreign ministry said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The killing of German-Iranian national Jamshid Sharmahd has put "extreme" strain on the relationship between Berlin and Tehran, a ministry spokesperson had said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Germany has already recalled its ambassador to Iran over Sharmahd's execution and summoned the Iranian charge d'affaires to voice Berlin's protest.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9p54r2_iran-flag-_625x300_14_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Germany has already recalled its ambassador to Iran over Jamshid Sharmahd's execution. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-enough-time-in-universe-for-monkeys-to-pen-shakespeare-study-6915900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Not Enough Time In Universe For Monkeys To Pen Shakespeare: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/not-enough-time-in-universe-for-monkeys-to-pen-shakespeare-study-6915900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:56:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This thought experiment has long been used to express how an infinite amount of time makes something that is incredibly unlikely -- but still technically possible -- become probable.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If a monkey types randomly at a keyboard for long enough, it will eventually write the complete works of Shakespeare.</p>

<p>This thought experiment has long been used to express how an infinite amount of time makes something that is incredibly unlikely -- but still technically possible -- become probable.</p>

<p>But two Australian mathematicians have deemed the old adage misleading, working out that even if all the chimpanzees in the world were given the entire lifespan of the universe, they would "almost certainly" never pen the works of the bard.</p>

<p>The "infinite monkey theorem" has been around for more than a century, though its origin remains unclear. It is commonly attributed to either French mathematician Emile Borel or British anthropologist Thomas Huxley, and some even think the general idea dates back to Aristotle.</p>

<p>For a light-hearted but peer-reviewed study published earlier this week, the two mathematicians set out to determine what happens if generous yet finite limits were placed on the monkey typists.</p>

<p>Their calculations were based on a monkey spending around 30 years typing one key a second at a keyboard with 30 keys -- the letters of the English language plus some common punctuation.</p>

<p>The "heat death" of the universe was assumed to take place in around a googol of years -- that is a one followed by 100 zeroes.</p>

<p>Other more practical considerations -- such as what the monkeys would eat, or how they would survive the Sun engulfing Earth in a few billion years -- were set aside.</p>

<p><strong>Monkey labour falls short</strong></p>

<p>There was only around a five percent chance that a single monkey would randomly write the word "banana" in their lifetime, according to the study in the journal Franklin Open.</p>

<p>Shakespeare's canon includes 884,647 words -- none of them banana.</p>

<p>To broaden out the experiment, the mathematicians turned to chimpanzees, the closest relative of humans.</p>

<p>There are currently around 200,000 chimps on Earth, and the study presumed this population would remain stable until the end of time.</p>

<p>Even this massive monkey workforce fell very, very short.</p>

<p>"It's not even like one in a million," study co-author Stephen Woodcock of the University of Technology Sydney told New Scientist.</p>

<p>"If every atom in the universe was a universe in itself, it still wouldn't happen."</p>

<p>And even if many more chimps who typed much quicker were added to the equation, it was still not plausible "that monkey labour will ever be a viable tool for developing written works of anything beyond the trivial," the authors wrote in the study.</p>

<p>The study concluded by saying that Shakespeare himself may have inadvertently given an answer as to whether "monkey labour could meaningfully be a replacement for human endeavour as a source of scholarship or creativity".</p>

<p>"To quote Hamlet, Act 3, Scene 3, Line 87: 'No'."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/qrtpmldg_baby-monkey-generic_625x300_28_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shakespeare's canon includes 884,647 words -- none of them banana. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jill-stein-green-party-s-us-presidential-candidate-against-harris-and-trump-6915502]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Election 2024: All About Green Party Nominee Jill Stein]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-jill-stein-green-party-s-us-presidential-candidate-against-harris-and-trump-6915502]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Oct 2024 17:44:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[American voters seeking a progressive, environmentally focused candidate with a proven history of challenging the political mainstream have achoice in 2024 -- Jill Stein, the Green Party's nominee and a two-time presidential candidate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American voters seeking a progressive, environmentally focused candidate with a proven history of challenging the political mainstream have a&nbsp;choice in 2024. Jill Stein, the Green Party's nominee and a two-time presidential candidate, is having another run. Known for her advocacy for climate justice, healthcare for all and social equity, Stein is positioning herself as an alternative in a race dominated by major party figures. As a secular Jew who grew up in Reform Judaism and deeply values social justice, Stein has previously made headlines for her bold stance on US foreign policy, including opposition to aid for Israel and support for the Boycott, Divestment&nbsp;and Sanctions (BDS) movement. Her left-leaning platform, which champions a “Green New Deal” and a significant reduction in military spending, aims to energise voters disillusioned by the familiar faces of Kamala Harris and Donald Trump and&nbsp; disrupt the well-trodden path of the US two-party system.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who Is Jill Stein?</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein is a former physician and environmental advocate, bringing a wealth of experience to the ballot. She advocates for bold policies centred on the Green New Deal and social justice with her call for “people, planet, and peace.” While her polling numbers currently hover between 1.1 per cent and 1.4 per cent nationally, her message resonates deeply with a tiny minority yearning for real change.<br />
<br />
<strong>Early Life And Education</strong><br />
<br />
Born on May 14, 1950, in Chicago, Jill Stein is of Russian-Jewish ancestry. She attended North Shore Congregation Israel and was influenced deeply by the values instilled in her. In a 2012 interview, she noted the significant impact of Reform Judaism's emphasis on social justice, saying her parents - especially her Holocaust-survivor mother - instilled in her &nbsp;the importance of social responsibility.<br />
She graduated from Harvard University with a degree in sociology in 1973 and earned her medical degree from Harvard Medical School in 1979.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
<strong>From Doctor To Activist</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein began her career as an instructor in internal medicine at Harvard Medical School. She practiced medicine for 25 years. In the 1990s, as a physician, she saw how toxic exposures linked to environmental issues harmed our health. This realisation drove her to fight for a cleaner environment, helping non-profits and marginalised communities address environmental injustice and racism. She played a key role in cleaning up the "Filthy Five" coal plants in Massachusetts, raising national standards for pollution.<br />
<br />
Stein also worked to close a toxic medical waste incinerator in Lawrence, Massachusetts, a low-income area in New England. She helped improve fish advisories&nbsp;to better protect women, children, Native Americans and immigrants from mercury contamination.<br />
<br />
Witnessing how lobbyists and campaign contributions blocked health and environmental protections, Stein focused on campaign finance reform. She helped pass the Clean Election Law through a voter referendum, which succeeded with a two-to-one margin. However, the Democratic-controlled Massachusetts Legislature repealed it later. This event strengthened Stein's alignment with the Green Party and her commitment to reducing corporate influence in politics.<br />
<br />
In 2003, Jill Stein co-founded the Massachusetts Coalition for Healthy Communities. Five years later, she led the “Secure Green Future” ballot initiative. This measure aimed to shift subsidies from fossil fuels to renewable energy and create green jobs. It received overwhelming support, winning over 81 per cent of the vote in the districts where it appeared on the ballot.<br />
<br />
<strong>Political Career</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein joined the Green Party in 2002, driven by her growing dissatisfaction with the Democratic Party's stance on environmental and social issues. The final straw was the repeal of Massachusetts' Clean Election Law, which provided public funding for candidates not receiving large private donations.<br />
<br />
Stein's transition to the Green Party began in 2000 when she participated in the Massachusetts Democratic Party's platform committee. She advocated for environmental and social justice measures but felt her efforts were ignored. In 2002, Stein ran for governor of Massachusetts as a Green-Rainbow Party candidate. She later became a member of the Lexington Town Meeting in 2005.<br />
<br />
<strong>2012 Presidential Election Campaign</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein ran for president in 2012 as the Green Party nominee. Her campaign focused on the Green New Deal, Medicare for All, free higher education, ending wars and occupations and climate action.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Throughout her campaign, Stein faced challenges, including being excluded from major presidential debates due to Commission on Presidential Debates rules requiring candidates to poll at 15 per cent nationally. Undeterred, Stein participated in alternative debates and engaged with voters through social media and grassroots events. She and running mate Cheri Honkala were arrested while attempting to enter the Hofstra University debate site.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
On Election Day, Stein received just 0.4 per cent of the total votes. Stein's 2012 run laid the groundwork for her subsequent presidential campaigns in 2016 and 2024.<br />
<br />
<strong>2016 Presidential Election Campaign</strong><br />
<br />
In her 2016 presidential campaign, Jill Stein focused on the “Power to the People Plan,” focusing on the Green New Deal, jobs as a right, and healthcare and education as fundamental rights. Her campaign gained traction, especially among Bernie Sanders' supporters at the Democratic National Convention. Stein selected human rights activist Ajamu Baraka as her running mate, and her campaign raised over $11 million, qualifying for federal matching funds.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
On Election Day, she received over 1.07 per cent of the popular vote, performing well in Hawaii, Oregon and Vermont.<br />
<br />
<strong>Jill Stein's Stance On Israel</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein previously called for ending all foreign aid to Israel, accusing it of committing war crimes. Her campaign supported the Boycott, Divestment, Sanctions (BDS) movement, claiming Israel engages in policies similar to apartheid and illegal settlements. She has also publicly criticised US support for Israel, arguing that it enables the Israeli government's worst behaviours.<br />
<br />
In 2016, she <a href="https://x.com/DrJillStein/status/752875581780402176 ">tweeted</a> against her opponents “Pro Israeli” Democrat Bernie Sanders and Republican Donald Trump, saying, “If you don't want to vote for a warmonger or racist billionaire, there are more options. The political revolution will keep going.”<br />
<br />
<strong>Awards And Recognition</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein has earned several awards for her work in health and environmental protection, including Clean Water Action's ‘Not in Anyone's Backyard' Award and the ‘Children's Health Hero' Award.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
She has been featured as an environmental health expert on major television programmes and served on the board of Physicians for Social Responsibility.<br />
<br />
<strong>Works</strong><br />
<br />
Jill Stein has co-authored two important reports: In Harm's Way: Toxic Threats to Child Development (2000) and Environmental Threats to Healthy Aging (2009). The first report has been translated into four languages and is used globally as a tool for health and environmental justice, linking human health, social justice and green economies.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-11/jill-stein_650x400_71479998530.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>