<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:29:00 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pms-private-chat-caught-on-camera-in-awkward-summit-blooper-6442254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian PMs Private Chat Caught On Camera In Awkward Summit Blooper]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-pms-private-chat-caught-on-camera-in-awkward-summit-blooper-6442254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:17:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An unguarded exchange between Australia's prime minister and a veteran US diplomat about a sensitive Pacific policing plan was caught on camera, causing blushes at a regional summit Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An unguarded exchange between Australia's prime minister and a veteran US diplomat about a sensitive Pacific policing plan was caught on camera, causing blushes at a regional summit Thursday.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Deputy Secretary of State Kurt Campbell were heard celebrating a deal at the Pacific Islands Forum in Tonga that is seen as a way of stymying similar Chinese-led efforts.</p>

<p>"We had a cracker," Albanese told Campbell, celebrating a deal to establish a police training facility and a crisis reaction force of about 200 personnel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It will make such a difference," he said, with a coffee cup in hand.</p>

<p>Campbell hailed the agreement as "fantastic" and said Washington had considered doing something similar, before allowing Australia to take the lead.</p>

<p>"We've given you the whole lane, so take the lane," Campbell urged Albanese, in an exchange filmed by a reporter.</p>

<p>Albanese seized the moment to jokingly ask if Washington would like to help bankroll the project: "You can go us halfsies on the cost if you like".</p>

<p>"It would only cost you a bit."</p>

<p>Australia has set aside US$271 million for the initial phase of the project.</p>

<p>The exchange will fuel often-repeated Chinese allegations that Australia is doing America's bidding in the region, and that both countries are preoccupied with countering Beijing's growing influence.</p>

<p>Sydney has tried to paint the police initiative as coming from the Pacific Islands -- despite Australia bankrolling the project and hosting the training facility in Brisbane.</p>

<p>Asked later Thursday about whether the pair had been guilty of saying "the quiet part out loud", Albanese bristled.</p>

<p>"This has come from the Pacific. And I'm aware of the video of a private conversation. Kurt Campbell's a mate of mine, it's us having a chat," he claimed.</p>

<p>"People try and read something into it, you must be pretty bored, frankly," he said.</p>

<p>"It is Pacific-led, this has been led by police ministers who have been meeting about this for a year," he said.</p>

<p>China's Pacific allies -- most notably Vanuatu and Solomon Islands -- had voiced concern that the policing plan represented a "geo-strategic denial security doctrine", designed to box out Beijing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China tried and failed to ink a region-wide security pact in 2022, but has since been plying some under-resourced Pacific police forces with martial arts training and fleets of Chinese-made vehicles.</p>

<p>While all members of the forum have endorsed the deal in principle, national leaders will have to decide how much they participate, if at all.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/34pb0548_australia-pm-with-kurt-campbell-x-_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australia PM Anthony Albanese was caught speaking to Kurt Campbell with a coffee cup in hand.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/listeria-outbreak-in-us-us-reports-more-illnesses-deaths-in-listeria-outbreak-linked-to-deli-meat-6441348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reports More Illnesses, Deaths In Listeria Outbreak Linked To Deli Meat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/listeria-outbreak-in-us-us-reports-more-illnesses-deaths-in-listeria-outbreak-linked-to-deli-meat-6441348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:05:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US has reported more than 50 illnesses and eight deaths in Listeria outbreak, according to the latest data released by the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US has reported more than 50 illnesses and eight deaths in Listeria outbreak, according to the latest data released by the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).</p>

<p>Listeria is a hardy germ that can remain on surfaces, like meat slicers, and foods, even at refrigerated temperatures, Xinhua news agency reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>It can also take up to 10 weeks for some people to have symptoms of listeriosis, according to CDC.</p>

<p>Epidemiologic, laboratory, and traceback data show that meats sliced at delis, including Boar's Head brand liverwurst, are contaminated with Listeria and are making people sick, according to CDC.</p>

<p>Listeria spreads easily among deli equipment, surfaces, hands, and food.</p>

<p>A total of 57 people have been hospitalised due to Listeria infections in the country, and eight deaths have now been reported, according to CDC.</p>

<p>This is the largest listeriosis outbreak since the 2011 outbreak linked to cantaloupe.</p>

<p>The CDC requested the public not to eat recalled deli products.</p>

<p>People who are at higher risk of getting sick with Listeria, such as those who are pregnant, are aged 65 or older, or have a weakened immune system, are suggested to avoid eating meats sliced at deli counters, unless heated until steaming hot just before serving.</p>

<p>The new deaths include two in South Carolina and one each in Florida, Tennessee and New Mexico. Illinois, New Jersey and Virginia have also reported deaths in the outbreak, which genetic testing has linked to liverwurst products manufactured by Boar's Head.</p>

<p>Boar's Head has recalled more than 7 million pounds of 71 different meat and poultry products as of July 30, according to the US Department of Agriculture.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/n2b54rv_hospital-generic_625x300_02_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Listeria Outbreak In US: Listeria spreads easily among deli equipment, surfaces, hands, and food.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-urges-telegram-to-help-combat-digital-sex-crimes-6442179]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Urges Telegram To Help Combat Digital Sex Crimes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-urges-telegram-to-help-combat-digital-sex-crimes-6442179]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 10:01:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korean authorities called on Telegram and other social media platforms on Wednesday to work together with them in deleting and blocking sexually explicit deepfake content, seeking to appease public and political outrage over the problem.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean authorities called on Telegram and other social media platforms on Wednesday to work together with them in deleting and blocking sexually explicit deepfake content, seeking to appease public and political outrage over the problem.</p>

<p>The steps follow reports by several domestic media outlets that sexually explicit deepfake images and videos of South Korean women were often found in Telegram chatrooms.</p>

<p>A 24-hour hotline for victims will also be set up and the number of regulatory personnel monitoring digital sex crimes will be doubled from the current number of 70, the Korea Communications Standards Commission said.</p>

<p>The Korean National Police Agency also said it will make a seven-month push to crack down on online sex crimes.</p>

<p>The media watchdog plans to set up a consultative body to enhance communication with social media firms about deleting and blocking sexual deepfake content, its chairman, Ryu Hee-lim, told a meeting on the issue.</p>

<p>For companies that don't have offices in South Korea, it wants to set up a face-to-face channel for regular consultation.</p>

<p>"Production, possession and distribution of deepfake sex crime videos are a serious crime that destroys the individual dignity and personal rights," Ryu said.</p>

<p>In addition to Telegram, the commission said it would be seeking cooperation from X as well as Meta's Facebook and Instagram and Google's YouTube.</p>

<p>Telegram said it actively moderates harmful content on its platform including illegal pornography.</p>

<p>"Moderators use a combination of proactive monitoring of public parts of the platform, sophisticated AI tools and user reports in order to remove millions of pieces of harmful content each day," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>The other companies did not respond to Reuter's requests for comment.</p>

<p>Criticism of Telegram in South Korea has coincided with the arrest of Pavel Durov, Telegram's Russian-born founder, on the weekend - part of a French probe into child pornography, drug trafficking and fraud on the encrypted messaging app.</p>

<p>The number of deepfake sex crime cases in South Korea has surged from 156 in 2021 when data was first collated to 297 so far this year, with most of the perpetrators being teenagers, according to police.</p>

<p>The victims are usually female and include school students as well as female soldiers in South Korea's military.</p>

<p>This year, South Koreans have made more than 6,400 requests for help from the Korea Communications Standards Commission to have sexually explicit deepfake content taken down. That compares with nearly 7,200 cases last year in which the commission agreed to help take down content.</p>

<p>Telegram is now the main platform of choice for perpetrators of sexually explicit deepfake content, said Kim Yeo-jin, the head of the Korea Cyber Sexual Violence Response Center, adding that police need to do more.</p>

<p>In many cases, victims have been told by police that filing a report wouldn't be effective because the content was on Telegram, making it tough to catch the criminals, she said.</p>

<p>Police officials did not respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>Information on how social media firms respond to requests by South Korean authorities is hard to come by.</p>

<p>But police data published by lawmaker Kim Young-bae in 2020 showed that police made seven requests to Telegram via email for help with investigations into digital sex crimes between February and August of that year and Telegram did not respond to any of them.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/momh7su8_telegram-reuters_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Criticism of Telegram in South Korea has coincided with the arrest of Pavel Durov (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-amplifies-false-claims-against-kamala-harris-veep-pick-tim-walz-6442005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Amplifies False Claims Against Kamala Harris' Veep Pick Tim Walz]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-amplifies-false-claims-against-kamala-harris-veep-pick-tim-walz-6442005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 09:25:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A barrage of attacks on Tim Walz fueled by misinformation over his support for LGBTQ communities has failed to dent the US vice presidential candidate's surging poll ratings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A barrage of attacks on Tim Walz fueled by misinformation over his support for LGBTQ communities has failed to dent the US vice presidential candidate's surging poll ratings, suggesting that voters are wearying of some "culture war" issues in a tight White House race.</p>

<p>The push, which includes false assertions that Walz signed a law protecting paedophiles, has been amplified by Donald Trump and top Republicans as political campaigning kicks into high gear ahead of the November 5 election.</p>

<p>Walz -- the popular two-term governor of Minnesota -- has also faced a torrent of misinformation about his legislative record on transgender rights and gender-affirming care.</p>

<p>Trump recently heaped scorn on Walz, saying he was "heavy into the transgender world."</p>

<p>Trump's supporters have mocked him as "Tampon Tim," falsely asserting that he forced schools to make tampons and pads available in boys' toilets after he signed a law that requires schools to make the products available for free for menstruating students.</p>

<p>But -- unlike an issue such as abortion, which has driven voters to polls at local, state and national levels since the Supreme Court overturned the right to the procedure in 2022 -- the attacks appear to have failed to move the needle on Walz.</p>

<p>"People are getting 'issue fatigue' with regards to the culture wars," Todd Belt, director of the political management program at George Washington University, told AFP.</p>

<p>"As the election gets closer, people want to hear out kitchen-table issues that have a material effect on their well-being."</p>

<h3><strong>'Real issues'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>"Inflation is Americans' most important issue," said an Economist-YouGov poll in mid-August, with 26 per cent expressing concern about prices.</p>

<p>When asked about other issues "important" to Americans, jobs and the economy, immigration, healthcare and climate change were listed as the top answers.</p>

<p>Abortion, which many Americans regard as a hot-button culture war issue, appeared on the list, at sixth place.</p>

<p>"Voters are insisting that politicians focus instead on the real issues facing our nation, including inflation, abortion rights, and climate change," said GLAAD president Sarah Kate Ellis.</p>

<p>Her statement followed a survey in March which concluded that campaigning on anti-transgender issues was a "losing strategy," with candidates who frequently discuss them creating more opposition than support for their campaigns.</p>

<p>That has not stopped both Republicans and Democrats from putting the culture wars at the centre of their campaigns, and in a volatile election cycle issues other than abortion could yet break through.</p>

<p>But for now, despite the hammering of his pro-LGBTQ record, Walz has stayed easily ahead of Republican vice-presidential nominee J.D. Vance in national polling.</p>

<h3><strong>'People are tired'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Much of the rhetoric against Walz involves children, including a viral claim across social media that he signed a bill last year protecting paedophiles in Minnesota, AFP fact-checkers reported.</p>

<p>The false claim, which garnered tens of thousands of views on sites such as Instagram, deploys a long-standing disinformation trope tying the LGBTQ community to paedophilia.</p>

<p>While lawmakers did remove a reference to paedophilia in the state's human rights law, experts including Naomi Cahn, a University of Virginia professor, said the move does not affect the "criminal laws concerning sexual contact with a child."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other posts falsely accuse Walz of allowing the state to terminate parental custody if trans children are stopped by their parents from receiving gender-affirming care.</p>

<p>"Tim Walz signed a bill that lets the state take away (your) kids... in the name of 'gender-affirming care,'" conservative talk show host Megyn Kelly wrote on the platform X, a falsehood that garnered over 2.5 million views and was widely shared by Trump supporters.</p>

<p>Walz battled such misinformation after he signed the Trans Refuge Bill last year, granting legal protection to transgender people who come to Minnesota to seek medical care, even if the treatment is illegal in their home state.</p>

<p>Top Republicans such as Florida Governor Ron DeSantis and Virginia Governor Glenn Youngkin did see electoral success in past voting cycles by stoking anti-LGBTQ rhetoric.</p>

<p>But polls showed that -- unlike Democrats with abortion rights -- Republicans had little success mobilizing voters around anti-trans issues in the 2022 midterm elections.</p>

<p>"It's not working right now" before the November election, Belt said, adding that "people are tired" of the messaging.</p>

<p>"You can't win an election just by being against something."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/oue2hme8_tim-walz-afp_625x300_21_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tim Walz has also faced a torrent of misinformation about his legislative record on trans rights (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-tv-slammed-after-pic-of-sexy-santa-dancers-at-staff-meeting-goes-viral-6441812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian TV Slammed As Pic Of "Sexy Santa" Dancers At Meeting Goes Viral]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/australian-tv-slammed-after-pic-of-sexy-santa-dancers-at-staff-meeting-goes-viral-6441812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 08:38:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A local Australian news channel has come under fire after a video of a dancing group of "sexy Santas" emerged from what has been described as a routine staff meeting.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A local Australian news channel has come under fire after a video of a dancing group of "sexy Santas" emerged from what has been described as a routine staff meeting. According to the <em>New York Post,</em> the meeting of Seven Network's parent company Seven West Media in Perth was held last week on Friday and was intended to introduce new appointments. It was when the Deputy news director was discussing an upcoming programme when Mariah Carey's '<em>All I Want for Christmas' </em>started playing, and a group of female dancers wearing Santa hats and short red dresses appeared on stage.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/26/media/news-station-under-fire-over-sexy-santas-at-staff-meeting/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>, a photo of the meeting was shared on social media and it drew heavy criticism, with many saying it was a scene pulled directly from the 1980s. In the meeting, female staff reacted with shock, and some even walked out in protest.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"OMG - if they thought that was even slightly appropriate given everything we've found out about them, the cultural makeup of that organization is badly broken," wrote one social media user. "That will help fix the culture issues which have been uncovered," said another.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A Seven West Media staff meeting last Friday featured women dancers dressed as sexy Santas. I thought this was a parody news report until I saw it confirmed by numerous news media. So Seven is STILL stuck in the 1970's," commented a third.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A Seven West Media staff meeting last Friday featured women dancers dressed as sexy Santas. I thought this was a parody news report until I saw it confirmed by numerous news media. So Seven is STILL stuck in the 1970's. ? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/media?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#media</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/sexism?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#sexism</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/journalism?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#journalism</a> <a href="https://t.co/mf0XxFyh9N">pic.twitter.com/mf0XxFyh9N</a></p>
— Peter Murphy (@PeterWMurphy1) <a href="https://twitter.com/PeterWMurphy1/status/1828290672161673428?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A spokesman for Seven West Media, on the other hand, defended the dancers, explaining that they were part of the Christmas Pageant, which is a "Perth institution".&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/us-woman-opens-up-about-weight-loss-journey-after-shedding-whopping-226-kg-6441548">US Woman Opens Up About Weight-Loss Journey After Shedding Whopping 226 Kg</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, according to the <em>Post</em>, the incident comes amid ongoing scrutiny over alleged inappropriate behaviour at the media network. In recent weeks, veteran Sydney reporter Robert Ovadia launched legal action in the Federal Court against the company. Mr Ovadia reportedly stood down in June following an investigation into allegations of inappropriate behaviour.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Ovadia lodged proceedings in the Federal Court against the Seven Network and its news boss, Anthony De Ceglie. He claimed that Seven told him that no complaints had been made against him. "Any suggestion that I have behaved inappropriately at any time is false, malicious and will be defended," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The media group, for its part, said that it takes any allegations in retaliation to sexual harassment, bullying and other behaviours deemed to be inappropriate "seriously".&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t4d7adno_channel-7-meeting_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the meeting, female staff reacted with shock.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-battery-maker-arrested-over-factory-fire-that-killed-23-6441726]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Battery Maker Arrested Over Factory Fire That Killed 23]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-battery-maker-arrested-over-factory-fire-that-killed-23-6441726]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 08:14:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The CEO of a South Korean lithium battery maker has been arrested over a factory fire that killed 23 people in June, a local court told AFP Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CEO of a South Korean lithium battery maker has been arrested over a factory fire that killed 23 people in June, a local court told AFP Thursday.</p>

<p>Park Soon-kwan, the CEO of Aricell, was arrested late Wednesday over the deadly incident, a spokesperson for the Suwon District Court said.</p>

<p>According to Seoul's labour ministry, Park's arrest is the first time a CEO has been arrested for violations of the Serious Accidents Punishment Act, a law implemented in 2022 to hold employers accountable for workplace disasters.</p>

<p>In a statement, the ministry said Park was arrested on "charges of causing the deaths of 23 people by employing unskilled contract workers to handle materials with a high fire risk".</p>

<p>Police have also previously blamed the company's "gross" safety failures for the deadly blaze.</p>

<p>The fire was caused by a rush to meet a supply deadline and a failure to address indications of dangerous quality defects in the batteries, according to police.</p>

<p>Aricell had also manipulated data to meet its military procurements and had been cheating on quality inspections since 2021, they said.</p>

<p>The blaze was one of South Korea's worst factory disasters in years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s6itfj58_south-korean-battery-factory-in-fire-reuters-_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The fire was caused by a failure to address indications of dangerous quality defects in the batteries.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-is-now-among-worlds-top-4-greenhouse-gas-emitters-due-to-wildfires-6441691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Is Now Among World's Top 4 Greenhouse Gas Emitters Due To Wildfires]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-is-now-among-worlds-top-4-greenhouse-gas-emitters-due-to-wildfires-6441691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 08:04:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Record wildfires in 2023 bumped Canada into the top four greenhouse gas-emitting countries in the world that year, according to a study Wednesday that also cast doubt on its forests' future ability to capture and store significant amounts of CO2.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Record wildfires in 2023 bumped Canada into the top four greenhouse gas-emitting countries in the world that year, according to a study Wednesday that also cast doubt on its forests' future ability to capture and store significant amounts of CO2.</p>

<p>Last year saw a catastrophic number of wildfires across the country, with 15 million hectares -- some 58,000 square miles, or about four per cent of Canada's total forest area -- burned and more than 200,000 people displaced.</p>

<p>Looking at satellite data of smoke plumes from fires that burned from May to September of last year, researchers determined that 2,371 megatonnes of carbon dioxide and monoxide were released, pushing Canada's ranking up from eleventh to fourth among the world's top carbon emitters.</p>

<p>It put the country behind only China, the United States and India for 2023.</p>

<p>The research was published in the journal Nature.</p>

<p>The researchers warn that the hot, dry weather responsible for those blazes is forecast to become the norm by the 2050s, and is "likely to drive an increase in fire activity."</p>

<p>"This raises concerns about whether potentially more frequent and intense fires in the coming decades will suppress the ability of Canadian forests to continue serving as carbon sinks," Brendan Byrne, lead author of the study, told AFP.</p>

<p>Canada's boreal forest, a vast swath stretching from the Pacific to the Atlantic oceans, holds significant amounts of what is known as "sequestered" CO2.</p>

<p>As scorched forests regrow over decades, the CO2 released by wildfires is usually reabsorbed.</p>

<p>But a jump in the size and number of annual fires, coupled with droughts in some regions, could mean forests take longer to grow back.</p>

<p>That in turn "could suppress carbon uptake by the forests," said the study.</p>

<p>Canada would have to adjust downward its level of allowable fossil fuel emissions in order "to compensate for reduced carbon uptake by forests," it concluded.</p>

<p>Ottawa has agreed under the Paris Agreement to reduce carbon emissions by 40 to 45 per cent from 2005 levels by 2030.</p>

<p>Canada's total CO2-equivalent emissions from burning fossil fuels in 2022 were 708 megatonnes, according to government data.</p>

<p>As human activity has warmed the planet over the past two decades, the frequency and intensity of extreme wildfires have more than doubled worldwide, according to another study published in June in the journal Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution.</p>

<p>The wildfire situation in Canada this year has been more subdued but still calamitous in some parts, with the beloved tourist town of Jasper in the western part of the country partially destroyed in July.</p>

<p>As of Wednesday, there were 732 fires burning -- 136 out of control.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-08/mrif6tpg_canada-wild-fire_625x300_03_August_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As of Wednesday, 732 fires were burning out of which 136 were out of control in Canada (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-considers-new-mixed-reality-glasses-as-an-alternative-to-headsets-6441654]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta Considers New Mixed Reality Glasses As An Alternative To Headsets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-considers-new-mixed-reality-glasses-as-an-alternative-to-headsets-6441654]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:57:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meta Platforms is planning a mixed reality device that resembles a bulky pair of glasses, the Information reported on Wednesday, citing two employees from the social media giant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meta Platforms is planning a mixed reality device that resembles a bulky pair of glasses, the Information reported on Wednesday, citing two employees from the social media giant.</p>

<p>Internally code-named "Puffin", the new project is focused on designing an alternative to the heavy headsets offered by Facebook's parent company, which have a limited consumer appeal, the report added.</p>

<p>Meta did not immediately respond to a Reuters' request for comment.</p>

<p>Mixed reality merges augmented and virtual reality and allows real-world and digital objects to interact.</p>

<p>Augmented reality overlays text, sounds, graphics and video onto real-world images that users see in front of them, while virtual reality puts users into a completely artificial environment, creating computer-generated experiences.</p>

<p>Puffin would be a significantly smaller device than Meta's existing Quest headsets, the report said, adding the project is still in the early stages with a planned release in 2027.</p>

<p>Meta's Reality Labs division, in charge of developing and marketing the Quest line of VR headsets, has incurred financial losses amounting to billions. Despite this, CEO Mark Zuckerberg remains optimistic about the future prospects of augmented and virtual reality technologies.</p>

<p>Unlike Quest headsets, the new Puffin device will not include handheld controllers as users will be able to operate it with hand gestures and eye movements, according to the report.</p>

<p>The virtual and mixed reality headset market gained renewed attention following Apple's entry last year, although its Vision Pro has faced challenges in sales due to a price tag of nearly $3,500.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/fr5311mo_meta-ai_625x300_30_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Puffin would be a significantly smaller device than Meta's existing Quest headsets (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-allowed-child-pornography-drug-trafficking-on-app-rules-france-court-6441623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram CEO Allowed "Child Pornography, Drug Trafficking" On App, Rules Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/telegram-ceo-pavel-durov-allowed-child-pornography-drug-trafficking-on-app-rules-france-court-6441623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:49:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, founder and CEO of Telegram, has been charged in France for allowing several criminal activities on the messaging app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pavel Durov, founder and CEO of Telegram, has been charged in France for allowing several criminal activities on the messaging app. The billionaire failed to curb spread of sexual images of children, drug trafficking and other illegal activities on Telegram, the court ruled.</p>

<p>In a statement, the Paris prosecutors said that Durov has been charged with refusing to share documents demanded by authorities as well as "dissemination of images of minors in child pornography" as well as drug trafficking, fraud and money laundering.</p>

<p>The charges against the 39-year-old paint a picture of a platform almost entirely uncooperative with authorities and include allegations he refused to help agencies run legal wiretaps on suspects. He has also been accused of enabling gangs and organised criminal networks to carry out illegal transactions on the app.</p>

<p>Russian-born Durov, who was arrested on Saturday, has been granted bail on the condition that he must not leave France and report to a police station twice a week. He has also been ordered to pay $ 5.6 million in bail.</p>

<p>In a statement released on Telegram on Sunday, the Dubai-based company asserted that Durov has "nothing to hide" and that the app abides by European laws.</p>

<p>"It is absurd to claim that a platform or its owner are responsible for abuse of that platform," the statement declared. "We're awaiting a prompt resolution of this situation."</p>

<p>The case has fuelled debate on where freedom of speech ends and enforcement of the law begins. It also underlines the uneasy relationship between governments and Telegram, which has close to 1 billion users, while serving as a warning shot to tech titans who refuse to comply with authorities over alleged illegality on their platforms.</p>

<p>Separately, Durov is also being investigated on suspicion of "serious acts of violence" towards one of his children while he and an ex-partner, the boy's mother, were in Paris, a source said. She also filed another complaint against Durov in Switzerland last year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m7qorqqs_pavel-durov_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaign-for-georgia-intensifies-ahead-of-us-polls-6441590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris Vs Trump: Campaign For Georgia Intensifies Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-campaign-for-georgia-intensifies-ahead-of-us-polls-6441590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:39:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Vice President Kamala Harris campaigned across southern Georgia by bus Wednesday as Democrats try to harness a surge of enthusiasm and put the swing state back in play in November's election against Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris campaigned across southern Georgia by bus on Wednesday as Democrats try to harness a surge of enthusiasm and put the swing state back in play in November's election against Donald Trump.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden had been on course to lose the southern state he flipped from Republican Trump in 2020, but since Harris replaced Biden as the candidate five weeks ago, the party has begun to hope it could win it again.</p>

<p>Both Harris and Trump are now ramping up their campaigns in seven key battleground states as an extraordinary -- and now super-short -- White House race enters its final 10-week sprint.</p>

<p>"We're seizing on the energy and putting in the work to win again in 2024," Harris's campaign said.</p>

<p>Riding a wave of enthusiasm from the Democratic National Convention last week, Harris and running mate Tim Walz are travelling through southern parts of Georgia on a two-day bus tour.</p>

<p>The blitz is focused on Black and working-class voters who the campaign believes are crucial to a Harris victory in the state in November.</p>

<p>She and Walz began their tour in Savannah, where they met students from a historically Black university, before heading by bus through rural communities where some onlookers waved Trump flags, and then stopping at Liberty County High School in Hinesville.</p>

<p>"We wanted to come by just to let you know that our country is counting on you," Harris told student marching band members there.</p>

<p>Back in Savannah the candidates ducked into Sandfly Bar-B-Q, a small restaurant where they chatted with diners and staff and posed for photographs.</p>

<p>"You have to stay in it," Harris encouraged a patron about the upcoming election.</p>

<h3><strong>'Dangerously liberal'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The bus tour culminates with a rally Thursday in Savannah, where the 59-year-old also faces a critical test on the same day: her first sit-down interview since starting her campaign, in a joint appearance on CNN with Walz.</p>

<p>Republicans have criticized her for not facing media scrutiny sooner, and Trump spokesman Jason Miller accused her on Wednesday of using Walz as a "human shield."</p>

<p>But Harris has been content to let her campaign do the talking in the frenetic weeks since the 81-year-old Biden stunned the country by bowing out.</p>

<p>She has reinvigorated the Democratic Party, raised more than half a billion dollars and wiped out Trump's lead in the polls.</p>

<p>Harris insists, however, she remains the underdog, and that the election will be won or lost in the battleground states.</p>

<p>In the last days of Biden's campaign, increasingly poor polls showed his only real remaining hope of victory was through winning the three "Rust Belt" states of Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin.</p>

<p>Harris is now also targeting the four "Sun Belt" states of Georgia, Arizona, Nevada and North Carolina as a way to give her multiple ways to win the overall Electoral College vote.</p>

<p>The Peach State is a particularly tough target. Biden won it by a razor-thin margin of less than 12,000 votes in 2020, a result that Trump bitterly contested.</p>

<p>The Republican now faces criminal charges in Georgia related to his alleged plot to overturn that vote.</p>

<p>On Wednesday in an uplift for her campaign, the latest Fox News poll shows Harris edging Trump in Georgia, 50 percent to 48 percent.</p>

<p>But Trump is also stepping up his swing state campaign as he seeks to recover his poise after being wrong-footed by new flag bearer Harris.</p>

<p>The vice president is not only two decades younger than Trump and of Black and South Asian heritage, but vying to be the first female US president.</p>

<p>Trump will be attacking Harris's "dangerously liberal policies" Thursday in Michigan and Wisconsin, before traveling to Pennsylvania on Friday, the campaign said.</p>

<p>But his team was embroiled in controversy Wednesday after a report that Trump's entourage shoved and verbally abused staff during a politicized visit to the United States' most hallowed resting place for its war dead.</p>

<p>National Public Radio reported that the incident happened when an Arlington National Cemetery official tried to prevent Trump aides from taking images in a section for those killed in recent wars, where filming and staging of political events is banned.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Both Kamala Harris and Donald Trump are now ramping up their campaigns in seven key battleground states.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/why-is-worlds-most-important-stock-nvidia-falling-expert-explains-6441549]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Is 'World's Most Important Stock' Nvidia Falling, Expert Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/why-is-worlds-most-important-stock-nvidia-falling-expert-explains-6441549]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 07:23:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence behemoth Nvidia on Wednesday said quarterly sales reached a higher-than-expected $30 billion in the last quarter, though that growth was slower than the furious pace seen in previous quarters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence behemoth Nvidia on Wednesday said quarterly sales reached a higher-than-expected $30 billion in the last quarter, though that growth was slower than the furious pace seen in previous quarters.</p>

<p>Declared by Wall Street to be the world's most important stock, the California-based AI chip-maker led by CEO Jensen Huang saw its share price fall by about four percent in after hours trading.</p>

<p>Even though sales and profit, which hit $16.5 billion in the period, more than doubled from a year earlier, investors showed nervousness that Nvidia's extraordinary growth, spurred by the AI frenzy, may be showing signs of normalization.</p>

<p>The world's biggest tech companies have invested tens of billions of dollars, quarter after quarter, into Nvidia's powerful AI chips and software in order to get their ChatGPT-style AI models up and running.</p>

<p>Microsoft, Google, Meta, Tesla and Amazon all depend on Nvidia technology to train generative AI models and execute the heavy computing workloads needed to deploy the new technology.</p>

<p>Ahead of the latest earnings, Nvidia's share price was up about 160 per cent year-to-date and has accounted for a third of the broad-based S&amp;P 500 index's gains this year.</p>

<p>Nvidia stock wavered in July, as investor sentiment hesitated over whether generative AI would be a money-making enterprise anytime soon.</p>

<p>But in recent weeks Nvidia's share price has been back on its historic tear, nearing the heights of a few months ago when the firm was very briefly the world's most valuable company when measured by stock valuation.</p>

<p>The market had expected the company to post sales at about $28 billion, more than double from a year ago.</p>

<p>"Nvidia once again delivered spectacular results, beating expectations with margins that rival its previous blockbuster quarters, despite growing economic uncertainties and AI bubble concerns," said Emarketer technology analyst Jacob Bourne.</p>

<p>Nvidia's financial postings have become must-see events on Wall Street after the company has repeatedly crushed expectations, many times tripling its revenue and profit.</p>

<h3><strong>'Disappointed a touch'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>But some analysts worried that Nvidia was slowly coming down to earth with its latest earnings, as stellar as they might be.</p>

<p>"It's less about just beating estimates now -- markets expect them to be shattered, and it's the scale of the beat today that looks to have disappointed a touch," said Matt Britzman, senior equity analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown.</p>

<p>Traders also focused on Nvidia's forecast that next quarter's revenue will be about $32.5 billion.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Though this was better than the average of analyst predictions, it left some observers disappointed that the days of triple-digit growth were over.</p>

<p>Investors were also laser focused on any potential delays to Nvidia's new generation Blackwell line of technology, the successor to the best-selling Hopper line of AI chips that thrust the company onto the world stage.</p>

<p>CEO Huang said the new product line would ship at scale to clients in the coming months, with its previous generation of AI chips expected to maintain very strong sales.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/aqaknihg_nvidia_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The world's biggest tech companies have invested billions of dollars into Nvidia's AI chips (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/condom-use-among-european-teens-worryingly-declining-who-6441394]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Condom Use Among European Teens "Worryingly" Declining: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/condom-use-among-european-teens-worryingly-declining-who-6441394]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:38:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Condom use among sexually active teens has declined significantly in Europe over the past decade, with rates of unprotected sex "worryingly high", the World Health Organization said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Condom use among sexually active teens has declined significantly in Europe over the past decade, with rates of unprotected sex "worryingly high", the World Health Organization said Thursday.</p>

<p>"This is putting young people at significant risk of sexually transmitted infections (STIs) and unplanned pregnancies," WHO Europe said in a statement.</p>

<p>Data from a survey of more than 242,000 15-year-olds across 42 of the 53 countries that make up the WHO European region, which includes Central Asia, showed that the proportion of sexually active teenage boys who used a condom the last time they had sex fell from 70 percent in 2014 to 61 percent in 2022.</p>

<p>The figure for girls who said a condom had been used the last time they had sex fell from 63 to 57 percent.</p>

<p>Almost a third of adolescents said they used neither a condom nor a contraceptive pill the last time they had intercourse, largely unchanged from 2018.</p>

<p>Use of contraceptive pills also remained relatively stable between 2014 and 2022, with 26 percent of 15-year-olds reporting that they or their partner had used it the last time they had sex.</p>

<p>The report also showed that teens from low-income families were more likely to not use a condom or a pill, with 33 percent reporting using neither during their last intercourse, compared to 25 percent from more affluent families.</p>

<p>"Age-appropriate comprehensive sexuality education remains neglected in many countries, and where it is available, it has increasingly come under attack in recent years on the false premise that it encourages sexual behaviour," WHO Europe director Hans Kluge said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The truth is that equipping young persons with the right knowledge at the right time leads to optimal health outcomes linked to responsible behaviour and choices," he said.</p>

<p>The WHO said that in addition to higher rates of STIs and unplanned pregnancies, inadequate sexuality education also leads to increased healthcare costs and disrupted education and career paths for young people.</p>

<p>"We are reaping the bitter fruit of these reactionary efforts, with worse to come unless governments, health authorities, the education sector and other essential stakeholders truly recognise the root causes of the current situation and take steps to rectify it," it said.</p>

<p>The agency urged policymakers, educators and healthcare providers to invest in comprehensive sexuality education, improve access to sexual health services, promote dialogue and better train educators.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-01/dipedhl_condoms-istock-650_625x300_17_January_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The report also showed that teens from low-income families were more likely to not use a condom.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-threatens-to-suspend-elon-musks-x-in-country-within-24-hours-6441356]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil Threatens To Suspend Elon Musk's X In Country Within 24 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazil-threatens-to-suspend-elon-musks-x-in-country-within-24-hours-6441356]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:20:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered Elon Musk on Wednesday to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country, a court decision showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes ordered billionaire Elon Musk on Wednesday to name a legal representative for his messaging platform X in Brazil within 24 hours or face the site's suspension in the country, a court decision showed.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, X announced it would close its operations and fire its staff in Brazil due to what it called "censorship orders" from Moraes, while adding the firm's service would remain available for users in Brazil.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court posted a screenshot of Wednesday's court decision on its X account, tagging Musk's and X's Global Government Affairs accounts.</p>

<p>X did not immediately respond to a request for comment sent outside normal working hours.</p>

<p>In the decision, Moraes says that under the country's law regulating internet issues, companies that do not respect Brazilian legislation or the confidentiality of private information could have their activities temporarily suspended.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/puugc1eg_elon-musk_625x300_27_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Earlier this month, X announced it would close its operations and fire its staff in Brazi.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-reveals-gunman-viewed-donald-trump-rally-as-target-of-opportunity-report-6441328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[FBI Reveals Gunman Viewed Trump Rally As "Target Of Opportunity": Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/fbi-reveals-gunman-viewed-donald-trump-rally-as-target-of-opportunity-report-6441328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 06:11:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The FBI on Wednesday revealed that the gunman who attempted to kill former President Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania campaign rally last month viewed the event as a "target of opportunity," Al-Jazeera reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The FBI on Wednesday revealed that the gunman who attempted to kill former President Donald Trump at a Pennsylvania campaign rally last month viewed the event as a "target of opportunity," Al-Jazeera reported.</p>

<p>Crooks of Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, fired shots, one of which grazed Trump in the ear at an outdoor rally in Butler. Thomas Matthew Crooks was planted on the roof of a manufacturing plant located over 130 yards away from the stage at Butler Farm Show grounds, the New York Post had reported, citing sources.</p>

<p>According to FBI officials, 20-year-old Thomas Crooks had mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July.</p>

<p>FBI officials said Thomas Crooks searched more than 60 times for details about Trump and his then-rival, Democratic President Joe Biden, before registering for the Trump rally.</p>

<p>"We saw ... a sustained, detailed effort to plan an attack on some events, meaning he looked at any number of events or targets," Kevin Rojek, the FBI's top official in western Pennsylvania, said in a telephone briefing to reporters on Wednesday, according to Al-Jazeera.</p>

<p>Rojek further said that Crooks became "hyper-focused" on the Trump rally when it was announced "and looked at it as a target of opportunity."</p>

<p>Notably, after the assassination attempt, the US Secret Service snipers had shot Crooks and an AR-style rifle was later recovered. Bethel Park is a village 40 miles south of where Trump's rally was held in Butler.</p>

<p>Donald Trump was on stage at a campaign rally in Pennsylvania's Butler before gunshots rang out and Secret Service agents stormed the stage, The Hill had reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thomas Matthew Crooks fired shots, one of which grazed Trump in the ear at an outdoor rally in Butler.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-mysterious-and-controversial-telegram-founder-6441269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pavel Durov: Mysterious And Controversial Telegram Founder]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pavel-durov-mysterious-and-controversial-telegram-founder-6441269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 05:51:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian-born tech entrepreneur Pavel Durov has founded wildly popular social networks, cryptocurrencies, amassed a multi-billion-dollar fortune and locked horns with authorities, in Russia and around the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian-born tech entrepreneur Pavel Durov has founded wildly popular social networks, cryptocurrencies, amassed a multi-billion-dollar fortune and locked horns with authorities, in Russia and around the world.</p>

<p>Still a few months shy of his 40th birthday, the man once dubbed the "Russian Zuckerberg" after Facebook founder Mark Zuckerberg now presides over the Telegram app which boasts more than 900 million users worldwide.</p>

<p>But Durov, 39, who preaches the virtues of ice baths for health and has fathered 100 children through sperm donations, is a controversial as well as enigmatic figure, accused of not doing enough to halt the spread of extremist content on his network.</p>

<p>His sensational arrest at a Paris airport last weekend could prove a turning point, with Durov charged by the French judiciary on Wednesday and banned from leaving the country.</p>

<p>A self-avowed libertarian, Durov has championed confidentiality on the internet and freedom of speech, defiantly refusing to allow the moderation of messages on Telegram.</p>

<p>Despite boasting a fortune estimated by Forbes magazine at $15.5 billion, Durov says his goal in life was never to become rich but "free".</p>

<p>"And to the extent that it is possible my mission in life was to allow other people to also become free... and using the platforms that we created my hope was that could express their freedoms," he told US talk show host Tucker Carlson in a rare interview in April.</p>

<p>"This is the mission of Telegram."</p>

<p><strong>- 'Thanks for all the fish' -</strong></p>

<p>Born in Soviet times into a family of academics in Leningrad, now known as Saint Petersburg, Durov spent his childhood in Italy before his family returned as the USSR crumbled.</p>

<p>While still in his 20s, he founded the VKontakte (VK) social network which catered to the needs of Russian-language users and outgunned Facebook throughout the former USSR.</p>

<p>In a stunt typical of his unpredictable behaviour, Durov in 2012 showered high-denomination notes on pedestrians from VK's headquarters on top of a historic bookstore on Saint Petersburg's Nevsky Prospekt.</p>

<p>After disputes with the Russian authorities and ownership battles, he sold out of VKontakte and founded Telegram along with his brother Nikolai, whom he credits as the mathematical brain behind its success.</p>

<p>Durov resigned from VK with a typical flourish, posting a picture of dolphins and the slogan "So Long and Thanks for All the Fish", a title in the famous "Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy" science fiction series.</p>

<p><strong>- '100 percent owned by myself' -</strong></p>

<p>He stopped living in Russia in 2014, leading a nomadic life that saw him pick up citizenship of the Caribbean nation of Saint Kitts and Nevis.</p>

<p>But his departure from Russia was reportedly not an abrupt exile: according to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing leaked border data, he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021.</p>

<p>Durov settled in Dubai, deciding it offered the best business climate to build up Telegram, also gaining UAE citizenship.</p>

<p>He boasted to Carlson that Telegram has just 30 core staff and spent "zero" on marketing, in stark contrast to its rivals. He made clear "Telegram is 100 percent owned by myself".</p>

<p>In August 2021, he also won French nationality following a low-profile procedure about which Paris remains highly discreet.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal reported that in 2018 President Emmanuel Macron hosted Durov for lunch in Paris and suggested Telegram be based in the French capital.</p>

<p>But Durov declined, said the newspaper, which also reported that France and the UAE had waged a joint operation to hack his phone over concerns Telegram was providing a platform for Islamist extremists.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Civic duty' -</strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Telegram enjoyed stratospheric success, presenting itself as a champion of individual freedoms, refusing "censorship" and protecting the confidentiality of its users.</p>

<p>This rankled with authorities, especially in his home country, and in 2018 a Moscow court ordered the blocking of the application.</p>

<p>But the imposition of the measure was shambolic and Russia has abandoned its efforts to block Telegram which is now used by both the Russian government and the opposition, with some channels boasting several hundred thousand subscribers.</p>

<p>Telegram also plays a key role in Russia's war against Ukraine, documented by bloggers from both sides who post their analyses and videos of the fighting.</p>

<p>Durov has also found time to set up cryptocurrencies, Toncoin and Notcoin which emerged from a viral Telegram game.</p>

<p>Dressed almost always in black and possibly trying to ape the look of Keanu Reeves in "The Matrix", Durov readily cultivates a mystical image.</p>

<p>In July, he boasted in a Telegram post of being the biological father of more than 100 children thanks to his sperm donations in a dozen countries, describing this as a "civic duty", an attitude to parenting that echoes fellow tech mogul, the X and Tesla chief Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Durov told Carlson he was delighted by Musk's acquisition of Twitter. "Twitter or X, that is seemingly becoming more pro-freedom of speech, it's a great development."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/03h9ob6g_pavel-durov_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Born in Soviet times, Pavel Durov is a controversial as well as enigmatic figure.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-makes-landfall-on-japanese-island-of-kyushu-weather-office-6441168]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Typhoon Makes Landfall On Japanese Island Of Kyushu: Weather Office]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/typhoon-makes-landfall-on-japanese-island-of-kyushu-weather-office-6441168]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 05:20:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major typhoon made landfall on Japan's main southern island of Kyushu on Thursday morning, the weather office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Typhoon Shanshan slammed into Japan's main southern island of Kyushu early Thursday, with authorities advising thousands of people to evacuate and issuing the highest warning level for wind and storm surges.</p>

<p>The weather office said that Japan's most powerful typhoon this year made landfall at around 8:00 am (2300 GMT Wednesday) packing gusts of up to 252 kilometres (157 miles) per hour.</p>

<p>Kyushu's utility operator said that 254,610 houses were already without power.</p>

<p>"Special warnings of violent storms, high waves and high tides are being issued to the Kagoshima region (of Kyuhsu)," the Japan Meteorological Office said.</p>

<p>"Please exercise maximum vigilance against violent storms, high waves and high tides in Kagoshima, as well as landslides, flooding in low-lying areas and overflowing rivers in southern Kyushu," it said.</p>

<p>"Please also be advised that the risk of a disaster due to heavy rain can rapidly escalate in western Japan as Friday approaches."</p>

<p>Heavy rain brought by Shanshan has been lashing large parts of Japan since Tuesday.</p>

<p>Three members of a family died after a landslide buried a house in Gamagori, a city in central Aichi prefecture, Japan's Kyodo news agency reported early Thursday, citing local government officials.</p>

<p>The deceased included a couple in their 70s as well as a son in his 30s, while two adult daughters in their 40s survived with injuries, Kyodo reported.</p>

<p>For southern Kyushu, the JMA predicted an enormous 1,100 millimetres (43 inches) of precipitation in the 48 hours to Friday morning.</p>

<p>Video on public broadcaster NHK TV showed roof tiles being blown off houses, broken windows and felled trees.</p>

<p>"Our carport roof was blown away in its entirety. I wasn't at home when it happened, but my kids say they felt the shaking so strong they thought an earthquake happened," a local resident in Miyazaki told NHK.</p>

<p>"I was surprised. It was completely beyond our imagination," she said.</p>

<p>Auto giant Toyota has suspended production at all 14 of its factories in Japan.</p>

<p>Japan Airlines cancelled 172 domestic flights and six international flights scheduled for Wednesday and Thursday, while ANA nixed 219 domestic flights and four international ones on Wednesday, Thursday and Friday.</p>

<p>The cancellations affected around 25,000 people.</p>

<p>Kyushu Railway said it would suspend some Shinkansen bullet train services between Kumamoto and Kagoshima Chuo from Wednesday night and warned of further possible disruption.</p>

<p>Trains between Tokyo and Fukuoka, the most populous city on Kyushu, may also be cancelled depending on weather conditions this week, other operators said.</p>

<p>Shanshan comes in the wake of Typhoon Ampil, which disrupted hundreds of flights and trains this month.</p>

<p>Despite dumping heavy rain, it caused only minor injuries and damage.</p>

<p>Ampil came days after Tropical Storm Maria brought record rains to northern areas.</p>

<p>Typhoons in the region have been forming closer to coastlines, intensifying more rapidly and lasting longer over land due to climate change, according to a study released last month.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/avmjs4jc_typhoon-generic_625x300_03_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A major typhoon made landfall on Japan's main southern island of Kyushu on Thursday morning.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-appoints-1st-female-government-spokesperson-6441092]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Appoints 1st Female Government Spokesperson]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-appoints-1st-female-government-spokesperson-6441092]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 04:56:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In another first, a woman will be the public face of the new Iranian government with Fatemeh Mohajerani being appointed the government spokesperson of Masoud Pezeshkian regime.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In another first, a woman will be the public face of the new Iranian government with Fatemeh Mohajerani being appointed the government spokesperson of Masoud Pezeshkian regime.</p>

<p>The appointment was made by President Pezeshkian in a cabinet meeting on Wednesday, Iranian media reported.</p>

<p>Mohajerani, 54, is a Doctor of Business Administration from Edinburgh and has earlier served as the head of the Technical and Vocational Training University of Shariati (for women) in the 11th government.</p>

<p>Mohajerani was named the head of the Center for Brilliant Talents by then-Education Minister Seyyed Mohammad Bat'hai in 2017 and has held other positions in the Education Ministry too.</p>

<p>This is the latest appointment of a woman to a senior position. President Pezeshkian had, last week, appointed Shina Ansari as Iran's Deputy President and Head of the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>Ansari, whose LinkedIn profile describes her as an experienced environmental specialist with a demonstrated history of working in environmental services and skilled in waste, RCRA, sustainable development, and environmental compliance, replaces Ali Salajegheh as head of the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>A PhD in Environmental Management from the Science &amp; Research University, she was presently the Advisor at the Air Quality Control Centre at Tehran Municipality and previously had been Head of Environment and Sustainable Development at the Municipality and General Director of the Bureau of Comprehensive Environmental Pollution Monitoring in the Department of Environment.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian's cabinet also has (post-1979 Islamic Revolution) Iran's second woman minister with Farzaneh Sadeq Malvajard being approved as the Roads and Urban Development Minister. The Deputy Minister of Urban Planning and Architecture from January 2019 to July 2023, she got 230 out of 285-odd lawmakers present and voting despite some opposition when her name was read out in Parliament when the ministerial choices were submitted earlier this month.</p>

<p>Sadeq, 48, follows Marzieh Vahid Dastjerdi who was Health and Medical Education Minister in populist President Mahmoud Ahmadinejad's second government (2009-13).</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mdc6hr5o_fatemeh-mohajerani_625x300_29_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fatemeh Mohajerani, 54, is a Doctor of Business Administration from Edinburgh.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-nations-vehicle-in-gaza-hit-by-israeli-gunfire-6440981]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[United Nations Vehicle In Gaza Hit By Israeli Gunfire]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-nations-vehicle-in-gaza-hit-by-israeli-gunfire-6440981]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 04:13:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Nations has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza, marked with the organisation's insignia, was fired upon 10 times by Israeli forces, including shots targeting its front windows.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;The United Nations has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza, marked with the organisation's insignia, was fired upon 10 times by Israeli forces, including shots targeting its front windows, while it was part of a convoy fully coordinated with the Israeli army.</p>

<p>UN spokesperson Stephane Dujarric stated on Wednesday that the two staff members in the vehicle were unharmed. He referred to comments made by a senior UN official, who requested anonymity, two days ago to journalists about the need for armoured vehicles in Gaza.</p>

<p>The incident underscored the importance of this, as the armoured vehicle saved the lives of the staff members and revealed that current coordination mechanisms are ineffective.</p>

<p>Dujarric assured that the UN would continue to work with the Israeli army to ensure that such incidents do not recur.</p>

<p>The international spokesperson stressed the necessity for all parties to respect international humanitarian law at all times, which includes the protection of civilians and the provision of their basic needs, such as food, water, shelter, and health care, wherever they are in Gaza.</p>

<p>He clarified that this applies to those under evacuation orders, whether they have moved or not, indicating that those who leave must be given sufficient time to depart, safe routes, and safe areas to which they can go.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/iq5k0vlg_-gaza-strip_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN has reported that one of its humanitarian vehicles in Gaza hit by Israeli gunfire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-charges-telegram-chief-pavel-durov-prosecutor-6440551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Telegram Chief Pavel Durov Charged, Banned From Leaving France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-charges-telegram-chief-pavel-durov-prosecutor-6440551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 01:59:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The chief of Telegram Pavel Durov on Wednesday was charged by the French judiciary with a litany of violations related to the messaging app but allowed to go free while being banned from leaving the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France on Wednesday charged Pavel Durov, the founder and chief of Telegram, with a litany of violations related to the messaging app and banned him from leaving the country while allowing the billionaire to walk free after four days under arrest.</p>

<p>Durov, 39, was charged on several counts of failing to curb extremist and illegal content on the popular messaging app following a hearing with investigating magistrates in Paris.</p>

<p>Russian-born Durov was arrested at Le Bourget airport outside Paris late Saturday and questioned in subsequent days under arrest by investigators.</p>

<p>He was granted conditional release against a bail of five million euros and on the condition he must report to a police station twice a week as well as remaining in France, Paris prosecutor Laure Beccuau said in a statement.</p>

<p>The charges concern alleged crimes involving an organised group including "complicity in the administration of an online platform to enable an illicit transaction".</p>

<p>Durov has also been charged with refusing to share documents demanded by authorities as well as "dissemination in an organised group of images of minors in child pornography" as well as drug trafficking, fraud and money laundering.</p>

<p>His lawyer David-Olivier Kaminski said it was "absurd" to suggest Durov could be implicated in any crime committed on the app, adding: "Telegram complies in all respects with European rules concerning digital technology."</p>

<p>Separately, Durov is also being investigated on suspicion of "serious acts of violence" towards one of his children while he and an ex-partner, the boy's mother, were in Paris, a source said. She also filed another complaint against Durov in Switzerland last year.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Not political' -</strong></p>

<p>The tech mogul founded Telegram as he was in the process of quitting his native Russia a decade ago. Its growth has been exponential, with the app now reporting more than 900 million users.</p>

<p>An enigmatic figure who rarely speaks in public, Durov is a citizen of Russia, France and the United Arab Emirates, where Telegram is based.</p>

<p>Forbes magazine estimates his current fortune at $15.5 billion, though he proudly promotes the virtues of an ascetic life that includes ice baths and not drinking alcohol or coffee.</p>

<p>Numerous questions have been raised about the timing and circumstances of Durov's detention, with supporters seeing him as a freedom of speech champion and detractors as a menace who wilfully allowed Telegram to get out of control.</p>

<p>Le Monde newspaper reported Wednesday that Durov had met President Emmanuel Macron on several occasions prior to receiving French nationality in 2021, via a special procedure reserved for those deemed to have made a special contribution to France.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal added that at one lunch in 2018, Macron -- who along with his team was in the past an avid user of Telegram -- had suggested it should be headquartered in Paris, but Durov refused.</p>

<p>According to a source close to the case, confirming a story first published on the Politico news site, both Pavel Durov and his elder brother Nikolai, a lower-profile figure seen as the mathematical brain behind Telegram, have been wanted by France since March this year.</p>

<p>In a post on X to address what he called "false information" concerning the case, Macron said Durov's arrest was "in no way a political decision" and it was "up to the judges to rule".</p>

<p>In Moscow, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the charges were very serious and thus needed "no less serious evidence".</p>

<p>Among those voicing support for Durov is fellow tech tycoon and chief executive of X, Elon Musk, who has posted comments under the hashtag #FreePavel.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Near total absence' -</strong></p>

<p>Durov left Russia a decade ago as he was setting up Telegram amid an ownership squabble concerning his first project, the Russian social network VKontakte.</p>

<p>But his departure from Russia was reportedly not an abrupt exile: according to the Vazhnye Istorii news site, citing leaked border data, he visited the country more than 50 times between 2015 and 2021.</p>

<p>Telegram has positioned itself as a "neutral" alternative to US-owned platforms, which have been criticised for their commercial exploitation of users' personal data.</p>

<p>It has also played a key role since Russia's invasion of Ukraine, used actively by politicians and commentators on both sides of the war.</p>

<p>The Paris prosecutor said the French judicial authorities had been made aware of the "near total absence of a response" from Telegram to requests from the authorities and had first opened an investigation in February 2024.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/5b78286g_pavel-durov_625x300_26_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The chief of Telegram Pavel Durov on Wednesday was charged by the French judiciary.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-spent-months-seeking-a-target-then-settled-on-donald-trump-fbi-6440260]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gunman Spent Months Seeking A Target, Then Settled On Donald Trump: FBI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunman-spent-months-seeking-a-target-then-settled-on-donald-trump-fbi-6440260]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:26:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The gunman who tried to kill Donald Trump mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July, FBI officials said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The gunman who tried to kill Donald Trump mounted a "sustained, detailed effort" to attack a major gathering of some sort before deciding to target the Republican presidential candidate at a Pennsylvania rally in July, FBI officials said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>FBI officials said Thomas Crooks, 20, searched more than 60 times for information about the Republican presidential candidate and his then-rival, Democratic President Joe Biden, before registering for the Trump rally in early July.</p>

<p>"We saw ... a sustained, detailed effort to plan an attack on some events, meaning he looked at any number of events or targets," Kevin Rojek, the FBI's top official in western Pennsylvania, said in a telephone briefing to reporters.</p>

<p>Rojek said Crooks became "hyper focused" on the Trump rally when it was announced in early July "and looked at it as a target of opportunity."</p>

<p>Rojek said the FBI has not yet been able to determine what motivated Crooks to try to assassinate Trump at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, on July 13.</p>

<p>Crooks' computer activity showed he was interested in a mix of ideologies, but did not show definitively that he was motivated by a particular left-leaning or right-leaning point of view, Rojek said.</p>

<p>FBI officials said they had not found any evidence indicated that Crooks had worked with other people, or had been directed by a foreign power.</p>

<p>There were no traces of illicit drugs or alcohol in his system.</p>

<p>The assassination attempt prompted questions about how Crooks was able to climb a nearby building and fire eight shots at the former president before being killed by a Secret Service sharpshooter. Several congressional and government probes are examining the event's security measures.</p>

<p>The FBI, meanwhile, is investigating Crooks himself. Officials said they had gained some understanding of his mindset, even if they still did not know what motivated him.</p>

<p>Crooks searched for Trump's campaign events as early as September 2023, FBI officials said, and began searching in April for campaign events for both candidates near where he lived in western Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>He also searched for the dates of both the Republican and Democratic presidential conventions, they said.</p>

<p>In the days leading up to the July 13 rally, he searched for information about the site, including where Trump would speak and details of the company that owned a nearby building where he would later fire the eight shots, one of which grazed Trump's ear. Video evidence shows Crooks was only on the building's roof for about six minutes.</p>

<p>Crooks, who left several explosive devices in his car, had searched for information about bomb components as early as 2019.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9ckehas_thomas-matthew-crooks-thomas-crooks_625x300_15_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[There were no traces of illicit drugs or alcohol in the gunman's system. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>