<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 15:00:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-admits-doctoring-cabinet-photo-to-make-ministers-look-less-unkempt-6734799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan Admits Doctoring Cabinet Photo To Make Ministers Look Less Unkempt]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-admits-doctoring-cabinet-photo-to-make-ministers-look-less-unkempt-6734799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 14:14:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's government admitted Monday manipulating an official photo of the new cabinet to make its members look less unkempt, after online mockery of their sagging trousers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's government admitted Monday manipulating an official photo of the new cabinet to make its members look less unkempt, after online mockery of their sagging trousers.</p>

<p>Images taken by local media showed what appeared to be an untidy patch of white shirt under the morning suits of Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba and Defence Minister Gen Nakatani.</p>

<p>In the official photo issued by Ishiba's office, these blemishes had mysteriously disappeared, but not quickly enough to stop a barrage of mockery of the "untidy cabinet" on social media.</p>

<p>"This is more hideous than a group picture of some kind of a seniors' club during a trip to a hot spring. It's utterly embarrassing", one user wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Minor editing was made," top government spokesman Yoshimasa Hayashi told reporters on Monday, while seeking to deflect criticism of the manipulation.</p>

<p>"Group photos during official events of the prime minister's office, such as the cabinet reshuffle, will be preserved forever as memorabilia, so minor editing is customarily performed on these photos," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In March, Catherine, Britain's Princess of Wales, apologised and said she had edited a photo with her children released by the palace.</p>

<p>The Mother's Day portrait of a smiling Kate included several inconsistencies and sparked a storm after major news agencies including AFP withdrew the photo saying it had been manipulated.</p>

<p>"Like many amateur photographers, I do occasionally experiment with editing," Kate said in a statement.</p>

<p>&nbsp;"I wanted to express my apologies for any confusion the family photograph we shared yesterday caused."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/37416dvg_japan-cabinet-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Minor editing was made," top government spokesman Yoshimasa Hayashi told reporters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-has-always-been-first-responder-pm-modi-meets-maldives-president-muizzu-6734473]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Has Always Been First Responder": PM Modi Meets Maldives President Muizzu]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-has-always-been-first-responder-pm-modi-meets-maldives-president-muizzu-6734473]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:30:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday underlined New Delhi's position as a "close friend" of the Maldives and emphasised his government's readiness to respond to medical and economic emergencies as part of its 'neighbourhood first' foreign policy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> on Monday met Maldives President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/mohamed-muizzu" target="_blank">Mohamed Muizzu</a> and underlined New Delhi's position as a "close friend" of the island nation, emphasising his 'neighbourhood first' foreign policy that has seen India act as a 'first responder' to financial and medical emergencies affecting Male, including supplying its nearly six lakh people with Covid vaccines during the pandemic.</p>

<p>The Maldives, the Prime Minister also said, has an important role in ensuring the security of the Indian Ocean Region - an issue red-flagged by many within the Indian government after President Muizzu - seen as a 'pro-China' leader - won last year's election on what was called an 'India out' platform.</p>

<p>"Be it essential commodities, vaccines during Covid, or drinking water... we have played a good neighbour," he said, adding that India had also inaugurated an airport and handed over 700 social housing units, and plans to support construction of a new port. Referring to the drinking water project now operational on 28 Maldivian islands, he said over 30,000 people would now get clean water.</p>

<p>India and Maldives also discussed the opening of consulates in Addu and Bengaluru, the PM said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Modi's comments came after he hosted President Muizzu to a bilateral meet in Delhi this afternoon; visuals of the two leaders clasping hands and smiling broadly - after a ceremonial welcome by President Droupadi Murmu at Raj Bhavan - were posted by news agency ANI and widely shared.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi receives Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu at Hyderabad House. The two leaders are holding a meeting here.<br />
<br />
(Video: DD News) <a href="https://t.co/P3oE9MVRay">pic.twitter.com/P3oE9MVRay</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1843168122641256932?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>For his part Mr Muizzu once again pitched for the large-scale return of Indian tourists to the Maldives; tourism is the island nation's biggest source of revenue and this took a hit last year after Indian tourists cancelled reservations to protest three Maldivian minister's comment about the Prime Minister.</p>

<p>The Maldives Foreign Ministry had distanced itself from the remarks.</p>

<p>The Maldivian leader said he also hopes to conclude a free trade agreement with India, with the aim of increasing investment in his country. The Indian government has already helped set up a substantial drinking water and sewerage facility in the Maldives and is also helping build road infrastructure.</p>

<p>"India is a key partner in the socio-economic and infrastructure development of Maldives and stood by Maldives during times of need. I would like to thank PM Modi, and the government and people of India for generous assistance and cooperation over the years..." he said.</p>

<p>"I am also thankful for the Indian government's decision to provide support - in the form of Rs 30 billion, in addition to a US$ 400 million bilateral currency swap agreement - which will be instrumental in addressing the foreign exchange issues we are facing right now," Mr Muizzu said.</p>

<h3><strong>India Is "Valued Partner, Friend"</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier today Mr Muizzu stressed his country would not act to undermine India's security, and that it views New Delhi as a "valued partner and friend". Cross-country cooperation in several fields - including defence - will "always be a priority", he told a leading English daily.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/maldives-president-mohamed-muizzi-india-visit-wont-do-anything-to-undermine-security-of-india-maldives-president-6732730#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Maldives President's Diplomatic U-turn, Appeal To Indian Tourists</a></p>

<p>"Maldives would never do anything to undermine security of India. While we enhance cooperation with other countries in various sectors, we remain committed to ensuring our actions do not compromise the security and stability of our region..." he told The Times of India in an extensive interview yesterday.</p>

<h3><strong>1st Bilateral Visit Amid Diplomatic Rows</strong></h3>

<p>This is Mr Muizzu's first bilateral visit and the comments reflect growing bonhomie after a months-long diplomatic stand-off last year, over three Maldivian ministers' comments about Prime Minister Modi after a social media post about Lakshadweep as an alternate tourist destination to the Maldives.</p>

<p>And then the request in May - weeks before attending Mr Modi's swearing-in ceremony - to remove 90 military personnel deployed to three aviation platforms gifted by India - also raised eyebrows.</p>

<p>Delhi accepted the request and replaced military personnel with "competent technical" staff.</p>

<p>The ejection of Indian military personnel and an 'India Out' agenda was seen as one of Mr Muizzu's key poll promises. Pressed on these topics, the Maldives President said he "did what the people of Maldives asked of me", but stressed India remains a key partner in efforts to secure regional stability.</p>

<p>He denied that his government has an 'India out' agenda and said it was simply the case that "the people of Maldives do not want a foreign soldier in their country".</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/nmojh3so_maldives-mohamed-muizzu-pm-modi-joint-statement_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Maldives President Muizzu met Prime Minister Modi in Delhi (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-last-minute-surprises-derail-kamala-harriss-chances-us-poll-nostradamus-explains-6734388]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Is Unfazed By Any Surprises, Predicts US Poll "Nostradamus"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/can-last-minute-surprises-derail-kamala-harriss-chances-us-poll-nostradamus-explains-6734388]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 13:16:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Despite his unwavering forecast for Kamala Harris, Dr Allan Lichtman emphasised the importance of voter participation. "The outcome is up to you, so get out and vote," he urged.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A prominent presidential historian, Dr Allan Lichtman, has reiterated his prediction that Vice President Kamala Harris will win the 2024 presidential election against former President Donald Trump, dismissing concerns about an "October surprise" affecting the outcome.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dr Lichtman, a professor at American University and renowned for accurately forecasting nine of the last ten US elections, made his prediction early in September.</p>

<p>In an interview with<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/05/politics/video/smerconish-commentary-october-surprise-digvid"> CNN's Michael Smerconish</a>, Dr Lichtman stated, "One of the greatest myths of American politics is the October surprise. I have never changed my prediction in response to an October surprise because the keys gauge the big picture of incumbent governance in strength and don't sway by the events of the campaign."</p>

<p>Dr Lichtman's "keys" refer to a system of 13 categories he uses to assess each candidate's viability for the presidency. In September, he said Mrs Harris holds an advantage in eight of the 13 keys, while Trump secured three.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Historically, Dr Lichtman's assertion about the insignificance of "October surprises" is supported by precedent. In the lead-up to the 2016 election, a leaked "Access Hollywood" tape revealed Trump making controversial remarks about women. Despite the fallout, Trump ultimately won the election, a prediction Lichtman had made based on his key system.</p>

<p>"I've never changed a prediction in 40 years, and I'm not doing it now," Lichtman affirmed. The scholar, who identifies as a registered Democrat, claims to have accurately predicted the outcome of every presidential race since 1984. However, some critics highlight inconsistencies in his rationale over the years, particularly regarding the 2000 and 2016 elections.</p>

<p>Despite his unwavering forecast for Harris, Dr Lichtman emphasised the importance of voter participation. "The outcome is up to you, so get out and vote," he urged.</p>

<p>Recent polling data shows Mrs Harris with a narrow lead over Donald Trump, holding a two-percentage point advantage in multi-candidate polls, according to the latest RealClearPolitics aggregate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As the election approaches, all eyes will be on whether Dr Lichtman's predictions hold true.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vsu6q5ig_trump-harris_625x300_11_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Kamala Harris during the US Presidential debate.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-october-7-the-day-we-failed-israels-army-chief-on-gaza-war-anniversary-6733766]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["October 7 - The Day We Failed": Israel's Army Chief On War Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-october-7-the-day-we-failed-israels-army-chief-on-gaza-war-anniversary-6733766]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 11:40:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel is fighting a "long war", the country's military chief told its soldiers and commanders a day ahead of the first anniversary of the 2023 Hamas attack, vowing to wipe out its "enemies" who seek to destroy Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel is fighting a "long war", the country's military chief told its soldiers and commanders a day ahead of the first anniversary of the 2023 Hamas attack, vowing to wipe out its "enemies" who seek to destroy Israel. Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi, Chief of the General Staff of Israel, praised their commitment and courage as the Middle East stared at uncertainty, plunging into more violence by the day. He asserted every day was becoming worse for their "enemies".</p>

<p>"This is a long war, measured not only by capabilities but also by willpower and perseverance over time. For our enemies - every month, every week, and every day is worse than the one before," the army chief said in his message.</p>

<p>Hamas, a Palestinian group that runs Gaza, launched an unprecedented attack on Israeli border towns on October 7, 2023, massacring over a thousand civilians. They called their attack the 'Al-Aqsa Flood', named after a holy site in Jerusalem that remains a bone of contention for Israel and Palestine and is believed to be sacred by both Jews and Muslims. The attack sparked the ongoing West Asia conflict.</p>

<p>Israel marked the war anniversary with vigils at massacre sites while Hamas said the attack shattered the "illusion" of superiority that Israel had.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-gaza-is-reduced-to-rubble-in-a-year-analysis-using-satellite-images-6731563">Satellite Images Show How Gaza Was Reduced To Rubble In A Year</a></p>

<p>"A year has passed since October 7th, the day we failed in our mission to protect the citizens of the State of Israel," said the Lieutenant General on Sunday. After the war ends, Halevi said, the enemies of Israel will know there will be no revival for those who seek to destroy the country.</p>

<p>The army chief further said a generation of warriors and commanders with unparalleled experience have emerged from this war. In his message, Halevi claimed Israel has defeated the military wing of Hamas, but continues to fight its "terrorist capabilities". "We have dealt a severe blow to Hezbollah, which has lost all of its senior leadership," he added.</p>

<p>Israel is fighting a multi-front war against the Hamas in Gaza and Lebanon on its northern border. It is also fighting Iran, which last week launched a barrage of missiles after the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, besides conducting airstrikes in Yemen.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-hamas-caught-between-airstrikes-gaza-journalist-risks-it-all-to-document-war-6731274">Caught Between Airstrikes, Gaza Journalist Risks It All To Document War</a></p>

<p>"We are not stopping - we fight, debrief, learn, and improve...We are destroying our enemies' capabilities, and we will ensure that these capabilities are not rebuilt, so that October 7th is never repeated," said the army chief.</p>

<p>The message from the commander-in-chief seeks to boost the morale of the troops with the focus of the war shifting from Gaza to Lebanon and its ally Iran.</p>

<p>With Iran entering the war, Israel now faces an even tougher challenge, especially after a warning from its supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei that Israel will "not last long".</p>

<p>The Middle East crisis has sparked a rise in oil price across the world. The US and other countries have urged Israel and Iran to avoid an all-out war amid fears of a retaliation to the missile attacks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5kd7dj_israeli-army-in-gaza_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-sets-his-arm-on-fire-in-us-to-protest-against-israel-hamas-war-6733584]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Sets His Arm On Fire In US To Protest Against Israel-Hamas War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-sets-his-arm-on-fire-in-us-to-protest-against-israel-hamas-war-6733584]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 11:04:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands marched in US cities from Washington to Los Angeles on Saturday, demanding an immediate ceasefire as the war in Gaza nears the one-year mark, with a man attempting to self-immolate in protest.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands marched in US cities from Washington to Los Angeles on Saturday, demanding an immediate ceasefire as the war in Gaza nears the one-year mark, with a man attempting to self-immolate in protest.</p>

<p>The marches were part of a worldwide day of action against the devastating war, which has recently seen Israel intensify its military operations in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The war was sparked on October 7 when the Palestinian armed group Hamas attacked Israel, resulting in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>More than 41,825 Palestinians, a majority of them civilians, have been killed in Israel's military campaign in the Gaza Strip since the war began, according to data provided by the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza. The UN has acknowledged the figures as reliable.</p>

<p>In Washington, more than a thousand angry protesters demonstrated outside the White House, with many demanding an end to the US military and other aid to its strategic ally, Israel.</p>

<p>"The US government has really shown what side of history it is on," Zaid Khatib, an organizer with the Palestinian Youth Movement, told AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The US government has performed and co-signed the most evil atrocities that we've seen of this century."</p>

<p>Protesters waved Palestinian and Lebanese flags, among others, with many holding up signs and chanting in unison to demonstrate solidarity with the Palestinian cause.</p>

<p>Almost two hours into the protest, a man approached the demonstration site and attempted to set himself on fire, AFP journalists saw.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">??????? A JOURNALIST set HIMSELF on FIRE outside the White House to protest the media's LIES about the Gaza GEN0C!DE. <a href="https://t.co/duotbSdjOj">pic.twitter.com/duotbSdjOj</a></p>
— Halima Khan (@khanhalima18) <a href="https://twitter.com/khanhalima18/status/1842870142612484576?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He succeeded in lighting his left arm ablaze before bystanders and police rushed to his aid, dousing him with water and extinguishing the flames using their keffiyehs, traditional Palestinian scarves.</p>

<p>"I'm a journalist and we neglect it, we spread the misinformation," he shouted, in between screams of pain as the fire on his arm was put out.</p>

<p>Police said the man was being treated for "non-life threatening injuries."</p>

<h3><strong>'Ethnic cleansing'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In New York, thousands marched in the city's famed Times Square neighbourhood, some carrying pictures of people killed by Israel's military offensive in Gaza, which has left much of the territory in rubble.</p>

<p>Among those marching was Cornel West, a prominent rights activist and an independent candidate running in the US presidential election.</p>

<p>"I'm here to forever be in solidarity with people undergoing a vicious genocide," he told AFP. "Dealing with ethnic cleansing it's getting worse, it's been a whole year now. You know, we got to keep fighting."</p>

<p>The United States is one of Israel's closest allies, providing billions in military assistance -- a subject that protesters in both cities focused on.</p>

<p>"As an American, we're tired of our tax money going to Israel to bomb kids in Palestine and then Lebanon," said Daniel Perez, a New York resident.</p>

<p>Protesters also took to the streets in Los Angeles, many holding signs calling for an end to "genocide" in Gaza.</p>

<p>In Washington, protesters' cries for "justice" and "peace" reverberated off office buildings downtown, with the crowd animated by a mix of righteous anger and raucous solidarity.</p>

<p>Laila, an American of Palestinian and Lebanese descent, told AFP the past year had left her disillusioned with her country's leaders -- so much so that she was unlikely to vote in November.</p>

<p>"It all disgusts me now," she said. "It's all a lie."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bjcjpki_man-sets-himself-on-fire-afp-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The man succeeded in lighting his left arm ablaze before bystanders and police rushed to his aid.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-hamas-caught-between-airstrikes-gaza-journalist-risks-it-all-to-document-war-6731274]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["So Much Death": Gaza Journalist Explains Mental Toll Of Covering War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-hamas-caught-between-airstrikes-gaza-journalist-risks-it-all-to-document-war-6731274]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 11:03:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On the morning of October 7, 2023, Ismail Abu Hatab, a photojournalist, woke up to the deafening roar of rockets being fired from Gaza towards Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the morning of October 7, 2023, Ismail Abu Hatab, a photojournalist, woke up to the deafening roar of rockets being fired from Gaza towards Israel. "It felt like the world was ending," he recalled. Ismail instinctively grabbed his phone, seeking clarity in the chaos. The headlines were unthinkable reports of a large-scale attack initiated by the Palestinian group Hamas on Israel. "Has the resistance really pulled this off?" he wondered in shock.</p>

<p>For <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-me-rebuilt-my-life-during-and-after-war-ismail-abu-ha">32-year-old Ismail</a>, the initial hours were a blur of activity. "I immediately started preparing - charging my camera equipment, emptying memory disks on my laptop, and reaching out to my fellow journalists and photographers to verify the situation," Ismail told NDTV. With adrenaline coursing through his veins, he grabbed his camera and ventured out, initially staying close to his neighbourhood in Gaza City, uncertain of what would come next. He joined his colleagues at the Al-Shifa medical complex, Gaza's largest hospital. Together, they climbed to the top of a tall building to capture the unfolding chaos.</p>

<p>After October 7, Gaza descended into mayhem. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ordered an invasion of Gaza. The besieged Palestinian enclave witnessed relentless strikes, with entire neighbourhoods flattened and reduced to rubble.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fs8cik6_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>"The following days were relentless. We lost some of our fellow journalists, and working conditions became incredibly difficult. We were forced to sleep on the streets after threats were made to media<br />
offices, and we began operating out of the Al-Shifa medical complex for a while due to the internet blackout in Gaza. Despite the brutal attacks by the Israeli military, we continued risking our lives to document the invasion," Ismail told NDTV.</p>

<h2><strong>Covering War In Gaza&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>For Ismail, work continued from the Al-Ghafari tower, Gaza's tallest building, where international and local journalists had set up a small office to document the strikes. But conditions were brutal. "There was no electricity, so we relied on electronic SIM cards to access the internet," Ismail recalled. Running up and down the tower's sixteen floors to capture footage had become routine. "If it was too dangerous to go home, we would sleep in our cars or even on the streets." Every day, the toll grew - physically and mentally - but the mission remained the same: to document Gaza's reality under siege.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/decong8g_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>Safety measures for journalists in Gaza are virtually nonexistent, Ismail explained, leaving many local reporters in an extremely precarious position. "While international news agencies provide some journalists with protective gear, vehicles, and offices, the resources available to local journalists are quite limited." For freelancers like Ismail, the challenges are even greater. There is no institutional support, no protective vests, no insurance. "Freelancers are left to fend for themselves," he says. Despite the lack of safety equipment, he continued his work, relying on his colleagues' help for transportation and protection when possible.</p>

<p>"During the conflict, many international agencies asked their journalists to leave Gaza City and move south for their safety. My work was often a collaborative effort with other journalists who had<br />
access to safety equipment and transportation, but this was only temporary. Personally, I found it difficult to secure a press vest and safe transport, relying on help from my colleagues for protection when possible," Ismail told NDTV.</p>

<h2><strong>A Faint Yellow Light</strong></h2>

<p>The risks culminated in tragedy on November 2, 2023, when Ismail was injured during an Israeli airstrike while working at the Al-Ghafari tower. "That night was intense-Israeli airstrikes were relentless, wiping out entire residential blocks," he recalled. The morning after, as he sat down to edit footage from the previous day, disaster struck.</p>

<p>"By morning, after making a cup of coffee, I sat down to review and edit footage from the previous day. As I worked, everything suddenly went dark. I couldn't hear or see anything for a moment. Then I realised I was buried under rubble - an entire wall had collapsed on me," Ismail said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qkbk1qog_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>Ismail's colleagues rushed to pull him out, and the pain hit him like a wave. "I remember seeing a faint yellow light through the dust, but I was completely disoriented. My left leg was severely injured. I could not stand. They carried me down 16 flights of stairs, and every step was agonising." With Israeli missiles exploding indiscriminately around the neighbourhood, the idea of an ambulance coming to rescue Ismail was unthinkable.</p>

<p>With his body covered in blood and his leg badly damaged, he was rushed to Al-Shifa Hospital by his colleagues. By the time they arrived, he had lost consciousness.</p>

<p>He woke to a scene of utter chaos. "The sounds of injured people, death, and cries of farewell surrounded me."</p>

<p>Due to the overwhelming number of casualties, Ismail could not get a bed, let alone the surgery he needed. A colleague took him to a tent for journalists, where he waited for days. Eventually, he was transferred to the Palestine Red Crescent Hospital in Tel Al-Hawa in southern Gaza City, but as fate would have it, the hospital itself came under siege. Ismail and others trapped inside feared for their lives, with Israeli forces advancing outside.</p>

<h2><strong>Road To Recovery</strong></h2>

<p>After days of terror, a breakthrough came - a phone call from the Israeli army, granting them half an hour to evacuate the injured. "We were loaded onto a truck under heavy fire," Ismail recalled. But even the evacuation was fraught with danger. At a checkpoint, Israeli forces forced the injured, including Ismail, to exit the truck, leaving them exposed to sniper fire. Eventually, they were moved to southern Gaza, and Ismail was taken to Al-Amal Hospital in Khan Younis for further medical care. It marked the beginning of a long and painful recovery process that would span months.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/57rfqqno_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>"I was taken to Al-Amal Hospital for further medical evaluation and then moved to stay with my sister in Khan Younis. Unfortunately, during this time, the Israeli army advanced further, and my brother-in-law was killed. We had to flee again, moving from Khan Younis to Rafah, then to Deir Al-Balah," Ismail told NDTV.</p>

<p>The scars of that day, both physical and psychological, are still raw for Ismail. "For ten months, I could not walk," he said. "My recovery has been slow."</p>

<p>Despite undergoing a second surgery, the procedure was botched, and he's still awaiting treatment abroad to correct it. "Despite everything, my recovery has been entirely personal," Ismail lamented, adding that no organisation - whether local or international - has offered financial support for his treatment. "I've had to cover all the expenses myself. Currently, I am unemployed, but I'm trying to rebuild my life."</p>

<h2><strong>'So Much Death'</strong></h2>

<p>The scenes that Ismail witnessed as a photojournalist continue to haunt him. "One of the most disturbing things I have witnessed is the use of fire belts - indiscriminate, sudden, and deadly," he said. "Buildings and entire neighbourhoods collapse. Lives are lost as if they were just numbers." It is the human toll that weighs heaviest on him. "Children, women, the elderly - all innocent lives taken away. When I go into the field to document these events, I often see people trapped under the rubble. It haunts me."</p>

<p>"I ask myself, what was their fault? Why are they dying when they loved life? What were their dreams? What were they doing just before they were killed? How did they live? What about their children and their spouses? I have seen many martyrs, their meals still in front of them, unable to finish eating because they were killed. I think about that moment they must have felt just before death. Why is an innocent person with simple dreams, a beautiful family, and a modest living taken away so cruelly?</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a16288b_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>"I have seen so much death. The mass graves and the final farewells - these things affect me deeply. How can one group of people decide the fate of another and kill them in this way? "</p>

<p>One particularly harrowing experience stands out in his memory. After the bombing of the Al-Ahli Baptist Hospital, Ismail met a mother and her young son. The boy suffered serious injuries to his internal organs due to an airstrike, affecting his mental health severely. "He was such a kind and cheerful boy," Ismail said. Trapped together for days at the Palestine Red Crescent Hospital during the siege, Ismail recalled a particularly poignant moment. "A man ran after our truck, shouting the boy's name. He climbed onto the truck and embraced him, saying, 'Forgive me, I didn't see you because I was busy saving others'. The man was the boy's father."</p>

<p>In this reunion, Ismail found a rare moment of humanity amidst the wanton carnage.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a1io5it_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>Another haunting memory is of a man Ismail helped rescue from beneath the rubble of a collapsed building near his home. "I heard a faint sound coming from beneath the rubble," he recalled. Along with local young men, he pulled the man out alive. By chance, he met the survivor again while recovering at the Red Crescent Hospital. "You are a miracle. How did you survive?" Ismail asked him. The man's calm response: "By the will of God, because I take care of orphans."</p>

<h2><strong>Mental Toll Of Covering War</strong></h2>

<p>Journalists covering war and conflict often suffer post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Being a photojournalist who has witnessed everything from children with their limbs severed to the destruction of infrastructure on an unprecedented scale, Ismail's mental health remains affected.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qgrq9f2o_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Ismail Abu Hatab </span></p>
</div>

<p>"I suffer from significant effects due to the experiences I've been through. I face difficulties with sleep, memory issues, and depression. The sounds of explosions and the cries of the families of martyrs echo in my mind." Despite the emotional and physical pain, Ismail continues to document Gaza's suffering, driven by a sense of duty towards his country. "I believe that I was created for a reason in this life," he said, "and I possess skills in filmmaking and storytelling that empower me to share the truth."</p>

<p>Many journalists in Gaza have paid the ultimate price for telling that truth. "I have lost colleagues and friends in this war," Ismail said. "But I have chosen to remain here, refusing to leave Gaza, because this country needs me. How can I abandon it in its time of need?"</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h79c4i8g_gaza-photojournalist-_625x300_06_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Abu Hateb was injured in an Israeli airstrike in November last year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/use-of-sarco-suicide-pod-suspended-amid-swiss-criminal-investigation-6733403]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Use Of Sarco 'Suicide' Pod Suspended Amid Swiss Criminal Investigation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/use-of-sarco-suicide-pod-suspended-amid-swiss-criminal-investigation-6733403]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:49:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Advocacy groups behind the controversial Sarco' suicide pod have suspended applications for its use, pending a criminal investigation into its first deployment in Switzerland.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Advocacy groups behind the controversial ‘<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swiss-police-make-arrests-after-suicide-capsule-is-used-for-first-time-6651845 ">Sarco</a>' suicide pod have suspended applications for its use, pending a criminal investigation into its first deployment in Switzerland. The decision comes after a 64-year-old American woman died using the device. At least 371 applications submitted till September 23 will remain on hold until the conclusion of the probe.</p>

<p>Florian Willet, president of The Last Resort, a Switzerland-based advocacy group, is currently in pretrial detention, according to the organisation and Exit International, an Australian-founded affiliate. Swiss police arrested Willet and several others following the woman's death on September 23 in a forest in Schaffhausen, near the German border. Authorities have since released the other detainees, though the investigation continues.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sarco-suicide-pod-how-the-controversial-capsule-functions-and-the-chilling-message-it-delivers-6653103"><strong>Read: Sarco Suicide Pod: How The Controversial Capsule Functions</strong></a></p>

<p>The Sarco, developed by Exit International, allows individuals to end their lives through inert gas asphyxiation.&nbsp;Short for “sarcophagus”, the Sarco pod is a 3D-printed, self-operated capsule designed to facilitate assisted suicide through nitrogen-induced hypoxia. The individual sits in the capsule, which fills with nitrogen gas, reducing the oxygen level to fatal amounts, resulting in death by suffocation within minutes.</p>

<p>Advocates, including Exit International's founder Philip Nitschke, argue that the Sarco offers a “peaceful, fast, and dignified” end of life. However, these claims have yet to be independently verified.</p>

<p>On the day of the US woman's death, Swiss Health Minister Elisabeth Baume-Schneider addressed lawmakers, declaring the use of the Sarco “not legal.” The incident sparked debate in Switzerland, where assisted suicide is permissible subject to a set of rules.</p>

<p>The device, which cost over $1 million to develop, was first introduced in Switzerland in 2019. The application process requires individuals to pass a psychiatric assessment and answer a series of questions within the capsule to ensure they are aware of the consequences of their decision.</p>

<p>“Only after the Sarco was used was it learned that Ms Baume-Schneider had addressed the issue,” the groups said in a statement, as per <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/06/europe/suicide-capsule-switzerland-intl-hnk/index.html ">CNN</a>. “The timing was a pure coincidence and not our intention.”</p>

<p>Switzerland's long-standing laws on assisted suicide have positioned the country as a “death tourism” destination, with individuals travelling from around the world seeking control over their end-of-life choices. The Sarco's creator, Philip Nitschke, has been a prominent figure in the euthanasia debate since the 1990s. He maintains that the capsule offers a humane and autonomous way to die, free from medical intervention.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/nfshf7g4_sarco-suicide-pod_625x300_26_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The device, which cost over $1 million to develop, was first introduced in Switzerland in 2019.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-attack-anniversary-overshadowed-by-renewed-israel-iran-conflict-6733399]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Year Later: Hamas Attack Anniversary Overshadowed By Renewed Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-attack-anniversary-overshadowed-by-renewed-israel-iran-conflict-6733399]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:30:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With candles, prayers and music, commemorations for the October 7 attack began in Israel's Tel Aviv on Sunday at a ceremony to mark the first anniversary of the Hamas onslaught at the Nova music festival.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With candles, prayers and music, commemorations for the October 7 attack began in Israel's Tel Aviv on Sunday at a ceremony to mark the first anniversary of the Hamas onslaught at the Nova music festival.</p>

<p>Picture of those killed appeared on a screen at the entrance to the ceremony, as hundreds gathered to light candles at a makeshift shrine, leave handwritten notes or simply embrace each other.</p>

<p>"Coming to this event one year after this terrible massacre that happened on October 7, it's very touching, it's very breathtaking," said one of the event's organisers Solly Laniado.</p>

<p>"Three days ago, we were not even going to hold the event at all," he said, citing the deluge of rocket warnings and last week's missile attack on Tel Aviv that have left many people on edge and large parts of the usually vibrant city empty.</p>

<p>The anniversary comes with Israel engaged in a fresh war in Lebanon against Hezbollah and preparing to retaliate against Tehran, raising fears of an even wider conflict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Anticipation is building over how and when Israel will respond to Iran's missile barrage last week, with the uncertainty casting a shadow over the commemoration.</p>

<p>"It's a difficult day," said Omri Sasi, 35, one of the producers of last year's festival who survived the attack.</p>

<p>By his own estimate, he lost roughly 50 friends that day, including an uncle, a pregnant cousin and her husband.</p>

<h3><strong>Onslaught of violence&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The two-day festival in the fields around Kibbutz Reim was just beyond the Gaza border in southern Israel and attracted over 3,000 attendees from October 6 and 7.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At least 370 people were killed at the Nova rave in the Negev desert, making it the deadliest location during the October 7 attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Footage from the day filmed by Hamas showed the militants gunning down festival-goers en masse as they attempted to flee and taking others hostages, with the heavily armed Hamas fighters moving through the area unopposed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following the attack, the festival location was left largely untouched with dozens of burnt-out vehicles and abandoned tents, sleeping bags and clothes strewn across the field.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The festival attack was part of an onslaught of violence unleashed by Palestinian Hamas militants that resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people on the Israeli side, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on the latest official Israeli figures. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Some 251 people were captured and taken as hostages to the Gaza Strip, of whom 97 are still held captive in the coastal territory, including 37 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>During a one-week truce in late November, 105 hostages were released in exchange for 240 Palestinian prisoners.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hours after the October 7 attack, Israel launched a blistering military offensive on Gaza that has reduced large swaths of the territory to rubble and displaced nearly all of its 2.4 million residents at least once amid an unrelenting humanitarian crisis.</p>

<p>In Gaza, at least 41,870 people have been killed since the start of the Israel offensive, a majority of them civilians, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>The figures have been deemed to be reliable by the United Nations.</p>

<p>But as the anniversary arrives, for many it's just the latest marker in a year tarnished by trauma, loss and ongoing war.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's not easy to think a lot about it," said Sasi.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q54ul7do_october-7-hamas-attack-anniversary-afp-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This comes with Israel engaging in a fresh war in Lebanon against Hezbollah.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-hamas-a-doctor-visited-his-gaza-hometown-a-week-before-october-7-he-never-left-6731177]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Doctor Visited His Gaza Hometown A Week Before October 7. He Never Left]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-gaza-hamas-a-doctor-visited-his-gaza-hometown-a-week-before-october-7-he-never-left-6731177]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 10:01:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It has been a year since the war between Israel and Hamas erupted, a conflict that has brought unspeakable devastation to the Gaza Strip. The days since October 7 have stretched into months of relentless bombings, displacement, and desperation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been a year since the war between Israel and Hamas erupted, a conflict that has brought unspeakable devastation to the Gaza Strip. The days since October 7 have stretched into months of relentless bombings, displacement, and desperation. For the people living in Gaza, the conflict has stripped them of their homes, their loved ones, and their sense of normalcy. It is not just buildings that have crumbled, but entire lives - careers, dreams, families - torn apart by the ravages of war.</p>

<p>The numbers tell only part of the story. Behind each statistic is a personal tragedy. Homes are now rubble, hospitals are overwhelmed, and the world seems to look on helplessly, watching as the conflict deepens. The war has displaced hundreds of thousands, turning vibrant communities into mere shadows of their former selves. For the survivors, daily life is a continuous struggle, and yet within that struggle, there are those who push forward.</p>

<p>One such individual is Dr Khaled Alshawwa, a 31-year-old surgeon from Gaza City. Khaled, like many in his community, never planned to be on the frontlines of a humanitarian crisis. Just a week before the war, he had completed his surgical training at Almakassed Hospital in Jerusalem, a prestigious medical institution. He had returned to Gaza for what was meant to be a brief family visit-just a few days to reconnect with loved ones before continuing his career.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/41i3rc68_gaza-doctor-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>But then the war began, and everything changed. In an instant, Khaled found himself in the midst of one of the most brutal conflicts Gaza has seen, unable to leave, compelled to stay and help.</p>

<p>"The immediate aftermath was chaos," Khaled recalls. "We faced an overwhelming influx of severely injured patients with limited medical supplies and infrastructure. This was much aggregated and intensified after the destruction of many hospitals. As a doctor, I have to prioritise cases, often making difficult decisions with minimal resources."</p>

<p>Khaled, a surgeon trained for the most complex procedures, was forced to make rapid, agonising decisions with almost no support.</p>

<p>"Life has drastically changed. I am constantly navigating between being a surgeon, managing medical points, struggling to provide basic daily needs to me and my family like fresh water, food and a place to stay in amidst severe shortages of resources and ongoing bombings," Khaled said.</p>

<p>The injuries that filled the hospitals were devastating: shrapnel wounds, blast injuries, complex fractures, severe burns, and traumatic amputations. "Many of the injuries involve multiple body parts," he explains, requiring teams of surgeons working in tandem. But with a healthcare system on the brink of collapse, they don't have the luxury of specialisation. "We are stretched beyond belief. A surgeon might have to handle trauma, pediatric surgery, even urology, and vascular procedures, all at once. It is exhausting, physically and mentally."</p>

<p>The situation was made worse by the fact that medical supplies are running low. Basic necessities - anaesthetics, sutures, bandages, antibiotics - are in short supply. "We have to improvise," he says. "In some cases, we had no choice but to turn to telemedicine, relying on colleagues abroad for guidance."</p>

<p>The chaos of the war meant that Khaled's life is in constant motion. "I have moved seven times since the war began," he says, each relocation a desperate attempt to keep his family safe. His base of operations has also shifted as the conflict ebbs and flows. "I have volunteered at almost every hospital in Gaza City," he explains, as the nature of the war has required him to be flexible. "Wherever I go, I try to offer what little help I can."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5kkd5dto_gaza-doctor-_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>For Khaled, each new base brings with it a fresh set of challenges. He describes the scenes with stark clarity - overcrowded refugee camps, where families huddle together in makeshift shelters, trying to stay alive amidst airstrikes from Israel. "Infection control is nearly impossible in these conditions," he says, pointing to the lack of sanitation and clean water. Overcrowding in the camps has led to the rapid spread of disease. "We are seeing infections in open wounds, as well as dermatological diseases in previously healthy people."</p>

<p>These camps, Khaled notes, are where the most vulnerable-women and children-are suffering the most. "Maternity and pediatric care are severely impacted," he says. "Many women are giving birth in unsafe environments, and children are missing out on basic healthcare." Immunisation programs, vital to protecting children from preventable diseases, have also been disrupted. Khaled himself was involved in a recent polio vaccination campaign organised by the Palestine Red Crescent Society. Despite the overwhelming challenges, including maintaining cold chains for vaccines in areas with no electricity, the team managed to vaccinate over 120,000 children under the age of ten in North Gaza.</p>

<p>But it is not enough.</p>

<p>The strain on Gaza's healthcare system is unprecedented, and the long-term impact of the war on public health is staggering. "The magnitude of disability we are witnessing is terrifying," Khaled says. The rise in amputations, spinal injuries, and traumatic brain damage will have consequences that last for decades. "These are injuries that will require years, if not a lifetime, of care," he warns. "The healthcare system simply isn't equipped to deal with this."</p>

<p>Like many in Gaza, Khaled's personal losses are intertwined with the collective grief of his people. "I lost my mother in a bombing," he revealed. In addition to his mother, he has lost his home and many close friends. But despite this immense personal loss, Khaled has remained resolute. "It's tough," he admits. "Psychologically, it's very hard. The constant pressure, the loss, the fear for your family - it takes a toll."</p>

<p>And yet, like so many others in Gaza, Khaled continues to move forward. "Staying focused on helping others is what keeps me going," he says, though there are moments when the weight of it all feels unbearable. "Every day is a struggle," he admits. "But I can't give up, not when there are so many people depending on us."</p>

<p>The war in Gaza is not happening in isolation. The Israeli-Hamas conflict has drawn in international players, with each new development bringing the risk of a broader regional conflict. In Lebanon, Israeli airstrikes have intensified, killing hundreds. Hezbollah, a militant group backed by Iran, has escalated its exchanges with Israel, meaning that the war has extended far beyond Gaza's borders.</p>

<p>In Europe, the conflict has sparked a political backlash. Countries like Spain and Ireland have recognised the State of Palestine in defiance of Israeli opposition. The United States on the other hand continues to provide Israel with military and financial support, most recently approving an $8.7 billion aid package. For Palestinians like Khaled, international aid is critical to the survival of Gaza's healthcare system, yet the future of that support remains uncertain.</p>

<p>The United Nations estimates that nearly 80,000 homes have been destroyed, and it could take decades to rebuild the city. Khaled agrees. "It will take years, maybe even decades, to get Gaza's health infrastructure back on track," Khaled says. "Without substantial international aid, the recovery will be slow, and people will continue to suffer."</p>

<p>But the road to recovery is long, and the scars of this war will linger for generations.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rn0eqo1g_gaza-doctor-_625x300_06_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strain on Gaza's healthcare system is unprecedented.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-bound-flight-played-r-rated-movie-for-all-passengers-with-no-option-to-switch-6733043]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Japan-Bound Flight Played R-Rated Movie For All With No Option To Switch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/japan-bound-flight-played-r-rated-movie-for-all-passengers-with-no-option-to-switch-6733043]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:27:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred on flight QF59, causing discomfort among travellers, particularly families with children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Passengers on a Qantas flight from Sydney, Australia, to Haneda, Japan, were shocked when an explicit movie was accidentally played on all in-flight screens due to a technical glitch, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/passenger-claims-qantas-played-an-xrated-film-to-entire-flight/news-story/21a8c95380e77adf90b5ab7fcea6776f" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>news.com.au </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incident occurred on flight QF59, causing discomfort among travellers, particularly families with children, as the film "Daddio" (2023) was shown without an option to turn it off.</p>

<p>The R-rated movie, starring Dakota Johnson and Sean Penn, includes explicit sexual content and scenes of graphic nudity.</p>

<p>"It was impossible to pause, dim, or turn it off. The worst part was that the movie was extremely inappropriate," one passenger wrote on Reddit, noting that it took nearly an hour to replace the film with a more family-friendly option.</p>

<p>"It was super uncomfortable for everyone, especially with families and kids on board"</p>

<p>Qantas acknowledged the incident, stating that a technical malfunction in the in-flight entertainment system prevented passengers from selecting individual films.</p>

<p>According to the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/06/world-news/qantas-flight-from-australia-to-japan-airs-r-rated-movie-daddio-to-entire-flight/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em> New York Post</em></a>, the airline explained that crew members attempted to resolve the issue by asking passengers for their movie preferences, which led to the entire cabin being shown "Daddio."</p>

<p>When it became apparent that the film was not appropriate for all viewers, crew members tried to help passengers avoid the movie by fixing their screens. However, when this proved impossible, they switched the film to a more family-friendly option, as reported by the *New York Post*.</p>

<p>In a statement to news.com.au, a Qantas spokesperson apologized for the incident, noting that the standard procedure is to play family-friendly films when individual selection is unavailable.</p>

<p>"The movie was clearly not suitable to play for the whole flight, and we sincerely apologize to customers for this experience," the spokesperson said, adding that they are investigating how the film was chosen.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sggmgs1g_qantas_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Qantas acknowledged the incident and said it was a technical glitch]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/esmail-qaani-the-iran-quds-chief-missing-since-israeli-strike-on-beirut-6733030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Esmail Qaani: The Iran Quds Chief, Missing Since Israeli Strike On Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/esmail-qaani-the-iran-quds-chief-missing-since-israeli-strike-on-beirut-6733030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 09:21:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Quds Force commander Esmail Qaani has not been heard from since Israeli strikes on Beirut late last week, two senior Iranian security officials told Reuters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Quds Force commander Esmail Qaani has not been heard from since Israeli strikes on Beirut late last week, two senior Iranian security officials told Reuters.</p>

<p>Qaani travelled to Lebanon after the killing last month of Hezbollah leader Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah in an Israeli airstrike.</p>

<h3><strong>Here are some facts about Qaani:</strong></h3>

<p>-Tehran named Qaani the head of the Revolutionary Guards Corps' overseas military intelligence service after the United States assassinated his predecessor Qassem Soleimani in a drone strike in Baghdad in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Part of Qaani's task in that post has been to manage Tehran's paramilitary allies across the Middle East, as well as in other regions around the world.</p>

<p>- According to people familiar with both Qaani and Soleimani, as well as Western military and political analysts, Qaani has never commanded the same respect as his predecessor Soleimani or maintained the same close relationships among Iran's allies in the Arab world.</p>

<p>- While Soleimani held the reins of the Quds Force during a time when Iran's proxies - from Lebanese Hezbollah to Iraqi Shi'ite Muslim militias to the Houthis of Yemen - grew their power in the Middle East, Qaani has presided over their battering at the hands of Israeli spies and warplanes.</p>

<p>- Qaani became deputy commander of the Quds Force, the overseas arm of Iran's Revolutionary Guards, in 1997 when Soleimani became the Force's chief commander.</p>

<p>- When Qaani took over he vowed to boot US forces out of the Middle East in revenge for Soleimani's killing. "We promise to continue martyr Soleimani's path with the same force ... and the only compensation for us would be to remove America from the region," state radio quoted Qaani as saying ahead of Soleimani's funeral in Tehran.</p>

<p>- Qaani, 67, was born in Mashhad, a conservative Shi'ite Muslim religious city in northeastern Iran. He fought for the Revolutionary Guards during the Iran-Iraq war in the 1980s.</p>

<p>- Qaani has also had experience of overseas operations beyond Iran's eastern borders, including Afghanistan and Pakistan. He does not speak Arabic, unlike Soleimani who spoke fluently with Iraqi militias and Hezbollah commanders.</p>

<p>- He has adopted less of a public persona than Soleimani and little information is available on him online or in leaked diplomatic cables.&nbsp;</p>

<p>- Unlike Soleimani, who over the years was widely photographed on battlefields in Iraq and Syria alongside the militias Tehran has armed and trained, Qaani has preferred to keep a lower profile and conduct most of his meetings and visits to neighbouring countries in private.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i3dt5df_esmail-qaani-reuters-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[When Esmail Qaani took over, he vowed to boot US forces out of the Middle East.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-chinese-nationals-killed-in-a-blast-in-pakistans-karachi-6732881]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Chinese Nationals Killed In A Blast In Pakistan's Karachi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-chinese-nationals-killed-in-a-blast-in-pakistans-karachi-6732881]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 08:47:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A massive blast on a road near the airport of Pakistan's largest city killed two Chinese nationals, Beijing's embassy said Monday, after a separatist militant group claimed an attack in the area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive blast on a road near the airport of Pakistan's largest city killed two Chinese nationals, Beijing's embassy said Monday, after a separatist militant group claimed an attack in the area.</p>

<p>An AFP journalist heard the explosion in Pakistan's southern megacity of Karachi around 11:00 pm (1800 GMT) Sunday.</p>

<p>The regional government of southern Sindh province said on X that a "tanker" had exploded on the airport motorway.</p>

<p>The separatist militant group the Baloch Liberation Army (BLA) said in a statement that it had "targeted a high-level convoy of Chinese engineers and investors" coming from Karachi's airport.</p>

<p>Beijing's embassy to Pakistan said in a statement on Monday that two Chinese citizens had been killed in a "terror attack" on a convoy of personnel from the Chinese-funded Port Qasim power project.</p>

<p>The attack also left one Chinese and several Pakistani citizens wounded, the embassy said.</p>

<p>The embassy urged authorities to "conduct a thorough investigation of the attack and severely punish the killers, while at the same time taking practical measures to fully ensure the safety of Chinese citizens, institutions and projects".</p>

<p>The BLA is a separatist militant group advocating for the autonomy of Pakistan's Balochistan province, the largest but poorest region of the country.</p>

<p>The group has regularly targeted Chinese nationals, claiming ethnic Baloch locals are not receiving their fair share of wealth extracted by foreign investors.</p>

<p>Pakistan's Civil Aviation Authority said flights from Karachi were continuing "as usual" and "agencies are investigating the cause at the scene of the accident/explosion".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-12/china-pakistan-flags-china-pak-reuters_650x400_81512469298.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Beijing's embassy to Pakistan said that a terror attack had killed 2 Chinese citizens. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/awarded-cop-killed-while-breaking-into-neighbours-house-in-us-6732877]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Off-duty Cop Killed While Breaking Into Neighbour's House In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/awarded-cop-killed-while-breaking-into-neighbours-house-in-us-6732877]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 08:44:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Recently, the officer was assigned to the Fugitive Unit of the Atlanta Police Department (APD). He joined the department in November 2015.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An off-duty police officer in Georgia, USA, who was previously honoured as "Investigator of the Year," was shot and killed while allegedly attempting to enter a neighbour's home, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/06/us-news/atlanta-police-officer-aubree-horton-shot-killed-while-breaking-into-neighbors-home/" rel="NoFollowNoIndex">New York Post reported</a>. Aubree Horton reportedly entered Winston's residence through the front door, where he confronted the homeowner. The police had been called to the scene regarding a suspected burglary in the St Andrews Country Club neighbourhood at around 5am.&nbsp;Authorities suspect that Horton was either undergoing a mental health crisis or was under the influence of drugs.</p>

<p>"When he entered the home, the homeowner acted in self-defence and shot him," said Captain John Mauney, as reported by Fox 5 Atlanta.</p>

<p>The officer was reported to be living only half a mile from where the incident took place, leaving residents in shock.</p>

<p>"I've been living here for five years, and this is something you'd never expect to happen," said resident Milton Johnston. Another neighbour commented, "It's a quiet golfing community. You just don't think something like this would ever happen here."</p>

<p>Recently, Mr Horton was assigned to the Fugitive Unit of the Atlanta Police Department (APD). He joined the department in November 2015. His recent recognition was linked to his work on a high-profile case involving the disappearance and death of 21-year-old Leondre Flynt, whose remains were found in July. Three suspects were arrested in connection with Flynt's death.</p>

<p>At the awards ceremony, Horton expressed his commitment to solving the case, saying, "It was a challenging investigation, but I felt the family deserved justice." Reflecting on the case's resolution, he added, "It was a significant achievement to provide the family with closure and hold someone accountable. That's why I do this job-to bring closure to people."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/brudu9r_aubree-horton-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities suspect that Aubree Horton was undergoing a mental health crisis.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/middle-east-war-israel-hamas-war-anniversary-live-updates-october-7-hamas-attack-al-aqsa-flood-israel-lebanon-iran-war-6732665]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: Air Raid Sirens In Israel After Rockets Fired From Gaza]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/middle-east-war-israel-hamas-war-anniversary-live-updates-october-7-hamas-attack-al-aqsa-flood-israel-lebanon-iran-war-6732665]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 08:31:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Today marks a year after the Palestinian militant group Hamas attacked Israel, triggering the year-long Israeli onslaught on the Gaza Strip. After nearly 1,200 people were killed during the October 7 attacks, Israel vowed to destroy Hamas.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today marks a year after the Palestinian militant group Hamas attacked Israel, triggering the year-long Israeli onslaught on the Gaza Strip. After nearly 1,200 people were killed during the October 7 attacks, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-ahead-of-gaza-war-anniversary-completely-transformed-reality-6732604" target="_blank">Israel vowed to destroy Hamas</a>.</p>

<p>Relentless <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-gaza-is-reduced-to-rubble-in-a-year-analysis-using-satellite-images-6731563" target="_blank">bombing in Gaza</a> and military campaigns continue in the strip of land even after a year. The death count there has crossed 41,000, according to the Gaza Health Ministry, while the United Nations estimates that nearly all of its 2.4 million population is eventually displaced.</p>

<p>Lebanon-based and Iran-backed&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israel-hezbollah-israel-strikes-lebanon-netanyahu-says-we-will-win-on-october-7-attack-anniversary-6732608#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Hezbollah</a> later joined the war against Israel in support of the Palestinians, triggering further tensions in the Middle East region.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the live updates on the first anniversary of&nbsp;Gaza war:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aulfehdg_school-destroyed-in-gaza-afp_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US-backed Israel still combats Hezbollah and Hamas while gearing up to strike Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-rallies-at-failed-assassination-site-a-month-before-us-polls-6732808]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Rallies At Failed Assassination Site A Month Before US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-2024-donald-trump-rallies-at-failed-assassination-site-a-month-before-us-polls-6732808]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 08:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump's much-hyped return to Butler, Pennsylvania, came exactly one month before the November 5 presidential election, the outcome of which President Joe Biden suggested on Friday might not be peaceful.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump defiantly returned Saturday to the site of a campaign rally where an assassin's bullet almost killed him in July, questioning whether his opponents were responsible and declaring he would "never quit."</p>

<p>"Exactly 12 weeks ago this evening, on this very ground, a cold-blooded assassin aimed to silence me," the Republican candidate told tens of thousands of supporters after taking the stage behind bulletproof glass.</p>

<p>Calling the gunman a "vicious monster," Trump vowed he would "never quit... never bend... never break" to cheers of "fight, fight, fight" from the crowd.</p>

<p>Trump's much-hyped return to Butler, Pennsylvania, came exactly one month before the November 5 presidential election, the outcome of which President Joe Biden suggested on Friday might not be peaceful.</p>

<p>Trump lashed out at his political opponents, calling them the "enemy within" who had pushed to indict him and "who knows, maybe even tried to kill me."</p>

<p>"I wasn't supposed to make it," he said ominously.</p>

<p>Security was noticeably tighter than Trump's July rally, with sniper squads atop surrounding buildings, and a surveillance drone deployed overhead.</p>

<p>"There's a lot going on that's unnerving," said Heather Hughes, 43, who had travelled from New Castle in must-win Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Do I think he's safe? No, I think there's going to be another attempt. But I think he's going to make it through."</p>

<p>After the assassination attempt, pictures of Trump -- with a blood-streaked face, pumping his fist and shouting "fight, fight, fight" -- became defining images of the campaign.</p>

<p>On Saturday, many Trump supporters wore shirts emblazoned with the iconography, and some sported ear coverings recalling the bandage the former president wore after the shooting.</p>

<p>Billionaire Elon Musk joined Trump on stage, stressing the tight margins that will likely decide the election in battleground states like Pennsylvania and encouraging voter registration.</p>

<p>Trump "must win to preserve democracy in America," said Musk, echoing the alarmist messaging he frequently pushes to his 200 million followers on his X platform.</p>

<h3><strong>Race upended&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Much has changed since Trump's last visit to Butler, when he was riding high in polls after crushing Biden in a TV debate.</p>

<p>Barely a week after the failed assassination bid, the presidential race was turned on its head when Biden dropped out and was replaced as the Democratic nominee by Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Harris has clawed back the poll deficit -- reversing it in some states -- and the seismic events in Butler that had threatened to unleash chaos were largely overtaken.</p>

<p>Trump's rally appeared aimed at recovering the momentum as a bruising campaign enters its final phase.</p>

<p>Harris, who Trump called incompetent, was in North Carolina Saturday meeting first responders and people hit by Hurricane Helene, which killed at least 220 as it ripped through the southeast.</p>

<p>The emergency response is "an example of the best we can do when we bring resources together at the federal, state and local level and tap into the kind of collegiality that produces results," she told officials at a briefing.</p>

<p>Trump has criticized the federal response, alleging without evidence that the Biden-Harris administration wrongly redirected relief funds to migrants.</p>

<h3><strong>Election violence?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The heavy security presence on Saturday highlighted persistent security fears, underscored when another attempt on Trump's life was foiled last month.</p>

<p>The Secret Service has been pilloried for failing to secure the building where the Butler shooter managed to fire at Trump eight times before being shot dead.</p>

<p>Along with Trump, two supporters were wounded and one -- firefighter Corey Comperatore -- was killed.</p>

<p>Trump and his campaign have sought to challenge Democrats' warnings about the former president representing a threat to democracy.</p>

<p>"The Republicans aren't violent... I think they (the Democrats) incite. They keep talking about Hitler and the end of democracy," said retiree Glen Scheirer, who was with five relatives wearing identical "By the grace of God" T-shirts showing Trump after the shooting. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In the immediate aftermath of the Butler incident, all sides urged a lowering of the political temperature.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Trump quickly reverted to his signature inflammatory rhetoric and refused to commit to accepting the eventual result in November.</p>

<p>He has been indicted over the effort to subvert the 2020 election that culminated in his supporters storming the Capitol.</p>

<p>Asked about the possibility of further election-related violence, Biden said Friday he did not know if the vote would be peaceful.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3ddh17n_donald-trump-_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump returned to the site exactly one month before the November 5 presidential election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/maldives-president-mohamed-muizzi-india-visit-wont-do-anything-to-undermine-security-of-india-maldives-president-6732730]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Maldives President's Diplomatic U-turn, Special Appeal For Indian Tourists]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/maldives-president-mohamed-muizzi-india-visit-wont-do-anything-to-undermine-security-of-india-maldives-president-6732730]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 08:04:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Maldives will not act to undermine India's security and views Delhi as a "valued partner and friend", and cooperation in several fields will "always be a priority", President Mohamed Muizzu said Sunday as he arrived in the national capital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/maldives" target="_blank">Maldives</a> will not act to undermine India's security and views New Delhi as a "valued partner and friend", and cooperation in several fields - including defence - will "always be a priority", President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/mohamed-muizzu" target="_blank">Mohamed Muizzu</a> said Sunday as he arrived in the national capital for his first bilateral visit.</p>

<p>Mr Muizzu - seen by some as a 'pro-China' leader who ran his election campaign on an 'India Out' platform - told a national English daily Maldives' relationship with India is "built on respect and shared interests" and that Delhi has been, and is, one of his country's largest trade and development partners.</p>

<p>The Maldives leader met Prime Minister Narendra Modi this afternoon; he received a ceremonial welcome from President Droupadi Murmu and Mr Modi at the forecourt of Rashtrapati Bhavan.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Delhi: Prime Minister Narendra Modi receives Maldives President Mohamed Muizzu at Hyderabad House. The two leaders are holding a meeting here.<br />
<br />
(Video: DD News) <a href="https://t.co/P3oE9MVRay">pic.twitter.com/P3oE9MVRay</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1843168122641256932?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Following his ceremonial welcome, Mr Muizzu left for Rajghat to pay tribute to Mahatma Gandhi, after which he holding bilateral talks with the Prime Minister at the Hyderabad House.</p>

<p>"Maldives would never do anything to undermine security of India. While we enhance cooperation with other countries in various sectors, we remain committed to ensuring our actions do not compromise the security and stability of our region..." he told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/president-muizzu-in-india-will-never-hurt-indias-security-interests-maldives-first-but-will-prioritise-ties-with-india/articleshow/113989329.cms" target="_blank">The Times of India</a>&nbsp;in an extensive interview yesterday.</p>

<p>Mr Muizzu, while not naming China, also underlined his administration's resolve to "fostering growth and development through diverse international collaborations". He flagged his 'Maldives First' policy, saying "it is essential for the Maldives to diversify international relations and reduce over-dependence on any one country". However, he said that such engagements would not undermine India's interests.</p>

<p>"Respect for our neighbours and friends is embedded in our DNA," he said as he also called on Indian tourists to return. "Indians make a positive contribution... Indian tourists are welcome," he said, batting for his country's most important economic sector, which took a hit last year after the diplomatic row.</p>

<p>This is Mr Muizzu's first bilateral visit and the comments reflect growing bonhomie after a months-long diplomatic stand-off last year, over three Maldivian ministers' comments about Prime Minister Modi after a social media post about Lakshadweep as an alternate tourist destination to the Maldives.</p>

<p>The Maldives' Foreign Ministry distanced itself from the remarks and the ministers were suspended; two - Mariyam Shiuna and Malsha Shareef - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maldivies-president-mohamed-muizzu-to-visit-india-soon-2-ministers-resign-amid-strained-ties-6533861" target="_blank">resigned last month</a>&nbsp;after the bilateral visit was confirmed.</p>

<p>And then the request in May - weeks before attending Mr Modi's swearing-in ceremony - to remove 90 military personnel deployed to three aviation platforms gifted by India - also raised eyebrows.</p>

<p>Delhi accepted the request and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/centre-confirms-withdrawal-of-indian-military-personnel-from-maldives-5627860" target="_blank">replaced military personnel with "competent technical" staff</a>.</p>

<p>The ejection of Indian military personnel and an 'India Out' agenda was seen as one of Mr Muizzu's key poll promises. Pressed on these topics, the Maldives President said he "did what the people of Maldives asked of me", but stressed India remains a key partner in efforts to secure regional stability.</p>

<p>"This historic relationship is intertwined like the roots of a tree... built on centuries of exchange and values shared. The relationship between the Maldives and India has always been strong..."</p>

<p>Earlier Mr Muizzu denied having an 'India Out' agenda but insisted his country had a "serious problem" with the presence of foreign military on its soil.&nbsp;"The people of Maldives do not want a single foreign soldier in the country," news agency PTI quoted his comments to local website adhadhu.com.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/never-followed-india-out-agenda-says-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-6665880" target="_blank">Never Followed "India Out" Agenda:: Maldives' Mohamed Muizzu</a></p>

<p>Mr Muizzu also spoke about India-assisted infrastructure projects, like the Greater Male connectivity scheme and water and sewerage facilities for 28 islands in the archipelago.</p>

<p>The Maldives is one of India's key maritime neighbours in the Indian Ocean region and the overall bilateral ties, including in the areas of defence and security, witnessed an upward trajectory under the previous government led by President Ibrahim Mohamed Solih.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-meeting-s-jaishankar-maldives-president-mohamed-muizzu-calls-india-one-of-closest-allies-6306693" target="_blank">"India One Of Closest Allies": Maldives Prez After Meeting S Jaishankar</a></p>

<p>India, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar said as he visited Male in August, during which recognises "common challenges and a shared interest in maintaining peace and security in the region".</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/glbucp8o_muizzu-modi_625x300_07_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israel-hezbollah-israel-strikes-lebanon-netanyahu-says-we-will-win-on-october-7-attack-anniversary-6732608]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Airstrikes In Beirut, Missiles Hit Israel City As Gaza War Completes A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-gaza-israel-hezbollah-israel-strikes-lebanon-netanyahu-says-we-will-win-on-october-7-attack-anniversary-6732608]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:27:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel and Hezbollah exchanged more fire ahead of the first anniversary of the Hamas attack, which triggered a war in Gaza and further escalated tensions in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel&nbsp;continued air strikes in Beirut's southern suburbs on Sunday as part of its campaign against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-israeli-airstrikes-hit-beirut-hezbollah-heir-apparent-missing-10-points-6726826" target="_blank">Hezbollah</a> in Lebanon, where the Iran-backed group is based.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">The Israeli military said it "struck Hezbollah terrorist targets and weapons storage facilities in Beirut". It also said Israeli warplanes hit targets belonging to Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-strikes-hit-south-beirut-sparking-flashes-of-red-and-white-seen-for-30-minutes-6726725" target="_blank">Beirut</a>.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hezbollah said it hit a military base south of Haifa, Israel's third-largest city, with "Fadi 1" missiles. Israeli media reported 10 people were injured in the country's north.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">In the Gaza Strip, at least 26 people were killed when Israeli airstrikes hit a mosque and a school sheltering displaced people on Sunday. Israel said it had conducted "precise strikes on Hamas terrorists".</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israel and Hezbollah started fighting across the Lebanese border after the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-and-tonnes-of-rubble-to-deal-with-gazas-continued-struggle-6728537" target="_blank">war in Gaza</a> erupted when <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-calls-october-7-attack-glorious-ahead-of-anniversary-6731348" target="_blank">Hamas</a>, a Hezbollah ally also backed by Iran, attacked Israeli towns on October 7 last year.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Hamas members killed about 1,200 people and took more than 250 hostages. Israel's retaliation has since then killed more than 41,000 people, the majority of them civilians.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">More than 2,000 people have also been killed in Lebanon in nearly a year of fighting.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Israeli Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-ahead-of-gaza-war-anniversary-completely-transformed-reality-6732604" target="_blank">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> on Sunday vowed to achieve victory and said his country's military "completely transformed reality" in the year since Hamas's October 7 attack.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Netanyahu told troops Israel "will win" as they fought in Gaza Strip and Lebanon.&nbsp;</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Tel Aviv may also strike its regional foe <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/will-israel-hit-irans-nuclear-facilities-what-top-us-official-said-6720390" target="_blank">Iran</a>, which had fired more than 180 missiles into Israel as a response to Israeli killings of Hezbollah chief Sayyed Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/djs4oop8_lebanon_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel continued air strikes in Beirut on Sunday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-ahead-of-gaza-war-anniversary-completely-transformed-reality-6732604]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Completely Transformed Reality": Netanyahu Ahead Of Gaza War Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/benjamin-netanyahu-ahead-of-gaza-war-anniversary-completely-transformed-reality-6732604]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 07:25:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday vowed to achieve victory and said his country's military "completely transformed reality" in the year since Hamas's October 7 attack, which has left the country fighting two wars.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Sunday vowed to achieve victory and said his country's military "completely transformed reality" in the year since Hamas's October 7 attack, which has left the country fighting two wars.</p>

<p>Netanyahu told troops Israel "will win" as it battles militants in both the Gaza Strip and Lebanon and prepares to strike Iran, almost a year since the unprecedented attack by Palestinian Hamas militants sparked the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Israel's army chief, Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said that, one year on, "we have defeated the military wing of Hamas".</p>

<p>Netanyahu had pledged to "crush... and destroy" the militants as fighting began last October, but troops have returned to several areas across Gaza where they had previously conducted operations against Hamas, only to find militants regrouping.</p>

<p>In late September Israel turned its focus north, intensifying military action against Iran-backed Hezbollah, which had been routinely sending rockets over the border from Lebanon in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>"A year ago, we suffered a terrible blow. Over the past 12 months, we have completely transformed reality," Netanyahu said during a visit to the Lebanon border, according to his office.</p>

<p>Hamas on Sunday called the October 7 attack "glorious" and said the Palestinians were "writing a new history with their resistance".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Their attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity. Dozens of other hostages are still held.</p>

<p>At last 370 people were killed at one location alone, the Nova rave in the Negev desert, which was commemorated with candles, prayer and music in Tel Aviv on Sunday.</p>

<p><strong>Destroyed, displaced</strong></p>

<p>In northern Gaza, the military said it had encircled the Jabaliya area after indications Hamas was rebuilding there despite a year of air strikes and fighting.</p>

<p>Rescuers said 17 people, including nine children, had been killed on Sunday by Israeli air strikes on the area.</p>

<p>Israel's military offensive in Gaza has killed at least 41,870 people, the majority of them civilians, according to figures provided by the Hamas-run territory's health ministry and described as reliable by the UN.</p>

<p>Most of Gaza's population is displaced and much of the territory's housing and other infrastructure destroyed.</p>

<p>Despite fighting, which has escalated in Lebanon since late September, and the threat of war with Iran, Netanyahu told French President Emmanuel Macron in a phone call that Israel's actions in Lebanon would help bring "stability, security and peace in the entire region", according to Netanyahu's office.</p>

<p>Lebanese Prime Minister Najib Mikati appealed to the international community to push Israel for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>US Vice President and Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris said in a pre-recorded interview that Washington was "not going to stop" pressuring Israel and Arab leaders to agree a Gaza truce.</p>

<p>The leaders of Jordan and the United Arab Emirates called for intensified international efforts to stop both wars. Iraqi Prime Minister Mohammed Shia al-Sudani warned the fighting could "plunge the region and the world into prolonged conflicts".</p>

<p>Such appeals, and efforts by mediators, failed to secure a truce and hostage-release deal in Gaza. Critics of Netanyahu accuse him of obstructing such a deal.</p>

<p>Israel has been on high alert in the run-up to the October 7 anniversary, which the military said could lead to "attacks on the home front".</p>

<p><strong>Policewoman killed</strong></p>

<p>In southern Israel's Beersheba central bus station, a border policewoman was killed and 10 other people injured, first responders said. Police called it a suspected "terrorist" attack, adding that the assailant had also been killed.</p>

<p>Official Lebanese media late Sunday reported four Israeli strikes on Hezbollah's south Beirut stronghold, shortly after the latest calls by Israel's military for residents to leave the area.</p>

<p>Israel's military said it struck weapons storage facilities and infrastructure while taking measures "to mitigate the risk of harming civilians".</p>

<p>In a later statement, they said the latest strikes had "struck Hezbollah terrorist targets and weapons storage facilities in Beirut".</p>

<p>Late Sunday, Lebanon's health ministry said six people were killed and 13 wounded in an Israeli strike on the village of Keyfoun, 20 kilometres (12 miles) from Beirut.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It said Israeli strikes around the country killed 25 people the day before.</p>

<p>Hezbollah said Sunday it launched attack drones towards a military base near the northern Israeli city of Haifa. It later said it had targeted a second base nearby with a salvo of rockets.</p>

<p>Israel's military said rockets fired from northern Gaza had crossed into Israel, with one intercepted and the rest falling on open areas.</p>

<p>UN peacekeepers accused the Israeli military of compromising their safety by operating "immediately adjacent" to one of their positions in south Lebanon.</p>

<p>UNIFIL previously said it had rejected an Israeli request to relocate some of its peacekeepers.</p>

<p>- Foreigners flee -<br />
Israel, which began ground operations in Lebanon last Monday, says it aims to allow tens of thousands of Israelis displaced over the past year by Hezbollah rocket fire into northern Israel to return home.</p>

<p>Tehran, which backs armed groups across the Middle East, on Tuesday launched around 200 missiles at Israel in revenge for Israeli killings of militant leaders including Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah.</p>

<p>Israeli officials including Netanyahu have said Israel will respond to Iran's missile barrage, most of which was intercepted by the country's sophisticated air defences.</p>

<p>Iran has prepared its own plan to respond to a possible Israeli attack, Tasnim news agency reported, citing an informed source.</p>

<p>Flights at some Iranian airports were suspended Sunday, Tehran's aviation body announced, citing "operational restrictions".</p>

<p>Across Lebanon, strikes have killed more than 1,110 people since September 23, according to an AFP tally based on official figures.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Director General of Education Imad Achkar said Sunday that 40 percent of Lebanon's 1.25 million school pupils had been displaced by Israel's strikes.</p>

<p>Several countries have been evacuating their nationals from Lebanon.</p>

<p>Gaza's health ministry said Sunday an Israeli strike on a mosque-turned-shelter in central Deir el-Balah had killed 26 people. Israel said it had targeted Hamas militants.</p>

<p>Ahead of the October 7 anniversary, tens of thousands of protesters marched in cities around the world over the weekend calling for a ceasefire in Gaza and Lebanon.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/itlt6efc_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu had pledged to "crush... and destroy" the militants as fighting began last October]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-gaza-is-reduced-to-rubble-in-a-year-analysis-using-satellite-images-6731563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Images Show How Gaza Was Reduced To Rubble In A Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-gaza-is-reduced-to-rubble-in-a-year-analysis-using-satellite-images-6731563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 01:27:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[On October 7, 2023, Hamas - a militant group which controlled Gaza - crossed over into Israel and launched 'Operation Al Aqsa Flood', a deadly terror attack, killed over 1,200 people across the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On October 7, 2023, Hamas - a militant group which controlled Gaza - crossed over into Israel and launched 'Operation Al Aqsa Flood', a deadly terror attack, that killed over 1,200 people across the country. Israel was caught off-guard. Hamas operatives fired over 5,000 rockets, they came through paragliders, broke the Gaza wall and went on a killing spree. Israel responded with an air-ground invasion of Gaza, which has killed over 40,000 since last year.</p>

<p>Israel primarily has three objectives - Avenge the killing of people, uproot Hamas from Gaza and ensure the safe return of hostages from the territory. Gaza is left to ruins with over 66 per cent of buildings have been flattened, lakhs have been displaced and thousands have died in bombings. Hamas' Command and Control structure has been disrupted while several hostages have returned, some (assumed to be alive) are still in Gaza.</p>

<h2><b>Reduced To Rubble</b></h2>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-thirds-of-buildings-in-gaza-damaged-since-war-began-last-year-un-6685216">UN Satellite Centre (UNOSAT)</a> analysed satellite images of the 365 sq km of land. The report compares satellite images from September 2024 with pictures taken before the invasion began. "UNOSAT identified 52,564 destroyed structures, 18,913 severely damaged structures, 56,710 moderately damaged structures, and 35,591 possibly damaged structures for 163,778 structures," the report said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/63ousal_jabalia-camp-getty_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Open-source satellite images from EOS Landviewer, accessed by NDTV, show the structural changes in north Gaza, primarily near the Jabalia refugee camp which was established in 1948 after the 1948 Arab-Israeli war. NDTV analysed four images - three after the war and one from 2022 to understand the changes to the buildings and loss of cropland after the bombing.</p>

<h2><strong>What Satellite Images Say</strong></h2>

<p>A picture taken on September 26, 2024, by Sentinel-2 shows a razed area, with almost no vegetation after the bombing campaign. When the image of the same area is compared with one taken on December 16, 2022 - A year before the invasion - a massive change is visible.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The grey patch represents buildings, while green represents croplands. Gaza is one of the most densely populated regions in the world with over 2.3 million living in an area 1/4th the size of Delhi. By September 26, the density was reduced after the area was bombed several times.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/iduql5v8_gaza-satellite-pic1_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wiped-off-the-map-gazans-back-in-war-ravaged-jabalia-refugee-camp-5795492">Several families in the region</a> have relocated and moved south to escape death. With their belongings on bullock carts, cars, trucks and other modes of transportation, the mass evacuation took place amid air strikes and ground assault.</p>

<p>The images were compared with UNOSAT's cropland damage analysis to underpin the notable changes. UNOSAT used the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), a widely used metric to quantify the health and density of vegetation using sensor data. North Gaza has 31.3 sq km of cropland, of which 24.6 sq km or 79 per cent has been destroyed, leaving just 6.7 sq km.</p>

<p>During a conflict, natural vegetation is the most vulnerable to damage, leading to soil erosion and damage to croplands, impacting food production and causing other health impacts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UN report states "The methodology evaluated the damage as a decline in the health and density of crops in September 2024, in comparison to the preceding seven seasons spanning from 2017 to 2024. The decline in the health and density of the crops can be observed due to the impact of activities such as razing, heavy vehicle activity, bombing, shelling, and other conflict-related dynamics. The analysis includes damage assessment for orchards and other trees, field crops and vegetables."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The analysis shows that the agricultural extent in the Gaza Strip is estimated to be 150 sq. km, accounting for approximately 41% of the total area of the Gaza Strip."&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6e4d5jtg_gaza-satellite-pic2_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The United Nations estimates there are over <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-year-of-devastation-and-tonnes-of-rubble-to-deal-with-gazas-continued-struggle-6728537">42 million tonnes of debris</a>, including both shattered edifices that are still standing and flattened buildings across Gaza.</p>

<h2><strong>Israel: One Year After Attacks</strong></h2>

<p>Israel is still under attack from all directions. The frequency of attacks from Gaza has significantly reduced, but the war opened several fronts for the nation to deal with. Hezbollah - A Shia militant group in Lebanon - has been relentlessly attacking north Israel in solidarity with Palestinians in Gaza, forcing over 70,000 Israelis to leave their homes for a safer location.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel said the gravity of the conflict has moved north to ensure the safe return of its citizens that have been under attack but the pager and walkie-talkie blasts across Lebanon to target Hezbollah, led to a wider conflict where the militant group alleged that Israel was behind the explosions. The conflict escalated to an air, artillery campaign, similar to Gaza, killing thousands including the group's chief, Hassan Nasrallah, and his potential successor Hashem Safieddine a week later. Israel has eliminated a majority of Hezbollah leaders.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Houthi rebels - a group backed by Iran - in Yemen have carried out several attacks since last year, opening another front for Tel Aviv.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Since last year, Israel and Iran - two arch-rivals in West Asia - have confronted each other directly with missile and drone attacks. In April, Iran launched a missile and drone attack on Israel after strikes on its consulate in Damascus, Syria. The projectiles were mostly aimed at non-civilian areas. An Israeli response followed it.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-iran-on-israel-civilians-hiding-in-bomb-shelters-says-israel-defence-forces-6694961">Six months later,</a> Iran launched over 200 missiles targetting military and civilian areas, a paradigm shift in its approach to confront Israel after it killed Nasrallah. An Israeli response to the attack is expected soon.</p>

<p>Since last year, the US and other regional powers have failed to broker a ceasefire since Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is adamant about fulfilling the military objectives and attacks from Gaza have not stopped.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bm36f4ng_israel-hamas-war-gaza-rubble_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since last year, the US and other regional powers have failed to broker a ceasefire,]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-calls-october-7-attack-glorious-ahead-of-anniversary-6731348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Calls October 7 Attack "Glorious" Ahead Of Anniversary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-calls-october-7-attack-glorious-ahead-of-anniversary-6731348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:12:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Palestinian group Hamas on Sunday praised its October 7 attack on Israel in a video message ahead of the first anniversary of the deadly storming of southern Israel which sparked the war in Gaza.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Palestinian group Hamas on Sunday praised its October 7 attack on Israel in a video message ahead of the first anniversary of the deadly storming of southern Israel which sparked the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The crossing of the glorious 7th of October shattered the illusions the enemy had created for itself, convincing the world and the region of its supposed superiority and capabilities," Qatar-based Hamas member Khalil al-Hayya said in a video statement.</p>

<p>Last year's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures that include hostages killed in captivity.</p>

<p>At least 41,870 Palestinians, a majority of them civilians, have been killed in Israel's military campaign in the Gaza Strip since the war began, according to data provided by the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza. The UN has acknowledged these figures as reliable.</p>

<p>Al-Hayya, said a year after the October 7 attack, "all of Palestine, particularly Gaza, and our Palestinian people are writing a new history with their resistance, blood, and steadfastness".</p>

<p>The Hamas member, who has emerged as the Islamist group's public face following the killing of its former leader Ismail Haniyeh in July, said Gazans had remained "resilient to all attempts at displacement... despite the kinds of torture and terrorism you have endured, and the horrific genocide and daily massacre".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/5dd8htho_hamas-attacks-israel_625x300_05_November_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last year's October 7 attack resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people in Israel (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>