<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:37:59 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obamas-half-sister-among-protesters-tear-gassed-in-kenya-report-5968395]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Barack Obama's Half-Sister Among Protesters Tear-Gassed In Kenya: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/barack-obamas-half-sister-among-protesters-tear-gassed-in-kenya-report-5968395]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:37:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan activist Auma Obama, the half-sister of former U.S. President Barack Obama, was among protesters tear-gassed on Tuesday during demonstrations outside the parliament building in Nairobi, a CNN interview showed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan activist Auma Obama, the half-sister of former US President Barack Obama, was among protesters tear-gassed on Tuesday during demonstrations outside the parliament building in Nairobi, a CNN interview showed.</p>

<p>Police opened fire on demonstrators trying to storm Kenya's legislature on Tuesday, with at least five protesters killed, dozens wounded and sections of the parliament building set ablaze as lawmakers inside passed legislation to raise taxes.</p>

<p>Auma Obama was taken aside by a CNN reporter and asked why she was there.</p>

<p>"I'm here because - look at what's happening. Young Kenyans are demonstrating for their rights. They're demonstrating with flags and banners. I can't even see anymore," she said, beginning to cough and shield her eyes from the spreading smoke.</p>

<p>"We are being tear-gassed."</p>

<p>A man behind her carried a sign reading, "Colonialism never ended in Kenya," while another yelled, "This is our country. This is our nation."</p>

<p>Auma Obama earlier posted photos of herself on Twitter at the protest.</p>

<p>The office of former President Obama did not immediately return a call seeking comment on the incident involving his sister or the violence in Kenya.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nf2bamm8_auma-obama_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Auma Obama earlier posted photos of herself on Twitter at the protest. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-migrant-on-bail-and-under-surveillance-rapes-and-kills-12-year-old-girl-5968317]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Illegal Migrant, On Bail And Under Surveillance, Rapes, Kills 12-Year-Old]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-migrant-on-bail-and-under-surveillance-rapes-and-kills-12-year-old-girl-5968317]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:25:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the hearing, the judge set Ramos' bail at $10 million, which exceeded the $5 million requested by prosecutors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Franklin Jose Pena Ramos, 26, a suspect in the murder of 12-year-old Jocelyn Nungaray in Houston last week, appeared in Harris County Criminal Court on Monday. It was disclosed during the court proceedings that he was wearing an ankle monitor from the Immigration and Customs Enforcement agency (ICE) at the time of the alleged murder.</p>

<p>He was issued the ankle bracelet after being arrested by Border Patrol agents for illegal entry into the country and subsequently released from custody. In a statement to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/illegal-immigrant-accused-raping-murdering-girl-12-wore-ice-ankle-monitor-when-crime-occurred"><em>Fox News</em></a> on Friday, ICE indicated that he "illegally entered the U.S. without inspection, parole, or admission by a U.S. immigration officer at an unspecified date and location."</p>

<p>ICE also has a retainer on Ramos, the agency said.</p>

<p>Judge Josh Hill, overseeing Monday's proceedings, also remarked that Ramos and 21-year-old Johan Jose Rangel Martinez, the other suspect in the case, were accused of attempting to collect funds to leave town.</p>

<p>During the hearing, the judge set Ramos' bail at $10 million, which exceeded the $5 million requested by prosecutors.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">NEW: One of the illegal Venezuelan migrants who allegedly r*p*d 12-year-old Jocelyn Nungaray appears in court where a $10 million bond was set.<br />
<br />
The judge noted that Franklin Jose Pena Ramos was an "astronomical" flight risk.<br />
<br />
New court documents reveal horrifying new details,… <a href="https://t.co/Aw3sHBCKXL">pic.twitter.com/Aw3sHBCKXL</a></p>
— Collin Rugg (@CollinRugg) <a href="https://twitter.com/CollinRugg/status/1805413537436795375?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Pena's defence had proposed a $1 million bail, but the judge argued that he posed an "astronomical" risk of flight and suggested the likelihood of his return to court was "almost nonexistent."</p>

<p>If Ramos were to post bail, the judge ordered him to wear a GPS monitor, be under 24/7 house arrest, stay within Harris County, refrain from contacting the other suspect or the victim's family, avoid contact with minors, abstain from possessing firearms, drugs, or alcohol, and surrender his passport.</p>

<p>Ramos and Martinez allegedly enticed the young girl under a bridge in Houston, where they proceeded to restrain and fatally harm her.</p>

<p>"In this case, the defendant lured a 12-year-old under a bridge, where he and his co-defendant remained with her for over 2 hours, took her pants off, tied her up, and killed her, then threw her body into the bayou," Harris County Assistant District Attorney Michael Abner wrote.</p>

<p>Police stated that investigators utilized surveillance footage to monitor the activities of the two individuals both before and after the homicide.</p>

<p>Both suspects face charges of capital murder, with Martinez scheduled to make his initial court appearance on Tuesday.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ad3j2kco_franklin-jose-pena-ramos_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[He was issued the ankle bracelet after being arrested by Border Patrol agents]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-slater-all-about-uk-teen-missing-in-tenerife-for-over-a-week-5967775]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jay Slater: All About UK Teen Missing In Tenerife For Over A Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jay-slater-all-about-uk-teen-missing-in-tenerife-for-over-a-week-5967775]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 19:09:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jay Slater, a 19-year-old from Oswaldtwistle, Lancashire, disappeared while on vacation in Tenerife after attending a music festival with friends.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major search and rescue operation has been launched on Tenerife in response to the disappearance of British teenager Jay Slater, who has been missing for more than a week.</p>

<p>During a vacation with friends, it is thought that the 19-year-old apprentice bricklayer from Oswaldtwistle, Lancashire vanished while attempting to return home from a rave.</p>

<p>Additionally, Jay's friend Lucy Law, who was his last contact, started a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-us-get-jay-home">GoFundMe page.</a> Over 33,000 pounds have been raised thus far, however according to Jay Duncan's mother Debbie Duncan, none of it has been taken back yet.</p>

<p><strong>Here's a closer look at the timeline of events surrounding Jay Slater's disappearance:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<ul>
	<li>On Sunday, June 17, Jay attended the NRG music festival with his friend, Lucy Law, who was the last to hear from him. At 8:35 pm, Jay posted a Snapchat video from the event in the island's southwest. Lucy left early, but Jay stayed, leaving later with two other Brits between Sunday night and Monday morning.</li>
	<li>On Monday, June 18, Jay remained at an Airbnb near Masca in Teno Rural Park, posting on Snapchat at 7:30 am. He attempted to take a bus back to Los Cristianos where he was staying. The last sighting of Jay was by the Airbnb owner, who described him walking briskly alone. Jay later called Lucy at 8:30 am, lost and in need of water after walking for some time. A missing persons report was filed at 9 am, initiating an extensive search effort with drones, dogs, and a helicopter. Lucy joined the search after receiving assistance from a local woman.</li>
	<li>On Tuesday, June 18, Jay's mother Debbie Duncan learned of his disappearance at 2 am and immediately flew to Tenerife with his older brother Zak at 7 am. Debbie received disturbing prank calls claiming to have taken Jay, while her partner speculated Jay may have simply lost his way.</li>
	<li>By Wednesday, June 19, police investigated a false sighting of Jay in Los Cristianos, redirecting the search initially south before refocusing north around Masca. His hotel room was searched, yielding only his belongings. Debbie described the ordeal as a "living nightmare" and pleaded for Jay's return, while Lucy described his disappearance as "suspicious and weird."</li>
	<li>On Thursday, June 20, new footage emerged showing Jay at the NRG rave, wearing sunglasses on his head as he walked through the crowd.</li>
	<li>By Friday, June 21, search efforts focused on the 2,000ft Masca ravine, known for its steep trail leading to the sea. Meanwhile, the individuals Jay stayed with returned to the UK. The Tenerife Civil Guard declined assistance from the Lancashire Constabulary, a decision that Debbie criticized, citing the need for more resources in the search.</li>
	<li>On Saturday, June 22, an unconfirmed sighting of Jay was reported in Santiago del Teide, approximately 3.5 miles from Masca. A witness claimed to have seen him with two men outside a church around 6 pm on Monday, nine hours after the missing persons report was filed. Jay's father, Warren Slater, visited the search area in response.</li>
	<li>By Sunday, June 23, search efforts concentrated on outbuildings in Masca. A journalist involved in the Madeleine McCann case offered assistance, and a GoFundMe campaign organized by Lucy exceeded 30,000 pounds in donations.</li>
	<li>On Monday, June 24, Jay's family shared a screenshot of CCTV footage capturing a figure walking past the church in Santiago del Teide, corroborating the reported sighting. Debbie expressed her deep concern, stating, "I really hope I am not taking my son home in a body bag."</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/clni9cko_jay-slater_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Despite efforts by authorities and volunteers, Jay Slater's whereabouts remain unknown.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptably-high-alcohol-kills-nearly-3-million-people-every-year-says-who-5967660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unacceptably High": Alcohol Kills Nearly 3 Million Every Year, Says WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/unacceptably-high-alcohol-kills-nearly-3-million-people-every-year-says-who-5967660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:52:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Alcohol kills nearly three million people annually, the World Health Organization said on Tuesday, adding that while the death rate had dropped slightly in recent years it remained "unacceptably high".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alcohol kills nearly three million people annually, the World Health Organization said on Tuesday, adding that while the death rate had dropped slightly in recent years it remained "unacceptably high".</p>

<p>The United Nations health agency's latest report on alcohol and health said alcohol causes nearly one in 20 deaths globally each year, through drink driving, alcohol-induced violence and abuse, and a multitude of diseases and disorders.</p>

<p>The report said 2.6 million deaths were attributed to alcohol consumption in 2019 -- the latest available statistics -- accounting for 4.7 percent of all deaths worldwide that year.</p>

<p>Nearly three-quarters of those deaths were in men, it said.</p>

<p>"Substance use severely harms individual health, increasing the risk of chronic diseases, mental health conditions, and tragically resulting in millions of preventable deaths every year," WHO director general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said.</p>

<p>He pointed out that there had been "some reduction in alcohol consumption and related harm worldwide since 2010".</p>

<p>"(But) the health and social burden due to alcohol use remains unacceptably high," he continued, highlighting that younger people were disproportionately affected.</p>

<p>The highest proportion of alcohol-attributable deaths in 2019 -- 13 percent -- were among people aged 20 to 39, the WHO said.</p>

<p><strong>Cancer, car crashes</strong></p>

<p>Drinking is linked to a slew of health conditions, including cirrhosis of the liver and some cancers.</p>

<p>Of all fatalities it caused in 2019, the report found that an estimated 1.6 million were from noncommunicable diseases.</p>

<p>Of these, 474,000 were from cardiovascular diseases, 401,000 from cancer and a huge 724,000 from injuries, including traffic accidents and self-harm.</p>

<p>Alcohol abuse also makes people more susceptible to infectious diseases such as tuberculosis, HIV and pneumonia, the report found.</p>

<p>An estimated 209 million people lived with alcohol dependence in 2019 -- 3.7 percent of the global population.</p>

<p>Total per capita consumption worldwide decreased slightly to 5.5 litres of alcohol in 2019 from 5.7 litres nine years earlier, the report found.</p>

<p>But alcohol consumption overall is unevenly distributed around the globe.</p>

<p>Well over half of the world's population over the age of 15 abstains completely.</p>

<p>Europe accounted by far for the highest levels of per capital drinking, at 9.2 litres, followed by the Americas at 7.5 litres.</p>

<p>The lowest consumption was in predominantly Muslim countries in Northern Africa, the Middle East and Asia, the report said.</p>

<p><strong>Heavy drinkers</strong></p>

<p>Among people who drank alcohol in 2019, the report determined they consumed 27 grammes of pure alcohol per day on average.</p>

<p>That is roughly equivalent to two glasses of wine, two small bottles of beer or two shots of spirits.</p>

<p>"This level and frequency of drinking is associated with increased risks of numerous health conditions and associated mortality and disability," the WHO warned.</p>

<p>In 2019, a full 38 percent of current drinkers acknowledged having engaged in heavy episodic drinking, defined as consuming at last 60 grammes of pure alcohol on one or more occasions in the preceding month.</p>

<p>Globally, 23.5 percent of 15- to 19-year-olds were considered current drinkers.</p>

<p>That jumped to more than 45 percent for people in this age group living in Europe, and to nearly 44 percent in the Americas.</p>

<p>The WHO said it was essential to improve access to quality treatment for substance use disorders.</p>

<p>In 2019, the proportion of people contacting such treatment services ranged from below one percent to 35 percent in countries providing this data.</p>

<p>"Stigma, discrimination and misconceptions about the efficacy of treatment contribute to these critical gaps in treatment provision," Vladimir Poznyak, head of WHO's unit for alcohol, drugs and addictive behaviours, told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/aaod9lbk_alcohol-generic-istock_625x300_23_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Drinking is linked to a slew of health conditions. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-re-install-maharaja-ranjit-singhs-statue-at-kartarpur-sahib-5967598]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan To Re-Install Maharaja Ranjit Singh's Statue At Kartarpur Sahib]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-to-re-install-maharaja-ranjit-singhs-statue-at-kartarpur-sahib-5967598]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:41:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Punjab government said on Tuesday that it will install the restored statue of the first ruler of the Sikh Empire, Maharaja Ranjit Singh, at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday so that visiting Sikhs from India would get to view it too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Punjab government said on Tuesday that it will install the restored statue of the first ruler of the Sikh Empire, Maharaja Ranjit Singh, at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday so that visiting Sikhs from India would get to view it too.</p>

<p>Kartarpur Sahib is also known as Gurdwara Darbar Sahib and is situated about 150 km northeast of Lahore, close to the Indian border.</p>

<p>The nine-foot-tall bronze statue of Maharaja Ranjit Singh was first installed at the Lahore Fort near his Samadhi in 2019. It was twice vandalised by activists of the Tehreek-e-Labbaik Pakistan (TLP), a far-right Islamic political party in Pakistan.</p>

<p>“We are going to install Maharaja Ranjit Singh's statue at Gurdwara Darbar Sahib, Kartarpur on Wednesday afternoon in the presence of local and Indian Sikhs,” Punjab's first Sikh Minister and President (pardhan) of the Pakistan Sikh Gurdwara Parbandhak Committee (PSGPC) Sardar Ramesh Singh Arora told PTI.</p>

<p>The restored statue is being placed at Kartarpur Sahib so that Indian Sikhs visiting there could see it, Arora said. He also assured better security to protect the restored statue.</p>

<p>The minister said restoration work of Maharaja Ranjit Singh's statue has already begun which will soon be completed.</p>

<p>Maharaja Ranjit Singh was the founder of the Sikh Empire, which ruled the northwest Indian subcontinent in the early half of the 19th century with his headquarters at Lahore.</p>

<p>Currently, 455 Sikhs, who arrived here from India last week to take part in festivities in connection with Maharaja Ranjit Singh's death anniversary, will also be present at Kartarpur Sahib on Wednesday when Singh's statue will be unveiled.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2018-11/40i71itg_shri-kartarpur-sahib-gurudwara_625x300_22_November_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-court-clears-man-of-sexual-assault-charges-as-victim-took-20-seconds-to-react-5967455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Court Frees Man Of Rape Charges As Woman Took 'Too Long' To React]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/italian-court-clears-man-of-sexual-assault-charges-as-victim-took-20-seconds-to-react-5967455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:23:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The case centres around Raffaele Meola, a former trade union official, who was accused of groping the attendant in 2018.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Italian judge is receiving criticism for clearing a man accused of groping a flight attendant. The controversial verdict hinged on the woman's alleged delayed reaction, which the judge inexplicably deemed too slow to be evidence of a genuine assault, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.it/article/vittima-aspetta-20-secondi-no-violenza-sessuale"><em>Vanity Fair Italy </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This justification has sparked outrage from women's rights groups and the attendant's legal team, who argue it sets a dangerous precedent and discourages victims from coming forward.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The case centres around Raffaele Meola, a former trade union official, who was accused of groping the attendant in 2018. This is reportedly not the first time the judge has ruled in Meola's favour based on the attendant's reaction time, raising concerns about potential bias. The verdict is being challenged, with the attendant's legal team vowing to fight for justice.</p>

<p>Her lawyer said following the verdict, "We will appeal to the Supreme Court because this sentence takes us back 30 years."</p>

<p>The lawyer said that the verdict went against Supreme Court precedent which 'for over ten years stated that a sexual act, carried out unexpectedly without ascertaining the woman's consent, is a crime of sexual violence and must be judged as such.'</p>

<p>Despite claiming to believe the victim, the judge, Nicoletta Guerrero, threw out the case due to a lack of "sufficient evidence." This justification stemmed from a detail from the alleged assault: Mr. Meola, standing behind the woman, reportedly touched, kissed, and massaged her for 30 seconds. The critical point? The court argued her continued reading of documents during this time implied a lack of immediate objection.</p>

<p>This supposed "slow reaction," according to Il Fatto Quotidiano, led the judge to believe Mr Meola might have misinterpreted the situation.</p>

<p>These are his words reported by <em>Corriere della Sera</em>. "This judicial case highlights once again the urgency of a reform of the law provided for by article 609 bis of the penal code which clearly defines that the crime of rape is any sexual act carried out without the consent of the woman, whose dissent is always presumed, as provided for by the Istanbul Convention. The burden of proving the woman's consent to the sexual act must be provided by the accused. Currently, the current law, together with non-specialised jurisprudence, favours the secondary victimization of women who report and this is unacceptable."</p>

<p>Elisa Ercoli, president of Differenza donna, also intervened, "This sentence is proof of how our law 66/96 is the cause of serious and continuous institutional violence, we reject a democracy that effectively prevents women from obtaining justice following rape. We urgently ask for a new law with evolved parameters of justice without having our institutions against us anymore."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/foj8vs9g_flight-attendant-generic_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The lawyer said that the verdict went against Supreme Court precedent]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reacts To Video Of Injured Palestinian Tied To Israeli Military Jeep]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:15:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.</p>

<p>At a State Department news briefing, a reporter asked: "Isn't that basically the army using Palestinians as human shields?"</p>

<p>State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller responded: "I will say we saw that video. It was shocking. The practice was absolutely unacceptable. Humans should never be used as human shields."</p>

<p>"The IDF should swiftly investigate what happened, hold people accountable," Miller said, using an acronym for the Israel Defense Forces.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian man to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the Israeli military said.</p>

<p>The video circulating on social media and verified by Reuters showed a Palestinian resident of Jenin, Mujahed Azmi, on a military jeep that passed between two ambulances.</p>

<p>The Israeli military in a statement said Israeli forces were fired at and exchanged fire, wounding a suspect and detaining him.</p>

<p>Soldiers then violated military protocol, the statement said.</p>

<p>The military said the "conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values" of the Israeli military and the incident will be investigated and dealt with. The military said the man was transferred to medics for treatment.</p>

<p>"I saw the statement they put out that the actions were inconsistent with the orders those soldiers received and that is being investigated and the people involved will be dealt with accordingly. That is absolutely appropriate," Miller said.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, already on the rise before the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza began in October, has escalated since then with frequent army raids on Palestinian groups, rampages by Jewish settlers in Palestinian villages, and deadly street attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/14eup9ns_palestinian-man-jeep_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Shot Dead, Parts Of Kenya Parliament On Fire During Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:02:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan protesters breached parliament barricades on Tuesday and entered the complex where lawmakers were debating contentious tax hike proposals that have sparked widespread anger, AFP journalists saw.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan police shot dead five during a protest near parliament Tuesday, a rights group said, with AFP journalists seeing three people lying motionless on the ground as crowds opposed to proposed tax hikes breached barricades to enter the parliamentary complex where a fire erupted.</p>

<p>The mainly Gen-Z-led rallies, which began last week, have caught the government off guard, with President William Ruto saying over the weekend he was ready to talk to the protesters.</p>

<p>But tensions sharply escalated on Tuesday afternoon, as crowds began to throw stones at police and push back against barricades, making their way towards the parliament complex, which was sealed off by police in full riot gear.</p>

<p>Police fired at crowds massing outside the parliament building, where lawmakers had been debating a contentious bill featuring tax hike proposals.</p>

<p>Shortly before, Irungu Houghton, the executive director of Amnesty International Kenya, told AFP that "human rights observers are now reporting the increasing use of live bullets by the National Police Service in the capital of Nairobi".</p>

<p>"Safe passage for medical officers to treat the many wounded is now urgent," he said.</p>

<p>Anger over a cost-of-living crisis spiralled into nationwide rallies last week, with demonstrators calling for the finance bill to be scrapped. The people are angry over the rising prices of bread and nappies.</p>

<p>Despite a heavy police presence, thousands of protesters had earlier marched through Nairobi's business district, pushing back against barricades as they headed towards parliament.</p>

<p>Police in full riot gear were firing tear gas and rubber bullets into the crowd, according to AFP journalists.</p>

<p>As protesters gained ground in their push towards parliament, many were livestreaming the action earlier in the day as they sang, chanted and beat drums.</p>

<p>Crowds also marched in the port city of Mombasa, the opposition bastion of Kisumu, and Ruto's stronghold of Eldoret, images on Kenyan TV channels showed.</p>

<p><strong>- 'At a crossroads' -</strong></p>

<p>The Independent Policing Oversight Authority watchdog and rights groups said that two people had died following Thursday's rallies in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Several organisations, including Amnesty International Kenya, said at least 200 people were wounded in last week's protests in Nairobi.</p>

<p>Amnesty's Kenya chapter posted on X Tuesday that "the pattern of policing protests is deteriorating fast", urging the government to respect demonstrators' right to assembly.</p>

<p>On Monday, ahead of the rallies, the rights body said Kenya was "at a crossroads".</p>

<p>"Despite mass arrests and injuries, the protests have continued to grow, emphasising the public's widespread discontent," it said, warning that "the escalation of force could lead to more fatalities and legal repercussions."</p>

<p>Rights watchdogs have accused the authorities of abducting protesters in violation of the law.</p>

<p>The Kenya Human Rights Commission said the abductions had mostly occurred at night and were "conducted by police officers in civilian clothes and unmarked cars", calling for the "unconditional release of all abductees."</p>

<p>Police have not responded to AFP requests for comment on the allegations.</p>

<p>The protesters have also deployed unconventional tactics, including asking bars to stop playing music at midnight on the weekend as partygoers burst into chants of "Ruto must go" and "Reject finance bill."</p>

<p>Their demonstrations have drawn support from some Anglican and Catholic church leaders.</p>

<p><strong>- Debt mountain -</strong></p>

<p>The cash-strapped government agreed last week to roll back several tax increases.</p>

<p>But it still intends to raise other taxes, saying they are necessary for filling the state coffers and cutting reliance on external borrowing.</p>

<p>Kenya has a huge debt mountain whose servicing costs have ballooned because of a fall in the value of the local currency over the last two years, making interest payments on foreign-currency loans more expensive.</p>

<p>The tax hikes will pile further pressure on Kenyans, with well-paid jobs remaining out of reach for many young people.</p>

<p>After the government agreed to scrap levies on bread purchases, car ownership and financial and mobile services, the treasury warned of a budget shortfall of 200 billion shillings ($1.56 billion).</p>

<p>The government now intends to target an increase in fuel prices and export taxes to fill the void left by the changes, a move critics say will make life more expensive in a country already saddled with high inflation.</p>

<p>Kenya has one of the most dynamic economies in East Africa but a third of its 52 million people live in poverty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/flna2alo_kenya-protests_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several have been wounded in police firing, Amnesty International said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: What Pilot Does After Plane's Canopy Bursts Open Mid-Air]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:42:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a dangerous situation during her aerobatic training flight when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a frightening situation when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air. A video she shared on social media showed the terrifying moment Melkumjan grappled to maintain control of her Extra 330LX aircraft.</p>

<p>Melkumjan, on her second aerobatic training flight a couple of years ago, appeared visibly distraught in the clip, toiling to keep her eyes open against the wind. After the canopy, a transparent enclosure that protects the cockpit of an aircraft, unexpectedly burst open, she applied all her skills to land the two-seater safely.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">*PLEASE MIND WHEN WATCHING. AT 2:17 MINUTE MARK VIDEO FOOTAGE BECOMES RATHER INTENSE*<br />
<br />
A couple of years ago during my second aerobatic training flight of that day, on a very hot summer day, the canopy of the Extra 330LX that I was flying opened in flight and shattered. As you… <a href="https://t.co/nLhvDqVnII">pic.twitter.com/nLhvDqVnII</a></p>
— Narine Melkumjan (@NarineMelkumjan) <a href="https://twitter.com/NarineMelkumjan/status/1804507833506931086?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Reflecting on the ordeal, Melkumjan acknowledged that the experience could have been avoided had she conducted proper pre-flight checks.</p>

<p>She admitted that the canopy locking pin was not properly secured before takeoff.</p>

<p>“I also made the mistake of going to the training camp right after recovering from COVID, without allowing my body enough time to fully regain strength. Additionally, flying without any eye protection made the flight even more challenging than it already was,” she wrote in a lengthy post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She said she experienced some “buffet and controllability challenges,” revealing the “most difficult part was to keep the power in, thus trading my vision and breathing for kinetic energy.”</p>

<p>Amid the chaos, communication with her coach became almost impossible due to the noise, yet she distinctly remembered the crucial advice – "Just keep flying."</p>

<p>She described the distressing aftermath, including the overwhelming noise, difficulties breathing and impaired visibility that followed.</p>

<p>"It took me nearly 28 hours to fully recover my vision," Melkumjan revealed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Melkumjan, known for her frequent posts of flying videos on social media, revealed that sharing the footage of her dramatic flight served as a "cautionary tale" for other pilots and that she regretted not sharing it sooner.</p>

<p>“If you are a pilot watching this, I hope that my story serves as a cautionary tale and that you will learn from my mistakes,” she wrote.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/28rqijuo_plane-canopy-opens_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narine Melkumjan was on her second aerobatic training flight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctic-study-reveals-tipping-point-for-runaway-melting-of-ice-sheets-5967122]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Antarctic Study Reveals "Tipping Point" For Runaway Melting Of Ice Sheets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antarctic-study-reveals-tipping-point-for-runaway-melting-of-ice-sheets-5967122]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:36:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have discovered a new tipping point toward "runaway melting" of Antarctic ice sheets, caused by warm ocean water intruding between the ice and the land it sits on, according to a study published on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have discovered a new tipping point toward "runaway melting" of Antarctic ice sheets, caused by warm ocean water intruding between the ice and the land it sits on, according to a study published on Tuesday.</p>

<p>While this type of melting has been previously studied, models used by the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) to project the impact of global warming on the Antarctic have yet to factor in this phenomenon.</p>

<p>They have also systematically underestimated ice loss seen thus far, said the study, published in the journal Nature Geoscience.</p>

<p>As ocean temperatures rise due to human-caused global warming, Antarctic ice sheets are melting, threatening a rise in global sea levels and putting coastal communities at risk.</p>

<p>"Increases in ocean temperature can lead to a tipping point being passed, beyond which ocean water intrudes in an unbounded manner beneath the ice sheet, via a process of runaway melting," the study said.</p>

<p>Antarctic ice sheets sit atop the bedrock and extend beyond the coast to float on the sea.</p>

<p>Previous studies have shown that warm seawater is seeping into the "grounding zone" -- where land and ice meet -- and further inland from under the floating ice.</p>

<p>As the water warms, even by a fraction, the intrusion accelerates from short distances of 100 metres (330 feet) to tens of kilometres (miles), melting ice along the way by heating it from below, explained the study's lead author Alexander Bradley.</p>

<p>"Every 10th of a degree (of warming) makes these kind of processes closer, these tipping points closer," said Bradley, a researcher with the British Antarctic Survey.</p>

<p>The risk to sea-level rise comes when the accelerated melting outpaces the formation of new ice on the continent.</p>

<p>Some areas of Antarctica are more vulnerable to this process than others due to the shape of the land mass, which has valleys and cavities where sea water can pool beneath the ice.</p>

<p>The Pine Island glacier, currently Antarctica's largest contributor to sea-level rise, is at high risk of melting due to the slope of the land that allows in more seawater, the study said.</p>

<p>Scientific models need to be updated to take into account the element of melt to better predict the risk of sea-level rise in the future and prepare for it, Bradley said.</p>

<p>"And it really just stresses the need for urgent climate action in order to prevent these tipping points from being passed," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/h4p22gho_antarctic-ice_625x300_25_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ocean temperatures rise due to human-caused global warming. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delay-in-starliners-return-adds-to-doubts-whistleblowers-make-a-big-claim-5967062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Is Indian-Origin Astronaut Sunita Williams Stuck In Space?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delay-in-starliners-return-adds-to-doubts-whistleblowers-make-a-big-claim-5967062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:29:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is stuck on the International Space Station (ISS) after glitches were found in the Boeing spaceship they travelled in.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is stuck on the International Space Station (ISS) after glitches were found in the Boeing spaceship they travelled in. Earlier set to return on June 26, it's not known now when the astronauts will attempt their journey back to the earth.</p>

<p>The Boeing Starliner, which is on its maiden trip, has been facing a series of glitches that had delayed its launch twice. The constant delays have raised doubts, but what aggravates their troubles are allegations that the issues with the spaceship were known beforehand.</p>

<p>The ISS is a "mini city in space" about the size of a football field that astronauts from multiple space agencies use for research.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore reached there on June 5 and were set to start their return journey on June 26. NASA, the space agency of US, confirmed on June 22 it had extended Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore's stay on the space station.</p>

<p>The Starliner had five helium leaks and five of its 28 thrusters were having issues, NDTV had reported two days ago. Experts say at least 14 thrusters are needed for a safe return.</p>

<p>Steve Stich, manager of NASA's commercial crew program, said the spaceship was performing well while docked to the space station and they were using the extra time to clear a path for some critical station activities while preparing for the two astronauts' departure.</p>

<p>Ms Williams, who is on her third space trip, had earlier described it a "fantastic spacecraft".</p>

<p>But allegations of neglect continue against Boeing.</p>

<p>Whistleblowers have alleged that Boeing and NASA managers involved in the mission knew of the technical faults with the Starliner, but went ahead as they considered was issues were too minor to further delay its launch.</p>

<p>At least 20 whistleblowers have now accused NASA of being casual about the issues and ignoring their concerns since the beginning, according to multiple reports.</p>

<p>Whistleblowers had raised safety allegations against Boeing in the past too.</p>

<p>Santiago Paredes, a former quality inspector at Spirit, told BBC earlier this month that plane bodies made by them regularly left their factory with serious defects. When he flagged his concerns, he was mocked for slowing down their production, he claimed.</p>

<p>Spirit AeroSystems, the Kansas-based company, "strong disagreed" with the allegation.</p>

<p>Boeing CEO David Calhoun too had defended his firm, telling a recent Congressional hearing, "we are proud of our safety record."</p>

<p><strong>Other Concerns For Starliner</strong></p>

<p>What adds to the concerns is that the astronauts have only 27 days of fuel left for the return voyage, according to a Business Today report. But NASA says they are not pressed for time to leave the station since they have enough supplies in the orbit.</p>

<p>Another headache for the residents of ISS is a "superbug" - a multi-drug resistant bacteria named 'Enterobacter bugandensis', which has evolved to be more potent in the closed environment of the ISS. The bacteria affects the respiratory system.</p>

<p>Boeing had also faced issues while manufacturing the Starliner, ending up spending about $5.7 million against its $4.2 billion contract.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hfqb9ep_sunita-williams-on-iss_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Boeing Starliner is on its maiden trip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elated-wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-wife-on-landmark-plea-deal-5966956]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Elated": WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange's Wife On Landmark Plea Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elated-wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-wife-on-landmark-plea-deal-5966956]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:12:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's wife Stella said she was "elated" that he will be a "free man" after a US judge signs off on his landmark plea deal on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's wife Stella said she was "elated" that he will be a "free man" after a US judge signs off on his landmark plea deal on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Stella Assange said the end of the years-long legal drama that saw him board a plane from London to Bangkok on Monday had been a "whirlwind of emotions".</p>

<p>"I'm just elated. Frankly, it's just incredible," the South African-born rights campaigner told BBC radio.</p>

<p>"We weren't really sure until the last 24 hours that it was actually happening."</p>

<p>Assange was on Monday freed on bail from a high-security prison in southeast London ahead of a plea hearing expected to take place in remote US territory.</p>

<p>He had been held in jail for five years as he fought extradition to the United States which sought to prosecute him for revealing military secrets.</p>

<p>He has agreed to plead guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information, according to a document filed in court in the Northern Mariana Islands in the Pacific where the hearing is expected to take place.</p>

<p>Stella Assange said the plea deal involved her husband pleading guilty to the single charge.</p>

<p>"The charge concerns the Espionage Act and obtaining and disclosing national defence information," she said.</p>

<p>"The important thing here is that the deal involved time served, that if he signed it, he would be able to walk free," she added.</p>

<p>- Extradition call to be withdrawn -</p>

<p>A charter plane flew the 52-year-old Australian publisher from London to Bangkok, where it made a scheduled stop to refuel.</p>

<p>From there it is set to fly to Saipan, the capital of the US territory where Assange is due in court on Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>"What there is, is an agreement in principle between Julian and the Department of Justice, and that has to be signed off by a judge in these Northern Mariana territories... in the Pacific Ocean where he is going to be headed," she said.</p>

<p>"He will be a free man once it has been signed off... and that will happen some time tomorrow."</p>

<p>Assange is later due to return to Australia under the deal.</p>

<p>Stephen Parkinson, chief prosecutor at Britain's Crown Prosecution Service (CPS), said a court hearing paving the way for Assange's departure was held last Thursday.</p>

<p>It was held in private at Assange's request, he said.</p>

<p>"Thirteen-and-a-half years and two extradition requests after he was first arrested, Julian Assange left the UK yesterday," he said.</p>

<p>The CPS said that since March it had worked closely with the UK's National Crime Agency to help put in place "the necessary practical arrangements to enable Mr Assange to leave the jurisdiction safely, and in accordance with his wishes and those of the US government".</p>

<p>"Following the sentencing by the US Federal Judge, the government of the USA is expected to formally withdraw the extradition request, bringing the English extradition proceedings to a formal and immediate conclusion," a CPS statement added.</p>

<p>Stella Assange told Britain's domestic Press Association news agency that her husband was paying $500,000 (£390,000) for the flights taking him from London to Australia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3pumrucg_julian-assange-2024-afp_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Stella Assange said the plea deal involved her husband pleading guilty to the single charge. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-meta-ai-google-gemini-what-technology-powers-chatgpt-google-gemini-and-meta-ai-5966894]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Tech That Powers ChatGPT, Google Gemini And Meta AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/chatgpt-meta-ai-google-gemini-what-technology-powers-chatgpt-google-gemini-and-meta-ai-5966894]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:04:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI Explainer:  Understanding how Large Language Models (LLMs) are responsible for running ChatGPT, Gemini and the most recently launched in India- Meta AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered how ChatGPT works? The short answer to this complex question lies in Large Language Models or LLMs which are foundational models that are trained using large amounts of textual data. These models do not process words as humans do. They instead use a long series of numbers, representing a single word. This data is fed to computers in the form of Word Vectors.</p>

<p>These sequences of numbers are known as Word Vectors and can be imagined as a single point in an imaginary space, with words that have similar meaning placed closer to each other. The scale of each model is massive and almost impossible to envision, but for reference, GPT4 has a staggering 1.76 trillion parameters, with millions of unique word vectors, according to a June 28, 2023 report by SemiAnalysis, a US-based independent AI research and analysis company. Processing such a huge number of vectors with trillions of parameters has been possible due to the dramatic advancement of computing power over the last few years. Most recently, on June 19, Nvidia became the largest public company in the world based on market capitalisation, surpassing Microsoft and Apple, as a result of surging demand on their AI capable chipsets.</p>

<p>ChatGPT, Google Gemini and Meta AI are all LLMs that work by predicting the next word, using word vectors. This prediction is done by transforming word vectors fed by the user as "prompts" into predictions, using Transformers.</p>

<p><strong>How Is Text Prediction Done In LLMs?</strong></p>

<p>LLMs are multi-layered. Each layer consists of a neural network architecture (imagine artificial neurons) known as transformers. These transformers process the input text - each word vector individually - and inside each transformer, words in the form of vectors look around and interact for relevant information. This process is repeated over and over again, not just for a single prompt, but even for the next time a user feeds a prompt with similar words into the LLMs. This enables efficiency in the future searches for better prediction of "the next word' in the sequence.</p>

<p><strong>How Are LLMs Trained?</strong></p>

<p>LLMs are trained using unsupervised learning, eliminating the need for human labelling of data. Data from web pages, books, and other textual sources is used to feed LLMs before going public. These have also courted controversy as it reflected human biases in some cases. Most notably, Microsoft's Twitter Chatbot Tay, Google's Gemini and OpenAI's Sora (text-to-video converter) have courted controversy over the years for giving bigoted, racial and gender discriminatory responses. To its credit, the industry has responded to the challenge and is constantly evolving to negate human biases from LLMs.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/g3gv78ps_artificial-intelligence-generic-pixabay_625x300_11_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[ChatGPT, Google Gemini and Meta AI are all LLMs that work by predicting the next word, using word vectors]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-kills-her-2-children-because-she-didnt-want-husband-to-have-them-5966439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Kills Her 2 Children "Because She Didn't Want Husband To Have Them"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-kills-her-2-children-because-she-didnt-want-husband-to-have-them-5966439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the trial-of-facts hearing, it was revealed that Mrs John stabbed Ethan over 20 times and caused brain damage to her daughter Elizabeth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman named Veronique John, 50, dialled 999 and confessed "I just killed my two kids" after stabbing them with a knife, Nottingham Crown Court was told. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/article/2024/jun/24/mother-killed-her-two-children-and-stabbed-husband-after-erupting-in-rage"><em>Guardian</em></a>, Mrs John killed her 7-year-old daughter Elizabeth and 11-year-old son Ethan because she did not want her husband to have their custody.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She stabbed her son, Ethan, more than 20 times and inflicted brain damage on her daughter, Elizabeth, before tracking down her husband, Nathan John, and stabbing him in the stomach.</p>

<p>During the trial-of-facts hearing, it was revealed that Mrs John stabbed Ethan over 20 times and caused brain damage to her daughter Elizabeth. She then went to a car wash wearing a dressing gown and stabbed her partner, Nathan John, in the stomach.</p>

<p>She then returned home, dialled 999 and said: "I am calling to report I just killed my two kids."</p>

<p>The charity shop worker allegedly told police who arrived at her Stoke-on-Trent home on June 11 last year, "If you have a gun, shoot me. I am not a monster - he was going to take them from me."</p>

<p>The day before the fatal attacks, John was arrested for assaulting her husband with a piece of wood while their children were getting ready for bed, suspecting him of having an affair.</p>

<p>The court heard that John and her husband had significant difficulties in their relationship, and she did not want him to have an internet-enabled phone.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Peter Grieves-Smith stated that Mrs John's "rage was boiling just under the surface" in the hours leading up to the children's deaths.</p>

<p>"What happened on 11 June didn't come out of the blue. Tension grew in the days before. That day she just erupted, killed her children and attacked Nathan," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Grieves-Smith stated that Mrs John killed her children just hours after conducting a "chilling" internet search, asking, "Can a foreigner be charged with murder in the UK?"</p>

<p>Ethan was pronounced dead after being found in a bedroom with a 17cm-long neck wound, while Elizabeth was discovered in the living room with head trauma and "three areas of sharp force," including one to her stomach.</p>

<p>The jury heard that a neighbour reported hearing "high-pitched screaming and crying that lasted for a little while" just minutes before John walked to the car wash where her husband had stayed the night.</p>

<p>The court heard how the 50-year-old later told interviewing officers: "I didn't want my husband to get them [the children]."</p>

<p>She continued: "It's something I was thinking about for a long time - just kill myself and the kids. Unless you guys are offering me the death penalty I have nothing else to say.</p>

<p>"I did it because I love my children - to protect the children. If there's any possible way I could be put to death, I would like that. I mean it 100%."</p>

<p>Mrs John is charged with two counts of murder, attempted murder and an alternative count of wounding, but has been ruled unfit to plead, Sky News reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She is currently being treated at a secure hospital and was not present in the dock to hear the Crown's opening statement.</p>

<p>The trial is ongoing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/dpt9q2q8_arrest-generic-istock-650_625x300_23_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court heard that Mrs John and her husband had difficulties in their relationship]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-air-strike-kills-10-family-members-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-gaza-officials-5966327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Air Strike Kills 10 Family Members Of Hamas Chief: Gaza Officials]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-air-strike-kills-10-family-members-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-gaza-officials-5966327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 15:51:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli air strike early Tuesday killed 10 family members of Hamas's Qatar-based chief Ismail Haniyeh, including his sister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli air strike early Tuesday killed 10 family members of Hamas's Qatar-based chief Ismail Haniyeh, including his sister.</p>

<p>The Israeli military, which is on a campaign to destroy Hamas over the October 7 attack, told AFP that it "was aware of the reports but we cannot confirm" them.</p>

<p>The strike hit the Haniyeh family home in the Al-Shati refugee camp, in the northern Gaza Strip, said Mahmud Basal, spokesman for the Hamas-ruled territory's civil defence.</p>

<p>"There are 10 martyrs... as a result of the strike, including Zahr Haniyeh, sister of Hamas political bureau chief Ismail Haniyeh," Basal told AFP.</p>

<p>He said a number of bodies were likely still under the rubble but "we do not have the necessary equipment" to extract them.</p>

<p>Civil defence crews transferred the bodies to Al-Ahli hospital in nearby Gaza City, Basal added, also reporting "several wounded" in the attack.</p>

<p>Hamas, the Islamist terrorist group that rules Gaza, is considered a terrorist organisation by Israel and key Western allies, including the United States.</p>

<p>Hamas in a statement named the Haniyeh family home as being bombed in a list of "massacres" it said were committed by Israel in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>It said the alleged bombing showed Israel "continues to defy all international laws, human norms and values by deliberately targeting innocent civilians and committing the most horrific massacres against them".</p>

<p>Haniyeh lost three sons and four grandchildren in an Israeli strike in April in central Gaza, with the military accusing them of "terrorist activities".</p>

<p>Haniyeh at the time said that about 60 members of his family had been killed since the war broke out on October 7.</p>

<p>The war began after Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's withering air, land and sea campaign since then has killed at least 37,626 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to the territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/jq2p0l6g_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike hit the Haniyeh family home in the Al-Shati refugee camp. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sedentary-non-coffee-drinkers-at-60-more-risk-of-dying-study-finds-5965600]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sedentary, Non-Coffee Drinkers At 60% More Risk Of Dying, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sedentary-non-coffee-drinkers-at-60-more-risk-of-dying-study-finds-5965600]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 15:45:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Non-coffee drinkers who sat for six or more hours a day were at almost 60 per cent higher risk of dying compared to coffee drinkers sitting for less than six hours, according to a research.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Non-coffee drinkers who sat for six or more hours a day were at almost 60 per cent higher risk of dying compared to coffee drinkers sitting for less than six hours, according to a research published in the journal BioMed Central (BMC) Public Health.</p>

<p>This indicated an increased risk of dying in sedentary people not consuming coffee, but not among those drinking coffee, researchers following over 10,000 adults in the US for up to 13 years said.</p>

<p>The researchers at the Medical College of Soochow University's School of Public Health in China also found that sedentary coffee drinkers were at a 24 per cent lower risk of death compared to non-coffee drinkers sitting for at least six hours a day.</p>

<p>The result, not featuring in the study, was calculated at The Washington Post's request, according to the media website's report.</p>

<p>"The benefits of coffee consumption in improving overall survival in adults compared to sedentary behaviour are manifold," the authors wrote in the study.</p>

<p>Consuming coffee lowers risk of metabolic problems known to worsen inflammation, which contributes to heightening death risks because of sedentary behaviour, they said.</p>

<p>In their study, the authors found that the risk of dying from any cause significantly lowered -- by 33 per cent -- among a fourth of all the participants consuming highest amounts of coffee compared to non-coffee drinkers.</p>

<p>The results were consistent with those from previous studies, which have found a link between drinking more coffee and a lowered risk of dying from any cause and heart disease, they said.</p>

<p>Compounds present in coffee, including caffeine and polyphenols, are anti-inflammatory in nature. However, how exactly coffee works in the body to lower risk of dying is still unclear, the researchers said.</p>

<p>Further, the team also found that sitting for more than eight hours a day was linked with over 40 per cent higher risk of death from any cause and almost 80 per cent higher risk of dying due to heart disease.</p>

<p>For their analysis, the researchers used data from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES), which follows Americans' health and nutrition.</p>

<p>"Given that coffee is a complex compound, further research is needed to explore this miracle compound," the authors wrote.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/nmu4jtlo_laptop-generic_625x300_03_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Non-coffee drinkers who sit for six or more hours a day are at 60% higher risk of dying]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-top-court-rules-army-must-draft-ultra-orthodox-jewish-students-5965827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Top Court Rules Army Must Draft Ultra-Orthodox Jewish Students]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-top-court-rules-army-must-draft-ultra-orthodox-jewish-students-5965827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:46:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Supreme Court ruled on Tuesday that the government must draft ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students to the conscript military, a decree likely to send shockwaves through Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's coalition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Supreme Court ruled on Tuesday that the government must draft ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students to the conscript military, a decree likely to send shockwaves through Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's coalition.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's coalition relies for its survival on two ultra-Orthodox parties that regard longstanding conscription exemptions as key to keeping their constituents in religious seminaries and away from a melting-pot military that might test their conservative customs.</p>

<p>The ultra-Orthodox conscription waiver has become especially charged as Israel's armed forces, made up mostly of teenage conscripts and older civilians mobilised for reserve duty, are overstretched by a multi-front war, in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>"At the height of a difficult war, the burden of inequality is more than ever acute," the court's unanimous ruling said.</p>

<p>Most Israelis are bound by law to serve in the military, whereas ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students have been largely exempt for decades.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/58dhodfo_israel-ultraorthodox-jewish-students-reuters-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Most Israelis, except the ultra-Orthodox Jewish students, have been law-bound to serve in the military.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-hajj-routes-claim-hundreds-of-lives-a-grave-warning-to-pilgrims-5965749]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Illegal Hajj Routes Claim Hundreds Of Lives: A Grave Warning To Pilgrims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-hajj-routes-claim-hundreds-of-lives-a-grave-warning-to-pilgrims-5965749]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:35:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of people died during this year's Hajj pilgrimage due to the extreme heat in Mecca with temperatures soaring past 50 degrees Celsius.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of people died during this year's Hajj pilgrimage due to the extreme heat in Mecca with temperatures soaring past 50 degrees Celsius. An alarming 83% of these victims were those who took illegal routes, highlighting the perilous risks involved with the pilgrimage.</p>

<p>The Saudi government disclosed that many of the victims had paid exorbitant sums to illegal tour operators, hoping to circumvent official channels. Instead of being transported comfortably in air-conditioned buses and housed in safe, regulated accommodations, these pilgrims found themselves exposed to the scorching desert heat, walking for miles amid extreme heat.</p>

<p><strong>What Are Hajj Permits</strong></p>

<p>The Hajj is one of the five pillars of Islam that all Muslims with the means must complete at least once in their lives.</p>

<p>Hajj permits are allocated to countries on a quota system and distributed to individuals by lottery.</p>

<p>Why Do Pilgrims Take Illegal Routes?</p>

<p>Cost: Some experts say that travelling without a permit is a cheaper alternative to official permits, each of which can cost thousands of dollars.</p>

<p>Convenience: Others seek to avoid lengthy application processes and waiting lists.</p>

<p>Lack of awareness: Some pilgrims may be unaware of the risks and legal requirements.</p>

<p>What Are The Risks Associated With Illegal Hajj Visit</p>

<p>Physical harm: Pilgrims may face harsh desert conditions, dehydration, and exhaustion while traversing treacherous terrain.</p>

<p>Arrest and deportation: Those caught taking illegal routes may be detained, fined, and deported.</p>

<p>Health risks: Unverified vaccinations and medical screenings increase the risk of contracting and spreading diseases.</p>

<p>Exploitation: Pilgrims may fall prey to human traffickers, scams, and extortion.</p>

<p>What Is The Government Doing</p>

<p>On Saturday, Egyptian Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouly ordered 16 tourism companies stripped of their licences and referred their managers to the public prosecutor over illegal pilgrimages to Mecca, Egypt's cabinet said.</p>

<p>It said the rise in the number of deaths of unregistered Egyptian pilgrims stemmed from some companies which "organised the Hajj programmes using a personal visit visa, which prevents its holders from entering Mecca" via official channels.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/e1r8ouk8_hajj-afp_625x300_28_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-fresh-israeli-airstrikes-kill-24-in-gaza-as-tanks-deepen-incursion-into-rafah-5965552]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes Kill 24 In Gaza As Tanks Deepen Incursion Into Rafah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-fresh-israeli-airstrikes-kill-24-in-gaza-as-tanks-deepen-incursion-into-rafah-5965552]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:05:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces killed at least 24 Palestinians in three separate airstrikes on Gaza City early on Tuesday, health officials said, while tanks deepened their incursion into the town of Rafah in the south of the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces killed at least 24 Palestinians in three separate airstrikes on Gaza City early on Tuesday, health officials said, while tanks deepened their incursion into the town of Rafah in the south of the enclave.</p>

<p>Two of the strikes hit two schools in Gaza City, killing at least 14 people, medics said. Another strike on a house in the Shati (Beach) camp, one of the Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps, killed 10 others.</p>

<p>The house in Shati belonged to the extended family of Hamas political chief, Ismail Haniyeh, who is based in Qatar, killing one of his sisters along with other relatives too, family members and medics said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh, who leads Hamas' diplomacy and is the public face of the group that has been running Gaza, has lost many of his relatives in Israeli air strikes since Oct. 7, including three of his sons.</p>

<p>Israel's military said its forces had targeted militants overnight in Gaza City who had been involved in the planning of attacks on Israel. The operatives included some involved in holding hostages captive and some who had taken part in Hamas' cross-border attack on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>The Israeli Air Force struck two structures "used by Hamas terrorists in Shati and Daraj Tuffah in the northern Gaza Strip. The terrorists operated inside school compounds that were used by Hamas as a shield for its terrorist activities", the military statement said.</p>

<p>Hamas denies using civilian facilities such as schools and hospitals for military purposes.</p>

<p>More than eight months into the fighting, international mediation backed by the United States has so far failed to bring a ceasefire agreement. Hamas says any agreement must bring an end to the war, while Israel says it will agree to only temporary pauses in fighting until Hamas is eradicated.</p>

<p>SHORTAGES OF MEDICINE</p>

<p>Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza was triggered when Hamas-led operatives stormed into southern Israel on Oct. 7, killing around 1,200 people and seizing more than 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The Israeli offensive in retaliation has killed almost 37,600 people, according to Palestinian health authorities, and has left the tiny, densely populated Gaza Strip in ruins.</p>

<p>Gaza's health ministry said on Tuesday that hospitals and medical centres in the enclave were experiencing a severe shortage of medicines and medical supplies due to the continued Israeli offensive, Israel's control and closure of all crossings and its targeting of the health sector in Gaza.</p>

<p>In particularly short supply are medications needed for emergency, anaesthesia, intensive care and operations, the ministry said in a statement, while cancer patients were unable to travel to hospitals.</p>

<p>Since early May, fighting has focused on Rafah, on Gaza's southern edge abutting the border with Egypt, where around half of the enclave's 2.3 million people have been sheltering after fleeing other areas.</p>

<p>Residents said fierce fighting had taken place overnight in western areas of Rafah, where tanks have extended their incursion in recent days, blowing up several homes in the area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bdgi79g8_israel-airstrike-on-gaza-reuters_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza's health ministry said that hospitals and medical centres are experiencing a shortage of medicines.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hr-employee-in-singapore-jailed-for-giving-herself-148-000-in-unauthorised-pay-raise-5965425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore HR Jailed For Giving Herself $148,000 In Unauthorised Pay Raise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hr-employee-in-singapore-jailed-for-giving-herself-148-000-in-unauthorised-pay-raise-5965425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:48:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A human resource employee in Singapore has been jailed for 18 months for making bogus pay claims for herself involving $148,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A human resource employee in Singapore has been jailed for 18 months for making bogus pay claims for herself involving $148,000. According to the <em>South China Morning Post (SCMP)</em>, Tan Lee Nah, 53, was in charge of the payroll system at D'Perception Singapore, an interior design firm. In May 2017, just two months after joining the company, she started to submit false claims for expenses, up until she was caught in November 2019. In these 2.5 years, she managed to give herself $148,000 in unauthorised pay rise to fund her child's tuition fee and her parent's medical bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3265427/singapore-hr-boss-jailed-giving-herself-us148000-fake-pay-rises-fund-childs-tuition"><em>SCMP</em></a>, a judge said that Ms Tan treated the company's coffers like her "personal piggy bank". The court found that she claimed false travel expenses, ranging from $750 to $7,300 each month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From January to November 2019, she added mobile phone expenses, paid holiday allowances and some extra expenses to her claims. In 2017, she was asked to transfer money to the Central Provident Fund (CPF) as two month's contributions for a new employee. However, she misappropriated the cheques and put them in her account, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Tan was the sole person with the password to the company's payroll system, and it was routine practice for her to input all the staff's salaries into the system.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/contact-me-if-thief-in-china-leaves-note-for-owner-after-stealing-watch-and-laptop-5965077">"Contact Me If...": Thief In China Leaves Note For Owner After Stealing Watch And Laptop</a></strong></p>

<p>Her scheme was exposed when an employee saw a copy of Ms Tan's salary statement on the printer, which showed she had received allowances in addition to her basic salary. The employee alerted the management which then launched an investigation and called the police a month later.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 53-year-old told the court that the money she had misappropriated was spent on her child's education and her parents' medical bills. She pleaded guilty on June 3 this year to two charges of sham reimbursement and one of criminal breach of trust for cashing two cheques. She had not compensated her employer because she lacked the financial means to do so.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/jail-generic_650x400_61469651050.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The employee pleaded guilty on June 3 this year. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>