<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:19:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-rover-discovers-evidence-of-3-42-billion-years-old-ocean-on-mars-6967539]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Rover Discovers Evidence Of 3.42 Billion Years Old Ocean On Mars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-rover-discovers-evidence-of-3-42-billion-years-old-ocean-on-mars-6967539]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:14:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Like Earth and our solar system's other planets, Mars formed about 4.5 billion years ago. At the time the ocean apparently existed, it might already have begun its transition away from being a hospitable planet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the assistance of China's Zhurong rover, scientists have gathered fresh evidence that Mars was home to an ocean billions of years ago - a far cry from the dry and desolate world it is today.</p>

<p>Scientists said on Thursday that data obtained by Zhurong, which landed in the northern lowlands of Mars in 2021, and by orbiting spacecraft indicated the presence of geological features indicative of an ancient coastline. The rover analyzed rock on the Martian surface in a location called Utopia Planitia, a large plain in the planet's northern hemisphere.</p>

<p>The researchers said data from China's Tianwen-1 Orbiter, NASA's Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, and the robotic six-wheeled rover indicated the existence of a water ocean during a period when Mars might already have become cold and dry and lost much of its atmosphere.</p>

<p>They described surface features such as troughs, sediment channels, and mud volcano formations indicative of a coastline, with evidence of both shallow and deeper marine environments.</p>

<p>"We estimate the flooding of the Utopia Planitia on Mars was approximately 3.68 billion years ago. The ocean surface was likely frozen in a geologically short period," said Hong Kong Polytechnic University planetary scientist Bo Wu, lead author of the study published in the journal Scientific Reports.</p>

<p>The ocean appears to have disappeared by approximately 3.42 billion years ago, the researchers said.</p>

<p>"The water was heavily silted, forming the layering structure of the deposits," Hong Kong Polytechnic University planetary scientist and study co-author Sergey Krasilnikov added.</p>

<p>Like Earth and our solar system's other planets, Mars formed about 4.5 billion years ago. At the time the ocean apparently existed, it might already have begun its transition away from being a hospitable planet.</p>

<p>"The presence of an ancient ocean on Mars has been proposed and studied for several decades, yet significant uncertainty remains," Wu said. "These findings not only provide further evidence to support the theory of a Martian ocean but also present, for the first time, a discussion on its probable evolutionary scenario."</p>

<p>Water is seen as a key ingredient for life, and the past presence of an ocean raises the prospect that Mars at least at one time was capable of harboring microbial life.</p>

<p>"At the beginning of Mars' history, when it probably had a thick, warm atmosphere, microbial life was much more likely," Krasilnikov said.</p>

<p>The solar-powered Zhurong, named after a mythical Chinese god of fire, began its work using six scientific instruments on the Martian surface in May 2021 and went into hibernation in May 2022, likely met with excessive accumulation of sand and dust, according to its mission designer. It exceeded its original mission time span of three months.</p>

<p>Researchers have sought to better understand what happened to all the water that once was present on the Martian surface. Another study, published in August and based on seismic data obtained by NASA's robotic InSight lander, indicated that an immense reservoir of liquid water may reside deep under the surface within fractured igneous rocks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hpdbto7g_ocean-on-mars_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ocean appears to have disappeared by approximately 3.42 billion years ago.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-will-assure-peaceful-orderly-transfer-of-power-to-donald-trump-6967491]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says Will Ensure "Peaceful, Orderly" Transfer Of Power To Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-says-will-assure-peaceful-orderly-transfer-of-power-to-donald-trump-6967491]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 22:09:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden says will assure "peaceful, orderly" transfer of power to Donald Trump]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden says he will ensure "peaceful, orderly" transfer of power to Donald Trump</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sl4h4vcg_biden_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-vaticans-congratulatory-message-for-trump-a-wish-for-wisdom-6967167]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Vatican's Congratulatory Message For Trump, A Wish For "Wisdom"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-vaticans-congratulatory-message-for-trump-a-wish-for-wisdom-6967167]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:17:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Vatican's secretary of state congratulated US president-elect Donald Trump Thursday, while expressing doubt that the Republican had a "magic wand" to end conflicts quickly as promised during the campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Vatican's secretary of state congratulated US president-elect Donald Trump Thursday, while expressing doubt that the Republican had a "magic wand" to end conflicts quickly as promised during the campaign.</p>

<p>"We wish him a lot of wisdom because that is the main virtue of leaders according to the Bible," Italian Cardinal Pietro Parolin told reporters on the sidelines of a conference in Rome.</p>

<p>Asked about Trump's promise to end the war in Ukraine "within 24 hours", Parolin replied: "Let's hope, let's hope. I believe that not even he has a magic wand."</p>

<p>"To end wars, a lot of humility is needed, a lot of willingness is needed, it really is necessary to seek the general interests of humanity rather than concentrate on particular interests," he said.</p>

<p>To overcome divisions in American society, Parolin said he hoped Trump would be "the president of the whole country".</p>

<p>He also hoped he would be "a factor that reduces tension... in the current conflicts that are bloodying the world."</p>

<p>Parolin's comments were the first diplomatic reaction from the Holy See to Trump's win for the White House against Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Pope Francis has not reacted.</p>

<p>In September, the Argentine pope criticised both candidates, accusing them of being "against life" in different ways: for Harris' support of abortion, and for Trump's anti-migrant policies.</p>

<p>During his first term in the White House, in May 2017, Trump was received by the Pope at the Vatican for a half-hour meeting.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/e59m21a8_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump was elected as the President of US against Kamala Harris.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/misprinted-1975-us-dime-sets-auction-record-sells-for-rs-4-crore-6967094]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Misprinted 1975 US Dime Sets Auction Record, Sells For Rs 4 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/misprinted-1975-us-dime-sets-auction-record-sells-for-rs-4-crore-6967094]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:05:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The rare 1975 No S Proof Dime set a new auction record, selling for $506,250 at GreatCollections, with bidders from around the world vying for the coin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A remarkable US coin, the '1975 No S Proof Dime', has set a new auction record, selling for $506,250&nbsp;(Rs 4,26,74,091) last night, according to GreatCollections auction house. The coin, known for its rarity, was released in error without the "S" mint mark, making it one of the most sought-after modern US coin rarities.</p>

<p>After being in private possession for over half a century, the 1975 dime was verified by the Professional Coin Grading Service (PCGS) and assigned the grade Proof-67. Additionally, the Certified Acceptance Corporation (CAC) approved it, according to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.greatcollections.com/kb/1975-No-S-Proof-Dime-Realizes-506250-at-GreatCollections-t652-4.html">news release.</a></p>

<p>According to Scott Schechter and Jeff Garrett's The 100 Greatest US Modern Coins, numismatic experts regularly rank the 1975 No S Proof Dime as the best modern US coin.</p>

<p>The coin was consigned to GreatCollections just two months ago after being acquired for $18,200 in 1978 by an Ohio collector and his mother from the famous Chicago dealer FJ Vollmer &amp; Co. The coin's status as a highly sought-after numismatic treasure has been cemented by the remarkable auction price, which represents over 30 times the amount paid for it 46 years ago.</p>

<p>"We received interest in this modern rarity from all over the world-serious collectors from Germany, Japan, and the UK, as well as collectors from the US-over 400 unique bidders were actively tracking the auction," GreatCollections President Ian Russell <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.greatcollections.com/kb/1975-No-S-Proof-Dime-Realizes-506250-at-GreatCollections-t652-4.html">said in a news release.</a></p>

<p>The dime is notable for its missing "S" mint mark, which would signify it was minted in San Francisco. It is only one of two examples known to still exist.</p>

<p>"This is the Grail of modern coins, one that is missing from the Smithsonian, ANS, and ANA institutional collections. After spirited bidding, it was ultimately won by a long-time client of ours who appreciates rarities that infrequently appear on the market. His goal is for his family to own it for the next 46 years, similar to the seller's family who consigned it to GreatCollections," Russell said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ldpkd6ag_the-proof-1975-dime_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The dime has more than tripled in value over 46 years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-offering-russia-concessions-on-ukraine-suicidal-zelensky-6967080]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Offering Russia Concessions On Ukraine "Suicidal": Zelensky]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-offering-russia-concessions-on-ukraine-suicidal-zelensky-6967080]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:03:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on Thursday said it would be "suicidal" for Europe to offer the Kremlin concessions to halt its invasion of Ukraine, after Moscow demanded the West enter direct talks on ending the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky on Thursday said it would be "suicidal" for Europe to offer the Kremlin concessions to halt its invasion of Ukraine, after Moscow demanded the West enter direct talks on ending the war.</p>

<p>Kyiv is scrambling to up the pressure on its allies for more support in its fight against Moscow following the victory of Donald Trump in this week's US presidential election.</p>

<p>Trump has boasted he could end the conflict within hours and repeatedly criticised American aid to Kyiv.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has demanded Ukraine cede swathes more territory in its east and south as a precondition to peace talks, while Kyiv has repeatedly ruled out ceding any land to Moscow in exchange for peace.</p>

<p>Ukraine and many in the West fear any settlement that rewards Putin would only embolden the Kremlin leader and lead to more aggression.</p>

<p>Speaking to European leaders at a summit in Hungary, Zelensky blasted those who were pressuring him to give in to some of Putin's hardline demands.</p>

<p>"There has been much talk about the need to yield to Putin, to back down, to make some concessions," Zelensky said, according to a copy of the address provided to AFP by the Ukrainian presidency.</p>

<p>"It's unacceptable for Ukraine and suicidal for all Europe," he added.</p>

<p>He also blasted some European leaders, without specifying who, of "strongly" pushing Ukraine to compromise.</p>

<p>"We need sufficient weapons, not support in talks. Hugs with Putin won't help. Some of you have been hugging him for 20 years, and things are only getting worse," Zelensky said.</p>

<h3><strong>'Choice'</strong></h3>

<p>Russia demanded earlier on Thursday that Kyiv's allies enter into negotiations with Moscow if they want to halt the brutish attacks on Ukrainians.</p>

<p>The head of Russia's Security Council Sergei Shoigu said the West faced a choice between opening direct talks with Moscow or the continuing "destruction" of Ukraine's population.</p>

<p>"Now, when the situation in the theatre of combat is not in Kyiv's favour, the West is faced with a choice," Shoigu said at a meeting with defence officials of other former Soviet states.</p>

<p>"To continue financing (Kyiv) and the destruction of the Ukrainian population or recognise the current realities and start negotiating," the former defence minister said.</p>

<p>They were among the first comments from a Russian official since Trump was confirmed to have been elected president of the United States.</p>

<p>Zelensky has previously said that without US aid, Ukraine would lose the war.</p>

<p>His outmanned and outgunned army is already on the backfoot in the eastern Donbas region, where Russian forces have been slowly advancing for months.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Moscow on Thursday said its forces had wrested control of Kreminna Balka, a village that had a pre-war population of fewer than 50 people in the industrial Donetsk region where Ukrainian defences have been pushed back again and again.</p>

<p>Ukraine meanwhile faced another night of aerial bombardments across the country, including on the capital Kyiv, ahead of what could be the country's toughest winter yet.</p>

<h3><strong>Overnight attacks</strong></h3>

<p>Ukrainian media reported that Donetsk region authorities were preparing to announce mandatory evacuations from seven more villages in the region that the Kremlin claimed in 2022 was part of Russia.</p>

<p>Moscow's overnight drone attack on Ukraine damaged buildings in the southern Black Sea city of Odesa where AFP journalists saw residents inspecting destroyed cars and residential buildings as dawn broke.</p>

<p>And at least three people were killed in the aerial attacks overnight and into Thursday -- one each in the Kherson, Sumy and Zaporizhzhia regions, according to local officials.</p>

<p>The air force said it had shot down 74 Russian-deployed drones in 11 different regions, out of a total of 106 drones launched by Moscow at Ukraine.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/guf7g9_zelensky_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky has previously said that without US aid, Ukraine would lose the war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-harris-paradox-the-us-elections-reveal-a-hidden-pattern-6967073]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Harris Paradox: The US Elections Reveal A Hidden Pattern]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-harris-paradox-the-us-elections-reveal-a-hidden-pattern-6967073]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:02:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In various states, Democratic Senate candidates outperformed Kamala Harris, despite her loss in the presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In various states, Democratic Senate candidates outperformed Kamala Harris, despite her loss in the presidential election.</p>

<p>Notably, Dan Osborn in Nebraska and Jon Tester in Montana had vote shares 7 points higher than Harris's, but still lost their respective races. In Arizona, Ruben Gallego's vote share was 4 points higher than Harris's and is currently leading. Colin Allred in Texas secured a 3-point higher vote share than Harris but failed to unseat Ted Cruz. Other notable performances include Jacky Rosen in Nevada, with a 2-point higher vote share, though the race remains too close to call, and Tammy Baldwin in Wisconsin, who won with a vote share less than 1 point higher than Harris's. Additionally, Elissa Slotkin in Michigan and Bob Casey in Pennsylvania had vote shares about 1 point higher than Harris' as of Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>According to a report by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/383197/kamala-harris-results-underperformed-democratic-senate-candidates">Vox</a>, these results suggest that voters are distinguishing between the presidential contest and statewide races, with some Democratic Senate candidates performing better than expected.</p>

<p>This distinction raises questions about the nature of the backlash against Democrats. Was it targeted at Harris specifically or reflective of a broader anti-Democratic sentiment?</p>

<p>In U.S. politics, it's common for candidates to hope that a popular presidential nominee will bring success to statewide races. This trickle-down effect can give their party a boost in other contests.</p>

<p>However, the phenomenon of ticket-splitting can sometimes ruin these plans. Ticket-splitting occurs when voters cast ballots for candidates from opposing parties in the same election.</p>

<p>Despite being rare in today's hyper-partisan climate, ticket-splitting still happens. Interestingly, even with a Republican White House victory, some state Democrats are managing to come out on top. This suggests that voters are making deliberate choices, rather than blindly voting along party lines.</p>

<p>In 2012, six states split their tickets in eight races. For example, Montana and Missouri elected Democrats to the governor's office and the Senate but voted for Republican Mitt Romney for president.</p>

<p>In 2016, five states split their tickets, voting for either a Republican governor or a Democratic governor alongside their presidential choice and only three states exhibited split-ticket voting in 2020.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4sb4k218_kamala-harris_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In various states, Democratic Senate candidates outperformed Kamala Harris]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-un-peacekeepers-injured-in-latest-israeli-airstrikes-on-lebanon-6966885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed, UN Peacekeepers Injured In Latest Israeli Airstrikes On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-un-peacekeepers-injured-in-latest-israeli-airstrikes-on-lebanon-6966885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Lebanese army said an Israeli strike on a vehicle near a checkpoint in the southern city of Sidon on Thursday killed three people and wounded troops and UN peacekeepers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Lebanese army said an Israeli strike on a vehicle near a checkpoint in the southern city of Sidon on Thursday killed three people and wounded troops and UN peacekeepers.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy targeted a car while it was passing through the Awali checkpoint," the main northern entrance to Sidon, the army said.</p>

<p>With the exception of a few limited strikes, Sidon, a Sunni Muslim-majority city, has been relatively spared the deadly air raids targeting south Lebanon in Israel's war against the Iran-backed Hezbollah movement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The strike killed three people, all of them passengers in the targeted vehicle, the army said.</p>

<p>Three Lebanese soldiers manning the checkpoint were also wounded alongside members of the Malaysian contingent of UNIFIL, according to the army.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UNIFIL peacekeeping force said a "convoy bringing newly-arrived peacekeepers to south Lebanon was passing Sidon when a drone strike occurred nearby."</p>

<p>"Five peacekeepers were lightly injured and treated by the Lebanese Red Cross on the spot. They will continue to their posts," it said, urging warring parties "to avoid actions putting peacekeepers or civilians in danger."</p>

<h3><strong>UNIFIL has thousands of peacekeepers&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency said a UNIFIL vehicle was on the "same lane" during the strike, which left UN peacekeepers with "minor injuries".&nbsp;</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent in the area saw the charred, mangled remains of the targeted vehicle which was only a few metres away from an army checkpoint.</p>

<p>The correspondent saw UNIFIL peacekeepers gathered on the sidewalk near the checkpoint, some of them bloodied and wounded after the raid, as paramedics attended to their injuries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UNIFIL convoy comprised a number of busses, the correspondent said.</p>

<p>Israeli raids have intensified in recent weeks on Haret Saida, a densely-populated Sidon suburb that has a significant population of Shiite Muslims.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has also increasingly launched targeted strikes on vehicles. A woman was killed Thursday in an Israeli strike targeting a car on a key road linking the capital Beirut with the Bekaa Valley and Syria, a security source told AFP.</p>

<p>Lebanon's National News Agency reported earlier that "an enemy drone targeted a car in Araya," adding that the strike left the route blocked to vehicular traffic.</p>

<p>The highway links Beirut to the Syrian capital of Damascus, through the Lebanese mountains.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vamtjmug_southern-lebanon-_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli raids have intensified in recent weeks on Haret Saida. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/go-work-for-another-company-amazon-group-firm-ceo-to-employees-protesting-end-of-wfh-6966800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Go Work For...": Amazon CEO To Employees Protesting End Of WFH]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/go-work-for-another-company-amazon-group-firm-ceo-to-employees-protesting-end-of-wfh-6966800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:24:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[523 Amazon employees protested the "return to office" policy and urged management to maintain remote work flexibility.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 500 Amazon Web Services (AWS) employees have petitioned the company to reconsider its new five-day in-office mandate, which is set to begin in January. In a letter to AWS CEO Matt Garman, 523 employees voiced opposition to the "return to office" policy and urged management to maintain remote work flexibility.</p>

<p>"AWS is not realizing its full potential with this mandate, and it is setting a discouraging path forward," the letter shared with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazon/amazon-employees-protest-5-day-a-week-office-return/"><em>The Seattle Times</em></a> stated. "While flexible and remote work does have its challenges, AWS has always been a company that tackles problems in innovative, forward-thinking ways, rather than falling back on outdated solutions that worked in the past. The cloud computing industry might not exist today if we had held onto such restrictive thinking in our early days."</p>

<p>Amazon CEO Andy Jassy previously announced in a memo that the policy would begin on January 2, 2025. Prior to this change, Amazon required employees to be in the office three days a week, a shift that sparked protests as well. About 15 months after that initial mandate, Amazon is now expanding the requirement to restore pre-pandemic work norms.</p>

<p>The recent letter from AWS employees responds to Garman's comments at an AWS town hall, where he suggested employees who don't wish to comply with the new five-day rule could explore other job options. Last week, Garman reiterated this stance in an interview, expressing confidence in the policy and stating that most employees he spoke to are supportive of the change. Garman and Jassy have acknowledged that while there may be flexibility under the new policy, such as managers occasionally working from home for specific tasks, the core requirement remains in place.</p>

<p>AWS employees argued in the letter that Garman's comments do not align with their own experiences, claiming, "You are silencing critical perspectives and harming our culture and future." They also contended that Amazon's decision lacked data-backed analysis, contradicting one of Amazon's key principles, and noted that the policy might hinder Amazon's goal of becoming "Earth's best employer."</p>

<p>The mandate is expected to particularly affect employees who depend on remote work flexibility, such as those with disabilities, caregiving duties, or visa restrictions. The employees also suggested that the mandate may drive senior staff members who often have the credentials and financial flexibility to seek other roles away from Amazon, potentially impacting the collaborative culture the company aims to foster.</p>

<p>The new policy will make Amazon one of the few major tech companies in Seattle with such a stringent in-office requirement. Starbucks recently implemented a similar approach, requiring corporate employees to work from the office three days a week starting in January, with non-compliance leading to potential job changes.</p>

<p>In their letter, AWS employees reiterated their desire for Amazon to reconsider its stance, emphasizing, "Remote and flexible work represents an opportunity for Amazon to lead, not a threat. We want to work for leaders who see this moment as a chance to reinvent how we work."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Amazon CEO Andy Jassy said at an all-hands meeting on Tuesday that the plan to require employees to be in-office five days per week is not meant to force attrition or satisfy city leaders, as many employees have suggested, Reuters reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A number of people I've seen theorized that the reason we were doing this is, it's a backdoor layoff, or we made some sort of deal with city or cities," said Jassy, according to a transcript of the meeting reviewed by Reuters.</p>

<p>"I can tell you both of those are not true. You know, this was not a cost play for us. This is very much about our culture and strengthening our culture," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jhsuuj3o_amazon-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mandate is expected to particularly affect employees who depend on remote work flexibility]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-sees-window-to-end-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-after-donald-trumps-victory-6966511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Sees 'Window' To End Wars In Gaza, Lebanon After Trump's Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-sees-window-to-end-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-after-donald-trumps-victory-6966511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:41:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot said Thursday in Jerusalem he saw prospects for ending Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon after Donald Trump was elected US president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot said Thursday in Jerusalem he saw prospects for ending Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon after Donald Trump was elected US president.</p>

<p>"I believe a window has opened for putting an end to the tragedy in which Israelis, Palestinians, and the entire region have been immersed since October 7" last year, Barrot told reporters in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Speaking alongside outgoing Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz, Barrot cited Trump's "wish to see the end of the Middle East's endless wars" as well as Israel's recent "tactical successes".</p>

<p>Barrot said he hoped a "diplomatic solution" would emerge "in the coming weeks".</p>

<p>"Force alone will not be enough to guarantee Israel's security," he said, adding that "military success could not be a substitute for a political perspective".</p>

<p>"It is time to move towards a deal that would allow for the liberation of all hostages, a ceasefire, and the mass entry of humanitarian aid into Gaza, and to prepare for the day after."</p>

<p>Barrot said "Israel has the right to defend itself" but pointed to "colonisation", "humanitarian aid restrictions" and "the continuation of air strikes in north Gaza" as risk factors for Israel's security.</p>

<p>Barrot is expected to speak with Palestinian Authority president Mahmud Abbas and his prime minister, Muhammad Mustafa.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f78af2v8_-jeannoel-barrot-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barrot said he hoped a "diplomatic solution" would emerge "in coming weeks".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-must-prepare-for-climate-calamity-un-chief-6966373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["World Must Prepare For Climate Calamity": UN Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-must-prepare-for-climate-calamity-un-chief-6966373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:25:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world is nowhere near ready for the "calamity" being caused by climate change and must urgently prepare for even worse in the future, UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world is nowhere near ready for the "calamity" being caused by climate change and must urgently prepare for even worse in the future, UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.</p>

<p>Global efforts to adapt to climate change -- from building defensive sea walls to planting drought-resistant crops -- have not kept pace as global warming accelerates the frequency and intensity of disasters.</p>

<p>Floods, fires and other climate shocks have affected nearly every continent in a year the EU climate monitor says is almost certain to be the hottest ever recorded.</p>

<p>The amount of money going to poorer countries for adaptation measures was barely one-tenth of what they needed to disaster-proof their vulnerable economies, the UN Environment Programme (UNEP) said in a new assessment looking at 2022, the latest year for which data is available.</p>

<p>"Climate calamity is the new reality. And we're not keeping up," said Guterres at the launch of UNEP's annual Adaptation Gap Report.</p>

<p>Rich nations are under pressure at this month's UN COP29 summit to substantially increase the $100 billion they pledged for climate action in developing countries, including for adaptation.</p>

<p>But some donor governments are under fiscal and political pressure, and major new commitments of public money are not expected at the conference in Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>A UN biodiversity meeting this month failed to reach a funding agreement and the election of Donald Trump -- who opposes global climate cooperation -- hangs over COP29.</p>

<h3><strong>No one immune</strong></h3>

<p>Most of the public money committed to climate change goes to reducing planet-warming emissions, not adapting to its long-term consequences.</p>

<p>Some $28 billion in public finance was paid to developing countries for climate adaptation in 2022.</p>

<p>This was an increase on the year prior, but still a drop in the ocean: UNEP estimates between $215 billion and $387 billion is needed annually for adaptation in developing countries.</p>

<p>Rich countries had pledged to double the amount by 2025 to roughly $40 billion a year but even this would leave an "extremely large" adaptation funding gap, UNEP said.</p>

<p>Climate disasters hit poorest communities hardest but the cost of inaction was no longer borne by them alone, said Patrick Verkooijen, CEO of the Global Center on Adaptation.</p>

<p>"From rising seas and extreme heat waves to relentless droughts and floods, the impacts of climate change now reach every corner of the globe. No nation, no community is immune," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>Spanish authorities were accused of being inadequately prepared when a major storm brought flooding that killed over 200 people last month.</p>

<p>Climate scientists say that global warming is fuelling more frequent and severe extreme weather.</p>

<p>"We can't postpone protection. We must adapt -- now," Guterres said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/otldtf18_antonio-guterres_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[loods, fires and other climate shocks have affected nearly every continent in a year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-command-china-space-military-technology-china-is-common-adversary-in-space-military-race-warns-top-us-general-6966358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China Is Common Adversary In Space-Military Race", Warns Top US General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-command-china-space-military-technology-china-is-common-adversary-in-space-military-race-warns-top-us-general-6966358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:22:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US wants to broaden cooperation and collaboration with India in space technology, particularly as it relates to militarisation of the 'final frontier' to deny common adversaries such as China, Major General Brian W Gibson said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US wants to broaden cooperation and collaboration with India in space technology, particularly as it relates to militarisation of the 'final frontier' to deny common adversaries such as China, Major General Brian W Gibson, the strategy chief of the US Space Command, told NDTV.</p>

<p>In Delhi to meet top military and space agency officials, General Gibson red-flagged Beijing's space programme, saying, "China is advancing at a breathtaking pace in the military use of space tech."</p>

<p>"Conflict in space is not inevitable... just like every other domain. And one way we seek to deter (our enemies) is to not go it alone... we go together, we do it together. So that is my purpose here - to broaden our relationship, collaborate where we can and where we have shared interests." He adds, "I hope this is just the beginning between two space enterprises and two militaries, bilateral dialogues only increase trust since interoperability is important in space."</p>

<p>The reality of the world as it is today, General Gibson said, is that much of the focus is on the US and India, and the challenges the two countries face together from "potential adversaries like China". He adds "partnerships will become important to fight collective threats".</p>

<p>"Their advance is breathtaking... in the military aspect of space alone, let alone the commercial," he said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/5ar0pumg_brian-gibson_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Major General W Brian Gibson, Director, Strategy, Plans and Policy, US Space Command, and ISRO chief Dr S Somanath participate in the India Space Conclave 3.0 in New Delhi</p>
</div>

<p>To deepen cooperation, the US Space Command signed agreements with at least two Indian startups Dhruva Space Pvt Ltd and Digantara to share open source data to help these startups get a fillip as they develop their technologies.</p>

<p>General Gibson said "India observed the US Space Command's Global Sentinel exercise in February 2024 and will participate in the exercise in 2025". The exercise is designed to improve the ability of allied forces to monitor space and cooperate.</p>

<p>The General's visit to Delhi - which experts say signals a major shift in Washington DC's space command policy - comes on the heels of Donald Trump's big win in this week's election.</p>

<p>Mr Trump beat his Democrat rival, outgoing Vice President Kamala Harris, in the 2024 US presidential election and will, in January, be installed as the 47th President of the United States. General Gibson's words of warning - i.e China - are not a new development.</p>

<p>In September last year, the US Space Force - the US military's space service established during Mr Trump's first term - said it had internal discussions about a 'hotline' to prevent space crises.</p>

<p>The comments came as the Space Force looked into establishing a Japan branch; this was in response to China's continuing military ambitions in the Indo-Pacific and the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>The Space Force's commander, General Chance Saltzman, told Reuters then that close cooperation with "like-minded countries" would be crucial in being able to monitor and understand activity in the space domain, and to deter China and counter 'grey zone activities' like jamming satellite signals.</p>

<p>Further back, in 2022, the then Commander of the US Space Command, General James H Dickinson, said China is building facilities that could put most of his country's space assets at risk.</p>

<p>General Gibson says the motto of the US Space Command is 'never a day without space' and America seeks to ensure "responsible, safe, sustainable use of space", adding "India's journey has just begun and India is ready as the stars are waiting, India has the capacity and will to succeed".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tlnvav88_brian-gibson_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Major General W Brian Gibson and Union Science Minister Jitendra Singh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-good-health-nasa-amid-reports-of-sunita-williams-declining-health-6966297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In Good Health": NASA Amid Reports Of Sunita William's Declining Health]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-good-health-nasa-amid-reports-of-sunita-williams-declining-health-6966297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:14:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid growing concerns over Sunita Williams' health, NASA recently clarified that all the astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) are in "good health".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid growing concerns over Sunita Williams' health, NASA recently clarified that all the astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) are in "good health".</p>

<p>A spokesperson for NASA's Space Operations Mission Directorate, Jimi Russell, told Daily Mail that all the NASA astronauts aboard ISS undergo routine medical evaluations and are monitored by dedicated flight surgeons.</p>

<p>"All are in good health," he said.</p>

<p>The space agency's statement comes amid media reports claiming that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-astronaut-sunita-williams-sends-diwali-wishes-from-space-6896558">Williams</a> is facing a health crisis after a prolonged stay on the ISS.</p>

<p>A picture of the NASA astronaut assembling a pepperoni pizza is also doing rounds on social media wherein it looks like she has lost a significant amount of weight. According to a Seattle-based pulmonologist, Williams looks "gaunt" in the picture, adding that she seems to be experiencing the natural stresses of living at a very high altitude for extended periods.</p>

<p>"Her cheeks appear a bit sunken and usually it happens when you've had sort of total body weight loss. 'I think what I can discern by her face and her cheeks being sunken in is that she has probably been at a significant calorie deficit for a while," the doctor told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-14045511/health-concerns-NASA-astronauts-stranded-ISS.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">Daily Mail</a>.</p>

<p>Williams and her fellow astronaut Barry Wilmore have been at the ISS since June. What was supposed to be an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-days-to-8-months-sunita-williams-barry-wilmores-extended-stay-in-space-6715868">eight-day ISS mission</a>, stretched into months due to a Starliner spacecraft malfunction. The astronauts will now return home in February next year.</p>

<p>On October 26, a NASA astronaut - part of the Crew-8, was hospitalised after returning from a nearly eight-month deployment on the ISS. According to NASA, astronauts Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt, Jeanette Epps, and Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin were flown together to Ascension Sacred Heart Pensacola in Florida. After a medical evaluation at the hospital, one of the astronauts was kept under observation as a precautionary measure. However, the details of the astronaut were not revealed to protect the crew member's medical privacy, NASA said.</p>

<p>The astronaut was released a day after in "good health", the US space agency said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ot9m3458_sunita-williams-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Williams and her fellow astronaut Barry Wilmore have been at the ISS since June.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reinstates-plea-deal-for-9-11-mastermind-other-suspects-6966231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reinstates Plea Deal For 9/11 Mastermind, Other Suspects]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reinstates-plea-deal-for-9-11-mastermind-other-suspects-6966231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:07:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US military judge has reinstated plea agreements for 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US military judge has reinstated plea agreements for 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants, an official said Thursday, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.</p>

<p>The agreements -- which are understood to take the death penalty off the table -- had triggered anger among some relatives of victims of the 2001 attacks, and Austin said that both they and the American public deserved to see the defendants stand trial.</p>

<p>"I can confirm that the military judge has ruled that the pretrial agreements for the three accused are valid and enforceable," the US official told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The prosecution has the opportunity to appeal the decision, but it was not immediately clear if they would do so.</p>

<p>The plea deals with Mohammed and two alleged accomplices were announced in late July in a step that appeared to have moved their long-running cases toward resolution after years of being bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings while the defendants remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>But Austin withdrew the agreements two days after they were announced, saying the decision should rest with him given its significance.</p>

<p>He subsequently told journalists that "the families of the victims, our service members and the American public deserve the opportunity to see military commission trials carried out in this case."</p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone methodical torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11 -- a thorny issue that the plea agreements would have avoided.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1jmfn9g_khalid-sheikh-mohammed_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/girl-3-goes-to-court-in-pakistans-lahore-as-air-quality-continues-to-be-hazardous-6966213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Girl, 3, Goes To Court In Lahore As Air Quality Continues To Be Hazardous]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/girl-3-goes-to-court-in-pakistans-lahore-as-air-quality-continues-to-be-hazardous-6966213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:03:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A three-year-old girl has filed a petition against the local government in Pakistan's Punjab as the province, especially its capital Lahore, continues to reel under the severe impact of smog, keeping the air quality in an extremely hazardous zone.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-year-old girl has filed a petition against the local government in Pakistan's Punjab as the province, especially its capital Lahore, continues to reel under the severe impact of smog, keeping the air quality in an extremely hazardous zone.</p>

<p>On Thursday morning, the Air Quality Index (AQI) of Lahore stayed on top of the global rankings with levels crossing much above the 800-mark, making the air seriously dangerous for the residents.</p>

<p>As per the Swiss air quality monitor IQAir, Lahore has been on top of the cities with the world's highest AQI. The levels have even exceeded the 1000 mark on many occasions.</p>

<p>The extended and prolonged bad weather has made it impossible for citizens to venture out of their homes. The hospitals too are getting filled up with people suffering from respiratory issues. The bad air quality has left thousands of citizens of the province vulnerable to respiratory diseases with the provincial government and doctors advising all to wear masks whenever they venture out of their homes.</p>

<p>The provincial government has imposed a smog emergency across the province and has shut down all educational institutions up to the higher secondary level in Lahore and other districts till November 17.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a three-year-old girl has reached out to the Lahore High Court (LHC) on Thursday, filing a case against the provincial government over its failure to control air pollution.</p>

<p>The petitioner, Amal Sekhera, through her lawyer maintained in the petition that young children and the elderly are severely affected by air pollution and sought justice for herself, friends and the future generations.</p>

<p>"Under Article 99-A of the Constitution, the government is obligated to provide citizens with a clean and healthy environment," the petition stated.</p>

<p>The petition criticised the Punjab government for failing to protect the fundamental rights guaranteed by the Constitution of Pakistan.</p>

<p>Punjab government's senior provincial minister Maryam Aurangzeb has said that the intensity of the smog is expected to continue for at least 10 more days, due to which the educational institutions have been shut down and people have been advised to wear masks.</p>

<p>Many other cities like Multan and Gujranwala are also severely impacted with the ongoing weather conditions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pkq2c0g8_lahore_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The petition criticised the Punjab government for failing to protect the fundamental rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-sparks-outrage-after-sharing-video-of-son-urinating-on-familys-meal-6965987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Woman Sparks Outrage With Video Of Son Urinating On Family Meal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-sparks-outrage-after-sharing-video-of-son-urinating-on-familys-meal-6965987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:38:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In China, a mothers social media post ignited a fierce debate when she shared an unusual family incident: her young son urinated on a dining table, and the family continued to eat the meal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media is becoming a place where people move from being creative to cliched to filthy in their posts due to the competition to publish pictures and videos and acquire views, likes, and followers. Despite many regulations by the social media platforms, there are hundreds of disgusting posts on social media that need to be removed. A similar post where a mother in China sparked severe online backlash after sharing on social media that her son urinated on a table full of food, and her family continued to eat the meal.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285406/disgust-china-mother-posts-online-photo-toddler-son-urinating-over-family-meal"><em>South China Morning Post, </em></a>the incident came to light in a recent social media post by a mother from Beijing, who told how her young son, held by his grandmother next to the dining table, suddenly began to urinate. In the post, the mother "proudly" captured the moment when her toddler's urine arced onto the table, which appeared to be breakfast, including steamed buns, eggs, and vegetables.</p>

<p>Details about the toddler's age and family background were not disclosed.The post quickly drew attention on social media, with many netizens expressing disbelief and concern, with one online observer asking, "So, did you guys end up eating that food?" To the shock of the online community, the mother confirmed: "Yes, we did eat it."</p>

<p><strong>In China, Young Boys' Urine Holds Unique Cultural Significance</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285406/disgust-china-mother-posts-online-photo-toddler-son-urinating-over-family-meal"><em>SCMP,</em></a> in traditional Chinese culture, it is believed that the urine of young boys possesses various "mysterious powers," from boosting yang energy and reducing fever to spiritual benefits such as warding off evil spirits and enhancing good fortune.</p>

<p>Urine from boys under the age of 10 is considered particularly potent, especially the first morning's urine collected on the day before a boy turns one month old.</p>

<p>A famous food recipe from southern China, known as "urine eggs," involves collecting urine from kindergartens or primary schools, cleaning fresh eggs, placing them in a pot, covering them with the urine, then cooking them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ttpi21ro_urinating-on-familys-meal_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident highlights longstanding cultural beliefs in China.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-win-will-affect-globalisation-s-jaishankar-explains-6965805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Donald Trump's Win Will Affect Globalisation? S Jaishankar Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-win-will-affect-globalisation-s-jaishankar-explains-6965805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:17:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a press briefing after his meeting with top business leaders and CEOs in Australia, S Jaishankar mentioned about "something that happened yesterday", referring to the US election result. Mr Jaishankar said India "perceives this as an opportunity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a press briefing after his meeting with top business leaders and CEOs in Australia, S Jaishankar mentioned about "something that happened yesterday", referring to the US election result. Mr Jaishankar said India "perceives this as an opportunity".</p>

<p>Former US President and Republican candidate Donald Trump made a stunning comeback after a 4-year gap to get re-elected as the 47th President of the United States of America. Mr Trump's win will almost certainly have an effect on the global order and significantly impact policy and trade for most nations.</p>

<p>Mr Trump's win will have a big impact on globalisation. Sharing his views on this, Mr Jaishankar said there are four aspects on how India views this: Firstly, "There was already a reordering of supply chains which was taking place (globally). It is very likely that this will get accelerated after the election result in the US."</p>

<p>He went on to say that "I'll be very candid with you, that some of this will be somewhat disruptive, but we in India perceive it as an opportunity because having kind of missed the manufacturing bus in the 1990s, early 2000s, we do think that this reordering of supply chain gives us a sort of second bite of the apple. And maybe this time around, starting with Apple, we are doing better than we were doing earlier."</p>

<p>"Secondly, there will be, in a way, more geopolitical hedging. that, what will inevitably happen as a consequence of policies which we can, at least those parts of it we can safely predict, will be that many more of us would be seeking more relationships (globally) to keep life stable," he added.</p>

<p>The foreign minister went on to highlight the significance of the digital age we all live in, explaining that digital payment platforms will ultimately become very valuable.</p>

<p>"The third aspect pertains to the digital digital side, and the digital side now pretty much covers everything." Mr Jaishankar said, adding that "What has been happening and will continue to intensify is about trust, and what accompanies the digital aspect of a product or service or technology will come under greater scrutiny."</p>

<p>He further noted that "Digital payment platforms, for example, would become, in a sense, much more valuable." adding that "which platform to use and share with whom, becomes an important question."</p>

<p>The fourth aspect, he said, is mobility. Speaking about it Mr Jaishankar said, "I think the demographic unevenness of the world is beginning to bite us that there would be, economies where the demand would be high. In those countries, the talents may not be plentiful."</p>

<p>"It could be different in other places, and what will happen, and is already happening is that we will be moving, perhaps in the next few years, to a much more integrated global workplace that many countries -- even a United States under Donald Trump -- will make a distinction in immigration and mobility for them. An economically-justified mobility will have to be fostered by those countries," the foreign minister explained.</p>

<p>"Businesses can move as well. We've already seen in the last few years," Mr Jaishankar said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iltj1phg_s-jaishankar-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar met CEOs and business leaders in Australia today. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-soldiers-get-internet-access-in-ukraine-hooked-on-porn-report-6965568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korean Soldiers Get Internet Access In Ukraine, Hooked On Porn: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-soldiers-get-internet-access-in-ukraine-hooked-on-porn-report-6965568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:47:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean soldiers, who joined the war front in Ukraine on behalf of Russia recently, received access to unrestricted internet - a wildly exciting concept for them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean soldiers, who joined the war front in Ukraine on behalf of Russia recently, received access to unrestricted internet - a wildly exciting concept for them. This has resulted in the military men taking advantage of the unfettered access and are hooked to pornographic content online, a report by The Financial Times said.</p>

<p>According to the report, the soldiers from the hermit country are "gorging" on adult content.</p>

<p>However, it did not provide further context on how they have details on the internet habits of North Korean soldiers sent by Kim Jong Un to Ukraine.</p>

<p>US Defense Department spokesperson Army Lt Col Charlie Dietz also said they could not confirm any "North Korean internet habits or virtual extracurriculars", reported The New York Post.</p>

<p>Amid the growing Moscow-North Korea ties, Russia deployed more than <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-troops-clashed-with-ukrainian-forces-in-russias-kursk-report-6955668">7,000 North Korean soldiers</a>, armed with AK-12 rifles, mortar rounds, and other assault weapons, to areas near the border with Ukraine on Monday. They underwent training at five different sites in Russia's Far East for potential support of Russia's war in Ukraine, the Defence Intelligence of Ukraine said.</p>

<p>Two days later, the North Korean troops reportedly clashed with Ukrainian forces for the first time and are occupying a portion of the Kursk region in Russia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p82j1as8_north-korean-troops-in-russia-afp_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean troops reportedly clashed with Ukrainian forces. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-the-facts-donald-trump-and-elon-musk-may-not-remain-bffs-for-long-6965492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Musk Is The Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-the-facts-donald-trump-and-elon-musk-may-not-remain-bffs-for-long-6965492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:35:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Musk, however, is also a risk to Trump as his business interests may clash with US foreign policy. For instance, Teslas largest factory is in Shanghai, and another one is in Berlin. Both countries are bracing for higher tariff barriers under Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s6mrg66_musk_625x300_07_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Just before dawn broke on November 6 over the East Coast, Donald Trump clinched the 270 electoral votes needed to secure a second four-year term as President of the United States. He delivered his victory speech hours before when it became clear that his path to the White House was open and free.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the speech that lasted a little over 25 minutes, Trump spoke about unifying America. He thanked several people, including his family, campaign managers and voters. The presumed President-elect also picked out one man for special praise. Let me tell you, we have a new star. A star is bornElon, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zVMxxiVvl4E">he said of billionaire businessman</a> Elon Musk. Trump also spent the next four minutes gushing about the spectacle of Musk-owned spacefaring company SpaceX's robots successfully catching a rocket returning from space. He is a super genius and we have to protect our super geniuses. We don't have many of them, Trump said.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>Still Sinking In</b></h2>

<p>Musk has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/10/26/elon-musk-political-donations-132-million-donald-trump-republican-races/">reportedly spent</a> $132 million on and actively campaigned for Donald Trump in the elections. Trump has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-adopt-musks-proposal-government-efficiency-commission-wsj-reports-2024-09-05/">floated</a> the idea of making him in charge of a bureaucratic purge. He wants Musk to head an efficiency commission, whose main job will be to shrink government expenditure, including by potentially firing thousands of career bureaucrats. Trump wants to rid the US government of what he believes is a cabal of federal employees, a deep state that pursues its own agenda. One of his allies, Kash Patel, who is helping in the regime transition, is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/06/politics/transition-donald-trump-jockeying/index.html">screening</a> people for potential positions in the Trump administration. Patel, who has written a book <em>Government Gangsters: The Deep State, the Truth, and the Battle for Our Democracy</em>&nbsp;himself, is said to be angling to be Trump's chief spook.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk responded to Trump's victory in typical style; a picture of himself carrying a kitchen sink with the Oval Office in the background and the line: Let that sink in!' That was a throwback to when he bought Twitter and walked into its headquarters with a sink. &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Biden's Battle With Big Tech</strong></h2>

<p>Trump's victory is arguably the most remarkable comeback in US political history. The epochal story's side track is the culmination of a not-so-quiet battle that Big Tech has been waging with Washington during the entire term of Joe Biden. The President's trusted lieutenant, Lina Khan, the chief of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), relentlessly pursued companies such as Facebook, Google and Apple, wielding the antitrust law like an electric whip. Billionaire CEOs sat shuddering before Congressional committees as combative members dragged them over coals. A Republican-led House Judiciary Committee <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/05/technology/election-2024-ftc-lina-khan.html">accused Khan</a> of weaponising the agency and pushing a far-left agenda. Khan and FTC occupied significant mind-space in the closing stages of the presidential campaign. She will be fired soon, Musk posted on X a day before the vote. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The entry of Musk, along with Vice-President JD Vance, signals the deepest incursion of Silicon Valley into US national politics. Vance, who once <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.in/politics/world/news/i-reread-jd-vances-hillbilly-elegy-he-hasnt-transformed-as-much-as-you-think-/articleshow/111845075.cms">derisively called</a> Trump cultural heroin, was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=dhtwitter&amp;utm_content=app.dashhudson.com/vanityfair/library/media/470296154">handpicked</a>, groomed and funded to first become Ohio governor and then Trump's running mate by libertarian founder of payment firm PayPal and data analytics company Palantir Technologies, Peter Thiel.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Reign Of The Unpredictables</strong></h2>

<p>To be sure, Trump has no love lost for entrepreneurs such as Mark Zuckerburg. His pals, Musk and Thiel, checked out of Woke California long ago. Trump has reversed his intention to ban Chinese social media app TikTok, a Meta rival, ostensibly after being persuaded by investor Jeffrey Yass, who owns a juicy slice of its parent Bytedance. The libertarian billionaire <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/republican-hedge-fund-owner-tiktok-investor-yass-emerges-top-donor-us-election-2024-03-21/">donated over</a> $46 billion to Republican causes. With the Senate and House also firmly packed with tens of elected legislators backed by billionaire tech entrepreneurs and investors, the power shift is all too evident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although Trump is seen as an uncontrollable wrecking ball, Musk has proven to be even more unpredictable. While countries the world over are bracing for the Trump impact, whether on tariffs, movement of professionals, technology transfer, or military deployment, Musk's influence if he joins the administration is an even bigger unknown. As the richest man on earth with a $286 billion fortune as of election day and business interests all over the world, Musk has close ties with many leaders, including Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin. Earlier this year, he abruptly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-shocked-musks-surprise-china-visit-leaves-them-spurned-2024-04-30/">cancelled a visit</a> to India at the last minute only to head to Beijing for confabulations with the Chinese leadership. That sojourn cleared Tesla's path in that country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has refused Tesla and Starlink lower entry barriers and requests for special treatment. Trump is known to intervene with other countries on behalf of American businesses. In his previous term, he had pushed India for concessions to Harley Davidson motorcycles.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>BFFs, But Probably Not For Long</strong></h2>

<p>Musk, however, is also a risk to Trump as his business interests may clash with US foreign policy. For instance, Tesla's largest factory is in Shanghai, and another one is in Berlin. Both countries are bracing for higher tariff barriers under Trump. Musk also has been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/russia/musk-putin-secret-conversations-37e1c187">reported</a> to have had secret dealings with Putin, who is said to have lobbied on behalf of his friend Xi to switch off Taiwan's access to Starlink. Musk has also made statements that are contradictory to US interests and publicly stated positions on Taiwan.</p>

<p>Trump's antipathy towards green initiatives and abiding faith in petroleum may not augur well for Tesla's electric cars, but <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/features/2024-11-03/election-2024-trump-may-let-musk-colonize-the-white-house">some believe</a> Musk may already be moving away from EVs. His future fortune and power rest on his other businesses, they say.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Given the contradictions, one as President of the United States and another as the founder of half a dozen futuristic enterprises, it is difficult to see Trump's and Musk's interests remaining aligned for very long. Both are individuals who brook no barrier to their personal agenda, and both are known to wear their opinion on their X handles.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Dinesh Narayanan is a Delhi-based journalist and author of 'The RSS And The Making Of The Deep Nation'.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cnltfv0g_musk_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/fictosexual-japan-man-celebrates-6-years-of-marriage-with-virtual-wife-admired-for-his-devotion-6965432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Fictosexual' Japan Man Celebrates 6 Years Of Marriage With Virtual Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/fictosexual-japan-man-celebrates-6-years-of-marriage-with-virtual-wife-admired-for-his-devotion-6965432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:29:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Akihiko Kondo, a Japanese man who married the fictional vocaloid character Hatsune Miku in 2018, recently celebrated his sixth anniversary with her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The idea of traditional relationships is changing, from self-marriage rituals to robotic companions. The increasing acceptability of many manifestations of love and devotion is reflected in these unorthodox unions.This ongoing series has a fresh addition: a Japanese guy who married the fictitious vocaloid Hatsune Miku in 2018 is still happily married and looking forward to their sixth anniversary.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3284801/fictosexual-japan-man-anticipates-6th-wedding-anniversary-wife-praised-loyalty"><em>South China Morning Post,</em></a> on October 23, 41-year-old Akihiko Kondo shared on his Instagram the receipt for a cake he bought for their anniversary, which falls on November 4.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by   (@akihikokondosk)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The cake bears the message, "I like Miku very much. Happy six-year anniversary." Kondo told the Japanese news outlet The Mainichi Shimbun that he had been romantically interested in women before secondary school.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja"> <a href="https://t.co/TNxbIHxAbC">pic.twitter.com/TNxbIHxAbC</a></p>
  ?? (@akihikokondosk) <a href="https://twitter.com/akihikokondosk/status/1853452513284092238?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He confessed his love seven times, but all were rejected, and he was laughed at and bullied for being an otaku-a person obsessed with anime and manga. Kondo fell in love with Miku in 2007 soon after the character was released. He was bullied at work and, as a result, was diagnosed with adjustment disorder and took long sick leave, reported the news outlet.</p>

<p>The character, whose name is translated as "the first sound of the future" in English, is officially known as a vocaloid, a type of singing voice synthesiser software. Those who are fond of her recognise her as a 16-year-old pop singer with long, turquoise twintails.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/61v2cm0o_akihiko-kondo_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fictosexual Akihiko Kondo is happily married to his synthesised wife.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-australia-today-india-calls-out-canadas-move-against-australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-6965431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Calls Out Canada's Move Against Outlet That Interviewed S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-australia-today-india-calls-out-canadas-move-against-australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-6965431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Responding strongly to reports of social media handles and pages of an Australian news outlet being blocked in Canada, India has said such actions highlight the hypocrisy of Canada towards freedom of speech.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Responding strongly to reports of social media handles and pages of an Australian news outlet being blocked in Canada hours after it carried a press conference of External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong as well as an interview of the Indian minister, India has said such actions highlight Canada's hypocrisy towards freedom of speech.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During his Australia visit, which ends on Thursday, Mr Jaishankar met Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and also co-chaired the 15th Foreign Ministers' Framework Dialogue with Ms Wong.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked about the social media handles of Australia Today being blocked in Canada, Ministry of External Affairs Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said on Thursday, "We understand that social media handles and pages of this outlet, which is an important diaspora outlet, have been blocked and are not available for viewers in Canada. This happened a few hours after this particular handle carried the press conference of the External Affairs Minister with Penny Wong."</p>

<p>Stating that the outlet had carried an interview with Mr Jaishankar as well as several articles on his visit, Mr Jaiswal added, "We were surprised. It looks strange to us. But, nonetheless, these are actions that yet again highlight the hypocrisy of Canada towards freedom of speech. In his media interactions, the External Affairs Minister spoke about three things: a pattern of Canada making allegations without evidence, the surveillance of Indian diplomats - which he termed unacceptable - and the political space being given in Canada to anti-India elements. So you can draw your conclusions from that on why the Australia Today channel was blocked."</p>

<p>Last week, India had said some of its consular officials were informed by the Canadian government that they have been under audio and video surveillance. Terming the action a "flagrant violation" of diplomatic conventions, India had said Canada could not hide behind technicalities to justify its harassment and intimidation and that a protest had been lodged with the Canadian government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Jaiswal also confirmed that some consular camps have been cancelled in Toronto because they did not get security assurance from Canada. The announcement came days after the attack on a Hindu temple in Brampton, where a consular camp was being held, on November 3. PM Narendra Modi had also condemned the attack and criticised "cowardly attempts" to intimidate Indian diplomats in Canada.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Ties between India and Canada have been strained since Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau claimed - without offering any evidence - last year that "Indian agents" were involved in the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. The allegation has been rubbished by New Delhi several times and it has asked Canada to produce evidence to back up the claim.</p>

<p>The relationship hit a new low last month when the Indian High Commissioner was termed a "person of interest" in the killing. India dismissed the fresh charge as "ludicrous" and withdrew the High Commissioner and some diplomats while expelling six Canadian officials, including Canada's acting High Commissioner Stewart Ross Wheeler.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d83eucg_s-jaishankar_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ministry also confirmed that some consular camps have been cancelled in Toronto.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>