<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 14:02:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/list-of-people-donald-trump-may-pardon-during-his-second-term-as-us-president-6978462]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[January 6 Rioters To Julian Assange: People Donald Trump May Pardon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/list-of-people-donald-trump-may-pardon-during-his-second-term-as-us-president-6978462]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 14:06:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Days after he defeated Kamala Harris in the Presidential polls, political observers in the US speculated that Trump would issue pardons for several controversial figures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump is preparing for his second term in the Oval Office. Days after he defeated Kamala Harris in the Presidential polls, political observers in the US speculated that Trump would issue pardons for several controversial figures. From January 6 rioters to prominent public figures, these potential pardons seem to be part of Trump's strategy to galvanise his political base and challenge what he views as a biased legal system.</p>

<p>According to the US Department of Justice, “The President's clemency power is conferred by Article II, Section 2, Clause 1 of the Constitution of the United States, which provides: ‘The President…shall have Power to grant Reprieves and Pardons for Offenses against the United States, except in Cases of Impeachment.'”</p>

<p>But pardons do not fully erase a criminal record. Even after a pardon, individuals may still face restrictions, such as being prohibited from voting in certain states.</p>

<h3><strong>Pardons for January 6 rioters</strong></h3>

<p>Trump has repeatedly expressed his intention to pardon those involved in the January 6 Capitol riots, though he remains vague on specifics. “If they're innocent, I would pardon them,” he remarked in July. Campaign spokesperson Karoline Leavitt told the<a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2024/11/06/jan-6-defendants-trump-pardons/"> Washington Post</a> that pardons would be decided on a “case-by-case” basis, with some defendants already invoking Trump's pardon promises in court since his election on November 5.</p>

<h3><strong>Hunter Biden</strong></h3>

<p>Trump hinted at the possibility of pardoning Hunter Biden, Joe Biden's son, who faces sentencing for federal tax and gun charges. Trump told conservative radio host Hugh Hewitt in October, “I wouldn't take it off the books… despite what they've done to me.”</p>

<h3><strong>Ross Ulbricht</strong></h3>

<p>Another person who may benefit from a potential pardon is Ross Ulbricht, founder of the Silk Road dark web marketplace, who has received vocal support from libertarians. Supporters of Ulbricht, who was sentenced to life imprisonment in 2015 for running the Silk Road marketplace on the dark web, expressed their hope on social media, with one tweet stating, "ROSS IS COMING HOME IN JANUARY. We are so grateful to @realDonaldTrump for his pledge to #FreeRoss and to all those who have supported us.”</p>

<h3><strong>Julian Assange</strong></h3>

<p>Julian Assange, the founder of WikiLeaks, may also receive a pardon. Trump expressed in May 2024 that he would “give very serious consideration” to granting clemency to Assange.</p>

<h3><strong>Peter Navarro</strong></h3>

<p>Trump has left the door open for a potential pardon of his former trade adviser, Peter Navarro, who was sentenced to four months in prison for contempt of Congress. Trump praised Navarro as a “great patriot,” claiming he was “treated very unfairly.”</p>

<h3><strong>Trump's self-pardon and legal boundaries</strong></h3>

<p>As for the possibility of Trump pardoning himself, the issue remains murky. While Trump previously dismissed the idea, telling <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-unlikely-pardon-convicted-presidency-meet-the-press-rcna104779">NBC News </a>last year it was “very unlikely” he'd pardon himself, because he “didn't do anything wrong,” legal experts remain divided on whether the Constitution permitted such an action. While Trump may avoid needing a self-pardon for federal charges, state-level prosecutions, including those in New York and Georgia, remain outside his jurisdiction.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/9rh0n91_assange-january-6-rioter-_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump has repeatedly expressed his intention to pardon those involved in the January 6 riots.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-earth-like-world-orbiting-dying-star-what-does-it-mean-6978672]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Newly Found Earth-Like Planet May Hold Key To Humanity's Survival]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-earth-like-world-orbiting-dying-star-what-does-it-mean-6978672]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 13:15:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A team of astronomers has uncovered an Earth-like planet orbiting a star located 4,000 light years away from the solar system, potentially offering insights into Earth's distant future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A team of astronomers has uncovered an Earth-like planet orbiting a star located 4,000 light years away from the solar system, potentially offering insights into Earth's distant future. The rocky planet, about the same mass as Earth, revolves around a white dwarf in the constellation Sagittarius.</p>

<p>The discovery brings a glimmer of hope for Earth's survival when our sun enters its final stages. It suggests that Earth could potentially avoid being consumed by the expanding sun, opening up possibilities for human migration to the outer solar system, with moons such as Europa, Callisto, and Ganymede around Jupiter, or Enceladus near Saturn, becoming possible havens for future generations.</p>

<h2><strong>What is a white dwarf?</strong></h2>

<p>A white dwarf is a star's remnant after it has run out of nuclear fuel and shed its outer layers. It symbolises the sun's eventual fate. The sun will grow into a red giant as its nuclear fuel runs out, then shrink to become a white dwarf. The extent of its expansion will determine which planets in the solar system will be engulfed - Mercury and Venus are likely to be consumed. But what about Earth?</p>

<p>In a study published in Nature Astronomy, researchers from the University of California, Berkeley, used the Keck Telescope in Hawaii to observe a system designated KMT-2020-BLG-0414. The system contains a white dwarf star with an Earth-sized planet in an orbit twice as far from the star as Earth is from the sun. Alongside the planet is a brown dwarf - a planet roughly 17 times the mass of Jupiter.</p>

<p>This finding supports the theory that as the sun expands into a red giant, its loss of mass will push the planets into more distant orbits. This phenomenon could allow Earth to escape destruction. Jessica Lu, an associate professor of astronomy at UC Berkeley, noted, "Whether life can survive on Earth through that (red giant) period is unknown. But certainly, the most important thing is that Earth isn't swallowed by the Sun when it becomes a red giant."</p>

<h2><strong>Future of Earth</strong></h2>

<p>"We do not currently have a consensus whether Earth could avoid being engulfed by the red giant sun in six billion years," said Keming Zhang, the lead author and a former doctoral student at the UC Berkeley, who is now an Eric and Wendy Schmidt AI in Science Postdoctoral fellow at UC San Diego.</p>

<p>"In any case, planet Earth will only be habitable for another billion years, at which point Earth's oceans would be vaporized by the runaway greenhouse effect-long before the risk of getting swallowed by the red giant." &nbsp;</p>

<p>Could humanity find refuge beyond Earth? As the sun swells into a red giant, the habitable zone in the solar system will shift outward to the orbits of Jupiter and Saturn. Many of their moons, such as Europa and Callisto, could become ocean worlds capable of supporting life. Zhang suggested, "Humanity could migrate out there."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jnhu5ru8_exoplanet_625x300_09_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The discovery brings a glimmer of hope for Earth's survival when our sun enters its final stages.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-and-the-inescapable-musical-chairs-of-politics-6978850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Trump And The Inescapable Musical Chairs Of Politics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-and-the-inescapable-musical-chairs-of-politics-6978850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:52:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[For Trump to leave the legacy he wants, he will have to be in offensive tackle mode for the next four years and deliver a magical Reaganesque solution to the working class pain. Or else, the Dems might be back in the White House in 2028.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/vuj2t74_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>As I walked out of my Upper West Side polling station in New York City after casting my vote, the lack of energy in America's most liberal city was palpable. The pins being sold just outside said “Keep Kamala and Carry On-a-la”, but the calmness was about to explode.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Donald Trump's stunning comeback forces an acknowledgement that Americans do not want to simply carry on. Much like India earlier this year. They are increasingly tired of the financial pain that started after the 2008 financial crisis, rendering many of them under-employed. The most powerful ingredients of rapid global economic growth in our lifetimes—globalisation and technological replacement—have ricocheted back to cause acute pain at the working-class Americans' dining tables. And they are hoping, against the odds, that their ballot can overpower that bullet.</p>

<p>This is precisely the reason why, much like the re-emergence of the former President, a defining trend is now categorising the American election cycle. And, I would argue, the Indian election cycle too.</p>

<h2><strong>Incumbents Beware</strong></h2>

<p>This is now the third presidential election since 2016 when the incumbent party has been voted out, a trend not seen since the 1970s when Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter and Ronald Reagan were voted in quick succession as inflation eclipsed all else. Once is an accident. Twice, a coincidence. Three times, a pattern.</p>

<p>In India, the lack of a majority for the incumbent party this year was an indication of that very problem that is proving difficult for any global leader to resolve. In fact, there has been a dissipation of existing power if not an outright change in every major government across the world this year—from the UK and Italy to Germany and Japan, and others.</p>

<p>As Bill Clinton's political strategist Jim Carville stated prophetically thirty years ago, “It's the economy, stupid.” But some would point out that the stock markets are at an all-time high and economic growth was at par in both Trump and Biden years. So, why the discontent? Didn't life seem good enough?</p>

<p>Yes, but only for the elite, whether in the US or India. The elite are the real beneficiaries of the riches-to-riches story. How long can you ignore the larger population that now has to work an average of 2.5 jobs to keep the same lifestyle as a decade ago? In the case of India, too, yes there are cheap mobile phones and food handouts, but job prospects cannot keep up with young aspirations.</p>

<p>In this discontented mix, a message like Trump's, which primarily centres around inflation and its many symptoms—immigration being an obvious one—will obviously be attractive. But so is that of any politician who offers a change in the existing status quo. It is akin to a company changing multiple CEOs in the hope its fortunes will change, not realising that the problem lies in the product itself.</p>

<h2><strong>The Polarisation Card Is Losing Its Edge&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>This election has broken several myths—the overriding one being polarisation—including that echo chambers are permanent and defined and will not sway voters from their trenches. That certainly was the case in 2016, when Trump's winnability was attributed to a fringe base of non-college-educated men. But in 2024, Trump's winnability is attributed to virtually all subsets.</p>

<p>A case in point is young men, and shockingly for the democrats, young men of colour—whether Latino or Indian-American—swinging in Trump's favour. The Left is finally realizing that they cannot club all minorities together, much like the Right in India is realizing the majority cannot always be a single voting bloc. Their loyalty, and more importantly, their ethics, are being questioned. I disagree. This was not a vote for the messenger, it was a vote for the message.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This election has stuck a needle into the bubble of polarisation that the world has sworn by throughout the last decade. Both sides tried to polarise voters, whether it was Trump with immigration or Harris with abortion. But it did not work. There are voters who have chosen Trump and abortion rights. The choice is no longer binary. Above all else, the voters in America are pragmatic.</p>

<p>The same is true for India. The 2024 India voting reflected the discontent among ordinary voters, where the economy superseded everything else. The conservative argument of caste or religious lines shaping voting patterns is increasingly becoming redundant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As it has long been said, democracy is a luxury when there is not enough food on the table. But there are also similarities between the out-of-touch ‘Khan market gang' in India and America's coastal elite. Instead of focusing on the real issue of voter pain, the Democrats' and the Indian Opposition's patronising tone of ‘How could you vote for him?' reeked of moral superiority borne out of privilege, not realism.</p>

<h2><strong>Only Betting Markets Got It Right &nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>The media and the pollsters have got it so far wrong that they are in danger of losing their voice. These echo chambers are now functioning as cheerleaders of political thought. They dole out a narrative rather than acting as arbiters of reason. It is ironic that the most truthful picture came from sources that are often the most tainted in history—the betting markets in the US and the satta bazaar in India. Whether Trump's sweep or the Bharatiya Janata Party's (BJP) underperformance, they were the only ones who got it right.</p>

<h2><strong>Kamala Played Well</strong></h2>

<p>Kamala Harris also emerged as a hero to many. Clearly, many things that were out of her control went wrong for her: Biden's selfishness in holding on to power, the war fatigue, and the all-important anti-incumbency.&nbsp;</p>

<p>When my 10-year-old daughter accompanying me to the voting booth asked me why a woman gets passed yet again for the most powerful job in the world, I told her to walk tall the next day. Because in the shortest presidential campaign in American history, of only 107 days, Kamala managed to achieve the impossible and did better than any reasonable hope. LOTUS for POTUS simply did not have enough time to bloom.</p>

<p>I do not think America acted like it did in 2016 and chose to vote against a female President. The pain threshold that Trump pressed on was much lower on Maslow's needs chart for the gender ceiling in American politics to even be a conversation. A famous meme from the Kamala campaign was a father going with his daughter to the polling booth and saying he was voting for her. I believe the father did still vote for his daughter, not necessarily as a mark of support for the candidate but as an act of hope of providing his family with a better life.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Needs A Hail Mary&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>But will Trump be able to deliver on that hope? In the America of the 1980s, the Republican party's modern hero, Ronald Reagan, achieved the impossible as he took on the structural inflation problem, giving birth to decades of prosperity.</p>

<p>For Trump to leave the legacy he wants, he will have to be in offensive tackle mode for the next four years and deliver a magical Reaganesque solution to the working class pain. Or else, given the musical chairs game global politics has become, the Dems will be back in the White House in 2028.</p>

<p><em>(Namrata Brar is an Indian-American journalist, investigative reporter, and news anchor. She is the former US bureau chief of NDTV)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the authors</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/sq17krb_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-astronauts-share-struggles-of-returning-to-earth-after-235-days-in-space-6978196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Weight Of Things Is Surprising": NASA Astronauts After 235 Days In Space]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-astronauts-share-struggles-of-returning-to-earth-after-235-days-in-space-6978196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:38:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The astronauts, who spent months aboard the ISS, faced a brief and unexpected hospitalisation after their return]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three NASA astronauts, who recently returned to Earth after a 235-day stay in space, have shed light on the challenges of readjusting to gravity and life on the planet. Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt and Jeanette Epps returned to Earth on October 25 aboard a SpaceX Crew Dragon capsule. During a NASA conference, they discussed the physical toll the mission had on their bodies.<br />
<br />
Dominick, a first-time space traveller and mission commander, revealed that while he expected dizziness and disorientation upon returning to Earth's gravity, some of the smaller struggles took him by surprise. “The big things you expect — being disoriented, being dizzy. But the little things like just sitting in a hard chair … My backside has not really sat on a hard thing for (235) days.” He also shared an amusing anecdote from a recent dinner with his family, where he found himself lying on a towel in the yard due to the discomfort of sitting.<br />
<br />
Epps, reflecting on the physical changes she faced, noted the unexpected weight and heaviness of objects once she returned to Earth. “The weight and the heaviness of things just is surprising, (I've been) laying any chance I got. But you have to move, and you have to exercise every day, otherwise you won't get those gains. You have to move regardless of how exhausted you feel,” she said.<br />
<br />
The astronauts, who spent months aboard the ISS, faced a brief and unexpected hospitalisation after their return. While NASA confirmed that all crew members were taken to Ascension Sacred Heart Pensacola “out of an abundance of caution,” details surrounding the medical issue, which led to one astronaut staying overnight at the hospital, have not been made public.<br />
<br />
Dominick, Barratt, Epps, and Russian cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin, who also participated in the mission, were originally scheduled to return home earlier, but their return was delayed by scheduling conflicts with other spacecraft and weather conditions. The Crew-8 astronauts' mission duration was extended by a few weeks due to these unforeseen delays.<br />
<br />
Barratt, a medical doctor and veteran astronaut, stressed the importance of medical privacy concerning the situation. "Medical privacy and the processes we have going on right now negate our ability to (discuss the issue),” he said during the press conference.<br />
<br />
According to <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/08/science/spacex-nasa-crew-8-astronauts-update/index.html">CNN</a>, medical checkups are routine after extended space missions. But astronauts are usually transported back to their base in Houston for reconditioning following splashdown, allowing them to transition back to Earth's gravity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/onsq8jco_nasa-astronauts-who-returned-from-space-_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The astronauts, who spent months in space, faced a brief, unexpected hospitalisation upon their return.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-discontinues-popular-student-visa-scheme-how-it-affects-indians-6978676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Discontinues Popular Student Visa Scheme: How It Affects Indians]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-discontinues-popular-student-visa-scheme-how-it-affects-indians-6978676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:23:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada discontinued its Student Direct Stream visa program for international students, amid a push by the country to cope with its housing and resource crisis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada on Friday discontinued its Student Direct Stream (SDS) visa program for international students, amid a push by the country to cope with its housing and resource crisis.</p>

<p>The program was implemented in 2018 by the Immigration, Refugees and Citizenship Canada (IRCC) to expedite study permit applications for international students from 14 countries, including Brazil, China, Colombia, Costa Rica, India, Morocco, Pakistan, Peru, Philippines and Vietnam. The g<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/news/notices/end-student-direct-stream-nigeria-student-express.html">overnment of Canada</a> said on its website that the initiative is being discontinued to "strengthen program integrity, address student vulnerability, and give all students equal and fair access to the application process".</p>

<p>Applications received till 2 pm ET on November 8 under the scheme will be processed, whereas all applications after this will be processed under the regular study permit stream.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The program had higher approval rates and faster processing times. With the discontinuation of this program, students from India and 13 other countries will have to undergo more lengthy visa processes.</p>

<p>Canada is looking to sharply lower the number of immigrants it allows into the country for the first time in years, in a dramatic policy change for an unpopular government trying to hang on to power.</p>

<p>A country that has long prided itself on welcoming newcomers, Canada is now moving the rhetoric towards migrants leading to a housing crisis, from rising cost of living to a strained healthcare system.</p>

<p>The issue has become one of the most contentious in Canadian politics with a federal election due no later than October 2025. Polls show a growing share of the population thinks Canada has too many immigrants.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-04/student-visa-pixabay_650x400_81522727800.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canada is looking to sharply lower the number of immigrants it allows into the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blast-rocks-railway-station-in-pakistan-21-killed-cctv-captures-moment-6978628]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blast Rocks Railway Station In Pakistan, 25 Killed, CCTV Captures Moment]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blast-rocks-railway-station-in-pakistan-21-killed-cctv-captures-moment-6978628]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:18:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A suspected suicide blast by an ethnic militant group rocked a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan region this morning, killing at least 24 people and injuring 46 others.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A suspected suicide blast by an ethnic militant group rocked a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan region this morning, killing 25 people and injuring 46 others. The victims included at least 14 soldiers, the police said. CCTV footage showed dozens of people waiting on the platform when the blast ripped through Quetta's main railway station.</p>

<p>Bodies were seen scattered across the platform and the roof was blown away. There was blood everywhere as rescue workers went through abandoned luggage to find survivors.</p>

<p>The blast occurred when the Jaffer express was about to depart for Peshawar, said a senior police official, adding that it seemed to be a suicide blast. Baloch Liberation Army (BLA), an ethnic militant group in the region, has claimed responsibility for the blast.</p>

<p>Reports suggest the explosion occurred at the railway station's booking office. Law enforcement teams immediately secured the area and took the injured to the civil hospital in Quetta, said the provincial government spokesperson Shahid Rind.</p>

<p>Officials said at least 46 injured were brought to the hospital in the aftermath of the blast. The hospital declared an emergency and called additional staff to attend the injured.</p>

<p>"The blast targeted army personnel from the Infantry School," said Mouzzam Jah Ansari, the Inspector General of Police in Balochistan.</p>

<p>Balochistan Chief Minister Sarfraz Bugti has ordered an immediate probe and condemned the attack as "a horrific act" that targeted innocent civilians. "The terrorists' target now are innocent people, labourers, children, and women. Those targeting innocent people do not deserve mercy," Dawn quoted him as saying.</p>

<p>The blast comes as Pakistan grapples with a rise in terror attacks by ethnic militant groups. Nearly three months ago, a wave of attacks on police stations and highways in Balochistan claimed at least 73 lives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cdq9cedg_pakistan-blast_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bodies were seen scattered across the platform]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-farhad-shakeri-afghan-man-behind-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-trump-6978018]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Farhad Shakeri, Afghan Man Behind Alleged Iran Plot To Kill Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-farhad-shakeri-afghan-man-behind-alleged-iran-plot-to-kill-trump-6978018]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:31:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Farhad Shakeri, an Afghan national who was deported from the United States in 2008, has been accused of plotting to assassinate Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Farhad Shakeri, an Afghan national who was deported from the United States in 2008, has been accused of plotting to assassinate Donald Trump. The 51-year-old allegedly masterminded a murder-for-hire operation in coordination with the Iranian Islamic Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC).</p>

<p>On November 8, Shakeri and two others were charged in a criminal complaint for their alleged involvement in the plot to assassinate a US citizen of Iranian descent in New York. While the other two suspects were arrested, Shakeri remains at large and is believed to be in Iran.</p>

<p>According to a criminal complaint, in September 2024, Shakeri was instructed by an official from the IRGC to focus on “assassinating, former President of the United States, Donald J. Trump.” This directive came after Shakeri had already been involved in multiple operations on behalf of the IRGC, utilising his criminal network to support the group's agenda.</p>

<p>The criminal complaint added that according to Shakeri, during his meeting with an IRGC official on or about October 7, 2024, he was instructed to provide a plan within seven days to kill Trump. If Shakeri failed to do so within that timeframe, the IRGC official said the plan would be delayed until after the US Presidential elections. It was believed that Trump would lose, and it would then be easier to carry out the assassination. Shakeri told the FBI that he did not intend to propose a plan within the set deadline.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice stated, “Shakeri has informed law enforcement that he was tasked on October 7, 2024, with providing a plan to kill President-elect Donald J. Trump. During the interview, Shakeri claimed he did not intend to propose a plan to kill Trump within the timeframe set by the IRGC.”</p>

<p>Shakeri was also assigned to keep an eye on two Jewish American citizens in New York and was offered $500,000 by an IRGC official for the murder of either target. Additionally, he was instructed to target Israeli tourists in Sri Lanka.</p>

<h2><strong>Background of Farhad Shakeri</strong></h2>

<p>Shakeri, an asset of the IRGC based in Tehran, immigrated to the US as a child. He was deported in 2008 after serving 14 years for a robbery conviction. In recent months, Shakeri has been involved in leveraging a network of criminal associates he met in US prisons to assist the IRGC. He has reportedly been supplying the IRGC with operatives for conducting surveillance and assassinations targeting individuals of interest, according to the US Department of Justice.</p>

<p>Though he was deported in 2008, his parole monitoring continued until 2015. In 2019, he was detained in Sri Lanka in connection with the seizure of a large quantity of heroin, highlighting an ongoing series of alleged criminal activities linked to his network.</p>

<p>Shakeri faces multiple charges, including conspiring to provide material support to a foreign terrorist organisation, which could result in up to 20 years in prison. He is also charged with providing material support to the same organisation, as well as conspiring to violate sanctions against the Iranian government under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, each of which carries a potential 20-year prison sentence.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s3p31418_trump-afp_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Farhad Shakeri was instructed by an IRGC official to focus on assassinating Trump (file)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-killed-30-injured-in-railway-station-blast-in-pakistan-report-6978296]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[21 Killed, 46 Injured In Railway Station Blast In Pakistan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-killed-30-injured-in-railway-station-blast-in-pakistan-report-6978296]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:15:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 21 people were killed and 46 others injured on Saturday in a powerful bomb explosion at a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan province.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 21 people were killed and 46 others injured on Saturday in a powerful bomb explosion at a crowded railway station in Pakistan's restive Balochistan province, officials said.</p>

<p>The explosion ripped through the provincial capital Quetta's railway station as passengers gathered on the platform before the scheduled departure of the Jaffar Express to Peshawar.</p>

<p>Quetta Senior Superintendent Police (SSP) Operations Muhammad Baloch said initial findings point to a possible suicide bombing.</p>

<p>He also confirmed that 21 people were killed in the explosion, adding that the number of victims could rise.</p>

<p>Baloch Liberation Army (BLA) has claimed responsibility for the attack.</p>

<p>Preliminary reports indicate that the explosion took place at the railway station's booking office.</p>

<p>Rescue and law enforcement teams responded immediately, securing the area and transporting the injured and dead to Civil Hospital Quetta, according to the provincial government spokesperson Shahid Rind.</p>

<p>An emergency was declared at the hospital where additional medical staff was summoned to deal with the injured, where officials said that 46 injured have been shifted so far.</p>

<p>The blast, which also damaged the platform's roof, was heard far and wide in various areas of the city.</p>

<p>Balochistan Chief Minister Sarfraz Bugti condemned the attack, terming it as "a horrific act targeting innocent civilians", and ordered an immediate investigation.</p>

<p>He said that terrorists are increasingly aiming civilians, labourers, women, and children, and vowed that those responsible would be pursued relentlessly.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/fdrlr07g_pak-blasts_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Officials said the train had not arrived at the platform at the time of the blast. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-2-0-doubling-down-or-back-to-zero-6978279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Trump 2.0: Doubling Down Or Back To Zero?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-2-0-doubling-down-or-back-to-zero-6978279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:11:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As Trump prepares to saunter to the White House yet again, it is worthwhile to quote John Wayne, the famous Hollywood Wild West icon: "A man deserves a second chance, but keep an eye on him."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ucnv8l_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>The results of the US elections held last week have produced both relief and shock in equal measure.</p>

<p>The world at large and the Americans in particular are relieved that even if the outcome was largely unexpected, it was unambiguous, decisive and uncontested. This belied many foreboding predictions. There was a clear swing towards the hard right, with the Republican Party making major gains. Donald Trump, its candidate, defied all odds to win the Presidency. The Republicans expanded their control of the Senate and are poised for a majority in the House of Representatives as well. Factoring in the right-leaning Supreme Court and Federal Reserve under pressure to ease its ‘tight money' policy—the GOP has never had it this good for a long time.</p>

<h2><strong>A Rude Shock For All</strong></h2>

<p>On the other hand, the “winner taking it all” outcome was a rude surprise not only for the defeated Democrats but also for the psephologists and the mainstream media, who predicted a victory for Kamala Harris and a greater countervailing balance in Congress. Few expected a massive popular endorsement of Mr Trump, a populist with controversial views often bordering on unsubstantiated extremism. To many, the outcome raised questions about the maturity of the electorate and fidelity to the electoral process itself. Despite a booming economy, low inflation and low unemployment, the American voter succumbed to clever manipulation of popular perceptions with pet popular peeves about immigration, globalisation and personal economics being weaponised. For many, this was not an outcome the US deserved.</p>

<p>But now that this is a<em> fait accompli</em>, the larger question that needs to be answered is: How will this binary split play out during the incoming Trump Presidency? A lot would depend on whether Trump 2.0 would hark back to Trump 1.0 or whether the experiences of being the 45th President have been internalised for the 47th Presidency. This requires a granular analysis to discern the likely course of Trump 2.0.</p>

<h2><strong>An Unapologetic Trump&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>To begin with, some basic observations are in order. Firstly, when the 78-year-old person concerned is not only unapologetic but triumphant about his past term, it raises some pertinent issues about his plans for the future in a vastly different context. Most of the catchy electoral promises made by candidate Trump were bare-bone intentions without precise targets. Similarly, many of the policy priorities articulated during the campaign intersect domestic and foreign affairs. Some of the planned and pre-announced quick fixes for the beginning of Trump 2.0 may open new Pandora's boxes. Further, given the unpredictability and transactional inconsistencies seen in Trump 1.0—from building an anti-immigrant wall on the southern border to the Summits with Kim Jong Un—were infructuous and were quietly abandoned. It cast doubts about keeping the new promises. Lastly, the bitter polarisation and name-calling of Trump 1.0 is a legacy that may haunt Trump 2.0. All these tactical complexities and shifts presage a pattern making Trump 2.0 invariably joined at the hip with Trump 1.0.</p>

<h2><strong>Pardons To MAGA To Immigration, A Domestic Roller-Coaster</strong></h2>

<p>Opening overtures of Trump 2.0 are likely to be dominated by domestic agenda. It's partly because his support base expects it and also because he has greater authority to do so. Firing inconvenient officials and presidential pardons, etc, are likely to be in the first flush. It may follow some measures at score-settling with “the enemies within” even as the bite may be less than the bark. He would find ways to flesh out his catchphrases such as “America First” and “Make America Great Again". Stopping illegal immigration and deporting those who have already done so would be a priority, even as some of these measures may be legally questionable.</p>

<p>On the economic side, Trump 2.0 may prune welfare spending and have a smaller government to balance with the promised lowering of taxes. Other intended moves such as high tariffs on imports and “Drill, Baby, Drill” may have collateral consequences in terms of trade wars, higher inflation, further demonise the “big oil”, environmental damage and lower export revenues. Rewarding Elon Musk and other corporate friends may lead to allegations of crony capitalism. The US political system does grant the President a high degree of impunity and the political context at the Congress and Supreme Court may be salubrious. Nevertheless, Mr Trump comes with the baggage of having been impeached twice and has the dubious distinction of being the first US President found guilty of 34 felony counts. His penchant for leaving a positive legacy is likely to restrain him.</p>

<h2><strong>The World Has Changed</strong>—<strong>For Trump, Too</strong></h2>

<p>In the foreign policy domain, President Trump would discover that the international context has turned far more complicated and nuanced. Despite bragging about his foreign policy accomplishments, Trump 1.0 was scarred by failed tactical initiatives, such as a deal with the Taliban, mollycoddling autocrats, reneging on the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA) with Iran, antagonising longstanding partners, undermining multilateral architecture, etc. No wonder most partners reacted cautiously to the Trump victory. Even the ruling British Labour Party, for instance, had to painfully ruminate over the serious pejoratives it used to describe Trump 1.0. The rightist fringes in Europe and Israel have warmly welcomed his re-ascendence. The countries demonised during Trump 1.0, such as China, and Iran, reacted with predictable defiance.</p>

<p>The reactions to his elections were a foretaste of the kind of difficulties Trump 2.0 is likely to face as his ambitious agenda. While the US remains the world's primordial superpower, her hard and soft powers are significantly lower now, making unilateral pursuit of a wish list more difficult, particularly as he promises to avoid military engagements abroad. Trump 1.0 diplomacy was more about treating the symptoms than the disease. Living in denial was an often-exercised option on softer global issues such as climate change and disarmament. These tactical approaches merely kicked the can down the road, making the hotspots more numerous, more entrenched and intractable as evinced in the South China Sea, the Urals and the Middle East. Further, the cynical transactional approaches of Trump 1.0 lacked moral underpinnings, often reducing them to exercises in cynical manipulations and/or arm-twisting. More dangerously, it often allowed Trump's interlocutors to pander to flattery or deception to get their goals.</p>

<h2><strong>'A Man Deserves A Second Chance, But...'</strong></h2>

<p>The US under Trump 2.0 has two divergent options: isolationism and living in denial and inverted snobbery, or getting down from the moral horse and engaging either singly or through the same multilateral institutions that were often disfranchised during Trump 1.0. If Trump 2.0 intends to go beyond the palliatives deals and resolve the stubborn global crises, it would need to reinvent and realign itself with the new realities of the China-Russia nexus, more assertive middle-rung countries, including India, Brazil, Mexico, Iran, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela, France, Germany, etc. Even traditional partners such as the UK, Japan, Australia, and Israel need to be courted afresh.</p>

<p>With his disregard for conventions, clipped deliveries, one-liners and over-the-top High Noons too often, Trump 1.0 styled itself more as an urbane cowboy than the conventional politician. We do not know if the invocation to resonate with the WASP psyche was accidental or deliberate. As he prepares to saunter to the White House yet again, it is worthwhile to quote John Wayne, the famous Hollywood Wild West icon: "A man deserves a second chance, but keep an eye on him."</p>

<p><em>(Mahesh Sachdev is a former Indian Ambassador. He currently heads Eco-Diplomacy and Strategies, a Delhi-based consultancy)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hkkhbshg_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-australia-today-row-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-threatened-us-australian-outlet-facing-canada-ban-6974746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Khalistani Terrorist Threatened Us': Australian Outlet Facing Canada Ban]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-australia-today-row-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-threatened-us-australian-outlet-facing-canada-ban-6974746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 11:05:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Australia Today founder and editor-in-chief Jitarth Jai Bhardwaj has questioned the Justin Trudeau government as to why the rights of the Hindu community in Canada are not being upheld.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling the blocking of the prominent diaspora outlet 'Australia Today' by Canada, the "murder of free press", its founder and editor-in-chief Jitarth Jai Bhardwaj questioned the Justin Trudeau government as to why the rights of the Hindu community in the country are not being upheld, as they face "repeated attacks on their places of worship."</p>

<p>This comes after Canada blocked the outlet's social media handles and pages shortly after it aired a press conference of External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar with his Australian counterpart Penny Wong in Canberra. During the presser, the EAM slammed Canada for making allegations against India without any specific evidence and termed the "surveillance of Indian diplomats" unacceptable and also highlighted that the "political space has been given in Canada to anti-India elements."</p>

<p>On Thursday, the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) also lambasted Canada for its "hypocrisy towards freedom of speech" following the blocking of 'The Australia Today' in the country.</p>

<p>Following the blocking by the Trudeau government, Mr Bhardwaj raised concerns over the move and said the publication would continue to advocate for open media.</p>

<p>In an interview with ANI, Mr Bhardwaj opened up about how their supporters notified them about not being able to access the outlet's content in Canada. After that, they found out that the press conference and interview of EAM Jaishankar went off the social media platform.</p>

<p>"We were notified by a lot of readers, followers of our page that they are not able to watch or view our content on Facebook and Instagram which they were able to watch like 10-15 minutes back and now they were not. They were trying to share it with their friends and colleagues and all of a sudden the press conference and the interview went off from the Facebook page and there was a notification written there that this content was not available for viewing in Canada by the order of Canadian government legislation," he said.</p>

<p>Condemning the Trudeau government's "dictatorial" move as a "murder of press freedom", the editor of the outlet said there should be a space for diverse views in a democracy.</p>

<p>"This is a murder of press freedom. This is not free speech, this is not how democracies act, and this is the way for dictators to act and clamp down on the press. In every democracy, there is space for diverse views and for the press to debate, interpret, analyse all those diverse views," Mr Bhardwaj said.</p>

<p>He added, "It seems that Canada is not kind of happy with how we were asking questions to Indian and Australian foreign ministers and they were not happy to see that a lot of Canadians were responding to it and they were trying to educate themselves than what Canadian government has been propagating for long now."</p>

<p>The Australia Today founder further elaborated on the news coverage of his outlet, and said they aim to provide coverage to the 'vibrant' Indian democracy, which he said, is being "left out".</p>

<p>"Australia Today is a news outlet that works for multicultural communities in the West. We do stories from UK, Canada, US, Australia, New Zealand, Fiji, Singapore, everywhere the Indian diaspora is hardworking and vibrant. Their stories are important, however, they are being left out by the so-called mainstream media, and this platform Australia Today highlights the issues which are very important to the Indian Australian community and Indian diaspora as a whole," he said.</p>

<p>While stating that the coverage of 'The Australia Today' is being appreciated everywhere for highlighting the condition of the Indian community, Mr Bhardwaj also shed light on the 'threats' received by the outlet. He alleged that the news platform and its journalists have been threatened by India-designated terrorist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun and other Khalistani extremists.</p>

<p>"Our coverage about what is happening by Khalistani groups in Canada or in the US was getting a lot of traction there. Our reporting was being appreciated in all the places. Gurpatwant Singh Pannun threatened us after issuing a video. He put pictures of me and my team online, telling his supporters to harm us in different ways. This has been going on and we have been reporting continuously without fear," he said.</p>

<p>Referring to the situation in Canada, 'The Australia Today' editor-in-chief said that the Hindu community is being "attacked, persecuted and suppressed" not just by the extremist elements, but also by the police and the authorities.</p>

<p>He also said that his outlet is willing to interview Prime Minister Justin Trudeau and ministers and ask why the rights of the Hindu community are not being realised in his country as they continue to face one untoward incident after the other.</p>

<p>"I'm just a reporter. I can report on what is going on. So I can say that the Hindu community is being attacked in Canada right now. The Hindu community is being persecuted in Canada right now by police, RCMP, and authorities. Everyone is working as if to suppress the rights of Canadian Hindu citizens," Mr Bhardwaj said.</p>

<p>"That's what I see right now and that's what we are reporting. If Trudeau or his ministers are happy to talk to us, we are happy to interview them and ask simple questions that any and every journalist should be asking them right now. Why Hindu community in Canada is being treated the way they are being treated? Why their rights are not upheld? Why are their temples being attacked? These are the questions Trudeau should be answering right now," he added.</p>

<p>Being asked about whether 'The Australia Today' will try to challenge the Canadian government's order, the editor said they would focus on reporting the issues of Canadian citizens without any fear.</p>

<p>"I don't think Canadian government is listening right now. But we will not stop doing what we do, that is reporting. Reporting the issues of Canadian citizens, Canadian Indians, and multilingual communities. That we will keep on doing," Mr Bhardwaj stressed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-10/l8063v1o_gurpatwant-singh-pannun-twitter_625x300_12_October_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-official-meets-taliban-minister-ex-afghan-president-hamid-karzai-6978130]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Official Meets Taliban Minister, Ex Afghan President Hamid Karzai]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-official-meets-taliban-minister-ex-afghan-president-hamid-karzai-6978130]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:49:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a significant move, an Indian delegation met Afghanistan's acting Defence Minister Mullah Mohammad Yaqoob and offered the use of Chabahar Port in Iran to businesses in his country, and also discussed extending humanitarian assistance to Kabul.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant move, an Indian delegation met Afghanistan's acting Defence Minister Mullah Mohammad Yaqoob and offered the use of Chabahar Port in Iran to businesses in his country, and also discussed extending humanitarian assistance to Kabul.</p>

<p>The delegation was led by J P Singh, the Joint Secretary of the Pakistan-Afghanistan-Iran division in the External Affairs Ministry.</p>

<p>During a weekly media briefing here, External Affairs Ministry spokesman Randhir Jaiswal said that apart from Mohammad Yaqoob, the delegation also met with former President Hamid Karzai and other senior ministers, along with the heads of UN agencies.</p>

<p>"They had discussions on India's humanitarian assistance, also how the Chabahar Port can be utilised by the business community in Afghanistan for transactions and for export and import and any other thing that they would like to do," Jaiswal said in response to a question.</p>

<p>India does not recognise the Taliban regime that has been ruling Afghanistan since 2021.</p>

<p>India has been providing humanitarian aid, including wheat, medicines and medical supplies, to the Afghan people from time to time.</p>

<p>"I also want to recall here that providing humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan is an important part of our assistance programme and so far in the last few months, and a few years, we have dispatched several shipments of humanitarian assistance. We have longstanding ties with the people of Afghanistan, and these ties will continue to guide our approach towards the country," Jaiswal said.</p>

<p>Earlier this year, India signed a 10-year contract with Iran to develop and operate the Chabahar Port which was built with its assistance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/1eemmk2_indian-delegate-meets-taliban-leader-_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India does not recognise the Taliban regime that has been ruling Afghanistan since 2021.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978124]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oxford University Student Died By Suicide Due To 'Cancel Culture': Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978124]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:45:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A consultant who investigated the case stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The suicide of a student at Oxford University has led to calls to review the 'cancel culture' prevalent in the elite institutions of the UK. Alexander Rogers (20), a third-year studying materials science at Corpus Christi College, took his own life in January earlier this year, after being 'ostracised' by his peers, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/11/07/oxford-student-kills-himself-cancel-culture-inquest-suicide/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Following two-day inquest proceedings at Oxford Coroner's Court, coroner Nicholas Graham concluded that the ostracisation "led him to form an intention to take his own life". The final report added that Rogers was "distraught" that his friends shunned him following an unreported allegation.</p>

<p>A former partner had alleged "discomfort over a sexual encounter" involving Rogers on January 11. Four days later, on January 15, a missing person's report was filed as Rogers wrote to friends, expressing "remorse for his actions and a belief that they were unintentional but unforgivable". His body was later pulled from the River Thames.</p>

<p>"While what we are dealing with here is in the interest of the public the family additionally has to carry the unique burden of grief, which is a heavy one. From what we have heard Alexander was an extremely able and popular young man and his passing is sad indeed," Graham added.</p>

<p>Dr Dominique Thompson, an independent consultant who investigated the case, stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture". She added that the allegation levelled caused a "pile-on" effect of students siding against Rogers because of an "unwritten" moral code to "do the right thing".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/anurag-kashyap-on-defending-sandeep-reddy-vanga-s-animal-5666884" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Asked To Explain His Sandeep Reddy Vanga Post, Anurag Kashyap Says: "Don't Like This Cancel Culture"</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>University taking action</strong></h3>

<p>Notably, the university was not aware of the cancel culture before the report and has since accepted its recommendations which "are being addressed with some diligence".</p>

<p>"Oxford University and Corpus Christi College extend our deepest sympathies to Alexander's family and everyone in our community who has been saddened by his tragic death," read a statement by the university.</p>

<p>"The College commissioned an independent review to identify all learning in this case with the aim of minimising the chance of such a tragic loss happening again," it added.</p>

<p>A prevention of future death report has also been sent to the Department of Education to consider the prevalence of "cancel culture" across higher education.</p>

<p>Roger's family said their priority was ensuring that the culture of social ostracisation is recognised so that similar tragedies can be prevented from reoccurring.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k1099l_alexander-rogers-suicide_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alexander Rogers took his life in January earlier this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Oxford University Student Died By Suicide Due To 'Cancel Culture', Probe Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/oxford-university-student-committed-suicide-due-to-cancel-culture-probe-finds-6978121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:45:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A consultant who investigated the case stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The suicide of a student at Oxford University has led to calls to review the 'cancel culture' prevalent in the elite institutions of the UK. Alexander Rogers (20), a third-year studying materials science at Corpus Christi College, took his own life in January earlier this year, after being 'ostracised' by his peers, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2024/11/07/oxford-student-kills-himself-cancel-culture-inquest-suicide/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>The Telegraph</em></a>. Following two-day inquest proceedings at Oxford Coroner's Court, coroner Nicholas Graham concluded that the ostracisation "led him to form an intention to take his own life". The final report added that Rogers was "distraught" that his friends shunned him following an unreported allegation.</p>

<p>A former partner had alleged "discomfort over a sexual encounter" involving Rogers on January 11. Four days later, on January 15, a missing person's report was filed as Rogers wrote to friends, expressing "remorse for his actions and a belief that they were unintentional but unforgivable". His body was later pulled from the River Thames.</p>

<p>"While what we are dealing with here is in the interest of the public the family additionally has to carry the unique burden of grief, which is a heavy one. From what we have heard Alexander was an extremely able and popular young man and his passing is sad indeed," Graham added.</p>

<p>Dr Dominique Thompson, an independent consultant who investigated the case, stated that Rogers' exclusion from the college community was characteristic of a "pervasive cancel culture". She added that the allegation levelled caused a "pile-on" effect of students siding against Rogers because of an "unwritten" moral code to "do the right thing".</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/entertainment/anurag-kashyap-on-defending-sandeep-reddy-vanga-s-animal-5666884" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Asked To Explain His Sandeep Reddy Vanga Post, Anurag Kashyap Says: "Don't Like This Cancel Culture"</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>University taking action</strong></h3>

<p>Notably, the university was not aware of the cancel culture before the report and has since accepted its recommendations which "are being addressed with some diligence".</p>

<p>"Oxford University and Corpus Christi College extend our deepest sympathies to Alexander's family and everyone in our community who has been saddened by his tragic death," read a statement by the university.</p>

<p>"The College commissioned an independent review to identify all learning in this case with the aim of minimising the chance of such a tragic loss happening again," it added.</p>

<p>A prevention of future death report has also been sent to the Department of Education to consider the prevalence of "cancel culture" across higher education.</p>

<p>Roger's family said their priority was ensuring that the culture of social ostracisation is recognised so that similar tragedies can be prevented from reoccurring.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k1099l_alexander-rogers-suicide_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alexander Rogers took his life in January earlier this year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-net-worth-surpasses-300-billion-after-donald-trumps-us-election-win-6978055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Musk's Net Worth Surpasses $300 Billion After Trump's US Election Win]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-net-worth-surpasses-300-billion-after-donald-trumps-us-election-win-6978055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:31:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk has added more to his personal fortune since Donald Trump's US election win than anyone else tracked by the Bloomberg Billionaires Index.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's net worth has surpassed $300 billion for the first time in almost three years, as shares of Tesla Inc. soar on bets that his close ties with President-elect Donald Trump will bolster the company.</p>

<p>Musk has added more to his personal fortune since Trump's win than anyone else tracked by the Bloomberg Billionaires Index. Tesla's stock has jumped 28% since Tuesday's close, increasing his wealth by $50 billion to $313.7 billion.</p>

<p>Trump has openly suggested moves that would benefit Musk's businesses. He said he'd reconsider his plans to slow the move to electric vehicles because of the Tesla co-founder's backing. Trump also voiced support for SpaceX, which makes up $82 billion of Musk's net worth, and its push to reach Mars. And the president-elect has floated the idea of Musk serving in a newly created role in his administration as efficiency czar.</p>

<p>"One of the best strategic bets he ever made was ultimately this bet on Trump," Wedbush Securities analyst Dan Ives said Thursday on Bloomberg TV. "Musk is the big winner in this Trump sweepstakes."</p>

<p>Musk inserted himself late into the presidential race, campaigning alongside Trump in the weeks leading up to the election and bankrolling stunts such as a $1 million daily sweepstakes for voters in battleground states. He became a part of Trump's inner circle, spending election night at Mar-a-Lago in Palm Beach.</p>

<p>Musk, 53, is the only person to ever have a fortune in excess of $300 billion, a mark he last reached in January 2022, according to Bloomberg's wealth index. It's still short of his all-time high of $340.4 billion in 2021.</p>

<p>Even before the election, Musk's net worth had been on the rise, with strong Tesla earnings in mid-October adding $34 billion to his fortune in a day.</p>

<p>Most of Musk's fortune is tied up in Tesla, the world's largest electric-vehicle manufacturer, whose prospects depend heavily on the federal government. Musk said during a Tesla earnings call last month that he'd push for a federal approval process for autonomous vehicles - a centerpiece of the company's future strategy - if selected for a role in the Trump administration.</p>

<p>Trump initially said he'd roll back EV initiatives in his acceptance speech at the Republican National Convention in July, but changed his position a month later.</p>

<p>"I'm for electric cars," Trump said at a rally in Atlanta. "I have to be, because Elon endorsed me very strongly."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/lpgnudlg_elon-musk-donald-trump-bloomberg_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk has close ties with US President-elect Donald Trump]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharifs-message-to-donald-trump-an-x-faux-pas-6978004]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak PM Shehbaz Sharif Congratulates Donald Trump On X, Gets Community Noted]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pakistan-pm-shehbaz-sharifs-message-to-donald-trump-an-x-faux-pas-6978004]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:21:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif extended his congratulations to Donald Trump for his "historic victory" in securing a second term as US President.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif extended his congratulations to Donald Trump for his "historic victory" in securing a second term as US President. However, the message, posted on X (formerly Twitter), came with a faux pas - given that Sharif's government has imposed a nationwide ban on the platform.</p>

<p>Sharif's post, which wished Trump well and expressed an eagerness to "strengthen and broaden the Pakistan - US partnership," was immediately flagged with a Community Note. The note pointed out that the Pakistani Prime Minister was in fact accessing the platform via a VPN, which, according to Pakistan's legal framework, is in violation of national regulations.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif has banned X (formerly Twitter) in Pakistan. He is using a VPN to access X, which is unlawful according to Pakistani law," the X Community Note read.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ev9d7an_shehbaz-sharif-twitter-community-note_625x300_09_November_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Screengrab of Shehbaz Sharif's post that received a Community Note on X.</p>
</div>

<p>Pakistan's interior ministry announced in April that access to X had been blocked due to national security concerns, with users reporting difficulties accessing the platform since mid-February. Despite the government's official stance, Sharif and other officials appear to have found ways to bypass the block using VPNs. In fact, many Pakistani leaders, including those from Sharif's own party, have continued to use the platform freely, ignoring their own legal restrictions.</p>

<p>The ban itself has stirred controversy. Initially, the government cited concerns over the platform's refusal to comply with local laws, including the controversial 2021 law called Removal and Blocking of Unlawful Online Content Rules. The government also raised alarms over "hostile elements" using social media to destabilise Pakistan, but critics argue that the restriction is politically motivated, particularly in the wake of allegations of election rigging.</p>

<p>Sharif's own political rival, Imran Khan, has been one of the most vocal users of social media in Pakistan, particularly X, &nbsp;where his party, the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI), has garnered millions of followers. Khan, in jail now, claimed that his ousting in 2022 was orchestrated by the military and that the elections earlier this year were manipulated to keep his party out of power. The government's restriction of X, some suggest, is an attempt to silence such opinions, particularly as the platform has been a critical outlet for dissent.</p>

<p>Critics argue that the Ministry of Interior overstepped its bounds in imposing the restriction, bypassing the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority (PTA), which is the only body authorised to regulate online content under the Prevention of Electronic Crimes Act, 2016. The real motivation behind the ban is to force X to comply with local censorship demands, as has been the case with other platforms like YouTube and TikTok.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/au3tdfno_shehbaz-sharif-reuters_625x300_04_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pakistan's interior ministry announced in April that access to X was blocked over national security.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-punjab-shuts-amusement-parks-museums-for-10-days-due-to-severe-smog-6977921]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pak Shuts Parks, Museums As Air Quality Worsens, Multans AQI Crosses 2,100]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistans-punjab-shuts-amusement-parks-museums-for-10-days-due-to-severe-smog-6977921]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:06:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's Punjab government in a bid to combat the hazardous smog conditions in the province, shut down amusement parks and museums for 10 days, from November 8 to 17, ARY News reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan's Punjab government in a bid to combat the hazardous smog conditions in the province, shut down amusement parks and museums for 10 days, from November 8 to 17, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>As per the ban imposed on Friday, the districts affected by this ban include Lahore, Gujranwala, Faisalabad, Multan, Sheikhupura, Kasur, Nankana Sahib, Gujarat, Hafizabad, Mandi Bahauddin, Sialkot, Narowal, Chiniot, Jhang, and Toba Tek Singh, ARY News reported. Lodhran, Vehari, and Khanewal districts are also under smog-related restrictions.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Pakistan's air pollution reached an alarming level, with seven cities topping the list of the world's most polluted cities, as per ARY News. Pakistan's meteorologists predicted worsening smog conditions due to low wind speeds of 11km/h around Lahore and 7km/h near Multan.</p>

<p>Multan's air quality had an AQI score of 2,135, and that of Lahore was 676. Peshawar, Islamabad, Hariput, Rawalpindi and Karachi fell under the 'hazardous air quality' category, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Earlier on Thursday, Lahore ranked number one on the most polluted city rankings, released by IQAir at a staggering 784.</p>

<p>Lahore's atmosphere has remained dangerous for its residents for weeks following its position as one of the cities with the world's highest AQI. The pollution levels have time and again touched 1,000 for the city.</p>

<p>As per Geo News, the prolonged exposure has increased hospital admissions for respiratory issues, with Lahore and other cities like Multan, Kasur, Sheikhupura, and Gujranwala severely affected.</p>

<p>The persistent dangerous atmosphere has made it difficult for citizens to breathe, leaving them vulnerable to respiratory diseases, as they struggle to continue with their daily activities.</p>

<p>Doctors have advised the residents of Lahore to wear masks when stepping outside their homes.</p>

<p>Geo News reported that private and government educational institutions, teaching up to the higher secondary level, in the city as well as other districts of Pakistan's Punjab have also been closed by the government till November 17, as per notification.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Punjab education department has ordered to keep tuition centres and academies closed.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pkq2c0g8_lahore_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Doctors have advised the residents of Lahore to wear masks when stepping outside their homes. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Relief Workers Told To Avoid Homes With Trump Signs During Hurricane Milton]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 10:03:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Florida Governor Ron DeSantis took to X (formerly Twitter) and announced an investigation into the matter.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The disaster relief workers in the US state of Florida were directed to "avoid homes" with signs supporting President-elect Donald Trump when Hurricane Milton ravaged the area, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/08/us-news/fema-workers-told-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-in-hurricane-ravaged-florida-community/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NY Post</em></a>, citing the Daily Wire. Marn'i Washington, a Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) supervisor passed the order to her workers both verbally and in a Microsoft Teams chat used by the group, which was working to secure homes and rescue people around Lake Placid - one of the worst-affected areas.</p>

<p>"Avoid homes advertising Trump," Washington wrote in a "best practices" memo sent to employees. As many as 20 homes displaying signs for the Republican leader - a common sight during the election season, were ignored between the end of October and into November, as part of the directive by Washington.</p>

<p>"I thought we could go help and make a difference. When we got there we were told to discriminate against people. It's almost unbelievable to think that somebody in the federal government would think that's okay," one of the workers was quoted as saying by the outlet.</p>

<p>Florida Governor Ron DeSantis took to X (formerly Twitter) and announced an investigation into the matter, calling it a "blatant weaponization of government by partisan activists".</p>

<p>"At my direction, the Division of Emergency Management is launching an investigation into the federal government's targeted discrimination of Floridians who support Donald Trump," wrote DeSantis.</p>

<p>"New leadership is on the way in DC, and I'm optimistic that these partisan bureaucrats will be fired," he added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The blatant weaponization of government by partisan activists in the federal bureaucracy is yet another reason why the Biden-Harris administration is in its final days.<br />
<br />
At my direction, the Division of Emergency Management is launching an investigation into the federal… <a href="https://t.co/3uFpE62vxb">https://t.co/3uFpE62vxb</a></p>
— Ron DeSantis (@GovRonDeSantis) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovRonDeSantis/status/1855030970140770445?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 8, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>A FEMA official conceded that they were aware of the incident and "taking action at this moment regarding the situation". Meanwhile, Washington had not been punished for the guidance but shifted to a different Florida county, according to the last update.</p>

<p>Notably, Trump and Vice President-elect JD Vance had criticised the current Biden-Harris administration for their slow response to the disaster as the region was pummeled by several two hurricanes in a relatively short period.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/milton-explained-how-milton-became-a-powerful-hurricane-and-why-its-a-concern-6750186" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Explained: How Milton Became A Powerful Hurricane And Why It's A Concern</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>Hurricane Milton's impact</strong></h3>

<p>At least 16 people lost their lives when Hurricane Milton dumped around 229 mm of rainfall in just three hours in Florida, causing flash flooding. Powerful tornadoes that preceded the hurricane's landfall further added to the destruction. At one point, over three million people were without electricity as the hurricane tore through the region.</p>

<p>A study last year stated that storms originating in the Atlantic Ocean were now more than twice as likely to strengthen from Category 1 to Category 3 in just 36 hours, based on data from 2001-2020 compared with 1971-1990.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qv1t50f_trump_625x300_09_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Trump election signs seen in the yards]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massachusetts-court-revises-engagement-rules-bride-ordered-to-return-70-000-ring-6977830]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bride vs Groom Over $70,000 Engagement Ring: US Court's Landmark Decision]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/massachusetts-court-revises-engagement-rules-bride-ordered-to-return-70-000-ring-6977830]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:49:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The engagement ring should be returned to the buyer when marriages are cancelled irrespective of whose fault it was for the relationship's failure, said the Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The engagement ring should be returned to the buyer when marriages are cancelled irrespective of whose fault it was for the relationship's failure, said the Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court on Friday. With that, the court overturned a six-decade-old state rule that required judges to determine the party at fault for the breakup, reported AP.<br />
<br />
The case involved two individuals – Bruce Johnson and Caroline Settino. According to court filings, Johnson and Settino began dating in 2016. Over the next year, they even took many trips together for which Johnson paid. He also sent Settino gifts such as handbags, clothes, jewellery and shoes. Johnson eventually bought a diamond engagement ring worth $70,000, and in August 2017, he asked Settino's father for her hand in marriage. Two months later, he bought a set of wedding bands estimated to be worth $3,700.<br />
<br />
Johnson later stated that following these gestures, Settino's behaviour shifted, becoming increasingly critical and unsupportive. He claimed she berated him and did not support him during his prostate cancer treatments, as noted in court filings.<br />
<br />
Johnson then discovered text and voicemail exchanges between Settino and another man. She reportedly referred to needing “playtime” while Johnson was away. He also discovered a voicemail in which the man called Settino “cupcake.”<br />
<br />
Johnson ended the engagement, despite Settino's claim that the man was just a friend. Initially, a trial judge ruled in favour of Settino, allowing her to keep the engagement ring. They believed Johnson's suspicions of infidelity were unfounded. The decision was later overturned by an appeals court, which concluded that Johnson was entitled to reclaim the ring. The case reached the Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court, where a more permanent precedent was set.<br />
<br />
In their ruling, the justices noted that the case raised the question of whether “who is at fault” should still determine the right to keep an engagement ring when the wedding is called off. They, instead, brought Massachusetts law into line with what has become the norm in many other states — that an engagement ring is a conditional gift that must be returned to the donor if the wedding does not go through, regardless of who ends the relationship or why.<br />
<br />
According to <a href="http://https://apnews.com/article/court-rules-engagement-ring-returned-massachusetts-8b962b2d75b04d936092ba8ad2bf1ecf" rel="nofollow noindex">AP</a>, the justices wrote in the November 8 ruling, “We now join the modern trend adopted by the majority of jurisdictions that have considered the issue and retire the concept of fault in this context. Where, as here, the planned wedding does not ensue and the engagement is ended, the engagement ring must be returned to the donor regardless of fault.”<br />
<br />
Stephanie Taverna Siden, Johnson's lawyer, said the court's ruling was “well-reasoned, fair.” Settino's lawyer, Nicholas Rosenberg, expressed disappointment with the outcome but acknowledged respect for the court's decision to align with the majority rule observed in other states.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hpca9kt_engagement-_625x300_09_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As per this law, an engagement ring is a gift that must be returned to donor if there's no wedding.(File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-a-hard-fought-loss-will-kamala-harris-chart-a-new-course-6973556]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After US Election Loss, What's Next For Kamala Harris?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-a-hard-fought-loss-will-kamala-harris-chart-a-new-course-6973556]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:40:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will demit office in 72 days and has no immediate plans as far as her political career is concerned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Vice President Kamala Harris addressed a sombre crowd at her alma mater Howard University after she lost to Republican rival Donald Trump. She vowed to continue the fight that fuelled her campaign for the US election.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old will demit office in 72 days and has announced no immediate plans as far as her political career is concerned.</p>

<p>So what is next for Kamala Harris?</p>

<p><b>Prepare For 2028?</b></p>

<p>The most obvious choice before the former Democratic nominee is to take time and prepare for another bid in 2028. There are a few examples from the past. John Kerry, the 2004 nominee, lost to George Bush but didn't entirely disappear from the political scene after that. He served as the Secretary of State in Barack Obama's second term.</p>

<p><b>Back To The Senate?</b></p>

<p>Like John Kerry, returning to state politics and building the momentum again is an option. However, the road for Ms Harris doesn't appear to be an easy one. Longtime Democrat donor Mark Buell expressed the disappointment shared by many in her home state. “Everybody is devastated,” he was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/07/us/politics/kamala-harris-2028-run-for-president.html"><em>New York Times</em></a>.</p>

<p>Richie Greenberg, a Republican commentator based in San Francisco, said that Ms Harris might struggle to secure the fundraising support she once enjoyed.</p>

<p><strong>Role In The Democratic Party</strong></p>

<p>One potential path for Ms Harris could be that of a spokesperson within the Democratic Party, given her broad name recognition and connections. However, Greenberg thinks she will face challenges reigniting financial support from her base in San Francisco.</p>

<p><strong>A Tell-All Book</strong></p>

<p>Like at least two of the former Democratic nominees -- Hillary Clinton and Al Gore -- who lost the Presidential bids and decided to immerse themselves in writing and other pursuits, Ms Harris could also think in the same direction. While Hillary wrote a book titled '<em>What Happened</em>' after losing to Trump in 2016, Gore produced a documentary film '<em>An Inconvenient Truth'</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Enjoy Time Away From Politics</strong></p>

<p>In a couple of months, Ms Harris will be out of the Vice-President's office and can do what she promised to herself on October 27. “I plan on putting on some pounds after this is over,” she said at a Pennsylvania bookstore. “They're working me to the bone.”</p>

<p>Other than that, Harris could also follow in the footsteps of Ms Clinton, who hasn't been that active in politics and is more focused on her personal life. However, she continues to maintain a good rapport with donors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/morejb4o_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris conceded defeat after she bagged 226 electoral votes against Donald Trump's 301.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-amid-india-canada-diplomatic-standoff-a-bombshell-from-justin-trudeau-6977740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Rift, Justin Trudeau's "Khalistani" Backpedal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-amid-india-canada-diplomatic-standoff-a-bombshell-from-justin-trudeau-6977740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 09 Nov 2024 09:23:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the diplomatic standoff between India and Canada continues, Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau has admitted for the first time the presence of Khalistanis in his country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the diplomatic standoff between <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/india-canada" target="_blank">India and Canada</a> continues, Canadian Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/justin-trudeau" target="_blank">Justin Trudeau</a> has admitted for the first time the presence of Khalistanis in his country. In an unexpected statement, Trudeau acknowledged the presence of a Khalistan support base within Canada but quickly added that they do not represent the Sikh community as a whole. His remark came during a Diwali celebrations event at Ottawa's Parliament Hill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Relations between India and Canada have deteriorated since the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar, a Khalistani terrorist, outside a gurdwara in Surrey, British Columbia, in June 2023. Trudeau's allegation that India may have been involved in the murder set off a diplomatic firestorm that continues to rage. During his Diwali address, Trudeau stated that while there are supporters of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's government in Canada, they do not represent all Hindu Canadians either.</p>

<p>"There are many supporters of Khalistan in Canada, but they do not represent the Sikh Community as a whole. There are supporters of the Modi government in Canada, but they do not represent all Hindu Canadians as a whole," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Growing Tensions</strong></h3>

<p>Earlier this week, protesters, some waving Khalistani flags, clashed with devotees at a temple in Canada's Brampton, throwing punches, swinging poles, and disrupting a consular event that had drawn Indian nationals and Canadian citizens alike. Videos that quickly went viral on social media appeared to show protesters physically confronting worshippers outside the temple grounds. The footage depicted chaotic scenes of fistfights, with people hitting each other with poles as the tension escalated.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Prime Minister Justin Trudeau condemned the violence, stressing that every Canadian has the right to practice their faith in peace. "The acts of violence at the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton today are unacceptable. Every Canadian has the right to practice their faith freely and safely," Trudeau wrote on X (formerly Twitter). "Thank you to the Peel Regional Police for swiftly responding to protect the community and investigate this incident."</p>

<p>The Centre expressed deep concern over the safety of Indian nationals in Canada, while unequivocally condemning the attack on the Hindu Sabha temple.</p>

<p>"We have seen violent disruption today (November 3), orchestrated by anti-India elements outside the consular camp co-organised with the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton, near Toronto," said MEA spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal in a statement. "We also remain very concerned for the safety of applicants, including Indian nationals, on whose demand such events are organised in the first place. Despite these efforts by anti-India elements, our Consulate was able to issue more than 1,000 life certificates to the Indian and Canadian applicants."</p>

<h3><strong>No Evidence, Only Intelligence</strong></h3>

<p>India has consistently rejected any link to the murder of Nijjar, a designated terrorist by the National Investigation Agency (NIA), and accused Trudeau's administration of pandering to Khalistani sympathisers for political gain. The Trudeau government has accused India of being complicit in Nijjar's killing, a claim India has vehemently denied.</p>

<p>India has termed the allegations as politically motivated, pointing to Canada's failure to address the rising tide of pro-Khalistan sentiment in the country. In the aftermath of Nijjar's death, Canadian police suggested that six Indian diplomats were involved in the plot, a claim that India quickly dismissed as "preposterous." Despite multiple exchanges, including meetings at international forums like the G20 Summit, Canada has failed to provide any conclusive evidence linking India to the murder.</p>

<p>Last month, the Centre issued a blistering response to Canada's charges, rejecting claims that India's High Commissioner to Canada, Sanjay Kumar Verma, was a "person of interest" in Nijjar's murder. India not only dismissed the claims about Verma but also pointed out that despite repeated requests for evidence, Canada had failed to share any substantive proof to substantiate its allegations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a startling admission during a public inquiry in October, Trudeau admitted that Canada had no "hard evidentiary proof" in 2023 to support allegations linking Indian government agents to the killing of Nijjar. &nbsp;Speaking during a public inquiry into alleged foreign interference in Canada's federal electoral processes and democratic institutions, Trudeau revealed that his claims about India's involvement were based on intelligence rather than conclusive evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I was briefed on the fact that there was intelligence from Canada, and possibly from Five Eyes allies that made it fairly clear, incredibly clear, that India was involved in this... Agents of the government of India were involved in the killing of a Canadian on Canadian soil," he said.</p>

<p>Trudeau explained that Canada had the option to go public with the allegations during the G20 summit held in New Delhi in September 2023 but chose not to.</p>

<p>"Our response was, well, it's within your security agencies," Mr Trudeau said, recounting Canada's exchanges with India. "At that point, it was primarily intelligence, not hard evidentiary proof. So we said, let's work together and look into your security services."</p>

<p>The Indian government has argued that Canada provides a safe haven for pro-Khalistani extremists and separatists who pose a threat to India's security. New Delhi also said that it had requested action against these elements, which Canada had failed to take seriously.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/33o00gkg_justin-trudeau-afp-_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Relations between India and Canada have deteriorated since the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>