<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:57:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/amazon-ai-microsoft-ai-ai-boom-amazon-set-to-join-big-techs-spending-surge-as-ai-race-heats-up-6240427]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amazon Set To Join Big Tech's Spending Surge As AI Race Heats Up]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/amazon-ai-microsoft-ai-ai-boom-amazon-set-to-join-big-techs-spending-surge-as-ai-race-heats-up-6240427]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:52:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As a result of the spending increase, Amazon's gross profit margin growth is expected to have slowed to 1.3% in the April-June quarter, compared with 2.6% in the previous quarter and an average of 2.7% over the past two years.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amazon.com is expected to join Google and Microsoft on Thursday in reporting a surge in capital spending on artificial intelligence as Big Tech companies rush to capitalize on the booming technology.</p>

<p>The e-commerce giant's capital investments - mostly for building cloud and generative AI infrastructure - is expected to have risen 43% in the second quarter to $16.41 billion, according to LSEG data. That represents a roughly $1.5 billion increase from the previous three months.</p>

<p>The steep spending is also expected to pressure Amazon's margins, outweighing benefits from cost cuts and supply chain efficiencies that are aiding the retail unit's profitability.</p>

<p>The company's Amazon Web Services (AWS) business has long dominated the cloud-computing market, but it has been facing tough competition from Microsoft in recent quarters after the Windows maker rolled out AI-powered services to its Azure cloud business.</p>

<p>In response, Amazon has partnered with the likes of Anthropic and offered startups free credits that cover the cost of using major AI models to boost the market share of its AI platform Bedrock. It also named a new head for the AWS unit in May.</p>

<p>Microsoft and Google-parent Alphabet also said earlier this month they would plow ahead with investments even as the payoff from AI takes longer than some investors had hoped. This knocked Big Tech stocks whose valuations have soared this year on the promise of AI.</p>

<p>"Amazon's capex spend will certainly be scrutinized closely. It has been slow on the adoption of AI and is skewed towards smaller companies which have struggled in the high interest-rate environment," said Ben Barringer, analyst at Quilter Cheviot.</p>

<p>"We would expect AWS to start speeding things up in its AI development going forward."</p>

<p>Amazon shares have risen about 23% this year. The stock has shed more than 6% since July 8, when it hit a record, part of a broader market selloff led by U.S. megacaps.</p>

<p>Growth at AWS is likely to have stayed similar to the previous quarter at just over 17%, according to LSEG data. But, Morgan Stanley analysts said: "AWS needs to grow 18%+ in order to ... ensure investors of AWS's (AI) positioning and its ability to generate high-teens growth through this heavy capex investment period."</p>

<p>As a result of the spending increase, Amazon's gross profit margin growth is expected to have slowed to 1.3% in the April-June quarter, compared with 2.6% in the previous quarter and an average of 2.7% over the past two years.</p>

<p>Growth in its North American retail business likely slowed to 8% between April and June, from 12.3% in the January-March quarter, amid signs of a wider slowdown in consumer spending and some competition from new and fast-growing Chinese players such as Temu and Tiktok Shop that are enticing more U.S. shoppers.</p>

<p>Amazon's total revenue is expected to have grown 10.6% to $148.56 billion - the slowest rise in five quarters.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/3bueir_amazon-ai-reuters_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Amazon's total revenue is expected to have grown 10.6% to $148.56 billion, slowest rise in five quarters]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rains-30-killed-35-missing-after-torrential-rains-in-china-report-6240108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[30 Killed, 35 Missing After Torrential Rains In China: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-rains-30-killed-35-missing-after-torrential-rains-in-china-report-6240108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:16:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 30 people are dead and 35 are missing in central China, state media reported Thursday, following days of torrential rain that lashed the country earlier this week.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 30 people are dead and 35 are missing in central China, state media reported Thursday, following days of torrential rain that lashed the country earlier this week.</p>

<p>The downpours were triggered by Typhoon Gaemi, which moved on from the Philippines and Taiwan to make landfall in eastern China a week ago, with hilly, landlocked Hunan province hit particularly hard.</p>

<p>More than 11,000 people had been evacuated from the city of Zixing after some areas endured record rainfall of 645 millimetres (25 inches) in just 24 hours, state news agency Xinhua reported on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Many roads connecting townships in the Zixing area were temporarily cut off by the extreme weather, which also affected the power supply and communications infrastructure.</p>

<p>On Thursday, state broadcaster CCTV said that "the roads, electricity and communications in eight towns in Zixing city that were most severely affected by Typhoon Gaemi have basically opened".</p>

<p>"Initial findings show that there have been 30 deaths and 35 are missing," the report said, adding that search and rescue efforts were still ongoing.</p>

<p>On Tuesday Xinhua said four people had been killed and three people were missing in Zixing.</p>

<p>Three people were killed in Hunan's Yongxing county, Xinhua said Tuesday, while a landslide on Sunday killed 15 people elsewhere in the province.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/80975gg8_china-rains_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Torrential rain hit China earlier this week]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-learns-of-rs-1-73-crore-lottery-win-from-spam-email-6240025]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Learns Of Rs 1.73 Crore Lottery Win From Spam Email]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-learns-of-rs-1-73-crore-lottery-win-from-spam-email-6240025]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:06:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since the BIG CA$H Second Chance games launched in 2022, players have won more than $8 million in progressive prizes, according to lottery organisers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman in the US learned about her $207,199 (Rs 1.73 crore) lottery win through an email in her Spam folder. The 54-year-old woman, who preferred to remain nameless, told lottery officials she was wary of the email since it was discovered as a junk, as per a report in&nbsp;<em>New York Post</em>. But it later turned out that she had been winning her drawing entries for the Second Chance online lottery games.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I didn't know that by playing certain games online I was earning entries into a second chance drawing, so I was confused when I came across an email from the Michigan Lottery in my spam folder saying I'd won a $207,199 BIG CA$H Second Chance jackpot prize," the woman from Macomb County in Michigan was quoted as saying by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/07/30/us-news/michigan-woman-learns-of-207199-lottery-prize-from-email-in-spam-folder/">the <em>Post</em></a>.</p>

<p>She found out about the prize through little bit of research.</p>

<p>"After looking into it, I figured out how I had earned the entries, and then I checked three different times to make sure the email was real," said the woman.</p>

<p>The windfall will allow her to pay some bills and make investments.</p>

<p>Since the BIG CA$H Second Chance games launched in 2022, players have won more than $8 million in progressive prizes, according to lottery organisers.</p>

<h3><strong>Other big lottery wins</strong></h3>

<p>A mystery person in the US state of New Jersey won a whopping $1.13 billion Mega Millions jackpot in March this year. It was the fifth-largest prize ever won by Mega Millions players and the first time in 2024 that a ticket matched all the numbers needed to get the grand prize. The estimated jackpot was also the eighth largest in US lottery history.</p>

<p>In April, Cheng Saephan, a 46-year-old immigrant from Laos battling cancer, defied the odds by winning a staggering $1.3 billion on the Powerball lottery. Officials confirmed Mr Saephan purchased the winning ticket for the April 7th draw in Portland, Oregon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ffbqum6g_spam-email-folder_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The windfall will allow her to pay some bills and make investments.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-mohammed-deif-hamas-military-wing-chief-confirmed-dead-by-israel-6239658]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was Mohammed Deif, Hamas Military Wing Chief Confirmed Dead By Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-mohammed-deif-hamas-military-wing-chief-confirmed-dead-by-israel-6239658]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 16:20:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mohammed Deif, the head of Hamas' military wing, was killed in an airstrike in Gaza last month, the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) have confirmed. Deif was believed to be a key architect of the October 7 attack, which killed 1,195 people in Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
	<li>Mohammed Deif was born in 1965 in the Khan Yunis Refugee Camp in the Gaza Strip. His family originated from al-Qubeiba, near Ramleh in Mandatory Palestine, and were displaced during the 1948 Palestine war. He graduated with a bachelor's degree in chemistry from the Islamic University of Gaza in 1988. Deif held an interest in the arts and established a theatre group called “The Returners” during his University years.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Deif joined Hamas in 1987, shortly after its founding during the First Intifada against Israeli occupation. Israeli authorities arrested him in 1989, but he was released in 1991 as part of a prisoner exchange after serving 16 months. He helped establish the Ezzedeen Al-Qassam Brigades, the armed wing of Hamas. In 2002, he took command of the Brigades after the assassination of Salah Shehade. Deif transformed the Brigades into organised military units, leading them to become a more effective force.</li>
	<li>Mohammed Deif orchestrated several devastating suicide bombings during the 1990s and early 2000s, including the 1996 Jaffa Road bus bombings. He also masterminded the kidnappings and killings of several Israeli soldiers. He developed and implemented Hamas' strategy of combining rocket attacks on Israel with tunnel warfare.</li>
	<li>He evaded seven Israeli assassination attempts since 2001, earning him the nickname “the cat with nine lives”. Israeli forces targeted him in airstrikes on his car, houses he visited and family homes. However, his survival has come at a high personal cost. In 2014, Israeli airstrikes killed his wife, infant son and 3-year-old daughter. Deif himself had suffered severe injuries, including the loss of an eye and limbs, as a result of these attempts on his life.</li>
	<li>Israel has pursued Mohammed Deif since 1995 for his role in killing soldiers and civilians, placing him on their 'most wanted' list. The US and European Union designated Deif as a terrorist, adding him to their terrorism lists in 2015 and 2023, respectively. Deif masterminded and carried out the 2023 October 7 Hamas-led attack on Israel. He claimed the attack was a response to Israeli actions at the Al-Aqsa mosque and the killing of Palestinians. In May 2024, the International Criminal Court's Prosecutor sought arrest warrants for Deif and other leaders for their actions during the attack.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/pulthnp_mohammed-deif_625x300_11_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has pursued Mohammed Deif since 1995 for his role in killing soldiers and civilians.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/openai-microsoft-sam-altman-openai-may-post-5-billion-loss-this-year-run-out-of-cash-in-12-months-report-6239442]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI May Post $5 Billion Loss, Run Out Of Cash In 12 Months: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/openai-microsoft-sam-altman-openai-may-post-5-billion-loss-this-year-run-out-of-cash-in-12-months-report-6239442]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:59:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[OpenAI is projected to earn between $3 billion to $4.5 billion in 2024, leaving behind a deficit of $5 billion in losses: The Information]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI is set to burn all of its cash at current expenditures in 12 months' time, according to a report by The Information. The San Francisco based AI startup leader is on track to lose $5 billion, mainly due to high capital expenditure on cloud infrastructure required for training and running AI programs, including that for ChatGPT.</p>

<p>OpenAI has long relied on Microsoft for providing computing infrastructure for running its AI programs. Microsoft was also one of the earliest investors, with a $1 billion investment, three years before the launch of ChatGPT.</p>

<p>The $80 billion market valued company OpenAI has around 350,000 Nvidia A100 chips for running its programs (for inference alone), with 290,000 of those specifically for running ChatGPT, a source told The Information. These servers containing A100s are rented to OpenAI at $1.3 per hour by Microsoft, resulting in $4 Billion of estimated expenditure on these servers in 2024 alone.</p>

<p>For training alone, the company plans to spend $3 billion in 2024 and another $1.5 billion on salaries for its 1500 strong employees.</p>

<p>OpenAI generates a revenue of about $2 billion through ChatGPT and about $1 billion through providing access to its large language model. According to its recent monthly revenue report, OpenAI is projected to earn between $3 billion to $4.5 billion in 2024, leaving behind a deficit of $5 billion in losses. The company needs to raise fresh funds to keep the pace of its development with OpenAI setting its eyes on developing Artificial General Intelligence (AGI).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lu7ak7e8_openai-cloud-ai-generated_625x300_01_August_24.png' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[OpenAI spends most of its money on Microsoft cloud servers (AI Generated Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/openai-sam-altman-us-senate-openai-says-dedicated-to-safety-in-letter-to-us-lawmakers-6238884]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Says Dedicated To Safety In Letter To US Lawmakers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/ai-startup-tech/openai-sam-altman-us-senate-openai-says-dedicated-to-safety-in-letter-to-us-lawmakers-6238884]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:51:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The startup sought to reassure lawmakers of its commitment to safety after five senators raised questions about OpenAI's safety policies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI, responding to questions from US lawmakers, said it's dedicated to making sure its powerful AI tools don't cause harm, and that employees have ways to raise concerns about safety practices.</p>

<p>The startup sought to reassure lawmakers of its commitment to safety after five senators including Senator Brian Schatz, a Democrat from Hawaii, raised questions about OpenAI's policies in a letter addressed to Chief Executive Officer Sam Altman.</p>

<p>"Our mission is to ensure artificial intelligence benefits all of humanity, and we are dedicated to implementing rigorous safety protocols at every stage of our process," Chief Strategy Officer Jason Kwon said Wednesday in a letter to the lawmakers.</p>

<p>Specifically, OpenAI said it will continue to uphold its promise to allocate 20% of its computing resources toward safety-related research over multiple years.</p>

<p>The company, in its letter, also pledged that it won't enforce non-disparagement agreements for current and former employees, except in specific cases of a mutual non-disparagement agreement. OpenAI's former limits on employees who left the company have come under scrutiny for being unusually restrictive. OpenAI has since said it has changed its policies.</p>

<p>Altman later elaborated on its strategy on social media.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">a few quick updates about safety at openai:<br />
<br />
as we said last july, we're committed to allocating at least 20% of the computing resources to safety efforts across the entire company.<br />
<br />
our team has been working with the US AI Safety Institute on an agreement where we would provide…</p>
— Sam Altman (@sama) <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1818867964369928387?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Our team has been working with the US AI Safety Institute on an agreement where we would provide early access to our next foundation model so that we can work together to push forward the science of AI evaluations," he wrote on X.</p>

<p>Kwon, in his letter, also cited the recent creation of a safety and security committee, which is currently undergoing a review of OpenAI's processes and policies.</p>

<p>In recent months, OpenAI has faced a series of controversies around its commitment to safety and ability for employees to speak out on the topic. Several key members of its safety-related teams, including former co-founder and chief scientist Ilya Sutskever, resigned, along with another leader of the company's team devoted to assessing long-term safety risks, Jan Leike, who publicly shared concerns that the company was prioritizing product development over safety.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m65qp6o8_openai_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[CEO Sam Altman also took to twitter to reassure the company's commitment to AI safety]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-urges-end-to-escalatory-actions-for-all-parties-in-middle-east-6238834]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken Urges End To "Escalatory Actions" For All Parties In Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/antony-blinken-urges-end-to-escalatory-actions-for-all-parties-in-middle-east-6238834]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:47:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The strike that killed Ismail Haniyeh came just hours after Israel said it had killed a top Hezbollah commander in a retaliatory strike on the Lebanese capital Beirut. The killings took place as regional tensions were already inflamed by the war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Thursday urged "all parties" in the Middle East to stop "escalatory actions" and achieve a ceasefire in Gaza, after Hamas's political leader was killed in a strike in Tehran that Iran blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>The strike that killed Ismail Haniyeh came just hours after Israel said it had killed a top Hezbollah commander in a retaliatory strike on the Lebanese capital Beirut.</p>

<p>The killings took place as regional tensions were already inflamed by the war in Gaza, a conflict that has drawn in Iran-backed operatives groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Israel has declined to comment on the Tehran strike.</p>

<p>Speaking in the Mongolian capital, top US diplomat Blinken warned the Middle East was on a path "toward more conflict, more violence, more suffering, more insecurity, and it is crucial that we break this cycle".</p>

<p>"That starts with a ceasefire that we've been working on," Blinken told reporters alongside his local counterpart.</p>

<p>"And to get there, it also first requires all parties to talk, to stop taking any escalatory actions, it requires them to find reasons to come to an agreement," he said.</p>

<p>As he did on Wednesday in Singapore, Blinken did not comment directly on the death of the leader of the Palestinian Islamist movement.</p>

<p>He also declined to speculate on the impact that Haniyeh's killing could have on a potential ceasefire in Gaza, which the United States has been spearheading along with Egypt and Qatar.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/ds79oupo_antony-blinken-afp_625x300_08_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Antony Blinken warned the Middle East was on a path toward more conflict, violence and sufferings (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weeks-after-blue-screen-of-death-cyberattack-causes-new-microsoft-outage-6238819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Weeks After "Blue Screen Of Death", Microsoft Suffers New Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/weeks-after-blue-screen-of-death-cyberattack-causes-new-microsoft-outage-6238819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:44:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The tech giant said it was a DDoS attack that floods a service with traffic in order to bring them to a standstill.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Less than two weeks after global outage, dubbed as "blue screen of death", Microsoft suffered another similar incident, which the company said was triggered by a distributed denial of service (DDoS) cyberattack. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kateoflahertyuk/2024/07/31/microsoft-confirms-new-outage-was-triggered-by-cyberattack/">According to <em>Forbes</em></a>, the latest attack was reported by several users on Tuesday in which users complained of not being able to access several Microsoft services, such as Office, Outlook and Azure. The incident lasted nearly 10 hours. Companies affected by the new outage include UK bank NatWest, as per the <em>BBC</em>.</p>

<p>Other impacted services included Azure App Services, Application Insights, Azure IoT Central, Azure Log Search Alerts, Azure Policy, as well as the Azure portal itself and "a subset of Microsoft 365 and Microsoft Purview services".</p>

<p>The tech giant said it was a DDoS attack that floods a service with traffic in order to bring them to a standstill.</p>

<p>Firms usually put protection in place for DDoS attacks, but an error in the implementation of defences "amplified the impact of the attack rather than mitigating it", said Microsoft.</p>

<p>This is the second major attack in nearly as many weeks. A Microsoft error had crippled Windows computers worldwide on July 19. It was later revealed that an update to the anti-virus program 'Falcon Sensor' by CrowdStrike caused the massive outage.</p>

<p>From airlines to news channels, the glitch led to the crashing of IT systems, disrupting the daily proceedings.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike's products are predominantly used by major organisations needing robust cyber attack protection, which is why the attack caused a global outage.</p>

<p>Reacting to the glitch, Crowdstrike CEO George Kurtz said it was not a security incident or cyberattack. The company identified the issue, isolated it and deployed a fix.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2558qqf_microsoft-outage_625x300_20_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The July 19 outage impacted airlines across the world.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-military-chief-mohammed-deif-killed-in-gaza-strike-israel-6238816]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Military Chief Mohammed Deif Killed In Gaza Strike: Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-military-chief-mohammed-deif-killed-in-gaza-strike-israel-6238816]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:44:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Thursday announced that Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif had been killed in a strike it carried out last month in Gaza's southern area of Khan Yunis.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's army confirmed on Thursday that Hamas military chief Mohammed Deif was killed in an air strike last month in the southern Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The announcement came a day after Hamas and Iran said the Palestinian movement's chief Ismail Haniyeh was killed in Tehran. Israel has not commented on that report.</p>

<p>"Mohammed Deif, the Osama bin Laden of Gaza was eliminated" on July 13, Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We can now confirm: Mohammed Deif was eliminated.</p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1818926099432161437?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This is a "significant milestone in the process of dismantling Hamas" in Gaza, Gallant added.</p>

<p>The army said fighter jets had struck Khan Yunis on July 13 and "following an intelligence assessment, it can be confirmed that Mohammed Deif was eliminated in the strike".</p>

<p>He was killed along with one of his top commanders, Rafa Salama, the military said.</p>

<p>Health authorities in Hamas-run Gaza said more than 90 people had been killed in that strike but Hamas has denied Deif was among them.</p>

<p>"Deif initiated, planned, and executed the October 7th massacre," the military said.</p>

<p>On that day the Hamas group attacked southern Israel, resulting in the death of 1,197 people, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Deif became head of Hamas's armed wing, Ezzedine al-Qassam Brigades, in 2002.</p>

<p>He was among Israel's most wanted man for nearly three decades and on a US list of "international terrorists" since 2015.</p>

<p>"During the war, he commanded Hamas's terrorist activity in the Gaza Strip by issuing commands and instructions to senior members of Hamas's military wing," the military said.</p>

<p>Deif, whose real name is Mohammed Diab al-Masri, was born in the Khan Yunis refugee camp in 1965.</p>

<p>The word Deif means "visitor" or "guest" and some say he chose it because he was always on the move with Israeli hunters on his trail, never spending more than one night in the same place.</p>

<p><strong>'Cat with nine lives'</strong></p>

<p>In videos, Deif has appeared masked or shown in a silhouette, while rare photographs have circulated of one of Israel's most wanted men.</p>

<p>In January, Israel released a picture of Deif showing him with one eye missing, without specifying when it was taken.</p>

<p>His enemies dubbed him the "cat with nine lives" because of his many close calls with death.</p>

<p>In 2014, Israel launched an air strike on Gaza, killing Deif's wife and a seven-month-old son.</p>

<p>It was Deif who announced the start of the Hamas attack -- operation "Al-Aqsa Flood" -- in an audio message on October 7.</p>

<p>Deif became involved in Hamas in the 1980s when he was a student at the Gaza Islamic University.</p>

<p>He is said to have played a key role in the huge network of tunnels built beneath Gaza.</p>

<p>He was detained by Israel since the 1980s and spent about two years in a prison run by the Palestinian Authority. He was released or escaped, reports said.</p>

<p>In May, the chief prosecutor of the International Criminal Court requested a warrant for his arrest -- alongside with Yahya Sinwar, the chief of Hamas in Gaza who is still being hunted by Israel -- for war crimes and crimes against humanity.</p>

<p>Hamas political leader Haniyeh, who was killed Wednesday in the Iranian capital, was also on that list.</p>

<p>The prosecutor has also sought warrants for Israel's prime minister Benjamin Netanyahu and defence minister Gallant.</p>

<p>During the October 7 attack, Hamas operatives also seized 251 people, 111 are still captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign since then has killed 39,480 people in Gaza, according to the health ministry in the territory, which does not provide details of civilian and militant deaths.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/pulthnp_mohammed-deif_625x300_11_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-accuses-kamala-harris-of-leaning-into-identity-politics-6238533]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Vivek Ramaswamy Accuses Kamala Harris Of Leaning Into 'Identity Politics']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vivek-ramaswamy-accuses-kamala-harris-of-leaning-into-identity-politics-6238533]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:04:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 38-year-old Indian-American biotech entrepreneur drew a comparison between Harris' heritage and his own to share his views on the subject.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Republican presidential candidate Vivek Ramaswamy has accused Vice President Kamala Harris of leaning into 'identity politics' and claimed that she only considered herself Indian-American when "convenient."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ramaswamy, who supports for president and the Republican Party's nominee Donald Trump now, said that Harris, the Democratic presidential nominee, leaned on her Indian American heritage while running for office in California, where there is a significant Asian American population, but has since shifted her focus away from that identity on the national stage.</p>

<p>The 38-year-old Indian-American biotech entrepreneur drew a comparison between Harris' heritage and his own to share his views on the subject. "On a very personal level, my parents were immigrants to this country, legal immigrants from southern India- the very same part of India that (Harris') mother also immigrated from," he told Fox News.</p>

<p>"I think it's a hard fact... it's a fact whether you like it or not, that many Indian-Americans in the US are indeed somewhat offended by the way Kamala has suddenly cast aside the Indian-American side of identity," Ramaswamy said.</p>

<p>She leaned into it when she ran for Office in California- big Asian-American and Indian-American population, he said. "So she wore that when it was convenient. She's wearing a different identity now when it is politically convenient on a national stage," he alleged.</p>

<p>He said he does not think Americans should be relying on these ethnic identities at all. "We're actually American. And the problem is, when you're Kamala Harris and you actually lean into your identity politics, then you open the door to that type of criticism," he said.</p>

<p>"But if you ask me, that shouldn't be how this election is decided one way or another. It should be decided on our own identity as Americans and what our vision is for the future of our country. And the number one thing missing in Kamala Harris' candidacy is that she lacks that vision for the country," he added.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, is Indian American and African American. Her mother emigrated from India, and her father emigrated from Jamaica.</p>

<p>Former President Trump, Harris' Republican rival, also mocked Vice President Harris's heritage during a combative live interview Wednesday at the National Association of Black Journalists (NABJ) convention, saying "she happened to turn Black" in recent years.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/7t9l89g_vivek-ramaswamy-afp_625x300_20_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kerala-police-has-warned-against-dark-tourism-know-what-it-is-6237006]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kerala Police Has Warned Against 'Dark Tourism'. Know What It Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kerala-police-has-warned-against-dark-tourism-know-what-it-is-6237006]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:45:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dark tourism has gained global attention in recent years, partly thanks to TV shows like Chernobyl and The Dark Tourist.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 167 people died in the devastating landslides in Wayanad on Wednesday. In response to the tragedy, Kerala authorities are urging the public to avoid the area, warning against "dark tourism" that may hinder critical rescue efforts.</p>

<p>"Please don't go to disaster areas for sightseeing. It will affect rescue operations. Call 112 for assistance," Kerala Police warned in a message posted on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ml">ദയവായി കാഴ്ചകൾ കാണാൻ ദുരന്ത പ്രദേശങ്ങളിലേക്ക് പോകരുത്????????<br />
അത് രക്ഷാപ്രവർത്തനത്തെ ബാധിക്കും<br />
<br />
സഹായങ്ങൾക്ക് 112 എന്ന നമ്പറിൽ വിളിക്കാം <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/keralapolice?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#keralapolice</a> <a href="https://t.co/D6irnQICNJ">pic.twitter.com/D6irnQICNJ</a></p>
— Kerala Police (@TheKeralaPolice) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheKeralaPolice/status/1818165471226826822?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<h2><strong>What is 'dark tourism'?</strong></h2>

<p>Dark tourism, a phenomenon gaining significant attention in recent years, has been thrust into the global spotlight by TV shows like Chernobyl and The Dark Tourist. But what is it?&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dark tourism refers to the practice of travelling to and visiting sites associated with death, suffering, tragedy, violence, or the unusual. These destinations can include cemeteries, mausoleums, mortuaries, disaster zones, battlefields, memorials, prisons, execution sites, and crime scenes.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dark tourism destinations may include the Chernobyl exclusion zone in Ukraine, the Killing Fields in Cambodia, the Auschwitz camp in Poland, and the 9/11 Memorial in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Other sites might be haunted houses, paranormal activity, or infamous historical events.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Definitions of 'dark tourism'</strong></h2>

<p>One of the earliest definitions of dark tourism was provided by <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0826450644/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=lifeasabutter-21&amp;creative=6738&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=0826450644&amp;linkId=ea7f09c74fbeea0c9125d950ed1088ff ">John Lennon and Malcolm Foley</a>, who described it as "the representation of inhuman acts, and how these are interpreted for visitors."</p>

<p>A more recent definition by <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/9781405165518.wbeosd045.pub2">Kevin Fox Gotham</a> expands on this idea, describing dark tourism as "the circulation of people to places characterised by distress, atrocity or sadness and pain."</p>

<p>Mr Gotham also introduced the concept of "disaster tourism", which refers to situations where tourism rises in response to a major disaster or traumatic event.</p>

<h2><strong>Why dark tourism is popular</strong></h2>

<p>For many, the appeal of dark tourism lies in the emotional connection they make with a place of tragedy. Visitors seek to immerse themselves in the history and culture of a location and connect with the emotions of those who experienced the tragedy firsthand.</p>

<p>By visiting these sites, people can tangibly engage with the past, paying respects to those who suffered. Dark tourism allows individuals to process and understand the significance of historical events and reflect on history.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2015-09/auschwitz-memorial650_650x400_81441163783.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dark tourism is a phenomenon gaining significant attention in recent years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-holds-funeral-for-murdered-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6238249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Holds Funeral For Hamas Chief Haniyeh, Calls For "Revenge" On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-holds-funeral-for-murdered-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6238249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:33:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Islamic republic's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei will lead the prayers for Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Doha, having earlier threatened a "harsh punishment" for his killing.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran held funeral processions on Thursday with calls for revenge after the killing in Tehran of Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh in a strike blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>The Islamic republic's supreme leader <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-leader-to-lead-funeral-prayers-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6236223" target="_blank">Ayatollah Ali Khamenei</a> led prayers for Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Qatar, having earlier threatened a "harsh punishment" for his killing.</p>

<p>In Tehran's city centre, thousands of mourning crowds carrying posters of Haniyeh and Palestinian flags gathered for the ceremony at Tehran University before a procession, according to an AFP correspondent.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's death was announced the day before by Iran's Revolutionary Guards, who said he and his bodyguard were killed in a strike on their accommodation in the Iranian capital at 2:00 am (2230 GMT) on Wednesday.</p>

<p>It came just hours after Israel targeted and killed top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr in a retaliatory strike on the Lebanese capital Beirut, sending fears of a wider regional war soaring in fallout from the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Israel has declined to comment on the Tehran strike.</p>

<p>Iran's state TV showed the coffins of Haniyeh and his bodyguards covered in Palestinian flags during the ceremony attended by senior Iranian officials.</p>

<p>President Masoud Pezeshkian and Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps chief, General Hossein Salami, were present. Haniyeh had been visiting Tehran for Pezeshkian's inauguration ceremony on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Senior Hamas figure Khalil al-Hayya, the movement's foreign relations chief, vowed during the funeral ceremony that "Ismail Haniyeh's slogan, 'We will not recognise Israel,' will remain an immortal slogan" and "we will pursue Israel until it is uprooted from the land of Palestine."</p>

<p>Iran's conservative parliamentary speaker Mohammad Bagher Ghalibaf said Iran "will certainly carry out the supreme leader's order (to avenge Haniyeh.)"</p>

<p>"It is our duty to respond at the right time and in the right place," he said in a speech with crowds chanting "Death to Israel, Death to America!"</p>

<h3><strong>Our duty</strong></h3>

<p>The caskets, with a black-and-white pattern resembling a Palestinian keffiyeh scarf, were borne on a flower-bedecked truck through leafy streets where cooling water mists sprayed the flag-waving crowds.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who has the final say in Iran's political affairs, said after Haniyeh's death that it was "our duty to seek revenge for his blood as he was martyred in the territory of the Islamic Republic of Iran".</p>

<p>The Islamic republic has not yet officially published any information on the exact location of the strike.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian said Wednesday that "the Zionists (Israel) will soon see the consequences of their cowardly and terrorist act".</p>

<p>The international community, however, called for de-escalation and a focus on securing a ceasefire in Gaza -- which Haniyeh had, according to a Hamas official previously, accused Israel of obstructing.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said the strikes in Tehran and Beirut represented a "dangerous escalation".</p>

<p>All efforts, he said, should be "leading to a ceasefire" in Gaza and the release of hostages taken during Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which began nearly 10 months of war.</p>

<p>The prime minister of key ceasefire broker Qatar said Haniyeh's killing had thrown the whole mediation process into doubt.</p>

<p>"How can mediation succeed when one party assassinates the negotiator on the other side?" Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al-Thani said in a post on social media site X.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken on Thursday called on "all parties" in the Middle East to "stop escalatory actions."</p>

<p>Earlier he said a ceasefire in Gaza was still the "imperative", though White House National Security Council spokesman John Kirby said the twin killings of Haniyeh and Shukr "don't help" regional tensions.</p>

<h3><strong>Tensions inflamed</strong></h3>

<p>While Iran has blamed the attack on its arch-foe, Israel has declined to comment on Haniyeh's death. It did, however, claim the killing of Shukr, whom it blamed for a weekend rocket strike that killed 12 youths in the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The killings come with regional tensions already inflamed by the war in Gaza, a conflict that has drawn in Iran-backed operatives groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>One of those groups, Yemen's Huthi rebels, "declared three days of mourning" for Haniyeh, with political leader Mahdi al-Mashat expressing "condolences to the Palestinian people and Hamas" over his killing, according to the group's Saba news agency.</p>

<p>The United Nations Security Council also convened an emergency meeting Wednesday at Iran's request to discuss the strike.</p>

<p>Hamas has for months been indirectly negotiating a truce and hostage-prisoner exchange deal with Israel, in talks facilitated by Egypt, Qatar and the United States.</p>

<p>Analysts told AFP that Haniyeh was a moderating influence within the Islamist group, and that while he would be replaced, the dynamics within Hamas could change.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for the October 7 attack that ignited war in Gaza.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Concern grew among Israelis over the fate of those still held in Gaza.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's killing "was a mistake as it threatens the possibility of having a hostage deal," said Anat Noy, a resident of the coastal city of Haifa.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,445 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cn8kv4f8_ismail-haniyeh-funeral_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Thousands of mourning crowds carrying posters of Haniyeh gathered for ceremony at Tehran University (AFP)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-to-meet-cops-after-protests-chant-save-our-kids-over-southport-knife-killings-6238027]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK PM To Meet Cops Over Stabbing Attack As Protesters Chant "Save Our Kids"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-to-meet-cops-after-protests-chant-save-our-kids-over-southport-knife-killings-6238027]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 13:07:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There were angry scenes in London on Wednesday evening as thousands of anti-immigration protesters gathered near Starmer's Downing Street office and residence chanting "save our kids" and "we want our country back".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer will meet senior police leaders on Thursday, his office said, between after a second night of clashes between protesters and police prompted by the deaths of three young girls in a frenzied knife attack at a dance class.</p>

<p>There were angry scenes in London on Wednesday evening as thousands of anti-immigration protesters gathered near Starmer's Downing Street office and residence chanting "save our kids" and "we want our country back".</p>

<p>The previous night more than 50 police officers were injured in violent clashes in the English seaside town of Southport, where Monday's stabbings took place.</p>

<p>A 17-year-old male was in police custody on suspicion of murder and attempted murder after the bloody rampage on Monday at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-in-shock-taylor-swift-on-uk-mass-stabbings-that-killed-3-girls-6224379" target="_blank">"Taylor Swift</a> yoga and dance workshop", a summer vacation event for children aged 6 to 11.</p>

<p>Starmer's office said he would use Thursday's meeting with police to "offer them the government's full backing following multiple high-profile incidents of extreme violence and public disorder on our streets".</p>

<p>"While the right to peaceful protest must be protected at all costs, he will be clear that criminals who exploit that right in order to sow hatred and carry out violent acts will face the full force of the law," his office added.</p>

<p>The disorder took place after false information was spread on social media that the suspect was a radical Islamist migrant.</p>

<p>Police are legally restricted in the details they can provide about the alleged teenage attacker, but they have said the incident was not terrorism-related and that he was born in Britain, quashing speculation on his origins.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/0ogi588k_keir-starmer_625x300_23_May_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[More than 50 police officers were injured in violent clashes in the English town of Southport (AFP)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-for-kamala-harriss-democratic-nomination-set-to-begin-today-6237769]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Voting For Kamala Harris's Democratic Nomination Set To Begin Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/voting-for-kamala-harriss-democratic-nomination-set-to-begin-today-6237769]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 12:52:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Less than two weeks after Joe Biden ended his re election bid, his 52-year-old vice president is in full control of the party, having emerged as the only Democrat in the running to challenge Republican Donald Trump in November.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris will be confirmed as the Democratic US presidential nominee in an electronic vote starting Thursday that replaces the fanfare of in-person balloting that usually kicks off the party's national convention.</p>

<p>Less than two weeks after <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/video/joe-biden-explains-why-he-ended-re-election-bid-818521" target="_blank">Joe Biden ended his re election bid</a>, his 52-year-old vice president is in full control of the party, having emerged as the only Democrat in the running to challenge Republican Donald Trump in November.</p>

<p>Just under 4,000 delegates, the grassroots activists and politicians allocated during the primary process, sent in signatures backing Harris to be on the ballot for the five-day electronic vote.</p>

<p>No other Democrats have stepped forward to challenge her elevation to the top of the ticket, making her confirmation as the first Black and South Asian woman ever to secure a major party's nomination a formality.</p>

<p>She won the support of 99 percent of the delegates who signed petitions, the Democratic National Committee (DNC) said in a statement, while no one else met the qualifying threshold of 300 signatures.</p>

<p>"Our delegates have an important responsibility -- and opportunity -- in the days ahead to cast their history-making ballots for Vice President Harris, ensuring that she will be on the ballot in every state this November," said DNC chair Jaime Harrison.</p>

<p>"Our party has met this unprecedented moment with a transparent, democratic and orderly process to unite behind a nominee with a proven record who will lead us in the fight ahead."</p>

<p>As well as the "pledged" delegates there are around 700 so-called "superdelegates" who get to vote because they hold elected office -- such as state governors or members of the US Congress -- or are party officials.</p>

<p>The roll call launches at 9:00 am (1300 GMT) Thursday and delegates have until 6:00 pm (2000 GMT) on Monday to return their votes via an online platform run by the DNC.</p>

<p>The announcement could come late Monday, as she hits the campaign trail for a swing across seven crucial battleground states with her newly minted running mate, who has not yet been announced.</p>

<p>US media reported that she would kick off the tour in Pennsylvania on Tuesday, although the DNC did not immediately respond to a request for confirmation.</p>

<p>The 2024 nominating system is largely as it was in 2020, when the Covid-19 pandemic prevented a large in-person convention, but it is still unusual.</p>

<p>The DNC swapped to a virtual process because of Ohio's deadline -- Wednesday next week -- for major parties to submit the names of their certified candidates for the November election.</p>

<p>Much remains unclear about the announcement of the results, however.</p>

<p>The DNC has not revealed if the vote will be livestreamed or if a rolling tally will be available to the public, and has not disclosed whether it would make the results public before the end of the voting period if they were available.</p>

<p>The virtual roll-call marks the official beginning of the 2024 convention, although in practice the festivities get going when thousands of the party's grassroots activists descend on Chicago on August 19.</p>

<p>There will be ceremonial votes for Harris and her running mate in Illinois, in what is expected to be a raucous celebration of her rise from state politics to the top of the ticket.</p>

<p>"Think about this: her dad is of Jamaican descent, her mother's of South Asian descent and then she went to the great Howard University, worked in California, worked in the United States Senate," Georgia Senator Raphael Warnock told a raucous, 10,000-strong crowd at Harris's rally in Atlanta on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"That is the American story. She brings all of those strands together. She sees us because in a real sense she is all of us."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/f31c6agc_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris won the support of 99 percent of the delegates who signed petitions (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-ismail-haniyeh-hamas-leader-killed-in-iran-6228475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Was Ismail Haniyeh, Hamas Leader Killed In Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-was-ismail-haniyeh-hamas-leader-killed-in-iran-6228475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 11:05:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was assassinated in Tehran, Iran, on July 31, the Palestinian militant group said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024 ">Ismail Haniyeh was assassinated</a> in Tehran, Iran, on July 31, the Palestinian militant group said. According to Iranian state media, Haniyeh and one of his bodyguards were killed in a strike on the building they were staying in.</p>

<p>The Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) said that Haniyeh was in Tehran to attend the inauguration ceremony of Iran's President Masoud Pezeshkian when the incident occurred.</p>

<p>Hamas released a statement condemning the attack and saying Haniyeh was killed in "a treacherous Zionist raid on his residence in Tehran". This allegation has not been confirmed by Iranian authorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Here are some facts about the Hamas leader:</strong></p>

<p>1. Ismail Haniyeh was born on January 29, 1962, in the Shati refugee camp in Gaza City, Gaza Strip. His family, Palestinian refugees, fled their home near the present-day Israeli town of Ashkelon during the 1948 Arab-Israeli war. He studied Arabic literature at the Islamic University of Gaza, graduating in 1987.&nbsp;</p>

<p>2. Haniyeh's involvement in politics began in the 1980s as a student leader at the Islamic University. He was a key figure in the founding of Hamas in 1987 and became a close advisor to Hamas founder Sheikh Ahmed Yassin. After Yassin's assassination in 2004, Haniyeh became the deputy chief of Hamas's political bureau. In 2017, he succeeded Khaled Mashal as the political chief of Hamas.</p>

<p>3. In 1988, he was <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ismail-haniyeh-facts-about-the-hamas-leader-that-ordered-attack-on-israel-4467224 ">arrested by Israeli authorities</a> for joining the First Intifada, a mass uprising against Israeli occupation that began in 1987 and lasted until 1993. He spent six months in jail and was arrested again in 1989. In 1992, he was deported to south Lebanon along with 400 other Islamists.</p>

<p>4. Haniyeh became the Prime Minister of the Palestinian Authority in 2006, a position he held until 2007. During this time, Hamas secured a surprising majority in the 2006 Palestinian legislative council elections. However, internal strife with rival Fatah led to the disbandment of the government and the formation of an independent Hamas-led administration in the Gaza Strip, which Haniyeh led from 2007 to 2014.&nbsp;</p>

<p>5. Ismail Haniyeh was married and was father to five children. His three sons, Hazem, Amir and Mohammad, were killed in an Israeli airstrike in Gaza on April 10, 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel vowed to kill Ismail Haniyeh and destroy Hamas after the October 7 attack that killed 1,195 people. Since then, Israel's war on Gaza has killed 39,400 people and caused injuries to 90,923&nbsp;others, according to the Gaza Health Ministry.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh was married and was father to five children.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-pilot-faints-on-lisbon-bound-flight-rare-red-alert-issued-6236842]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Co-Pilot Faints On Lisbon-Bound Flight, Rare "Red Alert" Issued]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/co-pilot-faints-on-lisbon-bound-flight-rare-red-alert-issued-6236842]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:13:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Airbus A320 aircraft issued a rare "red alert," which is an obligatory stop of operations as a safety precaution, as the medical situation developed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An co-pilot was hospitalised after he fainted on a flight from London to Portugal on July 27. He became ill during the approach to Lisbon Airport on easyJet Flight EZY2459 from Luton. Upon landing, he was attended to by paramedics at the airport. The first officer was then sent to Santa Maria Hospital in Lisbon for medical treatment, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/travel/news-and-advice/pilot-faints-easyjet-flight-lisbon-b2587488.html"><em>Independent</em></a>.</p>

<p>The Airbus A320 aircraft issued a rare "red alert," which is an obligatory stop of operations as a safety precaution, as the medical situation developed. The 193-passenger flight made a safe, "in line with procedures" landing in Portugal.</p>

<p>A spokesperson for easyJet said in a statement: "easyJet can confirm that the flight EZY2459 from Luton to Lisbon was met by the paramedics upon landing due to a pilot member feeling unwell.</p>

<p>"The Captain landed the flight routinely in line with procedures and passengers disembarked normally. At no point was the safety of the flight compromised. The safety and welfare of passengers and crew is easyJet's highest priority," they said.</p>

<p>Notably, passengers leaving for the return trip to London from Luton experienced a three-hour delay.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a few weeks ago, a pilot of a small aircraft experienced a medical emergency when a passenger took over and the aircraft crashed on an island in Massachusetts, US, as per The Washington Post.</p>

<p>The event happened in West Tisbury, Massachusetts, close to Martha's Vineyard Airport. According to Massachusetts State Police, the male pilot, who is aged 79, experienced an emergency during the plane's final approach. "The crash resulted in a hard landing outside the runway that caused the aircraft's left wing to break in half," The Post quoted the state police as saying.</p>

<p>The pilot was then taken to a Boston hospital in critical condition. The female passenger was not hurt and was released from a local hospital, according to The Post, citing authorities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0mus0ih_easyjet_625x300_01_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 193-passenger flight made a safe, "in line with procedures" landing in Portugal.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lord-el-chapos-son-not-involved-in-kidnapping-says-lawyer-6236700]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mexican Drug Lord El Chapo's Son Didn't Kidnap Fellow Gangster, Says Lawyer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-drug-lord-el-chapos-son-not-involved-in-kidnapping-says-lawyer-6236700]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:58:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The son of jailed Sinaloa Cartel kingpin Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman did not kidnap drug lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada, the Guzman family's lawyer said on Wednesday, following reports Guzman's son had betrayed Zambada to the United States.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The son of jailed Sinaloa Cartel kingpin Joaquin "El Chapo" Guzman did not kidnap drug lord Ismael "El Mayo" Zambada, the Guzman family's lawyer said on Wednesday, following reports Guzman's son had betrayed Zambada to the United States.</p>

<p>Joaquin Guzman Lopez and Zambada, one of the most consequential traffickers in Mexican history, were arrested last week by US agents after the plane in which they were travelling landed at a small airfield in New Mexico.</p>

<p>After the arrests, carried out without the knowledge of the Mexican government, speculation abounded as to whether the two had surrendered or Guzman Lopez had lured Zambada into a trap.</p>

<p>"A kidnapping is out of the question," the Guzman family lawyer, Jose Luis Gonzalez, told Radio Formula.</p>

<p>"No, no. Los Chapitos abide by their father's rules and they followed the usual policy," he said when asked whether Guzman Lopez may have betrayed the 76-year-old Zambada, who co-founded the legendary Sinaloa Cartel alongside his father.</p>

<p>El Chapo's four sons, known as "Los Chapitos," inherited their father's faction of the cartel.</p>

<p>Reuters reached out to Gonzalez but was unable to get an immediate comment.</p>

<p>His account contradicts Zambada's lawyer, Frank Perez, who said on Saturday that Guzman Lopez "kidnapped" his client.</p>

<p>Perez said Guzman Lopez and six men in military uniforms ambushed Zambada near the Sinaloa state capital of Culiacan and forced him onto a plane to the United States against his will.</p>

<p>Both Guzman Lopez and Zambada have pleaded not guilty to drug trafficking charges in US courts.</p>

<p>The Guzman family lawyer said the men's surrender was voluntary and followed about four years of negotiations with US authorities.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7vj0hpbo_joaquin-guzman-lopez-_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joaquin Guzman, one of the most consequential traffickers, was arrested last week by US Agents (file).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-advises-citizens-to-avoid-all-non-essential-travel-to-lebanon-6236419]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Advises Citizens To Avoid All Non-Essential Travel To Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-advises-citizens-to-avoid-all-non-essential-travel-to-lebanon-6236419]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 09:01:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid escalating tensions in the region, Indian Embassy in Lebanon has advised Indians to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid escalating tensions in the region, Indian Embassy in Lebanon has advised Indians to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon. They have been advised to exercise caution, restrict movements and remain in contact with Indian Embassy in Beirut.</p>

<p>Taking to X, the Indian Embassy in Lebanon stated, "In view of the recent escalations in the region, Indian nationals are advised to avoid all non-essential travel to Lebanon. All Indian nationals in Lebanon are advised to exercise caution, restrict their movements and remain in contact with Embassy of India in Beirut through their email id: cons.beirut@mea.gov.in or the emergency phone number 96176860128."</p>

<p>Tensions have further escalated after the rocket attack at Golan Heights, allegedly fired by Hezbollah killed 12 children. In response to the attack at Golan Heights, The Israel Defence Forces (IDF) said that top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr was killed in the Israeli strike in southern Lebanon on Tuesday (local time).</p>

<p>Fuad Shukr, the "most senior Hezbollah military commander," was killed in the Israeli strike, the IDF said in a statement. Shukr sat on the Jihad Council, Hezbollah's top military body, and was considered to be the head of its strategic division.</p>

<p>Since the October 7 attack by Hamas, he has been managing Hezbollah's attacks against Israel, including the deadly strike in Majdal Shams over the weekend that killed 12 children, according to the military.The IDF says Shukr was "responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets, and UAVs" and for the terror group's "force build-up, planning, and execution of terror attacks against the State of Israel," as reported by The Times of Israel.</p>

<p>"Eliminated: Fuad Shukr "Sayyid Muhsan," Hezbollah's Most Senior Military Commander and Hassan Nasrallah's Right-Hand Man," the IDF said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"Shukr has directed Hezbollah's attacks on the State of Israel since October 8th, and he was the commander responsible for the murder of the 12 children in Majdal Shams in northern Israel on Saturday evening, as well as the killing of numerous Israelis and foreign nationals over the years. He was also responsible for the majority of Hezbollah's most advanced weaponry, including precise-guided missiles, cruise missiles, anti-ship missiles, long-range rockets and UAVs," it added.</p>

<p>Houthis and Hamas have both condemned the Israeli strike in separate statements, CNN reported.</p>

<p>"While we affirm our solidarity with Lebanon and its resistance in the face of Zionist arrogance, we appreciate the great role of Hezbollah in supporting the Palestinian people and triumphing over their oppression, at a time when the Arab regimes have abandoned their role and responsibility in defending the Palestinian people and confronting crimes," a statement read from the Houthi political wing, also known as Ansar Allah.</p>

<p>In another statement, Hamas declared "full solidarity with our brotherly Lebanon and the brothers in Hezbollah."</p>

<p>Hamas also said it considers the Israeli strike a "dangerous escalation."Israel had blamed Hezbollah for the rocket attack at Golan Heights on Sunday. However, Hezbollah has denied responsibility for the attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/heo7ka68_israeli-strike-on-lebanon_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions have further escalated after the rocket attack at Golan Heights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/half-of-dementia-cases-could-be-curbed-by-addressing-key-risk-factors-study-6236379]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Half Of Dementia Cases Can Be Curbed By Addressing These Key Risk Factors]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/half-of-dementia-cases-could-be-curbed-by-addressing-key-risk-factors-study-6236379]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 08:43:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of cases of dementia could be prevented or delayed by reducing a range of risk factors such as smoking or air pollution, according to a major new study, though outside experts warn that such measures can only go so far.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of cases of dementia could be prevented or delayed by reducing a range of risk factors such as smoking or air pollution, according to a major new study, though outside experts warn that such measures can only go so far.</p>

<p>The debilitating condition, which progressively robs people of their memories, cognitive abilities, language and independence, currently affects more than 55 million people across the world.</p>

<p>Dementia is caused by a range of diseases, the most common of which is Alzheimer's.</p>

<p>A huge review of the available evidence published in The Lancet journal on Wednesday said that the "potential for prevention is high" in the fight against dementia.</p>

<p>The study follows a previous report in 2020 that also emphasised the importance of prevention.</p>

<p>At the time, the international team of researchers estimated that 40 per cent of dementia cases were linked to 12 risk factors.</p>

<p>The factors included people having a lower level of education, hearing problems, high blood pressure, smoking, obesity, depression, physical inactivity, diabetes, excessive drinking, traumatic brain injury, air pollution and social isolation.</p>

<p>The latest update adds two more risk factors: vision loss and high cholesterol.</p>

<p>"Nearly half of dementias could theoretically be prevented by eliminating these 14 risk factors," the study said.</p>

<h3><strong>EU turns down new drug</strong></h3>

<p>Decades of research and billions of dollars have failed to produce a cure or truly effective drug for dementia.</p>

<p>But since the start of last year, two Alzheimer's treatments have been approved in the United States: Biogen's lecanemab and Eli Lilly's donanemab.</p>

<p>They work by targeting the build-up of two proteins -- tau and amyloid beta -- considered to be one of the main ways the disease progresses.</p>

<p>However, the benefits of the drugs remain modest, they have severe side effects, and they are often very expensive.</p>

<p>In contrast to the US, the European Union's medicine watchdog last week refused to approve lecanemab, and it is still considering donanemab.</p>

<p>Some researchers hope the fact that the new drugs work at all means they will pave the way for more effective treatments in the future.</p>

<p>Others prefer to focus on ways to prevent dementia in the first place.</p>

<p>Masud Husain, a neurologist at the UK's University of Oxford, said that focusing on risk factors "would be far more cost-effective than developing high-tech treatments which so far have been disappointing in their impacts on people with established dementia".</p>

<h3><strong>&nbsp;'How much more could we do?'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The Lancet study was welcomed by experts in the field, among whom the importance of prevention is hardly debatable.</p>

<p>However, some said the idea that nearly half of all dementia cases could be prevented should be put in perspective.</p>

<p>It has not been proven that the risk factors directly cause dementia, as the authors of the study acknowledged.</p>

<p>For example, could it be dementia that is causing depression, rather than the other way around?</p>

<p>It is also difficult to separate the risk factors from each other, though the researchers tried.</p>

<p>Some could be intrinsically linked, such as depression and isolation, or smoking and high blood pressure.</p>

<p>Above all, many of the risk factors are societal scourges that have long proven near impossible to fully address.</p>

<p>The study lays out different recommendations ranging from the personal -- such as wearing a helmet while cycling -- to governmental, such as improving access to education.</p>

<p>"It is not clear whether we could ever completely eliminate any of these risk factors," Charles Marshall, a neurologist at Queen Mary University of London, told AFP.</p>

<p>"We already have public health programmes to reduce smoking and hypertension (high blood pressure), so how much more could we do?"</p>

<p>Tara Spires-Jones, a neuroscientist at the University of Edinburgh, said it was important that "we do not blame people living with dementia for their brain disease".</p>

<p>That is because "it is clear that a large portion of dementias could not be prevented due to genes and things beyond people's control, like opportunities for education as children", she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-07/6g03e98o_dementia-_625x300_15_July_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dementia robs people of their memories and cognitive abilities (representational).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-leader-to-lead-funeral-prayers-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6236223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Leader Ayatollah To Lead Funeral Prayers For Hamas Chief Ismail Haniyeh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-leader-to-lead-funeral-prayers-for-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6236223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 01 Aug 2024 08:02:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran was set to hold funeral processions on Thursday for Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Doha after he was killed in a strike in Tehran blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran was set to hold funeral processions on Thursday for Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh ahead of his burial in Doha after he was killed in a strike in Tehran blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei will lead the prayers for Haniyeh, having earlier threatened a "harsh punishment" for his killing.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's death was announced on Wednesday by Iran's Revolutionary Guards, who said he and his bodyguard were killed in a strike on their accommodation in the Iranian capital at 2:00 am (2230 GMT).</p>

<p>It came just hours after Israel targeted and killed top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr in a retaliatory strike on the Lebanese capital of Beirut, sending fears of a wider regional war soaring.</p>

<p>Israel declined to comment on the Tehran strike.</p>

<p>Khamenei, who has the final say in Iran's political affairs, said after Haniyeh's death that it was "our duty to seek revenge for his blood as he was martyred in the territory of the Islamic Republic of Iran".</p>

<p>The Hamas leader was in Tehran for the inauguration ceremony of newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Iranian president said on Wednesday that "the Zionists (Israel) will soon see the consequences of their cowardly and terrorist act".</p>

<p>Hamas political bureau member Musa Abu Marzuk also vowed retaliation, saying: "The assassination of leader Ismail Haniyeh is a cowardly act and will not go unanswered."</p>

<p>The international community, however, called for de-escalation and a focus on securing a ceasefire in Gaza.</p>

<p>UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres said the strikes in Tehran and Beirut represented a "dangerous escalation".</p>

<p>All efforts, he said, should be "leading to a ceasefire" in Gaza and the release of hostages taken during Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken also said Wednesday that a ceasefire in Gaza was still the "imperative".</p>

<h3><strong>Truce talks threatened&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>From the early hours of Wednesday, crowds took to the streets in cities across Iran to condemn Haniyeh's killing, with hundreds gathering in Tehran's Palestine Square to chant "Death to Israel, Death to America".</p>

<p>The Islamic Republic has not yet published any information on the exact location of the strike.</p>

<p>While Iran has blamed the attack on its arch-foe, Israel has declined to comment on Haniyeh's death. It did, however, claim the killing of Shukr, whom it blamed for a deadly weekend rocket strike on the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said it "eliminated" Hezbollah's top commander in the strike, and a source close to the group said Wednesday that they had found his body in the rubble. Iran's IRNA news agency said Iranian military adviser Milad Bidi also died.</p>

<p>The killings come with regional tensions already inflamed by the war in Gaza, a conflict that has drawn in Iran-backed militant groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Hamas has for months been indirectly negotiating a truce and hostage-prisoner exchange deal with Israel, with Egypt, Qatar and the United States facilitating the talks.</p>

<p>Analysts told AFP that Haniyeh was a moderating influence within the Islamist group and that while he would be replaced, the dynamics within Hamas could change.</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for the October 7 attack that ignited war in Gaza.</p>

<p>That attack resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Militants also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,445 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>The prime minister of key ceasefire broker Qatar said Haniyeh's killing had thrown the whole mediation process into doubt.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/7qhr89n8_haniyeh-reuters-_625x300_19_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Hamas leader was in Tehran for the inauguration ceremony of newly elected President Masoud Pezeshkian]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>