<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:07:07 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-supermoon-of-the-year-aligns-with-leonid-meteor-shower-this-weekend-7024636]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Final Supermoon Of The Year Aligns With Leonid Meteor Shower This Weekend]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/final-supermoon-of-the-year-aligns-with-leonid-meteor-shower-this-weekend-7024636]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:10:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Skygazers across the world better be ready to catch this week's supermoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Skygazers across the world better be ready to catch this week's supermoon. The next one won't come around for a bit. But on Thursday, the fourth and last supermoon of the year will pass within roughly 225,000 miles of Earth, appearing larger and brighter than usual. It will take until Friday to attain its full lunar phase. While seeing a supermoon in itself is a delight, the Leonid meteor shower could make for a dazzling bonus as it reaches its peak on Saturday night and into early Sunday, reported <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/14/science/full-beaver-moon-leonids-meteor-shower/index.html">CNN </a>quoting the American Meteor Society.</p>

<p>The full moon in November is referred to as "the beaver moon," a reference to the start of the animal's hibernating season. The upcoming full moon will reach the summit of its full phase on Friday at 4:29 pm Eastern Time. However, it will be visible to the naked eye as full one day prior to and after its peak, said Noah Petro, chief of NASA's Planetary Geology, Geophysics and Geochemistry Laboratory.</p>

<p>Petro said, “There is a moment in time when the moon is at its fullest, but if it's cloudy or you're busy, going out any other time either a day before, later in the evening or the following day you will still see the beauty that is the full moon.”</p>

<p>A supermoon, more of a popular word than a scientific one, happens when a full lunar phase coincides with an exceptionally close orbit around the Earth. This phenomenon occurs only three or four times a year and consecutively because of the moon's ever-changing oval orbit.</p>

<p>The full moon in November will be a little further away than the one in October, which was the closest moon of 2024 and was photographed worldwide.</p>

<p>If local weather conditions allow, the beaver moon will be visible to those in the Northern and Southern Hemispheres. They may even be able to witness a Leonid meteor burning brightly in the night sky.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-06/aecncqfg_supermoon-afp_625x300_15_June_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The full moon in November will be a little further away than the one in October.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazils-g20-presidency-hunger-poverty-inequality-top-priorities-7025125]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil's G20 Presidency: Hunger, Poverty, Inequality Top Priorities]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brazils-g20-presidency-hunger-poverty-inequality-top-priorities-7025125]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 14:07:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[G20 is the main forum for economic and financial cooperation -- areas increasingly tested by today's shifting geopolitics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the pantheon of global gatherings, the G20 is the main forum for economic and financial cooperation -- areas increasingly tested by today's shifting geopolitics.</p>

<p>The Group of Twenty brings together the world's biggest economies. It is made up of 19 nations, including the United States and China, and two regional organizations: the European Union and African Union.</p>

<p>Here is a primer on the G20 and what it does:</p>

<p><strong>Who is in the G20?</strong></p>

<p>Despite its name, the G20 today counts 21 members.</p>

<p>The 19 countries in it are: Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Britain, Canada, China, France, Germany, India, Indonesia, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Russia, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, South Korea, Turkey, and the United States.</p>

<p>Together, they account for 85 percent of global GDP and three-quarters of global trade.</p>

<p>The European Union has also long been a member, with the African Union admitted last year.</p>

<p><strong>How did it come about?</strong></p>

<p>The G20 was conceived in 1999, in response to the Asian financial crisis two years prior that shook the global system. It was originally designed as a coordination space for finance ministers and central bank chiefs.</p>

<p>It was elevated to leader-level in 2008 -- after another global financial crisis -- so heads of state and government could meet annually on international economic issues.</p>

<p>The gathering also encompasses side forums where representatives discuss topics such as health, culture, social justice, agriculture, tourism and fighting corruption.</p>

<p><strong>What's happening this G20?</strong></p>

<p>Brazil holds the rotating G20 presidency this year and has made fighting hunger, poverty and inequality its priorities, along with sustainable development and reforming global governance.</p>

<p>To back that up, it is holding a G20 Social forum days before the main November 18-19 event, designed to boost civil society's voice in the governments' discussions.</p>

<p>The G20 summit is taking place in Rio de Janeiro and will see US President Joe Biden attend alongside China's Xi Jinping and other leaders.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin announced last month he would not be traveling to Brazil.</p>

<p>He said his presence would "wreck" the summit, but insisted an International Criminal Court arrest warrant out against him for Russia's actions in Ukraine was not a factor in his decision. Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov is going in his place.</p>

<p><strong>Past frictions</strong></p>

<p>Recent G20s demonstrated discord between participating countries over Russia's war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>The last two summits, in Bali in 2022 and Delhi in 2023, had to ditch the traditional "family photo" of the leaders standing together in a symbol of unity because of different stances toward Moscow and how to characterize the war.</p>

<p>Xi also upbraided Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau at the Bali summit after details of talks they held were leaked to the media.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0lum2g4_g20_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Brazil holds the G20 presidency this year and has made hunger, poverty and inequality its priorities.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/megaquake-warning-hits-japans-growth-in-third-quarter-7024698]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Megaquake' Warning Hits Japan's Growth In Third Quarter]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/megaquake-warning-hits-japans-growth-in-third-quarter-7024698]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:04:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Japan's growth slowed in the third quarter after warnings of a major earthquake hit activity, official data showed, as Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba seeks to jumpstart the world's fourth-largest economy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Japan's growth slowed in the third quarter after warnings of a major earthquake hit activity, official data showed Friday, as Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba seeks to jumpstart the world's fourth-largest economy.</p>

<p>A "megaquake" alert in August and one of the fiercest typhoons in decades resulted in gross domestic product (GDP) expanding just 0.2 percent between July and September from the previous quarter, according to preliminary government data.</p>

<p>The data met market expectations, but marked a slowdown from a revised 0.5 percent in the previous three months.</p>

<p>On an annualised basis, GDP grew 0.9 percent, much slower than the revised 2.2 percent growth in April-June.</p>

<p>The government is expecting a "gradual recovery" of the economy -- beset for decades by stagnation and harmful deflation -- chief cabinet secretary Yoshimasa Hayashi said on Friday.</p>

<p>"Our country is at an important crossroads as it's about to transition into a growth-based economy driven by wage hikes and investment," he told a regular briefing.</p>

<p>"To realise that, we will implement all possible economic and fiscal policies, including a package currently under consideration."</p>

<p>Ishiba kept his job in a parliamentary vote on Monday, despite last month leading the ruling coalition to its worst general election result in 15 years.</p>

<p>The 67-year-old has unveiled plans for the government to support the AI and semiconductor sectors with more than 10 trillion yen ($64 billion) by 2030.</p>

<p>He also hopes to win over opposition parties this month to pass a draft supplementary budget for a new stimulus package -- reportedly to include cash handouts for low-income households and families.</p>

<p>Higher spending on cars, as production resumed after disruption related to a domestic testing scandal, helped boost output during the quarter, analysts said.</p>

<p>Wage hikes and temporary income tax cuts were also positive factors.</p>

<p>But this was tempered by Typhoon Shanshan and the "megaquake" alert, issued -- and later lifted -- by the weather agency in August for the first time under a new warning system.</p>

<p>This prompted consumers to stock up on emergency supplies, leading to shortages of rice in supermarkets, while thousands cancelled hotel bookings in one of Japan's biggest holiday periods.</p>

<p>Factory production was also hit when Typhoon Shanshan hit in the same month, forcing the cancellation of trains and flights.</p>

<p>Stefan Angrick, Moody's Analytics economist, called the challenges facing Japan "substantial", especially with Donald Trump's return as US president presaging a "tumultuous" time for global trade.</p>

<p>"Wage growth is improving but is not yet strong enough to keep up with inflation, stretching household finances. Weak external demand and domestic production issues will weigh down exports," Angrick said.</p>

<p>A further slide in the yen against the dollar might prompt the Bank of Japan to raise interest rates before year's end despite the poor run of data, he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hrm4fcao_japan_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A "megaquake" alert in August and one of the fiercest typhoons in decades resulted in slowed growth.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-remote-engineer-s-login-failure-grounded-flights-stranded-7-lakh-uk-passengers-7024136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When WFH Techie's Password Error Led To Travel Nightmare For 7 Lakh Fliers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-a-remote-engineer-s-login-failure-grounded-flights-stranded-7-lakh-uk-passengers-7024136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:52:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A technical glitch caused chaos for 7 lakh air travellers in the United Kingdom during a bank holiday weekend in August last year. The issue started when the corrupted file caused a breakdown in flight processing systems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A technical glitch caused chaos for seven lakh air travellers in the United Kingdom during a bank holiday weekend in August last year. The issue started when the corrupted file caused a breakdown in flight processing systems. This led to widespread flight cancellations, leaving travellers stuck at airports for hours, the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/14/world-news/british-air-traffic-employees-work-from-home-day-exacerbated-nightmare-delays-for-70k-travelers-report/ " rel="nofollow,noindex">NY Post</a> reported. The problem grew, as some engineers were working from home that day, and were unable to address the issue remotely on time. An investigation revealed that a critical delay in resolving the issue was caused by difficulties in authenticating a remote engineer's password credentials.</p>

<p>The glitch began early on August 28, 2023, and grounded flights nationwide. National Air Traffic Services (NATS) had arranged for a Level 2 engineer to be available on call, but not on-site, despite it being an exceptionally busy travel day. A Level 1 engineer, who was present at NATS' Swanwick facility in Hampshire, immediately began diagnostic procedures after the systems failed at 8:32 AM. However, the engineer struggled to resolve the issue because the senior technical support engineer was working remotely.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The remote engineer's attempts to log in and fix the issue were delayed after password authentication issues prevented timely access to the system. It took an hour and a half for the engineers to arrive at the airport, but they still couldn't resolve the problem right away. The glitch wasn't fully fixed until four hours after it was first detected but not before causing disruptions to flight schedules that stretched for several days.</p>

<p>The ripple effect of the disruption forced airlines to pay out over $126 million in compensation to affected travellers. The Civil Aviation Authority (CAA), which conducted the inquiry, has recommended 48 new policy measures, including the need for senior engineers to be available on-site during critical times, even when remote work is an option.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/5m2ck318_airport-generic_625x300_18_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covids-racism-to-2004-voter-fraud-rfk-jrs-many-conspiracy-theories-7024417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Covid's 'Racism' To 2004 'Voter Fraud': RFK Jr's Many Conspiracy Theories]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covids-racism-to-2004-voter-fraud-rfk-jrs-many-conspiracy-theories-7024417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:28:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kennedy, known for his controversial vaccine stances, has made several conspiracy theories over the years. The bizarre theories on Covid-19 during the pandemic have made headlines across the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr, the eccentric scion of America's most prominent political dynasty, has been named the head of the US Health Department by President-elect Donald Trump. Trump said that Robert Kennedy would restore agencies like the Health and Human Services to the traditions of gold-standard scientific research and end the chronic disease epidemic.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/people/robert-f-kennedy-jr-anti-vaccine-activist-who-is-now-us-health-secretary-7023554">Robert Kennedy Jr</a>, an anti-vaxxer known for his controversial views on vaccines, has been in the news for a string of conspiracy theories and bizarre statements over the years. If approved by the Senate, which Trump's Republican Party controls, the 70-year-old Kennedy Jr will have authority over 13 agencies that come under the Health and Human Services - which include the Food and Drug Administration (FDA); the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), which also has an international role; the National Institutes of Health that do cutting edge research; and Medicare, the government's health insurance for seniors. This may even give Kennedy Jr the power to subvert the entire US health system.</p>

<p>Let's take a look at some of RJK Jr's conspiracy theories:</p>

<h3><strong>Covid-19 Targets Certain Races</strong></h3>

<p>Robert Kennedy Jr had bizarrely suggested during the peak COVID-19 pandemic that the disease targets certain races while skipping others. According to him, Covid "ethnically targeted" white and black people and "spared" the Jewish and Chinese people.</p>

<p>Another theory he propagated was that Covid was genetically engineered and was a bioweapons problem.</p>

<p>He also promoted the use of unapproved treatment and prevention of Covid - &nbsp;ivermectin (an antiparasitic drug that studies have shown does not effectively treat or prevent Covid).</p>

<h3><strong>Vaccine Can Cause Autism&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>According to RFK Jr, vaccinations can cause autism - a neurological and developmental disorder. In a 2006 Rolling Stone article, the 70-year-old had said modern vaccine formulas are leading to a rise in autism, adding that the US government knew about it but was allowing the pharmaceutical industry to "poison" Americans, reported Forbes.</p>

<h3><strong>CIA Helped In John F Kennedy's Assassination&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Robert F <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-quits-white-house-race-a-look-at-his-bizarre-campaign-6406892">Kennedy</a> Jr claimed that the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) was involved in the 1963 assassination of former US President John F Kennedy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>RFK Jr is the nephew of John F Kennedy and the son of his brother, Robert, a Senator and former Attorney General - who was also assassinated in 1968.</p>

<h3><strong>Voter Fraud In 2004 Presidential Election&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>According to the longtime environment and health campaigner, voter fraud allowed George W Bush to win the 2004 US Presidential election against Democratic leader John Kerry.</p>

<h3><strong>Prescription Drugs Lead To Mass Shootings&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>During a Twitter Spaces discussion with Elon Musk a few years ago, RFK Jr linked prescription drugs to the mass shootings in the US. According to him, drugs like Prozac lead to the shootings.</p>

<p>"Before the antidepressants, there were no shooting incidents," he told Musk.</p>

<h3><strong>Parasitic Worm Ate His Brain&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr also shares strange stories from his personal life. He had once said a parasitic worm entered his brain, ate a portion of it, and then died.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2ml1er_robert-f-kennedy-jr-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-donald-trumps-top-team-rfk-jr-elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-pete-hegseth-tulsi-gabbard-among-firebrands-and-stalwarts-7024397]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump's Top Team: Firebrands And Stalwarts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-results-donald-trumps-top-team-rfk-jr-elon-musk-vivek-ramaswamy-pete-hegseth-tulsi-gabbard-among-firebrands-and-stalwarts-7024397]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 12:23:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President-elect Donald Trump is handing top roles for his future White House to a mix of political allies, firebrands and a few relatively conventional figures.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President-elect Donald Trump is handing top roles for his future White House to a mix of political allies, firebrands and a few relatively conventional figures.</p>

<p>These are the key nominations, some requiring potentially difficult Senate confirmations -- unless Trump can circumvent scrutiny through a process called recess appointments.</p>

<p><strong>Health Secretary: RFK Jr.</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2ml1er_robert-f-kennedy-jr-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>F. Kennedy Jr. is a longtime health and environmental campaigner, who at 70 proudly shows off his muscular body.</p>

<p>But the scion of the famous US political dynasty is also a leading anti-vaccine activist and conspiracy theorist who has promoted the disproven idea that childhood vaccines cause autism and claimed that Covid vaccines were deadly.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-chooses-anti-vaccine-activist-rfk-jr-to-head-health-department-7023541">Donald Trump Chooses Anti-Vaccine Activist RFK Jr. To Head Health Department</a></p>

<p><strong>'Government Efficiency': Elon Musk</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gniajb58_elon-musk-wealth_625x300_13_November_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Musk, the world's richest man, was tapped to lead a new Department of Government Efficiency, along with another wealthy Trump ally, Vivek Ramaswamy.</p>

<p>Musk says he is targeting $2 trillion in cuts from the federal government's $7 trillion budget, without explaining how.</p>

<p>There has been no explanation of how the Tesla, SpaceX and Starlink boss would navigate conflicts of interest as a major US government contractor.</p>

<p><strong>Secretary of State: Marco Rubio</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4dcjqha_marco-rubio_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Trump tapped the Florida senator to be top diplomat, with an eye to intensifying the US power struggle with China.</p>

<p>Rubio, a relatively traditional conservative hawk, has said China seeks "to reorient the world."</p>

<p>The son of Cuban immigrants is a fervent supporter of Israel and longtime critic of Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p><strong>Defense Secretary: Pete Hegseth</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/i67anblg_pete-hegseth_625x300_13_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Fox News host and National Guard veteran Hegseth was nominated to lead the world's most powerful military, despite a slim CV.</p>

<p>Hegseth joined Fox News -- Trump's favorite network -- in 2014 and hosts a weekend program. The Pentagon employs some 2.9 million people.</p>

<p><strong>National Security Advisor: Mike Waltz</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bgettsik_mike-waltz-michael-waltz-reuters_625x300_13_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Congressman and former special forces officer Waltz has been tapped as Trump's top White House foreign policy advisor.</p>

<p>Waltz is critical of both China and Russia, but backs winding down support for Ukraine.</p>

<p><strong>CIA Director: John Ratcliffe</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/hd0m43v8_john-ratcliffe-afp_625x300_03_August_19.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Ratcliffe, who was director of national intelligence at the tumultuous end of Trump's first term, has been tapped to lead the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>

<p>He defended Trump during his first impeachment trial for allegedly blackmailing Ukraine's president. But he is seen as somewhat of an institutionalist and a relatively safe pair of hands.</p>

<p><strong>Director of National Intelligence: Tulsi Gabbard</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s7vp5rvg_tulsi-gabbard-reuters_625x300_14_November_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>Gabbard, a former Hawaii congresswoman, switched sides from the Democrats to back Trump's reelection. She has stood out for echoing Kremlin talking points about the invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>As director of national intelligence, she'd oversee coordination of the 18 intelligence agencies.</p>

<p><strong>Attorney General: Matt Gaetz</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/bu592dr8_matt-gaetz-reuters_625x300_14_November_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: Reuters</span></p>
</div>

<p>A pro-Trump firebrand in Congress, Gaetz was subject to a House ethics probe into alleged sex trafficking.</p>

<p>The Justice Department, which he would head, announced last year that it would not bring charges in the same case, after a lengthy inquiry. The department is also expected to drop a string of criminal cases against Trump.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Trump named his personal attorneys Todd Blanche and Emil Bove, who defended him during his trial this year over hush money payments to former porn star Stormy Daniels, as deputies to Gaetz.</p>

<p>John Sauer, who represented Trump during his successful presidential immunity case before the Supreme Court, was also tapped as solicitor general.</p>

<p><strong>Homeland Security Secretary: Kristi Noem</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7tq94hrk_kristi-noem-afp_625x300_13_November_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>South Dakota Governor Noem, a longtime Trump loyalist, would play a key role in any Trump effort to restrict immigration and deport undocumented migrants.</p>

<p>Noem became famous for admitting that she shot an "untrainable" pet dog, saying it showed her ability to make tough choices.</p>

<p>Veteran immigration official Tom Homan is set to be the country's "border czar."</p>

<p><strong>Secretary of the Interior: Doug Burgum</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jdtago4o_doug-burgum_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>North Dakota Governor Doug Burgum, a billionaire businessman-turned-politician like Trump, was picked to lead the Department of the Interior, which oversees federal lands, including their oil and gas production.</p>

<p>Burgum ran against Trump in the 2024 Republican primary and was on the shortlist of his potential vice presidential picks.</p>

<p><strong>UN Ambassador: Elise Stefanik</strong></p>

<p>New York congresswoman Stefanik is a vocal Trump ally and pro-Israel stalwart. She was among the first to be nominated as the president-elect rolled out his choices.</p>

<p><strong>Ambassador to Israel: Mike Huckabee</strong></p>

<p>Trump says the former Arkansas governor, a Christian pastor-turned-politician, "loves Israel, and the people of Israel, and likewise, the people of Israel love him."</p>

<p><strong>Others</strong></p>

<p>Environmental Protection Agency: Former congressman Lee Zeldin.</p>

<p>White House Chief of Staff: Trump campaign manager Susie Wiles.</p>

<p>Veterans Affairs secretary: Iraq war veteran and former Georgia congressman Doug Collins.</p>

<p>Treasury, Commerce, Education, Agriculture: no announcement yet.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/0n68euvg_donald-trump-team_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/princess-mikasa-oldest-member-of-japans-royal-family-dies-at-101-7024151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Princess Mikasa, Oldest Member Of Japan's royal family, Dies At 101]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/princess-mikasa-oldest-member-of-japans-royal-family-dies-at-101-7024151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:40:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Princess Mikasa, the oldest member of Japan's royal family and great aunt to the emperor, died aged 101 on Friday in a Tokyo hospital, the Imperial Household Agency said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Princess Mikasa, the oldest member of Japan's royal family and great aunt to the emperor, died aged 101 on Friday in a Tokyo hospital, the Imperial Household Agency said.</p>

<p>She had been hospitalised since March after suffering a stroke and pneumonia and had been recuperating there following treatment in intensive care.</p>

<p>Born Yuriko Takagi to an aristocratic family on June 4, 1923, the princess was 18 when she married the younger brother of wartime emperor Hirohito.</p>

<p>The couple had five children -- two girls and three boys. She gave birth to her first, a daughter, in 1944 during World War II.</p>

<p>The imperial couple's house burned down in an air raid and she was forced to stay in a shelter with her baby, according to Japan's Asahi Shimbun daily.</p>

<p>Hirohito -- who served as Japan's commander-in-chief during its brutal march across Asia in the 1930s and 40s -- surrendered in an August 1945 speech, after the United States dropped atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki.</p>

<p>Princess Mikasa's husband Prince Mikasa, who died in 2016 at 100, was in favour of the decision to end the war.</p>

<p>But young officers who disagreed would come regularly to the shelter to try and change his mind.</p>

<p>Princess Mikasa recalled that the atmosphere was "very frightening" with "heated arguments and tension, as if bullets were about to fly", the Asahi Shimbun said.</p>

<p>Having lost their home, the decades that followed were far from luxurious for the princess, who took on domestic duties as the family struggled financially.</p>

<p>"When I was raising my children, Japanese society was still in a difficult period," she said on her 100th birthday in a statement released by the Imperial Household Agency.</p>

<p>"I recall with deep gratitude how many people, including my husband, always supported me," the princess added.</p>

<p>All three of Princess Misaka's sons passed away before her, including one who died aged 47 while playing squash at the Canadian embassy.</p>

<p>Male-only succession rules mean that Japan's royal women cannot ascend to the throne and must forgo their imperial status if they marry outside the family.</p>

<p>Princess Misaka has three granddaughters who remain princesses, including Akiko, whose 2015 book was a hit in Japan, describing her studies at Oxford and an incident in which her diplomatic passport caused suspicion at an airport.</p>

<p>The 101-year-old's passing followed reports since early November that her condition had begun to deteriorate.</p>

<p>Current Emperor Naruhito's 18-year-old nephew Prince Hisahito is the only young heir to the throne. Naruhito's daughter Princess Aiko is barred from the throne under the Imperial Household Law, in place since 1947.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6b1mue3o_japan-princess-mikasa_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Japan Princess Mikasa was in hospital since March.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/australian-couple-returns-home-from-work-finds-an-unexpected-guest-7023638]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Australian Couple Returns Home From Work. Finds An Unexpected Guest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/australian-couple-returns-home-from-work-finds-an-unexpected-guest-7023638]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:40:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Australian couple returned from work only to find a koala in their bedroom.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Australian couple returned from work only to find a koala in their bedroom. Fran Dias Rufino and her husband Brunno returned to their east Adelaide home around 12:30 AM on Wednesday and spotted the intruder. “I was scared, happy and excited at the same time,” Fran told <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/14/australia/australia-couple-home-koala-intl-hnk/index.html">CNN</a>.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Fran, a Brazilian immigrant in Australia, shared the shocking experience on Instagram, saying she was speechless when she saw the animal inside her house. In the video, the koala was seen sitting on the floor next to their bed and looking at Fran and her husband. Then, it jumped on a bedside table and leapt onto the bed. While Fran yelled in the background, the koala was seen scuttling around the house, perhaps trying to find a way out.<br />
&nbsp;<br />
“Only in Australia haahahahah. We came from work now (12:30am) and we just found A KOALA in my bedroom in my bed. Any tips? I was so nervous that I forgot my English ahahahha. Brunno put him out in the end but I was scared because he was aggressive,”&nbsp;Fran wrote.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCRjVOctNtX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCRjVOctNtX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCRjVOctNtX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DCRjVOctNtX/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by FRAN DIAS RUFINO (@frandiasrufino)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p><br />
Koalas are primarily found on Australia's east and southeast coasts. These animals are at risk of extinction in areas such as New South Wales, Queensland and the Australian Capital Territory, due to disease, drought, bushfires, and land clearing. Their numbers in South Australia, where the couple lives, are steady. In certain places, populations are so robust that they are being managed to protect the habitat.<br />
<br />
There are concerns that endangered populations along Australia's east coast may continue to fall due to disease and habitat destruction. A 10-year national recovery plan was introduced in 2022, but according to an annual report published in May, two years later, the long-term survival chances for wild koalas in designated areas are still "poor."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/slgd85jo_australian-couple-koala-instagram_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Koalas are primarily found on Australia's east and southeast coasts.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-world-s-largest-coral-in-solomon-islands-7024055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Stunned By Enormous Coral Discovery In Solomon Islands]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/scientists-discover-world-s-largest-coral-in-solomon-islands-7024055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:22:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists have found the world's largest coral -- as big as two basketball courts -- visible from space and at least 300 years old in the waters of the Solomon Islands.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have found the world's largest coral -- as big as two basketball courts -- visible from space and at least 300 years old in the waters of the Solomon Islands, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/14/climate/worlds-largest-coral-solomon-islands/index.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">CNN </a>reported.&nbsp;The gigantic coral was discovered in October during a scientific expedition launched by the National Geographic Pristine Seas program to study ocean health. According to Pristine Seas, the coral is longer than a blue whale, the largest mammal on Earth. In contrast to a reef, which is made up of numerous colonies, it is a single specimen that developed continuously for centuries.</p>

<p>“Just when we think there is nothing left to discover on planet Earth, we find a massive coral made of nearly 1 billion little polyps, pulsing with life,” said Enric Sala, marine ecologist and founder of Pristine Seas.</p>

<p>From above, the coral resembles a massive, swaying brown rock. At first, several members of the team, even thought it was a shipwreck. "I knew right away that I was looking at something special," said underwater videographer and marine biologist Manu San Félix. It's “close to the size of a cathedral.”</p>

<p>Later, when scientists looked at satellite photos, they discovered the coral was so enormous and could be seen from space.</p>

<p>With its intricate web of polyps and bursts of vibrant purples, yellows, blues, and reds contrast with its brown colour, the coral transforms into something amazing up close. Fish, crabs, and shrimp are among the many marine creatures that call the coral home. According to San Féliz, it's also like a living encyclopedia, with data on ocean conditions dating back hundreds of years.</p>

<p>Corals are vital for both humans and marine life. While marine creatures depend on them for food and shelter, corals indirectly provide food for an estimated 1 billion people by supporting fisheries and acting as a barrier against storms and sea level rise.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/4hp8qe8_worlds-largest-coral_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The newly discovered coral measures 112 by 105 feet, larger than the average blue whale.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/burnt-plants-ash-and-missing-birds-tell-tales-of-israel-hezbollah-war-7024022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Burnt Plants, Ash And Missing Birds Tell Tales Of Israel-Hezbollah war]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/burnt-plants-ash-and-missing-birds-tell-tales-of-israel-hezbollah-war-7024022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:19:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Across northern Israel's lush, green nature reserves, the ecological toll of the war between Israel and Hezbollah militants is laid bare: wild boar hit by shrapnel, trees reduced to ashes and swathes of charred vegetation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Across northern Israel's lush, green nature reserves, the ecological toll of the war between Israel and Hezbollah militants is laid bare: wild boar hit by shrapnel, trees reduced to ashes and swathes of charred vegetation.</p>

<p>In the Hula Valley, home to a unique migration sanctuary for birds, a flock of common cranes and their cacophony of calls fill the air -- but smoke billows in the distance and their sounds soon compete with the whir of Israeli military helicopters overhead.</p>

<p>The impact is particularly clear at the Agamon Hula Valley Nature Reserve, where all that remains in some areas after more than a year of Hezbollah rocket fire from Lebanon are burned plants and cinder-strewn soil.</p>

<p>Inbar Rubin, field director at the reserve, worries about the war's effects on birds.</p>

<p>"The noises of war, the sounds of interceptions, of (rockets) falling and the loud booms -- these are the sounds that birds hear," Rubin said. "It's a huge source of stress."</p>

<p>The war has driven visitors away from the reserve, which sits approximately 30 kilometres (19 miles) from the border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>"People say to me, 'Wow, the birds must be happier because there are no people,' but the damage the war does to nature is a million times more than the damage visitors do."</p>

<p>The reserve is an internationally known resting spot for hundreds of millions of birds migrating from Europe and Asia to Africa and back during the spring and autumn seasons.</p>

<p>It is home to pelicans, ducks, eagles and other birds of prey, as well as flamingos, which Rubin said is "a fairly new phenomenon".</p>

<p>But she noted that fewer birds were stopping at the sanctuary than in previous seasons, adding there was "much less nesting than in normal years" and reduced mating.</p>

<p><strong>Paradise lost?</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah began launching low-intensity attacks on Israel last year, in solidarity with its ally Hamas following the Palestinian militant group's October 7, 2023 attack.</p>

<p>After nearly a year of trading cross-border fire with Hezbollah, Israel widened the focus of its operations from Gaza to Lebanon, launching a massive aerial campaign and sending ground forces across the border.</p>

<p>The bombing has devastated villages in Lebanon, especially areas along its southern border with Israel, where Hezbollah holds sway.</p>

<p>Around 50,000 cranes came to the reserve the previous winter, said longtime ornithologist Yossi Leshem, "and for them, it was really paradise".</p>

<p>But after the Israel-Hezbollah war started, he added, the number of birds arriving dropped by 70 percent.</p>

<p>"It is a real threat," said Leshem, also the founder of an international bird migration research centre. The fighting and fires have also caused food resources for the birds to dwindle.</p>

<p>"Even if the war will stop in a year now -- and I hope it will stop as soon as possible... the impact can be felt for many more years," he told AFP.</p>

<p>In the long term, however, the conflict would not ultimately change the birds' pattern of migration, Leshem said. The birds passing through will be "less successful and so on, but finally, when the war stops, it (migration) goes on".</p>

<p>The damage is not limited to the reserve.</p>

<p>Israel's nature and parks authority has assessed that since the October 7 Hamas attack, around 92,400 acres (37,400 hectares) of nature reserves, national parks, forests and open areas have been burned across the country.</p>

<p>"The damage to nature is of course extensive and in numbers we are not used to," said Amit Dolev, an ecologist for the authority's northern district.</p>

<p>Israel's military has said nearly 16,000 projectiles, including exploding drones, have been fired into the country from Lebanese territory, many sparking wildfires.</p>

<p>Others, shot down by Israel's military, have sent shrapnel flying into open areas.</p>

<p><strong>Nature's resilience</strong></p>

<p>At the nature reserve of Tel Dan, adjacent to the Lebanese border, around 17 acres (seven hectares) out of 400 have been devastated by fires ignited by rockets.</p>

<p>On the banks of the burbling Dan stream, beside the silhouette of a burnt-out blackthorn tree, Ramadan Issa, who manages the reserve, said he had spent the last year putting out fires and rescuing animals injured or distressed by the fighting.</p>

<p>He pointed to suffering wildlife including porcupines, snakes and wild boars injured or killed by missiles or shrapnel, as well as the destruction of ancient trees.</p>

<p>But on the charred earth where he stood, small green blades of grass and vegetation were already sprouting.</p>

<p>"Nature is strong," Issa said. "It can grow back very fast and after the first (winter) rains, a lot will start to come back."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n8kp3j3o_northern-israel-nature-reserve_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A flock of Gray Cranes fly at the Agamon Hula Valley Nature Reserve in northern Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indonesian-celeb-lydia-onics-alleged-private-video-leaked-after-imsha-rehman-and-minahil-malik-7023908]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indonesian Celeb Lydia Onics Alleged Private Video Leaked]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indonesian-celeb-lydia-onics-alleged-private-video-leaked-after-imsha-rehman-and-minahil-malik-7023908]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:06:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An explicit video purportedly showing Indonesian e-sports star Lydia Onic has been leaked online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An explicit video purportedly showing Indonesian e-sports star Lydia Onic has been leaked online. The over 12-minute video has sparked discussion on social media, with many claiming the woman in the clip resembles Lydia Onic, also known as Lydia Setiawan in the gaming community.</p>

<p>Lydia Onic is a well-known professional gamer and content creator, with a strong presence in the e-sports world as a brand ambassador for ONIC Esports. She has over 1 million followers on Instagram and is popular for her gaming skills and content. Now, the leaked video, widely shared on social media, has shifted the focus to her personal life.</p>

<p>The new video has led to increased online searches as people try to verify the identity of the woman in the clip. There has been no official confirmation about whether it is indeed Ms Lydia.</p>

<p>This incident follows a series of similar controversies involving Pakistani TikTokers Imsha Rehman and Minahil Malik, whose <a href="http://https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-influencer-imsha-rehman-deactivates-social-media-accounts-after-private-video-leaks-7008463">private videos also went viral</a>&nbsp;in recent weeks.</p>

<p>Ms Rehman, a popular figure on TikTok, faced immense backlash after her intimate video surfaced online. The 22-year-old, who boasts a significant following, was accused by some social media users of deliberately leaking the video for attention. However, it appears that Ms. Rehman may have been a victim of a data breach. In the wake of the incident, she deactivated her social media accounts, describing the overwhelming flood of negative comments as the reason for her decision. In a post, she said, “Till the time video is viral, I have deactivated my account.” Screenshots from the video spread widely across platforms and even turned into memes, further fueling the controversy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Similarly, Minahil Malik, another Pakistani influencer, faced accusations of leaking an intimate video with her boyfriend, which she strongly denied. Ms Malik filed a complaint with the Federal Investigation Agency (FIA), but she, too, was criticised for allegedly using the controversy as a publicity stunt.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pvhnmofg_lydia-onic-instagram_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lydia Onic is a well-known professional gamer and content creator.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-rounds-fired-outside-music-studio-in-canadas-toronto-23-arrested-7023939]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[100 Rounds Fired Outside Music Studio In Canada's Toronto, 23 Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/100-rounds-fired-outside-music-studio-in-canadas-toronto-23-arrested-7023939]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 11:03:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 100 rounds were fired outside a music recording studio in Canada's Toronto. The late-night gunfire on Monday led to the arrest of 23 people and the seizure of 16 firearms, including two assault-style rifles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 100 rounds were fired outside a music recording studio in Canada's Toronto. The late-night gunfire on Monday led to the arrest of 23 people and the seizure of 16 firearms, including two assault-style rifles. The locality where the firing took place also houses studios frequented by Punjabi musicians in the city.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Toronto police were conducting an unrelated bail compliance check when the violence erupted around 11:20 pm. A stolen vehicle pulled up near a recording studio before three individuals stepped out and fired at the studio and those nearby. In response, members of a rival group reportedly returned fire, Toronto Police said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Toronto Police Deputy Chief Lauren Pogue said that plainclothes officers in an unmarked vehicle were caught in the crossfire, narrowly escaping injury despite their vehicle being hit multiple times.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The exchange of gunfire reportedly scattered suspects as they attempted to flee. Police acted quickly, using their unmarked vehicle to box in the stolen car, apprehending a gunman following a brief foot chase. However, two suspects managed to escape and are still missing.</p>

<p>A video surfaced prior to the gunfight, showed several individuals dancing with modern firearms. Following the initial arrest, a search of the area was conducted, leading to the seizure of 16 firearms hidden throughout the vicinity. Officers recovered several weapons discarded by fleeing suspects and others concealed on the rooftop, inside the recording studio, and even in nearby garbage bins. Among these firearms were multiple handguns and two high-powered rifles.</p>

<p>Several Punjabi artists use recording studios in the area. Popular Punjabi music artists like AP Dhillon and Gippy Grewal have previously been targeted in similar incidents. The area has a thriving Punjabi community and serves as a hub for artists who have connections to India.</p>

<p>This high-profile incident comes amid concerns from Indian and Canadian authorities about the presence of Khalistani separatists and organised crime syndicates reportedly supported by Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) in Canada. &nbsp;According to Indian security sources, previous cases have uncovered a flow of illegal firearms from ISI channels into Canada, aimed at arming Khalistani militants.</p>

<p>The June 2023 killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar triggered a diplomatic rift between India and Canada which continues to this day.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/grqo4c0o_canada-firing-_625x300_15_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A video surfaced prior to the gunfight, showed several individuals dancing with modern firearms.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-election-results-president-anura-dissanayakes-national-peoples-power-party-wins-parliamentary-majority-7023890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Landslide Victory For Lanka President's Party In Snap Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sri-lanka-election-results-president-anura-dissanayakes-national-peoples-power-party-wins-parliamentary-majority-7023890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:55:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sri Lanka Election Results: President Anura Dissanayake's National People's Power Party Wins Parliamentary Majority]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake's leftist coalition won a landslide victory in snap legislative elections, results showed Friday, as voters repudiated establishment parties blamed for triggering an economic crisis.</p>

<p>Dissanayake, a self-avowed Marxist, swept September presidential elections on a promise to combat graft and recover stolen assets, two years after a slow-motion financial crash imposed widespread hardships on the island nation.</p>

<p>His decision to immediately call polls and secure parliamentary backing for his agenda was vindicated on Friday, with his National People's Power (NPP) coalition taking at least 123 seats in the 225-member assembly and on track to win many more.</p>

<p>The coalition had a monumental 62 percent of the vote among the more than three-quarters of ballots counted so far, while opposition leader Sajith Premadasa's party was well behind with only 18 percent.</p>

<p>"People voted to get rid of corruption and a corrupt system," IT professional Chanaka Rajapaksha, who supported the NPP in the polls, told AFP on Friday.</p>

<p>In a sign of the magnitude of support for Dissanayake, his party won the most votes in the northern district of Jaffna, dominated by the island's minority Tamil community, for the first time since independence from Britain in 1948.</p>

<p>Dissanayake, the 55-year-old son of a labourer, said he expected "a strong majority" in parliament to press ahead with his platform after casting his ballot in Thursday's poll.</p>

<p>"We believe that this is a crucial election that will mark a turning point in Sri Lanka," he said. "At this election, the NPP expects a mandate for a very strong majority in parliament."</p>

<p>Police said the nine-hour voting period passed without any incidents of violence, unlike most ballots of recent years, but three election workers including a police constable died due to illness while on duty.</p>

<p>Voter turnout was estimated at under 70 percent, less than in September presidential polls that saw nearly 80 percent of Sri Lanka's eligible voters cast a ballot.</p>

<p>Dissanayake had been an MP for nearly 25 years and was briefly an agriculture minister but his NPP coalition held just three seats in the outgoing assembly.</p>

<p>He stormed to the presidency after successfully distancing himself from establishment politicians blamed for steering the country to its 2022 economic crisis.</p>

<p>The financial crash was the worst in Buddhist-majority Sri Lanka's history as an independent nation, sparking months-long shortages of food, fuel and essential medicines.</p>

<p>The resulting public anger culminated in the storming of then-president Gotabaya Rajapaksa's compound, prompting his resignation and temporary exile.</p>

<p>Dissanayake's pledge to change a "corrupt" political culture has resonated with millions of Sri Lankans struggling to make ends meet following tax hikes and other austerity measures imposed to repair the nation's finances.</p>

<p>His JVP party, the main constituent in the NPP coalition, led two insurrections in 1971 and 1987 that resulted in at least 80,000 deaths.</p>

<p>But he was sworn in after September's presidential polls, described as one of the island nation's most peaceful elections.</p>

<p>'Investor confidence'</p>

<p>Portraits of communist luminaries including Karl Marx, Vladimir Lenin, Friedrich Engels and Fidel Castro hang in Dissanayake's office in the capital.</p>

<p>Since his rise to popularity, however, he has softened some policies, saying he believes in an open economy and is not totally opposed to privatisation.</p>

<p>Dissanayake had campaigned on a pledge to renegotiate a controversial $2.9 billion International Monetary Fund (IMF) bailout secured by his predecessor.</p>

<p>But since taking office, he has resolved to maintain the existing agreement with the international lender.</p>

<p>The country's main private sector lobby, the Ceylon Chamber of Commerce, is tacitly supporting Dissanayake and his programme.</p>

<p>Sri Lanka's stock exchange has gained over 16 percent in the eight weeks since Dissanayake won the presidency.</p>

<p>'Opposition is dead'</p>

<p>Poll monitors and analysts said Thursday's election had failed to generate the level of enthusiasm -- or violence -- seen at previous polls.</p>

<p>"The opposition is dead," political analyst Kusal Perera said before the vote. "The result of the election is a foregone conclusion."</p>

<p>The outgoing parliament was dominated by Mahinda and Gotabaya Rajapaksa, two brothers from a powerful political clan who have both served as president, but it has since splintered.</p>

<p>Neither Rajapaksa is contesting, but Mahinda's son Namal, a former sports minister, is seeking re-election.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/39g29e2g_sri-lankan-president-anura-kumara-dissanayake_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sri Lankan President Anura Kumara Dissanayake]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-orders-mass-production-of-attack-drones-7023758]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korean Leader Orders 'Mass Production' Of Attack Drones]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-orders-mass-production-of-attack-drones-7023758]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 10:33:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has ordered the "mass production" of attack drones, as concerns mount over the country's deepening military cooperation with Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un has ordered the "mass production" of attack drones, state media reported Friday, as concerns mount over the country's deepening military cooperation with Russia.</p>

<p>Pyongyang first unveiled its attack drones in August, with experts saying the capability may be attributable to the country's budding alliance with Russia.</p>

<p>The nuclear-armed country has ratified a landmark defence pact with Moscow and is accused of deploying thousands of troops to Russia to support its war in Ukraine, prompting South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol to warn about the potential transfer of sensitive Russian military technology to North Korea.</p>

<p>Kim on Thursday oversaw the tests of drones designed to hit both land and sea targets, produced by North Korea's Unmanned Aerial Technology Complex, the Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) said.</p>

<p>"He underscored the need to build a serial production system as early as possible and go into full-scale mass production," KCNA said.</p>

<p>The unmanned drones are designed to carry explosives and be deliberately crashed into enemy targets, effectively acting as guided missiles.</p>

<p>Thursday's test saw the drones "precisely" hit targets after flying along predetermined paths, KCNA reported.</p>

<p>"The suicide attack drones to be used within different striking ranges are to perform a mission to precisely attack any enemy targets on the ground and in the sea," the agency said.</p>

<p>Kim said the drones were an "easy to use... component of striking power" due to their relatively low production cost and expansive range of applications, according to KCNA.</p>

<p>He said the North had "recently attached importance" to developing unmanned hardware systems and to integrating them with the country's overall military strategy.</p>

<p><strong>Russian tech?</strong></p>

<p>Experts said the drones -- in images released by state media in August -- looked similar to the Israeli-made "HAROP" drone, Russian-made "Lancet-3" and Israeli "HERO 30".</p>

<p>North Korea may have acquired these technologies from Russia, which in turn likely obtained them from Iran -- with Tehran itself suspected of accessing them through hacking or theft from Israel.</p>

<p>In 2022, Pyongyang sent drones across the border that Seoul's military was unable to shoot down, saying they were too small.</p>

<p>This year, North Korea has been bombarding the South with trash-carrying balloons, in what it calls retaliation for activists in the South floating anti-regime propaganda missives northwards.</p>

<p>The North has also accused Seoul of violating its sovereignty by flying drones over its capital Pyongyang to drop propaganda leaflets.</p>

<p>By mentioning the "production and practical deployment of various drones", North Korea may be hinting it could follow suit, Yang Moo-jin, president of the University of North Korean Studies in Seoul, told AFP.</p>

<p>Pyongyang could be "suggesting the possibility of using balloons to disseminate leaflets to the South with such drones," Yang said.</p>

<p>"Considering the effectiveness of drone attacks observed in the war in Ukraine, they could also be effectively utilised in the ongoing conflict there," he added.</p>

<p>South Korea launched a drone operation command last year to better address the growing threat.</p>

<p>In October, the North amended its constitution to define South Korea as a "hostile" state, an illustration of a sharp deterioration in ties since Kim in January declared Seoul his country's "principal enemy".</p>

<p>The North has continued to carry out UN sanctions-defying ballistic missile tests, and last month blew up its roads and railways linking it to the South.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jtqvm0b_north-korea-attack-drones_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/robert-f-kennedy-jr-anti-vaccine-activist-who-is-now-us-health-secretary-7023554]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Robert F Kennedy Jr, Anti-Vaccine Activist Who Is Now US Health Secretary]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/robert-f-kennedy-jr-anti-vaccine-activist-who-is-now-us-health-secretary-7023554]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:56:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump has appointed Robert F Kennedy Jr, an environmental advocate and vaccine sceptic, to lead the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President-elect Donald Trump has appointed Robert F Kennedy Jr, an environmental advocate and vaccine sceptic, to lead the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). Mr Kennedy, who dropped his independent presidential campaign in August and endorsed Trump, has expressed his commitment to prioritising the fight against chronic diseases. His stance on vaccines, however, sets him apart from previous HHS leaders. Mr Kennedy has frequently challenged vaccine mandates.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Kennedy will restore these agencies to the traditions of gold standard scientific research, and beacons of transparency, to end the chronic disease epidemic, and to Make America Great and Healthy Again!" <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-tracker-robert-f-kennedy-jr-anti-vaccine-activist-named-head-to-us-health-department-7022811 ">Trump said</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Who is Robert F Kennedy Jr?</strong></p>

<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr. was born on January 17, 1954, in Washington, D.C. He is the third of eleven children of former US Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy and Ethel Skakel Kennedy, and the nephew of former President John F. Kennedy. Both his father and uncle were assassinated in the 1960s.</p>

<p>He studied at Harvard University, attended the London School of Economics, and earned a law degree from the University of Virginia. Later, he completed a Master's Degree in Environmental Law from Pace University School of Law, where he co-founded the Environmental Litigation Clinic and served on the faculty for over 30 years.</p>

<p>In the 1980s, Mr Kennedy founded the Waterkeeper Alliance, an organisation focused on clean water advocacy, where he worked as chairman and attorney. His work to restore New York's Hudson River earned him the title "Hero for the Planet" from TIME Magazine and helped create over 300 similar Waterkeeper groups worldwide. He also played a key role in the New York City watershed agreement, now viewed as a global example of sustainable development.</p>

<p>Mr Kennedy founded Children's Health Defense to address their health issues and harmful exposures, serving as chairman and lead counsel. While claiming to support vaccine safety, he has also been found spreading false theories, such as vaccines causing autism and COVID-19 being targeted at specific ethnic groups. Before the COVID-19 pandemic, Mr Kennedy was already leading campaigns against vaccines and collaborating with anti-vaccine groups. His organisation has also filed lawsuits against news outlets, accusing them of bias against anti-vaccine views. Studies show his Twitter account was a major source of vaccine misinformation. Mr Kennedy has also met with anti-vaccine activists and supported anti-vaccine literature, despite evidence that vaccines are safe and necessary for public health.</p>

<p>Some of Mr Kennedy's legal wins include cases against Monsanto in 2018 and DuPont in 2019 for contamination, which inspired the movie Dark Waters. He has also advocated for Indigenous groups in North and South America.</p>

<p>Mr Kennedy has authored several books, including bestsellers Crimes Against Nature (2005) and The Real Anthony Fauci (2021). He has also written children's books on American history and Saint Francis of Assisi.</p>

<p>Robert F Kennedy Jr is married to actress Cheryl Hines and has seven children from three marriages.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d2ml1er_robert-f-kennedy-jr-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eva-longoria-reveals-moving-her-family-out-of-us-after-kamala-harris-defeat-7023545]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Eva Longoria Reveals Moving Her Family Out Of US After Kamala Harris' Defeat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eva-longoria-reveals-moving-her-family-out-of-us-after-kamala-harris-defeat-7023545]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:53:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Actor Eva Longoria, who endorsed Kamala Harris in the election, revealed that her family no longer lives in the United States, and is splitting time between Mexico and Spain.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Actor Eva Longoria, who endorsed Kamala Harris in the election, revealed that her family no longer lives in the United States, and is splitting time between Mexico and Spain.</p>

<p>"I had my whole adult life here," Longoria told Marie Claire of the US, as per The Hollywood Reporter.</p>

<p>"But even before [the pandemic], it was changing. The vibe was different. And then COVID happened, and it pushed it over the edge. Whether it's the homelessness or the taxes, not that I want to shit on California -- it just feels like this chapter in my life is done now."</p>

<p>The 'Desperate Housewives' actress mentioned the election as one reason for the finality of her conviction.</p>

<p>"The shocking part is not that he won...It's that a convicted criminal who spews so much hate could hold the highest office. If he keeps his promises, it's going to be a scary place," she said.</p>

<p>Longoria went on to acknowledge that she is "privileged" to be able to make the decision to move away. "I get to escape and go somewhere," she said. "Most Americans aren't so lucky. They're going to be stuck in this dystopian country, and my anxiety and sadness is for them."</p>

<p>Eva Longoria, 49, currently lives with her husband, Jose Baston, and their son, 6-year-old Santiago, in Mexico and Spain. She often ends up elsewhere in Europe and South America for work but doesn't frequently return to Los Angeles, according to The Hollywood Reporter.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Tuesday, Trump announced several key apppointments, including former Congresswoman and Governor from South Dakota, Kristi Noem, as the Secretary of the US Department of Homeland Security, Elon Musk, CEO of Tesla, SpaceX, and 'X' along with Indian-origin Vivek Ramaswamy to lead the new Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE), Pete Hegseth as the Secretary of Defense, William Joseph McGinley as White House Counsel, among others.</p>

<p>In a historic political comeback, Trump won a second term as President of the United States after securing 295 electoral votes in the 2024 presidential election, defeating Democratic rival, Kamala Harris, who garnered 226 votes.</p>

<p>Trump's return to the White House marks only the second time in US history that a president has served two non-consecutive terms. The first such instance was Grover Cleveland, who served as president in 1884 and 1892. Trump had earlier served as US President from 2016 to 2020.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/eva-longoria_650x400_61469779578.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Actor Eva Longoria revealed that her family no longer lives in the United States.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-chooses-anti-vaccine-activist-rfk-jr-to-head-health-department-7023541]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Chooses Anti-Vaccine Activist RFK Jr. Fpr Health Department]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-chooses-anti-vaccine-activist-rfk-jr-to-head-health-department-7023541]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:51:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Thursday tapped anti-vaccine activist and conspiracy theorist Robert F. Kennedy Jr. as his secretary of health in the latest provocative nomination from the incoming Republican president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Thursday tapped anti-vaccine activist and conspiracy theorist Robert F. Kennedy Jr. as his secretary of health in the latest provocative nomination from the incoming Republican president.</p>

<p>"We want you to come up with things and ideas and what you've been talking about for a long time and I think you're going to do some unbelievable things," Trump told Kennedy Jr. during an event at his Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida on Thursday evening.</p>

<p>Moving quickly since his election last week, Trump has embarked on a campaign of political shock and awe as he rolls out an administration designed to upend -- and in some cases literally dismantle -- the US government.</p>

<p>Several of Trump's choices for top jobs -- including a TV news anchor at the helm of the Pentagon and an ally embroiled in sexual misconduct allegations for attorney general -- have unnerved the Washington establishment.</p>

<p>Trump also announced Thursday that his personal attorneys Todd Blanche and Emil Bove, who defended him at trial this year over hush money payments to porn star Stormy Daniels, would serve as deputy attorneys general.</p>

<p>Kennedy, a scion of the famous political family who is popularly known as RFK Jr., is a longtime environmental campaigner who abandoned a fringe bid for the presidency to endorse Trump against Democratic candidate Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Trump had said previously he wanted Kennedy to "go wild" in changing health care and the two campaigned together promising to "Make America Healthy Again."</p>

<p><strong>Vaccine scepticism</strong></p>

<p>If approved by the Senate, which Trump's Republican Party controls, 70-year-old Kennedy will take over the Health and Human Services Department, a mammoth institution with a budget of close to $2 trillion.</p>

<p>In a statement explaining his choice, Trump echoed many of Kennedy's talking points, saying "Americans have been crushed by the industrial food complex and drug companies who have engaged in deception, misinformation, and disinformation."</p>

<p>The nomination could meet opposition, given Kennedy's history of promoting medical conspiracy theories -- including the disproven claim that childhood vaccines cause autism -- and saying that the Covid-19 vaccine was deadly.</p>

<p>He is also burdened by a string of colorful and even bizarre stories from his personal life.</p>

<p>These include his statement that a parasitic worm once entered his "brain and ate a portion of it and then died."</p>

<p>An admission this year that he was behind the long unsolved mystery of a dead bear dumped in New York's Central Park a decade ago raised eyebrows.</p>

<p><strong>Energy</strong></p>

<p>Trump has yet to select treasury and commerce chiefs, or an education secretary, whose department he wants to abolish.</p>

<p>During the event in Mar-a-Lago on Thursday evening, he said that wealthy North Dakota Governor Doug Burgum would be appointed secretary of the interior, putting him in charge of national parks which could be opened to more oil exploration.</p>

<p>"We're going to slash energy costs," Trump told the event organized by the America First Policy Institute, where he was introduced by libertarian Argentinian President Javier Milei and Hollywood A-lister Sylvester Stallone.</p>

<p>"Rocky" star Stallone told the audience, which included ever-present Tesla CEO Elon Musk, that Trump was a "mythical character."</p>

<p>Trump joked that he couldn't get Musk out of his Mar-a-Lago resort.</p>

<p>"He likes this place, I can't get him out of here," he said. "I like having him here as well. He's done a fantastic job, an incredible mind."</p>

<p>Trump's first recruitments -- including secretary of state pick Marco Rubio, a traditional conservative on foreign policy -- were seen as relatively mainstream choices.</p>

<p>But then he caused concern even among some in the Republican Party as he appeared to put preference for personal loyalty above expertise or suitability.</p>

<p><strong>Personal lawyers</strong></p>

<p>A major shock was naming Matt Gaetz -- a firebrand Republican far-right figure in Congress who was drawn into a years-long criminal probe into sex trafficking -- as future attorney general.</p>

<p>Gaetz denies wrongdoing and has never faced charges but was still being investigated by the House Ethics Committee.</p>

<p>That decision followed Trump's nomination of former Democratic congresswoman Tulsi Gabbard -- who met Syria's president Bashar al-Assad and echoes Russian President Vladimir Putin's talking points -- to take charge of the nation's most sensitive secrets as director of national intelligence.</p>

<p>Trump recruited Pete Hegseth -- a combat veteran who has no experience running large organizations but is a host on Trump's favorite Fox News network -- as defense secretary.</p>

<p>Trump and his aides have vowed that much of his second term will be about clearing the deck of federal officials who acted as a restraining influence on his populist, right-wing agenda during his first term.</p>

<p>Gaetz's appointment would hand Trump, whose election likely means being freed from a string of serious criminal investigations, the advantage of a fierce partisan at the top of the Justice Department.</p>

<p>He intends to place a third personal attorney at the department by nominating John Sauer as solicitor general, which represents the US government at the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly threatened to go after a variety of political opponents.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/oi2oa188_robert-f-kennedy-jr_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump and RFK Jr campaigned together promising to "Make America Healthy Again."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-worried-as-lifesaving-malaria-drug-in-africa-proving-less-effective-7023510]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Worried As Lifesaving Malaria Drug In Africa Proving Less Effective]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-worried-as-lifesaving-malaria-drug-in-africa-proving-less-effective-7023510]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:50:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Malaria is caused by a parasite called Plasmodium falciparum, which spreads through the bite of a mosquito.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists have warned that the fight against malaria in Africa may have got tougher after a new study found that a lifesaving drug was becoming less effective among children with serious infections. The study published in the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2826317" rel="noindex, nofollow"> <em>Journal of the American Medical Association</em></a> (JAMA) stated that children had developed resistance to artemisinin - a key malaria drug that rapidly eliminates most malaria parasites in the body. Artemisinin resistance was first identified in southeast Asia in the 2000s but it is the first time it has been identified specifically in children with severe malaria in Africa.</p>

<p>Malaria is caused by a parasite called Plasmodium falciparum, which spreads through the bite of a mosquito. The World Health Organization's (WHO) 'gold standard' treatment involves the use of a course of pills containing an artemisinin derivative combined with a 'partner' drug that circulates in the body for longer and kills the remaining parasites. These regimens are called artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs).</p>

<h3><strong>Study methodology</strong></h3>

<p>The study was conducted in Uganda, involving 100 children hospitalised with severe malaria. The test findings showed that 11 of these children had developed partial resistance to artemisinin -- meaning that the parasites were evolving to evade the 'gold standard' malaria treatment. All the children with resistant malaria carried genetic mutations linked to drug resistance.</p>

<p>"If this is verified by other studies, it could change guidelines for treatment of severe malaria in African children, and they are the biggest target group by far," Chandy John, a specialist in paediatric infectious diseases at Indiana University in Indianapolis and co-author of the study told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://Scientists have warned that the fight against malaria in Africa may have got tougher after a new study found that a lifesaving drug was becoming less effective among children with serious infections. The study published in the Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA) stated that children had developed resistance to artemisinin - a key malaria drug that rapidly eliminates most malaria parasites in the body.  Malaria is caused by a parasite called Plasmodium falciparum, which spreads through the bite of a mosquito. The World Health Organization's (WHO) 'gold standard' treatment involves the use of a course of pills containing an artemisinin derivative combined with a 'partner' drug that circulates in the body for longer and kills the remaining parasites. These regimens are called artemisinin-based combination therapies (ACTs).  Study methodology The study was conducted in Uganda, involving 100 children hospitalised with severe malaria. The test findings showed that 11 of these children had developed partial resistance to artemisinin -- meaning that the parasites were evolving to evade the 'gold standard' malaria treatment. All the children with resistant malaria carried genetic mutations linked to drug resistance.  &quot;If this is verified by other studies, it could change guidelines for treatment of severe malaria in African children, and they are the biggest target group by far,&quot; Chandy John, a specialist in paediatric infectious diseases at Indiana University in Indianapolis and co-author of the study told Nature.  Notably, another group of ten children in the study had a malaria infection that recurred after their treatment concluded.  &quot;What the recurrence suggests to us is that maybe that partner drug is not working as well as it should, because the parasites are coming back,&quot; said John, adding that recurrence might have been caused by resistance to lumefantrine, a partner drug administered orally during ACT.  Also read | Making Mosquitoes Deaf Can Stop Spread Of Dengue, Study Finds  What does it mean? As the resistance spreads, it could make treating malaria harder, especially in a region like Africa which accounted for 95 per cent of the 608,000 malaria-related deaths in 2022.  &quot;The emergence of artemisinin partial resistance in Africa is a major threat to malaria control,&quot; he says. &quot;We are now only starting to understand what's going on,&quot; said Philip Rosenthal, a malaria specialist at the University of California, San Francisco.  &quot;Even if the drug still works, that slower action could make a difference and lead to higher levels of mortality,&quot; he added.  Resistance to artemisinin was first identified in southeast Asia in the 2000s but it is the first time it has been identified specifically in children with severe malaria in Africa." rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Nature</em></a>.</p>

<p>Notably, another group of ten children in the study had a malaria infection that recurred after their treatment concluded.</p>

<p>"What the recurrence suggests to us is that maybe that partner drug is not working as well as it should, because the parasites are coming back," said John, adding that recurrence might have been caused by resistance to lumefantrine, a partner drug administered orally during ACT.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/making-mosquitoes-deaf-can-stop-spread-of-dengue-study-finds-6954115" rel="noindex, nofollow"><strong>Also read | Making Mosquitoes Deaf Can Stop Spread Of Dengue, Study Finds</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What does it mean?</strong></h3>

<p>As the resistance spreads, it could make treating malaria harder, especially in a region like Africa which accounted for 95 per cent of the 608,000 malaria-related deaths in 2022.</p>

<p>"The emergence of artemisinin partial resistance in Africa is a major threat to malaria control," he says. "We are now only starting to understand what's going on," said Philip Rosenthal, a malaria specialist at the University of California, San Francisco.</p>

<p>"Even if the drug still works, that slower action could make a difference and lead to higher levels of mortality," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-11/op90fov8_malaria_625x300_20_November_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As the resistance spreads, it could make treating malaria harder.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/central-america-braces-for-tropical-storm-saras-life-threatening-downpour-7023496]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tropical Storm Sara To Provoke "Life-Threatening" Downpour In Central America]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/central-america-braces-for-tropical-storm-saras-life-threatening-downpour-7023496]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:44:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Central American countries scrambled on Thursday night to make preparations for the impact of Tropical Storm Sara, with Honduras likely to be the first in the storm's path as it slowly churns from the Caribbean.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Central American countries scrambled on Thursday night to make preparations for the impact of Tropical Storm Sara, with Honduras likely to be the first in the storm's path as it slowly churns from the Caribbean.</p>

<p>Sara is moving west toward the northern coast of Honduras at a speed of 10 mph (16 kph), and is expected to weaken over the next few days, according to the U.S. National Hurricane Center (NHC).</p>

<p>The NHC expects Sara to provoke "life-threatening and potentially catastrophic flash flooding and mudslides" across Honduras before moving on to Belize on Sunday. The center forecasts accumulated rainfall of 10-20 inches (25-51 cm) over the next few days, with some areas seeing as much as 30 inches.</p>

<p>Through early next week, the tropical storm is expected to hit El Salvador, eastern Guatemala, western Nicaragua, and the southern Mexican state of Quintana Roo, the Miami-based forecaster added, areas that are home to significant coffee production.</p>

<p>Honduras has issued a "red alert" for its northern region, while other countries activated emergency measures to prepare for potentially catastrophic rainfall.</p>

<p>The storm was located 130 miles (209 km) southeast of the island of Guanaja, just off the Honduran coast, on Thursday night.</p>

<p>The tropical storm could remain "semi-stationary" off Honduras' Caribbean coast through Sunday morning, the country's National Risk Management System warned.</p>

<p>After Honduras, Sara will bear down on Guatemala, where local officials asked residents to secure their homes and prepare emergency supplies in the event of evacuation orders.</p>

<p>In Nicaragua, Vice President Rosario Murillo announced that northern coastal areas will feel the brunt of Sara's impact as it makes its away across the country.</p>

<p></p>

<p>(Reporting by Alvaro Murillo in San Jose, Gustavo Palencia in Tegucigalpa, Sofia Menchu in Guatemala City, Gabriela Selser and Raul Cortes in Mexico City; Writing by Aida Pelaez-Fernandez; Editing by David Alire Garcia and Nicholas Yong)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/2pkpsl6_honduras-tropical-storm-sara-_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sara is moving west toward the northern coast of Honduras.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/barron-trump-donald-trumps-youngest-son-loves-football-6-feet-9-inches-tall-what-you-need-to-know-about-barron-trump-7019953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Loves Football, 6 Feet 9 Inches Tall: What You Need To Know About Barron Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/people/barron-trump-donald-trumps-youngest-son-loves-football-6-feet-9-inches-tall-what-you-need-to-know-about-barron-trump-7019953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Nov 2024 07:27:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It was well past midnight on November 5, 2024, the election day in the United States. The results were still coming, but a jubilant Republican crowd in Florida was certain of Donald Trump's return to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was well past midnight on November 5, 2024, the election day in the United States. The results were still coming, but a jubilant Republican crowd in Florida was certain of Donald Trump's return to the White House. They gave him and his entire entourage a hero's welcome. Among those on stage were his wife, Melania, and his youngest son, Barron Trump, who remained anonymous for much of his father's campaign trail.</p>

<p>Standing well over 6 feet and 9 inches tall, Barron, an imposing figure, flashed a smile at the sea of supporters. While Barron's four older half-siblings — Donald Trump Jr, Ivanka Trump, Eric Trump and Tiffany Trump —&nbsp; have all taken on roles as political advisors and business figures, he remained more of a backroom guy.</p>

<p>Barron has reportedly been advising Trump on connecting with the Gen Z voters who are crucial to modern political campaigns. The President-elect credited his youngest son for persuading him to appear on Joe Rogan's podcast, a major success nearing 50 million views.</p>

<p>The election was special for the 18-year-old, who also cast his first vote this year. Photographed at the voting booth, he proudly supported his father in the presidential race.</p>

<p>Let's take a closer look at this young man and his journey so far.</p>

<p><strong>Early life</strong></p>

<p>Born on March 20, 2006, Barron Trump is the only child of Donald and Melania. Trump named him Barron, a name he always liked but never had the opportunity to use for his other sons, reported People.</p>

<p>His early years were spent mostly away from the spotlight, which followed the lives of his older siblings and parents.</p>

<p>During Donald Trump's presidential campaign in 2016, Barron, though young, became a subject of public curiosity. When his father won the presidency and moved into the White House, Barron stayed behind in New York City for several months to finish the school year. This move was initially seen as an attempt to give Barron some semblance of a normal childhood, despite his father's sudden and meteoric rise to the highest office in the United States.</p>

<p><strong>Schooling and education</strong></p>

<p>Barron Trump has attended a series of prestigious schools. During his early years in New York City, he was enrolled at the Columbia Grammar and Preparatory School on Manhattan's Upper West Side. In May 2017, it was announced that Barron would move to St. Andrew's Episcopal School in Potomac, Maryland. Unlike every other presidential child over the past 35 years, who attended Sidwell Friends, Barron made history as the first to attend St. Andrew's. In a statement, Melania Trump expressed her admiration for the school's “diverse community and commitment to academic excellence.”</p>

<p>In 2024, Barron Trump began his freshman year at New York University's prestigious Stern School of Business, a departure from the tradition set by his older siblings and father. Unlike Donald Trump and Barron's siblings — Donald Trump Jr, Ivanka Trump, Eric Trump and Tiffany Trump — who attended or graduated from institutions such as the University of Pennsylvania and Georgetown University, with strong connections to the family, Barron charted his path.</p>

<p><strong>Moving to the White House</strong></p>

<p>When Trump first won the presidency, he said that Barron was initially nervous about the move from New York City to the White House. At the time, Barron was just nine years old and strongly attached to his life in New York, school and friends. The prospect of leaving everything behind for a new chapter in Washington D.C. was a significant change for the young boy.</p>

<p>“He does love New York and he loves his school. Not so much living in the White House. He does like what he's got right now. That would be a whole change of life. But when he hears I'm going to help people that solves the problem,” Trump told People magazine.</p>

<p>Finally, at 11, Barron moved into the White House, where he lived with his parents until 2019. That year, the Trump family permanently relocated to Mar-a-Lago, Donald Trump's private club in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>

<p><strong>Barron Trump's hobbies</strong></p>

<p>Despite keeping a low profile, Barron's interests and activities have occasionally come to the media's notice. He is known for his love for sports, something his mother Melania confirmed in 2018. One of the sports he enjoys is football, but his father, Donald Trump, has expressed some reservations about the dangers in the game. He has also been involved in other activities such as golf and basketball, reflecting a well-rounded personality with a strong interest in athletics.</p>

<p><strong>Command of English and Slovenian</strong></p>

<p>Barron Trump is bilingual and can speak English and Slovenian, the native language of his mother. As a child, Barron would often call his grandmother and speak with her solely in Slovenian, Melania told People magazine. When it comes to the language Barron should use in public, she and her husband, Donald Trump, are in agreement. English remains his primary language.</p>

<p><strong>The tallest Trump</strong></p>

<p>Barron Trump's height is something you just cannot ignore. Standing at a reported 6 feet 9 inches, he is the tallest member of the Trump family. This towering figure surpasses his father, Donald Trump, who is 6 feet 3 inches tall. Compared to his half-brothers, Barron stands out. Donald Trump Jr. is 6 feet 1 inch and Eric Trump is 6 feet 5 inches.</p>

<p>While Google lists Barron's height as 6 feet 9 inches, Donald Trump mentioned in a January 2024 speech that Barron is “already 6 feet 7 inches” — still a remarkable height, regardless of the exact measurement. Donald jokingly attributed his son's height to the home-cooked meals prepared by Melania's late mother, Amalija Knavs.</p>

<p>Barron's height often draws attention, especially during public appearances.</p>

<p>After Trump's victory in elections, his campaign's senior adviser Jason Miller said Barron was involved in recommending several podcasts his father must do ahead of the November 5 voting. “Hats off to the young man. Every single recommendation he's had has broken the internet,” Miller told Politico's Playbook Deep Dive podcast.</p>

<p>With Donald Trump already making important appointments to his cabinet ahead of the January 20th inauguration for his second term, many wonder if the 18-year-old will be more actively involved in the next four years.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/n4hahr48_barron-trump-afp_625x300_15_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barron Trump's height often draws attention, especially during public appearances.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>