<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 15:53:03 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/middle-east-on-verge-of-full-scale-war-russian-president-vladimir-putin-6862839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Middle East On Verge Of Full-Scale War": Russian President Vladimir Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/middle-east-on-verge-of-full-scale-war-russian-president-vladimir-putin-6862839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 15:03:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Violence in the Middle East will not end until the creation of an independent Palestinian state, Russian President Vladimir Putin said at the BRICS summit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin told a BRICS summit on Thursday that the Middle East was on the verge of full-scale war.</p>

<p>"The military action that started a year ago in Gaza has now spread to Lebanon. Other countries in the region are also affected," Putin told a meeting in Kazan attended by several world leaders.</p>

<p>"The level of confrontation between Israel and Iran has sharply risen. This is all reminiscent of a chain reaction and puts the whole Middle East on the verge of full-scale war," Putin said.</p>

<p>Violence in the Middle East will not end until the creation of an independent Palestinian state, Putin said at the summit, attended by Palestinian leader Mahmoud Abbas.</p>

<p>"The key demand for restoring peace and stability on Palestinian territories is carrying out the two-state formula approved by the UN Security Council and General Assembly," the Russian president said.</p>

<p>He added that this would be "correcting the historical injustice towards the Palestinian people".</p>

<p>"Until this question is resolved, it will not be possible to break the vicious circle of violence."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dcvjqtfg_vladimir-putin_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-model-claims-donald-trump-groped-her-describes-twisted-game-linked-to-jeffrey-epstein-6861737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Felt Like A Piece Of Meat": Former Model Claims Donald Trump Groped Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/former-model-claims-donald-trump-groped-her-describes-twisted-game-linked-to-jeffrey-epstein-6861737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:52:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former model has accused Donald Trump of groping and sexually touching her when they first interacted in 1993.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former model has accused Donald Trump of groping and sexually touching her when they first interacted in 1993. Stacey Williams alleged that the incident was part of a "twisted game" involving Trump and sexual abuser Jeffrey Epstein, who introduced her to the former president.</p>

<p>Ms Williams, who began her modelling career in the 1990s, met Trump at a Christmas party in 1992 through Epstein, whom she described as a close friend of Trump. “It became very clear then that he and Donald were really, really good friends and spent a lot of time together,” she told <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/23/donald-trump-accuser-stacey-williams-jeffrey-epstein" rel="nofollow,noindex">The Guardian</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Epstein was later convicted with multiple allegations of sex trafficking and abuse of minors. He killed himself in prison in 2019.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The alleged groping occurred months later when Jeffrey Epstein suggested they visit Trump at his Manhattan residence. Upon arrival, Ms Williams claims Trump greeted her before pulling her closer and putting his hands all over her “breasts”, as well as her waist and buttocks. She claims to have frozen up and recalls being “confused” about what was happening. She remembers having seen the two men secretly smiling at each other after the incident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Following the incident, Ms Williams and Epstein left Trump Tower, where she claims Epstein was "raging" at her. “Jeffrey and I left and he didn't look at me or speak to me, and I felt this seething rage around me,” she recounted. Epstein reportedly asked her, “Why did you let him do that?” Ms Williams described feeling “disgusting” and “confused” after the encounter.</p>

<p>“I felt shame and disgust and as we went our separate ways, I felt this sensation of revisiting it, while the hands were all over me. And I had this horrible pit in my stomach that it was somehow orchestrated. I felt like a piece of meat,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Stacey Williams, now 56 and living in Pennsylvania, had previously shared snippets of her experience on social media but disclosed further details during a Zoom call organised by ‘Survivors for Kamala', a group supporting Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris. The call featured notable speakers, including actress Ashley Judd and legal scholar Anita Hill.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Donald Trump's campaign responded to Ms Williams' allegations through press secretary Karoline Leavitt, calling the accusations “unequivocally false” and suggesting they were politically motivated. “It's obvious this fake story was contrived by the Harris campaign,” she claimed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Williams, in an interview with The Guardian, shared a postcard from Trump sent to her agent later in 1993. It had an aerial view of Mar-a-Lago with the message, “Stacey – Your home away from home. Love Donald.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>The accusations against Trump add to a growing list of women who have alleged sexual misconduct by the former president, including instances of unwanted touching and harassment. A jury previously found Trump liable for sexual abuse in a case involving columnist E. Jean Carroll, awarding her $5 million.</p>

<p>Ms Williams explained, “I watched what has happened to women who come out, and it is so horrifying and abusive.”</p>

<p>Ms Williams confided in friends about the incident years ago. One of her friends recalled that she had shared the details of the groping in 2005 or 2006. “What I recall is that it was groping … what we would call feeling someone up,” the friend said.</p>

<p>Another friend recalled a conversation in 2015, shortly after Trump announced his presidential candidacy, where Ms Williams said, “He's vile, he groped me in Trump Tower.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f41du9is_donald-trump-afp_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Stacey Williams alleged it was part of a "twisted game" involving Trump and Jeffrey Epstein]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-calls-for-urgent-reforms-to-un-security-council-at-brics-6862716]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar Pushes For India Seat At UN Body, Replugs PM's No War Message]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-calls-for-urgent-reforms-to-un-security-council-at-brics-6862716]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:44:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pushing for a permanent seat for India at the United Nations Security Council, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar today said established institutions must be reformed to create a more equitable global order.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pushing for a permanent seat for India at the United Nations Security Council, External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar today said established institutions must be reformed to create a more equitable global order. He also reiterated Prime Minister Narendra Modi's message that this is not an era of war and global disputes must be resolved through dialogue and diplomacy.</p>

<p>Speaking at the 16th BRICS Summit in Russia's Kazan, Dr Jaishankar said, "BRICS is a statement of how profoundly the old order is changing. At the same time, many inequities of the past also continue. In fact, they have assumed new forms and manifestations. We see that in the access to developmental resources and modern technology and efficiencies. Let us also recognise that the benefits of globalisation have been very uneven. Adding to all that, the Covid pandemic and multiple conflicts have aggravated the burdens borne by the Global South. Concerns of health, food and fuel security are particularly acute."</p>

<p>The minister said the world is in danger of falling significantly behind in realising targets of sustainable development goals. "How do we create a more equitable global order? First, by strengthening and expanding platforms of an independent nature, and by widening the choices in different domains and minimising undue reliance on those that can be leveraged. This is really where BRICS can make a difference for the Global South," he said.</p>

<p>"Second, by reforming established institutions and mechanisms, especially the UN Security Council, in the permanent and the non-permanent categories. So too the multilateral development banks, whose working procedures are just as outdated as that of the UN," he added. India, Dr Jaishankar said, initiated an effort in this direction during its G20 Presidency and is glad to see Brazil take it forward.</p>

<p>A permanent seat at the UN Security Council has been India's longstanding demand. This demand is backed by major world powers, including the US, UK and France. Currently, China, France, Russia, the UK and the US are permanent members of the UN Security Council.</p>

<p>"Third, by democratising the global economy through creating more production hubs. The Covid experience is a sharp reminder of the need for more resilient and shorter supply chains. For essential needs, every region legitimately aspires to create their own production capabilities. Fourth, by correcting distortions in global infrastructure that are a legacy from the colonial era. The world urgently needs more connectivity options that enhance logistics and mitigate risks. This must be a collective endeavour for the common good, with the utmost respect for territorial integrity and sovereignty. And fifth, by sharing experiences and new initiatives. India's Digital Public Infrastructure, its Unified Payment Interface, the Gatishakti infrastructure all hold a larger relevance," he said.</p>

<p>The minister added that the International Solar Alliance, the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, the Global Biofuel Alliance, Mission LiFE and the International Big Cat Alliance are initiatives of common interest. "As a First Responder, be it for natural calamities, health emergencies or economic crises, we seek to do our fair share."</p>

<p>Referring to the war in West Asia and Ukraine, Dr Jaishankar said addressing conflicts effectively is a particular need of the day. "Prime Minister Modi has emphasised that this is not an era of war. Disputes and differences must be settled by dialogue and diplomacy. Agreements, once reached, must be scrupulously respected. International law should be adhered to, without exception. And there should be zero tolerance for terrorism," he said.</p>

<p>"The situation in the Middle East, West Asia for us, is an understandable concern. There is a widespread anxiety that the conflict would spread further in the region. Maritime trade has also been deeply affected. The human and material consequences of further escalation are truly serious. Any approach has to be fair and durable, leading to a two state solution," the minister said, reiterating India's long-held stand on the Palestine issue.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7uisai7o_s-jaishankar-pti_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister Dr S Jaishankar addressed the BRICS Summit today]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-tesla-promises-paid-robotaxis-next-year-6862582]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Tesla Promises Paid Robotaxis Next Year]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-tesla-promises-paid-robotaxis-next-year-6862582]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:27:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk on Wednesday said the electric vehicle maker will roll out driverless ride-hailing services to the public in California and Texas next year, a claim likely to face significant regulatory and technical challenges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk on Wednesday said the electric vehicle maker will roll out driverless ride-hailing services to the public in California and Texas next year, a claim likely to face significant regulatory and technical challenges.</p>

<p>"We think that we'll be able to have driverless Teslas doing paid rides next year," Musk said on Tesla's quarterly earnings call. He said Tesla currently offers an app-based ride-hailing service to employees in the San Francisco Bay Area.</p>

<p>His statement doubled down and expanded on a pledge he made at Tesla's robotaxi unveiling two weeks ago, where he said he expected to roll out "unsupervised" self-driving in certain Tesla vehicles in 2025. The lack of a business plan around the robotaxi at that event sent its stock plunging.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, however, Tesla won back some investor confidence by forecasting a jump in vehicle sales next year.</p>

<p>In California, in particular, the company will face an uphill climb in securing the needed permits to offer fully autonomous rides to paying customers.</p>

<p>Alphabet's Waymo, which offers paid rides in autonomous vehicles in the Bay Area and Los Angeles, as well as in Phoenix, Arizona, spent years logging millions of miles of testing before it received its first permit from the California Public Utilities Commission (CPUC), which regulates ride-hailing services.</p>

<p>The California Department of Motor Vehicles, which regulates testing and deployment of autonomous vehicles in the state, told Reuters that Tesla last reported using its autonomous vehicle testing permit in 2019. That permit requires a safety driver.</p>

<p>The company does not have, and has not applied for, a testing permit without a driver, the agency said.</p>

<p>Tesla did not respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>As for the ride-hailing service in the Bay Area for employees, CPUC said Tesla does not need a permit, because employees are not considered passengers.</p>

<p>At Tesla's robotaxi event on Oct 10, Musk unveiled a two-seater, two-door "Cybercab" without a steering wheel and pedals that would use cameras and artificial intelligence to navigate roads.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, he acknowledged the potential difficulties in California, saying "it's not something we totally control," but adding "I would be shocked if we don't get approval next year."</p>

<p>Ross Gerber, a Tesla shareholder and CEO of Gerber Kawasaki Wealth and Investment Management, said "dealing with regulators is a very difficult process" and that no one should consider it "a walk in the park."</p>

<p>Texas has far fewer regulatory requirements for autonomous vehicles than California, but companies often test for months or years before deploying paid services.</p>

<p>Rules around deployment of autonomous vehicles are largely left to individual states. Musk on the call said there should be a "national approval process for autonomy."</p>

<p>Tesla's advanced driver assistance system, called Full Self-Driving (FSD), which is the bedrock for Tesla's robotaxi ambitions, has faced questions from regulators.</p>

<p>Last week, the U.S. National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) opened an investigation into 2.4 million Tesla vehicles equipped with FSD after four reported collisions, including a 2023 fatal crash.</p>

<p>Still, the idea of Tesla rolling out a robotaxi fleet sent shares of ride-hailing apps Uber and Lyft down 2.3% in post-market trading.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b0kt0l6g_tesla-robotaxi-reuters_625x300_12_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tesla won back some investor confidence by forecasting a jump in vehicle sales next year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-artist-honours-killed-soldiers-by-painting-them-on-walls-6862508]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Artist Honours Killed Soldiers By Painting Them On Walls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-artist-honours-killed-soldiers-by-painting-them-on-walls-6862508]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:17:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Artist Eugene Gladenko has created a dozen murals around Kyiv to commemorate soldiers killed fighting Russian forces.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Liudmyla Bordus lost her son Maksym to the war with Russia, but he is never far away - his likeness emblazoned in vivid colour across her apartment building in Kyiv.</p>

<p>"I can feel him every day, every time I pass him here," she said, stroking the spray-painted image.</p>

<p>"I greet him in the morning and in the evening, always."</p>

<p>The sweeping mural of the 23-year-old former boxer is one of a dozen around the Ukrainian capital created by artist Eugene Gladenko to commemorate troops killed fighting Russian forces.</p>

<p>Moscow's February 2022 invasion galvanised Ukrainians, who have memorialised their fallen in myriad ways. Billboards tower over highways and plaques adorn village schools where soldiers studied.</p>

<p>Gladenko, 31, said he is motivated by love of country and a calling to "create comfort" for Ukrainians who have lost loved ones. Many of his creations are deeply personal, he added, ordered by relatives or friends.</p>

<p>"Every story ... is a story of a hero, an example for their entire district or neighbourhood," said Gladenko, whose own friend was killed in the war.</p>

<p>Bordus acknowledged that the image of Maksym, who was killed in southeastern Ukraine last June when a tank shell struck his trench, is painful.</p>

<p>But she added that it was a potent reminder of the sacrifice made by Ukrainian troops like her son.</p>

<p>"It feels as if an angel is looking at you from above."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1s842ms_ukraine-soldiers_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Many Ukrainian soldiers have been killed fighting Russian forces.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-to-release-tomorrow-as-microsoft-pushes-for-gaming-supremacy-6862489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Call of Duty' To Release Tomorrow As Microsoft Pushes For Gaming Supremacy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/call-of-duty-black-ops-6-to-release-tomorrow-as-microsoft-pushes-for-gaming-supremacy-6862489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:14:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft bought the game's publisher Activision-Blizzard a year ago for $69 billion in the sector's biggest takeover.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft's ambition to become the "Netflix of video games" faces a huge test this week with the release of "Call of Duty: Black Ops 6" on Friday. The US software giant bought the game's publisher Activision-Blizzard a year ago for $69 billion in the sector's biggest takeover.</p>

<p>Activision's prized asset was the "Call of Duty" franchise, one of the world's best-selling games, and Friday's release will be the first in the series to be available from day one on Microsoft's Xbox Game Pass subscription service.</p>

<p>The game will also be available to PlayStation users -- as well as on PC.</p>

<p>Mat Piscatella from analyst firm Circana told AFP it was "the biggest push" anyone had made to bolster a subscription platform.</p>

<p>Video game companies once made their money from selling hard copies of their games to players who were plugged into consoles.</p>

<p>But the industry now gets its profits from in-game sales and subscriptions on a model like Netflix or Disney+.</p>

<p>"How consumers react may result in a dramatic industry shift to -- or away -- from the subscription model," said Piscatella of the "Call of Duty" release.</p>

<h3><strong>'Something for everyone'</strong></h3>

<p>Microsoft is not messing about with its ambitions for Game Pass.</p>

<p>It has a target of 100 million customers by 2030.</p>

<p>But the industry has slowed since the boom-time of the pandemic when much of the world spent time confined to their homes.</p>

<p>As of February this year, Game Pass had around 34 million subscribers.</p>

<p>For Friday's release, Microsoft has rejigged its pricing and only subscribers to the most expensive "Ultimate" tier will get the game as it launches.</p>

<p>Despite the vital importance of the game to Microsoft's business, the makers were keen to promote the strengths of the game itself.</p>

<p>"There's really something for everyone with Black Ops 6," Stephanie Snowden, communications head at Call of Duty Studios, told AFP on the sidelines of a promotional event in London.</p>

<p>Players are plunged into an alternate reality of conspiracy and paranoia during the 1991 Gulf War.</p>

<p>But she insisted the game was not saying anything about contemporary divisions in the United States, or the forthcoming presidential election.</p>

<p>"We consider it like a giant blockbuster moment and entertainment moment of the year," she said. "But we're not sending any kind of political message."</p>

<h3><strong>'Cherry on top'</strong></h3>

<p>The saga has generated more than $30 billion in revenue worldwide in a little over 20 years.</p>

<p>But Brian Comiskey of the Consumer Technology Association, an industry group, said Microsoft got more than just a straightforward gaming title when it bought Activision.</p>

<p>"It's not just a game, it's a community," he told AFP.</p>

<p>The first "Call of Duty" games were pioneers by allowing many players to join the same game online.</p>

<p>Many of those players have grown up together, playing the game with each other no matter where they are in the world.</p>

<p>"Video gaming is a social media platform and Call of Duty has been doing that for a very long time," said Comiskey.</p>

<p>So these older players may well get involved even if the game itself is not so impressive.</p>

<p>"The interest isn't necessarily always the content," he said. "That's just a cherry on top."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ketfm7i_call-of-duty-black-ops-6_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The game will also be available to PlayStation users -- as well as on PC.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/come-2025-and-uk-will-ban-disposable-vapes-to-crack-down-on-teen-use-environmental-harm-6862390]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Ban Disposable Vapes To Crack Down On Teen Use, Environmental Harm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/come-2025-and-uk-will-ban-disposable-vapes-to-crack-down-on-teen-use-environmental-harm-6862390]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:01:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain will ban single-use vapes from next year, a government minister said on Thursday, seeking to crack down on the environmental harm and rising usage levels among children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain will ban single-use vapes from next year, a government minister said on Thursday, seeking to crack down on the environmental harm and rising usage levels among children.</p>

<p>Health authorities have raised concerns about the use of vapes among young adults, with their colourful designs and fruity flavours making them stand out on grocery store shelves. According to a 2024 survey by health charity ASH, about one in five children aged 11-17 said they had tried vaping.</p>

<p>It is illegal to sell nicotine-containing e-cigarettes to anyone under the age of 18 or for adults to buy them on behalf of under-18s.</p>

<p>The plan to ban disposable vapes was initially set out by the previous Conservative government in January but was not implemented before the July election, which was won by the Labour Party.</p>

<p>Labour's culture minister said that the number of children vaping had tripled in the last three years, and that disposable vapes were causing a lot of problems for the environment.</p>

<p>"We have been increasingly concerned," she told Sky News.</p>

<p>"We hope (this) will help to break this cycle where children are getting into the habit of vaping at younger and younger ages."</p>

<p>The government's Department For Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs (Defra) did not immediately respond to a Reuters' request for details on the measure. Media reports said the ban was due to come into force in June.</p>

<p>A separate study by ASH this year said vapes were the most popular aid to quitting among tobacco smokers, with nearly 3 million people in Britain having quit smoking with a vape in the last 5 years.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/46vcvfcg_vape-reuters_625x300_28_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It is illegal to sell nicotine-containing e-cigarettes to anyone under the age of 18.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-and-heat-hit-greeces-chestnut-harvest-set-to-shrink-6862348]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drought And Heat Hit Greece's Chestnut, Harvest Set To Shrink]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drought-and-heat-hit-greeces-chestnut-harvest-set-to-shrink-6862348]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 13:57:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The chestnut harvest in Greece is expected to drop to about 15,000 tonnes in 2024 because of the extreme weather, half the average over the past five years, according to George Nanos, a professor of Pomology at the University of Thessaly.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In Greece, one of the world's largest chestnut producers, farmer Anestis Altinis searches for nuts suitable for harvest. But after months of searing heat and drought, most have not ripened, a familiar problem in his village where output is expected to drop 90%.</p>

<p>"I don't remember this happening before," said Altinis, a third-generation chestnut producer in Kissos village on Mount Pelion in central Greece.</p>

<p>"We have reached almost the end of the harvest season and the chestnuts remain on the trees," he said.</p>

<p>The chestnut harvest in Greece is expected to drop to about 15,000 tonnes in 2024 because of the extreme weather, half the average over the past five years, according to George Nanos, a professor of Pomology at the University of Thessaly.</p>

<p>Greece exports most of its chestnuts to Europe and the Balkans where they are used in confectionery and cooking.</p>

<p>The drop in production comes after Greece's warmest winter and summer on record and is the latest sign of the impact of climate change on crops across southern Europe. Drought conditions in Spain, Portugal and France already bode ill for yields of various crops in those countries.</p>

<p>Chestnut producers in Thessaly, a region accounting for about a quarter of Greece's agricultural output, including chestnuts, say some areas haven't experienced rainfall for 13-months after floods in September 2023 decimated the area.</p>

<p>"This year, the situation is tragic," Nanos said. "We have dead or very damaged trees, with very little production."</p>

<p>Cherry, apple and walnut harvests have also been hit, farmers and scientists said.</p>

<p>That's a bad sign for Greece, where agricultural products account for a fifth of its total exports, and whose economy is still recovering from a decade long debt crisis.</p>

<p>In a recent report, Greece's central bank said it expects crop and fruit prices to rise in the coming years due to climate change. It sees the financial impact of climate change exceeding 1% of economic output annually in the coming years, up from about 0.2%-0.3% on average in the past decade.</p>

<p>For farmer Altinis, picking chestnuts with his grandfather shaped his childhood and paved his future. But the fall in output is driving people away.</p>

<p>He urged authorities to help with irrigation or risk desertification in some areas.</p>

<p>"If they don't produce chestnuts, the villages will shrink, the mountain will be deserted," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/c3in818o_chestnut_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Greece is one of the world's largest chestnut producers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-india-is-very-very-dear-to-worlds-computer-industry-6862332]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["India Is Very, Very Dear To World's Computer Industry": Nvidia CEO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-india-is-very-very-dear-to-worlds-computer-industry-6862332]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 13:55:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India, a country "dear" to the world's computer industry, is set to witness 20 times growth in compute capacities in 2024, and will soon be exporting impactful AI solutions, Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen Huang said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India, a country "dear" to the world's computer industry, is set to witness 20 times growth in compute capacities in 2024, and will soon be exporting impactful AI solutions, Nvidia founder and CEO Jensen Huang said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Speaking at the Nvidia AI Summit 2024 here, Huang emphasised Nvidia's commitment to expanding its ecosystem in India.</p>

<p>"India is very, very dear to the world's computer industry, central to the IT industry, at the centre and core of the IT of just about every single company in the world.</p>

<p>"Nvidia's ecosystem in India is very rich; 2024 will see a a 20 times growth in compute capacities in India," he said.</p>

<p>Huang described the current state of the industry as undergoing a "seismic change" due to AI advancements and suggested that India, which has traditionally been a hub for software exportation, is poised to become a leader in AI exportation in the future.</p>

<p>"India exported software; in the future, India will export AI," he said, pointing towards the country shifting from merely being a back office for software production to becoming a powerhouse in AI development and delivery.</p>

<p>"India has focused on being a back office to produce software, the next generation of it will be of producing and delivering AI. It will be dramatically more impactful," he asserted.</p>

<p>"In the long term, I am hoping that all of us have our own AI co-pilots," he further said.</p>

<p>Addressing concerns about job displacement, Huang asserted that while AI will not eliminate jobs outright, it will fundamentally change how they are performed.</p>

<p>"AI will absolutely not take away a job, but the person who uses AI to do a job better will take away the job," he said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/65oh9s5o_jensen-huang_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-biden-hastened-the-slide-of-pax-americana-6862325]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: America Is No Longer What It Used To Be, Thanks To Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-biden-hastened-the-slide-of-pax-americana-6862325]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 13:51:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The decline of Pax Americana may not have started under Biden, but it certainly accelerated under him.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dar3gjio_biden_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The pinnacle of Joe Biden's presidency was day one in Oval Office, when he confidently declared "America is back". He had said that as America rejoined the Paris climate agreement—an optimistic promise to reclaim global leadership. The lowest point of his Presidency was October 7, 2023, when Hamas launched its brutal attack on Israel. It was a stark reminder that American influence and security assurances, once taken for granted, were no longer what they used to be. It's the journey between those two dates that has come to define the chequered legacy of the 46th President of America.</p>

<p>Biden's credibility has gone up in flames in West Asia and he is in danger of leaving behind a dark legacy that his successor would try to erase from the pages of history. But his failures on other issues have also been shocking.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, let's start with his sunshine moments first.</p>

<h2><strong>A Hero's Welcome In Germany</strong></h2>

<p>Last Friday, Biden tiptoed into Germany, almost unnoticed, to receive the country's highest civilian award for his contribution to trans-Atlantic relations. The world's most powerful leader shuffled along next to German President Frank-Walter Steinmeier; their slow, tentative steps felt as though a ghostly presence was tagging along—a moment straight out of T.S. Eliot's <em>The Waste Land</em>: "Who is the third who always walks beside you?"</p>

<p>Biden's farewell visit to Germany comes with a cloud of unease looming over Europe. The spectre of Donald Trump, their ‘tormentor-in-chief' so to speak, &nbsp;possibly returning to power has made Berlin and Europe jittery. They remember Trump's views on NATO all too well, which had left the European members wondering whether the US was serious about protecting Europe against a potential Russian attack.</p>

<p>The elusive third figure in Eliot's poem could just be Europe's collective dread of a Trump redux. Steinmeier still carries the scars from those years (2016-2020), recalling a time when the US-Europe bond was fraying. "...just a handful of years ago, the distance had grown so wide that we almost lost each other," he reminisced. Thankfully, to Germany and Europe's collective relief, Biden was quick to restore Europe's faith in the trans-Atlantic alliance “literally overnight”, as the German President said.</p>

<p>Surely, Biden's European outreach and climate action were two of the very few successes of his presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Biden, Blinken and Bibi &nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>As Israel continues to pound Lebanon and Gaza, one thing is glaringly obvious: the US influence on Israeli decision-making has been greatly cut down since the October 7 Hamas attacks. Sure, Israel's military might squash terrorist threats for now. But lasting peace? That's unlikely and uncertain. Meanwhile, the US Secretary of State, Antony Blinken, is in West Asia again, but he, like his boss, is taken seriously neither by Benjamin aka ‘Bibi' Netanyahu nor by Arab allies. Biden has lost his credibility in the region as an honest peace broker largely due to his weak handling of Netanyahu and letting daily massacres in the region continue. If war breaks out in West Asia, Biden might just hand Kamala Harris's campaign its own little farewell party.</p>

<p>Trump had at least got Israel to sign the Abraham Accords Peace Agreement between Israel and the United Arab Emirates (UAE), Bahrain and Morocco. These agreements aimed to normalise diplomatic relations, expand economic cooperation, and promote regional peace and stability. What does Biden have to show for? The deal with Saudi Arabia was almost ready to be signed, but the Hamas attacks pushed it back. And so far, Biden hasn't been able to persuade the warring parties to come to a ceasefire agreement in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<h2><strong>Abraham Accords, A Flawed Trump Legacy</strong></h2>

<p>The Abraham Accords had come as a beacon of hope for West Asia. I even remember watching an interview with American-Israeli rabbi Yaakov Israel Herzog, who had parked himself in Saudi Arabia, boldly declaring his plan to open the first Jewish community centre in Riyadh. Saudi rulers just pretended not to notice. Everyone assumed the peace deal with Israel was practically signed, sealed, and delivered. Jews visiting the Kingdom? That was almost possible, and it would have been some achievement.</p>

<p>But here's the thing—the Abraham Accords had overlooked the Palestinian issue. Normalising relations without even mentioning Palestinian self-determination was, in hindsight, unwise. That's a recipe for fragile peace. The real issues—borders, settlements, Jerusalem, refugees—were left out of purview. And let's not forget, the Palestinian leadership wasn't even invited to the table. A peace deal without the main player was myopic, at best.</p>

<p>Granted that Biden inherited a diplomatic mess and an uphill battle. He was supposed to dive into the deep end, fix the flaws in the Accords and put the Palestinian issue back on the agenda. But he didn't. The result was Hamas's deadly October attack. Now, the world has been left calling, once again, for a renewed focus on Palestinian statehood.</p>

<h2><strong>A Host Of Other Failures</strong></h2>

<p>Whoever gets the keys to the White House next will inherit the dilemma of either trying to bring order to West Asia, which could overshadow US priorities in Europe and China, or dealing with all the Biden failings simultaneously. There is no doubt that Biden's legacy in West Asia is in tatters; it carries the baggage of extreme violence, death and destruction. Thousands have died, including women and children, millions have been rendered homeless, and a big number have migrated to safer countries. The Israelis, escaping the war, have been flooding into Cyprus. Many in the region believe it will take generations for the scars to be erased. One wonders whether Biden will ever reflect on his failures once he leaves the White House.</p>

<p>Biden's approach to China has also faced scrutiny. His administration's efforts to establish a coalition of like-minded nations, which included India, have yielded mixed results. The Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF) and the Quad security dialogue have been touted as key initiatives, but their effectiveness remains uncertain. China's growing economic and military influence has significant implications for global governance and regional stability.</p>

<h2><strong>Ukraine: Pumping In Money Without A Goal</strong></h2>

<p>Ukrainians are dreading Donald Trump;'s possible return to power because he has made it clear he would strike a peace deal with Russia. He is also not in favour of the US pumping in billions of dollars and sending plane-loads of weapons to Ukraine. The Ukrainians would thus like Kamala Harris as President, as they believe she will carry on defending Ukraine and continue to help it with cash and weapons.</p>

<p>Under Biden, Pax Americana, the era of America-led global order, has been showing clear signs of decline. From the chaotic withdrawal from Afghanistan to the US's impotency in West Asia, Biden's foreign policy has often been seen as reactive rather than proactive. The cowardly pullout from Kabul in 2021, which left behind chaos and emboldened the Taliban, sent a message that US military power no longer guarantees stability in the regions it occupies. This failure, followed by Washington's inconsistent handling of alliances, signalled a retreat from the role of a ‘global enforcer' that the US has played since World War II.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The China-Russia Question</strong></h2>

<p>Clearly, Biden's response to the rising influence of China and Russia has been less than robust, weakening American hegemony. While efforts like the Quad alliances aim to counterbalance China's assertiveness in the Indo-Pacific, Beijing continues to expand its influence through economic investments, military posturing, and diplomatic and multilateral efforts such as the Belt and Road Initiative and BRICS. Simultaneously, Russia's invasion of Ukraine has drawn attention to the limits of US deterrence.</p>

<p>The decline of Pax Americana may not have started under Biden, but it certainly accelerated under him. Domestically, Biden's presidency has focused on economic recovery, social justice, and climate action. The American Rescue Plan and Inflation Reduction Act have helped stabilise the economy and address social issues to some extent. However, bipartisan cooperation has been more elusive than ever, and many of Biden's initiatives have faced resistance from Congress.</p>

<p>If Donald Trump wins on November 5, Biden's legacy could be swept into the dustbin of history. But if Kamala Harris comes out on top, she will have to work very hard to salvage it—while defining her own legacy.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vcl7dano_biden_625x300_24_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/broken-but-determined-french-mass-rape-victim-tells-court-6862090]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Broken But Determined": French Mass Rape Victim Tells Court]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/broken-but-determined-french-mass-rape-victim-tells-court-6862090]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 13:21:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gisele Pelicot, whose ex-husband and dozens of other men are on trial in France accused of raping her while she was drugged, told the court she was "broken" by her ordeal, but also determined to "change society" for sex assault victims.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gisele Pelicot, whose ex-husband and dozens of other men are on trial in France accused of raping her while she was drugged, told the court Wednesday she was "broken" by her ordeal, but also determined to "change society" for sex assault victims.</p>

<p>The 71-year-old has become a feminist icon in France since the trial of Dominique Pelicot and 50 other men opened last month in the southern French city of Avignon.</p>

<p>The case has sparked horror, protests and a debate about male violence in French society, with the country keenly following the harrowing testimonies in court.</p>

<p>"I am a woman who is completely broken," Gisele Pelicot told the court in her second address to the court on Wednesday.</p>

<p>But she expressed her "determination to change this society" in terms of how it deals with sexual assault.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot insisted from the start that the trial should be open to the public to draw attention to the use of drugs to commit sexual abuse.</p>

<p>And she has encouraged other women who have been sexually assaulted to come forward.</p>

<p>"I wanted all women who are rape victims to say to themselves: 'Mrs Pelicot did it, so we can do it too'," she said.</p>

<p>"It's not us who should feel shame, but them (the perpetrators)", she said.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot addressed the court on Wednesday at the invitation of presiding judge Roger Arata, who asked for her "impressions" of the trial so far.</p>

<p>"I don't know how I'm going to rebuild myself," she said. "I'm 72 soon and I'm not sure my life will be long enough to recover from this."</p>

<p><strong>'Immeasurable betrayal'</strong></p>

<p>She then addressed her former husband who was sitting in the dock without looking at her, asking him to explain what made him drug her over almost a decade, rape her and enlist strangers to do the same.</p>

<p>"I'm trying to understand how my husband, who was the perfect man, became like this. How my life changed. How you could allow these people into our house knowing that I disliked swinging.</p>

<p>"For me, this betrayal is immeasurable. After 50 years together... I used to think I was going to be with this man until the end."</p>

<p>She added, looking steadily at her husband, who looked away: "I always tried to lift you higher. You plumbed the depths of the human soul, but unfortunately you made your own choices."</p>

<p>Her ex-husband, also 71, remained seated without any apparent reaction bar lowering his eyes.</p>

<p>His six other co-defendants whose cases are being studied by the court this week likewise stayed silent, surrounded by their counsels.</p>

<p>Gisele Pelicot, who was greeted with applause by the audience as she arrived Wednesday, has attended the trial most days.</p>

<p>In mid-September, she dropped her usual reserve to talk of her humiliation and her anger towards several lawyers who had made insinuations about her ordeal.</p>

<p>"A rape is a rape," she said.</p>

<p><strong>Abuse on film</strong></p>

<p>Dominique Pelicot filmed much of the abuse against his then-wife and also took meticulous records of the strangers visiting their home, which subsequently helped police uncover the crimes.</p>

<p>He has admitted to drugging her and inviting men to rape her between 2011 and 2020.</p>

<p>But he insists he is no different from the dozens of other men he recruited online to take part in the sexual abuse, alleging they all knew what they were signing up for.</p>

<p>Many of his co-defendants deny this, accusing him of manipulating them into raping his spouse of half a century.</p>

<p>Forty-nine other men are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot -- with nearly none of them admitting guilt.</p>

<p>One has admitted to sedating his own spouse so that he and Dominique Pelicot could sexually assault her.</p>

<p>The trial is scheduled to last until December.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ri9hq92o_gisele-pelicot_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[50 men are accused of raping or attempting to rape Gisele Pelicot.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-rolls-out-hindi-language-ai-model-6862182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nvidia Rolls Out Hindi-Language AI Model]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nvidia-rolls-out-hindi-language-ai-model-6862182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:32:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chip behemoth Nvidia launched a lightweight artificial intelligence model on Thursday for India's widely-used Hindi language, as it looks to tap into a growing market for AI technologies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chip behemoth Nvidia launched a lightweight artificial intelligence model on Thursday for India's widely-used Hindi language, as it looks to tap into a growing market for AI technologies.</p>

<p>Chief Executive Jensen Huang is set to chat with the chairman of conglomerate Reliance Industries, Mukesh Ambani, who is also Asia's richest man, at a conference in the business capital of Mumbai, the California-based company said.</p>

<p>Nvidia is rolling out its new small language model, dubbed Nemotron-4-Mini-Hindi-4B, with 4 billion parameters, for firms to use in developing their own AI models, the company said.</p>

<p>"The model was pruned, distilled and trained with a combination of real-world Hindi data, synthetic Hindi data and an equal amount of English data," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>Indian IT services and consulting company Tech Mahindra is the first to use the Nvidia offering to develop a custom AI model called Indus 2.0, focused on Hindi and dozens of its dialects, the U.S. company said.</p>

<p>Just a tenth of the population of 1.4 billion speaks English in India, where the constituion recognises 22 languages, it added.</p>

<p>From large companies to startups, businesses in India have focused on building AI models based on its diverse languages to grow consumer appeal and drive activities such as customer service AI assistants and content translation.</p>

<p>Unlike large-language models, such as OpenAI's GPT-4, used to power ChatGPT, small language models are trained on much smaller and more specific datasets.</p>

<p>They are typically cheaper, making them more attractive for companies with fewer resources.</p>

<p>Global chip firms are investing in India and setting up facilities to expand their presence as the country races to build up its semiconductor industry and compete with major hubs such as Taiwan, though analysts say the effort could take years.</p>

<p>Nvidia, which first set up shop in India nearly two decades ago, has engineering and design centers there, as well as offices in major cities such as the southern tech hub of Bengaluru and neighbouring Hyderabad.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8lllhf0o_nvidia-_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nvidia is rolling out its new small language model, dubbed Nemotron-4-Mini-Hindi-4B.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-sips-kava-becomes-samoan-high-chief-6861809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[King Charles Sips Kava, Becomes Samoan "High Chief"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-sips-kava-becomes-samoan-high-chief-6861809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:30:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles III took part in a traditional kava-drinking ceremony before a line of bare-chested, heavily tattooed Samoans and was declared a "high chief" of the one-time Pacific island colony Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles III took part in a traditional kava-drinking ceremony before a line of bare-chested, heavily tattooed Samoans and was declared a "high chief" of the one-time Pacific island colony Thursday.</p>

<p>The British monarch is on an 11-day tour of Australia and Samoa, both independent Commonwealth states -- the first major foreign trip since his cancer diagnosis earlier this year.</p>

<p>Wearing a white safari-style suit, the 75-year-old king sat at the head of a carved timber longhouse where he was presented with a polished half-coconut filled with a narcotic kava brew.</p>

<p>The peppery, slightly intoxicating root drink is a key part of Pacific culture and is known locally as "ava".</p>

<p>The kava roots were paraded around the marquee, prepared by the chief's daughter and filtered through a sieve made of dried bark.</p>

<p>Once ready, a Samoan man screamed as he decanted the drink, which was finally presented to the king.</p>

<p>Charles uttered the words: "May God Bless this ava" before lifting it to his lips.</p>

<p>Charles's wife, Queen Camilla sat beside him, fanning herself to ease the stiffing tropical humidity.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r94be7no_king-charles_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>High Chief</strong></p>

<p>Many Samoans are excited to host the king -- his first-ever visit to the Pacific Island nation that was once a British colony.</p>

<p>The royal couple visited the village of Moata'a where Charles was made "Tui Taumeasina" or high chief.</p>

<p>"Everyone has taken to our heart and is looking forward to welcoming the king," local chief Lenatai Victor Tamapua told AFP ahead of the visit.</p>

<p>"We feel honoured that he has chosen to be welcomed here in our village. So as a gift, we would like to bestow him a title."</p>

<p>Tamapua raised the issue of climate change and showed the king and queen around the local mangroves.</p>

<p>"The high tides is just chewing away on our reef and where the mangroves are," he told AFP, adding that food sources and communities were being washed away or inundated.</p>

<p>"Our community relies on the mangrove area for mud crab and fishes, but since, the tide has risen over the past 20 years by about two or three metres (up to 10 feet)."</p>

<p>The king is also in Samoa for the Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting, and will address a leaders' banquet on Friday.</p>

<p><strong>Colonialism and climate</strong></p>

<p>The legacy of empire looms large at the meeting.</p>

<p>Commonwealth leaders will select a new secretary-general nominated from an African country –- in line with regional rotations of the position.</p>

<p>All three likely candidates have called publicly for reparations for slavery and colonialism.</p>

<p>One of the three, Joshua Setipa from Lesotho, told AFP that the resolution could include non-traditional forms of payment such as climate financing.</p>

<p>"We can find a solution that will begin to address some injustices of the past and put them in the context happening around us today," he said.</p>

<p>Climate change features heavily on the agenda.</p>

<p>Tuvalu, Vanuatu and Fiji have backed calls for a "fossil fuel non-proliferation treaty" -- essentially calling for Australia, Britain and Canada to do more to lower emissions.</p>

<p>Pacific leaders argue the trio of "big countries" have historically accounted for over 60 percent of the 56-nation Commonwealth's emissions from fossil fuels.</p>

<p>Vanuatu's special envoy for climate change Ralph Regenvanu called on other nations to join the treaty.</p>

<p>"As a Commonwealth family, we look to those that dominate fossil fuel production in the Commonwealth to stop the expansion of fossil fuels in order to protect what we love and hold dear here in the Pacific," he said.</p>

<p>Australia's foreign minister Penny Wong said her gas and mineral-rich nation was working to be cleaner.</p>

<p>"We know we have a lot of work to do, and I've been upfront with every partner in the Pacific," she said.</p>

<p>Pacific island nations -- once seen as the embodiment of palm-fringed paradise -- are now among the most climate-threatened areas of the planet.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cf5kflno_king-charles_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles III was declared a "high chief" of the one-time Pacific island colony.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-justice-department-warns-elon-musk-over-1-million-giveaway-to-registered-voters-6861979]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Justice Department Warns Elon Musk Over $1 Million Giveaway]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-justice-department-warns-elon-musk-over-1-million-giveaway-to-registered-voters-6861979]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 12:05:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk, a Trump supporter, announced plans to give $1 million to one registered voter in a swing state every day until the US election on November 5.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk's America PAC has been warned by the Justice Department that its $1 million daily giveaways to registered voters may violate federal law, US media reported Wednesday.</p>

<p>Musk, the world's richest man, announced the contest on Saturday in Pennsylvania, one of the seven "swing states" that will likely determine who will become the next US president -- Donald Trump or Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Musk, a Trump supporter, announced plans to give $1 million to one registered voter in a swing state every day until the US election on November 5.</p>

<p>CNN and 24sight News said the letter from the Justice Department to Musk's political action commitee warns that the $1 million sweepstakes may violate federal law, which prohibits paying people to register to vote.</p>

<p>The Justice Department declined to comment.</p>

<p>The winners of the contest are chosen at random but they must be registered voters. They are also required to sign a petition that supports "free speech and the right to bear arms."</p>

<p>Danielle Lang, a professor at Georgetown Law School who specializes in election law, told AFP earlier this week that the contest could be "subject to civil or criminal enforcement by the Department of Justice."</p>

<p>"It is illegal to give out money on the condition that recipients register as voters," Lang said.</p>

<p>"As the terms of this 'contest' to win $1 million require the recipient to be a registered voter in one of seven swing states (or to register if they have not already), the offer violates federal law," she said.</p>

<p>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Musk has pulled out all the stops in recent weeks to support former president Trump, including donating $75 million to a pro-Trump political action committee and appearing at campaign rallies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5q7moe8_elon-musk-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Elections 2024: Elon Musk is a Donald Trump supporter.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-olaf-scholzs-delhi-visit-to-meet-pm-narendra-modi-germany-bets-on-india-as-ties-with-china-sour-6861472]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[With Olaf Scholz's Visit, Germany To Bet On India As Ties With China Sour]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-olaf-scholzs-delhi-visit-to-meet-pm-narendra-modi-germany-bets-on-india-as-ties-with-china-sour-6861472]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:57:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Germany is trying to cultivate India as a source of trade and geopolitical support as its deteriorating relations with China cast a pall over the country's economic future.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Germany is trying to cultivate India as a source of trade and geopolitical support as its deteriorating relations with China cast a pall over the country's economic future.&nbsp;Chancellor Olaf Scholz embarks on a three-day visit to India Thursday accompanied by a large delegation of ministers and executives as he seeks to forge a strategic partnership with Prime Minister Narendra Modi. The two leaders will meet on Friday morning and chair a joint cabinet meeting.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The trip comes at a crucial time for Scholz who is struggling to revive the German economy which has been buffeted by the war in Ukraine and competition from China. <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-consensus-a-long-pending-matter-at-un-what-pm-narendra-modi-said-at-brics-6858811">PM Modi</a> will have just returned from the BRICS summit in Russia where he embraced President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-explainer-understanding-the-lac-and-the-stand-off-with-china-6858970" target="_blank">India also just signed a border deal with China</a> to ease tensions with its neighbor after a four-year standoff.</p>

<p>Here are the main issues to watch:</p>

<h3><strong>Submarine Contract</strong></h3>

<p>India is planning to order six new submarines as part of its strategy to counter China's expanding naval presence in the Indo-Pacific region and Germany's Thyssenkrupp AG is bidding for the 400 billion rupee ($4.8 billion) order. German government spokesperson Christiane Hoffmann declined to comment on whether there might be a decision during the visit.</p>

<p>Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez is due to visit India later this month to open an Airbus SE plant in Gujarat and Spain's Navantia is also competing for the contract.</p>

<p>India has been looking to diversify its supplies of military hardware since Russia, its biggest source of weapons, invaded Ukraine in 2022 and became entangled in a web of Western sanctions.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>Russia and Ukraine</strong></h3>

<p>India has maintained its traditionally close ties with the Kremlin all the same and Scholz plans to discuss the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-in-very-good-position-to-listen-to-both-russia-ukraine-german-envoy-6856947" target="_blank">war in Ukraine</a> with PM Modi following his talks with Putin and Xi. There have been reports that India is supplying the Russian army with military equipment.</p>

<p>"The chancellor will be very curious about what the prime minister has to say after this meeting," Germany's ambassador to India, Philipp Ackermann, said. "India is in a very good position to basically listen to both sides and to have both sides in mind. And we have seen the prime minister going to Kyiv, and we have seen a renewed interest in the conflict."</p>

<h3><strong>China and Trade</strong></h3>

<p>The German government has been trying to persuade companies to ease their reliance on trade with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-summit-brics-summit-russia-india-china-patrolling-agreement-pm-modi-xi-welcome-complete-disengagement-between-soldiers-al-6857182" target="_blank">China</a> and some people have suggested India, the world's fifth-largest economy, as a potential alternative. But the country's close relation with Russia and the fact that it just resolved a yearlong border dispute with Beijing suggests that India isn't ready to go all in as a strategic partner for Germany. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Germany is already India's largest trading partner in Europe and the seventh-largest worldwide. Bilateral trade was $22 billion in 2020-21, according to the Indian government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Scholz is also likely to seek help in navigating the obstacles that small and medium-sized German firms face when doing business in India. More than 60% of German businesses cited bureaucratic hurdles - such as protectionist measures and procurement rules - as the biggest drawback to operating in the country, according to a survey from the Indo-German Chamber of Commerce released in June.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Scholz will continue his trip to the port city of Vasco da Gama, where he'll visit two German navy ships which recently passed the Strait of Taiwan for the first time in 22 years in defiance of Chinese warnings.</p>

<h3><strong>Help Wanted</strong></h3>

<p>Germany's workforce is set to shrink by 7 million people over the next decade due to an aging population unless the government can attract an influx of skilled migrants. Labor shortages this year are already costing the economy almost $54 billion), according to the German Economic Institute. In an attempt to reverse this trend, Scholz's government has eased immigration laws for skilled workers.</p>

<p>"Germany views India as an especially important partner when it comes to the issue of skilled labor migration," said Labor Minister Hubertus Heil, who will be part of the delegation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>That's a potential win-win for the two leaders, since PM Modi is under pressure to create more jobs for young people, who make up more than half of the country's 1.4 billion population. His government has already negotiated several mobility agreements with other countries facing aging societies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>There are currently 137,000 Indians employed in Germany in total and the country needs about 400,000 migrant workers per year to keep its workforce stable, according to government calculations.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/opp7hev_pm-modi-olaf-scholz_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[German Chancellor Olaf Scholz will meet PM Modi on Friday (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-model-accuses-trump-of-groping-her-in-1992-says-epstein-introduced-them-6861453]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ex Model Accuses Trump Of Groping Her In 1992, Says Epstein Introduced Them]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-model-accuses-trump-of-groping-her-in-1992-says-epstein-introduced-them-6861453]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:53:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A former model has accused Donald Trump of groping her after the two were introduced by sexual abuser Jeffrey Epstein in the 1990s, The Guardian newspaper reported on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A former model has accused Donald Trump of groping her after the two were introduced by sexual abuser Jeffrey Epstein in the 1990s, The Guardian newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Stacey Williams said she met the Republican White House candidate at a party in 1992 after being introduced by the disgraced financier, whom she had dated.</p>

<p>"It became very clear then that he and Donald were really, really good friends and spent a lot of time together," Williams was quoted as saying.</p>

<p>Williams discussed the alleged assault on a call on Monday organized by Survivors for Kamala, a lobby group supporting Trump's Democratic presidential rival Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Epstein, who was convicted on sex offenses and killed himself in prison in 2019, paid Trump an impromptu visit with Williams in 1992 at his New York office block, where he pulled her toward him and began groping her, she alleged.</p>

<p>Williams, now 56, says Trump put his hands "all over" her breasts, waist and buttocks, causing her to freeze on the spot, and she noticed that the two men appeared to be smiling at each other.</p>

<p>The Trump campaign did not immediately respond to AFP's request for comment, but The Guardian quoted a campaign spokeswoman dismissing the allegations as a "fake" story.</p>

<p>She said it was invented by the Harris campaign and described Williams "a former activist" for Democratic ex-president Barack Obama.</p>

<p>Williams shared a postcard depicting Trump's south Florida mansion she said he had sent her agent after the episode, with the message, in his handwriting: "Stacey – Your home away from home. Love Donald."</p>

<p>Trump has been accused of sexual assault or harassment by more than 20 women but denies all wrongdoing.</p>

<p>He was ordered by a New York court in January to pay $83.3 million to compensate the writer E. Jean Carroll, whom he was found liable for sexually assaulting and defaming.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/tvelgd5_donald-trump_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Former model Stacey Williams says Trump put his hands "all over" her breasts, waist and buttocks.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/standing-for-long-hours-could-increased-risk-of-circulatory-problems-study-6862292]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Standing For Long Hours Could Increased Risk Of Circulatory Problems: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/standing-for-long-hours-could-increased-risk-of-circulatory-problems-study-6862292]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:48:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new study from Australia involving over 83,000 participants found that prolonged standing may not improve heart health and could even increase the risk of certain circulatory problems.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The global market for standing desks is booming, projected to reach <a href="https://www.gminsights.com/industry-analysis/standing-desk-market">US$12.6 billion by 2032</a> (£9.7 billion). These desks have been hailed as a simple fix for the health risks associated with sitting all day. However, recent research suggests that standing might not be the health booster many hoped for.</p>

<p>A <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39412356/">new study</a> from Australia involving over 83,000 participants found that prolonged standing may not improve heart health and could even increase the risk of certain circulatory problems.</p>

<p>Researchers discovered that standing for extended periods did not reduce the risk of heart disease and stroke. In fact, spending too much time either sitting or standing was linked to a higher risk of problems such as varicose veins and feeling dizzy or lightheaded when you stand up.</p>

<p>The phrase “sitting is the new smoking” has <a href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=sitting+is+the+new+smoking&amp;year_start=1800&amp;year_end=2022&amp;corpus=en&amp;smoothing=3">become popular</a> in the past decade, highlighting the dangers of a sedentary lifestyle. Prolonged sitting has been associated with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30817262/">obesity, diabetes and cardiovascular diseases</a>. In response, standing desks emerged as a trendy solution, offering a <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34558602/">way to reduce sitting</a> time without drastically changing daily routines.</p>

<p>But was there solid evidence to support the benefits of standing desks?</p>

<p>Much of the enthusiasm was based on limited studies that didn't comprehensively assess long-term health consequences. This gap in knowledge prompted researchers to investigate further.</p>

<p>In the new study, participants wore devices to track their sitting, standing and physical activity over several years. This objective measurement provided accurate data, reducing the inaccuracies <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32131845/">often found in self-reported information</a>. The researchers found that sitting for more than ten hours a day was associated with a higher risk of heart disease and stroke.</p>

<p>However, simply standing more didn't mitigate this risk. In fact, standing for extended periods was linked to an increased risk of circulatory problems.</p>

<p>Prolonged standing can cause blood to pool in the legs, leading to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25047584/">conditions such as varicose veins</a>.</p>

<p>The study's large sample size and use of objective data strengthen the reliability of these findings. However, as an observational study, it cannot definitively establish cause and effect. Also, the average age of participants was around 61 years, which may limit how these results apply to younger people.</p>

<figure class="align-center "><img alt="A man's lower legs covered in varicose veins." sizes="(min-width: 1466px) 754px, (max-width: 599px) 100vw, (min-width: 600px) 600px, 237px" src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip" srcset="https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 600w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1200w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=600&amp;h=400&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 1800w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=1 754w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=30&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=2 1508w, https://images.theconversation.com/files/626925/original/file-20241021-15-2y6k27.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=15&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;h=503&amp;fit=crop&amp;dpr=3 2262w" />
<figcaption><span class="caption">Standing for long periods can increase the risk of varicose veins.</span> <span class="attribution"><a class="source" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/image-photo/elderly-mans-bare-legs-varicose-veins-2509061249">sutulastock/Shutterstock</a></span></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2><strong>Movement is key</strong></h2>

<p>These findings suggest that simply swapping sitting for standing isn't a perfect solution. Our bodies respond better to regular movement rather than static positions, whether that's sitting or standing.</p>

<p>Incorporating short walks, stretching or light exercises throughout the day can interrupt long periods of inactivity and offer <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33239350/">significant health benefits</a>.</p>

<p>Workplace interventions promoting movement have shown promise. Researchers found that office workers who reduced their sitting time by adding periods of <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25113139/">standing and light activity</a> saw improvements in blood sugar levels and other health markers.</p>

<p>Another study indicated that alternating between sitting and standing, combined with brief walks, was <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6334681/">more effective for health</a> than standing alone.</p>

<p>Sit-stand desks, designed to facilitate easy position changes, offer a promising solution. They promote <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22374636/">frequent posture changes</a> and can alleviate discomfort associated with prolonged static positions. Some models even feature reminders to encourage regular movement, integrating activity into the workday.</p>

<p>Getting more physical activity into our lives doesn't have to be complex. Simple actions such as taking the stairs, walking to a colleague instead of emailing, or standing during phone calls can all contribute. Setting a timer to remind you to move every 30 minutes can help break up long periods of sitting or standing, empowering you to take control of your health.</p>

<p>Movement is key. Standing all day isn't necessarily better than sitting – both have drawbacks when overdone. By focusing on regular physical activity and varying our positions, we can better address the health challenges posed by sedentary lifestyles. Small changes, such as taking short active breaks or incorporating stretching exercises, can make a <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33239350/">significant difference</a>.</p>

<p>Ultimately, while standing desks offer an alternative to prolonged sitting, they shouldn't be seen as a complete solution. Embracing a more active lifestyle, both in and out of the office, is likely to yield the greatest health benefits. It's not just about standing or sitting; it's about moving more and sitting less.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/241687/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span>(Author:&nbsp;<a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/jack-mcnamara-1352749">Jack McNamara</a>, Senior Lecturer in Clinical Exercise Physiology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-east-london-924">University of East London</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/standing-desks-are-bad-for-your-health-new-study-241687">original article</a>.)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-02/standing-desk_650x400_81517543112.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[he global market for standing desks is booming, projected to reach US$12.6 billion by 2032.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/londoners-push-for-worlds-first-afro-hair-emojis-6862707]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Londoners Push For World's First Afro Hair Emojis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/londoners-push-for-worlds-first-afro-hair-emojis-6862707]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:42:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[There are nearly 4,000 emojis - symbols that represent human emotions or objects online - but none feature Black or mixed-race hairstyles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Aiming to break down beauty stereotypes and make the digital world more inclusive, a group of young students and professionals from London have designed what they hope will become the first ever emojis of Black and mixed-race hairstyles.</p>

<p>The project, a partnership between youth-led organisation RISE.365 and PR agency Good Relations, aims to tackle texturism, a form of discrimination where Afro hair is often perceived as "unprofessional", "unattractive" or "unclean", they said.</p>

<p>There are nearly 4,000 emojis - symbols that represent human emotions or objects online - but none feature Black or mixed-race hairstyles. RISE.365 and Good Relations took matters into their own hands to change that.</p>

<p>A group of young people sketched what the emojis should look like, and then designers came up with the final product.</p>

<p>"(The emojis) would break down the society standards of your hair having to be straight to be seen as desirable," said Jayzik Duckoo, a 17-year-old who worked on the project. "I hope people wear their hair proudly."</p>

<p>Four emojis were created featuring afros, braids, cornrows and locs. They will be submitted to Unicode, the California-based group responsible for emojis, in April 2025 for consideration.</p>

<p>Googling 'Afro hair' could help the emojis' acceptance, as Unicode considers how frequently the term associated with the symbol is used, RISE.365 said.</p>

<p>Unicode did not reply to a Reuters request for comment.</p>

<p>Olivia Mushigo, senior creative behind the project, said she hoped the emojis would make people "feel empowered and ... actually seen".</p>

<p>The 28-year-old has never experienced discrimination because of her hair, but her young brother has, she said.</p>

<p>"My little brother will have an emoji that looks like him to hopefully boost his confidence and show him that his hair is beautiful," she said. "On a more personal note, I finally have an emoji that looks like me, that I can identify with."</p>

<p>A poll of RISE.365 members - a total of 104 respondents - showed 61% had experienced discrimination or bullying because of their hair. A 2023 study by the CROWN Research Studies showed 66% of Black women change their hair for a job interview.</p>

<p>Vanita Brown, who designed the emojis, said a reason why such emojis were still not available was due to eurocentric beauty standards being seen as the norm.</p>

<p>Lack of representation in stock imagery is also an issue, Brown said, and Mushigo highlighted the diversity gap in tech companies, where Black people are underrepresented.</p>

<p>"Hopefully with greater diversity and inclusivity among tech teams, we will start to see more emojis that actually represent the diversity of the world we live in," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/tfpimop8_emoji-catalog_625x300_12_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Four emojis were created featuring afros, braids, cornrows and locs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaire-sex-saga-is-latest-scandal-to-rock-australian-ceos-6861354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Billionaire Sex Saga Is Latest Scandal To Rock Australian CEOs]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/billionaire-sex-saga-is-latest-scandal-to-rock-australian-ceos-6861354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:39:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The alleged sex-for-investment scandal embroiling Australian tech billionaire Richard White is just the latest corporate calamity in a country fast losing its reputation as a tightly-regulated market with strict governance standards.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The alleged sex-for-investment scandal embroiling Australian tech billionaire Richard White is just the latest corporate calamity in a country fast losing its reputation as a tightly-regulated market with strict governance standards.</p>

<p>More than A$7 billion ($4.6 billion) of market value has been wiped from WiseTech Global Ltd. this week after media reports that White - the company's co-founder, chief executive officer and largest shareholder - paid millions of dollars to a former sexual partner to settle allegations of inappropriate behavior.&nbsp;</p>

<p>With a board review underway, the crisis enveloping the freight software giant and its figurehead CEO deepened Thursday as the Australian Financial Review reported a former director had accused White of intimidation and bullying. Earlier, the newspaper said White also had a years-long relationship with an employee before gifting her a A$7 million waterfront house in Melbourne. The transaction wasn't disclosed to the board, according to the report.</p>

<p>Helen Karlis, a spokesperson for White's lawyers at Clayton Utz, said the law firm had no immediate comment on the latest allegations that have been aired. The firm hasn't responded to earlier repeated requests for comment. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In a matter of months, accusations of operational or ethical failures have also hit Australia's two dominant supermarkets, one of the major banks, the largest insurer, the biggest listed media company and Sydney's main casino. In a country with one of the planet's biggest pension pools, where worker contributions are mandatory, everyday savers are picking up the tab when stock prices decline.</p>

<p>Another tycoon founder, Mineral Resources Ltd.'s Chris Ellison, also this week found himself embroiled in scandal with the company investigating historic undeclared payments that helped him avoid tax. Australia's corporate watchdog has launched a probe, and almost A$2 billion has been slashed from the miner's market value since Monday.</p>

<p>The mining magnate described his actions in a statement on Monday as "a poor decision and a serious lapse of judgment." He had subsequently "voluntarily" disclosed the matters to the Australian Taxation Office in full, with all outstanding tax, penalties and interest repaid. The company's board said earlier this week it retained confidence in Ellison.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While executive or corporate transgressions are a worldwide phenomenon, it seems to be particularly pronounced in Australia, where a confluence of factors come into play. Many of the country's largest industries - aviation, banking, groceries and retailing - are duopolies or oligopolies, comfortable environments that can be conducive for market-power abuse.</p>

<p>Australia is home to only 27 million people and has a relatively small pool of independent board directors to oversee listed companies. Many directors have roles at multiple businesses. Advocacy groups have long said board members are reluctant to speak out when standards lapse at one company for fear of losing a board position at another firm.</p>

<p>That's not the only problem. Some of the country's watchdogs are either short of resources, have few corporate scalps to their name, or dish out fines that do little to deter bad behavior. Star Entertainment Group Ltd. was this month fined just A$15 million - less than 1% of revenue - by its regulator after an inquiry found the casino operator had breached its license several times and was unfit to run its flagship Sydney complex, despite having had two years to address its problems.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The head of a Senate inquiry into the Australian Securities and Investments Commission, the country's primary corporate regulator, in July described the agency as "an organization without transparency, few prosecutions, and a litany of cultural, structural and governance issues."</p>

<p>One of the most damning assessments of an Australian workplace came only last week when Nine Entertainment Co., publisher of the Sydney Morning Herald and the AFR, released an independent review of its own practices. The report uncovered systemic abuses of power and authority, bullying, discrimination and sexual harassment.</p>

<p>At too many businesses, internal governance measures aren't detecting problems before they develop into major public scandals, said Rahat Munir, a professor at Macquarie University's business school who leads the department of accounting and corporate governance. Australia's geographical remoteness, far from the world's major financial and corporate hubs, means its companies risk operating in their own bubble, he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"As a result, it's very, very easy to manipulate the local market," he said.</p>

<p><strong>WiseTech Woes</strong></p>

<p>At WiseTech, shareholders feeling the pain from the claims against White and the board include Australia's sovereign wealth fund, along with its largest pension fund, AustralianSuper Pty. WiseTech shares fell as much as 5.8% Thursday, with the stock on track for its worst monthly performance since February 2020.</p>

<p>"We should all be concerned that these are not isolated examples, but a pattern of behavior that is causing direct losses to shareholders," said Brendan Lyon, a professor with the University of Wollongong's faculty of business and law. Corporate regulation is failing, Lyon said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The flurry of allegations against WiseTech and White now threaten the company's leadership. Former director Christine Holman accused White of "sustained intimidation and bullying" as she quit the board in October 2019 after less than a year, the AFR reported Thursday. The AFR said it wasn't suggesting White bullied or intimidated Holman, only that she accused him of doing so. Holman declined to comment to the newspaper.&nbsp;</p>

<p>AGL Energy Ltd., where Holman is now a board member, forwarded her an interview request from Bloomberg News earlier this week, which she declined. AGL didn't reply to a fresh request from Bloomberg on Thursday for comment from Holman on her reported resignation letter from WiseTech.</p>

<p>A WiseTech spokesperson didn't comment on the latest AFR report, but said the company has clear policies related to the disclosure of close personal relationships in the workplace. White confirmed he has complied with the policy, according to the spokesperson.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The board continues to proactively make enquiries on a range of matters, monitor the situation and carefully consider all relevant factors," the spokesperson said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Monday, the AFR cited White as saying he was concerned about any allegations, even untested ones.&nbsp;</p>

<p>White last week reached an out-of-court settlement with an another alleged former lover he was pursuing for bankruptcy, the case that first thrust him into the media spotlight. The woman had alleged White expected her to have sex with him in exchange for an investment in her business.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/05s91tsg_richard-white-bloomberg_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Richard White's lawyers said they had no immediate comment on the allegations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-health-advisers-back-pfizer-merck-pneumonia-shots-for-adults-over-50-6861331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Health Advisers Back Pfizer, Merck Pneumonia Shots For Adults Over 50]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-health-advisers-back-pfizer-merck-pneumonia-shots-for-adults-over-50-6861331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 11:33:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A key panel of US health advisers voted in favor of lowering the age recommendation for vaccines made by Pfizer Inc and Merck & Co that protect against pneumococcal disease, clearing a path for wider use.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A key panel of US health advisers voted in favor of lowering the age recommendation for vaccines made by Pfizer Inc and Merck &amp; Co that protect against pneumococcal disease, clearing a path for wider use.</p>

<p>Members of the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices voted 14-to-1 to recommend all adults aged 50 and older get vaccinated to prevent the bacterial infections behind pneumonia and meningitis.</p>

<p>The group's recommendation was endorsed by CDC Director Mandy Cohen. The CDC's prior guidance for pneumococcal vaccines was for adults aged 65 and over and children under 5. The shots are also suggested for certain adults and children who are immunocompromised.</p>

<p>Both companies had asked the CDC to lower age recommendations to include adults 50 and up.</p>

<p>The wider recommendations could bode well for Pfizer, which has been struggling to find new sources of revenue amid a decline in sales of its Covid-19 vaccine and treatment. The company's pneumococcal shot, called Prevnar, is one of its best-selling products with about $6 billion in annual sales.</p>

<p>Merck's recently approved vaccine, however, gives Pfizer some major competition. The shot, called Capvaxive, protects against bacterial strains that cause about 84% of cases of adult pneumoccocal disease. In comparison, Prevnar works against about half of disease-causing strains.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qb680fao_pneumonia-shot-bloomberg_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The group's recommendation was endorsed by CDC Director Mandy Cohen.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>