<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:36:54 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-didnt-agree-to-discuss-israel-arms-embargo-says-aide-6294561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Didn't Agree To Discuss Israel Arms Embargo, Says Aide]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-didnt-agree-to-discuss-israel-arms-embargo-says-aide-6294561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:24:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris did not agree to discuss imposing an arms embargo on Israel during an exchange with pro-Palestinian activists who are pushing for changes to US policy toward its ally over the Gaza war, an aide said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris did not agree to discuss imposing an arms embargo on Israel during an exchange with pro-Palestinian activists who are pushing for changes to US policy toward its ally over the Gaza war, an aide said on Thursday.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted National Movement had said late on Wednesday that Harris, the 2024 Democratic presidential candidate, had "shared her sympathies and expressed an openness to a meeting with Uncommitted leaders to discuss an arms embargo" during the interaction while campaigning in Detroit, the aide said.</p>

<p>The aide, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said Harris did not express a willingness to discuss an arms embargo. But a campaign spokesperson said the vice president did tell members of the Muslim and Palestinian community she would continue to engage with them on the war between Israel and Palestinian militants Hamas in Gaza, which local officials say has killed nearly 40,000 people.</p>

<p>"The vice president has been clear: She will always work to ensure Israel is able to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist groups. The vice president is focused on securing the ceasefire and hostage deal currently on the table," the campaign spokesperson said.</p>

<p>Two founders of the group, Layla Elabed and Abbas Alawieh, said they spoke briefly with both Harris and newly minted running mate Tim Walz of Minnesota about their concerns about the U.S. supplying weapons to Israel as it wages war in Gaza.</p>

<p>Alawieh said on Thursday that both he and Elabed specifically asked for a meeting to discuss the demand for an arms embargo on Israel, "and in both cases, Vice President Harris expressed an openness to following up."</p>

<p>He said he was very encouraged by his engagements with Harris' office and "we're hopeful that continued discussions will continue to be fruitful."</p>

<p><strong>HUMANITARIAN CRISIS</strong></p>

<p>Israel launched its assault on the besieged Palestinian enclave in retaliation for an Oct. 7 attack on southern Israel by Hamas militants who killed 1,200 people and took some 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted political group was organized to oppose President Joe Biden's staunch support for Israel's war, which has displaced nearly 80 percent of Gaza's 2.3 million people and caused severe food shortages.</p>

<p>The humanitarian catastrophe in Gaza has prompted calls for Washington to put conditions on the billions of dollars in military funding and other assistance it provides to Israel, which has received more U.S. foreign aid since World War Two than any other country.</p>

<p>The United States in May paused a shipment of 2,000-pound and 500-pound bombs due to concern over the impact they could have in Gaza.</p>

<p>The Uncommitted movement amassed sizable vote totals in presidential nominating contests in Michigan, Minnesota and Hawaii, and has won at least 25 delegates. Leaders have said they want to use their influence at this month's Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>

<p>In a reminder of how divisive the issue has been for Democrats, a group of pro-Palestinian protesters briefly interrupted Harris' speech in Detroit on Wednesday, chanting, "Kamala, Kamala, you can't hide, we won't vote for genocide."</p>

<p>She paused for a moment, saying she believed in democracy and the importance of every voice, and then added, "But I am speaking now." When the chants continued, she repeated, "You know what? If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that. Otherwise, I'm speaking."</p>

<p>Trump has criticized Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for Israeli security failures that enabled Hamas to carry out the Oct. 7 attack and said he would work to bring about a quick end to the war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9jgs0hjg_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States in May paused a shipment of 2,000-pound and 500-pound bombs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-prize-winner-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-6294401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus Takes Oath As Head Of Interim Government In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-interim-government-led-by-nobel-prize-winner-muhammad-yunus-takes-oath-6294401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 21:03:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Signalling the beginning of a new chapter after 15 years of Sheikh Hasina as the prime minister, Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took oath as the head of the interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Signalling the beginning of a new chapter after 15 years of Sheikh Hasina as the prime minister, Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus took oath as the head of the interim government in Bangladesh on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I will uphold, support and protect the constitution and will perform my duties sincerely," Mr Yunus said at the swearing-in event, which comes at a tumultuous time for Bangladesh. The country has witnessed violence and clashes after the student-led protests forced Ms Hasina to resign and flee the country on Monday.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus, 84, was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2006 for pioneering microcredit and microfinance, which he put into action through the Grameen Bank. He was sworn in hours after he returned to Dhaka from Paris, where he had been undergoing medical treatment. The oath was administered by Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin at his official residence, Bangabhaban.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi extended his best wishes to Mr Yunus and said India is hoping for an early return to normalcy in Bangladesh, which would also ensure the safety of Hindus and other minorities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My best wishes to Professor Muhammad Yunus on the assumption of his new responsibilities. We hope for an early return to normalcy, ensuring the safety and protection of Hindus and all other minority communities. India remains committed to working with Bangladesh to fulfill the shared aspirations of both our peoples for peace, security and development," PM Modi wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/k4mimtrg_muhammad-yunus-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi has extended his best wishes to Mr Yunus.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attend-mosque-or-be-punished-taliban-chief-orders-government-workers-6293812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Attend Mosque Or Be Punished, Taliban Chief Orders Government Workers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/attend-mosque-or-be-punished-taliban-chief-orders-government-workers-6293812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:31:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Afghan government employees must attend mosque five times a day or face punishment, Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada said Thursday in his latest edict enforcing an austere interpretation of Islam.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Afghan government employees must attend mosque five times a day or face punishment, Taliban supreme leader Hibatullah Akhundzada said Thursday in his latest edict enforcing an austere interpretation of Islam.</p>

<p>Since the 2021 Taliban takeover Akhundzada has overseen sweeping restrictions on society -- shutting many women and girls out of education, ordering male chaperones for females and effectively banning music.</p>

<p>"The officials of the ministries and institutions of the (Taliban government) are obliged by Sharia to pray in congregation at their fixed times," said the order signed by Akhundzada.</p>

<p>It added that employees who miss a prayer "without a reasonable excuse" should receive a warning, and if they repeat the transgression "the relevant official is obliged to appropriately punish him".</p>

<p>A Taliban government spokesman did not respond to a query from AFP asking what the punishment would entail.</p>

<p>According to Islam, Muslims must strive to pray five times a day, either in private or at a mosque.</p>

<p>The times are adjusted according to the sun, but some fall within working hours.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear how the order for employees to attend prayer during non-work hours would be policed.</p>

<p>Akhundzada directs the government from his hideout in southern Kandahar, the spiritual heartland of the Taliban movement which first ruled Afghanistan from 1996 to 2001.</p>

<p>He rarely appears in public, and when he does bodyguards prohibit spectators from taking photographs or video of the man who has led the Taliban since 2016.</p>

<p>But his intermittent edicts now define how Afghans can lead their lives.</p>

<p>A United Nations report last month said "restrictive measures to regulate activities of individuals in both public and private spheres contribute to a climate of fear and intimidation among segments of the population".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/hrfdt17o_taliban-generic_625x300_16_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Since the 2021 Taliban takeover, Akhundzada has overseen sweeping restrictions on society]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-sorry-about-hamas-october-7-attack-6294009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Benjamin Netanyahu Says He Is "Sorry" About Hamas October 7 Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/netanyahu-sorry-about-hamas-october-7-attack-6294009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:15:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry" that Hamas was able to carry out its October 7 attack, without explicitly taking responsibility.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in an interview published Thursday that he was "sorry" that Hamas was able to carry out its October 7 attack, without explicitly taking responsibility.</p>

<p>Netanyahu, who has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack and focused on destroying Hamas, was asked if he would apologize during an interview with Time magazine.</p>

<p>"Apologize?" he was quoted as replying.</p>

<p>"Of course, of course. I am sorry, deeply, that something like this happened. And you always look back and you say, 'Could we have done things that would have prevented it?'" he said.</p>

<p>The right-wing leader is Israel's longest-serving prime minister and has long billed himself as a staunch protector of Israel's security.</p>

<p>Shortly after the October 7 attack, Netanyahu posted on social media that intelligence services had failed to anticipate the Hamas operation and warn him.</p>

<p>He deleted and apologized for that post after numerous Israelis accused him of deflecting blame and jeopardizing national unity.</p>

<p>In the interview, Time asked Netanyahu what his message would be to a political rival who presided over the country's worst security failure.</p>

<p>Netanyahu replied that it depended on whether the leader could lead Israel "to victory."</p>

<p>"Can they assure that the postwar situation will be one of peace and security? If the answer is yes, they should stay in power."</p>

<p>Hamas on October 7 carried out the deadliest attack in Israel's history. A total of 1,198 people died, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,677 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/ap4d2k3o_benjamin-netanyahu-afp_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu has resisted making an apology for security failures over Israel's worst-ever attack]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-suggests-starving-millions-in-gaza-sparks-global-outrage-6292847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Minister Says Starving Millions In Gaza Is "Justified And Moral"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-minister-suggests-starving-millions-in-gaza-sparks-global-outrage-6292847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 20:04:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich's suggestion that starving millions to death in Gaza was "justified and moral" has sparked global outrage. His comments, made during a speech last week, have been widely condemned by global powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich's suggestion that starving millions to death in Gaza was "justified and moral" has sparked global outrage. His comments, made during a speech last week, have been widely condemned by global powers, including the European Union, the United Kingdom and France.</p>

<p>Smotrich remarked that halting aid to the besieged territory could be a means to "free the hostages".</p>

<p>"No one in the world will allow us to starve two million people, even though it might be justified and moral in order to free the hostages," the far-right minister said, as quoted by news agency AFP.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The EU swiftly responded, labelling the deliberate starvation of civilians a "war crime" and demanding the Israeli government distance itself from the minister's words. They said the remarks showed "contempt for international law and for basic principles of humanity".</p>

<p>France expressed "deep dismay" and criticised the far-right minister, stating that providing humanitarian aid to Gaza is an "obligation under international humanitarian law" due to Israel's control over the territory's access, AFP reported.</p>

<p>Germany strongly denounced the remarks, calling them "completely unacceptable and outrageous". A spokesman for the Foreign Office in Berlin stated that civilians must be protected in war and have access to essential resources like water and food as it was a "basic principle" mandated by international humanitarian law.</p>

<p>UK Foreign Secretary David Lammy called on the Israeli government to "retract and condemn" the remarks, while in a separate development, the US State Department demanded a full investigation into allegations of sexual abuse against Palestinian detainees by Israeli soldiers. The allegations came to light following the release of a video on Israel's Channel 12, which appeared to show soldiers leading a detainee out of camera view to commit acts of abuse.</p>

<p>The video has intensified scrutiny of Israel's treatment of Palestinian detainees, with Israeli authorities launching an investigation into alleged abuse by soldiers. The investigation has already led to the arrest of nine soldiers, which led to protests from right-wing Israelis who stormed two military facilities in response.</p>

<p>Amid growing concerns, Israeli rights group B'Tselem has published a report stating the mistreatment of Palestinian prisoners had become so widespread that it amounted to a policy of "institutionalised abuse."</p>

<p>In May, International Criminal Court Chief Prosecutor Karim Khan announced plans to issue arrest warrants for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Defense Minister Yoav Gallant. The warrants are related to war crimes and crimes against humanity committed in Gaza. The devastating conflict, now nearing 10 months, has left vast areas of Gaza in ruins. A crippling blockade has severely limited access to essential resources like food, clean water, and medicine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's war in Gaza has created a dire humanitarian crisis, displacing almost all 2.4 million residents, killing nearly 40,000 and injuring almost 1 lakh Palestinians. Israel faces accusations of genocide at the International Court of Justice, which has ordered an immediate halt to military operations in Rafah. The southern city had provided refuge for over 1 million Palestinians before being invaded and bombed in May.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/0vlg7p5_gaza-children_625x300_18_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video has intensified scrutiny of Israel's treatment of Palestinian detainees.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-rise-in-ocean-temperatures-is-threatening-marine-life-6293817]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Rise In Ocean Temperatures Is Threatening Marine Life]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-rise-in-ocean-temperatures-is-threatening-marine-life-6293817]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:50:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Since April, the world has seen record high ocean temperatures and that's bad news for the plants and animals that call the ocean home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since April, the world has seen record high ocean temperatures and that's bad news for the plants and animals that call the ocean home.</p>

<p>Longer and more frequent bouts of extreme temperatures can cause the exodus of some species and the invasion of others, with potentially devastating impacts on the resident ecosystem.</p>

<p>Global warming manifests as a gradual increase in temperatures over time around the world, caused by increased greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>However, scientists are finding that the most important impacts come from short-term spikes in temperature.</p>

<p>In the ocean, these discrete periods of extreme temperatures, lasting weeks to months, are called marine heatwaves.</p>

<p>Marine heatwaves can be generated by either the atmosphere or by ocean processes.</p>

<p>For example, weather systems like high pressure systems can lead to low cloud and greater solar heating while ocean changes can be driven by strengthened poleward currents that move heat from high to low latitudes.</p>

<p>The likelihood and intensity of these atmospheric and oceanic drivers of marine heatwaves can also be affected by large-scale phenomena like El Nino or La Nina.</p>

<p>Larger portions of the oceans are likely to experience marine heatwaves during El Nino events.</p>

<p>Marine heatwaves can have dramatic impacts on marine organisms and ecosystems that may extend for long periods after temperatures have returned to normal.</p>

<p>Impacts range from the suppressed growth of microscopic marine plants to mass deaths in fish and marine mammals, encroachment of invasive species and toxic algal outbreaks.</p>

<p>Importantly, marine heatwaves have been associated with extensive dieback of species like coral reefs, kelp forests and seagrass beds that form the homes and breeding grounds for a large amount of the ocean's biodiversity.</p>

<p>These impacts can have devastating knock-on effects for fisheries, aquaculture and tourism industries, with individual events linked to direct losses of up to hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>

<p>The Ningaloo Nino that formed early in 2011 was an iconic extreme event.</p>

<p>Intensified winds along the Pacific equator - associated with an extreme La Niña - forced warm water westwards and through the Indonesian Archipelago, into the Indian Ocean and poleward along the coast of Western Australia.</p>

<p>This flood of warm water caused a record-breaking marine heatwave that wiped out the endemic kelp forest for over 100 km along the Australian coast along with one-third (1,300 square kilometres) of the Shark Bay seagrass meadow, a UNESCO world heritage site.</p>

<p>The Ningaloo Nino caused deaths and reduced reproduction in abalone, scallops and crabs that led to the closure of associated fisheries for several years.</p>

<p>The Tasman Sea is another hotspot for ocean warming and marine heatwaves.</p>

<p>Two consecutive extreme events occurred the summer of 2015/16 and 2017/18. Their causes were very different.</p>

<p>The first was primarily caused by an intensification of the warm East Australian Current while the second was caused by a long-lasting high pressure system over the ocean.</p>

<p>These and previous events brought an invasion of sea urchins from mainland waters that led to the decimation of kelp forests off eastern Tasmania.</p>

<p>The 2015/16 event alone led to new diseases in cultured oysters, poor salmon performance and high mortalities of abalone. Together this led to economic losses of more than half a billion dollars.</p>

<p>As marine heatwaves exist on the backdrop of long-term global ocean warming, these extreme events are becoming more intense and more frequent.</p>

<p>Over the past century the number of days each year experiencing marine heatwave conditions has increased by more than 50 percent.</p>

<p>The shorter time between marine heatwaves means that many populations no longer have the time to recover between events, which can lead to species moving their range or being wiped out.</p>

<p>And this will only worsen in the future.</p>

<p>Many studies show that some coral reefs are losing their hard corals.</p>

<p>And with increased future warming the very existence of tropical coral reefs are in doubt.</p>

<p>Since April, the oceans have been warmer than at any time during the instrumental record.</p>

<p>It's probably at least 100,000 years - before the last ice age - since temperatures could have been this warm.</p>

<p>As a consequence, scientists are seeing more of the ocean experiencing marine heatwave conditions than ever. And that's before the added push from the developing El Nino.</p>

<p>Over the past few weeks alone, there have been extreme marine heatwaves in all of the ocean basins, including around the UK and Japan, off Peru and in waters extending off of the Californian, Florida and east and west Canadian coasts.</p>

<p>As the Northern Hemisphere enters its warmest season, marine heatwaves are at their most dangerous, pushing marine organisms above their thermal limits.</p>

<p>Over the next few months, expect reports of significant ecosystem harm to start to emerge.</p>

<p>An understanding of the physical drivers of these events and their biological impacts provides scientists with some ability to forecast their likelihood in the future.</p>

<p>This can help marine resource managers make decisions, like moving aquaculture stocks, reducing fishing quotas or taking direct action to suppress warming (like shading of aquaculture cultivation areas, or moving aquaculture pens out of harm's way) in small, high-value regions.</p>

<p>But ultimately, to avoid escalating impacts the only solution is to stop greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p><em>Associate Professor Alex Sen Gupta is a research scientist and lecturer at the Climate Change Research Centre and the Centre For Marine Science and Innovation at UNSW. His work revolves around the role of the ocean in the climate system, how the ocean influences regional climate and what global climate models tell us about the future of the ocean, with a recent focus on marine heatwaves.</em></p>

<p><em>Associate Professor Sen Gupta's research has been funded by the Australian Research Council.</em></p>

<p><em>Dr Katie Smith is a postdoctoral research assistant at the Marine Biological Association in the UK. Her research interests include understanding the impacts of climate change on marine species, throughout their life history and from individual to whole-ecosystem level.</em></p>

<p><em>Originally published under<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"> Creative Commons</a> by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://360info.org/more-marine-heatwaves-could-spell-disaster-for-ocean-life/">360info</a>.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-08/marine-life_650x400_51502364370.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Marine heatwaves can be generated by either the atmosphere or by ocean processes (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-taylor-swift-fans-said-after-foiled-isis-attack-on-vienna-concerts-6293706]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Taylor Swift Fans Said After Foiled ISIS Attack On Vienna Concerts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-taylor-swift-fans-said-after-foiled-isis-attack-on-vienna-concerts-6293706]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:36:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taylor Swift fans turned to social media on Thursday, grappling with sorrow, anger, and disbelief after the singer's three Vienna concerts were abruptly cancelled following the Austrian government's confirmation of a planned attack at the venue.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taylor Swift fans turned to social media on Thursday, grappling with sorrow, anger, and disbelief after the singer's three Vienna concerts were abruptly cancelled following the Austrian government's confirmation of a planned attack at the venue.</p>

<p>Some 195,000 fans in total were expected for the concerts at Vienna's Ernst Happel Stadium, with many having travelled from abroad for a chance to see the pop superstar live.</p>

<p>"One year of excitement is gone in one second," lamented a fan in response to the organizer's Instagram message cancelling the concerts, less than 24 hours before the first was due to begin.</p>

<p>The post gained over 5,500 responses, ranging from understanding to outrage, with many urging Swift to address her fans directly and reschedule her shows in the Austrian capital.</p>

<p>"Please reschedule Vienna, your silence is just heartbreaking," another fan wrote. The 34-year-old singer-songwriter has yet to issue a public statement.</p>

<p>Austrian Interior Minister Gerhard Kanner expressed understanding for the decision to cancel, emphasizing, "I repeat, this has prevented a tragedy."</p>

<p>Austrian police on Wednesday detained two people suspected of plotting attacks. The main suspect, a 19-year-old Austrian who has North Macedonian roots, had allegedly masterminded a plot to attack Swift fans in Vienna with a bomb or knife and had pledged allegiance to the Islamic State terrorist group, authorities said on Thursday.</p>

<p>He made a full confession in custody, Austria's general director for public security Franz Ruf told a news conference.</p>

<p>Swift has previously spoken about her fears regarding safety on tour, especially in light of the 2017 Manchester Arena bombing that killed 22 and the Las Vegas shooting that claimed 60 lives.</p>

<p>"I was completely terrified to go on tour this time because I didn't know how we were going to keep 3 million fans safe over seven months," she shared in a 2019 interview with Elle magazine, revealing that her fear of violence had made her carry military-grade bandages for emergencies.</p>

<p>Barracuda Music, the concert organizer, said all tickets would be automatically refunded within 10 days. However, for many fans who had travelled from afar, the reimbursement fell short of covering their expenses.</p>

<p>"What are the people that have spent thousands of dollars to see her in Vienna supposed to do!?," one frustrated fan commented on the singer's Taylor Nation's Instagram, which has over nine million followers. Others expressed a mix of gratitude for their safety and disbelief at the situation.</p>

<p>Tracy Jo Clark Neusser said she was shocked and devastated after flying from the United States for the concert.</p>

<p>"We would never be able to afford the trip back again even if she does reschedule," Neusser wrote on Instagram, asking how she could get a poster for the cancelled concert.</p>

<p>"It would certainly be a story on our wall, even if it's an unfortunate one. Gonna just have to believe everything happens for a reason," she added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3ou5mc6_taylor-swifts-magical-eras-tour_625x300_24_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Some 195,000 fans in total were expected for the concerts in Vienna]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/live-updates-muhammad-yunus-set-to-take-oath-as-bangladesh-leader-6293657]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: Bangladesh Interim Government, Led By Muhammad Yunus, Takes Oath]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/live-updates-muhammad-yunus-set-to-take-oath-as-bangladesh-leader-6293657]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:29:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus will today take oath as the leader of the interim Bangladesh government. After landing in the country, Yunus paid tribute to those killed in Bangladesh's deadly protests that toppled Sheikh Hasina's government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus will today take oath as the leader of the interim Bangladesh government. After landing in the country, Yunus paid tribute to those killed in Bangladesh's deadly protests that toppled Sheikh Hasina's government, saying their sacrifices had brought the nation a "second independence".</p>

<p>"Today is a glorious day for us," he told reporters at the airport in Dhaka shortly after returning to the country to lead a caretaker government.</p>

<p>"Bangladesh has created a new victory day. Bangladesh has got a second independence."</p>

<p>Yunus called for the restoration of order after weeks of violence that left at least 455 people dead, calling on citizens to guard each other, including minorities who came under attack.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the Live updates:</strong></h2>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/qrk2shdo_muhammad-yunus_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus was overwhelmingly backed by Bangladesh's student leaders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-south-africa-contestant-pulls-out-of-final-after-citizenship-row-6293475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Miss South Africa Contestant Pulls Out Of Final After Citizenship Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/miss-south-africa-contestant-pulls-out-of-final-after-citizenship-row-6293475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 19:03:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Chidimma Adetshina, a law student, has been the subject of vicious, xenophobic attacks on social media since she was announced as a finalist in July.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Miss South Africa contestant whose Nigerian heritage sparked a national controversy and a government investigation withdrew from the beauty pageant Thursday.</p>

<p>Chidimma Adetshina's announcement that she would not take part in Saturday's final came a day after the Home Affairs ministry accused her mother of fraud and identity theft.</p>

<p>"After much careful consideration, I have made the difficult decision to withdraw myself from the competition for the safety and wellbeing of my family and I," Adetshina, 23, wrote on Instagram.</p>

<p>Adetshina, a law student, has been the subject of vicious, xenophobic attacks on social media since she was announced as a finalist in July, with many -- including cabinet ministers -- questioning her credentials because of her Nigerian descent.</p>

<p>Adetshina has previously told local media she was born in Soweto to a Nigerian father and a South African mother of Mozambican descent.</p>

<p>The ruckus led to an investigation into her citizenship following a request from the pageant's organisers.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, home affairs minister Leon Schreiber said the investigation uncovered "prima facie indications" that Adetshina's mother might have committed fraud and stolen the identity of a South African woman.</p>

<p>The ministry said it was obtaining legal advice on the implications of this on the citizenship of Adetshina, who was an infant at the time of the alleged fraud.</p>

<p>South Africa grants citizenship by birth to anyone born in the country after 1995 to a South African parent or permanent resident.</p>

<p>Adetshina's participation in the pageant stoked anti-foreigner sentiment in the nation, which has witnessed violent, and at times deadly, attacks on immigrants in the past.</p>

<p>Politicians, celebrities and ordinary citizens weighed in on the debate. While many came to her defence, others argued she should be disqualified.</p>

<p>Announcing her decision to quit, Adetshina thanked everyone who "stood beside me right from the start of my Miss South Africa journey".</p>

<p>"I am really grateful for all the love and support I have been shown," she wrote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/gr8tctlg_miss-south-africa-contestant-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chidimma Adetshina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-teen-suspects-motive-for-taylor-swifts-concert-attack-6292829]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explosives, Knives, Teen Suspects: Inside Taylor Swift Concert Attack Plot]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-teen-suspects-motive-for-taylor-swifts-concert-attack-6292829]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:16:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The suspect had recently changed his appearance and had been consuming and sharing Islamist propaganda online, security officials said, adding that he had pledged allegiance to Islamic State but also held sympathies for Al Qaeda.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 19-year-old has been detained in Austria for allegedly plotting to kill people outside a stadium at a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/austrian-police-disrupts-taylor-swift-concert-attack-plot-seizes-chemicals-6291225" target="_blank">Taylor Swift concert</a>, prompting the cancellation of the pop superstar's three shows in Vienna this week.</p>

<p>Two other teenagers have been identified as suspects.</p>

<p>Here is what security officials have said about the three.</p>

<h3><strong>THE 19-YEAR-OLD</strong></h3>

<p>The Austrian national with North Macedonian roots was arrested in the early hours of Wednesday during a police operation at his home in Ternitz, a town near the Hungarian border.</p>

<p>The teen, who had posted a video online confessing to the plot, quit his job on July 25, telling people that he "had big plans", public security chief Franz Ruf told reporters on Thursday.</p>

<p>The suspect had recently changed his appearance and had been consuming and sharing Islamist propaganda online, security officials said, adding that he had pledged allegiance to Islamic State but also held sympathies for Al Qaeda.</p>

<p>A neighbour told Austrian broadcaster Puls24 that the young man kept himself to himself and that he had grown a "Taliban beard".</p>

<p>During a search of his home, law enforcement authorities secured various substances and tools used for building bombs, as well as Islamic State propaganda, 21,000 euros ($23,000) in counterfeit money, machetes, knives and blank ammunition.</p>

<p>The Kurier newspaper, citing sources familiar with the situation, reported that the suspect had stolen the chemicals from his former workplace, a metal processing company also in Ternitz. Officials did not comment on where he got the chemicals from, adding that this was a focus of their investigation.</p>

<h3><strong>THE 17-YEAR-OLD</strong></h3>

<p>After initially being tipped off to a single suspect, Austrian investigators came across the other two, including a 17-year-old Austrian national with Turkish-Croatian roots who was arrested in Vienna on Wednesday afternoon.</p>

<p>He had been acting conspicuously in the area of the Ernst Happel Stadium, where Swift's stadium shows had been due to take place on Thursday, Friday and Saturday.</p>

<p>The 17-year-old had been given a job with a company a few days ago that was providing services at the stadium.</p>

<p>The boy, who also appears to have been radicalised and was already known to authorities, had recently broken up with his girlfriend, Ruf said.</p>

<p>He is still to make a statement to police so his exact role in the plot is unclear, but he had extensive contact with the main suspect, officials said.</p>

<h3><strong>THE 15-YEAR-OLD</strong></h3>

<p>The third and final suspect is an Austrian national with Turkish heritage.</p>

<p>During questioning, the youngster said the main suspect had changed considerably in recent months and had also regularly enquired about devices to ignite explosives, officials said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-11/glh4faoo_taylor-swift-afp_625x300_15_November_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[One teen had posted a video online confessing to the plot telling people that he had "big plans" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decoding-chinese-scholars-decades-long-espionage-operation-in-us-6292703]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How A Chinese Scholar Ran A Spy Ring In US For Decades Before Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/decoding-chinese-scholars-decades-long-espionage-operation-in-us-6292703]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 18:06:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Chinese-American scholar, who projected himself as a pro-democracy activist, has been convicted by a US court of using his reputation to gather information on dissidents and sharing it with the Chinese government.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese-American scholar, who projected himself as a pro-democracy activist, has been convicted by a US court of using his reputation to gather information on dissidents and sharing it with the Chinese government.</p>

<p>A federal jury in New York delivered the verdict on Tuesday, The Guardian reported.</p>

<p>The 75-year-old lived a double life for over a decade at the behest of China's main intelligence agency, the Ministry of State Security, the prosecutors said.</p>

<p>In an opening statement last month, US attorney Ellen Sise said that Wang pretended to be opposed to the Chinese government to "get close to people who were actually opposed to the Chinese government”.</p>

<p>“And then, the defendant betrayed those people, people who trusted him, by reporting information on them to China," Sise noted.<br />
<br />
<strong>'Plot of a spy novel'</strong></p>

<p>Wang was convicted of providing the contact information of prominent dissidents to the intelligence agency in his homeland. He further lied to federal law enforcement officers about the scheme. The jury found him guilty on four counts following the week-long trial in the Brooklyn federal court, Reuters reported.</p>

<p>“The indictment could have been the plot of a spy novel, but the evidence is shockingly real,” Breon Peace, the US attorney for the Eastern District of New York, said in a statement on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“Wang was willing to betray those who respected and trusted him," Peace noted.<br />
<br />
Wang faces up to 25 years in prison, when he is to be sentenced on January 9 next year.<br />
<br />
<strong>Who is Shujun Wang?</strong><br />
<br />
Wang, an American citizen, has been settled in New York since the 1990s after his stint as a visiting university scholar of East Asian studies, The New York Times reported.</p>

<p>To commemorate figures linked to the 1989 Tiananmen Square uprising, he helped found a pro-democracy group in 2006 in the Flushing neighbourhood of Queens.</p>

<p>Hu Yaobang and Zhao Ziyang Memorial Foundation is named for two leaders of the Chinese Communist Party in the 1980s. As per its official website, the group's mission is to promote China's "constitutional transformation.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, prosecutors said that Wang used his position and status among the Chinese community to act as a “covert intelligence asset in his own community,” since at least 2006.</p>

<p>Wang, according to the prosecutors, was ordered to collect information about topics and people the Chinese government deemed undesirable. Later, he passed on this information to his handlers via in-person meetings as well as written correspondence, including “diaries,” describing his interactions with prominent activists</p>

<p>Ellen Sise, in the opening statements, noted that Wang led a "double life".&nbsp;</p>

<p>“He portrayed himself as an academic and a pro-democratic activist... Appearances can be deceiving,” she said.</p>

<p>Wang emigrated to the US in 1994. He was arrested by officials in March 2022.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/s2f5a07o_shujun-wang-_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wang was convicted of providing the contact information of prominent dissidents.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-seeks-15-years-sentence-for-us-russian-ballerina-over-pro-ukraine-donation-6292785]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Seeks 15 Years For US-Russian Ballerina Over Pro-Ukraine Donation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-seeks-15-years-sentence-for-us-russian-ballerina-over-pro-ukraine-donation-6292785]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:40:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russian prosecutors have requested a 15-year prison sentence for a dual US-Russian national charged with "treason" for making a donation to a pro-Ukraine organisation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russian prosecutors have requested a 15-year prison sentence for a dual US-Russian national charged with "treason" for making a donation to a pro-Ukraine organisation.</p>

<p>The FSB security service said in February it had arrested ballerina Ksenia Karelina, who lives in the United States and was visiting family in Russia, accusing her of providing financial assistance to the Ukrainian army.</p>

<p>"The state prosecutor asked the court to sentence Karelina to 15 years in prison," the Sverdlovsk Regional Court in the Urals city of Ekaterinburg said in a statement Thursday.</p>

<p>Her lawyer, Mikhail Mushailov, also confirmed the 15-year request in a post on his Instagram account.</p>

<p>Karelina donated around $50 to a US-based pro-Ukraine charity after Russia launched its full-scale military offensive in 2022, US media reported, citing her family and employer.</p>

<p>Russia's FSB security service accused her of collecting money that was "used to purchase tactical medical supplies, equipment, weapons and ammunition for the Ukrainian armed forces."</p>

<p>"The defendant pleaded guilty," the court said in its statement.</p>

<p>The verdict will be delivered next Thursday.</p>

<p>Russian courts almost always side with the prosecution, and acquittals in treason cases are almost unheard of.</p>

<p>Moscow has launched dozens of criminal cases against Russian citizens it accuses of supporting or collaborating with Kyiv.</p>

<p>Karelina, who is in her early 30s and worked in Los Angeles, is just one of a string of US citizens and dual nationals that have also been targeted.</p>

<p>Last week Russia released three of them -- journalists Evan Gershkovich and Alsu Kurmasheva, as well as ex-marine Paul Whelan -- in the largest East-West prisoner swap since the Cold War.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4ggbm5ho_ksenia-karelina_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Karelina is just one of a string of US citizens and dual nationals that hav been targeted.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-ismail-haniyeh-israel-made-costly-strategic-mistake-by-killing-hamas-chief-iran-6292734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Made Costly "Strategic Mistake" By Killing Hamas Chief: Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-ismail-haniyeh-israel-made-costly-strategic-mistake-by-killing-hamas-chief-iran-6292734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:36:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel committed a costly "strategic mistake" with its killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week, Iran's acting foreign minister told AFP in an interview on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel committed a costly "strategic mistake" with its killing of Hamas political leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran last week, Iran's acting foreign minister told AFP in an interview on Thursday.</p>

<p>"The act that the Zionists carried out in Tehran was a strategic mistake because it will cost them gravely," Ali Bagheri said one day after attending an extraordinary session of the Organisation of Islamic Cooperation (OIC) in the Saudi coastal city of Jeddah.</p>

<p>Although Israel has not commented on Haniyeh's death, Iran has vowed to retaliate, setting the region on edge.</p>

<p>Bagheri accused Israel of wanting "to expand tension, war and conflict to other countries," while asserting it was not in a position to fight Iran.</p>

<p>"The Zionists are in no position to start a war against the Islamic Republic of Iran," he said.</p>

<p>"They neither have the capacity nor the strength."</p>

<p>The meeting on Wednesday of foreign ministers from the 57-member OIC produced a declaration holding Israel "fully responsible" for the "heinous" killing of Haniyeh, who lived in Qatar and was a major player in talks to end the war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The war began with Hamas's October 7 attacks on southern Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,198 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Palestinian militants seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held in Gaza, including 39 the Israeli military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign in Gaza has killed at least 39,699 people, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and militant deaths.</p>

<p>Hamas's Lebanese ally Hezbollah has also pledged to retaliate for Haniyeh's killing and that of its military commander Fuad Shukr in an Israeli strike in Beirut hours earlier.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/v49bimrg_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_31_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-demands-probe-into-us-anti-doping-agency-alleges-double-standard-6292553]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Demands Probe Into US Anti-Doping Agency, Alleges Double Standard]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-demands-probe-into-us-anti-doping-agency-alleges-double-standard-6292553]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:24:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's anti-doping agency on Thursday called for an independent probe into its US counterpart after a media investigation found that American authorities allowed athletes who failed drug tests to continue to compete.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's anti-doping agency on Thursday called for an independent probe into its US counterpart after a media investigation found that American authorities allowed athletes who failed drug tests to continue to compete.</p>

<p>The report by the Reuters news agency on Wednesday said the global and US anti-doping authorities were in disagreement over the American side's tactic of allowing athletes who tested positive for banned substances to avoid prosecution in return for giving undercover information on other drug cheats.</p>

<p>The World Anti-Doping Agency (WADA) said the strategy by the US authority (USADA) was "in direct contravention of the World Anti-Doping Code" and "threatened the integrity of sporting competition".</p>

<p>The China Anti-Doping Agency (CHINADA) said Thursday that it "strongly calls for an independent investigation into USADA's cover-up of serious violations" of the code designed to prevent athletes from taking illicit substances that improve performance.</p>

<p>"USADA's practice... seriously damaged fair competition in sports and the rights and interests of clean athletes, and showed that its anti-doping work lacked transparency," CHINADA said.</p>

<p>It added that the revelations showed the US exercised "double standards" in criticising alleged doping by other countries while "turning a blind eye" to its own issues.</p>

<p>Chinese and American sports authorities have traded barbs since a separate media investigation in April found 23 Chinese swimmers tested positive for a banned substance before the Tokyo Olympics in 2021 but were still allowed to compete.</p>

<p>They were not punished because WADA accepted the argument of Chinese authorities that the positive results were caused by contaminated food.</p>

<p>The disclosures brought widespread criticism of WADA, particularly from the US, which infuriated China by accusing the global governing body of a cover-up.</p>

<p>CHINADA said in a separate statement earlier Thursday that US track and field athletes were plagued by "systemic" doping abuses.</p>

<p>It cited the case of American sprinter Erriyon Knighton, who tested positive for a banned substance in March but was cleared to compete in Paris after an independent arbitrator ruled that the result likely came from contaminated meat.</p>

<p>Knighton has qualified for Thursday's Olympic 200m final in Paris.</p>

<p>CHINADA called for more tests on American track and field athletes, alleging "deep-rooted stains in... US athletics and USADA's repeated disregard for procedures and standards".</p>

<p>CHINADA provided no evidence that American athletes currently at the Games had failed doping tests.</p>

<p>The US tops the Olympics medals table with 27 golds, just ahead of China on 25.</p>

<p>China named 11 of the swimmers implicated in the doping scandal in their Paris Olympics team. China's swimmers finished with 12 medals -- two gold, three silver and seven bronze.</p>

<p>CHINADA said in June that it would "never" agree to a US demand to release details of its investigation into the 23 swimmers.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jqanqi5_olympics_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US tops the Olympics medals table with 27 golds, just ahead of China on 25. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/increasingly-likely-2024-could-be-hottest-on-record-eu-climate-monitor-6292560]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Increasingly Likely" 2024 Could Be Hottest On Record: EU Climate Monitor]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/increasingly-likely-2024-could-be-hottest-on-record-eu-climate-monitor-6292560]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:16:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It is "increasingly likely" 2024 will be the hottest year on record, despite July ending a 13-month streak of monthly temperature records, the EU's climate monitor said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is "increasingly likely" 2024 will be the hottest year on record, despite July ending a 13-month streak of monthly temperature records, the EU's climate monitor said Thursday.</p>

<p>The Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S) said last month was the second warmest on record books going back to 1940, only slightly cooler than July 2023.</p>

<p>Between June 2023 and June 2024, each month eclipsed its own temperature record for the time of year.</p>

<p>"The streak of record-breaking months has come to an end, but only by a whisker," said Samantha Burgess, deputy director of C3S.</p>

<p>Last month the global average temperature was 16.91 degrees Celsius, only 0.04C below July 2023, according to C3S's monthly bulletin.</p>

<p>But "the overall context hasn't changed, our climate continues to warm," said Burgess.</p>

<p>"The devastating effects of climate change started well before 2023 and will continue until global greenhouse gas emissions reach net zero," she said.</p>

<p>From January to July global temperatures were 0.70C above the 1991-2020 average.</p>

<p>This anomaly would need to drop significantly over the rest of this year for 2024 not to be hotter than 2023 -- "making it increasingly likely that 2024 is going to be the warmest year on record", said C3S.</p>

<p><strong>'Too hot to handle'</strong></p>

<p>July 2024 was 1.48C warmer than the estimated average temperatures for the month during the period 1850-1900, before the world started to rapidly burn fossil fuels.</p>

<p>This has translated into punishing heat for hundreds of millions of people.</p>

<p>The Earth experienced its two hottest days on record with global average temperatures at a virtual tie on July 22 and 23 reaching 17.6C, C3S said.</p>

<p>The Mediterranean was gripped by a heatwave scientists said would have been "virtually impossible" without global warming as China and Japan sweated through their hottest July on record.</p>

<p>Record-breaking rainfall pummelled Pakistan, wildfires ravaged western US states and Hurricane Beryl left a trail of destruction as it swept from the Caribbean to the southeast of the United States.</p>

<p>"The end of record-breaking monthly temperatures is not cause for celebration," said Friederike Otto, a climate scientist at London's Imperial College.</p>

<p>Otto described the heat-related deaths of 21 people in a single day in Morocco in July as "a shocking illustration of just how deadly extreme heat can be".</p>

<p>"To stop climate change, we need to stop burning fossil fuels, stop deforestation and replace them with renewable energy. We have all the technology and know-how to do that... We just lack the political will," she said.</p>

<p>Temperatures for the oceans, which absorb 90 percent of the excess heat caused by human activities, were also the second warmest on record for the month of July.</p>

<p>Average sea surface temperatures were 20.88C last month, only 0.01C below July 2023.</p>

<p>This marked the end of a 15-month period of tumbling heat records for the oceans.</p>

<p>However, scientists at C3S noted that "air temperatures over the ocean remained unusually high over many regions" despite a swing from the El Nino weather pattern that helped fuel a spike in global temperatures to its opposite La Nina, which has a cooling effect.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, World Meteorological Organization Secretary-General Celeste Saulo reflected on a year of "widespread, intense and extended heatwaves".</p>

<p>"This is becoming too hot to handle," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/99d98mr8_climate-change_650x400_05_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Between June 2023 and June 2024, each month eclipsed its own temperature record for the time of year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvest-begins-early-in-italys-drought-hit-vineyard-as-35-less-rainfall-6292594]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harvest Begins Early In Italy's Drought-Hit Vineyard With 35% Less Rainfall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/harvest-begins-early-in-italys-drought-hit-vineyard-as-35-less-rainfall-6292594]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:11:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The prestigious Donnafugata vineyards, which span the Italian island from the slopes of Marsala to the mantle of Mount Etna, began their harvest on July 22, an unprecedented two weeks early.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the hills of the Contessa Entellina vineyard in western Sicily, the harvest is already well underway, the grapes ripening earlier than usual because of drought and high temperatures.</p>

<p>The prestigious Donnafugata vineyards, which span the Italian island from the slopes of Marsala to the mantle of Mount Etna, began their harvest on July 22, an unprecedented two weeks early.</p>

<p>At Contessa Entellina, the company's main estate in the province of Agrigento, there has been almost no rain since May.</p>

<p>"Between October and the end of July, there has been 35 percent less rain," said Antonino Santoro, the estate's technical director and oenologist.</p>

<p>In 2022, the harvest had already begun on July 29.</p>

<p>The Sicily of myth is a fertile orchard blessed with rivers of pure water, but the modern day Mediterranean island suffers more and more from global warming.</p>

<p>Since the end of spring, water has stopped flowing, the soil and the springs parched.</p>

<p>Farmers here are used to the naturally arid territory, but they are being tested.</p>

<p>Even citrus fruits and olive trees are suffering from the drought and scorching temperatures which in 2021 set the European record of 48.8 degrees Centigrade (119.8 Fahrenheit).</p>

<h3><strong>Drop by drop</strong></h3>

<p>With 460 hectares of vines and 3.6 million bottles per year across all its territories, the Donnafugata company has the financial resources to adapt.</p>

<p>"Before, irrigation was useful, today it is essential," Santoro said.</p>

<p>Around Contessa Entellina the estate has installed several retention basins which meet around 75 percent of its irrigation needs, the rest covered by public reserves.</p>

<p>During June and July, it irrigates the vines using a micro-sprinkler system, which provides water at a rate of four litres per hour per vine.</p>

<p>"The aim is to optimise water use," said Giuseppe Milano, the estate's head of cultivation.</p>

<p>Irrigation is not cheap, costing between 4,000 and 6,000 euros per hectare per year. The average size of an Italian vineyard is 11 hectares.</p>

<p>At the end of July, the Italian government recognised Sicily was facing "force majeure conditions and exceptional circumstances" due to the drought, according to Sicilian authorities.</p>

<p>This eases some EU rules on agriculture and allows farmers to defer payments and charges, the region said, in response to a year-long drought it said was "one of the most serious in the last 50 years".</p>

<h3><strong>Quantity and quality</strong></h3>

<p>Donnafugata takes its name from the fictional town in "The Leopard", the novel by Giuseppe Tomasi di Lampedusa set in the area during the unification of Italy in the late 19th century.</p>

<p>Back then, the grape harvest did not begin before September.</p>

<p>As well as irrigation, Contessa Entellina adapts by growing its vines taller, up to 1.5 metres, so the upper foliage serves as a canopy to screen the grapes from the sun.</p>

<p>There is no such shade for the grape pickers, who use pruning shears to harvest the grapes under a blazing sun.</p>

<p>They started at dawn, and by 10:00am it is already 29 degrees Celsius.</p>

<p>For the first time, regional authorities have banned working in the fields during the hottest hours of the day, between 12:30 pm. and 4:00 pm.</p>

<p>They are now picking the Merlot grapes for red wine. The white Chardonnay ones were picked in July.</p>

<p>Depending on the varieties and the terroir, the grape harvest in Sicily this year will be spread out over three or four months -- "a unique situation in Europe", according to national agricultural association Coldiretti.</p>

<p>Contessa Entellina's harvest will be smaller than last year, with smaller grapes.</p>

<p>But Milano insisted that what it lacks in quantity is made up in quality.</p>

<p>Today, Donnafugata is involved in research projects to help prepare the vines for the evolving conditions.</p>

<p>"I am optimistic," said Santoro. "The vine adapts better than other crops."</p>

<p>It is not just heat that is affecting the harvest.</p>

<p>Last year, a combination of frost and floods in the north and mildew in the south cost the Italian wine industry a quarter of its production -- allowing France to take the title of the world's leading wine producer.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/b38s9ipg_italy-sicily-farms_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For the first time regional authorities have banned working on fields during the hottest hours of the day]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-isis-supporter-arrested-for-planning-attack-at-taylor-swift-concert-6292226]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Teen ISIS Supporter Arrested For Planning Attack At Taylor Swift Concert]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/teen-isis-supporter-arrested-for-planning-attack-at-taylor-swift-concert-6292226]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:06:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 19-year-old IS sympathiser arrested in Austria was planning a suicide attack at a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna designed to kill many people, the intelligence agency said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 19-year-old Islamic State sympathiser planned a suicide attack at a Taylor Swift concert in Vienna designed to kill many people, the country's intelligence agency said on Thursday.</p>

<p>Austrian authorities detained two suspects Wednesdsay for allegedly plotting to attack this week's Vienna concerts by the US star, which organisers cancelled at the last minute.</p>

<p>The 19-year-old main suspect had confessed, saying he "intended to carry out an attack using explosives and knives," domestic intelligence agency (DSN) head Omar Haijawi-Pirchner told a news conference.</p>

<p>"His aim was to kill himself and a large number of people during the concert... either today or tomorrow," he added. The concerts were to run from Thursday to Saturday.</p>

<p>The second suspect, a 17-year-old Austrian, was employed at a facility management company which would have "provided services" at the Ernst Happel Stadium where Swift was to perform, said Haijawi-Pirchner.</p>

<p>The younger suspect, who has so far refused to talk to authorities, was "in the area" of the stadium where he was detained, said Haijawi-Pirchner.</p>

<p>According to Interior Minister Gerhard Karner, a "tragedy was averted". "The situation was very serious", he added, particularly in view of a recent attack at a Taylor Swift themed event in Britain, where three girls were killed in Great Britain.</p>

<p>Explosives and detonators were found in a search of the main suspect's apartment, authorities said.</p>

<p><strong>Disappointed Swifties</strong></p>

<p>Austria's top security chief Franz Ruf told reporters the two suspects had recently made changes in their private lives,</p>

<p>The main suspect, an Austrian with Northern Macedonian roots, had changed "his appearance and adapted it to Islamic State propaganda", while the second, an Austrian of Turkish or Croatian origin, had broken up with his girlfriend, he said.</p>

<p>Ruf earlier confirmed that authorities had received information "from foreign partners" which led to the arrests, but he declined to specify.</p>

<p>Police had promised to ramp up security for the concerts while having minimised any concrete danger, but organisers still cancelled Swift's shows. About 65,000 people were expected at each show.</p>

<p>Swift did not immediately comment on the decision to cancel the Vienna shows but after the British attack said she was "completely in shock". Three girls were killed and five people seriously wounded in the mass stabbing at a dance class in Southport inspired by the American singer.</p>

<p>According to Ruf, police "did everything humanly possible to ensure" that the Vienna concerts "could go ahead", but the cancellation decision was taken by the organisers.</p>

<p>The 34-year-old star was to bring her record-breaking "Eras" Tour, which began its European leg in Paris in May, to Vienna on Thursday.</p>

<p>Following France, the tour stopped in Sweden, Portugal, Spain, the United Kingdom, Ireland, the Netherlands, Switzerland, Italy, Germany and Poland.</p>

<p>In Austria, more than 170,000 spectators were expected to attend the shows, bringing in some 100 million euros, according to estimates by the news agency APA.</p>

<p>By the end of the year, "Eras" had already become the first tour to sell more than $1 billion in tickets and it is on track to more than double that by the time it concludes in Vancouver in December.</p>

<p>Austria experienced its first deadly jihadist attack in November 2020, when a convicted IS sympathiser went on a shooting rampage in Vienna, killing four people and wounding 23 before police shot him dead.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ppmudgjg_taylor-swift_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Vienna leg of the Taylor Swift concert has been cancelled.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-future-clouded-with-uncertainity-4-possible-scenarios-6292507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Future Clouded With Uncertainity: 4 Possible Scenarios]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-future-clouded-with-uncertainity-4-possible-scenarios-6292507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 17:00:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Protests and bloodshed have toppled Sheikh Hasina's regime, but the way forward is far from certain. Here are four possible scenarios.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Protests and bloodshed have toppled Sheikh Hasina's regime, but the way forward is far from certain. Here are four possible scenarios.</p>

<p>The uprising in Bangladesh has been a political earthquake. Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, in power for the last 15 years, has fled, and leaders of the ruling Awami League are in hiding or have also absconded.</p>

<p>Economist and Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus was picked by Bangladesh President Mohammed Shahabuddin to lead a new interim government. For the moment, a feeling of hope and elation has swept across much of the country.</p>

<p>But as with an earthquake, once the dust has settled, the foundations will remain largely the same as before.</p>

<p>To gauge where the country might move in the immediate and not-so-immediate future, there are a few fundamentals that need to be recognised.</p>

<p>The people who rose up consisted of students and some teachers, large groups of other young people, urban poor and political opposition groups. They represented widespread sentiments.</p>

<p>Dictatorial, violent and smug, Sheikh Hasina's regime was no longer able to deliver on its promise of economic development and criticism of her gross human rights violations became increasingly public and bold.</p>

<p>The popularity of the protests against Sheikh Hasina should not, however, obscure the fact that "the people" are not of one mind. The protests were driven by frustration and anger, not by any explicit alternative political vision.</p>

<p>There is also no formal organisation behind the uprising. It was an extremely powerful and driven movement, which may prove to be too exhausting to hold up in the long term.</p>

<p>All of this did happen suddenly, but in another sense it was building for a long time.</p>

<p>The country has seen several popular protest movements over the last decade - Shahbagh, Hefazat, road safety, no VAT on education, and the quota movement in 2018.</p>

<p>In addition, the low turnout in elections, low tax compliance and various other forms of foot-dragging and reluctance indicated that Sheikh Hasina's regime lacked widespread legitimacy.</p>

<p>Surveys have shown that an overwhelming majority of Bangladeshis want democracy, human rights and to be able to vote for their representatives - and to criticise them when called for. These are fundamental facts of the country.</p>

<p><strong>Who's who</strong></p>

<p>Politically, the Awami League is wounded but still alive.The opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party is a resilient organisation that has survived 18 years in oblivion and is now likely to win overwhelmingly in any free and fair election.</p>

<p>Similarly, because the centre ground of politics is still divided between BNP and the Awami League, there is little chance the Awami League will somehow just go away. Though its autocratic leader may have abandoned them, the party remains a network of people who will not cease to seek power.</p>

<p>But there is one big difference between the two parties - leadership.</p>

<p>BNP's exiled leader Tareque Rahman is still the legitimate heir and boss of the party, oddly reminiscent of 16th-century Mughal Emperor Humayun, who retained his claim to the throne during 15 years of exile.</p>

<p>The Awami League, on the other hand, has no apparent successor to Sheikh Hasina, who actively prevented any heir from emerging. It will take time for the party to rebuild.</p>

<p>There is one last (and perhaps most important) fundamental: all the other political forces are still there. First, Jamaat, Hefazat, the leftists and the voices of civil society. Although they all seek power and some are radical, few of them are strong. But they may provide a plank for Awami League members to abandon ship.</p>

<p>And there are the business leaders, top brass officials, military officers and judges - many of whom were appointed by Sheikh Hasina or benefitted from her regime. All will have interests to protect and changes in mind, but moderate ones.</p>

<p>If there is any lesson to be had from similar popular mobilisations in Sri Lanka, Southeast Asia or the Middle East, it is that those entrenched forces may prove to be much stronger and durable than street mobilisations, however much the demand persists for fundamental reform.</p>

<p><strong>Four future scenarios</strong></p>

<p>First is that sufficient power has been generated by the uprising for Yunus to ensure comprehensive reforms.</p>

<p>This would include the establishment of constitutional guarantees for free and fair elections. The first election will possibly be held in the coming months - under the watchful eyes of the military, a mobilised populace and civil society, as well as foreign allies.</p>

<p>The challenge is to ensure that the government that follows will not re-enact the Sheikh Hasina regime and prevent rivals from mounting an effective organisation and campaign.</p>

<p>In effect, the country will need a new caretaker government, as BNP and the opposition has demanded. This will likely benefit a reconstituted Awami League in the long run and be their best bet.</p>

<p>A second scenario is that Yunus proves to be politically naive and the power generated by the popular uprising dampens. Then the stage would be set for the seasoned warhorses of Bangladeshi politics and opportunistic generals and officials to run the show.</p>

<p>A third scenario is that there is no agreement on basic issues, the economy suffers, protests erupt in the streets and eventually Yunus is driven to resign. The generals would then take over for a while before they quickly organise an election, negotiate an agreement and effectively hand power to Rahman and BNP.</p>

<p>A final scenario is that the students form a political party and bring people from both BNP and Awami League and emerge as a potent political force by disrupting Bangladesh's traditional two-party structure.</p>

<p>The odds are perhaps stacked against them, but this would bode well for a long-lasting democratic transition for Bangladesh.</p>

<p><em>Arild Engelsen Ruud is professor of South Asia studies at the Department of Culture Studies and Oriental Languages, University of Oslo.</em></p>

<p><em>Dr Mubashar Hasan is a postdoctoral research fellow at the Department of Culture Studies and Oriental Languages, University of Oslo. His research was funded by the Norwegian Research Council.</em></p>

<p>Originally published under Creative Commons by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://newshub.360info.org/wire?item=4309e1df-4677-4b09-a5d2-42e0358a77d7">360info</a>.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/d3t8m64g_bangladesh-protests-reuters_625x300_07_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh unrest did happen suddenly, but in another sense it was building for a long time. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/false-paraguayan-swimmer-luana-alonso-on-being-kicked-out-of-paris-olympics-athletes-village-6292401]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["False": Paraguayan Swimmer On Being "Kicked Out" Of Athlete's Village]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/false-paraguayan-swimmer-luana-alonso-on-being-kicked-out-of-paris-olympics-athletes-village-6292401]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:44:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Paraguayan swimmer Luana Alonso has dismissed reports that she was asked to leave the Paris Olympic'sathletes' village for allegedly creating an "inappropriate" environment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paraguayan swimmer <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luana-alonso-swimmer-kicked-out-of-olympic-village-for-inappropriate-conduct-6290596">Luana Alonso</a> has dismissed reports that she was asked to leave the Paris Olympic's&nbsp;athletes' village for allegedly creating an "inappropriate" environment. The 20-year-old stated that the claims against her were untrue. "I just wanted to clarify that I was never kicked out or expelled from anywhere, please stop spreading false information. I don't want to make any statement but I'm not going to let lies affect me either," she said in a <a href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/sport/29688660/olympics-2024-luana-santos-kicked-out-athlete-village-behaviour/">statement</a> on Monday.</p>

<p>Ms Alonso reportedly left the&nbsp;athletes' village&nbsp;to visit Disneyland. Paraguayan Olympic Committee boss Larissa Schaerer said that her presence was "creating an inappropriate atmosphere within the Team."</p>

<p>As per reports, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-luana-alonso-swimmer-kicked-out-of-olympic-village-for-inappropriate-conduct-6290596">Luana Alonso</a> missed out on qualification for the women's 100m butterfly semi-final by just 0.24 seconds at the Paris Olympics 2024. After failing to qualify for the event, she announced her retirement. Following her lacklustre show, Ms Alonso said, "It was my last race. I am retiring from swimming."</p>

<p>Earlier, during a live stream on social media ahead of the Paris Olympics, she triggered a controversy having allegedly said, "I want to represent the United States more".</p>

<p>Born on September 19, 2004, Luana Alonso is the national record holder for Paraguay in the 100m butterfly event. A student at the Southern Methodist University in the US Dallas, Alonso shot to fame having represented her country at the Tokyo Olympics in 2021.</p>

<p>She competed in the last Olympics at the age of 17. Despite the fanfare, Ms Alonso could not qualify for the semifinals back then having registered a 28th-place finish in Tokyo.</p>

<p>The Paraguayan swimmer also competed in various other significant tournaments such as the Youth Olympic Games, the South American Games and the World Championships.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/cnkjqbb8_paraguay-olympic-swimmer-luana-alonso-instagram_625x300_08_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Luana Alonso competed in the last Olympics at the age of 17 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-good-shes-gone-but-indian-american-lawmaker-on-sheikh-hasina-6292313]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["It's Good She's Gone, But...": Indian-American Lawmaker On Sheikh Hasina]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/its-good-shes-gone-but-indian-american-lawmaker-on-sheikh-hasina-6292313]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 08 Aug 2024 16:36:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-American Congressman Ro Khanna today said former Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina's ouster from her country was "good" but the "violence now targeting Hindus was wrong".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-American Congressman Ro Khanna today said former Bangladesh PM Sheikh Hasina's ouster from her country was "good" but the "violence now targeting Hindus was wrong".</p>

<p>"Bangladeshi students had just human rights concerns against PM Hasina. It's good she is gone. But the violence now targeting Hindus is wrong. PM Yunus must uphold the rule of law &amp; prevent the targeting of temples or people of any political party or faith from violence," Ro Khanna wrote in a post on X today.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Bangladeshi students had just human rights concerns against PM Hasina. It's good she is gone. But the violence now targeting Hindus is wrong. PM Yunus must uphold the rule of law &amp; prevent the targeting of temples or people of any political party or faith from violence.</p>
— Ro Khanna (@RoKhanna) <a href="https://twitter.com/RoKhanna/status/1821423062484504764?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 8, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, 76, was forced to resign as Prime Minister on Monday after a month-long anti-government protest over a government jobs quota killed over 400.</p>

<p>Ms Hasina left Bangladesh capital Dhaka in a military aircraft for India post her resignation. Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday said the government is giving time to Sheikh Hasina to "recover" and let them know about her next move.</p>

<p>Sources had earlier mentioned she wanted to leave for London and claim asylum, but this claim was dismissed by her son Sajeeb Wazed.</p>

<p>The Bangladesh Army formed an interim government in the country on Thursday, with Nobel Laureate Muhammad Yunus as its chief advisor.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/rc8rot8o_ro-khanna_625x300_09_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ro Khanna is an Indian-American Congressman]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>