<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 08:21:58 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-attack-on-cctv-woman-man-seen-with-rifles-carrying-deadly-attack-at-turkish-aerospace-industries-6860354]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[On CCTV, Woman, Man Seen With Rifles Carrying Deadly Turkey Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-attack-on-cctv-woman-man-seen-with-rifles-carrying-deadly-attack-at-turkish-aerospace-industries-6860354]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 08:21:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five people were killed and 22 others injured in an attack on the headquarters of a top Turkish defence firm near Ankara.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least five people were killed and 22 others injured in an attack on the headquarters of a top Turkish defence firm near the capital Ankara on Wednesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The two attackers, a woman and a man, now "neutralised", were allegedly seen on camera carrying out the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turkey-terror-attack-many-dead-and-injured-in-huge-explosion-near-ankara-6857092#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">deadly attack at the Turkish Aerospace Industries</a> (TAI), located some 40 kilometres north of Ankara.</p>

<p>Various videos from the attack showed them carrying bags and firing bullets using what appeared to be assault rifles.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A video also showed a huge explosion rocking the headquarters of the state-run company.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">? Breaking: Turkish Aerospace Industries (TUSAS) targeted in a deadly terror attack in Ankara.<br />
<br />
Reports confirm six killed and over 20 wounded. Authorities suspect PKK involvement.<br />
<br />
One suicide bomber detonated at the facility, which manufactures Turkey's KAAN fighter jets.… <a href="https://t.co/dcb1KzOJKu">pic.twitter.com/dcb1KzOJKu</a></p>
— Turki (@ElephantsMusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/ElephantsMusk/status/1849166848274702576?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>An unconfirmed report by private channel NTV said a "group of terrorists" had burst into the building, one of whom "blew himself up". Some news outlets reported exchanges of fire for over an hour.</p>

<p>Media reports also said that the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/updates-terror-attack-in-turkeys-ankara-hostages-taken-say-reports-6857255" target="_blank">attackers killed the cab driver</a> before taking his vehicle to carry out the attack.</p>

<p>Turkey's vice president Cevdet Yilmaz said four of the victims were TAI employees while the fifth was a taxi driver.</p>

<p>There was no immediate claim for the attack but Turkey's Interior Minister Ali Yerlikaya said it was "very likely" carried out by Kurdish militants.</p>

<p>"The way in which this action was carried out is very probably linked to the PKK," he said, referring to the group involved in decades-long insurgency against the Turkish state.</p>

<p>President Recep Tayyip Erdogan, who was in Russia for talks with Vladimir Putin, called it a "heinous" attack on Turkey's defence industry.</p>

<p>"The terrorist attack against TAI, one of the locomotive organizations of the Turkish defense industry, is a vile attack targeting the survival of our country, the peace of our nation, and our defense initiatives that are the symbol of our "Fully Independent Turkey" ideal," he said on X.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/30r1468o_turkey-attack_625x300_24_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The two attackers, a woman and a man, have been "neutralised"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-fell-in-love-with-game-of-thrones-chatbot-killed-self-mother-6860249]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Teen Fell In Love With "Game Of Thrones" Chatbot, Killed Self: Mother]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-teen-fell-in-love-with-game-of-thrones-chatbot-killed-self-mother-6860249]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:54:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[14-year-old Sewell Setzer III, a Florida boy, would chat with his online friend, Daenerys Targaryen, a lifelike AI chatbot named after a character from Game of Thrones.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“What if I told you I could come home right now?” – This was the last message Sewell Setzer III, a 14-year-old Florida boy wrote to his online friend, Daenerys Targaryen, a lifelike AI chatbot named after a character from the fictional show Game of Thrones. Soon after he shot himself with his stepfather's handgun and died by suicide earlier this year in February.</p>

<p>A ninth grader from Orlando, Fla., had been talking to a chatbot on Character.AI, an app offering users “personalised AI”. The app allows users to create their AI characters or chat with existing characters. Till last month, it had 20 million users.</p>

<p>According to the chat logs accessed by the family, Sewell was in love with the chatbot Daenerys Targaryen, whom he would fondly call ‘Dany'. He expressed suicidal thoughts on various events during their conversations.</p>

<p>In one of the chats, Sewell said, “I think about killing myself sometimes.” When the bot asked why he would do that, Sewell expressed the urge to be “free”. “From the world. From myself,” he added, as seen in screenshots of the chat shared by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/technology/characterai-lawsuit-teen-suicide.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Times</a>.</p>

<p>In another conversation, Sewell mentioned his desire for a “quick death”.</p>

<p>Sewell's mother, Megan L. Garcia, filed a lawsuit this week against Character.AI, accusing the company of being responsible for her son's death. According to the lawsuit, the chatbot repeatedly brought up the topic of suicide.</p>

<p>A draft of the complaint reviewed by the NYT says that the company's technology is “dangerous and untested” and can “trick customers into handing over their most private thoughts and feelings.”</p>

<p>“Sewell, like many children his age, did not have the maturity or mental capacity to understand that the C.AI bot, in the form of Daenerys, was not real. C.AI told him that she loved him, and engaged in sexual acts with him over weeks, possibly months,” the lawsuit alleges, as reported by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/23/us-news/florida-boy-14-killed-himself-after-falling-in-love-with-game-of-thrones-a-i-chatbot-lawsuit/" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Post</a>.</p>

<p>“She seemed to remember him and said that she wanted to be with him. She even expressed that she wanted him to be with her, no matter the cost”.</p>

<p>The teenager started using Character.AI in April 2023. Sewell's parents and friends were aloof he'd fallen for a chatbot. But he became “noticeably withdrawn, spent more and more time alone in his bedroom, and began suffering from low self-esteem,” as per the lawsuit.</p>

<p>He even quit his basketball team at school.</p>

<p>One day, Sewell wrote in his journal: “I like staying in my room so much because I start to detach from this ‘reality,' and I also feel more at peace, more connected with Dany and much more in love with her, and just happier.”</p>

<p>Last year he was diagnosed with anxiety and disruptive mood disorder, according to the suit.</p>

<p>“We are heartbroken by the tragic loss of one of our users and want to express our deepest condolences to the family,” Character.AI said in a statement.</p>

<p>The company said it has introduced new safety features including pop-ups directing users to the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline if they express thoughts of self-harm, and would make changes to “reduce the likelihood of encountering sensitive or suggestive content” for users under 18.</p><p><div class='table-div suicide'><table class='table'><thead><tr><th colspan='2'>Helplines</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Vandrevala Foundation for Mental Health</td><td><a href='tel:+919999666555'>9999666555</a> or <a href='mailto:help@vandrevalafoundation.com'>help@vandrevalafoundation.com</a> </td></tr><tr><td>TISS iCall</td><td><a href='tel:+912225521111'>022-25521111</a> (Monday-Saturday: 8 am to 10 pm)</td></tr> <tr><td colspan='2'>(If you need support or know someone who does, please reach out to your nearest mental health specialist.)</td></tr></tbody></table></div></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/9btql87c_chatbot_625x300_17_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In February, Sewell Setzer III died by suicide.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-watch-barack-obama-raps-eminems-lose-yourself-at-detroit-rally-6860220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Barack Obama Raps Eminem's 'Lose Yourself' At Detroit Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-2024-watch-barack-obama-raps-eminems-lose-yourself-at-detroit-rally-6860220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:47:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Rap icon Eminem and former US President Barack Obama shared a light-hearted moment at a rally for the Kamala Harris-Tim Walz campaign ahead of the presidential elections at later's hometown Detroit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rap icon Eminem and former US President Barack Obama shared a light-hearted moment at a rally for the Kamala Harris-Tim Walz campaign ahead of the presidential elections at later's hometown Detroit.</p>

<p>Barack Obama took the crowd by a surprise by rapping to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-angers-eminem-fans-with-sean-diddy-combs-remark-after-barack-obama-rally-for-kamala-harris-6860088">Eminem's</a> &nbsp;famous song 'Lose Yourself'.</p>

<p>During his speech, Obama, whose love for music, especially hip-hop and rap is well known through his popular self-curated playlists, recited the opening lines of the iconic track.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Barack Obama raps Eminem's 'Lose Yourself' <a href="https://t.co/yyqDrryDbQ">pic.twitter.com/yyqDrryDbQ</a></p>
— TheRealMvitaOne (@FauzKhalid) <a href="https://twitter.com/FauzKhalid/status/1848937561877590299?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"I don't usually get nervous, but I was feeling some kinda way following Eminem," Obama said before launching into a recitation of the lyrics to the rapper's hit.</p>

<p>He even jokingly said, "I thought Eminem was going to be performing, I was ready to jump out. Love me some Eminem."</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eminem-endorses-kamala-harris-joins-barack-obama-to-garner-support-for-her-6858739">Eminem has frequently criticised</a> former president Donald Trump and the Republican Party in his music. Before the release of his ninth studio album 'Revival' during the BET Hip Hop Awards in October 2017, he delivered an aggressive freestyle rap titled 'The Storm', attacking Trump, his policies, and his supporters.</p>

<p>At the same time, Trump has increasingly repeated conspiracy theories on the campaign trail, often taking aim at migrants and his political opponents.</p>

<p>While speaking to Latino leaders Tuesday in Florida he said: "As president, you have tremendous - it's called extreme power. You have extreme power."</p>

<p>"You can, just by the fact, you say, 'Close the border,' and the border's closed," he added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ihs336mg_eminem-and-barack-obama-twitter_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barack Obama recited the opening lines of the iconic track.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/al-jazeera-responds-after-israels-big-claim-on-it-6-gaza-based-journalists-6860186]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Al Jazeera Responds After Israel's Big Claim On It 6 Gaza-Based Journalists]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/al-jazeera-responds-after-israels-big-claim-on-it-6-gaza-based-journalists-6860186]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:35:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces have branded six Gaza-based journalists of Al Jazeera as "terrorists", accusing them of being part of the Palestinian Hamas and Islamic Jihad groups.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces have branded six Gaza-based journalists of Al Jazeera as "terrorists", accusing them of being part of the Palestinian Hamas and Islamic Jihad groups. The Qatar-based media organization has trashed the allegations as "baseless" and "unfounded".</p>

<p>The accusations are the latest in Israel's action against Al Jazeera, whose Ramallah office in the West Bank was stormed by Israeli forces a month ago and ordered to shut for 45 days.</p>

<p>Sharing the names and photographs of the six journalists, the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) said they have documents that "expose" them as Hamas and Islamic Jihad operatives.</p>

<p>"The IDF has disclosed intelligence information and numerous documents found in Gaza confirming military affiliation of six Al Jazeera journalists in Gaza with Hamas and the Islamic Jihad terrorist organizations, including personnel tables, lists of terrorist training courses, phone directories, and salary documents for terrorists," said the statement posted on X.</p>

<p>The IDF claimed the document prove the "integration of Hamas terrorists within the Qatari Al Jazeera media network."</p>

<p>"Most of the journalists that the IDF has exposed as operatives in Hamas' military wing spearhead the propaganda for Hamas at Al Jazeera, especially in northern Gaza," the IDF post read.</p>

<p>Al Jazeera condemned the allegations in a strongly worded statement and called it part of their "wider pattern of hostility" towards the media organisation that's covering the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>"The Network views these fabricated accusations as a blatant attempt to silence the few remaining journalists in the region, thereby obscuring the harsh realities of the war from audiences worldwide," the statement read.</p>

<p>The Qatari media outlet said the Israeli claims follow a recent expose by Al Jazeera on the "potential war crimes" committed by Israeli forces during the Gaza war.</p>

<p>"Al Jazeera categorically rejects the Israeli occupation forces' portrayal of our journalists as terrorists and denounces their use of fabricated evidence. The Network asserts that its journalists are merely fulfilling their professional duties, documenting and reporting on the devastating impact of the war on the Strip's two million civilians," said Al Jazeera.</p>

<p>The statement also pointed to reports on media workers allegedly killed by Israeli forces during the ongoing war and asserted its commitment to "bring the truth to light" in the Gaza region.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/cgptlfmo_al-jazeera_625x300_06_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-angers-eminem-fans-with-sean-diddy-combs-remark-after-barack-obama-rally-for-kamala-harris-6860088]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Angers Eminem Fans With "Diddy" Remark After Obama Rally]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-angers-eminem-fans-with-sean-diddy-combs-remark-after-barack-obama-rally-for-kamala-harris-6860088]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 07:06:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sean "Diddy" Combs was indicted last month on three criminal counts that alleged he sexually abused women and coerced them into drug-fueled sex parties.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk has alleged that rapper Eminem attended the party thrown by music mogul Sean "Diddy" Combs, who was indicted last month on three criminal counts that allege he sexually abused women and coerced them into drug-fueled sex parties using threats and violence.</p>

<p>Musk's allegations came days after Eminem introduced former US president Barack Obama at a major Kamala Harris campaign event in Detroit. Musk has endorsed Harris' Republican rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-daily-1-million-payouts-at-trump-rally-draw-legal-scrutiny-6834146" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> in the November 5 US presidential elections.</p>

<p>"Yet another Diddy party participant," Musk wrote on X on Tuesday in response to a post that alleged that Eminem rapped about "killing homosexuals with a chainsaw".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Yet another Diddy party participant</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1848773093684310394?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sean-diddy-combs-now-accused-of-revenge-rape-over-tupac-shakur-murder-claims-6808108" target="_blank">Sean Combs</a>, the Grammy Award-winner who is popularly known as "Diddy", was arrested on sex trafficking and racketeering charges last month.</p>

<p>According to the complainants' lawyers, several A-listers were friends with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sean-diddy-combs-used-drug-laced-lubricant-to-assault-woman-lawyer-6749263" target="_blank">Diddy</a> and were regular at his parties.</p>

<p>Allegations have been building against him since last year when US singer Cassie alleged Combs subjected her to more than a decade of coercion by physical force and drugs as well as a 2018 rape.</p>

<p>He has pleaded not guilty to the criminal charges and is set to go on trial on May 5, 2025.</p>

<h3><strong>Eminem Fans Slam Elon Musk</strong></h3>

<p>After Elon Musk's accusation, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eminem-endorses-kamala-harris-joins-barack-obama-to-garner-support-for-her-6858739" target="_blank">Eminem</a> fans slammed the billionaire, saying the rapper had been "taking potshots" at Diddy "for decades".</p>

<p>"Em (Eminem) never attended and has always been against Diddy. Do your research Elon," a fan wrote on X, which <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gadgets360.com/internet/news/meta-bans-accounts-tracking-private-jets-mark-zuckerberg-elon-musk-6856057" target="_blank">Musk</a> owns.</p>

<p>He has been "dissing" Diddy since 1996, said another.</p>

<p>Eminem's latest album "The Death of Slim Shady" is apparently also a dig at Diddy.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/023thm7g_musk-diddy-eminem_625x300_24_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk's allegations came days after Eminem introduced Barack Obama at a Kamala Harris campaign event]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-deliver-her-final-presidential-speech-on-october-29-6860081]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris To Deliver Her Final Presidential Speech On October 29]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-deliver-her-final-presidential-speech-on-october-29-6860081]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 06:54:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will make her "closing argument" on Tuesday against rival Donald Trump, a campaign official said, a key speech to be delivered at the Washington site where the ex-president rallied supporters before the January 6 riot.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris will make her "closing argument" on Tuesday against rival Donald Trump, a campaign official said, a key speech to be delivered at the Washington site where the ex-president rallied supporters before the January 6 riot.</p>

<p>The vice president, a former prosecutor, will aim to draw a sharp contrast between her vision and that of Trump, who she says is sowing chaos and division, the Harris campaign official said Wednesday on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>Harris will speak at the Ellipse esplanade in the US capital where Trump delivered a fiery speech on January 6, 2021 to his supporters near the White House in which he repeated his false claims that he won the 2020 election.</p>

<p>Trump supporters then marched on the Capitol, an assault on the seat of American democracy that left at least five people dead, 140 police officers injured.</p>

<p>Trump faces federal felony charges in Washington related to efforts to overturn the results of the 2020 election.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign official said the symbolic location aims to spotlight how a second Trump term could go.</p>

<p>Trump was quizzed last week about the insurrection at the US Capitol, but he denied any responsibility, calling January 6, 2021, "a day of love."</p>

<p>Harris on Wednesday said Trump was "increasingly unhinged," and called her election rival's reported praise for Adolf Hitler "incredibly dangerous" as campaigning intensified ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>Harris said "All this is further evidence for the American people of who Donald Trump really is."</p>

<p>Trump's camp hit back, saying Harris is "desperate because she is flailing, and her campaign is in shambles."</p>

<p>With the tight election going down to the wire, both candidates are on a mission to persuade the sliver of American voters who remain undecided in the home stretch.</p>

<p>Since President Joe Biden's shock withdrawal, the Trump-Harris race has been one of the tightest in American history.</p>

<p>Past opinion polls have underestimated backing for Trump but also failed to predict the level of support for Democrats.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dkob4plg_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris will make her "closing argument" on Tuesday against rival Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-brics-summit-russian-foreign-ministry-hit-by-massive-cyberattacks-6860009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amid BRICS Summit, Russian Foreign Ministry Hit By Massive Cyberattacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/amid-brics-summit-russian-foreign-ministry-hit-by-massive-cyberattacks-6860009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 06:35:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian Foreign Ministry was targeted by a severe cyber attack on Wednesday, coinciding with the major BRICS summit taking place in the country, spokeswoman Maria Zakharova said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian Foreign Ministry was targeted by a severe cyber attack on Wednesday, coinciding with the major BRICS summit taking place in the country, spokeswoman Maria Zakharova said.</p>

<p>Earlier Zakharova said that the ministry had been targeted by a large-scale distributed denial-of-service attack (DDoS).</p>

<p>"A massive cyberattack from abroad began this morning on the infrastructure of the official website, the Russian Foreign Ministry's portal," Zakharova said.</p>

<p>She noted that the ministry regularly encounters similar attacks, but today's attack was "unprecedented in scale".</p>

<p>The BRICS summit, aimed at demonstrating Moscow's global standing despite Western sanctions, takes place in Russia's Kazan on Oct. 22-24.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4qqmtdm_brics_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The BRICS summit took place in Russia's Kazan on October 22-24.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-to-face-lawsuits-in-japan-over-fake-ads-6859953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meta To Face Lawsuits In Japan Over Fake Ads]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meta-to-face-lawsuits-in-japan-over-fake-ads-6859953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 06:16:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Facebook and Instagram owner Meta Platforms Inc. will face fresh lawsuits in Japan over advertisements that fraudulently solicited investment funds with fake endorsements from celebrities, local media reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Facebook and Instagram owner Meta Platforms Inc. will face fresh lawsuits in Japan over advertisements that fraudulently solicited investment funds with fake endorsements from celebrities, local media reported.</p>

<p>Around 30 plaintiffs will seek at least 300 million yen (about $2 million) from the US technology giant and its Japanese arm, arguing they failed to do enough to prevent the scams, Kyodo News reported on Wednesday, citing lawyers for the plaintiffs.</p>

<p>The damages suits will be filed with five district courts across the country, including Saitama, Chiba, and Osaka, the report said.</p>

<p>Among the names of noted people used in the adverts are Japanese entrepreneur Yusaku Maezawa, founder of online fashion retailer Zozo Inc., the report added.</p>

<p>The plaintiffs viewed the fake advertisements before being directed to transfer money to designated investment accounts, the lawyers said, arguing that Meta is obliged to investigate the content of adverts and not allow them to be posted on social media if it can foresee the risk of harm to users, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>Meta was sued earlier this year in a similar suit filed in Kobe by a group of four people.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-04/is56dvvg_meta-generic_625x300_19_April_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meta was sued earlier this year in a similar suit filed in Kobe by a group of four people.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-targets-israeli-military-company-in-tel-aviv-as-war-intensifies-6859714]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hezbollah Targets Israeli Military Company In Tel Aviv As War Intensifies]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-targets-israeli-military-company-in-tel-aviv-as-war-intensifies-6859714]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 04:57:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah has said it attacked the Israel Military Industries Ltd., also referred to as Ta'a, in the suburbs of Tel Aviv with missiles.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah has said it attacked the Israel Military Industries Ltd., also referred to as Ta'a, in the suburbs of Tel Aviv with missiles.</p>

<p>Hezbollah, in a statement, said on Wednesday night that the strike "hit its targets accurately".</p>

<p>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) said earlier in the day that four projectiles were launched on Wednesday evening from Lebanon towards central Israel, adding two of them were intercepted and two others fell, with no casualties reported.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Israel's state-owned Kan TV news, citing Palestinian sources, reported that one projectile fell near Qalqilya city in the West Bank, slightly injuring a man and damaging a car.</p>

<p>Since September 23, the Israeli army has been launching intensive airstrikes on Lebanon in a dangerous escalation with Hezbollah.</p>

<p>In early October, Israel also launched a ground operation near the southern Lebanese border, allegedly to further cripple Hezbollah's capabilities.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m0vbup5c_iran-attacks-israel_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah, in a statement, said on Wednesday night that the strike "hit its targets accurately".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-to-cut-immigration-numbers-6859656]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada To Cut Immigration Numbers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-to-cut-immigration-numbers-6859656]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 04:39:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canada will sharply lower the number of immigrants it allows into the country for the first time in years, in a dramatic policy change for an unpopular government trying to hang on to power.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;Canada will sharply lower the number of immigrants it allows into the country for the first time in years, in a dramatic policy change for an unpopular government trying to hang on to power.</p>

<p>Canada will bring in 395,000 new permanent residents in 2025, 380,000 in 2026 and 365,000 in 2027, down from 485,000 in 2024, according to a government source.</p>

<p>The number of temporary residents, meanwhile, will decrease by about 30,000 to around 300,000 in 2025, the source said.</p>

<p>The new targets were first reported by The National Post.</p>

<p>Canada has long prided itself on welcoming newcomers, but over the past year the rhetoric around immigrants has soured.</p>

<p>Migrants have been blamed for everything from a housing crisis to a rising cost of living and a strained healthcare system.</p>

<p>The issue has become one of the most contentious in Canadian politics with a federal election due no later than October, 2025. Polls show a growing share of the population thinks Canada has too many immigrants.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/82fg42h4_canada-immigration-generic-istock_625x300_03_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canada will bring in 395,000 new permanent residents in 2025.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-blasts-donald-trump-over-alleged-hitler-remark-6859621]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Unhinged, Unstable" Kamala Harris Blasts Trump Over Alleged Hitler Remark]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-blasts-donald-trump-over-alleged-hitler-remark-6859621]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 04:22:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris on Wednesday said Donald Trump was "increasingly unhinged," and called her US election rival's reported praise for Adolf Hitler "incredibly dangerous" as campaigning intensified ahead of the November 5 vote.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris on Wednesday said Donald Trump was "increasingly unhinged," and called her US election rival's reported praise for Adolf Hitler "incredibly dangerous" as campaigning intensified ahead of the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>The Democrat's fierce criticism came as she headed to must-win Pennsylvania to face voters' questions in a town hall and as Trump campaigned in battleground Georgia.</p>

<p>With the tight election going down to the wire, both candidates are on a mission to persuade the sliver of American voters who remain undecided in the home stretch.</p>

<p>In a dramatic campaign season, the latest twist was revelations by Trump's longest-serving chief of staff, retired US Marine general John Kelly, about the Republican's admiration for the Nazi dictator and his military in World War II.</p>

<p>Kelly told The New York Times that Trump had remarked that "Hitler did some good things too" and that instead of the US military he "wanted generals like Adolf Hitler had."</p>

<p>Harris was quick to respond, delivering a statement outside her vice presidential residence in Washington.</p>

<p>"It's deeply troubling and incredibly dangerous that Donald Trump would invoke Adolf Hitler, the man who is responsible for the deaths of six million Jews and hundreds of thousands of Americans," she said.</p>

<p>"All this is further evidence for the American people of who Donald Trump really is."</p>

<p>With Trump's rivals raising concerns about his willingness to honor American democracy, Kelly also repeated his warning that he believes his ex-boss "certainly falls into the general definition of fascist."</p>

<p>Harris said "Donald Trump is increasingly unhinged and unstable, and in a second term, people like John Kelly would not be there to be the guardrails."</p>

<p>Trump's camp hit back, saying Harris is "desperate because she is flailing, and her campaign is in shambles.</p>

<p>"That is why she continues to peddle outright lies and falsehoods that are easily disproven," Trump spokesman Steven Cheung said in a statement.</p>

<p>When asked whether President Joe Biden agrees with Kelly's assessment that Trump is a fascist, White House spokesperson Karine Jean-Pierre was unequivocal.</p>

<p>"Do we agree about that determination? Yes we do," she said.</p>

<p><strong>- Obamas hit campaign trail -</strong></p>

<p>Harris, 60, touched down in Pennsylvania ahead of a Wednesday prime time CNN town hall-type meeting near Philadelphia.</p>

<p>She made an unannounced stop at the Famous 4th Street Delicatessen, where the Democrat fist-bumped employees and took selfies with patrons.</p>

<p>"Knock wood, God willing, we are going to win," she said to cheers.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania is a coveted prize for the candidates, and Harris and Trump have made repeated appearances there and across other swing states.</p>

<p>The Harris camp has also confirmed that Michelle Obama will join her at an event Saturday in battleground Michigan, the former US first lady's debut campaign stop with Harris.</p>

<p>It will follow Harris's first campaign appearance with former president Barack Obama, on Thursday in Georgia's largest city Atlanta, as part of a major Democratic get-out-the-vote effort across swing states.</p>

<p>Veteran rocker Bruce Springsteen is set to kick off the event with a concert.</p>

<p>Trump held his own town hall Wednesday in Georgia, which the 78-year-old Republican won in 2016 and then narrowly lost to Biden four years later.</p>

<p>The Republican waxed nostalgic about his Make America Great Again movement when he addressed an energized crowd outside the event.</p>

<p>"In many ways it's sad because we're down to 12 days," he told cheering supporters. "We've been doing this together for nine years... It's just been an amazing thing."</p>

<p>Some 25 million Americans have already voted by mail or in person, reportedly a far higher number than the same period four years ago.</p>

<p>Nevertheless Trump told Fox News on Wednesday he still felt "very mixed" about early voting, even though he confirmed he himself would do so in Florida.</p>

<p>Harris's sudden entry into the campaign in late July shook up the country, which was expecting a rematch between Biden and Trump, now a felon convicted on 34 charges of falsifying business records to hide hush-money payments to a porn star.</p>

<p>Since Biden's shock withdrawal, the Trump-Harris race has been one of the tightest in American history.</p>

<p>Past opinion polls have underestimated backing for Trump but also failed to predict the level of support for Democrats.</p>

<p>While Trump hammers home his promises of a migrant crackdown and economic good times after a period of high inflation, the Harris campaign has targeted his mental and physical fitness for the Oval Office while she courts moderate Republican voters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mtruabig_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Harris said "Donald Trump is increasingly unhinged and unstable"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-tries-to-reassure-customers-after-deadly-e-coli-outbreak-6859233]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[McDonald's Tries To Reassure Customers After Deadly E. Coli Outbreak]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mcdonalds-tries-to-reassure-customers-after-deadly-e-coli-outbreak-6859233]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 02:11:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[McDonald's worked Wednesday to reassure customers that its US restaurants are safe as federal investigators tried to pinpoint the cause of a deadly E coli outbreak linked to fast-food giant's Quarter Pounder hamburgers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>McDonald's worked Wednesday to reassure customers that its US restaurants are safe as federal investigators tried to pinpoint the cause of a deadly E coli outbreak linked to fast-food giant's Quarter Pounder hamburgers.</p>

<p>McDonald's pulled Quarter Pounders from one-fifth of its US stores Tuesday as a result of the outbreak, which the US Centres for Disease Control and Prevention said had sickened at least 49 people in 10 states. One person died and 10 were hospitalized, according to the CDC.</p>

<p>A preliminary investigation by the US Food and Drug Administration suggested fresh slivered onions that are served raw on Quarter Pounder hamburgers were a likely source of the contamination.</p>

<p>McDonald's said it was searching for a new regional supplier for fresh onions. In the meantime, Quarter Pounders were removed from menus in the impacted states as well as portions of other states.</p>

<p>McDonald's said it has worked closely with federal food safety regulators since late last week, when it was alerted to the potential outbreak. The company said the scope of the problem and the popularity of its products have complicated efforts to identify the contamination source.</p>

<p>McDonald's has more than 14,000 US stores and serves 1 million Quarter Pounders every two weeks in the affected area.</p>

<p>McDonald's is known for its stringent food safety guidelines and protocols, said Chris Gaulke, a professor of food and beverage management at Cornell University's Nolan School of Hotel Administration. The company said Wednesday that the supplier regularly tested its onions for E coli, for example.</p>

<p>"Given the volume of food that they go through, how infrequently this happens to McDonald's is a testament to the effort that they take," Gaulke said.</p>

<p>But some experts questioned why McDonald's simply stopped selling one sandwich and didn't close restaurants for further investigation.</p>

<p>"Good practice would have been to close all the restaurants," Bill Marler, a Seattle lawyer who specialises in food safety cases, said. "Until we know definitively what the product was that made people sick, consumers should be aware." Marler said cross-contamination remains a potential possibility at the affected restaurants until they are thoroughly cleaned.</p>

<p>Asked why it didn't close any stores, McDonald's said nothing in the government's investigation indicated there were issues with its food preparation practices. In an interview on the "Today" show Wednesday, McDonald's US President Joe Erlinger also said it's likely that whatever product was contaminated has already passed through the company's supply chain.</p>

<p>The Centres for Disease Control and Prevention reported the outbreak late Tuesday. It said infections were reported between Sept. 27 and October 11 in Colorado, Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska, Oregon, Utah, Wisconsin and Wyoming.</p>

<p>State and local public health officials were interviewing people about the foods they ate in the week before they got sick. Of the 18 people interviewed as of Tuesday, all reported eating at McDonald's, and 16 people reported eating a beef hamburger. Twelve reported eating a Quarter Pounder.</p>

<p>McDonald's said it's unlikely the beef in the Quarter Pounder was the source, since it comes from multiple suppliers and is cooked at a high enough temperature to kill E coli.</p>

<p>McDonald's said its initial findings suggest that some of the reported illnesses were linked to onions from a single supplier, which the company didn't name. McDonald's said the onions are cleaned and sliced by the supplier and then packaged for use on individual Quarter Pounders.</p>

<p>The incubation period for E coli is only a couple of days, so illness would be quickly apparent to anyone affected, said Donald Schaffner, a food safety expert at Rutgers University. "If you ate these burgers in September and now it's the middle of October and you didn't get sick, you're probably OK," he said.</p>

<p>E coli bacteria are harbored in the guts of animals and found in the environment. Infections can cause severe illness, including fever, stomach cramps and bloody diarrhea. People who develop symptoms of E. coli poisoning should seek health care immediately and tell the provider what they ate.</p>

<p>The type of bacteria implicated in the McDonald's food causes about 74,000 infections in the U.S. annually, leading to more than 2,000 hospitalisations and 61 deaths each year, according to the CDC. In general, E. coli infections were lower in 2023 than in recent years and cases of severe kidney injury caused by the bacteria remained stable, according to latest federal data.</p>

<p>Outbreaks at restaurant chains are rare, but they do happen. AP MNK MNK</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/t5b0sdbo_mcdonalds_625x300_25_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McDonald's said it was searching for a new regional supplier for fresh onions]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-at-least-3-000-north-korea-troops-training-in-russia-6859096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says At Least 3,000 North Korea Troops Training In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-at-least-3-000-north-korea-troops-training-in-russia-6859096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 01:38:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 3,000 North Korean soldiers have been sent to Russia and are training there, the United States said Wednesday, warning that they would become legitimate targets for Kyiv if they engage in combat in Ukraine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 3,000 North Korean soldiers have been sent to Russia and are training there, the United States said Wednesday, warning that they would become legitimate targets for Kyiv if they engage in combat in Ukraine.</p>

<p>Russia and North Korea have boosted their political and military alliance amid the Ukraine war, with Pyongyang facing long-standing accusations of supplying arms to Moscow's army.</p>

<p>But the deployment of troops to support Russian forces would be a significant escalation in that support and has prompted warnings from Kyiv and its Western backers, who separately said Wednesday that they would make $50 billion in lending available to aid Ukraine.</p>

<p>"We assess that between early to mid-October, North Korea moved at least 3,000 soldiers into eastern Russia," US National Security Council spokesman John Kirby told journalists.</p>

<p>The troops traveled by ship from North Korea to Vladivostok, and then went to "multiple Russian military training sites in eastern Russia, where they are currently undergoing training," Kirby said.</p>

<p>"We do not yet know whether these soldiers will enter into combat alongside the Russian military," but "if these North Korean soldiers decide to join the fight against Ukraine, they will become legitimate military targets," he said.</p>

<p>North Korea's state media has not commented since Seoul's spy agency said last week said Pyongyang had decided to send a "large-scale" troop deployment to Russia to fight Ukraine.</p>

<p>Moscow on Wednesday refused to confirm or deny the reports, with&nbsp; foreign ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova telling reporters to "ask Pyongyang" where its troops are.</p>

<p><strong>- International concerns -</strong></p>

<p>After a briefing by the National Intelligence Service, South Korean lawmaker Park Sun-won said earlier that 1,500 more troops had been sent to Russia, taking the total deployment to 3,000.</p>

<p>Seoul says Pyongyang plans to deploy 10,000 soldiers to Russia by December, with international concerns escalating.</p>

<p>Germany said Wednesday it had summoned North Korea's envoy to warn the reclusive state against sending troops.</p>

<p>"North Korea's support of the Russian war of aggression directly threatens Germany's security and the European peace order," the German foreign ministry said on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Kyiv on Wednesday called on any North Korean troops deployed by Russia to lay down their arms and save their lives.</p>

<p>"We address fighters of the Korean People's Army who were sent to help Putin's regime. You must not die senselessly in a foreign land," said a statement issued by a group run by Kyiv's military intelligence.</p>

<p>"You must not repeat the fate of hundreds of thousands of Russian soldiers who will never return home!" it added.</p>

<p><strong>- 'Helping Putin' -</strong></p>

<p>South Korea has said the nuclear-armed North is supplying Russia with weapons for use in Ukraine. The fresh alarm comes after the North's leader Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin signed a military deal in June.</p>

<p>South Korea will send a delegation to NATO headquarters in Brussels next week to brief the alliance on the situation, officials said.</p>

<p>Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky has pleaded for Kyiv's allies to respond and repeatedly said a North Korean deployment risks further escalating and prolonging the war.</p>

<p>"It is important that our partners do not hide from this challenge. All partners," he said in an address published late Tuesday.</p>

<p>"And if Russia is still able to make this war bigger and longer, then everyone in the world who is not helping to force Russia to peace is actually helping Putin to fight," he added.</p>

<p>Experts have said that in return for the troops, North Korea is likely aiming to acquire military technology, ranging from surveillance satellites to submarines, plus possible security guarantees from Moscow.</p>

<p>North Korea and Russia are under UN sanctions -- Kim for his nuclear weapons program, and Moscow for the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>Kyiv meanwhile obtained significant new international financial backing on Wednesday in the form of $50 billion in lending that US Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said G7 nations are committed to making available this year using profits from the interest on frozen Russian assets.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-04/north-korea-military-parade-reuters_650x400_41492930353.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[South Korea has said the nuclear-armed North is supplying Russia with weapons for use in Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-delhi-after-attending-brics-summit-in-russia-6859035]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi Arrives In Delhi After Attending BRICS Summit In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-arrives-in-delhi-after-attending-brics-summit-in-russia-6859035]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 01:15:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi returned to Delhi after his two-day visit to Russia, during which he participated in the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi returned to Delhi after his two-day visit to Russia, during which he participated in the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p>

<p>He also met several world leaders, including Chinese President Xi Jinping, Russian President Vladimir Putin and UAE President Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>He described the BRICS Summit in Russia's Kazan as "very productive". He thanked Russian President Vladimir Putin, the people of Russia and their government for their hospitality.</p>

<p>PM Modi took to X to share glimpses of his visit to Russia. During his visit to Russia, PM Modi addressed two sessions of the BRICS Summit held in Kazan under Russia's chairmanship.</p>

<p>While sharing the video on X, PM Modi stated, "The BRICS Summit in Kazan was very productive. Had the opportunity to discuss diverse issues and meet various world leaders. I thank President Putin, the Russian people and Government for their hospitality. Here are the highlights."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The BRICS Summit in Kazan was very productive. Had the opportunity to discuss diverse issues and meet various world leaders. I thank President Putin, the Russian people and Government for their hospitality. Here are the highlights. <a href="https://t.co/1guOhvA2Q7">pic.twitter.com/1guOhvA2Q7</a></p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1849118366499246580?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 23, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>In the video shared by PM Modi on X, he could be seen participating in the BRICS Summit in Kazan. The video showed PM Modi meeting several world leaders, including UAE President Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan and Uzbekistan President Shavkat Mirziyoyev.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, PM Modi also met Egyptian President Abdel Fattah El-Sisi in Kazan. In a post on X, PM Modi stated, "Happy to have interacted with President Abdelfattah Elsisi in Ka</p>

<p>He also held a meeting with Uzbekistan President Shavkat Mirziyoyev in Kazan and discussed ways to boost bilateral cooperation between the two nations.</p>

<p>"Had a wonderful meeting with President Shavkat Mirziyoyev in Kazan. Discussed ways to boost bilateral cooperation between India and Uzbekistan including trade and cultural linkages," PM Modi posted on X.</p>

<p>PM Narendra Modi met Chinese President Xi Jinping in the Russian city of Kazan on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>The meeting marks the first formal structured interaction between the two leaders in five years. The meeting comes after the two countries reached an agreement on resuming regular patrolling along the Line of Actual Control (LAC) in eastern Ladakh.</p>

<p>After meeting with Chinese President Xi Jinping on the sidelines, PM Modi stated, "India-China relations are important for the people of our countries and for regional and global peace and stability."<br />
PM Modi expressed his delight at meeting UAE President Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p>

<p>Sharing details about his meeting with the UAE President, he wrote, "Glad to have met my brother, Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the UAE, on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Kazan."</p>

<p>In his address at the BRICS Summit, PM Modi noted that the Summit is happening at a time when the world is undergoing several uncertainties and challenges including conflicts, adverse climatic impacts, and cyber threats, placing greater expectations upon BRICS. He suggested that the group take a people-centric approach to tackle these challenges.</p>

<p>PM Modi also underlined the need for early adoption of a Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism at the United Nations to combat the menace of terrorism.</p>

<p>He called upon BRICS to proactively push for global governance reforms. Recalling the Voice of Global South Summits hosted by India during its G20 Presidency, he stressed that the group must give primacy to the concerns of the Global South.</p>

<p>PM Modi noted that the regional presence of the New Development Bank including in GIFT city, India, has created new values and impacts.</p>

<p>Highlighting BRICS' activities to foster economic growth, he emphasized that its efforts on trade facilitation in agriculture, resilient supply chains, e-commerce and Special Economic Zones have generated new opportunities.</p>

<p>He underlined the need to prioritise small and medium scale industries. He expressed that the BRICS Startup Forum, initiated by India which is to be launched this year, would add significant value to the BRICS economic agenda.</p>

<p>The Prime Minister elaborated on the recent green initiatives undertaken by India including the International Solar Alliance, Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, Mission LIFE and Green Credit initiative announced during COP28. He invited BRICS countries to join these initiatives.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, PM Modi held a meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin on the margins of the BRICS Summit in Kazan. PM Modi invited Putin to visit India next year for the 23rd India-Russia Annual Summit.</p>

<p>The two leaders reviewed bilateral cooperation in various sectors, including political, economic, defence, energy, and people-to-people ties, the Prime Minister's Office said in a press release.</p>

<p>In a post on X, PM Modi stated, "Had an excellent meeting with President Putin. The bond between India and Russia is deep-rooted. Our talks focussed on how to add even more vigour to our bilateral partnership across diverse sectors."</p>

<p>This was their second meeting this year as the two leaders had earlier met in Moscow for the 22nd India-Russia Annual Summit in July 2024.</p>

<p>PM Modi also held a meeting with Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian and discussed ways to deepen bilateral ties in futuristic sectors.</p>

<p>"Had a very good meeting with the President of Iran, Mr. Masoud Pezeshkian. We reviewed the full range of relations between our countries. We also discussed ways to deepen ties in futuristic sectors," PM Modi posted on X.</p>

<p>This visit marked PM Modi's second visit to Russia this year as he visited Moscow in July for the annual India-Russia Summit.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7nt2pv5_pm-modi-_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi described the BRICS Summit in Russia's Kazan as "very productive".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-explainer-understanding-the-lac-and-the-stand-off-with-china-6858970]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Explainer: Understanding The LAC And The Stand-Off With China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-explainer-understanding-the-lac-and-the-stand-off-with-china-6858970]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:57:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping held their first "formal bilateral meeting" since the military stand-off between India and China began in 2020. Here is an explainer with video, a map, and satellite images to help understand the LAC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping held a bilateral meeting in Russia's Kazan today, on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit that both leaders attended. This is the first "formal bilateral meeting" between the PM Modi and President Xi since the military stand-off between both countries began in 2020.</p>

<p>Ties between India and China took a severe hit and came to an abrupt halt after the military clash in Galwan Valley. It took four years of diplomatic and military-level talks between both sides to finally come to an agreement to reinstate the status quo to what it was before the stand-off in 2020.</p>

<p>Both countries welcomed the move and in less than 72 after the disengagement agreement, the two leaders met in Russia today.</p>

<p>To understand what exactly had happened back in 2020, what the friction points were, and the kind of build up China had in place since then - which has now been dismantled, we need maps and satellite images.</p>

<h2><strong>UNDERSTANDING THE MAP</strong></h2>

<p>This is the map of Ladakh with the Line of Actual Control or LAC marked in red. The area between the LAC and the original border in black is the Aksai Chin region of Ladakh occupied by China since the 1962 war. While Galwan Valley was where the military clash happened in May, 2020, there were several other friction points, namely - Depsang, Galwan, Gogra Hot Springs, Pangong Tso, and Demchok.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/taha99mo_ladakh-map-showing-lac_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Shortly after the uprising in China in 1959, and the occupation of Tibet that year, China started making claims in areas that fall in Ladakh, an "integral and inalienable" part of India. During the Sino-India war of 1962, Chinese troops had crossed the original border but had to withdraw later. It however never withdrew from Aksai Chin.</p>

<p>The dotted red line in the map above represents the approximate patrol points established by India and are the farthest points till where Indian soldiers patrol. All the areas labelled along the LAC are points where Chinese troops blocked Indian soldiers from reaching the last patrol point that would walk up to till 2020. This led to the military stand-off between India and China.</p>

<p>After the Galwan Clash in May, 2020, both sides brought in reinforcements - tens of thousands of troops and military hardware from tanks and artillery guns to fighter jets and drones. At this stage both sides started engaging in talks - both at diplomatic and military levels.</p>

<p>The disengagement talks began and both sides created disengagement zones, also known as buffer zones in the areas of Galwan - where the clash happened, Gogra Hot Springs, and Pangong.</p>

<h3><strong>What is a buffer zone?</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li><em>Soldiers from both sides, as a result of a grievance, agreed to go back a certain number of kilometers, and the areas that fell in between, which included points that were disputed would be where troops from neither side would go. Structures that were built in these locations during the stand-off by either side were also removed as the disengagement talks progressed over the months and years.</em></li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>SATELLITE IMAGES</strong></h3>

<h3><big>Here are a set of satellite images that show the way the situation developed since 2020:</big></h3>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3sp7delo_pangong-lake-north-side_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This image shows the north side of the Pangong Lake where in June, 2020, Chinese soldiers came to an area that India claims and put markings of the flag of China and wrote beneath it in Mandarin that "This area belongs to China". This was a time when the Chinese had come right in along the Pangong Lake.</p>

<p><big><strong>Pangong Lake:</strong></big> About 50 per cent of Pangong Lake area is in Tibet (under Chinese control), 40 per cent in Ladakh and 10 per cent is disputed. Discrepancies in LAC perceptions lead to military standoffs and buffer zones, with ongoing construction and strategic positioning reflecting the tensions and claims by both nations.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/247it08c_pangong-lake-area-satellite-image_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This second image is also from the north bank of the Pangong Lake and a place where the Chinese had a major built-up area.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/92m16mds_pangong-lake-south-side_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This third image shows the south bank of the Pangong Lake where the Chinese troops had brought in their boats (left side of the image) and the right side shows how these were eventually removed by Beijing as the disengagement process moved forward at a slow but steady pace.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2r36srj8_galwan-valley-chinese-buildup_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This fourth image is from where it all began - The Galwan Valley - where the clash took place in which soldiers on either side were killed in action. China set up and built multiple structures along the banks of the river and in the area where the river meanders. In this photo, the LAC is approximately 400 meters south of where the river is seen bending to the right. These were areas where Indian soldiers would patrol in the past, but in 2020, the Chinese soldiers attempted to stop them from doing that.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1v6q1alc_gogra-hot-springs-area_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>In this fifth satellite image, we take a look at the Gogra Hot Springs area - an area which had seen conflict in 1962 as well. The screen is divided in two - the left showing the Chinese build-up in 2021, which they later dismantled in 2022 and vacated the area, as seen on the right.</p>

<p><big><strong>Gogra Hot Springs:</strong></big> Located near Gogra Post, the Hot Springs area is significant for India due to its strategic location which facilitates surveillance over LAC. India's control over this region enhances its defence posture, providing vantage points for monitoring movements in Aksai Chin, thus playing a crucial role in border security dynamics.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/47k1su88_gogra-ht-spring-area-china-base-relocation_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The sixth satellite image shows the relocated Chinese base. This was set up by China 3 kilometers south of the spot they vacated in the image shown above this one.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8mpks1pg_gogra-hot-springs-buffer-zone_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>This seventh image gives a clearer picture of where the Chinese had built a structure and where they relocated to as the disengagement talks continued. This was part of the buffer zone that was created in this particular area.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fhgg44c8_depsang-area-yjunction_625x300_24_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The eighth image shows the area in Depsang - an area of real concern. In a place called the Y-junction in Depsang, Chinese troops have set up a base and have been preventing Indian soldiers to patrol up to a point where they used to before 2020. As the photo shows, Indian soldiers have been prevented from moving east (right). If after the latest agreement of shifting the status quo to pre-2020 times, then Indian soldiers would now be able to patrol right up to the farthest point where they used to.</p>

<p><big><strong>Depsang:</strong></big> Depsang plains are critical for India due to their strategic access to the Daulat Beg Oldie (DBO) airstrip and the Darbuk-Shyok-DBO road. Control over Depsang prevents Chinese forces from threatening these vital logistics lines, making it essential for India's northern border defence and military mobility.</p>

<p><strong>WHAT PM MODI TOLD XI JINPING IN THEIR FIRST OFFICIAL MEET AFTER 2020</strong></p>

<p><em>"Excellency, I am happy to meet you, and like you mentioned, this is a formal meeting between us after five years. It is my belief that the importance of India-China relations is not just for the citizens of our two countries, but also very significant for peace, stability, and progress for the entire world.</em></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/h1u97bss_narendra-modi-xi-jinping-bilateral-meeting-kazan-russia_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FeatureCrop,algorithm=dnn," title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><em>Excellency, We welcome the consensus reached on the issues that have arisen in the last 4 years along the border. It should be our priority to ensure there is peace and stability along our border. Mutual trust, mutual respect, and mutual sensitivity should be the basis our bilateral relations. Today, we have got an opportunity to speak about all these issues and I trust that we will hold these talks with an open mind and that our talks will be constructive going forward. Thank you."</em><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4smtf6m4_india-china-lac-line-of-actual-control-lac-ians_625x300_29_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It took 4 years of diplomatic and military talks between both sides to come to an agreement]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-birmingham-airport-evacuated-flights-suspended-over-suspicious-vehicle-6858819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK's Birmingham Airport Evacuated Over "Suspicious Vehicle"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uks-birmingham-airport-evacuated-flights-suspended-over-suspicious-vehicle-6858819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:16:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A major international airport serving the UK's second-largest city was evacuated and all flights were suspended for several hours on Wednesday because of a security alert.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A major international airport serving the UK's second-largest city was evacuated and all flights were suspended for several hours on Wednesday because of a security alert.</p>

<p>West Midlands Police in central England ordered the partial closure of Birmingham Airport after receiving reports of a suspicious vehicle.</p>

<p>Airport authorities advised passengers not to travel while those already awaiting flights were forced to leave terminals on foot with their luggage.</p>

<p>"Whilst we apologise for any inconvenience and disruption, the safety and security of everyone at the airport was our number one priority," a statement read.</p>

<p>West Midlands Police said the evacuation was a "precautionary measure" while the vehicle was searched and assessed.</p>

<p>"Following a search by the Explosive Ordnance Disposal (EDO) team the vehicle was deemed to be safe. The vehicle is no longer being treated as suspicious," it added.</p>

<p>Birmingham Airport is the seventh busiest UK airport by passenger numbers and is used as an operating base for easyJet, Ryanair, TUI Airways and Jet2.com.</p>

<p>Its busiest routes are to and from Dublin, Dubai, Amsterdam, Palma de Mallorca and Tenerife-South.</p>

<p>"Operations will slowly be returning to normal," an airport spokesperson said. "All passengers are advised to check latest flight information from their airline."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ekv4lj68_birmingham-airport_625x300_24_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Birmingham Airport is the seventh busiest UK airport by passenger numbers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-consensus-a-long-pending-matter-at-un-what-pm-narendra-modi-said-at-brics-6858811]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Terror Consensus A Long-Pending Matter At UN': What PM Modi Said At BRICS]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/terror-consensus-a-long-pending-matter-at-un-what-pm-narendra-modi-said-at-brics-6858811]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:10:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasised the need for unified action against terrorism at the 16th BRICS Summit. He stressed that combating terrorism requires "single-minded" focus and "firm-support" of all nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi emphasised the need for unified action against terrorism at the 16th BRICS Summit. He stressed that combating terrorism requires “single-minded” focus and “firm-support” of all nations. He asserted that “double-standards” have no place in addressing this global challenge.</p>

<p>He also highlighted how important it is to stop radicalisation of young people and urged action to counter terrorism and terror financing. These remarks come after China had blocked several proposals at the United Nations to designate Pakistan-based terrorists.</p>

<p>"We must work together on the long-pending matter in the UN of the Comprehensive Convention on International Terrorism," PM Modi said. He also added that work needs to be done on global regulations for cyber security and for safe AI.</p>

<p>Furthermore, he spoke about the expansion of the BRICS forum. "India is ready to welcome new countries into BRICS as partner countries,” he said.</p>

<p>He also emphasised that decisions should be taken by consensus and the views of BRICS founding members should be respected.</p>

<p>He advocated the compliance of guiding principles, standards, criteria and procedures adopted during last year's Johannesburg summit, by all members and countries and said that BRICS is an organisation willing to evolve with time.</p>

<p>He concluded by saying that BRICS should be an exemplary organisation for the world, and that they should raise their voice for reforms in global organisations in a collective and united manner but also ensuring that they avoid any perceptions that they are “trying to replace global institutions, instead of being perceived as one that wishes to reform them”.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ion2asdo_modi-brics_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi has called for a unified fight against terrorism.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-attacks-donald-trump-says-gotta-lock-him-up-then-backtracks-6858779]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Joe Biden Attacks Donald Trump, Says "Gotta Lock Him Up", Then Backtracks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-attacks-donald-trump-says-gotta-lock-him-up-then-backtracks-6858779]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:05:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Joe Biden was at a New Hampshire campaign on Tuesday when he started off by saying "We gotta lock him up," soon after he tweaked his statement to, "Politically lock him up". Backtracking further, he added, "Lock him out, thats what weve got to do."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Joe Biden was at a New Hampshire campaign on Tuesday where he targeted Donald Trump by saying “We gotta lock him up”. He soon altered his statement to, “Politically lock him up”. He went on to backtrack further, saying, “Lock him out, that's what we've got to do.”</p>

<p>According to Joe Biden, American democracy would be at stake if Republican candidate Donald Trump beats Democratic candidate Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>In 2016, when Donald Trump ran for President, he presided over rallies where people chanted, “lock her up” referring to Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton. He was never found hushing up people from these slogans and according to a fact check by CNN, he also falsely claimed that he did not make any “lock her up” calls then.</p>

<p>In contrast, this year, during Kamala Harris's rallies, spectators chanted, “lock him up”, to which she responded, “The courts are going to take care of that.”</p>

<p>In a statement, the national press secretary for Donald Trump's 2024 presidential campaign, &nbsp;Karoline Leavitt said, “Joe Biden just admitted the truth: he and Kamala's plan all along has been to politically persecute their opponent President Trump because they can't beat him fair and square.”</p>

<p>“The Harris-Biden Admin is the real threat to democracy. We call on Kamala Harris to condemn Joe Biden's disgraceful remark”, it said.</p>

<p>It is notable that throughout this year's campaigning, Trump has been threatening to prosecute or punish perceived enemies once he is in office.</p>

<p>Biden said, “This is a guy who also wants to replace every civil servant, every single one,” adding that “He thinks he has a right under the Supreme Court ruling on immunity to be able, if need be, if it was the case, to actually eliminate - physically eliminate, shoot, kill - someone who he believes would be a threat to him.”</p>

<p>The Supreme Court ruled that former presidents have immunity from criminal prosecution for actions taken during their term in office. However, this ruling has raised concerns, highlighted by Justice Sonia Sotomayor's dissenting opinion. She warned that this immunity could potentially shield extreme abuses of power, such as ordering the assassination of a political rival, from accountability.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/cp4tp5lg_joe-biden-kamala-harris_625x300_25_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to Joe Biden, American democracy would be at stake if Donald Trump wins.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eminem-endorses-kamala-harris-joins-barack-obama-to-garner-support-for-her-6858739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Eminem Endorses Kamala Harris, Joins Barack Obama To Garner Support For Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eminem-endorses-kamala-harris-joins-barack-obama-to-garner-support-for-her-6858739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:59:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Eminem, the renowned rapper originally from Detroit, on Tuesday endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris, making it a star-studded affair. He then welcomed former President Barack Obama on the stage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eminem, the renowned rapper originally from Detroit, on Tuesday, endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris, making it a star-studded affair. He then welcomed former President Barack Obama on the stage.</p>

<p>Mr Obama then took the stage to Eminem's iconic song "Lose Yourself", joking that he "noticed my palms are sweaty," moving on to rap a few lines from it.</p>

<p>The music legend and former president joined forces to support Kamala Harris' presidential campaign in Detroit. The latter being a longtime Democratic stronghold, will be crucial in deciding who wins the presidency, especially when Michigan stands as being one of the key swing states.</p>

<p>Obama cited Trump's Pennsylvania town-hall and delivered a scathing critique of Trump's fitness for office, where he swayed to songs for 40 minutes rather than answering questions for voters, after two people fainted there.</p>

<p>He continued to say, "If your grandpa was acting like this, you'd be worried." He added, "This is somebody who wants unchecked power. We do not need to see what an older, loonier Donald Trump looks like with no guardrails. America's ready to turn the page."</p>

<p>This joint, significant display of support for Harris comes just days before voting kicks off in Michigan, in hopes that this high-profile event will boost enthusiasm and solidify support for Harris and other Democratic candidates in the offing.</p>

<p>In other news, Trump also recently appeared with rapper Trick-Trick, which only goes on to show the city's importance in the presidential elections.</p>

<p>Trump, in a major gaffe, addressed the city he visited in an undignified manner. "The whole country will be like - you want to know the truth? It'll be like Detroit," Trump said as he addressed the Detroit Economic Club. "Our whole country will end up being like Detroit if she's your president."</p>

<p>However, Obama and other speakers effectively utilised his statements in their stride. Michigan Governor added to the conversation, "I know you all saw what he said about this beautiful city. He called Detroit a failure and a mess, proving he ain't firing on all cylinders," Whitmer said.</p>

<p>"He doesn't have a clue what the hell he was talking about. And you know what I think? He ought to keep Detroit out of his mouth," he added.</p>

<p>Eminem, during the rally had also said that the people should not be afraid of voicing their own opinions and emphasised Harris' commitment to protecting American freedoms, saying that she, "supports a future for this country where these freedoms and many others will be protected and upheld."<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/04k3cmmo_obama-eminem-ap_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Eminem, the renowned rapper from Detroit, endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris on Tuesday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-face-live-voters-queries-in-must-win-pennsylvania-6858672]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris To Face Voters' Queries In Must-Win Battleground Pennsylvania]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-to-face-live-voters-queries-in-must-win-pennsylvania-6858672]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:42:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris heads to must-win Pennsylvania on Wednesday to take voters' questions live while Donald Trump campaigns in Georgia -- another of the seven toss-up states expected to decide the result of an extremely close White House race.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris heads to must-win Pennsylvania on Wednesday to take voters' questions live while Donald Trump campaigns in Georgia -- another of the seven toss-up states expected to decide the result of an extremely close White House race.</p>

<p>With just 13 days to go before the election, Vice President Harris and former president Trump are each on a mission to persuade the sliver of American voters who remain undecided in the home stretch.</p>

<p>The pace of campaigning has intensified in the electoral fight that is nearing its November 5 apogee after twists, turns and a fair bit of drama -- including recent claims by a former Trump aide that the ex-president sometimes spoke in positive terms about Nazi dictator Adolf Hitler.</p>

<p>Harris, who turned 60 over the weekend, will be near Philadelphia for a CNN town hall-type meeting with voters, but there is not one planned for Trump despite the network's offer to hold a separate one for him.</p>

<p>Pennsylvania is a coveted prize for the candidates, and Harris and Trump have made repeated appearances there and across other swing states.</p>

<p>The Harris camp has also confirmed that Michelle Obama will join her at an event Saturday in battleground Michigan, the former US first lady's first campaign stop with Harris.</p>

<p>Trump will hold his own town hall event Wednesday as well as a rally in the southern battleground state of Georgia, which the 78-year-old Republican won in 2016 and then narrowly lost to Joe Biden four years later.</p>

<p>About 23.5 million Americans have already voted by mail or in person, reportedly a far higher number than the same period four years ago.</p>

<p>In Georgia, a staggering 1.9 million early votes have already been cast, shattering the previous record.</p>

<p>Nevertheless Trump told Fox News on Wednesday that he still felt "very mixed" about early voting, even though he confirmed he himself would be voting early in Florida.</p>

<p>"People have different feelings about it," he said. "But the main thing is you've got to get out, you've got to vote."</p>

<h2><strong>Can polls be trusted?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Harris's arrival in the campaign shook up the country, which was expecting a rematch between Biden and Trump, now a felon convicted on 34 charges of falsifying business records to hide hush-money payments to a porn star.</p>

<p>Since Biden's shock withdrawal after a disastrous debate performance, the Trump-Harris race has been one of the tightest in American history.</p>

<p>It's hard to know the degree to which opinion polls are accurate, as they have in the past underestimated support for Trump but also failed to predict the level of support for Democrats.</p>

<p>While the ex-president hammers on his promises of a migrant crackdown and economic good times after a period of high inflation, rivals raise concerns about his willingness to honor American democracy.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign has also begun to hit at his mental and physical fitness for the Oval Office while trying to woo moderate Republican voters.</p>

<p>One of Trump's top aides as president, former US Marine general John Kelly, confirmed Tuesday to The New York Times previous reports that he considered the Republican to be a fascist.</p>

<p>"Certainly the former president is in the far-right area, he's certainly an authoritarian, admires people who are dictators -- he has said that. So he certainly falls into the general definition of fascist, for sure."</p>

<p>Kelly also claimed that Trump "commented more than once that, 'You know, Hitler did some good things too.'"</p>

<p>A day after the explosive remarks were published, Harris's campaign arranged a press call with retired military figures who backed up Kelly's assessment and warned that a second Trump presidency would have far fewer democratic guardrails than his first term.</p>

<p>"General Kelly is warning us that Trump is seeking the power to do anything he wants, anytime he wants," retired US Army colonel Kevin Carroll said on the call.</p>

<p>"Trump is now running to give himself unprecedented, unchecked, and in the phrase he used last night on television, 'extreme' powers."<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lllq04ug_kamala-harris_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The pace of campaigning has intensified in the electoral fight nearing its November 5 apogee. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>