<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:09:35 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modis-full-speech-at-16th-brics-summit-in-russia-6856263]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM's Modi Full Speech At 16th BRICS Summit In Russia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-narendra-modis-full-speech-at-16th-brics-summit-in-russia-6856263]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:09:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi today strongly pitched for "single-minded" focus and "firm support" of all in combating terrorism, asserting that there is no place for "double standards" to deal with the challenge.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi today strongly pitched for "single-minded" focus and "firm support" of all in combating terrorism, asserting that there is no place for "double standards" to deal with the challenge. In an address at the 16th BRICS Summit, PM Modi also underlined the need to take "active steps" to stop the radicalisation of young people.</p>

<p>Here's PM Modi's full speech at the BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>Your Highness,</p>

<p>Excellencies,</p>

<p>Ladies and Gentlemen,</p>

<p>Congratulations to President Putin for the excellent organisation of the 16th BRICS Summit.</p>

<p>And, once again, a warm welcome to all the new friends who have joined BRICS. In its new avatar, BRICS accounts for 40 per cent of the world's humanity and about 30 per cent of the global economy.</p>

<p>In the last nearly two decades, BRICS has achieved many milestones.I am confident that in the times to come, this organisation will emerge as a more effective medium to face global challenges.</p>

<p>I would also like to convey warm greetings to Her Excellency Dilma Rousseff, President of the New Development Bank.</p>

<p>Friends,</p>

<p>In the last 10 years, this bank has emerged as an important option for the development needs of the countries of the Global South. The opening of GIFT or Gujarat International Finance Tech City in India as well as regional centres in Africa and Russia has boosted the activities of this bank. And, development projects worth about $35 billion have been sanctioned. NDB should continue to work on the basis of the demand driven principle. And, while expanding the bank, ensuring long-term financial sustainability, healthy credit rating and market access should remain a priority.</p>

<p>Friends,</p>

<p>In its new expanded avatar, BRICS has emerged as an economy of more than $30 trillion. The BRICS Business Council and the BRICS Women Business Alliance have played a special role in increasing our economic cooperation.</p>

<p>This year, the consensus reached within BRICS on WTO reforms, trade facilitation in agriculture, resilient supply chains, e-commerce and Special Economic Zones will strengthen our economic cooperation. Amidst all these initiatives, we should also focus on the interests of small and medium scale industries.</p>

<p>I am pleased that the BRICS Startup Forum proposed during India's presidency in 2021 will be launched this year. The Railway Research Network initiative taken by India is also playing an important role in increasing logistics and supply chain connectivity among BRICS countries. This year, the consensus reached by BRICS countries, in collaboration with UNIDO, to prepare a skilled workforce for Industry 4.0 is quite significant.</p>

<p>The BRICS Vaccine R&amp;D Centre launched in 2022 is helping increase health security in all the countries. We would be happy to share India's successful experience in Digital Health with BRICS partners.</p>

<p>Friends,</p>

<p>Climate change has been a subject of our common priority. The consensus reached for the BRICS Open Carbon Market Partnership under Russia's presidency is welcome. In India too, special emphasis is being laid on green growth, climate resilient infrastructure and green transition. Indeed, India has taken up several initiatives like the International Solar Alliance, Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure, Mission LiFE i.e. Lifestyle for Environment, Ek Ped Maa Ke Naam.</p>

<p>Last year, during COP-28, we started an important initiative called Green Credit. I invite BRICS partners to join these initiatives.</p>

<p>Special emphasis is being laid on the construction of infrastructure in all BRICS countries. We have established a digital platform called the Gati-Shakti portal to rapidly expand multi-modal connectivity in India. This has helped in integrated infrastructure development planning and implementation and has reduced logistics costs.</p>

<p>We will be happy to share our experiences with all of you.</p>

<p>Friends,</p>

<p>We welcome efforts to increase financial integration among BRICS countries.</p>

<p>Trade in local currencies and smooth cross-border payments will strengthen our economic cooperation. The Unified Payments Interface (UPI) developed by India is a huge success story and has been adopted in many countries.</p>

<p>Last year, together with His Highness Sheikh Mohamed, it was launched in the UAE as well. We can also cooperate with other BRICS countries in this area.</p>

<p>Friends,</p>

<p>India is fully committed to increasing cooperation under BRICS. Our strong belief in our diversity and multipolarity is our strength. This strength of ours, and our shared belief in humanity, will help in giving a meaningful shape to a prosperous and a bright future for the generations to come.</p>

<p>I thank everyone for today's very important and valuable discussions. As the next President of BRICS, I extend my heartfelt best wishes to President Lula. India will give its full support for the success of your BRICS presidency.</p>

<p>Once again, many thanks to President Putin and all the leaders.</p>

<p><em>(This is the approximate translation of the Prime Minister's remarks. Original remarks were delivered in Hindi.)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n8k7eob_modi-xi-jinping_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Climate change has been a subject of our common priority, PM Narendra Modi said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-heroic-passengers-take-control-of-running-bus-after-driver-suffers-seizure-in-us-6856235]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Passengers Take Control Of Bus After Driver Suffers Seizure In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-heroic-passengers-take-control-of-running-bus-after-driver-suffers-seizure-in-us-6856235]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 18:06:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two passengers on a Colorado Springs transit bus heroically intervened when the driver collapsed due to a medical emergency on October 14.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two quick-thinking passengers on a Colorado Springs transit bus averted a potential tragedy on October 14 when the driver collapsed due to a medical emergency, according to <em>Fox News.</em> The incident occurred around 7:45 am on a Mountain Metropolitan Transit (MMT) Route 1 bus travelling from Hillside to Hancock Plaza.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.foxnews.com/us/passengers-colorado-bus-aid-driver-steer-vehicle-safety-your-driver-having-seizure"><em>Fox News, </em></a>as the driver fell from his seat, one passenger quickly moved to the front of the bus, while another rushed from the back to take control of the steering wheel. They safely brought the bus to a stop and contacted a dispatcher for assistance. At the time, only three people were on board: the driver and the two passengers, who acted heroically to prevent a serious accident.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/vi_shukla/status/1848861960735261120">Video footage</a> from inside the bus shows the two passengers rushing to the front as the driver falls from his seat. One is seen holding what appears to be a coffee cup and is heard asking the unseen driver, "Are you all right?"</p>

<p>The other is heard radioing a dispatcher to report the emergency while stopping the vehicle at a bus stop.</p>

<p>"Dispatch, I am on No. 1 southbound," the second passenger said. "Your bus driver is having a seizure. I am parking the bus."</p>

<p>"He's breathing, but the seizure seems to have stopped," he said as the bus came to a stop.</p>

<p>MMT spokesperson Elaine Sheridan told <em>Fox News Digital</em> that the agency has the name of the second passenger who jumped into the driver's seat but has not been able to reach him to get permission to disclose his identity. The other passenger left the scene before first responders arrived because he needed to get to work, she said.</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="250" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FMountainMetro%2Fposts%2Fpfbid0iZVmHRJmwbozrWCNUQM4Csv6hFrF4DEQP1gqw2JKx45ibe5dGvzryJuwbZz6kbRFl&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="500"></iframe></p>

<p>"We have publicly requested that these passengers contact us because we would like to provide them with passes as a token of our appreciation for their assistance that morning," Sheridan said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/47c7pev_running-bus_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The agency seeks to recognize the passengers for their bravery.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/microsoft-launches-ai-agents-that-can-send-emails-manage-records-take-action-on-your-behalf-6856037]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Launches AI Agents That Send Emails, Take Action On Your Behalf]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/microsoft-launches-ai-agents-that-can-send-emails-manage-records-take-action-on-your-behalf-6856037]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:42:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The next phase in AI revolution is building agents - tools that can complete established tasks without human intervention by combining reasoning powered by generative AI with existing databases and software.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp. is launching a set of artificial intelligence tools designed to send emails, manage records and take other actions on behalf of business workers, expanding an AI push that intensifies competition with rivals like Salesforce Inc.</p>

<p>The Redmond, Washington-based software maker said Monday it would roll out 10 "autonomous agents" to complete tasks on behalf of people in areas such as sales, customer support and accounting. The agents will be available in "public preview," beginning in December and continuing through early 2025. Microsoft also said that Copilot Studio, which lets companies build their own agents, will soon get the capability to have those agents act on their own initiative. That will be released in a preview version next month.</p>

<p>The agents are like smartphone apps for the AI age, said Jared Spataro, who oversees Microsoft's workplace AI products. The AI tools, some acting autonomously and others in concert with a worker, can complete tasks like researching and sorting through sales leads or updating a customer support ticket after a phone call.</p>

<p>"We have just found places where people spend tons of time and tons of money," Spataro said. "They tend to be tasks and processes that they wish they didn't have to do, but they have to do over and over again. There's high yield if we can essentially automate that."</p>

<p>Microsoft, thanks largely to its partnership with ChatGPT maker OpenAI, is at the forefront of the technology industry's effort to infuse software with the ability to generate text and images and display humanlike reasoning. Since early 2023, Microsoft has focused on AI features that require a prompt from the user - a prominent example being the company's Copilot, which it has deployed across Word, Outlook and other products.</p>

<p>The next phase is building agents - tools that can complete established tasks without human intervention by combining reasoning powered by generative AI with existing databases and software. ServiceNow Inc., Workday Inc., HubSpot Inc. and SAP SE are among the cadre of software companies now emphasizing AI agents.</p>

<p>Salesforce, the biggest maker of customer management software, spent much of its annual Dreamforce conference last month touting the new approach, saying its agents can handle tasks like customer service without supervision. Its tool - Agentforce - will become generally available later this month, with initial pricing of about $2 per conversation, the company has said.</p>

<p>While promoting Salesforce's tools, Chief Executive Officer Marc Benioff has also taken repeated shots at Microsoft's effort over the past few weeks. "When you look at how Copilot has been delivered to customers, it's disappointing," Benioff posted Wednesday on X.</p>

<p>Microsoft hasn't announced pricing on its agents, which will be added to the company's Dynamics 365 software. Copilot Studio, the custom agent-building tool, is included in Microsoft 365 Copilot, which it sells to business customers for $30 a month per user.</p>

<p>"All the competitive positioning will really come down to who's really got product that real customers are using and what are they realizing," Spataro said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/ub9599no_microsoft-generic_625x300_07_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chinas-xi-jinping-bilateral-starts-in-russia-first-since-2020-6856030]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi, Xi Hold Bilateral Talks In Russia, First Since Ladakh Standoff]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-chinas-xi-jinping-bilateral-starts-in-russia-first-since-2020-6856030]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:40:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[PM Modi and Xi Jinping met in Russia today for the first bilateral meeting since 2019. Ties between India and China had taken a severe hit since the military standoff in Ladakh as a result of Beijing's "unilateral" actions of violating the LAC.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping met in Russia today for the first bilateral meeting since 2019. Ties between India and China had taken a severe hit since the military standoff in Ladakh as a result of Beijing's "unilateral" actions of violating the Line of Actual Control, the de-facto boundary between the two countries.</p>

<p>The bilateral talks between PM Modi and Xi Jinping took place on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in the city of Kazan in Russia. It happened less than 72 hours from a breakthrough in talks - both at a diplomatic and a military level - ensuring that the status quo returns to what it was before May 2020, when the stand off in Ladakh began.</p>

<p>The breakthrough in the patrolling arrangement comes four years after the Galwan Valley clash and signals a move towards de-escalation in a region where both countries stationed tens of thousands of troops.</p>

<p>The meeting underscored the upturn in the India-China relation following a consensus on patrolling arrangement along the Line of Actual Control that had faced multiple hiccups over the last few years.</p>

<p>There have been a couple of brief interactions between the two leaders since the 2020 Galwan clash -- on the sidelines of the the G20 summit in Indonesia's Bali in November 2022 and the BRICS summit in South Africa's Johannesburg in August 2023. However, these were not bilateral meetings where trade, economic and other factors were discussed.</p>

<p>There had been no direct flight between the two nations for four years. Visa for Chinese technicians was granted after extra layers of security and investments from companies based in neighbouring countries needed extra vetting and security clearances.</p>

<p>The outcome of the bilateral meeting will make it clear if trade, economic and people-to-people ties will return to normalcy.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q4ktklm4_pm-modi-xi-jinping-meeting-ians_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[PM Modi and China's Xi Jinping held bilateral talks in Russia on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/what-makes-trump-what-he-is-6855728]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: What Makes Trump What He Is]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/what-makes-trump-what-he-is-6855728]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 17:07:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[How does such a deceitful, narcissistic, and malicious man seek election to the most powerful office in the world for the third time as the head of a party once led by Abraham Lincoln?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont">
<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/algql11o_donald-trump_625x300_23_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<p>Even by the standards of someone best known for scandal, corruption, and criminality, a recent <em>New York Times</em> listing of Donald Trump's controversial deeds makes for sober reading. "He is the only president in American history impeached twice for high crimes and misdemeanours, the only president ever indicted on criminal charges, and the only president convicted of a felony (34 counts, in fact)," the narrative begins.</p>

<p>By the time he ran for president in 2016, Trump had been involved in 4,095 lawsuits, in which he or his companies were defendants in 1,026 cases related to not paying taxes, not paying overtime, not compensating hired companies, and failing to abide by contracts. He was forced to shell out $25 million to students who accused him of scamming them, was found liable for widespread business fraud, and had his real estate firm convicted in criminal court of tax crimes.</p>

<p>Estimated by <em>Forbes </em>to be worth $5.5 billion, he has paid less income tax than at least half of American taxpayers, year after year. "That was smart," he has boasted.</p>

<h2><strong>The Seven Characteristics That Define Trump</strong></h2>

<p>Tony Schwartz, who ghostwrote Trump's bestseller <em>The Art of the Deal</em>, wrote recently: "There are seven characteristics associated with antisocial personality disorder, according to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders: deceitfulness, impulsivity, failure to conform to social norms with respect to lawful behaviour, irritability and aggressiveness, reckless disregard for the safety of self or others, consistent irresponsibility, and lack of remorse. I've observed all seven in Trump over the years and watched them get progressively worse. It's the last one - lack of remorse - that gives him license to freely exercise the other six."</p>

<p>Depending on how you count them, Trump has been accused of sexual misconduct by 19, 26, or 67 women. He has boasted about grabbing women by their private parts and is reported to have cheated on all three of his wives.</p>

<p>For the first time in its history, America may send a criminal to the Oval Office. The Chief of Army Staff who served under Trump has called him "a fascist to the core" and "the most dangerous man for this country". His longest-serving White House Chief of Staff has echoed these sentiments.</p>

<p>If elected, Trump has said he would turn the "military" on the "enemy within"—which he defines as anyone who crosses him or has crossed him in the past. To tackle urban crime, he suggests "one hour of widespread, extrajudicial violence by the police". Oh, and by the way, he has demanded the execution of the former Chief of Army Staff.</p>

<h2><strong>Understanding Trump's Unusual Rise</strong></h2>

<p>How does such a deceitful, narcissistic, and malicious man seek election to the most powerful office in the world for the third time as the head of a party once led by Abraham Lincoln? How does he stand a good chance of becoming the 47th President of the United States?</p>

<p>His 2024 campaign rallies resemble vaudeville acts where he alternately portrays himself as the saviour and protector, hurls lies and insults, compares migrants to Hannibal Lecter, promises political violence (mass migrant evictions will be a "bloody story"), and makes anti-democratic statements (such as prosecuting opponents and praising foreign dictators). He stumbles through words like "deportated," "bureucats," "Midworsten," and "Insaniticy." In a recent rally, when words ran out, he bobbed and danced to music for 39 minutes.</p>

<p>How does such a candidate improve his poll ratings from winning 41% of the electoral college vote in September, after a disastrous debate with Kamala Harris, to over 50% now? Most of his gains have come from the key swing states of Michigan, Wisconsin, and Pennsylvania.</p>

<h2><strong>The Ripples From The Mayflower</strong></h2>

<p>To begin to seek answers to that question, one might explore the deep vein of emotional nativism in American history; it's only half-jokingly said that those who arrived on the Mayflower in 1620 regard all who came later as outsiders. A more definitive starting point would be 1993, the year the US signed NAFTA (North American Free Trade Agreement). NAFTA led to the shuttering of over 97,000 factories in the US, primarily in the Midwest and Pennsylvania, resulting in the loss of around five million jobs as manufacturing moved to Mexico. The ripples have not ceased.</p>

<p>Chancy Adams, 43, lost his job at an iconic lock-making company in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, as recently as March 2024, when the unit shut down without notice. He began working there in 2010 for $10 an hour and moved up to a supervisory role at $30. He even bought a house for his family of five, including four children. Now, he works two jobs a day and still earns less money. He does not plan to vote on November 5; if he does, it will certainly not be for Kamala Harris—maybe Trump. Adams is Black.</p>

<p>When Trump declared his bid for the presidency in August 2015, he was not a political novice, as widely thought. He had fully developed his playbook, drawing on his sharp political instincts. He would be a populist, a demagogue, a Macho Man. He would cater to the basest instincts of man, mining anger and sowing division.</p>

<h2><strong>Attack, Attack, Attack</strong></h2>

<p>His personality was shaped by his father and his mentor, lawyer Roy Cohn, around three pillars: Attack, attack, attack—never say sorry, never admit defeat, and follow your gut instincts. His public image was constructed as that of a highly successful businessman on the hugely popular reality show <em>The Apprentice</em>, which obscured his massive inheritance and his six bankruptcies. Trust in politicians has dipped to a new low in the US, and Trump, the master of branding, never pretended to be one—in fact, quite the opposite. His Make America Great Again (MAGA) voter base was ready to be shaped into a cult.</p>

<p>By August 2015, he had already built an electoral base of 15% of what would eventually become his MAGA support by long cultivating three populist audiences: listeners of ultra-right-wing conspiracy theorist podcasts, followers of professional wrestling (WWF) who enjoy the spectacle despite knowing it's scripted, and readers of tabloids like the <em>National Enquirer</em>. Common to all three groups is an inability to distinguish fantasy from reality.</p>

<p>Political and behavioural scientists have offered a range of insights into human behaviour that explain Trump's enduring appeal. Social status is one of the strongest motivators for human behaviour, and citizens care much more about relative losses than about equivalent gains. Across developed democracies, the lower people feel their social status is, the more inclined they are to vote for anti-establishment candidates.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump's Popularity And Fears Among Whites</strong></h2>

<p>White men react more aggressively to a lack of status than any other group in US society, and there were many warning signs flashing for them in the 21st century. While non-college-educated white men bore the brunt of NAFTA, college-educated elites benefited from the growing digitalisation and financialisation of the economy. Much of Trump's appeal stems from his ability to turn the shame of downward mobility among white, non-college-educated individuals into a sense of blame.</p>

<p>Adding insult to injury, men were feeling overshadowed by the growing feminisation of US society, with girls outscoring boys in school and women outnumbering men in college admissions. The dominant dread among white men became the "fear of falling"—anxiety that, in the face of economic or cultural shocks, they might descend further down the social ladder.</p>

<p>US politics, meanwhile, was dominated by high-status professionals in both parties. Their alienation from the underclass, along with the erosion of the Democratic Party's blue-collar base, was best reflected in Hillary Clinton's characterisation of Trump's supporters as a "basket of deplorable." This constituency of "cultural losers of modernisation found themselves without any mainstream political actors willing to represent and defend their way of life", as one commentator noted. Enter Trump with the Authentic Appeal of the Lying Demagogue: "The greater his willingness to antagonise the establishment by making himself persona non grata, the more credible his claim to be his constituency's leader," the commentator continued.</p>

<h2><strong>What Makes MAGA So Appealing</strong></h2>

<p>Racial animus and general resentment toward minorities among whites—particularly Blacks, Hispanics, Muslims, and LGBTQ+ individuals, who are more inclined to vote Democrat—are among the strongest forces binding MAGA supporters. Trump built on this animus to incite fear of migrants.<br />
He claims that 20-25 illegal migrants are "terrorising" the US; in fact, according to the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office, 9 million migrants have entered the country under Biden, of which half may be illegal. He began targeting migrants in 2016, labelling them as "rapists" and "criminals". Today, he holds them responsible for high home prices, unemployment, infectious diseases, rising car insurance costs, unsafe elections, and even missing house pets. Not coincidentally, more than half of Americans support mass deportation of illegal migrants.</p>

<h2><strong>American Myths</strong></h2>

<p>The final word on Trump's enduring appeal rests with historian Richard Slotkin. The professor of American Studies argues that Trump rides on several key American myths. The first is the 'Myth of the Frontier', which posits that the increase in white wealth was predicated on expansion to the beyond and the subjugation of Native Americans, thereby embedding racial exclusion as a societal norm.</p>

<p>According to Slotkin, Trump's MAGA appeal also rests on the 'Myth of the Lost Cause'—the South's yearning for the days before the Civil War. This myth, Slotkin writes, "celebrates the Old South and its culture, and justifies violence, sometimes extreme, first to defend and then to restore its traditional structures of patriarchy and white supremacy".</p>

<p>Trump's 2024 campaign rhetoric, Slotkin notes, follows the 'Lost Cause' playbook. "He invokes fear of racial pollution by characterising liberal policies on immigration as the poisoning of the American bloodstream. He identifies himself as the agent of his people's retribution."</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly refuted all charges against him—personal, political, or relating to his business dealings—and has asserted that the true judgment of the American people will be delivered on November 5. That will be the day the American electorate demonstrates how good, or otherwise, they are at judging a person's character.</p>

<p><em>(Ajay Kumar is a senior journalist. He is former Managing Editor, Business Standard, and former Executive Editor, The Economic Times.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/g52btqeo_donald-trump_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-police-raided-restaurant-after-pizza-with-side-of-cocaine-became-best-seller-dish-6855295]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[German Police Raided Pizzeria For Serving Side Orders Of Cocaine]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/german-police-raided-restaurant-after-pizza-with-side-of-cocaine-became-best-seller-dish-6855295]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 16:15:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Authorities were alerted in March by food inspectors, and following months of surveillance, they arrested the pizzeria's manager at his home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police raided a pizzeria in western Germany after discovering it was covertly selling cocaine to customers who ordered a particular menu item. Authorities were alerted in March by food inspectors, and following months of surveillance, they arrested the pizzeria's manager at his home.</p>

<p>A large quantity of drugs, including 1.6kg of cocaine and 400g of cannabis, along with 268,000 Euro in cash, was found at the residence, according to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cew1wq8dr02o" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC</em></a>.</p>

<p>Although the manager was initially released from custody, he continued to operate the pizzeria and sell drug-infused pizzas, prompting a broader investigation. This ultimately led to the dismantling of a regional drug ring.</p>

<p>In a series of raids, around 150 officers targeted multiple locations, including two cannabis plantations-, one in Monchengladbach, where 300 plants were discovered, and another in Solingen, where 60 plants were found. Several homes linked to suspected dealers were also raided, resulting in the arrest of several individuals, including a 22-year-old believed to be the head of the operation.</p>

<p>During the raids, police confiscated weapons, money, and luxury watches. The pizzeria manager was rearrested while attempting to flee the country and remains in custody.</p>

<p>According to police spokesperson Mr Moltke, the pizza listed as "number 40" was particularly popular. Authorities have not disclosed the identities of others involved in the operation or the price of the drug-laced pizza.</p>

<p>It remains unclear how much the pizzeria charged for the special order.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lp8j7j7_pizza_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[During the raids, they came across two cannabis plantations]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-origin-pam-kaur-hsbcs-1st-female-cfo-in-160-year-history-6855240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Is Indian-Origin Pam Kaur, HSBC's 1st Female CFO In 160-Year History]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-indian-origin-pam-kaur-hsbcs-1st-female-cfo-in-160-year-history-6855240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 16:07:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[HSBC Bank has named Indian-origin Pam Kaur as its new Chief Financial Officer (CFO), the first woman to hold this position in its 160-year history. She is replacing Georges Elhedery, who took over as CEO earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>HSBC Bank has named Indian-origin Pam Kaur as its new Chief Financial Officer (CFO), the first woman to hold this position in its 160-year history. She is replacing Georges Elhedery, who took over as CEO earlier this year.</p>

<p>In a press release, HSBC Bank said that Pam Kaur will also serve as the Executive Director of the Board of Directors, effective January 1, 2025.</p>

<p>At 60, Ms Kaur has nearly four decades of banking experience, focusing on auditing, risk management and compliance.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Who is Pam Kaur?</strong></p>

<ol>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Pam Kaur qualified as a chartered accountant at Ernst &amp; Young and began her career in internal audit at Citibank. She joined HSBC in April 2013 as Group Head of Internal Audit and became the Group Chief Risk Officer in January 2020, taking on the responsibility for Compliance in June 2021.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">She holds an MBA in Finance and a BCom (Hons) from Panjab University in Chandigarh. She is a Fellow Member of The Institute of Chartered Accountants in England and Wales.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Pam Kaur has held several senior positions at major global financial institutions. Her former roles include Global Head of Group Audit for Deutsche Bank, CFO and COO of the Restructuring and Risk Division at Royal Bank of Scotland Group PLC and Group Head of Compliance and Anti-Money Laundering at Lloyds TSB. She also served as Chief Compliance Officer at Citigroup International and Global Director of Compliance for Citigroup's Global Consumer Group. She currently acts as a non-executive Director of Abrdn PLC.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">As CFO, Pam Kaur will earn an annual base salary of £803,000 (Rs 8.3 crore), a fixed pay allowance of £1,085,000 (Rs 8.7 crore), and a pension allowance of £80,300 (Rs 64 lakh). She is also eligible for discretionary variable pay, including an annual incentive award of up to 215 per cent of her base salary and a long-term incentive award of up to 320 per cent of her base salary.</p>
	</li>
	<li dir="ltr">
	<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Pam Kaur joined HSBC shortly after the bank faced scrutiny for anti-money laundering and sanctions violations, leading to a deferred prosecution agreement with the US Justice Department. Since then, she has significantly influenced the bank's risk management strategies, including her appointment in April 2019 as Head of Wholesale Market and Credit Risk and Chair of the enterprise-wide non-financial risk forum.</p>
	</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/a23ffml8_pam-kaur_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pam Kaur has held several senior positions at major global financial institutions (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-support-dialogue-and-diplomacy-not-war-pm-modi-at-brics-summit-6855089]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["We Support Dialogue And Diplomacy, Not War": PM Modi At BRICS Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/we-support-dialogue-and-diplomacy-not-war-pm-modi-at-brics-summit-6855089]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:47:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Wednesday said "India supports dialogue and diplomacy... and not war" as he spoke at a closed-door plenary session of the BRICS Summit in Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> on Wednesday said "India supports dialogue and diplomacy... and not war" as he spoke at a closed-door plenary session of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/brics-summit" target="_blank">BRICS Summit</a> in Russia.</p>

<p>Mr Modi - who on Tuesday told Russia's Vladimir Putin, whose country is at war with Ukraine, that "all conflict can be solved with dialogue" - emphasised his concern today and told the bloc of multiple challenges facing its members and the world at large, and called for action on those fronts instead.</p>

<p>"Our meeting is taking place at a time, when the world is facing several pressing challenges. The world is also talking about the North-South and East-West divides. At this time, preventing inflation... ensuring food, energy, health, and water security... these are matters of priority. And, in this era of technology, new challenges have emerged, like misinformation (spread online) and cyber frauds like deepfakes..."</p>

<p>"At such a time, there are high expectations of the BRICS grouping and I believe that we, as a diverse and inclusive platform, can play a positive role in all these areas," the PM said.</p>

<p>"In this regard, our approach must remain people centric. We have to tell the world BRICS is not divisive and that we support dialogue and diplomacy, and not war ..." Mr Modi said.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-meets-putin-on-sidelines-of-brics-summit-in-russia-6847075" target="_blank">In Meet With Putin, PM's Push For Peaceful Solution To Ukraine War</a></p>

<p>As an example, the Prime Minister pointed to the pandemic and how BRICS (which stands for Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa, the founding members) worked together, and said, "Just as we were able to overcome Covid, we can create ensure a secure, strong, and prosperous future..."</p>

<p>The global war on terrorism - a particular focus of the Modi government - was also flagged.</p>

<p>"In order to counter terrorism and terror-financing, we need the single-minded and firm support of all... there is no place for double standards on this serious matter," Mr Modi asserted.</p>

<p>"We need to take active steps to stop radicalisation of youth in our countries."</p>

<h3><strong>PM's UN Reforms Push</strong></h3>

<p>The PM also pitched for reforms of global institutions like the United Nations Security Council.</p>

<p>"We should move forward in a timely manner for reforms in global institutions like UNSC, multilateral development banks, and World Trade Organization," he said, while also cautioning BRICS members and partners against wanting to replace these institutions instead of reforming them.</p>

<h3><strong>On New BRICS' 'Partner Countries'</strong></h3>

<p>On the introduction of 'partner countries' like Egypt, Iran, Ethiopia, and the United Arab Emirates, Mr Modi said he was happy the "extended family" is meeting for the first time. "In this regard all decisions should be taken by consensus," he said, adding, "Guiding principles, standards, and procedures adopted at Johannesburg Summit should be followed by all member and partner countries."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Modi also expressed gratitude to Russian President Vladimir Putin for hosting the BRICS Summit in Kazan and for his leadership of the bloc over the past 12 months.</p>

<p>India and Russia share a "special and privileged strategic partnership", the PM said.</p>

<p>Russia has touted the BRICS Summit as a diplomatic triumph that shows Western attempts to isolate Moscow over the Ukraine conflict have failed. The United States has dismissed BRICS as a "geopolitical rival" but is concerned over Moscow flexing diplomatic muscles as the Ukraine war rages.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/egja187_modi-putin-xi-reuters_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-incoming-israeli-missile-turn-residential-building-to-dust-in-beirut-6855013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Shows Israeli Missile Turns Residential Building To Dust In Beirut]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-shows-incoming-israeli-missile-turn-residential-building-to-dust-in-beirut-6855013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:39:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The event has sparked global outrage and heightened tensions between the two nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The video of an Israeli missile striking a residential building in Beirut, Lebanon, on Tuesday is going viral across various social media platforms amid ongoing clashes between Israel and Hezbollah in Lebanon.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/video/shocking-moment-israeli-missile-brings-down-entire-building-in-beirut/"><em>The New York Post,</em></a> the multi-story building was reportedly located in the Tayouneh neighbourhood, next to Horsh Beirut, a city park. The viral video of the incident showed that the impact of the missile attack was so catastrophic that it caused the entire structure to collapse instantly within a few seconds.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Beirut, Lebanon<br />
<br />
US missile blows up entire apartment building with innocent civilians inside ??<br />
<br />
?Make sure you follow us for more uncensored news because our account is being censored <a href="https://t.co/zHqLdsT1Pl">pic.twitter.com/zHqLdsT1Pl</a></p>
— Fx Dose (@Zayn_Fxdose) <a href="https://twitter.com/Zayn_Fxdose/status/1848815071339708679?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>About 40 minutes prior to this missile attack, an Israeli military spokesperson had issued a social media post in Arabic alerting residents in and around two buildings on the southern suburbs of Beirut to leave the area.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-rules-out-negotiations-during-fighting-with-israel-6848780#pfrom=home-ndtvworld_world_top_news"><strong>Also Read | Hezbollah Rules Out Negotiations During Fighting With Israel</strong></a></p>

<p>The incident has sparked widespread outrage around the world. Local authorities and emergency services were immediately dispatched to the scene to assess the damage and provide assistance to any affected individuals.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Lebanon's Hezbollah movement said on Tuesday there would be no negotiations while fighting continued with Israel, and it claimed sole responsibility for a drone attack on Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's holiday home.</p>

<p>The group "takes full and sole responsibility" for targeting Netanyahu's house, Mohammad Afif, head of the Iranian-backed operator group's media office, told a press conference in the southern suburbs of Beirut.</p>

<p>"If our hands didn't reach you the previous time, then days, nights, and the battlefield are still between us," he said.<br />
<br />
<em>(With inputs from Reuters)</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ho0ledcg_missile-strike_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The missile strike led to the immediate collapse of the building.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hsbc-names-indian-origin-banker-pam-kaur-as-its-first-woman-cfo-6854901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[HSBC Names Indian-Origin Banker Pam Kaur As Its First Woman CFO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hsbc-names-indian-origin-banker-pam-kaur-as-its-first-woman-cfo-6854901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:28:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[HSBC Holdings Plc, which was founded by a Scotsman more than 150-years ago, named Pam Kaur the first female chief financial officer in its history.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>HSBC Holdings Plc, which was founded by a Scotsman more than 150-years ago, named Pam Kaur the first female chief financial officer in its history.</p>

<p>The 60-year-old brings a long focus on auditing, risks, and compliance across almost four decades of banking career spanning various global lenders. She joined HSBC in April 2013 as internal audit head, coming aboard shortly after the bank admitted to anti-money laundering and sanctions violations and entered a deferred prosecution agreement with the US Justice department.</p>

<p>Ms Kaur, who was educated at Punjab University in India, takes on her new role at a challenging time as interest rates fall and amid geopolitical tensions in key markets, including China and Hong Kong. The bank on Tuesday unveiled a broad restructuring across different business lines and geographies as newly appointed Chief Executive Officer Georges Elhedery embarks on ambitious cost cuts.</p>

<p>HSBC will have to find a way to shave off $2 billion in costs in order to sustain a key measure of the bank's profits, according to Bloomberg Intelligence.</p>

<p>"We had a strong bench of internal and external candidates to choose from and Pam was the exceptional candidate to recommend to the board," said Elhedery, who was elevated from CFO, in a statement.</p>

<p>Shares of HSBC slipped 0.4% at 1:03 p.m. in London.</p>

<p>With the promotion, Ms Kaur becomes one of the most senior women in banking across Europe. She had been seen as a front-runner for the role, ahead of other candidates including Greg Guyett, head of global banking and markets, Willard McLane, group head of strategy and corporate development, and Kavita Mahtani, the CFO of HSBC's Europe and Western Markets, Bloomberg previously reported.</p>

<p>Before joining HSBC, she also held compliance and audit roles at Citigroup Inc. and Deutsche Bank AG. Ms Kaur has served on HSBC's group executive committee for more than a decade and was named head of wholesale market and credit risk in 2019.</p>

<p>Her remuneration as CFO will consist an annual base salary of 803,000 pounds ($1.04 million), a fixed pay allowance of 1,085,000 pounds and a pension allowance of 80,300 pounds.</p>

<p>She's eligible to be considered for discretionary variable pay that consists of an annual incentive award up to 215% of base salary, and a long-term incentive award up to 320% of base salary.</p>

<p>"We are welcome to see more and more woman leadership in the market, especially for multi-national financial institutions," said Melissa Fung, a partner at Deloitte LLP. "This also echoes with the enhancement of board diversity policy under the Corporate Governance Code suggested by HKEX."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lahrqqco_pam-kaur_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-north-gaza-polio-campaign-postponed-due-to-violence-who-6854764]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Impossible For...": WHO Says Gaza Polio Campaign Postponed Due To Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-north-gaza-polio-campaign-postponed-due-to-violence-who-6854764]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:08:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A polio vaccination campaign in north Gaza has been postponed due to Israeli bombardments, mass displacement and lack of access, the World Health Organization said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A polio vaccination campaign in north Gaza has been postponed due to Israeli bombardments, mass displacement and lack of access, the World Health Organization said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>This final phase, due to begin on Wednesday, aimed to vaccinate more than 119,000 children in the Palestinian enclave under siege for over a year in response to militant group Hamas' attacks on Israel.</p>

<p>"The current conditions, including ongoing attacks on civilian infrastructure, continue to jeopardize people's safety and movement in northern Gaza, making it impossible for families to safely bring their children for vaccination, and health workers to operate," the UN agency said in a statement, reiterating its call for a ceasefire.</p>

<p>The polio campaign began on Sept. 1 after the WHO confirmed in August that a baby was partially paralysed by the type 2 polio virus, the first such case in the territory in 25 years.</p>

<p>Delays in a second dose for children could jeopardise efforts to halt transmission. "This could also lead to further spread of poliovirus in the Gaza Strip and neighbouring countries, with the risk of more children being paralysed," the agency said.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the U.N. Palestinian refugee agency called for a temporary truce to allow departures from areas of north Gaza, where it said "people are just waiting to die" after three weeks of Israeli attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2v00j6v8_north-gaza-polio-campaign_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This final phase, due to begin on Wednesday, aimed to vaccinate more than 119,000 children]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-at-brics-summit-to-hold-with-bilateral-with-xi-jinping-today-6854754]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi At BRICS Summit, To Hold Bilateral With Xi Jinping Today]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pm-modi-at-brics-summit-to-hold-with-bilateral-with-xi-jinping-today-6854754]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:05:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping will hold their first bilateral meeting since the 2020 Galwan clash today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who is in Russia to attend the BRICS summit, will hold his first bilateral meeting today with Chinese President Xi Jinping since the 2020 Galwan clash. The two leaders will meet in the city of Kazan, Foreign Secretary Vikram Misri had announced yesterday.</p>

<p>"I can confirm that there will be a bilateral meeting held between Prime Minister Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping tomorrow on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit," said Mr Misri. The BRICS is a grouping of Brazil, Russia, India, China, and South Africa.</p>

<p>The bilateral marks another upturn in the India-China ties after a consensus between the two countries on patrolling arrangements along the Line of Actual Control.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-discusses-early-discharge-of-remaining-indian-nationals-in-russian-army-with-president-putin-6851142">At BRICS, PM Discusses Release Of Indians From Russian Army With Putin</a></p>

<p>The two leaders, who arrived in Kazan on Tuesday to participate in the BRICS summit, had brief interactions only twice since the 2020 clash -- on the sidelines of the G20 summit in Bali in 2022 and the BRICS summit in Johannesburg in 2023.</p>

<p>PM Modi met Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian yesterday at the summit and emphasised the need for peace in West Asia. He also held bilateral talks with Russia's Vladimir Putin and said the Russia-Ukraine conflict should be resolved in a peaceful manner.</p>

<h3><b>First India-China Bilateral Since 2020</b></h3>

<p>The bilateral meeting between PM Modi and Xi Jinping will be the first since the 2020 face-off between the troops of the two countries.</p>

<p>Indian and Chinese troops had clashed in the Galwan Valley in June 2020, sparking a major standoff along the Line of Actual Control. Both sides had sustained casualties and ties between the two nations had soured.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-delhi-can-play-a-part-iran-president-meets-pm-modi-over-west-asia-crisis-6851024">"Delhi Can Play A Part": Iran President Meets PM Modi Over West Asia Crisis</a></p>

<p>The two sides held a series of military and diplomatic talks in the last couple of years, after which the troops disengaged from a number of friction points. In the latest breakthrough that is expected to lower tensions, the two countries this week reached a patrolling deal along the Line of Actual Control.</p>

<p>After the deal, Foreign Minister S Jaishankar said at the NDTV World Summit, Indian and Chinese soldiers would be able to patrol the border area in the way they did before the 2020 face-off.</p>

<p>Mr Misri the immediate focus of patrolling deal will be on disengagement and they will take up the issue of de-escalation and de-induction of troops at an appropriate time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/egja187_modi-putin-xi-reuters_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-leans-on-enthusiasm-of-black-voters-6854750]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Elections: Kamala Harris Leans On Enthusiasm Of Black Voters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-kamala-harris-leans-on-enthusiasm-of-black-voters-6854750]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:04:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One recent New York Times/Siena poll that set off alarm bells said Harris has only 78 percent Black support, compared to approximately 90 percent for President Joe Biden when he defeated Trump four years ago.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marching bands blared as students and alumni mingled during the homecoming parade at Howard University, the historically Black college in Washington where <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-absolutely-ready-for-first-woman-president-kamala-harris-6853027">Kamala Harris</a> graduated four decades ago.</p>

<p>The cutthroat US presidential election is likely to be won on the thinnest of margins, and polls showing gains by Republican Donald Trump among traditionally Democratic Black voters, particularly men, have made headlines.</p>

<p>One recent New York Times/Siena poll that set off alarm bells said Harris has only 78 percent Black support, compared to approximately 90 percent for President Joe Biden when he defeated Trump four years ago.</p>

<p>So, Harris will be counting on the enthusiasm of Black voters at cultural lynchpins like Howard -- one of a network of HBCUs, or historically black colleges and universities, that emerged during the decades of racial segregation and continue to exert powerful influence.</p>

<p>The Democrat may even use Howard's campus as her election night headquarters, according to NBC News.</p>

<p>Certainly, the homecoming festivities last weekend indicated strong support for Howard's most famous living graduate, as vendors sold campaign merchandise and visitors took photos with cutouts of the vice president.</p>

<p>Kacy Haynes, up from Louisiana to visit his son, said he "hadn't really heard a lot of the support" for Trump.</p>

<p>And while the Trump campaign has made inroads into the Black electorate, particularly among men, that support shouldn't be overstated, analysts say.</p>

<p>Michael Strawbridge, assistant professor of political science at Washington University in St. Louis, pointed to research that shows unflagging Black support for the Democratic Party, adding that he didn't think Republicans are "winning over anyone who isn't already on their side."</p>

<p>He also cautioned against polls that sometimes only include small subsets of Black voters.</p>

<p>"The real issue for many Black Americans is not Democrat or Republican.... The real threat among Black voters is them not voting on Election Day at all and feeling that they're not being appealed to and supported by either party," he told AFP.</p>

<p><strong>Barber shops vs HBCUs</strong></p>

<p>Trump may not be welcome at HBCUs but he is finding fertile turf in male-orientated circles, like the barber shop he visited last week in New York's Bronx borough. The event in the mostly Latino and Black neighborhood of Castle Hill was broadcast by right-wing TV network Fox News.</p>

<p>"You guys are the same as me. It's the same stuff. We were born the same way. I grew up in Queens and all of that," said the former president, who grew up in the borough's upscale Jamaica Estates community, and inherited a fortune from his father.</p>

<p>Strawbridge said such sporadic appeals to minority voters "come across as very opportunistic."</p>

<p>For Harris, the HBCU connections are especially useful in the pre-election period which coincides with campus homecomings -- a tradition in which alumni return for an autumn football game, parade and other celebrations.</p>

<p>The festivities are particularly pronounced at HBCUs like Howard, where Harris, who is half Black and half Indian-American, graduated in 1986.</p>

<p>Kalyssa Gillespie, a third-year Howard student said on a practical level Harris "doesn't really have to cater to us, because she already has our vote."</p>

<p>But, she said, Harris's efforts show "that she cares, that she will come back and give to her community instead of forgetting about where she came from."</p>

<p>As Election Day approaches, Harris has tried to spread her net further.</p>

<p>She chatted with popular radio host Charlamagne tha God and launched a new economic plan specifically to court African American males.</p>

<p>Last weekend, she visited Black churches in Georgia, including a Baptist megachurch near Atlanta.</p>

<p>Appealing to Black churches, HBCUs and Black sororities, which serve organizational roles in the Black community, is "crucial to a campaign that wants to get Black folks to the polls," Strawbridge said.</p>

<p>Confirming Harris's strong pull, visiting Howard parent Haynes said the only good things he had heard about Trump were "based off of his legacy as a businessman."</p>

<p>"But in those same breaths (were) the comments and the concerns of the past things that went on," including the ex-president's "behavior, stance on minorities, LGBTQ -- just all of the different demographics" he has offended.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dkob4plg_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Elections 2024: Kamala Harris will be counting on the enthusiasm of Black voters.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-relations-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-washington-post-trudeau-aides-spoke-to-us-paper-before-bishnoi-gang-links-claim-rep-6854740]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trudeau Aides Spoke To US Paper Before "Bishnoi Gang Links" Claim: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-relations-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-washington-post-trudeau-aides-spoke-to-us-paper-before-bishnoi-gang-links-claim-rep-6854740]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 15:01:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Senior aides of Canada Prime Minister Justin Trudeau, including his national security advisor Nathalie Drouin, shared confidential information about India - and claiming 'interference' in Ottawa's affairs - to a US paper, a Canadian publication said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two senior aides of Canada Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/justin-trudeau" target="_blank">Justin Trudeau</a>, one of whom is his national security advisor, Nathalie Drouin, shared confidential information about India - and claimed Delhi 'interference' in Ottawa's affairs - to a United States newspaper, a Canadian publication reported Tuesday.</p>

<p>The information was provided days before Canadian federal police alleged - as Mr Trudeau has in the past, but without concrete evidence - that "agents" of the Indian government work with criminal gangs to "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-bishnoi-gang-canada-bishnoi-gang-linked-to-indian-government-agents-canada-cops-big-claim-6792233" target="_blank">target South Asians... specifically pro-Khalistani elements</a>" in that country.</p>

<p>Royal Canadian Mounted Police Commissioner Mike Duhene and his deputy, Brigitte Gauvin, told reporters they believed Indian government "agents" had ties with the Lawrence Bishnoi gang, and were involved in the killing of Khalistani terrorist <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/hardeep-singh-nijjar" target="_blank">Hardeep Singh Nijjar</a>, a Canadian citizen, in June last year, as well as case of "extortion, intimidation, and coercion".</p>

<p>India had strongly rejected what it called "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.mea.gov.in/press-releases.htm?dtl/38417" target="_blank">preposterous imputations</a>" and underlined that since allegations were first made - by Mr Trudeau in September last year - the Canadian government "has not shared a shred of evidence with the Government of India, despite many requests..."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-we-had-said-no-evidence-whatsoever-india-on-justin-trudeaus-deposition-6806506#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"As We Said, No Evidence...": India On Justin Trudeau's Deposition</a></p>

<p>That sentiment was underlined last week after Mr Trudeau told a Commission of Inquiry he had only intel-based speculation and no "proof" when he linked "agents" of Delhi to Nijjar's killing.</p>

<h3><strong>Canada Officials, US Paper Met?</strong></h3>

<p>Canada newspaper <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/politics/article-federal-officials-provided-secret-information-about-india-to/" target="_blank">The Globe and Mail</a> said its sources had spoken of Ms Drouin and David Morrison, the Deputy Minister of Global Affairs, briefing the Washington Post on various aspects of India's 'interference', including involvement in the September 2023 killing of another Sikh leader, Sukhdool Gill, a gangster from Punjab's Moga linked to the Khalistani terror movement.</p>

<p>Gill was killed two days after Mr Trudeau first accused India in the Nijjar killing.</p>

<p>Spokespersons for Ms Drouin and Mr Morrison have claimed no information was shared, but spoke of an unsealed United States indictment from November 2023. According to The Globe and Mail, this, however, did not name Gill or the other Canadian targeted for assassination.</p>

<p>The Post, sources told the Canadian publication, was instructed not to report anything till Mr Duheme and Ms Gauvin held that press conference. The Post eventually did so citing 'Canadian officials' who claimed to have linked Gill's murder to India, although the federal police did not.</p>

<p>In their presser Mr Duheme and Ms Gauvin claimed to have evidence - none was presented citing ongoing investigation - that some Indian diplomatic staff work with organised crime elements to "collect - through questionable and illegal means - information on Canadian citizens... (that is fed to criminal organisations) that would then take violent actions..."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/WATCH?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#WATCH</a> | Ottawa, Ontario (Canada): "It (India) is targeting South Asian community but they are specifically targeting pro-Khalistani elements in Canada...What we have seen is, from an RCMP perspective, they use organised crime elements. It has been publically attributed and… <a href="https://t.co/KYKQVSx7Ju">pic.twitter.com/KYKQVSx7Ju</a></p>
— ANI (@ANI) <a href="https://twitter.com/ANI/status/1845871856990998816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Hours after the police officers' press conference Mr Trudeau spoke to reporters and doubled down on charges against the Indian government.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-doubles-down-on-charges-after-india-canada-diplomatic-showdown-6791322#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Trudeau Doubles Down On Charges Amid India-Canada Diplomatic Row</a></p>

<p>"I think it is obvious the Government of India made a fundamental error in thinking they could engage in supporting criminal activity against Canadians, here on Canadian soil..." he declared.</p>

<h3><strong>India, Canada Expel Diplomats</strong></h3>

<p>His government also named High Commissioner Sanjay Verma as one of the six 'persons of interest' in this affair, triggering further fury from Delhi, which retaliated by ejecting Canada's High Commissioner and five of his staff. On the expulsions (the second tit-for-tat round), Delhi said, "Sanjay Verma is India's senior-most serving diplomat", and slammed a "strategy of smearing India for political gains".</p>

<p>Canadian authorities investigating Nijjar's killing have arrested four people so far, and Mr Duheme said last week that 30 others, including those with alleged links to the Indian government. were charged.</p>

<p><strong>Trudeau's Political Future</strong></p>

<p>Mr Trudeau's allegations coincide with sliding support and tanking popularity; this month he survived a second parliamentary confidence vote in as many weeks before the 2025 election.</p>

<p>Ties between Ottawa and Delhi have plummeted since Mr Trudeau's allegations broke, with his critics in India accusing him of pandering to Khalistani terrorist vote banks in that country.</p>

<p>In May, Foreign Minister S. Jaishankar said that Justin Trudeau, by allowing political space to Khalistani separatist elements, had indicated the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/canada-showing-its-vote-bank-is-more-powerful-than-its-rule-of-law-s-jaishankar-5631952" target="_blank">terrorists' votes were more important than the rule of law</a>.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar underlined his assessment this week at the NDTV World Summit and criticised the Canadian government for "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-justin-trudeau-doubles-down-on-charges-after-india-canada-diplomatic-showdown-6791322#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">double standards</a>", referring to apparent differences between how Ottawa treats other nations' diplomats on its soil and the "license' it allows its representatives in India.</p>

<h3><strong>US' Position</strong></h3>

<p>The US has been discreet since the row erupted in September last year and has only emphasised the need for cooperation between the two countries, an appeal it made again last week.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220" target="_blank">NDTV Explains: US Charge Over Plot To Kill Terrorist, India's Reaction</a></p>

<p>The United States - which is conducting an inquiry about an ex-Indian spy linked to a murder-for-hire attempt targeting Gurpatwant Pannun, whom India considers a Khalistani terrorist - called for Delhi and Ottawa to work together, and said that charges need to be viewed "very seriously".</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-diplomatic-row-hardeep-singh-nijjar-killing-on-nijjar-killing-us-says-wanted-to-see-india-canada-cooperate-but-6800196" target="_blank">On Nijjar Killing, US Says "Wanted To See India, Canada Cooperate But..."</a></p>

<p>Nijjar - the mastermind behind banned terror outfit Khalistan Tiger Force - was on Delhi's list of 'most wanted' terrorists for multiple crimes, including the murder of Hindu priest in Punjab. Anti-terror agency NIA had offered a Rs 10 lakh reward for information leading to his capture.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/32dkuepo_justin-trudeau-reuters_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau faces a general election next year (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stranded-in-lebanon-sierra-leone-women-shelter-from-war-in-warehouse-6854635]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Stranded In Lebanon, Sierra Leone Women Shelter From War In Warehouse]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stranded-in-lebanon-sierra-leone-women-shelter-from-war-in-warehouse-6854635]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:50:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scores of migrants from Sierra Leone travel to Lebanon every year for work, intending to support families back home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not far from Beirut's heavily bombed southern suburbs, Jaiatu Koroma and her five-month-old daughter have taken refuge along with dozens of women from Sierra Leone in a dilapidated warehouse turned shelter.</p>

<p>After Israeli forces began heavily striking Lebanon around a month ago, Koroma, 21, from Freetown, said she strapped her young child to her back and fled her home in south Beirut, initially sleeping "in the streets".</p>

<p>She eventually was taken to the volunteer-run shelter -- an old concrete structure on the outskirts of Beirut now filled with mattresses, bed covers and hastily packed suitcases, as well as a donated baby crib and change table.</p>

<p>Wearing a red beanie, she expressed gratitude that she and her baby were now getting "food, water", nappies and a place to sleep.</p>

<p>A year of deadly cross-border exchanges between Israel and Lebanon's Hezbollah over the Gaza conflict escalated to all-out war on September 23, with Israel heavily striking Hezbollah strongholds in south and east Lebanon and Beirut's southern suburbs.</p>

<p>The bombardment has sent more than one million people fleeing, according to Lebanese authorities, with at least 2,546 people killed in a year of violence, more than half of them in the past month.</p>

<p>At the graffitied building -- an empty venue called The Shelter, usually hired out for events -- women sat on mattresses talking, resting, praying or doing each other's hair.</p>

<p>Others carried laundry in plastic tubs to and from a washing area, where lines of brightly coloured clothes were hung up to dry in a dark, damp room.</p>

<p><strong>Kafala system</strong></p>

<p>"I want to return to my country," said Koroma, as the sound of chatter echoed around the derelict space.</p>

<p>She said she worked for months but her employment agent took her earnings and she got "nothing", adding that the agent also had her passport.</p>

<p>Jaward Gbondema Borniea from the Sierra Leone consulate in Beirut said that "a huge number of our citizens... have been stranded".</p>

<p>Scores of migrants from Sierra Leone travel to Lebanon every year for work, with the aim of supporting families back home.</p>

<p>Migrant workers are employed under Lebanon's controversial "kafala" sponsorship system, which rights groups have repeatedly said facilitates exploitation, with persistent reports of abuse, unpaid wages and long work hours.</p>

<p>Borniea said the consulate was working to provide emergency travel documents for the most vulnerable, and collaborating with the International Organization for Migration (IOM) to facilitate repatriations.</p>

<p>Mathieu Luciano, the IOM's head of office in Beirut, said the United Nations agency had received "15,000 requests from migrants and their embassies for return assistance", including 1,300 who hail from Sierra Leone.</p>

<p>The UN agency estimates that "approximately 17,500 migrants... have been displaced" by the war, Luciano told AFP, out of around 180,000 migrants residing in Lebanon before the crisis.</p>

<p>Dea Hage Chahine, among a handful of volunteers running the warehouse shelter, said that "when we started 21 days ago, we hosted 60 women. We are at 175 now."</p>

<p>"We're working non-stop," she said, adding that some of the women require medical or psychological assistance.</p>

<p>"The hardest thing is... the number of women coming in every day is increasing".</p>

<p><strong>'Second-class humans'</strong></p>

<p>The volunteer said she secured the space after finding women camped outside the Sierra Leone consulate, who had later been kicked out of a government shelter to make way for Lebanese families.</p>

<p>The volunteers have set up a kitchen, subscribed to a patchy power generator system, installed some lights and arranged water deliveries for washing and showering.</p>

<p>They are also running an online fundraising campaign to help cover the women's journeys home and associated expenses, Hage Chahine said, noting many "don't have their passports".</p>

<p>She blamed the kafala system and an "inherited education of racism" for the lack of support for migrant workers, saying they were often treated as "second-class humans".</p>

<p>Among those hoping to leave is Susan Baimda, 37, who said she came to the shelter two weeks earlier "because of the fighting".</p>

<p>"The situation is very rough," said Baimda, but in the shelter, "it's very fine now."</p>

<p>"Everybody is taking care of us," she added as she and others helped prepare large quantities of pasta salad for dinner.</p>

<p>She has four children back home in Freetown, and has only seen them via video call since she came to Lebanon three years ago.</p>

<p>"Let me go back to them" and "to our country", she said.</p>

<p>"We are tired of the fighting... we want to save (our) lives," Baimda added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gt0tq5r8_isreal-attack-lebanon_625x300_16_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The UN agency estimates that "approximately 17,500 migrants... have been displaced" by the war.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/now-is-the-time-to-end-gaza-war-says-us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-6854535]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Now Is The Time" To End Gaza War, Says US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/now-is-the-time-to-end-gaza-war-says-us-secretary-of-state-antony-blinken-6854535]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:31:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Wednesday "now is the time" to end the conflict in Gaza, and urged Israel to avoid further escalation with Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said on Wednesday "now is the time" to end the conflict in Gaza, and urged Israel to avoid further escalation with Iran.</p>

<p>Israel is fighting Iran-backed Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon, and has pledged to hit back against Iran's October 1 missile strike.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, state media reported an Israeli drone strike on Tyre, after the military warned residents of parts of the coastal city to flee ahead of operations targeting Hezbollah.</p>

<p>The warning sparked a new exodus from the once vibrant city, which is perched on the Mediterranean coast, and AFPTV footage showed a plume of thick black smoke rising from the city after the strike.</p>

<p>"The situation is very bad, we're evacuating people," said Mortada Mhanna, who heads Tyre's disaster management unit.</p>

<p>"You could say that the entire city of Tyre is being evacuated," said Bilal Kashmar, the unit's media officer.</p>

<p>Blinken's visit to the region is his 11th since the start of the war in Gaza and his first since Israel-Hezbollah violence escalated to all-out war late last month.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began with Hamas's October 7, 2023 attack on Israel, which resulted in the deaths of 1,206 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally of Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed 42,718 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to figures from the Hamas-run territory's health ministry which the UN considers reliable.</p>

<p>"Since October 7 a year ago, Israel has achieved most of its strategic objectives when it comes to Gaza... Now is the time to turn those successes into enduring, strategic success," Blinken said as he left Israel, following meetings with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and other top officials.</p>

<p>On aid to Gaza, Blinken said he saw "progress being made, which is good, but more progress needs to be made and, most critically, it needs to be sustained".</p>

<p>Of Israel's pledge to retaliate for Iran's October 1 missile attack, the US top diplomat said: "It's also very important that Israel respond in ways that do not create greater escalation."</p>

<p>After Israel, Blinken will visit Saudi Arabia, which has put on hold talks towards a normalisation deal with Israel until a Palestinian state is created.</p>

<p>The US diplomat urged Israel to seize what he described as an "incredible opportunity" to move towards a deal with Saudi Arabia.</p>

<p>Previous US efforts to end the Gaza war and contain the regional fallout have failed, as did a bid spearheaded by President Joe Biden and his French counterpart Emmanuel Macron to secure a temporary ceasefire in Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>Hostages still in Gaza</strong></p>

<p>In his meeting with Netanyahu on Tuesday, Blinken urged his ally to seize on the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar in Gaza to work towards a ceasefire.</p>

<p>Sinwar was the architect of the October 7, 2023 attack that triggered the Gaza war.</p>

<p>Hailing his killing, Netanyahu said it did not mean the war was over, though he added that it could be the beginning of the end.</p>

<p>The militants also took 251 hostages back into Gaza. Ninety-seven are still being held there, including 34 the Israeli military has said are dead.</p>

<p>During his meeting with the Israeli premier in Jerusalem, Blinken "underscored the need to capitalise" on the death of Sinwar, US State Department spokesman Matthew Miller said.</p>

<p>This would be done by "securing the release of all hostages and ending the conflict in Gaza in a way that provides lasting security for Israelis and Palestinians alike", he added.</p>

<p>Netanyahu told Blinken that Sinwar's death "could have a positive impact on the return of the hostages", according to a statement from the prime minister's office.</p>

<p>Blinken also pressed for more aid to be allowed into besieged Gaza as concerns rise for tens of thousands of civilians trapped by fighting in the hard-to-reach north.</p>

<p>Israel launched a major air and ground assault in northern Gaza this month, vowing to stop Hamas militants from regrouping in the area.</p>

<p>The only medical facility still partially functioning in the targeted area has "no medicine or medical supplies", warned Kamal Adwan Hospital director Hossam Abu Safia.</p>

<p>"People are being killed in the streets, and we can't help them. Bodies are lying on the streets."</p>

<p><strong>Hezbollah heir</strong></p>

<p>After nearly a year of war with Hamas in Gaza, Israel shifted its focus to Lebanon in late September, vowing to secure its northern border under fire from Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Israel ramped up its air strikes on Hezbollah strongholds around the country and sent in ground troops late last month, in a war that has killed at least 1,552 people since September 23, according to an AFP tally of Lebanese health ministry figures.</p>

<p>Hezbollah kept up its attacks on Israel Wednesday, saying it had fired rockets at an Israeli military intelligence base in the suburbs of commercial hub Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the Israeli army said it had killed the Hezbollah cleric tipped to succeed the group's slain leader Hassan Nasrallah in an air strike three weeks ago.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has not issued a statement confirming Hashem Safieddine's death, but a high-level source close to the group had said that the militant leader had been out of contact since the strikes.</p>

<p>"We have reached Nasrallah, his replacement and most of Hezbollah's senior leadership", Israeli army chief Lieutenant General Herzi Halevi said in a statement.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the Israeli military again struck the southern suburbs of Beirut, a once densely populated bastion of Hezbollah, after issuing new calls for residents to evacuate the area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rngv1mh8_israel-hamas-war_625x300_20_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel is fighting Iran-backed Hamas in Gaza and Hezbollah in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/sikh-woman-employee-found-dead-inside-walk-in-oven-in-canada-walmart-6854421]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sikh Woman Employee Found Dead Inside Walk-In Oven In Canada Walmart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/sikh-woman-employee-found-dead-inside-walk-in-oven-in-canada-walmart-6854421]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:31:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 19-year-old Sikh woman was found dead inside a walk-in oven of the Walmart store's bakery department in Canada's Halifax city, according to media reports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 19-year-old Sikh woman was found dead inside a walk-in oven of the Walmart store's bakery department in Canada's Halifax city, according to media reports.</p>

<p>Halifax Regional Police (HRP) said they were called to a sudden death at the Walmart at 6990 Mumford Road around 9:30 pm on Saturday.</p>

<p>According to police, the woman, who has not been identified, was employed at the store.</p>

<p>Her body was found in a walk-in oven, police said.</p>

<p>The Maritime Sikh Society confirmed to CTV News that she was a member of their community.</p>

<p>“It's very sad for us, for her family as well, because she came for a better future and she lost her life,” said Anmolpreet Singh, with the Maritime Sikh Society.</p>

<p>She had recently moved to Canada from India, The Globe and Mail newspaper said.</p>

<p>The store has remained closed since Saturday night while the investigation is ongoing.</p>

<p>HRP Constable Martin Cromwell said police were aware of online speculation about the woman's cause of death.</p>

<p>“The investigation is complex,” said Cromwell.</p>

<p>“We understand the public is involved, and we just wanted to encourage the public to be patient with our investigation and be mindful that there are family members and coworkers involved.” Cromwell said Halifax police were coordinating with the appropriate agencies to help with the investigation.</p>

<p>“We urge the public to be mindful of sharing speculative information on social media,” HRP said in a statement on Tuesday.</p>

<p>A spokeswoman for the province's labour department said a stop-work order has been issued for the bakery and “one piece of equipment” at the Walmart store.</p>

<p>“It is important to note that the investigation has not yet reached a point where the cause and manner of death have been confirmed,” HRP said.</p>

<p>Nova Scotia's medical examiner is working to determine the cause of death, and the province's Department of Health and Safety is taking part in the investigation.</p>

<p>Walk-in ovens, also referred to as cabinet or batch ovens, allow for curing, drying or baking in batches using wheeled racks or carts. They are often found in large-volume bakeries in places such as supermarkets.</p>

<p>In a statement, Walmart Canada said the company is heartbroken and their thoughts are with the woman's family.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/90a6u5v_walmart_625x300_05_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[According to police, the woman, who has not been identified, was employed at the store.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-west-master-of-espionage-must-shun-its-double-standards-6854501]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: With CIA And Mossad, West Shouldn't Lecture Others On Espionage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/why-west-master-of-espionage-must-shun-its-double-standards-6854501]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:29:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[From the CIA's colossal resources and Mossad's precision strikes to MI6s legacy of colonial espionage and RAW's rising influence, these agencies navigate the murky waters of international politics anddiplomacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hrlt7l28_spy_625x300_23_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On a blustery, cold January day in 2011 in Lahore, a CIA contractor and former US Special Forces operative was driving through a busy street when two motorcyclists who allegedly attempted to rob him—or that is what he claimed—were shot and killed by him. In the ensuing chaos, he hit another car, got caught and was promptly charged with murder. You might think this was a minor incident, but Washington didn't.</p>

<p>Raymond Davis was hardly a big fish in the CIA pond, yet the Obama administration threw a diplomatic tantrum generally typical of a superpower. Diplomatic relations and the $2 billion in annual aid to Pakistan were frozen. The US falsely claimed Davis was a diplomat, deserving immunity. Pakistan's investigation showed he was a Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) operative and therefore wasn't covered by diplomatic immunity. Initially, it refused to back down despite the political heat.</p>

<p>In the end, after a 50-day standoff, Davis was whisked back to the US, but not before $2.34 million of blood money exchanged hands, reportedly compensating the victims' families. He later wrote about this cloak-and-dagger saga in his 2016 book&nbsp;<i>The Contractor: How I Landed in Pakistan's Deadliest Jail and Then Escaped</i>, revealing how the CIA operates when things get messy.</p>

<h2><strong>CIA's Long Arms</strong></h2>

<p>The Raymond Davis affair revealed how deeply the CIA was operating in Pakistan's backyard, raising public anger about America's covert meddling in a country it called an "ally" in the war on terror. The Pakistanis felt betrayed by their trusted ally.</p>

<p>This brings us to the present: the CIA, the agency behind countless covert operations all around the world, lectures India on cooperating with Canada over Hardeep Singh Nijjar's assassination. It's as if the US forgot it's been running around the world in the shadows since the CIA's inception in 1947, toppling governments, orchestrating coups, and assassinating foreign leaders—all in the name of national interest. But let's not dwell on the hypocrisy or "double standards", as India's foreign minister S. Jaishankar put it in a recent interview with&nbsp;<i>NDTV</i>. He didn't hold back in calling out Canada's double standards and pointed out how it is quick to gather intel through its diplomats on foreign soil but becomes very protective when it comes to limiting similar activities by diplomats from other nations on its own turf.</p>

<p>Indeed, while Canada plays the victim, it conveniently turns a blind eye to the unchecked privileges its own diplomats enjoy in India. Jaishankar, ever direct, put it plainly: "Double standards is a very mild word for it." His pointed remark wasn't just a dig at Canada's hypocrisy but also an indictment of the wider Western duplicity.</p>

<p>Take the recent case of the US charging former Indian intelligence agent Vikas Yadav with being involved in a plot to assassinate Sikh separatist Gurpatwant Singh Pannun in New York. Now, imagine if the tables were turned. Would the US sit quietly? Absolutely not. By now, Washington would have launched a full-scale diplomatic offensive to bring its man home, just like it did in the above-mentioned case of Davis. And if this led to a potential diplomatic row, so be it. The hypocrisy is so obvious.</p>

<h2><strong>West's Unquestioned Hypocrisy</strong></h2>

<p>In the murky realm of espionage, agencies like the CIA, Mossad and MI6 have always played by their own rules, causing diplomatic rifts, regime changes and the occasional assassinations. But when the tables turn, if at all, well, it's all about the rule of law and international cooperation. I do not suggest the Indian spy agency RAW is doing what the likes of CIA, Mossad and MI6 have been doing for decades without being questioned by anyone. The US, for instance, never lectured Israel for Mossad's countless extraterritorial activities overseas. India is cooperating with the US in the Vikas Yadav case. It wants to cooperate with Canada in its investigation of Hardeep Singh Nijjar's murder upon receipt of credible evidence.</p>

<p>Jaishankar's view isn't just an Indian perspective—countries across the Global South, and even some in the West, are getting increasingly fed up with the blatant foreign policy double standards.</p>

<h2><strong>'Ajax' To 'Condor', CIA's Myriad Assassination Plots</strong></h2>

<p>The US government's own report on assassination plots involving foreign leaders reveals some shocking truths about the CIA's covert operations overseas. The report&nbsp;<i>Alleged Assassination Plots Involving Foreign Leaders</i>&nbsp;wasn't fully declassified and released until July 23, 2002. The report, also known as the Church Committee report, investigated alleged CIA assassination plots against foreign leaders, including Cuba's Fidel Castro and Congo's Patrice Lumumba. The report also mentions other foreign leaders who were targeted for assassination, although their names were not disclosed.</p>

<p>Despite the White House's efforts to bury the report, the Church Committee conducted a thorough investigation into the CIA's assassination plots. It confirmed the CIA's involvement in these plots and recommended legislation to prohibit assassinations. The reports also raised important questions about the ethics and legality of targeted killings, which remain relevant today. And yet, the CIA often disregards its rule books and ethical standards.</p>

<p>Some of its notable plots were&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li><strong>Operation Ajax (1953)</strong>: Successfully overthrew Iranian Prime Minister Mohammad Mosaddegh, consolidating Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi's power. This was a joint operation between the CIA and Britain's MI6.&nbsp;</li>
	<li><strong>Bay of Pigs Invasion (1961): </strong>Failed to overthrow Cuban leader Fidel Castro, resulting in embarrassment to the US and loss of life.</li>
	<li><strong>Operation Condor (1970s-1980s):</strong> Supported Latin American dictatorships in eliminating leftist opposition, leading to human rights abuses.</li>
</ul>

<p>In more recent times, the CIA's extraterritorial actions in the Middle East, especially during the ‘War on Terror', have had long-term destabilising effects. US drone strikes, covert actions in Pakistan, Yemen and Somalia and operations in Iraq and Afghanistan have sometimes led to increased radicalisation. While these operations are aimed at counterterrorism, the resulting instability often fuels new cycles of violence and anti-American sentiment.</p>

<h2><strong>Mossad's Misdemeanours</strong></h2>

<p>Many experts in the West are bracing for a fiery Israeli strike on Iran in response to Tehran's October 1 missile attack. But here's the catch—it may not come from the skies at all. Instead of sending jets and missiles, Israel could very well stick to its trusted playbook: cyberattacks or political assassinations. After all, these methods have proven highly effective in the past, often executed with the help of local assets within Iran. So, while everyone waits for a military show of force, Israel might be quietly sharpening its digital knives or preparing for another covert strike that leaves no fingerprints but sends a very loud message.</p>

<p>It is widely believed, and not disputed by Israel, that Mossad has been actively involved in covert operations inside Iran for years, particularly targeting Iran's nuclear programme. One might recall the cyberattack using the Stuxnet virus, which disrupted uranium enrichment in 2010. In 2018, Mossad is believed to have stolen 55,000 pages of documents and 183 CDs from Iran's nuclear archives, revealing the country's nuclear programme details.</p>

<p>However, Mossad's most high-profile and controversial actions have been the assassinations of Iranian nuclear scientists. These operations are believed to be part of a broader Israeli strategy to delay or dismantle Iran's nuclear capabilities, which Israel sees as an existential threat. Between 2010 and 2012, at least five Iranian nuclear scientists were assassinated in Tehran in a series of precision attacks that many attributed to Mossad. Israel has not commented on them. The most notable method involved motorcyclists attaching magnetic bombs to the victims' cars during busy commutes. The victims included Majid Shahriari, a key figure in Iran's nuclear research, and Mostafa Ahmadi Roshan, a prominent scientist at Iran's Natanz nuclear facility. These killings sent shockwaves through Iran's scientific community, severely damaging its nuclear programme and provoking outrage from Tehran, which accused Israel and the West of orchestrating the murders.</p>

<h2><strong>The Strikes On Iran's Nuclear Ambitions</strong></h2>

<p>The most striking assassination occurred in 2020 when Mohsen Fakhrizadeh, considered the father of Iran's nuclear weapons programme, was killed in a highly sophisticated operation. Reports suggested the use of a satellite-controlled machine gun to eliminate Fakhrizadeh near Tehran. This assassination was a major blow to Iran's nuclear ambitions. Mossad's operations inside Iran demonstrate the agency's deep penetration into the country and its relentless efforts to undermine Iran's nuclear ambitions.</p>

<p>Iranian secret agents have also been active against Israel, with the Israeli government successfully foiling Iranian plots to assassinate Israelis in Israel, Cyprus and elsewhere.</p>

<h2><strong>MI6 And Its Legacy Spy Network</strong></h2>

<p>The United Kingdom, as the original colonial power, practically wrote the book on covert operations. MI6, founded in 1909 as the Empire's main Secret Intelligence Service, was tasked with protecting British interests worldwide—sometimes by any means necessary. One of its most infamous escapades was its role in the 1953 coup against Iran's Prime Minister Mohammad Mossadegh, a man who dared to nationalise Iran's oil, threatening Britain's golden pipeline. As mentioned above, the MI6 teamed up with the CIA for Operation Ajax, toppling Mossadegh and reinstalling the Shah, whose authoritarian reign would last until the 1979 revolution.</p>

<p>In more recent times, especially during the early 2000s, MI6 found itself embroiled in another scandal, this time involving Libya. Partnering again with the CIA, MI6 was accused of helping to render Libyan dissidents back to Gaddafi's regime, where they were tortured. The most prominent case was that of Abdel Hakim Belhaj, an opposition leader kidnapped and sent to Libya allegedly with MI6's help. After years of legal battles, Belhaj won an apology from Prime Minister Theresa May in 2018.</p>

<h2><strong>India's RAW Power</strong></h2>

<p>India's Research and Analysis Wing (RAW) was established in 1968 as the nation's primary external intelligence agency. While RAW has gained significant prominence within the global intelligence community, its capabilities still trail behind those of the CIA, Mossad, and MI6. With a reported budget of around $700 million, RAW operates on a fraction of the resources available to the CIA, whose budget hovers between $18-20 billion. Its main mandate is national security, with a sharp focus on counterterrorism—disrupting terror outfits, cutting off funding to extremists, and monitoring state enemies abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Contrary to popular belief, RAW does not operate with unchecked power. Its operations are governed by strict directives from the Indian government and, at least on paper, must adhere to Indian laws. While RAW plays a crucial role in safeguarding the nation, it is by no means a rogue agency; it works within the limits of its mandate, with each mission requiring government approval.</p>

<p>From the CIA's colossal resources and Mossad's precision strikes to MI6's legacy of colonial espionage and RAW's rising influence, these agencies navigate the murky waters of international politics and&nbsp;diplomacy.&nbsp;Yet, they remain indispensable tools of statecraft in an increasingly complex world.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/gtq0m7hg_spy_625x300_23_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-ndtv-world-summit-fedex-s-kami-viswanathan-urges-for-more-women-in-male-dominated-sectors-6854060]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Increase Representation": FedEx's Kami Viswanathan At NDTV Summit 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/at-ndtv-world-summit-fedex-s-kami-viswanathan-urges-for-more-women-in-male-dominated-sectors-6854060]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 13:23:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kami Viswanathan discussed the importance of “increasing the representation” of women in the logistics and supply chain sector]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"There is a lot more work to be done," said Kami Viswanathan, President of FedEx for the Middle East, Indian Subcontinent and Africa, as she addressed the challenges women face in traditionally male-dominated fields like logistics. Speaking at the NDTV World Summit, where the theme "Women Shaping the Future" resonated deeply, she highlighted FedEx's commitment to building a culture of diversity, equity, and inclusion. "Currently, 36 per cent of our board comprises women, and we have 26 per cent women across management globally," she said.</p>

<p>As India strives to become a $5 trillion economy, the contribution of women will be vital in achieving this ambitious goal. Today, women-led businesses are thriving across various sectors, including technology, healthcare, education and e-commerce. The panel discussion at the summit showcased how women are breaking barriers and setting new benchmarks.</p>

<p>Kami Viswanathan discussed the importance of "increasing the representation" of women in logistics and supply chains, saying that "includes changing preconceptions and biases."</p>

<p>She pointed out the critical issue of high middle management drop-off rates among women due to societal expectations around caregiving. She said, "Typically, we see a drop-off in women's participation due to added responsibilities and societal expectations around child care, elder care and so forth."</p>

<p>The panel also included Preeti Bajaj, CEO and MD of Luminous Power Technologies, who shared her insights on fostering an inclusive environment in the energy sector. Ms Bajaj highlighted that her senior leadership team comprises 33 per cent women and stressed the need for equity in access to opportunities. "The first A is access, equity of access to opportunities."</p>

<p>"Make sure that you're intentional about the calibre of women and they're getting equal representations on recruitment lists and that we are able to address the biases sometimes that come in," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The second bit is ambition," Preeti Bajaj said, adding, "Women have to aspire to field roles to get to senior leadership roles."</p>

<p>Ms Bajaj also articulated a call to action for women in the energy sector, declaring, "This is a revolutionary time in energy. We should be part of it so that we are part of the 2047 Viksit Bharat, so to speak," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Padmaja Ruparel, Co-Founder of IAN Group, reflected on her early days in the field. "When I started life in this field, there wasn't anybody, and that was the fun of it," she said. She emphasised how her journey involved a lot of "adaptation, education and evolution," which she believed was tied to a woman's intuition.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As an early-stage investor, Padmaja Ruparel stressed the importance of entrepreneurs. She said, "I can't be an investor if there are no entrepreneurs." However, she pointed out the troubling reality of India's women entrepreneurs, describing the growth as "very abysmal," with only 14.7 per cent of funding going to women in 2022, dropping further to 9.7 per cent in 2023. She found this decline "not encouraging."</p>

<p>Throughout the discussion, Kami Viswanathan stressed FedEx's commitment to building a culture of "diversity, equity and inclusion". "Our DEI Council sets priorities and tracks progress," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"And we have a program called 'Walk in Someone Else's Shoes' that helps build empathy for people of different diverse backgrounds and so forth. I think there is a lot more to be done. It's an ongoing journey for us," Kami Viswanathan added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/n64ju8h_ndtv-world-summit-womens-inclusivity-_625x300_22_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/american-billionaires-cliffside-mansion-is-up-for-sale-for-108-million-6853683]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Billionaire's Cliffside Mansion Is Up For Sale For  $108 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/american-billionaires-cliffside-mansion-is-up-for-sale-for-108-million-6853683]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:57:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Darwin Deason's estate spans nearly 13,000 square feet and features stone columns, balconies and a private elevated beach. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>American businessman Darwin Deason's La Jolla estate, ‘The Sandcastle', has been listed for $108 million, a potential record-breaking price for San Diego County real estate. If sold at the asking price, it would surpass the current record of $44 million, held by billionaire Egon Durban, who bought a Del Mar oceanfront property earlier this year.<br />
<br />
Mr Deason's estate spans nearly 13,000 square feet and features stone columns, balconies and a private elevated beach. The interior is inspired by old-world Europe, with gold accents, marble floors and mosaics. The guest house is modelled after Versailles's Le Petit Trianon. The billionaire, who founded Affiliated Computer Services and sold it to Xerox for over $6 billion in 2009, purchased the estate and a neighbouring parcel for $26 million that same year. He has since invested an estimated $60 million into its construction.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ltr1845g_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Mr Deason enlisted renowned designer Timothy Corrigan, who has designed for Hollywood elites and royalty, to craft the interiors. Designed with French elegance and inspired by the Hotel du Cap-Eden-Roc in Antibes, the estate features custom-made furnishings, a dining room that seats 16 and a nautically themed bar. The grounds include a pool, fitness centre and a beachfront boathouse with slate roof tiles imported from China.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k05eqvog_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Mr Deason also brought in $40,000 of imported sand to match Augusta National Golf Club's signature white shade. “Everyone who watches the golf tournament knows it is a spectacular shade of white,” he told <a href="https://www.wsj.com/real-estate/luxury-homes/a-billionaire-built-a-cliffside-version-of-versailles-now-its-asking-108-million-848fbaaa?mod=real-estate_lead_story" rel="nofollow,noindex">The Wall Street Journal</a>, which first reported the listing. The property also includes two natural caves at its base.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/njgk5jf8_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Credit: sandcastlelajolla.com</span></p>
</div>

<p>Despite the lavish design, Mr Deason, a Dallas-based businessman, says he doesn't use the property as much as his other homes. “In the history of La Jolla, there has never been and will never be another property built on the waterfront like The Sandcastle due to the present oceanfront construction standards established by the State of California,” agents Brett Dickinson and Ross Clark from Compass said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/50k3etlo_the-sandcastle_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The home features old-world European-inspired interiors.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>