<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:12:38 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israel-iran-conflict-excalates-india-inc-braces-for-sea-trade-disruption-6699258]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Israel-Iran Conflict Escalates, India Inc Braces For Trade Disruption]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israel-iran-conflict-excalates-india-inc-braces-for-sea-trade-disruption-6699258]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:07:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As the conflict in the Middle East escalates with Israel vowing to retaliate after the missile attacks by Iran, India Inc is bracing for a wider trade disruption across the key Red Sea route.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the conflict in the Middle East escalates with Israel vowing to retaliate after the missile attacks by Iran, India Inc is bracing for a wider trade disruption across the key Red Sea route.</p>

<p>The conflict can lead to higher cargo freight rates as Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah militia has close ties with the Houthi rebels in Yemen -- responsible for most attacks on ships travelling via the Red Sea route, say industry experts, adding that a direct conflict between Israel and Iran may severely disrupt the crucial trade route for the Indian exporters.</p>

<p>The Red Sea crisis started in October last year, with Iran-backed Houthi rebels disrupting trade in the area.</p>

<p>This has affected India's petroleum exports which dropped 37.56 per cent to $5.96 billion in August this year, down from $9.54 billion in the same month last year.</p>

<p>As per a recent Crisil Ratings report, Indian companies use the Red Sea route through the Suez Canal to trade with Europe, North America, north Africa, and part of the Middle East.</p>

<p>The report mentioned that these regions accounted for 50 per cent of India's exports worth Rs 18 lakh crore and 30 per cent of imports worth Rs 17 lakh crore in FY23. The country's overall merchandise trade (exports and imports combined) in FY23 was Rs 94 lakh crore, with 68 per cent (in value terms) and 95 per cent (in volume terms) shipped by sea.</p>

<p>The attacks on ships sailing in the Red Sea area since November last year have forced companies to look for alternative, longer routes past the Cape of Good Hope.</p>

<p>The Crisil report further said that this has not only stretched delivery time by 15-20 days, but also increased the transit cost substantially because of incremental freight rates and insurance premiums.</p>

<p>Industry experts say that India's trade with the Middle East still remains healthy due to friendly regional players such as Saudi Arabia, the UAE, Kuwait, and Qatar. The bilateral trade between India and the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) countries reached $162 billion last year.</p>

<p>As per the latest government data, the GCC now contributes 15 per cent of India's total trade and sectors like energy, defence, security and health are growing in the region.</p>

<p>Moreover, according to the latest International Monetary Fund (IMF) data, the trade via the Egyptian Suez Canal nosedived by 50 per cent (year-over-year) in the first two months of the year. In FY24, the Suez Canal's annual revenue dropped by about 23.4 per cent due to the Red Sea crisis. According to Osama Rabie, Chairman of the Suez Canal Authority (SCA), "revenues fell to $7.2 billion in the fiscal year 2023/2024 that ended in June from $9.4 billion a year earlier".</p>

<p>According to experts, the rising tensions in the Red Sea area are not only affecting the Suez Canal but also the maritime transportation market, trade movement and international supply chains.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, India issued a travel advisory for its citizens, advising them to avoid all non-essential travel to Iran due to the escalating tension in the region.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mg9iatt8_houthis-attack-ship-in-red-sea-reuters_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Red Sea crisis started in October last year, with Iran-backed Houthis disrupting trade.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescuers-save-4-stranded-killer-whales-in-russias-kamchatka-report-6700374]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rescuers Save 4 Stranded Killer Whales In Russia's Kamchatka: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rescuers-save-4-stranded-killer-whales-in-russias-kamchatka-report-6700374]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 17:07:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A group of Russian rescuers and volunteers have saved four killer whales stranded for hours off the Kamchatka Peninsula in Russia's far east after leading them to deeper waters, the SHOT Telegram channel reported on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A group of Russian rescuers and volunteers have saved four killer whales stranded for hours off the Kamchatka Peninsula in Russia's far east after leading them to deeper waters, the SHOT Telegram channel reported on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Russia's emergency situations ministry had earlier warned that the whales - two orcas and two calves - were stuck in a silted estuary.</p>

<p>That prompted more than 30 rescuers to use small boats to aid the whales, dousing them with water as they tried to push them into deeper waters.</p>

<p>SHOT said the whale family had been successfully escorted out and were safe.</p>

<p>Video published by SHOT showed rescuers trying to aid the whales in the pitch dark. "All right, everybody's safe and sound," one of the rescuers is heard saying.</p>

<p>The Kamchatka Peninsula is a 1,250-kilometre-long (777 miles) peninsula in the Russian far east, some 6,500 kilometres east of Moscow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/hjkpqvu_killer-whales-stranded-in-russia_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The whale family had been successfully escorted out and were safe: Report]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/matthew-perry-death-case-accused-doctor-expected-to-plead-guilty-6700196]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Matthew Perry Death Case: Accused Doctor Expected To Plead Guilty]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/matthew-perry-death-case-accused-doctor-expected-to-plead-guilty-6700196]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 16:40:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One of two California doctors who were among the five people charged in the overdose death of "Friends" star Matthew Perry is expected to plead guilty on Wednesday to a charge of illegally distributing the drug ketamine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of two California doctors who were among the five people charged in the overdose death of "Friends" star Matthew Perry is expected to plead guilty on Wednesday to a charge of illegally distributing the drug ketamine.</p>

<p>Dr. Mark Chavez has signed an agreement with prosecutors to plead guilty to a single felony count of conspiracy to distribute ketamine, a short-acting anesthetic with hallucinogenic properties.</p>

<p>Chavez is scheduled to appear in U.S. District Court in Los Angeles at 10 a.m. local time (1700 GMT) to enter his plea. At sentencing, he could face up to 10 years in prison.</p>

<p>Another physician charged in the case, Dr. Salvador Plasencia, has pleaded not guilty, as has co-defendant Jasveen Sangha, who authorities said was an illicit supplier of the drug and was known as the "ketamine queen." The pair are scheduled to go on trial in March.</p>

<p>Perry's live-in personal assistant, Kenneth Iwamasa, who admitted to injecting Perry, and the alleged middleman who said he obtained ketamine from Sangha, have already pleaded guilty to charges they faced.</p>

<p>Authorities said Plasencia purchased ketamine from Chavez, and in text messages to Chavez discussing the amount to charge Perry for the drug wrote: "I wonder how much this moron will pay."</p>

<p>Plasencia administered ketamine to Perry and supplied vials that were injected by the assistant, according to court documents.</p>

<p>Perry died at age 54 in October 2023 from "acute effects" of ketamine and other factors that caused him to lose consciousness and drown in his hot tub, according to a December 2023 autopsy report.</p>

<p>The actor had publicly acknowledged decades of substance abuse, including during the years he starred as Chandler Bing on the hit 1990s television sitcom "Friends."</p>

<p>Matt Binninger, Chavez's attorney, told reporters in August that his client was "doing everything in his power to cooperate, to help in this situation."</p>

<p>"He's incredibly remorseful," Binninger said.</p>

<p>The lawyer added that Chavez's regret stemmed not from Perry's celebrity but from the fact that "someone who was trying to seek treatment died."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i5lcn0rg_matthew-perry_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Matthew Perry died at age 54 in October 2023 from "acute effects" of ketamine. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stain-on-un-israel-bars-entry-of-secretary-general-antonio-guterres-6700005]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Stain On UN":  Israel Bars Entry Of Secretary General Antonio Guterres]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/stain-on-un-israel-bars-entry-of-secretary-general-antonio-guterres-6700005]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 16:13:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel has declared UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres as persona non grata and barred him from entering the country following his failure to "unequivocally condemn" Iran's massive missile attack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel has declared UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres as persona non grata and barred him from entering the country following his failure to "unequivocally condemn" Iran's massive missile attack on Israel.</p>

<p>A social media post from Israel's foreign ministry said, "Anyone who cannot unequivocally condemn Iran's heinous attack on Israel, as almost every country in the world has done, does not deserve to step on Israeli soil".</p>

<p>The post also said Mr Guterres is yet to denounce the massacre and sexual atrocities committed by Hamas murderers on October 7. Neither has he declared Hamas a terrorist organization.</p>

<p>"A Secretary-General who gives backing to terrorists, rapists, and murderers from Hamas, Hezbollah, the Houthis, and now Iran-the mothership of global terror-will be remembered as a stain on the history of the UN. Israel will continue to defend its citizens and uphold its national dignity, with or without António Guterres," the post read.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Today, I have declared UN Secretary-General <a href="https://twitter.com/antonioguterres?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@antonioguterres</a> persona non grata in Israel and banned him from entering the country.<br />
<br />
Anyone who cannot unequivocally condemn Iran's heinous attack on Israel, as almost every country in the world has done, does not deserve to step...</p>
— ישראל כ"ץ Israel Katz (@Israel_katz) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel_katz/status/1841422324890812763?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Yesterday, Iran launched a wave of missiles into Israel -- &nbsp;its second in the past seven months --to avenge the killing of top Hezbollah and Hamas leaders, escalating the conflict in the middle-east.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/otldtf18_antonio-guterres_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-tries-to-kill-terminally-ill-wife-to-ease-her-suffering-faces-5-years-in-prison-6699947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Tries To Kill Terminally Ill Wife To "Ease Her Suffering"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-tries-to-kill-terminally-ill-wife-to-ease-her-suffering-faces-5-years-in-prison-6699947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 16:01:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In December 2021, DeWayne attempted to kill Arenda by choking her, claiming he wanted to end her suffering.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Utah man, DeWayne McCulla, 46, pleaded guilty to attempted manslaughter for choking his terminally ill wife, Arenda Lee McCulla, 47, in an alleged attempt to "ease her suffering." According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/02/us-news/utah-husband-dewayne-mcculla-admits-to-trying-to-kill-his-wife-in-front-of-her-family-to-ease-her-suffering-in-hospice/">New York Post</a></em>, Arenda was diagnosed with invasive ductal carcinoma breast cancer in 2020, which spread to her brain, lungs, and liver by 2021.&nbsp;Despite undergoing multiple rounds of radiation therapy to combat her terminal breast cancer, the disease had progressed, leaving hospice care as the final option.</p>

<p>In December 2021, DeWayne attempted to kill Arenda by choking her, claiming he wanted to end her suffering. Family members intervened, pulling DeWayne off Arenda as she struggled to breathe. Investigators later learned that Arenda was "gasping for air" during the disturbing incident. She died from her long battle with the illness the next night.</p>

<p>“She didn't die with dignity,” her son Anthony Ryder told&nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.ksl.com/article/50819436/sons-complaint-led-to-charge-against-utahn-accused-of-trying-to-kill-terminally-ill-wife" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">KSL</a></em>&nbsp;in December.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2022, Mr Ryder filed a police report against his father, prompting an investigation.&nbsp;According to the arrest affidavit, DeWayne McCulla confessed to authorities that he had attempted to end his wife Arenda's life while she was receiving hospice care. This investigation led to McCulla's arrest and subsequent guilty plea to attempted manslaughter.&nbsp;</p>

<p>''During the conversation with DeWayne McCulla, he admitted to placing his hand over the victim Arenda's neck in an attempt to ease her suffering as she was dying from cancer and was on hospice. He said he put his face up against hers and put his one hand around her neck next to her carotid artery and pushed just hard enough to help her suffering and make her pass away quicker,''&nbsp;detectives wrote in the court documents.</p>

<p>During the investigation, DeWayne McCulla shockingly declared that "he would do it again" because of his love for his wife. He&nbsp;initially faced severe charges for attempted murder, carrying a potential sentence of 15 years to life in prison. However, he pleaded guilty to attempted manslaughter, a third-degree felony, in Utah's Fifth District Court. Instead of a lifetime imprisonment, he now faces up to five years in state prison.</p>

<p>McCulla's sentencing hearing is scheduled for December 12, where the court will determine the outcome of his case.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qd7a22to_arenda-mcculla_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[McCulla's sentencing hearing is scheduled for December 12.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-elizabeth-had-a-form-of-bone-cancer-claims-boris-johnson-in-memoir-6699937]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Queen Elizabeth Had A Form Of Bone Cancer, Claims Boris Johnson In Memoir]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/queen-elizabeth-had-a-form-of-bone-cancer-claims-boris-johnson-in-memoir-6699937]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 16:00:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Late Queen Elizabeth II had a form of bone cancer in her final years, former British Prime Minister Boris Johnson claimed in his memoir.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late Queen Elizabeth II had a form of bone cancer in her final years, former British Prime Minister Boris Johnson claimed in his memoir. In the book, titled<em> 'Unleashed',</em> which will be released on 10 October, Mr Johnson recalled the monarch's final days at Balmoral, Scotland. He also described the queen's appearance days before she died on September 8, 2022. Notably, the ex-UK PM's account is the first public indication by a former senior government official as to what the Queen's cause of death might have been. It is listed as "old age" on her death certificate.</p>

<p>"I had known for a year or more that she had a form of bone cancer, and her doctors were worried that at any time she could enter a sharp decline," Boris Johnson wrote in the excerpt, per <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/01/uk/boris-johnson-queen-elizabeth-ii-intl-scli/index.html" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>CNN</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the book, the 60-year-old recalled travelling to the royal residence of Balmoral for the customary outgoing audience and resignation. He described Queen Elizabeth in her last days, saying, "She seemed pale and more stooped, and she had dark bruising on her hands and wrists, probably from drips or injections".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"But her mind - as Edward (Queen's private secretary) had also said - was completely unimpaired by her illness, and from time to time in our conversation, she still flashed that great white smile in its sudden mood-lifting beauty," Mr Johnson wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-revelations-about-princess-diana-rumours-on-harrys-biological-father-6668803">New Revelations About Princess Diana In Memoir By Her Former Hairdresser</a></strong></p>

<p>Boris Johnson described the weekly prime minister audiences with Queen Elizabeth&nbsp;as a "privilege" and a "balm". "She radiated such an ethic of service, patience and leadership that you really felt you would, if necessary, die for her," he continued.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"That may sound barmy to some people (and totally obvious to many more), but that loyalty, primitive as it may appear, is still at the heart of our system. You need someone kind and wise, and above politics, to personify what is good about our country. She did that job brilliantly," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, according to <em>CNN</em>, Buckingham Palace has a policy not to comment on books released about the royal family and, as such, has not confirmed or denied Mr Johnson's assertions.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in the same book, Mr Johnson has also claimed that Buckingham Palace asked him to persuade <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/boris-johnson-gave-manly-pep-talk-to-prince-harry-in-bid-to-persuade-him-to-stay-in-uk-reveals-book-6665318">Prince Harry</a> not to quit royal life or leave the UK shortly before the Sussexes moved to North America. He wrote that he delivered a "manly pep talk" to the Duke of Sussex in a bid to convince him it would be a mistake to leave Britain. He said that officials in Downing Street and Buckingham Palace approached him in January 2020, believing that he might be able to dissuade Prince Harry of his decision.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0e98u5m_boris-johnson-queen-elizabeth_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Buckingham Palace has not confirmed or denied Mr Johnson's assertions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/47-tigers-die-in-vietnam-zoos-due-to-h5n1-bird-flu-virus-report-6699812]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[47 Tigers Die In Vietnam Zoos Due To H5N1 Bird Flu Virus: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/47-tigers-die-in-vietnam-zoos-due-to-h5n1-bird-flu-virus-report-6699812]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:42:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Forty-seven tigers, three lions and a panther have died in zoos in south Vietnam due to the H5N1 bird flu virus, state media said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Forty-seven tigers, three lions and a panther have died in zoos in south Vietnam due to the H5N1 bird flu virus, state media said Wednesday.</p>

<p>The deaths occurred in August and September at the private My Quynh safari park in Long An province and the Vuon Xoai zoo in Dong Nai, near Ho Chi Minh City, the official Vietnam News Agency (VNA) reported.</p>

<p>According to test results from the National Centre for Animal Health Diagnosis, the animals died "because of H5N1 type A virus", VNA said.</p>

<p>The zoos declined to comment when contacted by AFP.</p>

<p>No zoo staff members in close contact with the animals had experienced respiratory symptoms, the VNA report added.</p>

<p>Education for Nature Vietnam (ENV), an NGO that focuses on wildlife conservation, said there were a total of 385 tigers living in captivity in Vietnam at the end of 2023.</p>

<p>About 310 are kept at 16 privately owned farms and zoos, while the rest are in state-owned facilities.</p>

<p>The World Health Organisation (WHO) says that since 2022, there have been increasing reports of deadly outbreaks among mammals caused by influenza viruses, including H5N1.</p>

<p>It also says H5N1 infections can range from mild to severe in humans, and in some cases can even be fatal.</p>

<p>Vietnam notified the WHO about a human fatality from the virus in March.</p>

<p>In 2004, dozens of tigers died from bird flu or were culled at the world's largest breeding farm in Thailand</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7pfa0k2g_tiger-generic_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Vietnam notified the WHO about a human fatality from the virus in March. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/health/diagnostic-errors-can-occur-in-1-out-of-every-14-patients-new-study-shows-6699567]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Diagnostic Errors Can Occur In 1 Out Of Every 14 Patients, New Study Shows]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/health/diagnostic-errors-can-occur-in-1-out-of-every-14-patients-new-study-shows-6699567]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:08:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Diagnostic errors are likely to be occurring in as many as 1 in every 14 (7 per cent) hospital patients which requires new approaches to medical surveillance, a new study has stressed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Diagnostic errors are likely to be occurring in as many as 1 in every 14 (7 per cent) hospital patients which requires new approaches to medical surveillance, a new study has stressed.</p>

<p>The study, published online in the journal BMJ Quality and Safety, said that 85 per cent of these errors are likely preventable and underscored the need for new approaches to improving surveillance to avoid these mistakes from happening in the first place.</p>

<p>The most frequent diagnoses associated with diagnostic errors included heart failure, acute kidney failure, sepsis, pneumonia, respiratory failure, altered mental state, abdominal pain and hypoxaemia (low blood oxygen levels).</p>

<p>According to the study, cases deemed to be at high risk of diagnostic error were categorised as transfer to intensive care 24 or more hours after admission, death within 90 days of admission either in hospital or after discharge and complex clinical issues but no transfer to intensive care or death within 90 days of admission.</p>

<p>"Complex clinical issues included clinical deterioration, treatment by several different medical teams, unexpected events such as cancelled surgery, unclear or discrepant diagnostic information recorded in the medical notes," the findings showed.</p>

<p>Harm was classified as minor, moderate, severe, and fatal, and whether the diagnostic error contributed to the harm and whether it was preventable were also assessed. Cases with discrepancies or uncertainty about the diagnostic error or its impact were further reviewed by an expert panel.</p>

<p>Among all the cases reviewed, diagnostic errors were found in 160 cases (154 patients). These comprised intensive care transfer (54), death within 90 days (34), complex clinical issues (52) and low risk patients (20).</p>

<p>The study authors wrote that an estimated 85 per cent of harmful diagnostic errors were preventable, with older, White, non-Hispanic, non-privately insured and high-risk patients most at risk.</p>

<p>The researchers suggested that a careful analysis of the errors and integrating AI tools into the workflow should help minimise their prevalence, by improving monitoring and triggering timely interventions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/0eclt3g8_ai-tool-to-help-make-real-time-diagnosis-during-surgery-says-study_625x300_26_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The study shows that 85 per cent of harmful diagnostic errors were preventable. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strike-targets-beirut-southern-suburbs-again-lebanon-state-media-6699540]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Targets Beirut's Southern Suburbs After Night Strikes: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-strike-targets-beirut-southern-suburbs-again-lebanon-state-media-6699540]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:02:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanese official media said an Israeli strike Wednesday targeted Beirut's southern suburbs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanese official media said an Israeli strike Wednesday targeted Beirut's southern suburbs, after a night of repeated strikes on the area, where Hezbollah holds sway.</p>

<p>"Israeli aircraft targeted the southern suburbs with a strike," the National News Agency reported, while an AFP photographer saw more smoke rising from the area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1b90eifo_israel-strikes-lebanon-afp-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli strike reportedly took place in the southern suburbs of Beirut where Hezbollah holds sway.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-special-ops-israel-carried-out-in-24-hours-of-ground-raids-into-lebanon-6699536]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside Israeli Ground Raids Against Lebanon's "Conquer The Galilee" Plan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-special-ops-israel-carried-out-in-24-hours-of-ground-raids-into-lebanon-6699536]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:01:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezbollah is planning to replicate its own "October 7-style" attack on Israel to capture the northern Galilee region, the Israeli Defence Forces have claimed as they began ground incursions into the Hezbollah stronghold on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hezbollah is planning to replicate its own "October 7-style" attack on Israel to capture the northern Galilee region, the Israeli Defence Forces have claimed as they began ground incursions into the Hezbollah stronghold on Monday. The claims of ground invasion by Israel have been denied by Hezbollah though the Lebanese government has termed it "one of the most dangerous phases of its history".</p>

<p>The October 7 attacks by the Palestinian Hamas group sparked the deadly Middle East crisis that has expanded to the Hezbollah-ruled Lebanon. Israel, which is fighting Hezbollah on its north and Hamas on its south, claims the Lebanese group was using border villages to launch a fresh assault, dubbed the 'Conquer the Galilee' operation.</p>

<h2><strong>'Conquer The Galilee'</strong></h2>

<p>The region of Galilee lies north of Israel, known for the lake Sea of Galilee where Jesus Christ is believed to have walked on water. It's a mountainous and fertile region that extends from the coastal plains to the shores of the Mediterranean Sea. Israel claims Hezbollah's rocket attacks in this northern region have forced about 60,000 Israelis out of their homes, whom they now want to rehabilitate.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/4kmrcgu8_israel-operation-in-lebanon_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Hezbollah has openly declared it plans to carry out an October 7-style massacre on an even larger scale on Israel's northern border, said IDF spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari. To facilitate their plan, they have been digging tunnels under the homes in border villages and stocking arms, he said while de-classifying Israeli operations into Lebanon.</p>

<p>The operations saw Israeli forces enter Hezbollah compounds in dozens of locations and dismantle Hezbollah infrastructure. The raids exposed Hezbollah's hidden weapons cache while over 700 Hezbollah terror assets were dismantled, said the spokesperson.</p>

<p>Here are three such operations carried out by Israeli operations in</p>

<h2><strong>Meiss El Jabal</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pdokhcmo_meiss-el-jabal_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Lebanese village of Meiss El Jabal is just a few hundred meters from Kiryat Shmona, an Israeli city. Israel claims over 20,000 residents had to flee this city due to Hezbollah attacks, so did Lebanese residents due to their "terrorist activities".</p>

<p>Hezbollah operatives dug underground infrastructure under a house in the village to store weapons, said Rear Admiral Hagari said Israeli troops. They had planned this to be their preparation area before they invade Israeli territory, he added.</p>

<p>In the basement of the house, an elevated platform was built to hide the shaft that led to an underground tunnel. The Israeli spokesperson said the tunnel was 150 metres long and excavated in stone, and they dismantled it ground and aerial strikes.</p>

<h2><strong>Kfarkela</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aniok9ug_kfarkela-_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Much like Meiss El Jabal, Kfarkela is another border village only a few hundred meters from Israel's Metula. In Kfarkela, Israeli troops conducted a targeted raid on this house where a tunnel was exposed under the bed in a children's room.</p>

<p>"The soldiers went inside the tunnel shaft and revealed a 100-meter-long underground tunnel excavated in stone. The troops scanned the tunnel and found weapons stored in barrels. In one of the rooms, they exposed a weapons storage facility intended to be used by Hezbollah on the day of the planned invasion," said Rear Admiral Hagari.</p>

<h2><strong>Nurit</strong></h2>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bvhvcl98_nurit_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Nurit lies between the Israeli border and the Lebanese village of Ayt Al Shaab. Israelis targeted what they claimed were Hezbollah targets in this village, including military outposts and rocket launchers. Here, the IDF located a "Hezbollah combat compound" that included combat trenches, both above and below the ground. "This network of trenches connects to an underground tunnel which included a weapons storage facility, a command, and control center, and preparation and living spaces for Hezbollah terrorists," said Hagari.</p>

<p>The spokesperson said Israeli soldiers raided combat trenches at the top of a mountain and found an access point to underground tunnel routes - towards the Lebanese village of Ayt Al Shaab. In the tunnel, the sounds found a large number of weapons, Israel claimed.</p>

<p>Hagari said they also found a map in a Hezbollah compound that the group planned to give to its operatives before their 'Conquer the Galilee' invasion. The map marked Israeli communities, IDF posts, access roads and targets for attack.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/td3no74_israel-troops-in-lebanon_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-what-are-countries-doing-to-rescue-nationals-out-of-lebanon-amid-conflict-6699382]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Countries Are Doing To Rescue Nationals Out Of Lebanon Amid Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-lebanon-conflict-what-are-countries-doing-to-rescue-nationals-out-of-lebanon-amid-conflict-6699382]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:40:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Western nations are ramping up contingency plans to evacuate citizens from Lebanon after a sharp escalation in the conflict between Israel and the Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah, coupled with Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Western nations are ramping up contingency plans to evacuate citizens from Lebanon after a sharp escalation in the conflict between Israel and the Lebanese armed movement Hezbollah, coupled with Iran's missile attack on Israel on Tuesday.</p>

<p>No country has launched a large-scale military evacuation yet, though some are chartering aircraft as Beirut airport stays open. Plans to evacuate to Cyprus by sea will enable the movement of larger groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Here are details on contingency planning:</p>

<h3><strong>AUSTRALIA</strong></h3>

<p>Its contingency plans could include evacuation by sea, though authorities have urged an estimated 15,000 citizens in Lebanon to leave while Beirut airport remains open.</p>

<h3><strong>BELGIUM</strong></h3>

<p>Belgium's foreign ministry has advised citizens to leave as soon as possible, the Belga news agency said.</p>

<h3><strong>CANADA</strong></h3>

<p>News reports from Canada suggest it will cooperate with Australia in evacuating nationals by sea. The plan involves contracting a commercial vessel to ferry out 1,000 people a day, the Toronto Star newspaper said.</p>

<h3><strong>CYPRUS</strong></h3>

<p>The European Union member state closest to the Middle East is a likely hub for evacuations, having processed about 60,000 people fleeing the Hezbollah-Israel war in 2006. Neighbouring Turkey has offered facilities as well.</p>

<p>Cyprus has asked Greece to provide an aircraft that could be used to evacuate its nationals who wish to leave. There are an estimated 1,500 Cypriots in Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>FRANCE</strong></h3>

<p>France has not issued an evacuation order, despite having had plans for several months. Present contingency plans centre on Cyprus and Beirut airport, while it is also discussing evacuations via Turkey. France has a warship in the region, while a French helicopter carrier will arrive in the eastern Mediterranean in the coming days and take up position in case a decision is taken to evacuate foreign nationals from Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>GERMANY</strong></h3>

<p>Germany has evacuated non-essential staff, families of embassy workers and German nationals who are medically vulnerable from Lebanon and will support others trying to leave, the foreign and defence ministries said in a joint statement on Monday.</p>

<h3><strong>GREECE</strong></h3>

<p>The Greek foreign ministry has urged its citizens to leave Lebanon and avoid any travel there, with a frigate on standby in case assistance is needed.</p>

<h3><strong>ITALY</strong></h3>

<p>Italy has cut diplomatic staff and beefed up security personnel at its Beirut embassy. Foreign Minister Antonio Tajani has repeatedly urged nationals to leave the country and sought assurances from Israel over the safety of Italian peacekeepers in the area.</p>

<h3><strong>THE NETHERLANDS</strong></h3>

<p>The Netherlands will repatriate its citizens from Lebanon, Dutch news agency ANP said on Tuesday.</p>

<h3><strong>POLAND</strong></h3>

<p>Poland will limit staff numbers at its Beirut embassy, a foreign ministry spokesperson said on Tuesday, adding that Warsaw would organise transport for citizens wanting to leave Lebanon.</p>

<h3><strong>PORTUGAL</strong></h3>

<p>Prime Minister Luis Montenegro has advised against travel to Lebanon, which assisted in the evacuation of a small number of Portuguese citizens living there.</p>

<h3><strong>TURKEY</strong></h3>

<p>Turkey is ready for a possible evacuation of Turks from Lebanon via air and sea and is working with about 20 countries to ready its ports and airports for a possible evacuation of foreign nationals via Turkey. About 14,000 Turkish citizens were registered at the consulate in Lebanon, but the number was not definitive.</p>

<h3><strong>UNITED KINGDOM</strong></h3>

<p>Britain has urged nationals to leave immediately. It has moved about 700 troops to Cyprus, bolstering its military assets, including two Royal Navy ships. It also has two military bases on the island. Britain has chartered a flight to help meet any additional demand from Britons wishing to leave on Wednesday and will fly them directly back to London.</p>

<h3><strong>UNITED STATES</strong></h3>

<p>The United States has ordered dozens of troops deployed to Cyprus to help prepare for scenarios such as an evacuation of Americans from Lebanon. It is working with airlines to add flights out of Lebanon, with more seats for Americans, the State Department said on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8t455i7_beirut-airport-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Western nations are ramping up contingency plans to evacuate citizens from Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-tim-walz-vice-presidential-debate-us-elections-2024-fact-checking-who-said-what-in-the-vance-walz-veep-debate-ahead-of-us-polls-6699277]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Checking Who Said What In The Vance-Walz Veep Debate Ahead Of US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jd-vance-vs-tim-walz-vice-presidential-debate-us-elections-2024-fact-checking-who-said-what-in-the-vance-walz-veep-debate-ahead-of-us-polls-6699277]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:28:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democrat Tim Walz and Republican JD Vance faced off in New York City on Tuesday night for their one and only vice-presidential debate, hosted by CBS News.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democrat Tim Walz and Republican JD Vance faced off in New York City on Tuesday night for their one and only vice-presidential debate, hosted by CBS News.</p>

<p>Reuters examined 12 statements made by the two running mates.</p>

<p>While Reuters monitored the entire debate, this fact check did not examine every statement. It focuses on topics and narratives that are part of broader public discourse and can be assessed with credible evidence.</p>

<h3><strong>STATEMENTS BY WALZ</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Walz said that the US is producing more natural gas and more oil than ever before. (Timestamp 9:15 p.m. ET)</p>

<h4><strong>&nbsp;WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is mostly true. In March 2024, the government Energy Information Administration said in a release that the US had produced "more crude oil than any nation at any time" for a sixth straight year. The report added that it is unlikely the record for 2023 will be broken by another country in the "near term," as none have a production capacity of 13.0 million barrels per day. The US averaged 12.9 million barrels per day that year.</p>

<p>Monthly production of dry natural gas in the US reached a record high in December 2023, having steadily increased through most of the past decade. However, production is forecast to decline in 2024, which would mark the first time output declined since 2020.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>"Donald Trump hasn't paid any federal tax in 10 of the last 15 years, and the last year as president." (9:35 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>This is mostly true based on the information available. In 2020, the New York Times reported, based on an analysis of tax return data from 2017, that Trump had paid no income taxes in 10 of the previous 15 years. This was "largely because he reported losing much more money than he made," the Times said. Trump did pay $750 the year he won the 2020 election, the paper added, as well as in his first year in the White House. Trump had dismissed the report as "fake news."</p>

<p>In 2022, the US House Ways and Means Committee released Trump's tax returns for 2015 through 2020, which showed that Trump paid no income tax during the final full year of his presidency. "Trump and his wife, Melania, paid some form of tax during all four years, the documents showed, but were able to minimize their income taxes in several years as income from Trump's businesses was more than offset by deductions and losses," Reuters reported.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Minnesota's child tax credit "reduces childhood poverty by a third." (9:30 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is unknown. The 2023 child tax credit program for low- and middle-income families was projected to cut child poverty in Minnesota by one-third based on an analysis by Columbia University's Center on Poverty &amp; Social Policy. &nbsp;</p>

<p>No report examining whether the child tax credit program did result in a one-third reduction in child poverty in the state has been published.&nbsp;</p>

<p>An August 2024 press release by the governor noted figures from the state's Department of Revenue that said the program "put over $545 million into the budgets of more than 215,000 Minnesota families" between 2023 and 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Minnesota is ranked first in healthcare (9:46 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This depends on who you ask. It is true based on data published in July 2024 by the financial information site WalletHub, which Walz has previously cited as governor of Minnesota.</p>

<p>The site ranked Minnesota as the state with the best healthcare system that provides low healthcare costs, a high number of convenient care clinics per capita, a high-quality public hospital system and low emergency room wait times.</p>

<p>Minnesota also topped the chart in a Forbes analysis, but other rankings with different methodologies rate the states differently.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<h4>"Minneapolis is the one city where we've seen the lowest inflation rates," the Minnesota governor said. (10:07 p.m.)</h4>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW </strong>&nbsp;</h4>

<p>This is mostly true during certain periods in the past 1.5 years. Data from the US Bureau of Labor Statistics on the 12-month percentage change in the Consumer Price Index, which measures inflation across metropolitan areas, found that the Minneapolis-Saint Paul area recorded the lowest inflation rate in the country in May and July 2023, and again in March 2024.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Walz said Trump created the largest trade deficit in American history with China. (9:34 p.m. ET)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is true. The US trade deficit in goods with China reached a record high during Trump's second year in the White House. The trade gap rose by 11.6% to $419.2 billion in 2018, from the previous record of $375.5 billion in 2017, a Commerce Department report showed in 2019. &nbsp;</p>

<p>In 2018 under Trump, the US imposed tariffs on $250 billion worth of goods imported from China, with Beijing then retaliating with duties on $110 billion worth of American products, including soybeans and other commodities.</p>

<h3><strong>STATEMENTS BY VANCE</strong></h3>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said Iran "received over $100 billion in unfrozen assets thanks to the Kamala Harris administration." (Timestamp 9:06 p.m.)&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is mixed. In August 2023, US President Joe Biden approved a prisoner swap deal between the US and Iran that involved the unfreezing of $6 billion in Iranian funds that were frozen in South Korea.&nbsp;</p>

<p>After the Iranian-backed Palestinian group Hamas attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, the U.S. said five days later that Iran would not gain access to the funds, parked in a Qatari bank, anytime soon and that Washington retained the right to freeze the funds.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, Biden had previously sought to revive a 2015 nuclear deal with Iran, which had been abandoned by Donald Trump. The talks stalled in September 2022.</p>

<p>In 2015, US officials said that the deal would give Iran access to $100 billion in frozen assets if implemented. Former Israeli Prime Minister Yair Lapid said in 2022 that the deal would give Tehran $100 billion a year to destabilize the Middle East, but did not provide details for the calculation.&nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>"When was the last time that an American president did not have a major conflict break out? The only answer is during the four years Donald Trump was president," Vance said. (9:10 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This needs more context. Trump joins other presidents such as Barack Obama, Bill Clinton, Ronald Reagan, Jimmy Carter, Gerald Ford, Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy and Dwight D. Eisenhower in not officially bringing the US into a new war since 1945.</p>

<p>Trump's presidency, however, involved military hostilities and the risk of new wars. Trump ordered in 2020 a drone strike that killed Iranian General Qassem Soleimani, and launched in 2017 an attack on a Syrian army base, a move that marked an escalation of the US military's role in Syria.</p>

<p>The former president also said in 2017 during a speech to the United Nations General Assembly that he would "totally destroy" North Korea.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said the US is "the cleanest economy in the entire world." (9:12 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>This is false. According to the EU's Emissions Database for Global Atmospheric Research 2024 report, the US was second only to China as the highest emitter of greenhouse gas emissions globally last year.</p>

<p>The US accounted for 11.25% of global greenhouse gas emissions, while China represented 30.1%.</p>

<p>Per capita, greenhouse gas emissions in 2023 for the US stood at 17.61 tons of CO2 equivalent, higher than China's 11.11, the UK's 5.55, and Mexico's 5.15, but lower than Canada's 19.39 and Russia's 18.66.</p>

<p>In a 2024 World Economic Forum report on the Global Average Energy Transition Index, a measure of performance and readiness for clean energy transition, the US ranked 19th. Sweden tops the list, followed by Denmark, Finland, Switzerland and France.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to this year's Environmental Performance Index - a project by Yale and Columbia universities that evaluates countries based on indicators like climate change mitigation, air pollution, deforestation and biodiversity protection - the rankings put Estonia in pole position, followed by Luxembourg, and Germany. The US ranks 34th.</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM</strong></h4>

<p>When discussing ways to address carbon emissions, Vance said Kamala Harris' policies have led to "more energy production in China, more manufacturing overseas" (9:13 pm)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>Vance could be referring to the 2022 Inflation Reduction Act that provides incentives to boost domestic energy production and manufacturing investment, including support for clean energy jobs and the sale of new and used electric vehicles.</p>

<p>The impact of the IRA on the US manufacturing sector is still too early to tell, but some research has found it has benefited domestic clean energy manufacturing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The IRA provides billions of dollars in tax credits to help consumers buy EVs and firms to produce renewable energy as part of the Biden administration's plan to decarbonize the U.S. power sector. China, which dominates the global battery supply chain, is among the four countries excluded from the subsidy available to firms looking to invest in the US EV supply chain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>China has since requested the World Trade Organization set up a panel to help settle the dispute over what it describes as "discriminatory subsidies."</p>

<p>Another area of the global supply chain that China dominates is solar panel production. Some Chinese-backed companies with factories in the US are claiming those subsidies for clean energy manufacturing under the IRA, and a bipartisan group of US lawmakers introduced a bill in July that would block them from claiming subsidies for their American factories. &nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM &nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>Vance said Donald Trump's economic policies delivered the highest take-home pay in a generation. (9:33 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is true. US median household income reached a record high of $68,703 during the Trump administration in 2019, a 6.8% increase from 2018 - the highest the country had seen since the U.S. Census Bureau started tracking the data in 1967.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The White House Council of Economic Advisers at the time said an increase in the number of workers in the country drove the income increase. "There were 2.2 million more people working at some point in 2019 compared with 2018, and 1.2 million more people working full-time year-round," the council added. &nbsp;</p>

<h4><strong>CLAIM&nbsp;</strong></h4>

<p>"The gross majority, close to 90% in some of the statistics I've seen, of the gun violence in this country is committed with illegally obtained firearms." (10:00 p.m.)</p>

<h4><strong>WHAT WE KNOW</strong></h4>

<p>This is misleading. Most public mass shootings - a shooting that kills four or more people - between 1966 and 2019 were carried out by legally obtained handguns, according to research funded by the National Institute of Justice.</p>

<p>The data showed "77% of those who engaged in mass shootings purchased at least some of their guns legally," an article on the 2021 study said, while 13% of the mass shootings involved illegally purchased firearms.</p>

<p>The report also noted that over 80% of individuals involved in K-12 school shootings had stolen guns from family members.</p>

<p>Between 2017 and 2021, over 1.4 million crime guns were traced to a known purchaser with a Federal Firearms License, of which 99% were acquired from a dealer, pawnbroker or manufacturer, according to a 2023 report (page 7) by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives.</p>

<p>These crime guns, however, "may change hands a number of times after that first retail sale, and some of those transactions may be a theft or violate one or more regulations on firearm commerce," the report adds.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9b77t7e8_walz-vance-debate-reuters-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[JD Vance faced off Tim Walz in their first Vice Presidential debate almost a month before US Elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-missile-attack-iron-dome-video-israel-shoots-down-irans-onslaught-but-some-missiles-sneak-past-6699211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video Shows Iran Launching Hundreds Of Ballistic Missiles At Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-israel-missile-attack-iron-dome-video-israel-shoots-down-irans-onslaught-but-some-missiles-sneak-past-6699211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 14:18:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran launched a large-scale missile offensive against Israel - its second in the past seven months - Tuesday, targeting military bases in a strike dubbed 'Operation True Promise II'.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/iran" target="_blank">Iran</a> launched a large-scale missile offensive against <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/israel" target="_blank">Israel</a> - its second in the past seven months - Tuesday, targeting military bases in a strike dubbed '<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Operation True Promise II</a>'. Iran's Revolutionary Guards said the attack - which sharply escalates military tension in West Asia - was in response to the killing last week of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh.</p>

<p>A chilling video shared on X by Iranian news outlet Press TV shows multiple rockets being fired and arcing into the night sky, filling it with a deafening roar. As the video plays out, and pans to show more of the sky, more and more burning orange spots appear on the horizon.</p>

<p>The final 25 seconds of the clip show dozens of what look like burning balls dropping over an urban centre; many of them explode mid-air, having been successfully intercepted.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Op. True Promise II: Iran launches hundreds of missiles at Zionist entity, 90% hit targets<br />
<br />
Follow Press TV on Telegram: <a href="https://t.co/B3zXG73Jym">https://t.co/B3zXG73Jym</a> <a href="https://t.co/IxJfhOOZyE">pic.twitter.com/IxJfhOOZyE</a></p>
— Press TV ? (@PressTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/PressTV/status/1841351956738011398?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Several, though, seem to break through and hit the ground.</p>

<p>Another video shared online shows a massive crater near the Mossad HQ in Tel Aviv. The video was geolocated by American news outlet CNN to establish it was shot from a high-rise apartment building in Herzliya, less than 3 km from the Mossad headquarters.</p>

<p>The barrage of 180+ projectiles included, for the first time, the Fattah hypersonic missiles. The missiles' flight path meant it streaked over Jordan too, prompting Amman to announce a suspension of air traffic.</p>

<p>However, Israel's formidable multi-layered aerial defence system, at the core of which is the Iron Dome, was in action to intercept the missiles.</p>

<p><strong>VIDEO |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israels-air-defence-system-in-action-to-intercept-iranian-missiles-6695307" target="_blank">Israel's Air Defence System In Action To Intercept Iranian Missiles</a></p>

<p>As with the April attack, Iran and Israel have squabbled over the strike rate of these missiles, with Tehran claiming a 90 per cent success rate but Tel Aviv insisting most were tracked and destroyed by the Iron Dome and Arrow systems.</p>

<p>No injuries were reported in Israel, but one man was killed in occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>The April strike was retaliation for what Iran said was an Israeli air strike on its consulate in Syria's Damascus, in which seven Guards officers, including two commanders, were killed.</p>

<p><strong>NDTV Explains |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Inside 'True Promise II': What Changed In Iran's Latest Israel Attack</a></p>

<p>Then, for 'Operation True Promise I', Tehran fired nearly 200 ballistic missiles and older models of explosive drones, a staggering 99 per cent of which, Tel Aviv claimed, had been intercepted.</p>

<p>Ballistic missiles are an important part of Tehran's arsenal; Iran says these are a key deterrent and retaliatory force against the United States, Israel and other potential regional targets. According to the United States, Iran has the most numbers of such weapons in the region.</p>

<p>Iran is also believed to have cruise missiles like the Kh-55, an air-launched nuclear-capable weapon with a range up to 3,000 km, and the advanced anti-ship missile the Khalid Farzh, which has a smaller range - around 300 km. Both, however, can carry a 1,000-kg warhead.</p>

<p>Early this morning Iran said its attack had been completed and no further military action is expected, barring further provocation. Israel and the US, however, have vowed to retaliate.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-it-has-finished-attack-on-israel-amid-fears-of-spreading-conflict-in-middle-east-6696722" target="_blank">Iran Says Attack On Israel Over Amid Fears Of Spreading Conflict</a></p>

<p>The US said it would work with Israel to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-lebanon-hezbollah-after-irans-missile-attack-on-israel-us-severe-consequences-warning-6696958#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">make sure Iran faced "severe consequences"</a>. Israel, meanwhile, has again bombed Lebanon, targeting Beirut's southern suburbs - a Hezbollah stronghold.</p>

<p>Guy Nir, spokesperson for the Israeli embassy in India, told NDTV Tehran would get an appropriate response. "If he (Iran leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them. Israel's response is going to be strategic and pin-pointed... not a full-scale war."</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6581g6mo_iran-missile-attack-on-israel-video-press-tv_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/escalating-tensions-in-west-asia-india-calls-for-restraint-by-all-sides-6699055]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Escalating Tensions In West Asia: India Calls For Restraint By All Sides]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/escalating-tensions-in-west-asia-india-calls-for-restraint-by-all-sides-6699055]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:51:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In its first reaction to fresh escalation of tensions in West Asia, India on Wednesday called for restraint by all sides and said the conflict must not take a wider regional dimension.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In its first reaction to fresh escalation of tensions in West Asia, India on Wednesday called for restraint by all sides and said the conflict must not take a wider regional dimension.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India's comments came a day after Iran fired around 200 missiles into Israel in response to Israel's killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah and other commanders of the militant outfit.</p>

<p>New Delhi said it is deeply concerned over the escalating security situation in West Asia and called for addressing all issues through "dialogue and diplomacy".</p>

<p>"We are deeply concerned at the escalation of the security situation in West Asia and reiterate our call for restraint by all concerned and protection of civilians," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said.</p>

<p>"It is important that the conflict doesn't take a wider regional dimension and we urge that all issues be addressed through dialogue and diplomacy," it said in a statement.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/12pq7qro_israel-iran-war_625x300_14_April_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India's comments came a day after Iran fired around 200 missiles into Israel]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Fact Check: Did Netanyahu Run Into A Bunker During Iran's Missile Attack?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 13:21:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Following Iran's massive rocket attack on Israel Tuesday night, video clips circulating on social media showed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu allegedly running for cover inside a bunker.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following Iran's massive rocket attack on Israel Tuesday night, video clips circulating on social media showed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu allegedly running for cover inside a bunker. As Iran's missiles, some of which were hypersonic, entered Israeli airspace, sirens were sounded across the country, prompting thousands to seek safety.</p>

<p>Pro-Iranian social media handles shared a video clip that allegedly showed Benjamin Netanyahu running across the hallways of an alleged bunker. "Moments in which the Prime Minister of Israel, Benjamin Netanyahu, flees to a bunker in the face of the Iranian response," claimed one post.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Someone please give Benjamin Netanyahu a place to hide. The poor guy is not even running away. After all, he saved his life by hiding in a bunker. He ran away and hid, leaving his countrymen to fend for themselves," claimed another.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-iraq-the-year-is-1980-and-iran-has-a-new-best-friend-in-middle-east-its-israel-6697695#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">When Israel And Iran Joined Hands To Fight A Common Enemy</a></p>

<p>However, the purported video is at least three years old, a fact corroborated by posts on Facebook that shared the same video in 2021. The original video allegedly shows Benjamin Netanyahu rushing through the corridors of the Knesset, the Israeli parliament.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Original video:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="476" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fm.magadli%2Fvideos%2F3099680666968955%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=267&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="267"></iframe></p>

<p><strong>Screengrab of 2021 post:</strong></p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fvqh2oq8_netanyahu-viral-post-_625x300_02_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Netanyahu termed Iran's missile attack "a big mistake" and vowed to make Tehran "pay for it".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Iran made a big mistake tonight and will pay for it," he said. "Whoever attacks us, we attack them."</p>

<p>The missile salvo is the second direct attack by Iran on Israel this year, following a similar offensive in April, which was quickly subdued by Israeli and allied defences. Tuesday's strikes, according to Iranian officials, were in retaliation for the recent killing of senior Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Israeli military operations.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel</a></p>

<p>Guy Nir, spokesperson of the Israeli embassy in India, speaking exclusively to NDTV, said an appropriate response will be given to Tehran. "If he (Ayatollah Ali Khamenei) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them (Iran)," Mr Nir told NDTV. "Israel's response is going to be something strategic and pin-pointed, and not a full-scale war. I don't think any side wants that."</p>

<p>Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) claimed that 90 per cent of its missiles successfully hit their targets, despite Israel's advanced defence systems.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j3i153uo_netanyahu-viral-post-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Netanyahu termed Iran's missile attack "a big mistake" and vowed to make Tehran "pay for it".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-people-to-sue-us-rapper-sean-diddy-combs-in-sex-assault-case-6698693]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Over 100 People To Sue US Rapper Sean 'Diddy' Combs In Sex Assault Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/over-100-people-to-sue-us-rapper-sean-diddy-combs-in-sex-assault-case-6698693]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:59:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[More than 100 people, including dozens of children, who say they were victims of rape, sexual assault and sexual exploitation at the hands of Sean "Diddy" Combs are to sue the US rap star, a lawyer said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than 100 people, including dozens of children, who say they were victims of rape, sexual assault and sexual exploitation at the hands of Sean "Diddy" Combs are to sue the US rap star, a lawyer said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The latest legal action will heap further pressure on a man who once bestrode American pop culture, but who has long been dogged by accusations of violent abuse of women, and who is now sitting in jail on criminal charges.</p>

<p>"The biggest secret in the entertainment industry, that really wasn't a secret at all, has finally been revealed to the world," Texas-based attorney Tony Buzbee said as he announced plans by 120 people, including 25 minors, to take civil action.</p>

<p>"The wall of silence has now been broken, and victims are coming forward."</p>

<p>Combs was indicted last month on three criminal counts that allege he sexually abused women and coerced them into drug-fueled sex parties using threats and violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Allegations have been building against the Grammy Award-winner since last year, when singer Cassie, whose real name is Casandra Ventura, alleged Combs subjected her to more than a decade of coercion by physical force and drugs as well as a 2018 rape.</p>

<p>A spate of similarly lurid lawsuits since have painted a picture of Combs as a violent man who used his celebrity status to prey on women.</p>

<p>Combs has pleaded not guilty to the criminal charges. He has been jailed awaiting trial.</p>

<h3><strong>Pattern of abuse&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>At a press conference in Houston, Buzbee said more than 3,000 people had come forward with allegations against Combs, and he appealed for anyone else who might have been a victim to come forward.</p>

<p>He said much of the abuse Combs and members of his entourage are alleged to have carried out followed a pattern.</p>

<p>"I would say 90 per cent of the cases, these individuals were drugged," he told reporters.</p>

<p>"One individual who was 22 years old at the time she was assaulted, said that... when you were handed a drink -- and now we know that the drink is laced with something -- if you refused to drink it, you were kicked out of the party."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Buzbee described instances of repeated rape of teenagers, allegedly carried out by Combs and his associates.</p>

<p>He said alleged abuse of minors often took place in the context of a promise of fame and fortune in the music industry.</p>

<h3><strong>Fears of retribution&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>One boy, who was just nine years old at the time, was taken to New York to audition for Combs' label Bad Boy Records.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This individual was sexually abused, allegedly by Sean Combs and several other people at the studio, in the promise to both his parents and to himself of getting a record deal," Buzbee said.</p>

<p>"Another incident, an individual, 15 years old at the time, flown to New York City to attend a party, was drugged and then taken into a private room, allegedly in the presence of Mr Combs, where this female individual, a minor, was raped, and then other individuals took turns raping her."</p>

<p>Buzbee praised the courage of those who had come forward despite fears of retribution or backlash from their own communities.</p>

<p>"I expect that through this process, many powerful people, many dirty secrets will be revealed.</p>

<p>"We know what we are potentially up against, and as is always the case in situations like this, when a celebrity is involved, people can be downright mean and nasty."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/amruf0fg_sean-diddy-combs_625x300_17_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Sean "Diddy" Combs has pleaded not guilty to the criminal charges. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-how-successful-were-missile-attacks-what-iran-and-israel-said-6698674]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Successful Were Missile Attacks? What Iran And Israel Said]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-how-successful-were-missile-attacks-what-iran-and-israel-said-6698674]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:53:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran launched a wave of missiles into Israel last evening to avenge the killing of top Hezbollah and Hamas leaders as the war in Middle East threatens to snowball into a larger regional conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran launched a wave of missiles into Israel last evening to avenge the killing of top Hezbollah and Hamas leaders as the war in Middle East threatens to snowball into a larger regional conflict. Israelis scrambled for bomb shelters as sirens sounded across the nation and orange streaks lit up the night sky, showed visuals. Israel said they had intercepted most of the missiles and vowed to make Iran "pay" for the attack. Amid claims and counterclaims by Iran and Israel, it is hard to figure out how successful Tuesday's attacks were and whether Israel will launch an immediate retaliation.</p>

<p>Here's what Israel and Iran said about Tuesday's attacks:</p>

<div class="CetSht_cn">
<ol class="CetSht_ol">
	<li class="CetSht_li">There were reports yesterday of up to 400 missiles being fired at Israel from Iran. But Iran confirmed this morning it had fired 200 missiles while&nbsp;Israel gave a count of 180. Sirens were sounded across the country and&nbsp;most of the missiles were intercepted by Israeli air defences or allied air forces before they reached their territory.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">State media footage showed Iranian missiles being launched at Israel. The missiles targeted "three military bases" around Tel Aviv and other bases, The Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) said, adding that 90% of those "hit their targets". Israel denied this claim and said only 20 missiles landed while the rest were intercepted.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran has claimed to have hit the headquarters of Mossad, Israel's premier intelligence agency. Israel, however, has denied it and said some missiles landed on an empty ground. A video showing a massive crater near the Mossad headquarters has emerged on the social media - probably due to a missile strike.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran said yesterday they used hypersonic Fattah missiles to target military facilities in Israel, which were successful. This claim was opposed by Israel as they claimed to have intercepted most of the missiles. Israel said the attacks resulted in only two injuries.</li>
	<li class="CetSht_li">Iran warned it would carry out "crushing attacks" against Israel if it retaliates to the Iranian missile attack. But Israel termed the missile attack as the "biggest mistake by Iran" and vowed retaliation at a time and place of its choosing. "This attack will have consequences. We have plans, and we will operate at the place and time we decide," said IDF spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari.</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/78bfinkg_iran-israel-missiles_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/avoid-non-essential-travel-indias-advisory-amid-iran-israel-conflict-6698662]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Avoid Non-Essential Travel": India's Advisory Amid Iran-Israel Conflict]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/avoid-non-essential-travel-indias-advisory-amid-iran-israel-conflict-6698662]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:51:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indians have been asked to avoid travelling to Iran after they launched a massive missile attack on Israel while those already present in the country have been asked to stay vigilant.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indians have been asked to avoid travelling to Iran after they launched a massive missile attack on Israel. The government said Indian nationals who are already present in the country must stay vigilant and stay in touch with its embassy in Tehran.</p>

<p>The war situation in the Middle East saw a sharp escalation yesterday after a barrage of hypersonic missiles lit up the night sky above Israel - an offensive that Iran said was to avenge the recent killings of top Hamas and Hezbollah leaders.</p>

<p>The Indian government is closely monitoring the recent escalation in security situation in the region, the foreign ministry said in a statement shared online by spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Travel advisory for Indian nationals regarding Iran:<a href="https://t.co/FhUhy3fA5k">https://t.co/FhUhy3fA5k</a> <a href="https://t.co/tPFJXl6tQy">pic.twitter.com/tPFJXl6tQy</a></p>
— Randhir Jaiswal (@MEAIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia/status/1841372293064261752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 2, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"Indian nationals are advised to avoid all non-essential travel to Iran. Those currently residing in Iran are requested to remain vigilant and stay in contact with the Indian Embassy in Tehran," the travel advisory read.</p>

<p>The Indian embassy in Tel Aviv had yesterday asked Indians in the country to excise caution, avoid unnecessary travel and stay close to the safety shelters.</p>

<p><strong>Read | </strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655">Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel</a></p>

<p>"The Embassy is closely monitoring the situation and remains in regular touch with the Israeli authorities to ensure the safety of all our nationals," the embassy said in its advisory.</p>

<p>Foreign Minister S Jaishankar yesterday expressed concern at the possibility of the Middle East crisis growing into a larger regional conflict. "We are very much concerned at the possibility of a broadening of the conflict, not just what happened in Lebanon, but also, you know, I referred earlier to the Houthis and the Red Sea, and, you know, to some extent, everything that happens between Iran and Israel," he said.</p>

<p>Tuesday's attack marked a massive escalation in the Israel-Iran ties that had worsened after the October 7 Hamas attacks. Iran backs the Hamas and the Palestinian cause. Israel is also fighting the Iran-backed Hezbollah, which runs Lebanon.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/r95f3jc8_iran-missile-attack-afp-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside "True Promise II": What Changed In Iran's Latest Attack On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-true-promise-ii-what-changed-in-irans-latest-attack-on-israel-6698655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:50:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) launched its second missile attack against Israel in less than six months, targeting military bases on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) launched its second missile attack against Israel in less than six months, targeting military bases on Tuesday. Dubbed Operation True Promise II, this attack differed from Iran's earlier strike in April, showcasing a higher degree of technological sophistication and strategic ambition.</p>

<p>Iran deployed hypersonic missiles for the first time in this operation, marking a technological advancement over the older drones and ballistic missiles used in April's Operation True Promise. The IRGC claimed that 90 per cent of its missiles successfully hit their targets, despite Israel's advanced defence systems.</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> | <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-iraq-the-year-is-1980-and-iran-has-a-new-best-friend-in-middle-east-its-israel-6697695">When Israel And Iran Joined Hands To Fight A Common Enemy</a></p>

<p>Unlike April's attack, which primarily targeted isolated military sites, this assault appeared to target more densely populated urban centres near Tel Aviv. Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian framed the missile strikes as a proportional response to Israeli "aggression," warning Israel not to provoke further escalation.</p>

<p><strong>Key Differences Between April And October Attacks:</strong></p>

<p>Iran used hypersonic missiles for the first time in Operation True Promise II, marking a shift from the older technology drones and ballistic missiles used in the April attack. This latest attack involved a broader array of advanced weaponry.</p>

<p><strong>Fact Check </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-missile-attack-fact-check-did-benjamin-netanyahu-run-into-a-bunker-during-irans-missile-attack-6698839">Did Benjamin Netanyahu Run Into A Bunker During Iran's Missile Attack</a></p>

<p>In April, Iran targeted military bases in remote areas, while this time, urban centres near Tel Aviv were in the crosshairs. Iran claimed a 90 per cent success rate in hitting its targets in this latest attack, despite Israel's sophisticated defence systems, compared to the high interception rate of missiles in April.</p>

<p>One Palestinian man died after being hit by debris from an Iranian missile in West Bank. Despite no casualties reported on Israel's side, the proximity of the attack to populated areas signals that Israel's next response may be far more comprehensive and severe.</p>

<p>With Israeli citizens under direct threat, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is expected to take a stronger stance than after the April attack, potentially heightening the conflict with Iran. Resistance groups across the Middle East praised Iran's operation, raising the potential for further involvement from Hezbollah, Hamas, and other allied factions in the region.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/48gmq8co_israel-bunker-reuters-_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran used hypersonic missiles for the first time in Operation True Promise II.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-6698529]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Analysis: Yes, Calling Someone Mentally Disabled Causes Real Harm]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/analysis-yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-6698529]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 12:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a recent speech, Donald Trump used the language of intelligence, or intellectual impairment, as a weapon against Kamala Harris. And he used similar language about Vice presidential candidate Tim Walz in a TV appearance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">In <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/09/28/trump-harris-attacks-mentally-impaired-criticism/">a recent speech</a>, Donald Trump used the language of intelligence, or intellectual impairment, as a weapon against Kamala Harris. And he used <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/10/01/us/walz-vance-vp-debate/d5878199-2d8d-5282-9922-47316fd56f9f?smid=url-share">similar language about Vice presidential candidate Tim Walz</a> in a TV appearance.</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>In a rally on Sept. 29, 2024, in Prairie du Chien, Wisconsin, <a href="https://www.wpr.org/news/trump-harris-mentally-disabled-wisconsin-speech-immigration">Trump told supporters</a> that “Joe Biden became mentally impaired. Kamala was born that way. She was born that way. And if you think about it, only a mentally disabled person could have allowed this to happen to our country.” He <a href="https://whyy.org/articles/donald-trump-calls-kamala-harris-mentally-impaired-erie-pennsylvania-rally/">made similar comments</a> at a rally in Erie, Pennsylvania, over the same weekend.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.aapd.com/ableist-trump-comments-september-24/">Disability rights advocates</a> were quick to point out that Trump's language is what is called “ableist,” meaning that it assumes people with disabilities are somehow less valuable than those without.</p>

<p>In an attempt to fire back, “Saturday Night Live” Weekend Update host Colin Jost <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y2tOpMV6T0I">quipped </a>“I cannot</p>

<p>Special education classrooms are disproportionately filled with students of colour, <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED610548.pdf">most often diagnosed with behavioral disabilities</a>. These students often end up in the <a href="https://inclusivity.consulting/2017/12/08/school-prison-pipeline-intersection-race-disability/">school-to-prison pipeline</a>. These classrooms show how something as “simple” as an IQ test – something as innocuous as a label – can end up sentencing the country's children to lives of segregation and social oppression.</p>

<h3><strong>Not just Trump's words</strong></h3>

<p>Temperatures are running high during this presidential election. Yet Trump's words about Harris, while extraordinarily coarse and ugly for a presidential candidate, are often found among disparaging descriptions used by both sides. These phrases are part of a culture that uses measures of intelligence as a way to measure the worth of a human being.</p>

<p>Words are powerful: They can either, like the literature I teach, broaden perspectives of the world, or they can serve to reinforce limiting ideologies that perpetuate oppression.</p>

<p>Terms such as “low IQ,” “idiot” and “mentally impaired” have a traumatic history, one that many cognitively disabled, lower-class and minority people continue to live with today. I believe politicians and their constituents should understand the destructive history of these terms – and think twice before using words like these as an easy means to attack one another.<br />
<!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/kathleen-beres-rogers-1641673">Kathleen Béres Rogers</a>, Professor of English and Director, Program in Medical Humanities, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/college-of-charleston-734">College of Charleston</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/yes-calling-someone-mentally-disabled-causes-real-harm-239659">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/b64vd7go_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_22_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Disability rights advocates have said that Donald Trumps language against Kamala Harris is ableist.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>