<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:00:34 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-you-are-fired-thunders-trump-as-race-for-white-house-remained-razor-tight-6921682]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Kamala You Are Fired', Says Trump As Race For White House Remained Tight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-you-are-fired-thunders-trump-as-race-for-white-house-remained-razor-tight-6921682]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 17:00:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The latest CNN polls showed that Harris has a narrow advantage in Michigan and Wisconsin, while she and Trump remain tied in Pennsylvania.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump held competing rallies in Wisconsin while trying to outperform each other in the key battleground state as the race for the White House remained razor tight five days ahead of the election day.</p>

<p>The latest CNN polls showed that Harris has a narrow advantage in Michigan and Wisconsin, while she and Trump remain tied in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In Michigan, Harris holds a lead over Trump by 48 per cent to 43 per cent among likely voters, according to the findings.</p>

<p>Harris also leads Trump in Wisconsin, where 51 per cent support her to 45 per cent for Trump, but the race is tied in Pennsylvania, with both having 48 per cent support.</p>

<p>As the race for the White House remained very close, Trump mounted a sharp attack on Harris while using President Joe Biden's comments that appeared to call Trump's supporters "garbage".</p>

<p>Dressed in a garbage vest, Trump arrived at the venue of the rally in Wisconsin's Green Bay area in a dump truck and addressed several thousand of his supporters, arguing that Harris is not fit to become the President.</p>

<p>"My response to Joe and Kamala is very simple: You can't lead America if you don't love Americans, it's true. You can't be president if you hate the American people, which I believe they do, and Kamala Harris is not fit to be president of the United States," he said.</p>

<p>"Kamala, you are fired," Trump thundered.</p>

<p>Before the rally, Trump also spoke to reporters.</p>

<p>"How do you like my garbage truck? This truck is in honour of Kamala and Joe Biden," he said.</p>

<p>"For Joe Biden to make that statement -- it's really a disgrace," he said.</p>

<p>Earlier, Harris distanced herself from Biden's "garbage" remarks, saying she strongly disagrees with criticising anyone based on how they vote.</p>

<p>"I am sincere in what I mean: When elected president of the United States, I will represent all Americans, including those who don't vote for me, and address their needs and their desires," she said.</p>

<p>The Democratic Party leader also cautioned people against electing Trump.</p>

<p>"On day one, Donald Trump would walk into office with an enemies list," said Harris.</p>

<p>She also touched upon various policy issues, including how she plans to cut taxes on small businesses and expand healthcare coverage for families.</p>

<p>The US Presidential Election Day is on November 5.</p>

<p>Over 59 million Americans have already cast their votes in early voting.</p>

<p>Of the total number of early votes, 31,018,125 were cast in person and 27,952,363 were cast through mail, according to official details.</p>

<p>To win the race for the White House, the successful candidate will have to secure 270 of the 538 electoral votes up for grabs.</p>

<p>The seven key swing states which are seen to be crucial to determining the election results are Georgia, Michigan, Arizona, Pennsylvania, North Carolina, Wisconsin and Nevada.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/6ruok92g_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dressed in a garbage vest, Trump arrived at the venue of the rally in Wisconsin's Green Bay area]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-russia-says-it-launched-over-2-000-drones-at-ukraine-in-october-6921651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says It Launched Over 2,000 Drones At Ukraine In October]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-conflict-russia-says-it-launched-over-2-000-drones-at-ukraine-in-october-6921651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:58:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia launched more than 2,000 attack drones at civilian and military targets across Ukraine last month, Kyiv's military said on Friday, as Kremlin forces press a grinding offensive on the front line of their February 2022 invasion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia launched more than 2,000 attack drones at civilian and military targets across Ukraine last month, Kyiv's military said on Friday, as Kremlin forces press a grinding offensive on the front line of their February 2022 invasion.</p>

<p>Moscow has carried out regular air strikes on Ukrainian towns and cities, with the capital Kyiv coming under attack 20 times in October alone, according to city officials.</p>

<p>Ukraine's General Staff said in a statement it had intercepted 1,185 of the 2,023 drones launched last month and that another 738 were "locationally lost".</p>

<p>"In total, since the beginning of 2024, the enemy has launched 6,987 attack UAVs on the territory of Ukraine. Enemy drones mostly targeted civilian and critical infrastructure," it said.</p>

<p>Ukraine said on Friday it had destroyed 31 drones and one missile in Russia's latest overnight strike, which damaged residential buildings in at least two regions and a fire station in the southern Odesa region.</p>

<p>Russia has denied aiming at civilians and said power facilities are legitimate targets when they are part of Ukrainian military infrastructure.</p>

<p>Ukraine is girding for another season of power cuts amid the threat of new Russian attacks on the country's energy system, which had already been weakened by a series of strikes earlier this year.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/b2bq228g_russia-attack-on-ukraine_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ukraine's General Staff said it had intercepted 1,185 of the 2,023 drones launched in October. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-false-claims-about-voter-fraud-raises-concern-of-trump-contesting-results-6921527]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[False Claims About Voter Fraud Raises Concern Of Trump Contesting Results]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-elections-false-claims-about-voter-fraud-raises-concern-of-trump-contesting-results-6921527]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:39:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[False claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania have raised concerns that former Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump may once again seek to overturn the vote there or in other battleground states likely to determine the winner next Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>False claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania have raised concerns that former Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump may once again seek to overturn the vote there or in other battleground states likely to determine the winner next Tuesday.</p>

<p>Opinion polls, both nationally and in the seven closely divided states, show Trump locked in a tight race with Democratic Vice President Kamala Harris with four days to go before Election Day.</p>

<p>Trump continues to falsely claim his 2020 loss to Democratic President Joe Biden was the result of widespread fraud in multiple states that Trump lost, while he and his supporters have spread baseless claims about this election in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>Similar rhetoric about voter fraud after the 2020 vote led to a violent mob of Trump supporters attacking the US Capitol on January 6, 2021, seeking to halt or sway the congressional count of the electoral votes that determine who becomes president.</p>

<p>"This is sowing the seeds for attempts to overturn an election result that cuts against Donald Trump," said Kyle Miller, a Pennsylvania policy strategist for the advocacy group Protect Democracy. "We saw it in 2020 and I think the lesson Trump and his allies have learned since is that they have to sow these ideas early."</p>

<p>Trump on Thursday stepped up his unfounded allegations that probes into suspect voter registration forms are proof of voter fraud. Some of his supporters alleged voter suppression when long lines formed this week to receive mail-in ballots.</p>

<p>State officials and democracy advocates said the incidents show a system working as intended. A judge extended the mail-in ballot deadline by three days in Bucks County, north of Philadelphia, after the former US president's campaign sued over claims that some voters were turned away before a Tuesday deadline.</p>

<p>Election officials discovered potentially fraudulent registrations in Lancaster and neighboring York counties, prompting investigations by local law enforcement. There is no evidence the applications have led or will lead to illegal votes.</p>

<p>"This is a sign that the built-in safeguards in our voter registration process are working," Al Schmidt, Pennsylvania's top elections official, told reporters this week.</p>

<p><strong>PREPARING TO BLAME A LOSS ON FRAUD</strong></p>

<p>Trump tells his rallies to expect a big victory on Tuesday, saying he could only envision losing "if it was a corrupt election."</p>

<p>Trump's claims have raised concerns that he is preparing to again blame a potential loss in Pennsylvania, the largest of the seven states likely to decide the result of the election, on voter fraud.</p>

<p>In a social media post on Thursday, he said: "We caught them CHEATING BIG in Pennsylvania" and demanded criminal prosecutions.</p>

<p>A senior Harris campaign official on Thursday said Trump's claims were an example of the former president trying to "sow doubt in our elections and institutions when he's afraid he can't win."</p>

<p>Should Trump win the vote fairly, all the talk of fraud may dissipate quickly.</p>

<p>But the United States' unique method of choosing a president, rooted in the 1789 Constitution, provides openings for Trump and his supporters to seek to undermine or delay election results at the local, state and national level.</p>

<p>In 2020, the Trump team attempted 60 court cases alleging fraud in multiple states, all without success. But the experience has prepared lawyers from both parties for another attempt, each side sharpening their knowledge of election law.</p>

<p>Should Trump followers overturn or delay any unfavorable state results long enough through the courts or legislative obstruction, they could prevent a duly elected Harris from taking office and tilt the result to Trump.</p>

<p>Some US states are warning county and local officials not to intervene illegally or refuse to certify results.</p>

<p>But the final arbiter in such a case would be the nine-member US Supreme Court.</p>

<p>With six conservative justices, three of them appointed by Trump, the court has already granted the former president a victory in his bid to seek criminal immunity from acts committed as president.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/s9s65cf_donald-trump-pti_625x300_29_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump tells his rallies that he could only lose "if it was a corrupt election". (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gidan-badamasi-hit-nigerian-tv-show-raises-awareness-on-family-size-and-population-challenges-in-africa-6921443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hit Nigerian TV Show Raises Awareness On Population Challenges In Africa]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/feature/gidan-badamasi-hit-nigerian-tv-show-raises-awareness-on-family-size-and-population-challenges-in-africa-6921443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:22:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The popular Nigerian TV show has stirred discussions on family planning across Africa, highlighting the challenges of raising large families.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Families eagerly assemble every week in Kano, the second-largest city in Nigeria, to watch the hit television program "Gidan Badamasi," a comedy-drama that emphasises the social effects of large families, according to <em>The New York Times.</em></p>

<p>Thursday nights are a time when families gather around their little TVs to witness the fictional story of a rich but careless protagonist who battles to care for his many children. The presentation highlights the difficulties of raising large children in a society that aims to provide education and employment possibilities despite a global shift in birthrates, addressing an issue that is highly relevant throughout Africa, where a sizable young population is expanding quickly.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/21/world/africa/africa-nigeria-birthrate-fertility.html"><em>The New York Times </em></a>report, many African women have far more children than women on other continents do: women in Nigeria have an average of over five children, while American and European women have about 1.5, and Chinese women even fewer. And recent progress in reducing child mortality in Africa means more of them survive into adulthood than ever before.</p>

<p>But Africa's birthrate is also gradually dropping. It has fallen by about 38 percent over the past 60 years. That is largely because of education, economics, and shifting attitudes toward family size on display in conversations prompted by shows like “Gidan Badamasi,” one of the biggest hits of recent years on the leading Hausa-language television channel.</p>

<p>“It's a very bad habit, breeding children he can't take care of,” Sani Ibrahim, 53, a school principal and the father of the six siblings, told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/21/world/africa/africa-nigeria-birthrate-fertility.html"><em>NYT.</em></a></p>

<p>“It's a problem for me,” he said, “that I have this many children.”</p>

<p>Northern and southern Africa have long been going through “fertility transitions"—significant reductions in their birthrates. But in most of the rest of Africa, fertility has mostly stayed high.</p>

<p>“Gidan Badamasi” had a “massive, instant” effect, starting conversations about reducing family size. It succeeded, many viewers told NYT, where many international organisations had failed.</p>

<p>“You can't just come to this part of the world saying that people should not get married, people should not give birth to many children, people should get birth control,” the show's main writer, Nazir Adam Salih, said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/g8l7rni_gidan-badamasi_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The show resonates with viewers, sparking conversations about family size.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-hold-duel-campaign-in-wisconsin-with-high-stakes-and-star-power-6921411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump, Harris Hold Duel Campaign In Wisconsin With High Stakes, Star Power]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-trump-harris-hold-duel-campaign-in-wisconsin-with-high-stakes-and-star-power-6921411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 16:20:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump and Kamala Harris hold dueling campaign rallies Friday in Wisconsin's largest city Milwaukee, as both candidates make frantic last-ditch appeals to wavering voters with Election Day just around the corner.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump and Kamala Harris hold dueling campaign rallies Friday in Wisconsin's largest city Milwaukee, as both candidates make frantic last-ditch appeals to wavering voters with Election Day just around the corner.</p>

<p>Republican Trump will return to the venue where he was crowned his party's presidential nominee over the summer, his ear bandaged in bright white gauze after he was wounded in an attempted assassination just days earlier, while Democrat Harris will lean on the star power of rapper Cardi B to outshine her rival.</p>

<p>Their race back to the so-called Blue Wall states came after the pair spent Thursday in the US West, with three appearances each.</p>

<p>The highlight for Harris had been a star-studded rally in Las Vegas where she was introduced by pop maven Jennifer Lopez, while Trump spent a comfortable evening basking in mutual affection with right-wing provocateur Tucker Carlson in Glendale, Arizona.</p>

<p>With Tuesday's vote looming, the candidates appear set for a photo finish, despite fierce efforts by the rival campaigns to move the dial and dominate the news cycle in a week so far defined by bitter disputes and gaffes on both sides over issues including race, gender and reproductive rights.</p>

<p>Wisconsin, one of the key battleground states that will swing the November 5 election, was decided by less than one percentage point in 2016 and 2020, and the race for its 10 electoral college votes is just as tight this time around.</p>

<p>Harris -- who has fought to maintain her image as a "joyful warrior" even as Trump hurls insults against her and other Democrats -- was seeking to harness the power of musicians such as GloRilla, the Isley Brothers and Flo Milli at a "When We Vote We Win" rally and concert in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>Grammy award-winning rapper Cardi B was due to speak at the event, Harris's campaign said.</p>

<p>Trump was returning to the Fiserv Forum, the venue that hosted perhaps the high-water mark of his campaign, the Republican National Convention.</p>

<p>The convention came as the tycoon was riding high in the polls after two major events -- the assassination attempt and a debate with then-candidate Joe Biden which proved disastrous for the Democrat -- but before Biden dropped out of the race and handed the baton to Harris.</p>

<p>Lifted by a surge of enthusiasm, Harris quickly ate away at Trump's lead -- but the polls have remained mostly deadlocked ever since.</p>

<p>With fears growing that Trump could refuse to accept the result if he loses the election, many Americans were bracing for violence and unrest in the days after November 5.</p>

<p>Washington's police chief Pamela Smith told a press briefing this week that no "credible threats" had been identified against the capital, which saw a deadly riot by Trump supporters seeking to overturn Biden's election win on January 6, 2021.</p>

<p>Smith said that officials were remaining "vigilant." Police would support peaceful protests, she said, but "we will not tolerate any violence of any kind."</p>

<p>"We will not tolerate any riots, we will not tolerate the destruction of property, we will not tolerate any unlawful behavior," she said.</p>

<p>Some 63.5 million people have cast their ballots early, more than 40 percent of the 2020 total vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0co3a0fs_kamala-harris-donald-trump-harris-trump-reuters_625x300_10_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rapper Cardi B was due to speak at the event, Kamala Harris's campaign said. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-word-is-named-as-word-of-the-year-by-collins-dictionary-it-is-6921270]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Word Is Named As 'Word Of The Year' By Collins Dictionary. It Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-word-is-named-as-word-of-the-year-by-collins-dictionary-it-is-6921270]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:53:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brat, the word redefined by singer Charli XCX and adopted by supporters of US presidential candidate Kamala Harris, was on Friday named the Collins Word of the Year 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brat, the word redefined by singer Charli XCX and adopted by supporters of US presidential candidate Kamala Harris, was on Friday named the Collins Word of the Year 2024.</p>

<p>"Brat" was the name of the UK singer's hit sixth album, and the word has now come to represent a "confident, independent, and hedonistic attitude", said Collins, rather than simply a term for a badly-behaved child.</p>

<p>"Inspired by the Charli XCX album, 'brat' has become one of the most talked about words of 2024," said the UK-based dictionary.</p>

<p>"More than a hugely successful album, 'brat' is a cultural phenomenon that has resonated with people globally, and 'brat summer' established itself as an aesthetic and a way of life," it added.</p>

<p>The 32-year-old pop star, whose real name is Charlotte Emma Aitchison, described the typical brat girl as someone "who is a little messy and likes to party and maybe says some dumb things sometimes, who feels herself, but then also maybe has a breakdown, but kind of parties through it".</p>

<p>She tweeted in July that "Kamala IS brat", in reference to the US Vice President, prompting the presidential nominee to use her song "365" in one of her TikTok videos.</p>

<p>Her campaign account also re-branded with a lime green photo in the style of the Brat album cover.</p>

<p>The album hit number one in her native UK and number three in the US.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-06/oxford-dictionary-650x400_650x400_61498638775.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA['Brat' is a cultural phenomenon that has resonated with people globally.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-report-wars-of-famine-aggravated-by-conflicts-and-climate-shocks-6921067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UN Report Wars Of Famine, Aggravated By Conflicts And Climate Shocks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/un-report-wars-of-famine-aggravated-by-conflicts-and-climate-shocks-6921067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:18:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Severe food crises threaten people in vulnerable areas, including the Palestinian territories, Sudan, South Sudan, Haiti, and Mali, where populations face or near famine, says a report by the United Nations' food agencies released on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Severe food crises threaten hundreds of thousands of people in vulnerable areas, including the Palestinian territories, Sudan, South Sudan, Haiti, and Mali, where populations face or near famine, says a report by the United Nations' food agencies released on Thursday.</p>

<p>Conflicts, economic instability, and climate shocks -- combined with reduced funding for emergency food and agriculture assistance -- are driving alarming levels of acute food insecurity, the report warned.</p>

<p>“Immediate, scaled-up intervention is needed to prevent further deterioration in these already vulnerable regions,” it added.</p>

<p>The UN Food and Agriculture Organization and the World Food Programme said acute food insecurity is projected to worsen across 16 “hunger hotspots” during the next six months in 14 countries and two regions.</p>

<p>Sudan, South Sudan, Haiti, Mali and the Palestinian territories remain at the “highest concern level,” the report said.</p>

<p>Chad, Lebanon, Myanmar, Mozambique, Nigeria, the Syrian Arab Republic and Yemen are classified as “hotspots of very high concern,” where large numbers of people are facing or are projected to face critical levels of acute food insecurity.</p>

<p>“Conflict and armed violence continue to be the primary drivers of hunger in numerous hotspots, disrupting food systems, displacing populations, and obstructing humanitarian access,” the report warned.</p>

<p>FAO and WFP experts believe that the conflict in Sudan is likely to expand, “driving mass displacement, resulting in famine levels likely to persist and the number of people in catastrophic conditions to increase.”</p>

<p>That will further aggravate the regional humanitarian crisis, resulting in increased cross-border movements to neighbouring countries, primarily Chad, South Sudan, Egypt, Libya, Ethiopia and the Central African Republic.</p>

<p>The UN agencies also stressed that the ongoing conflict in the Palestinian territories has driven “unprecedented needs, with near-total displacement of the population and an increased risk of regional spillover”.</p>

<p>In Lebanon, the ongoing escalation of conflict is significantly increasing the number of people requiring humanitarian assistance and is severely impacting levels of acute food insecurity, they added.</p>

<p>Since the last report in May 2024, Kenya, Lesotho, Namibia and the Niger have been added to the hunger hotspots list, partly due to the impact of climate extremes.</p>

<p>Beyond conflict, weather extremes and increased climate variability are exacerbating acute food insecurity in many regions, the report said.</p>

<p>La Niña -- a natural climate pattern that influences global weather marked by cooler ocean temperatures in the equatorial Pacific – is expected to persist through March 2025, with a significant impact on rainfall patterns and temperatures.</p>

<p>“While La Niña may enhance agricultural prospects in some areas, it also increases the risk of flooding in parts of Nigeria, Malawi, Mozambique, South Sudan, Zambia and Zimbabwe,” the report said.</p>

<p>The UN agencies warned that without “immediate humanitarian efforts and concerted international action” to address severe constraints and advocate for the de-escalation of conflicts, further starvation and loss of life are likely in Palestine, the Sudan, South Sudan, Haiti and Mali.</p>

<p>“Addressing and preventing famine in these regions will require greater investment in integrated solutions that cut across traditional mandates, targeting the root causes of food insecurity and reducing dependency on emergency aid,” they said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-06/famine-istock-650_650x400_71498659841.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[FAO and WFP experts believe that the conflict in Sudan is likely to expand, "driving mass displacement"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-man-asks-selena-gomez-to-chant-jai-shri-ram-her-reaction-6920985]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian Man Asks Selena Gomez to Chant 'Jai Shri Ram'. Her Reaction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-man-asks-selena-gomez-to-chant-jai-shri-ram-her-reaction-6920985]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:02:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent video capturing an unusual interaction between an Indian man and pop star Selena Gomez has ignited a flurry of reactions online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent video capturing an unusual interaction between an Indian man and pop star Selena Gomez has ignited a flurry of reactions online. In the viral clip, the man eagerly snaps a selfie with Ms Gomez before making a surprising request: please chant "<em>Jai Shri Ram</em>."</p>

<p>When Ms Gomez appears puzzled, the man attempts to clarify, adding, "India's best slogan - <em>Jai Shri Ram</em>." However, the 32-year-old Gomez, politely dismissive, responds with a simple, "Aww, thank you, honey."</p>

<p>The video was first shared by Instagram user Pallav Paliwal and has rapidly gained traction across social media platforms. Mr Paliwal captioned it, "One of our followers met Selena Gomez and she said '<em>Jai Shri Ram</em>' on the occasion of Diwali."&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBwJv5CKgCk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBwJv5CKgCk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBwJv5CKgCk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBwJv5CKgCk/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Pallav Paliwal (@pallav_paliwal)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>According to his post, the exchange supposedly took place on Diwali. However, sharp-eyed viewers have identified Gomez's attire which she wore at the 2024 Cannes Film Festival in May.&nbsp;</p>

<p>This unusual request has sparked strong reactions online, with many users expressing their embarrassment and frustration. "I got levels of embarrassment I couldn't believe were possible," one user wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Others were less restrained in their criticism. "Most pathetic thing I've seen all year," commented another. A third user added, "Even though I am not associated with these people, I got secondhand embarrassment from just watching this. What kind of incurable inferiority complex is this?!"</p>

<p>Mr Paliwal's original post on Instagram has garnered nearly 20,000 likes. On other platforms like X and Facebook, the video has fetched millions of views as well.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/u8t5qsco_selena-gomez-jai-shri-ram-_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This unusual request has sparked strong reactions online.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-has-banned-protests-outside-abortion-clinics-but-silent-prayer-is-gray-area-6920936]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Britain Has Banned Protests Outside Abortion Clinics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/britain-has-banned-protests-outside-abortion-clinics-but-silent-prayer-is-gray-area-6920936]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:57:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A British ban on protesting outside abortion clinics went into effect on Thursday, though it left a question mark over whether anti-abortion demonstrators who pray silently will be breaking the law.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A British ban on protesting outside abortion clinics went into effect on Thursday, though it left a question mark over whether anti-abortion demonstrators who pray silently will be breaking the law.</p>

<p>The law, which applies to England and Wales, bars protests within 150 metres of clinics. Scotland and Northern Ireland, which make their own health policies, recently enacted similar bans.</p>

<p>The new rules make it an offense to obstruct someone using abortion services, “intentionally or recklessly” influence their decision, or cause “harassment, alarm or distress.” Offenders face a fine, with no upper limit.</p>

<p>The buffer zone rule was passed 18 months ago as part of the previous Conservative government's Public Order Act, but wrangling over whether it would apply to silent prayer protests, and a change in government in July, have delayed it taking effect.</p>

<p>The Crown Prosecution Service says silent prayer near an abortion clinic “will not necessarily commit a criminal offense,” and police say they will assess each case individually.</p>

<p>Anti-abortion campaigners and religious groups argue that banning silent-prayer protests would be an affront to freedom of religion. But pro-choice campaigners say silent anti-abortion demonstrators are often intimidating to women entering clinics.</p>

<p>“It's difficult to see how anyone choosing to perform their prayers right outside an abortion clinic could argue they aren't attempting to influence people — and there are countless testimonies from women who say this makes them feel distressed,” said Louise McCudden, UK head of external affairs at MSI Reproductive Choices, one of Britain's biggest abortion providers.</p>

<p>In March 2023, lawmakers rejected a change to the legislation proposed by some conservative legislators that would have explicitly allowed silent prayer within the buffer zones. The final rules are a potentially messy compromise that is likely to be tested in court.</p>

<p>Crime and Policing Minister Diana Johnson said she was “confident that the safeguards we have put in place today will have a genuine impact in helping women feel safer and empowered to access the vital services they need.”</p>

<p>But Bishop John Sherrington of the Catholic Bishops' Conference of England and Wales, said the government had “taken an unnecessary and disproportionate step backwards” on religious freedom.</p>

<p>“Religious freedom includes the right to manifest one's private beliefs in public through witness, prayer and charitable outreach, including outside abortion facilities,” he said.</p>

<p>Abortion is not as divisive an issue in the UK as in the US, where women's access to terminations has been rolled back, and banned in some states, since the Supreme Court overturned the landmark Roe vs Wade ruling in 2022.</p>

<p>Abortion was partly legalised in Britain by the 1967 Abortion Act, which allows abortions up to 24 weeks of pregnancy if two doctors approve. Later abortions are allowed in some circumstances, including danger to the mother's life.</p>

<p>But women who have abortions after 24 weeks in England and Wales can be prosecuted under the 1861 Offenses Against the Person Act.</p>

<p>Last year a 45-year-old woman in England was sentenced to 28 months in prison for ordering abortion pills online to induce a miscarriage when she was 32 to 34 weeks pregnant. After an outcry, her sentence was reduced.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-01/us-anti-abortion-activists_650x400_71485513272.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A British ban on protesting outside abortion clinics went into effect]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-israels-attacks-suggest-rejection-of-ceasefire-lebanon-prime-minister-6920931]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Israel's Attacks Suggest Rejection Of Ceasefire": Lebanon Prime Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-israels-attacks-suggest-rejection-of-ceasefire-lebanon-prime-minister-6920931]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:56:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Friday criticised Israel's "expansion" of its attacks on his country, saying they indicated a rejection of efforts to broker a truce after more than a month of war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's Prime Minister Najib Mikati on Friday criticised Israel's "expansion" of its attacks on his country, saying they indicated a rejection of efforts to broker a truce after more than a month of war.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy's renewed expansion of the scope of its aggression on Lebanese regions, its repeated threats to the population to evacuate entire cities and villages, and its renewed targeting of the southern suburbs of Beirut with destructive raids are all indicators that confirm the Israeli enemy's rejection of all efforts being made to secure a ceasefire," Mikati said.</p>

<p>Mikati's statement came a day after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu met visiting US officials to discuss a possible deal to end the war in Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Lebanese premier added that Israel's diplomatic behaviour suggested it was rejecting a ceasefire.</p>

<p>"Israeli statements and diplomatic signals that Lebanon received confirm Israel's stubbornness in rejecting the proposed solutions and insisting on the approach of killing and destruction," Mikati said in a statement.</p>

<p>Since fighting in Lebanon escalated on September 23, the war has killed at least 1,829 people in Lebanon, according to an AFP tally of health ministry figures.</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Mikati said US envoy Amos Hochstein had signalled during a phone call that a ceasefire in the Israel-Hezbollah war was possible before US elections are held on November 5.</p>

<p>The same day, Hezbollah's new leader said the group would agree to a ceasefire with Israel under acceptable terms, but added that a viable deal has yet to be presented.</p>

<p>During talks on Thursday, Israeli leader Netanyahu told US envoys Amos Hochstein and Brett McGurk that any Lebanon deal must guarantee Israel's longer-term security.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o6n037vo_south-lebanon-nabatieh_625x300_30_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mikati's statement came a day after Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu met visiting US officials.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shootout-linked-to-drug-trafficking-injures-five-in-france-6920853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Shootout Linked To Drug Trafficking Injures Five In France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/shootout-linked-to-drug-trafficking-injures-five-in-france-6920853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:43:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A massive shootout linked to drug trafficking has left a teenager and four others seriously wounded in western France, Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A massive shootout linked to drug trafficking has left a teenager and four others seriously wounded in western France, Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau said Friday, in the latest such gunfight to injure children.</p>

<p>The shootout erupted in front of a restaurant overnight in the western city of Poitiers, Retailleau told BFMTV/RMC radio.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"What started as a shooting at a restaurant ended up in a fight between rival gangs that involved several hundred people", Retailleau said.</p>

<p>The 15-year-old boy wounded was between life and death, he said.</p>

<p>The minister warned that the country was at a "tipping point" when it came to drug trafficking violence, saying that he was planning to travel later in the day to the northwestern city of Rennes, where a five-year-old child was also between life and death after being shot on Saturday in another fire exchange related to drug trafficking.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The shootout erupted in front of a restaurant overnight in the western city of Poitiers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-to-define-herself-kamala-harris-looks-to-her-mother-who-moved-to-us-from-india-6920801]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[To Define Herself, Harris Looks To Her Mother Who Moved To US From India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-to-define-herself-kamala-harris-looks-to-her-mother-who-moved-to-us-from-india-6920801]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:37:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In each important speech she makes, Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks about one woman first and foremost: her late mother.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In each important speech she makes, Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris speaks about one woman first and foremost: her late mother, a trailblazing scientist who came to the United States from India.</p>

<p>The anecdotes serve not just to explain her life story -- they help the vice president, who has not made her identity a central theme of the White House race, to talk about feminism and racism.</p>

<p>"My mother was a brilliant, five-foot-tall, brown woman with an accent. And as the eldest child, I saw how the world would sometimes treat her," Harris said in August at the Democratic National Convention.</p>

<p>In the speech, her first as the party's official presidential nominee, Harris recounted at length the journey of Shyamala Gopalan, who left her homeland at the age of 19 to do a master's degree in California.</p>

<p>Gopalan would go on to become a prominent breast cancer researcher, who contributed to the development of several treatments for the disease.</p>

<p>This week in Washington, as Harris spoke before tens of thousands of supporters in the center of the US capital, the person she mentioned the most -- after her Republican rival Donald Trump -- was her mother.</p>

<p>The vice president talks about her mother's American experience as a woman of color -- a concept she hardly ever discusses as it pertains to her own life.</p>

<p>Harris never mentions the fact that she will become the first woman US president if elected, as well as the first Black woman and person of South Asian descent in the Oval Office.</p>

<p>Debbie Walsh, the director of the Center for American Women and Politics at Rutgers University in New Jersey, says it is a deliberate choice by Harris not to mention these potentially historic milestones.</p>

<p>"She has to convince the people who need to be 'reassured' that a woman can do this job and be strong and tough," Walsh told AFP.</p>

<p>But "there is racism, there is sexism," the researcher notes. "That all exists out there, and she can't act as though that doesn't exist," so talking about her mother is "a way for her to acknowledge it, but not have it focus as much on her."</p>

<h3><strong>'Long hours'</strong></h3>

<p>Gopalan met Jamaican immigrant Donald Harris in the early 1960s at the University of California, Berkeley, where he had come to study economics.</p>

<p>They found each other right in the heat of the civil rights movement, and Kamala Harris -- born in 1964 -- was brought to marches in a stroller.</p>

<p>After her parents divorced when she was five, Harris and her sister Maya were mainly raised by their mother.</p>

<p>"She taught us to never complain about injustice, but do something about it," Harris has said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The early, hectic days of her campaign, which only began in July once President Joe Biden stepped aside, were marked by an unexpected symbol, drawn from one of Gopalan's favorite expressions -- a coconut.</p>

<p>But Harris has since used stories from her childhood to make a more personal connection with voters, and emphasize how she intends to work for middle-class families that reflect her own upbringing.</p>

<p>Harris often talks about how her mother "worked long hours," and then sat late at night drinking tea with "a pile of bills in front of her." Gopalan kept a strict budget, Harris says, and focused on saving for a first home.</p>

<p>The vice president has also talked about caring for her sick mother, preparing meals and choosing clothes that would not irritate her skin. Gopalan died after a battle with colon cancer in 2009.</p>

<h3><strong>Single mothers</strong></h3>

<p>With women's rights at the heart of the White House battle, Harris has put her mother -- a woman who married for love in an "act of self-determination" rather than face an arranged marriage in India -- front and center.</p>

<p>The vice president, who helped raise her husband's two children from his previous marriage, speaks rarely about her father, who is in his 80s and lives in Washington.</p>

<p>Trump has called Donald Harris a "Marxist," but the retired university professor has distanced himself from politics for a long time.</p>

<p>For Walsh, it's neither surprising nor new for a presidential candidate to put their mother -- and not father -- in the limelight.</p>

<p>Bill Clinton and Barack Obama -- who, like Harris, never highlighted that he would make history by becoming America's first Black president -- were both raised by single mothers, and spoke of them often while campaigning, Walsh said.</p>

<p>Those mothers "then become an outsized force in their lives, and in talking about who they are and how they grew up, they would really be center stage, right?" she said.</p>

<p>"I mean, it would be kind of odd to think they wouldn't."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b2onbrbg_kamla-harris_625x300_31_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris talks about her mother's American experience as a woman of color.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-american-groups-praised-trump-for-promising-to-protect-rights-of-hindus-globally-6920773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hindu Americans Back Trump's Promise to Safeguard Global Hindu Interests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hindu-american-groups-praised-trump-for-promising-to-protect-rights-of-hindus-globally-6920773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:32:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In his Diwali greetings on Thursday, Trump strongly "condemned the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities in Bangladesh", which he said remains in a "total state of chaos."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hindu American groups have applauded Republican presidential candidate and former president Donald Trump for promising to protect the human rights of Hindus across the world, including the US and Bangladesh and protect them from the "anti-religion agenda of the radical left."</p>

<p>In his Diwali greetings on Thursday, Trump strongly "condemned the barbaric violence against Hindus, Christians, and other minorities in Bangladesh", which he said remains in a “total state of chaos.”</p>

<p>“It would have never happened on my watch. Kamala and Joe have ignored Hindus across the world and in America. They have been a disaster from Israel to Ukraine to our own Southern Border, but we will Make America Strong Again and bring back Peace through Strength,” he said.</p>

<p>“We will also protect Hindu Americans against the anti-religion agenda of the radical left. We will fight for your freedom. Under my administration, we will also strengthen our great partnership with India and my good friend, Prime Minister (Narendra) Modi,” Trump had said.</p>

<p>Utsav Sanduja, founder and chairman of Hindus for America First told PTI in an interview that they are very grateful to President Trump.</p>

<p>"I'm very grateful to President Trump, eternally grateful and eternally appreciative. It sucks that Kamala Harris hasn't said anything about this issue. I think that there's going to be a big change in this election coming from this,” Sanduja said.</p>

<p>HinduAction also thanked Trump for his statement.</p>

<p>“As you rightly pointed out, the situation of the Hindus in Bangladesh is precarious. Below is a summary head with regularly updated data on the atrocities against Hindus in Bangladesh,” it said.</p>

<p>“Thank you President Trump for showing moral clarity and unequivocally condemning anti-Hindu pogroms in Bangladesh,” said Indian-American Nathan Punwani.</p>

<p>“Trump is a great man and, a great leader, full credit goes to him for wishing all the Hindus, Buddhists, and Jain Sikhs a very blessed Diwali. I think Trump really, really cares about these communities. He really understands what's going on in Bangladesh. He sees the ongoing persecution of Hindus. He is concerned about religious minorities that are suffering right now in that country,” Sanduja said.</p>

<p>“He has done such a great favour to millions of Americans who are concerned about human rights issues. To deliver on Diwali, such an auspicious day, such a magnificent thing. I'd like to say that many of us in the Hindu community played a small part in persuading President Trump's team, talking about this, giving briefings, and putting papers together,” he said.</p>

<p>“We are seeing that 60 per cent of Indian Americans are supporting Kamala Harris. In the last election, I think 68 per cent supported Biden. There's a dip in support for the Democratic presidential candidate. Trump, last time around, had 22 per cent of the Indian American community. Now he's at 32 per cent. This is according to Carnegie Endowment's latest survey on Indian American attitudes,” he said.</p>

<p>“With this statement, it's going to open up the eyes of more Indian Americans, Hindu Americans, and so on. They're going to give President Trump the vote,” Sanduja said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/k68cdff_utsav-sanduja-founder-and-chairman-of-hindus-for-america-first-pti_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Utsav Sanduja, founder, chairman of Hindus for America First, during an interview with PTI]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-international-airport-has-never-lost-a-bag-in-30-years-of-operation-kansai-international-airport-in-japan-6920729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This International Airport Has Never Lost A Bag In 30 Years Of Operation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-international-airport-has-never-lost-a-bag-in-30-years-of-operation-kansai-international-airport-in-japan-6920729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:27:00 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The airport says it has never lost a suitcase, a set of golf clubs, a stroller or anything in fact -- a feat its employees humbly shrug off as nothing special.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kansai International Airport in Japan can't be held responsible for the less superlative performance of airlines or other stops on a traveller's journey, but it claims its handlers never lose a bag.</p>

<p>In 30 years of operation, the airport serving the region around Osaka and Kyoto says it has never lost a suitcase, a set of golf clubs, a stroller or anything in fact -- a feat its employees humbly shrug off as nothing special.</p>

<p>"We just follow the work processes and rules and do what we have to do," Tsuyoshi Habuta, the supervisor at CKTS, one of the handling companies at Kansai, told AFP.</p>

<p>There is no "special training" but Habuta and his teams handle more than 3,000 pieces of luggage every day with attention to detail.</p>

<p>"We carefully handle suitcases to avoid shocks. Suitcase handles are aligned in a direction that is easy for customers to pick up," Habuta said.</p>

<p>"We hand fragile items, strollers, surfboards and skis directly to passengers," he said.</p>

<p>Luggage is on the carousel inside in the terminal building "within 15 minutes of the aircraft's arrival to minimise stress of customers," he added.</p>

<p>One of Japan's busiest international airports, Kansai was ranked the World's Best Airport for Baggage Delivery by UK-based airport rating organisation SKYTRAX in April.</p>

<p>"Everyone at the Kansai Airport is proud of this," co-CEO of the airport Benoit Rulleau told AFP.</p>

<p>Rulleau acknowledged that it is easier to achieve zero lost bags at an airport such as Kansai, which serves relatively few connecting passengers.</p>

<p>But he said the achievement reflects the "incredible devotion" of the airport's staff.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The number of lost or delayed bags has sharply decreased globally in the past decade thanks to technology, said Nicole Hogg, baggage portfolio director at SITA, a Geneve-based IT services provider in the air transport industry.</p>

<p>"If you think about the passenger volumes that we have, 6.9 bags being mishandled (per 1,000 passengers) is a very low figure," Hogg told AFP.</p>

<p>"A decade ago, we were in double figures," she said, adding "the industry investing in technology is definitely paying off."</p>

<p>She explained that baggage is rarely mishandled when passengers have no connections.</p>

<p>"The complexity really comes in the transfer process where passengers have short connection times and they're trying to get from one flight to another," she said.</p>

<p>Kansai recently returned to its pre-pandemic level of 25 million international passengers a year.</p>

<p>Ahead of the Osaka Expo 2025 it has gone through a renovation with a new security checkpoint that allows for an even smoother experience.</p>

<p>Rulleau said the airport will be able to accommodate up to 40 million passengers a year -- and probably none of them will lose their bag.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7gd06i0o_kansai-airport_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The airport serves the region around Osaka and Kyoto]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-unstable-obsessed-with-revenge-consumed-with-grievance-kamala-harris-6920669]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Unstable, Obsessed With Revenge, Consumed With Grievance: Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-unstable-obsessed-with-revenge-consumed-with-grievance-kamala-harris-6920669]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:18:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump is becoming increasingly unstable, obsessed with revenge and is out for unchecked power, Vice President Kamala Harris said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former President Donald Trump is becoming increasingly unstable, obsessed with revenge and is out for unchecked power, Vice President Kamala Harris said on Friday in an unprecedented attack on her Republican rival ahead of next week's election.</p>

<p>In a rally in Las Vegas, Harris, the Democratic leader of Indian heritage said Trump is all about "hate" and more division and that he would bring an "enemies list" to the White House while she would carry a "to-do list" of priorities.</p>

<p>Singer Jennifer Lopez joined the Democratic leader at the rally.</p>

<p>"We all know who Donald Trump is. He is not someone who is thinking about how to make your life better. He is someone who is increasingly unstable, obsessed with revenge, consumed with grievance, and he is out for unchecked power," Harris said at the rally.</p>

<p>With just four days left for the November 5 vote, the race between Trump and Harris remained very tight in the key battleground states.</p>

<p>"If he (Trump) is re-elected, Donald Trump will walk into the office with an enemies list. If I am elected, I will walk in with a 'to-do list' on behalf of you," Harris said.</p>

<p>"And at the top of my list is bringing down the cost of your living. That will be my focus every single day as the President," she added.</p>

<p>Harris said she would put the country ahead of her party and be a president for all Americans.</p>

<p>"Unlike Donald Trump, I do not believe that people who disagree with me are the enemy. He wants to put them in jail. I want to give them a seat at the table. That's what real leadership look like," she said.</p>

<p>"I pledge to always put country above party, and self and to be a president for all Americans," she added.</p>

<p>Harris said, if elected to the White House, she would make housing more affordable by building more houses.</p>

<p>"We will cut taxes for small business, we will lower health care costs."</p>

<p>"I see the promise of America in everyone here," she said.</p>

<p>The Democratic leader also attacked Trump for his comment that he would protect women whether they "like it or not".</p>

<p>The comments showed that Trump "does not understand women's rights to make decisions about their own lives, including their own bodies," she said.</p>

<p>The remarks by Harris came as the presidential election race remained razor-tight. The latest CNN polls showed that Harris has a narrow advantage in Michigan and Wisconsin, while she and Trump remain tied in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>In Michigan, Harris holds a lead over Trump by 48 per cent to 43 per cent among likely voters, according to the findings.</p>

<p>Harris also leads Trump in Wisconsin, where 51 per cent support her to 45 per cent for Trump, but the race is tied in Pennsylvania with both having 48 per cent support.</p>

<p>More than 62 million voters have cast early ballots, according to the University of Florida's Election Lab.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/l19grjt_kamala-harris-in-second-presidential-debate_625x300_11_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In a rally, Harris said Trump is all about "hate" and more division]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mauritius-bans-social-media-untill-elections-end-after-wire-tapping-scandal-6920618]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mauritius Bans Social Media Untll Elections End After Wire-Tapping Scandal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mauritius-bans-social-media-untill-elections-end-after-wire-tapping-scandal-6920618]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 14:10:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A scandal broke out earlier this month in Mauritius when secret recordings of phone calls by politicians, journalists, members of civil society and even foreign diplomats were leaked online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Ocean island of Mauritius blocked access to social media on Friday, just days ahead of a general election as tensions mounted over a wire-tapping scandal.&nbsp;The shock move was announced by telecoms operator EMTEL, which said it was ordered late Thursday by the Information and Communication Technologies Authority to block access to all social media platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The blockage is due to last until November 11 -- a day after the election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>EMTEL said the order referred to "illegal postings that may impact national security and public safety".&nbsp;</p>

<p>It follows a scandal that broke out earlier this month when secret recordings of phone calls by politicians, journalists, members of civil society and even foreign diplomats were leaked online.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment from the government on the social media ban.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It's shocking, revolting, and unacceptable. It's a sign of panic," said Paul Berenger, one of the leaders of the opposition Alliance for Change coalition.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are dealing with people who are dangerous to the country. Lawyers are working on what can be done legally. We will move very quickly on the legal and political level."</p>

<p>Prime Minister Pravind Kumar Jugnauth is seeking re-election as head of the Militant Socialist Movement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He inherited the premiership on the death of his father in 2017 and secured a victory for his coalition in polls two years later.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"This is the last desperate act of a regime in disarray," said Nando Bodha, head of opposition grouping Linion Reform.</p>

<p>"It attacks head-on the fundamental rights of citizens guaranteed by the constitution, including freedom of expression," he added, calling for an intervention by the Election Commission to ensure the polls are "free and fair".&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/l6ms9v4g_social-media-ban_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-slams-donald-trumps-offensive-remark-on-women-no-respect-6920269]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Respect...": Kamala Harris Slams Trump's "Offensive" Remark On Women]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-elections-kamala-harris-slams-donald-trumps-offensive-remark-on-women-no-respect-6920269]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 13:13:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris on Thursday slammed Donald Trump for "very offensive" remarks about women as she pressed her case that his misogyny has no place in 21st century America, just days ahead of a nail-biter election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris on Thursday slammed Donald Trump for "very offensive" remarks about women as she pressed her case that his misogyny has no place in 21st century America, just days ahead of a nail-biter election.</p>

<p>With each candidate seeking even the slightest of advantages, they took their knife-edge White House race to western battleground states, homing in on immigration and wooing Latinos five days before voting concludes November 5.</p>

<p>In one of three stops in the West, Trump painted a dark picture of immigration run amok as he addressed supporters in border state New Mexico, saying migrants are "unleashing a violent killing spree all across America."</p>

<p>There is no evidence of a migrant crime wave in the United States.</p>

<p>As the Democratic vice president and Republican former president chase one another through the seven swing states expected to decide the election, Harris is conveying a more upbeat message, with her final stop of the day at a star-studded rally in Las Vegas, where she was introduced by pop maven Jennifer Lopez.</p>

<p>Harris targeted Trump over his remarks when he told a Wednesday rally he wanted to "protect" American women "whether the women like it or not."</p>

<p>She branded the comments "offensive to everybody."&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>'Yes we can'</strong></h3>

<p>In Las Vegas, she slammed Trump as a man who "simply does not respect the freedom of women or the intelligence of women to be able to make decisions about their own lives."</p>

<p>"And we know if he were elected, he would ban abortion nationwide, restrict access to birth control, put IVF treatments at risk, and for states, listen to this, to monitor women's pregnancies."</p>

<p>Reproductive rights have served as a rallying cry for Democrats -- and an Achilles' heel of sorts for Trump -- since the conservative-dominated US Supreme Court ended the federal right to abortion in 2022.</p>

<p>Polling for this year's election shows a wide gender gap, with women voters tilting toward Harris, and Trump earning more support from men, so abortion could play a determining role in the outcome.</p>

<p>Trump's three stops were characterized by his now-usual stream of insults, including against Democrats Barack Obama, Hillary Clinton and Harris.</p>

<p>"She destroyed our economy," Trump said, referring to a period that, contrary to his criticism, is showing robust US growth, low unemployment and increasing consumer confidence, despite voter concerns about high prices.</p>

<p>In what was billed as an interview with right-wing provocateur Tucker Carlson, Trump got personal again, calling the vice president "a low IQ individual... dumb as a rock."</p>

<p>Carlson, who once texted a colleague that he hated Trump "passionately", had given the former president a fawning introduction, and said he would be proudly voting for him.</p>

<h3><strong>'I love Hispanics'</strong></h3>

<p>Trump is betting frustrations over the Biden-Harris administration's immigration policy will swing border state Arizona back in his favor after Biden beat Trump there in 2020.</p>

<p>His appearance in New Mexico was a head-scratcher, though, given that polls suggest Harris will carry the state. Nevertheless he courted Hispanic voters there.</p>

<p>"I love Hispanics. They are hard workers," said Trump, who faced backlash from Puerto Ricans earlier in the week after a racist comment by a warm-up speaker at a rally. "And they are warm -- sometimes they are too warm, if you want to know the truth."</p>

<p>On Thursday night, J Lo became the latest person of Puerto Rican heritage to lash Trump for the jibe.</p>

<p>"He reminded us who he really is and how he really feels," she told a cheering crowd.</p>

<p>"It wasn't just Puerto Ricans that were offended that day, okay? It was every Latino in this country, it was humanity and anyone of decent character."</p>

<p>Latinos traditionally have aligned more with Democrats, but recent polling shows a noticeable trend toward Republicans.</p>

<p>In Nevada, Trump also confirmed that he had sued US television network CBS for $10 billion over an interview given by Harris this month to its flagship news show, "60 Minutes."</p>

<p>According to the complaint, Harris gave a confusing answer to a question on the Biden administration's handling of Israel's war in Gaza, and CBS edited the answer to cover up "word salad."</p>

<p>Trump -- whose own rhetorical meanderings have at times been glossed over by the press in a practice some have dubbed "sanewashing" -- called it "election interference fraud." CBS has denied the accusation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The latest New York Times/Siena poll showed Harris with 52 percent support among Hispanic voters to Trump's 42 percent.</p>

<p>More cat-and-mouse campaigning occurs Friday in Wisconsin, where both candidates will hold rallies in Milwaukee.</p>

<p>Some 63.5 million Americans have cast their ballots early, more than 40 percent of the 2020 total vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ppug5hs_kamla-harris_625x300_30_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris branded Donald Trump's comments "offensive to everybody."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turban-wearing-smiling-australian-pm-celebrates-bandi-chhor-divas-6920229]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Turban-Wearing, Smiling Australian PM Celebrates Bandi Chhor Divas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/turban-wearing-smiling-australian-pm-celebrates-bandi-chhor-divas-6920229]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 13:09:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese wished the Sikhs on Bandi Chhor Divas and visited a gurdwara in Glenwood.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese posted a few photos on his X handle of himself celebrating the Bandi Chhor Divas, a big day for the Sikh community, on Friday (November 1). It marks the release of 52 Hindu princes from the Gwalior fort with the help of the sixth Guru Hargobind Sahib on Diwali and hence is celebrated as the sacred day. On Bandi Chhor divas (Prisoner Liberation Day), Guru Hargobind returned to Amritsar along with 52 princes who were imprisoned by the Mughal emperor Jahangir in 1619.</p>

<p>Mr Albanese wished the Sikhs on Bandi Chhor Divas and visited a gurdwara in Glenwood.</p>

<p>"Happy Bandi Chhor Divas! Wonderful to celebrate at Gurdwara Sahib Glenwood today and open the newly expanded kitchen, serving thousands of people every week," he said on X.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Happy Bandi Chhor Divas!<br />
<br />
Wonderful to celebrate at Gurdwara Sahib Glenwood today and open the newly expanded kitchen, serving thousands of people every week. <a href="https://t.co/FVVi8HVKmg">pic.twitter.com/FVVi8HVKmg</a></p>
— Anthony Albanese (@AlboMP) <a href="https://twitter.com/AlboMP/status/1852212827102286039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The accompanying photos show the Australian Prime Minister smiling while wearing a turban, and posing with people at the gurdwara for selfies.</p>

<p>"You look smart Prime Minister Anthony Albanese," one X user said while commenting on the Australian leader's post. "Thanks for the warm wishes," said another.</p>

<p>According to non-profit Sikh Youth Australia, Sikhism is the fastest-growing religious group in Australia and ranks as the fifth-largest religious community in the country.</p>

<p>The state of Victoria hosts the largest Sikh population in Australia, followed by New South Wales and Queensland, where significant Sikh communities are also present.</p>

<h3><strong>The history of Bandi Chhor Divas</strong></h3>

<p>According to the Shiromani Gurdwara Parbandhak Committee (SGPC), to stop the Sikh faith from flourishing, Mughal emperor Jahangir imprisoned Sri Guru Hargobind Sahib at Gwalior Fort.</p>

<p>Jahangir fell ill and could not get well despite efforts. To get rid of his illness, Sufi Saint Sain Mian Mir advised Jahangir to release Guru Hargobind Sahib.</p>

<p>Guru Hargobind Singh refused to be released alone. Jahangir said whoever can come out holding a 'palla' (end portion of a robe) of imprisoned Guru, can be released. The Guru got a special robe stitched, holding which 52 imprisoned princes got released from jail.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ajaaj5i8_anthony-albanese-turban_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Australian PM Anthony Albanese at a gurdwara in Glenwood.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasas-rover-captures-googly-eye-eclipse-on-mars-watch-6920035]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NASA's Rover Captures 'Googly Eye' Eclipse On Mars - Watch]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasas-rover-captures-googly-eye-eclipse-on-mars-watch-6920035]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:37:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The potato-shaped Martian moon was passing directly between the Sun and a point on the surface of Mars]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perseverance rover, currently roaming the red, rocky surface of Mars, captured a video of the partial eclipse in the atmosphere as Phobos crossed in front of the Sun, giving the illusion of what NASA referred to as 'googly eye'. The potato-shaped Martian moon was passing directly between the Sun and a point on the surface of Mars, obscuring a large part of the Sun's disc when it was clicked by Perseverance's Mastcam-Z camera on its 1,285th day (September 30) on the Red Planet.</p>

<p>"Ever feel like someone's watching you? That's how I felt when I observed this transit of the Martian moon Phobos! The pupil in this "googly eye" is the potato-shaped moon, and the iris is our Sun," the X (formerly Twitter) handle of Perseverance captioned the intriguing video.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Ever feel like someone's watching you?<br />
<br />
That's how I felt when I observed this transit of the Martian moon Phobos! The pupil in this "googly eye" is the potato-shaped moon, and the iris is our Sun. Learn more: <a href="https://t.co/jUYoXY1jpK">https://t.co/jUYoXY1jpK</a> <a href="https://t.co/7izVWOHEPH">pic.twitter.com/7izVWOHEPH</a></p>
— NASA's Perseverance Mars Rover (@NASAPersevere) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAPersevere/status/1851715598637764846?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Since landing at Mars' Jezero Crater in February 2021, Perseverance has captured several Phobos transits. Curiosity captured a video in 2019 while Opportunity captured an image in 2004.</p>

<h2><strong>About Phobos</strong></h2>

<p>Phobos was discovered in 1877 by Asaph Hall who named it based on the mythological sons of Ares, the Greek counterpart of the Roman god, Mars. Phobos means fear and is the brother of Deimos.</p>

<p>Phobos is larger than Deimos, measuring 27 by 22 by 18 kilometres in diameter. It orbits Mars three times a day and is so close to the planet's surface that in some locations on Mars it cannot always be seen.</p>

<p>Phobos' proximity to Mars means it is set on a collision course with the Red Planet. It is nearing Mars at a rate of six feet (1.8 meters) every hundred years which means it will either crash into Mars in 50 million years or break up into a ring.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/scientists-discover-mysterious-structures-hidden-under-the-surface-of-mars-6579050"><strong>Also read | Scientists Discover Mysterious Structures Hidden Under The Surface of Mars</strong></a></p>

<h2><strong>Sign of life on Mars</strong></h2>

<p>In July this year, the rover discovered an intriguing rock sample, nicknamed "Cheyava Falls," which contains organic molecules and structures that could have been formed by microbial life.</p>

<p>''The rock exhibits chemical signatures and structures that could possibly have been formed by life billions of years ago when the area being explored by the rover contained running water,'' NASA said at the time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/7k59pl7_mars_625x300_01_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Martain moon Phobos passing across Sun]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-hires-metas-former-engineering-head-jay-parikh-6919956]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Microsoft Hires Meta's Former Engineering Head Jay Parikh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/microsoft-hires-metas-former-engineering-head-jay-parikh-6919956]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Nov 2024 12:22:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Corp, which is struggling to bring data centers online fast enough to meet the demand for its artificial intelligence products, hired one of the engineering chiefs who kept Facebook's infrastructure humming.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft Corp, which is struggling to bring data centers online fast enough to meet the demand for its artificial intelligence products, hired one of the engineering chiefs who kept Facebook's infrastructure humming.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Jay Parikh will join the senior leadership team and report to Satya Nadella, Microsoft's chief executive officer.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"There are very few leaders in our industry with Jay's experience in leading teams through the rapid growth and scale required to support today's largest internet businesses," Nadella said Thursday in an internal email, which the Redmond, Washington-based company also posted on its corporate blog.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Parikh, who most recently ran cloud security startup Lacework, previously led engineering at Facebook, now Meta Platforms Inc. Nadella said the company would share details on Parikh's role in "the next few months."</p>

<p>A Microsoft spokesperson didn't immediately comment beyond the CEO's note.</p>

<p>Parikh joined Facebook in 2009 and spent more than a decade there, working on technical infrastructure and data center projects that helped the company grow into the world's largest social network.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meta broke ground on more than a dozen data centers around the world while Parikh was there. As many technology companies unplugged their own data centers in favor of rented computing power from Microsoft or Amazon.com Inc., Meta remained one of the few companies capable of building cutting-edge server farms at a massive scale.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Parikh oversaw several other technical projects, including Meta's efforts in subsea cables and its ill-fated Aquila drone project intended to beam wireless internet down to rural places in the US.</p>

<p>Microsoft, which operates subsea cable and data center design projects of its own, is increasingly focused on infrastructure projects that can help it wring greater power and efficiency from its network. Thanks largely to its partnership with ChatGPT maker OpenAI, Microsoft is at the forefront of the effort to build tools that rely on generative artificial intelligence. The company is racing to build data centers and chips to back that effort.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Microsoft forecast slower growth in its critical Azure cloud business as the company struggles to get data centers up and running fast enough to meet demand.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ne43u378_jay-parikh_625x300_01_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jay Parikh joined Facebook in 2009]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>