<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:05:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-elon-musk-suggests-hell-be-thrown-in-prison-if-kamala-harris-beats-donald-trump-in-upcoming-election-6743507]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Suggests He'll Be Thrown In Prison If Kamala Harris Beats Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-elon-musk-suggests-hell-be-thrown-in-prison-if-kamala-harris-beats-donald-trump-in-upcoming-election-6743507]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:02:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Billionaire Elon Musk suggested on Monday that he would end up in prison if US Vice President Kamala Harris beats Donald Trump in the upcoming presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk suggested on Monday that he would end up in prison if US Vice President Kamala Harris beats Donald Trump in the upcoming presidential election. After appearing alongside Mr Trump at a weekend rally, Mr Musk used a two-hour chat with Tucker Carlson to push right-wing talking points. "If he (Donald Trump) loses, I'm f****d," Mr Musk told Mr Carlson in an interview broadcast on X (formerly Twitter). "How long do you think my prison sentence is going to be? Will I see my children? I don't know," he quipped.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Watch the interview below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Elon Musk is all in.<br />
<br />
(0:00) Elon Musk Is All in on Donald Trump<br />
(6:35) Providing Starlink to Victims of Hurricane Helene<br />
(9:22) If Trump Loses, This Is the Last Election<br />
(21:49) The Epstein and Diddy Client List<br />
(33:38) Vaccines<br />
(35:49) The Movement to Decriminalize Crime… <a href="https://t.co/jNqB1ThqQz">pic.twitter.com/jNqB1ThqQz</a></p>
— Tucker Carlson (@TuckerCarlson) <a href="https://twitter.com/TuckerCarlson/status/1843375397024485778?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Musk's interview with Mr Carlson comes after he endorsed Donald Trump and appeared alongside the Republican on Saturday at his rally in Butler, Pennsylvania. During the interview, Mr Musk ramped up his public support for Donald Trump, telling Mr Carlson that he is "all in" on the Republic presidential candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My view is that if Trump doesn't win this election it's the last election we are going to have," Mr Musk said, explaining that he fears millions of migrants that the Harris-Biden administration "has been importing" will eventually be granted citizenship and tip future votes permanently.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"My prediction is, if there is another four years of a Democratic administration, they will legalize so many illegals that the next election, there will be no swing states," he predicted, forecasting that will lead to "single-party rule."&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maye-elon-musk-s-mother-sparks-controversy-with-post-suggesting-voter-fraud-6741864">Elon Musk's Mother Faces Backlash For Suggesting Voter Fraud Before US Polls</a></strong></p>

<p>To back his stance, Mr Musk cited the 1986 Immigration Reform and Control Act, which guaranteed amnesty to millions of migrants in the country illegally, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/07/us-news/elon-musk-suggests-hell-be-thrown-in-prison-if-harris-beats-trump-if-he-loses-im-fed/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Thereafter, California turned very strongly Dem," he said. "You just need enough [new citizens] for there to not be swing states. I think we want to remain a democracy and we don't want to become a one-party state. The people who are saying Trump is a threat to democracy are themselves a threat to democracy. One party-rule is not democracy," Mr Musk said.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/dhjbtamo_elon-musk-twitter_625x300_06_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["If he (Donald Trump) loses, I'm f****d," Mr Musk told Mr Carlson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-ordered-to-leave-france-over-social-media-posts-6743498]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Osama Bin Laden's Son Ordered To Leave France Over Social Media Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/osama-bin-ladens-son-ordered-to-leave-france-over-social-media-posts-6743498]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 16:01:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French authorities have ordered Omar bin Laden, a son of slain Al Qaeda leader Osama bin Laden, to leave the country over posts on social media, France's interior minister announced on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French authorities have ordered Omar bin Laden, a son of dead Al Qaeda leader Osama bin Laden, to leave the country over posts on social media, France's interior minister announced on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Born in Saudi Arabia, where he spent his early years, Omar bin Laden, 43, has also lived in Sudan and Afghanistan. He left his father at the age of 19 and eventually settled in Normandy in northern France in 2016, taking up painting.</p>

<p>France's new interior minister, Bruno Retailleau, said on X (former Twitter) that Omar bin Laden had lived in the department of Orne in Normandy as a spouse of a British national.</p>

<p>The minister said that the jihadist's son "posted comments on his social networks in 2023 that advocated terrorism."</p>

<p>"As a result, the prefect of Orne issued an order to leave French territory," Retailleau said.</p>

<p>"The courts have confirmed the legality of this decision taken in the interests of national security," he added.</p>

<p>The interior minister also said he had signed off on a ban preventing Omar bin Laden "to return to France for any reason whatsoever."</p>

<p>He did not provide further details and it was not clear if Omar bin Laden had already left France.</p>

<p>Omar bin Laden's marriage to British woman Jane Felix-Browne, a grandmother who had been divorced five times previously and over two decades his senior, had caused considerable media interest when it was confirmed in 2007.</p>

<p>After marriage she took on the Muslim name of Zaina Mohammed. Omar bin Laden sought to live in the UK, but his bid was rejected by the British authorities.</p>

<p>Osama bin Laden, himself the son of a hugely wealthy Saudi construction magnate, is believed to have had some two dozen children.</p>

<p>US special forces killed the Al-Qaeda founder in Pakistan in 2011.</p>

<p>Retailleau has vowed to bring "order" on immigration and crime, insisting that "the rule of law is neither intangible nor sacred."</p>

<p>His appointment as France's top cop is emblematic of the rightward shift of the government under new Prime Minister Michel Barnier following this summer's legislative elections that resulted in a hung parliament.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bmsc01gg_omar-bin-laden_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Osama bin Laden is believed to have had some two dozen children. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madeleine-mccann-case-suspect-cleared-of-separate-sex-crimes-6743351]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Madeleine McCann Case Suspect Cleared Of Separate Sex Crimes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madeleine-mccann-case-suspect-cleared-of-separate-sex-crimes-6743351]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:44:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The German convicted rapist and main suspect in the 2007 disappearance of British toddler Madeleine McCann was on Tuesday cleared of all charges in an unrelated sex crimes trial.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>The German convicted rapist and main suspect in the 2007 disappearance of British toddler Madeleine McCann was on Tuesday cleared of all charges in an unrelated sex crimes trial.</p>

<p>The case has been closely watched because the acquittal means 47-year-old Christian Brueckner could be released from jail as early as next year, according to court officials.</p>

<p>State prosecutors said they would appeal the verdict handed down in the court in the central city of Brunswick.</p>

<p>Brueckner is currently behind bars, serving a sentence for raping a 72-year-old US tourist in 2005 in Praia da Luz -- the same Portuguese seaside resort where Madeleine went missing two years later.</p>

<p>Prosecutors in Brueckner's latest trial had called for him to be jailed for a further 15 years, describing him as a "dangerous psychopathic sadist".</p>

<p>However, the presiding judge Uta Engemann said Brueckner could "not be convicted of the acts he is accused of" because of insufficient evidence and ruled: "The defendant is acquitted."</p>

<p>Brueckner, a tall man with blond hair, blue eyes and sporting the same grey coat he has worn throughout the hearings, showed no visible reaction to the verdict.</p>

<p>He was revealed as a suspect in 2020 in a bombshell development in the "Maddie" investigation, one of the highest-profile missing persons cases in history.</p>

<p>German prosecutors have not charged him over Madeleine's disappearance, although they also say investigations are continuing and that they are certain that Madeleine is dead.</p>

<p>Two years ago, Brueckner was charged with five separate counts of rape and child sex abuse that prosecutors alleged he had committed in Portugal between 2000 and 2017.</p>

<p>The charges came about as a result of investigations into the "Maddie" case, according to prosecutors.</p>

<p><strong>Lack of hard evidence</strong></p>

<p>In one of the alleged cases, Brueckner was accused of entering the holiday apartment of a woman aged between 70 and 80, tying her up and beating and sexually assaulting her.</p>

<p>In another, prosecutors said he had entered a young Irish woman's apartment via her balcony while she was sleeping, threatening her with a knife and raping her several times.</p>

<p>He had also been accused of exposing himself to a 10-year-old German girl on a beach and to an 11-year-old Portuguese girl at a playground.</p>

<p>Notebooks seized from Brueckner detailing his sexual fantasies were also used as evidence. But, despite their disturbing content, they provided no direct link to the alleged crimes.</p>

<p>The presiding judge, Engemann, labelled some of the witness testimonies as "inconsistent" and "almost worthless".</p>

<p>She acknowledged that the verdict might be "unsatisfactory" for the victims but said the judges were bound by their oath to impartiality and not the expectations of prosecutors, the media or the public.</p>

<p>Christian Wolters, a spokesman for the prosecution, told AFP that "we consider the judgement to be wrong in substance and will therefore appeal so that the Federal Court of Justice will review the decision again for legal errors".</p>

<p><strong>Missing without trace</strong></p>

<p>In July, Brueckner's lawyers had first succeeded in having an arrest warrant against him cancelled as there was no longer deemed to be an "urgent suspicion" that he committed the five offences.</p>

<p>The move at the time was a technicality as Brueckner remained behind bars. But his lawyer, Friedrich Fuelscher, argued that the court's decision was a "clear sign that the defendant will be acquitted".</p>

<p>Brueckner's current rape sentence runs until September 2025, according to Wolters, although Fuelscher has said the defendant could be free as soon as the spring.</p>

<p>Three-year-old Madeleine went missing from her family's holiday apartment in Portugal's Algarve region in May 2007 while her parents were dining at a nearby tapas bar.</p>

<p>Despite a huge international manhunt and global media attention, no trace of her has been found.</p>

<p>Investigations are continuing in the "Maddie" case and would proceed regardless of the outcome of the trial, Wolters told AFP earlier this week.</p>

<p>"At present, I am unable to say when we will be able to conclude these investigations and with what result," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/k10925g_christian-b-defendant-and-prime-suspect_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Prosecutors in Brueckner's latest trial had called for him to be jailed for a further 15 years. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-divers-body-parts-found-in-sharks-stomach-heres-why-her-friend-still-denies-shark-attack-6741489]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Diver Feared Eaten By Shark, But Friend Still Denies Shark Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-divers-body-parts-found-in-sharks-stomach-heres-why-her-friend-still-denies-shark-attack-6741489]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:41:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An American woman, presumed to have been killed by a shark while diving in Indonesia, possibly died from a medical condition before any encounter with the predator, according to her friend.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An American woman, presumed to have been killed by a shark while diving in Indonesia, possibly died from a medical condition before any encounter with the predator, according to her friend.</p>

<p>Colleen Monfore, 68, a mother of two and a Michigan resident, was on what was meant to be a dream diving holiday - a seven-week excursion with her husband Mike - when tragedy struck on September 26, said family friend Rick Sass.</p>

<p>Just days into their adventure, Monfore went missing during a group dive near Pulau Redang island, reported <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/07/us-news/american-eaten-by-shark-in-indonesia-may-have-had-medical-issue/">The New York Post</a>. Two weeks later, fishermen discovered a shark and retrieved human remains from its stomach, around 113 km away from the location of her disappearance. Authorities later identified Monfore through fingerprints, according to Sass, who has been in regular contact with the family.</p>

<p>“We do not believe this was a shark attack. Mike thinks she suffered some kind of medical issue in the water,” Sass told the New York Post.</p>

<p>Sass and his wife, Kim, who co-owned a dive shop for more than four decades, reviewed photos from the dive, engaged in conversations with Mike and analysed data from his diving computer.</p>

<p>Sass said that Monfore may have become separated from her group due to rough waters and was not killed by a shark. At the time of her disappearance, she was around 24 feet underwater and likely had half a tank of air remaining, according to the New York Post report.</p>

<p>"There was a down current at the turnaround site, but it was manageable. I've easily done 1000+ dives with this gracious woman. I don't believe it was the environment and certainly not a shark that ended her life,” Kim Sass mentioned in a Facebook post.</p>

<p>Rick Sass said, “They dove massive numbers of trips with us over 30 years. Bali, Philippines, Bikini Atoll, you name it. She knew what she was doing,” adding, “We used to call her ‘Saint Colleen.' She was an amazing woman. She loved nature and animals. I know she would have never wanted a shark to be blamed for this tragedy."</p>

<p>Sass also noted that shark attacks on divers were extremely uncommon. "And sharks are not that way. We've dived with hammerheads, tiger sharks, and bull sharks. You have to give them respect and be cautious, but they won't just attack you," he said.</p>

<p>The circumstances surrounding Colleen Monfore's death remain unclear. Images from the scene show the shark cut open, with human remains in a black wetsuit nearby.</p>

<p>"The shark was caught, but it was not in normal health. I thought it had swallowed plastic or a fishing net. It was cut open to find the problem, and inside there were the remains of a woman,” told a fisherman, as reported by Asia Pacific Press.</p>

<p>Indonesian authorities have announced that an investigation is underway.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/unsplash--shark-generic_625x300_1530432631269.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The circumstances surrounding Colleen Monfores death remain unclear. (representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-physics-goes-to-john-hopfield-geoffrey-hinton-for-work-on-machine-learning-6743213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Nobel Prize In Physics Goes To 2 Scientists For Work On AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-physics-goes-to-john-hopfield-geoffrey-hinton-for-work-on-machine-learning-6743213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:27:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists John Hopfield and Geoffrey Hinton won the 2024 Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries and inventions that enable machine learning within artificial neural networks, the award-giving body said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scientists John Hopfield and Geoffrey Hinton won the 2024 Nobel Prize in Physics for discoveries and inventions that enable machine learning within artificial neural networks, the award-giving body said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The award comes with a prize sum of 11 million Swedish crowns ($1.1 million), which is shared between the winners if there are several. The physics prize is awarded by the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences.</p>

<p>"This year's two Nobel Laureates in physics have used tools from physics to develop methods that are the foundation of today's powerful machine learning," the award-giving body said in a statement.</p>

<p>Widely considered the most prestigious prize for physicists across the world, it was created, along with awards for achievements in science, literature and peace, in the will of Alfred Nobel.</p>

<p>The prizes have been awarded with a few interruptions since 1901, though the Nobel economics honour is a later addition in memory of the Swedish businessman and philanthropist, who had made a fortune from his invention of dynamite.</p>

<p>Outside the sometimes controversial choices for peace and literature, physics often makes the biggest splash among the prizes, with the list of past winners featuring scientific superstars such as Albert Einstein, Niels Bohr and Enrico Fermi.</p>

<p>Last year's physics prize was awarded to Pierre Agostini, Ferenc Krausz and Anne L'Huillier for their work in creating ultra-short pulses of light that can give a snapshot of changes within atoms, potentially improving the detection of diseases.</p>

<p>Physics is the second Nobel to be awarded this week, after U.S. scientists Victor Ambros and Gary Ruvkun won the medicine prize for their discovery of microRNA and its role in gene regulation, shedding light on how cells specialise.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/3s2htn5o_nobel-prize-for-physics-_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel Prize In Physics: John Hopfield and Geoffrey Hinton won the 2024 Nobel Prize in Physics]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-the-second-warmest-september-on-record-says-climate-watchdog-6743182]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[This Is The Second-Warmest September On Record, Says Climate Watchdog]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/this-is-the-second-warmest-september-on-record-says-climate-watchdog-6743182]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:21:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Last month was the second-warmest September ever registered globally in an exceptional year "almost certain" to become the hottest on record, the EU climate monitor Copernicus said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month was the second-warmest September ever registered globally in an exceptional year "almost certain" to become the hottest on record, the EU climate monitor Copernicus said on Tuesday.</p>

<p>The Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S) said the average global temperature last month was second only to September 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p>September saw "extreme" rainfall and destructive storms in many parts of the world, events that are occurring with greater severity and frequency as global temperatures rise due to climate change.</p>

<p>Warmer air can hold more water vapour, and warmer oceans mean greater evaporation, resulting in more intense rainfall.</p>

<p>Hurricane Helene pounded the southeast United States, Typhoon Krathon slammed into Taiwan and Storm Boris brought floods and devastation to central Europe in a month of wild weather.</p>

<p>"The extreme rainfall events of this month, something we are observing more and more often, have been made worse by a warmer atmosphere, leading to more intense rainfall with months' worth of rain falling in just a few days," said Samantha Burgess, Deputy Director of the Copernicus Climate Change Service (C3S).</p>

<p>2023 was the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/worlds-hottest-day-record-broken-in-24-hours-says-climate-watchdog-6179974">warmest year</a> ever recorded but the months January through to September 2024 have set fresh highs, said Copernicus.</p>

<p>The monitor said it was "almost certain that 2024 is going to be the warmest year on record".</p>

<p>Copernicus records go back to 1940 but other sources of climate data such as ice cores, tree rings and coral skeletons allow scientists to expand their conclusions using evidence from much further in the past.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/ejdg1oc_global-warmingl_625x300_10_June_23.png' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[2023 was the warmest year ever, but January to September 2024 have set fresh highs. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-russian-mountaineers-killed-while-climbing-dhaulagiri-in-nepal-6742934]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Russian Mountaineers Killed While Climbing Dhaulagiri In Nepal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-russian-mountaineers-killed-while-climbing-dhaulagiri-in-nepal-6742934]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:53:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five Russian mountaineers were killed while climbing in Nepal, a tourism official said Tuesday, two days after the team lost contact while on the world's seventh-highest mountain, Dhaulagiri.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five Russian mountaineers were killed while climbing in Nepal, a tourism official said Tuesday, two days after the team lost contact while on the world's seventh-highest mountain, Dhaulagiri.</p>

<p>Rakesh Gurung, from Nepal's tourism department, said the team went missing late on the evening of October 6 during an attempt to summit the 8,167 metres (26,795 feet) high Himalayan peak.</p>

<p>"Five dead bodies were discovered by a helicopter rescue team," Gurung told AFP. "They fell from 7,700 meters."</p>

<p>He said one climber who quit the summit attempt had been rescued from the mountain and had "been admitted to hospital" in the capital Kathmandu.</p>

<p>Hundreds of people from around the world travel to the Himalayas each year for the autumn climbing season in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mount-makalu-mountain-guide-dies-in-nepal-after-climbing-worlds-fifth-highest-peak-5624318">Nepal.</a></p>

<p>Nepal is home to eight of the world's 14 highest peaks and foreign climbers that flock to its mountains are a major source of revenue for the country.</p>

<p>The rapid growth of the climbing industry has created fierce competition among companies for business and also raised <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-climbers-rescue-porters-body-a-year-after-k2-summit-6275998">fears </a>that some are cutting corners on safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Dhaulagiri's peak was first scaled in 1960 by a Swiss-Austrian team and has since been climbed by hundreds of people.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7u4190m_mountain-climbing-generic-_625x300_08_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nepal is home to eight of the world's 14 highest peaks. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-declares-need-for-reforms-before-elections-in-bangladesh-6742819]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus Declares Need for Reforms Before Elections In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-declares-need-for-reforms-before-elections-in-bangladesh-6742819]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:40:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's interim leader has refused to give a timeframe for elections following the ouster of his autocratic predecessor, saying in an interview published Tuesday that reforms are needed before polls.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's interim leader has refused to give a timeframe for elections following the ouster of his autocratic predecessor, saying in an interview published Tuesday that reforms are needed before polls.</p>

<p>Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus was appointed the country's "chief advisor" after the student-led uprising that toppled ex-premier Sheikh Hasina in August.</p>

<p>The 84-year-old microfinance pioneer is helming a temporary administration, to tackle what he has called the "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mountain-like-challenges-muhammad-yunus-asks-bangladesh-for-patience-6416647">extremely tough</a>" challenge of restoring democratic institutions.</p>

<p>"None of us are aiming at staying for a prolonged time," Yunus said of his caretaker government, in an interview published by the Prothom Alo newspaper.</p>

<p>"Reforms are pivotal," he added. "If you say, hold the election, we are ready to hold the election. But it would be wrong to hold the election first."</p>

<p>Hasina's 15-year rule saw widespread human rights abuses, including the mass detention and extrajudicial killings of her political opponents.</p>

<p>More than 600 people were killed in the weeks leading up to her ouster, according to a preliminary United Nations report which said the figure was likely an underestimate.</p>

<p>Her government was also accused of politicising courts and the civil service, as well as staging lopsided elections, to dismantle democratic checks on its power.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/want-good-ties-with-india-but-on-basis-of-fairness-equality-bangladeshs-chief-adviser-muhammad-yunus-6542712">Yunus </a>said he had inherited a "completely broken down" system of public administration that needed a comprehensive overhaul to prevent a future return to autocracy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Reforms mean we will not allow a repetition of what happened in the past", he added.</p>

<h3><strong>'Write as you please'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Yunus also batted away criticism at the numerous politicians, senior police officers and other Hasina loyalists arrested on murder charges after her government's ouster.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The arrests have prompted accusations that Yunus' caretaker government would hold politicised trials of senior figures from Hasina's regime.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But Yunus said it was his intention that any criminal trials initiated against those arrested would remain free from government interference.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Once the judicial system is reformed, then the issues will come forward, about who will be placed on trial, how justice will be carried out," he said.</p>

<p>At least 25 journalists -- considered by Hasina's opponents to be partisans of her government -- have been arrested for alleged violence against protesters since her downfall.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Press watchdog Reporters Without Borders has condemned those arrests as "systematic judicial harassment".</p>

<p>But Yunus insisted he wanted media freedom.</p>

<p>"Write as you please," he told the newspaper.</p>

<p>"Criticise. Unless you write, how will we know what is happening or not happening?"</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mvg10g7g_muhammad-yunus-martyrs_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus said he had inherited a completely broken down system of public administration. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-suspect-acquitted-of-sexual-abuse-charges-in-madeleine-mccann-case-6742681]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Suspect Acquitted of Sexual Abuse Charges In Madeleine McCann Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-suspect-acquitted-of-sexual-abuse-charges-in-madeleine-mccann-case-6742681]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:20:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A suspect in the disappearance of British toddler Madeleine McCann was acquitted of unrelated sexual abuse charges by a court in the German city of Brunswick on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A suspect in the disappearance of British toddler Madeleine McCann was acquitted of unrelated sexual abuse charges by a court in the German city of Brunswick on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Christian Brueckner has been formally identified as a suspect in the case of "Maddie" McCann, who disappeared from her bedroom in 2007 during a family holiday in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madeleine-mccann-case-sniffer-dogs-join-search-at-portuguese-reservoir-4063923">Portugal</a>. He denies any involvement and charges have not been brought.</p>

<p>In the trial in Brunswick, Brueckner faced three charges of aggravated rape and two of sexual abuse of children committed between 2000 and 2017.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/madeleine-mccann-16-years-on-search-for-missing-child-resumes-in-portugal-4059604">Prosecutors</a> had argued for the German national to be handed a 15-year sentence while his lawyer had called for him to be acquitted.</p>

<p>Brueckner, in his 40s, is already serving a seven-year prison term in Germany for raping a woman in the part of Portugal's Algarve region where McCann went missing.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/o5t38lro_christian-brueckner-acquitted-_625x300_08_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Christian Brueckner has been formally identified as a suspect in the case of "Maddie" McCann.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/phantom-cost-explained-why-people-think-freebies-are-too-good-to-be-true-6742551]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Phantom Cost Explained: Why People Think Freebies Are Too Good To Be True]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/phantom-cost-explained-why-people-think-freebies-are-too-good-to-be-true-6742551]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:02:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[If you're offered a free cookie, you might say yes. But if you're paid to eat a free cookie, would your response be the same?]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title"><span style="font-size: 13px;">If you're offered a free cookie, you might say yes. But if you're paid to eat a free cookie, would your response be the same?</span></p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>In our <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/01461672241235687">new research</a>, twice as many people were willing to eat a cookie when they weren't offered payment compared with when they were.</p>

<p>From a purely economic perspective, our findings reflect irrational decision-making. Objectively, a cookie plus money is better than just a cookie.</p>

<p>But people aren't purely economic. They're social animals with a tendency to look for hidden reasons behind other people's behaviours.</p>

<p>In the case of overly generous deals, people are expecting a “phantom cost” – one hidden in the initial offer. And this expectation influences their decision to accept something or not.</p>

<p>Research participants who were offered a free cookie plus payment thought maybe the cookies were poisoned. Or maybe someone spat on them. Or they expected they would then owe a favour to the person handing out the treats once the cookie was eaten.</p>

<h3><strong>Too good to be true</strong></h3>

<p>Our cookies study was just one of ten experiments involving 4,205 participants in the United States and Iran.</p>

<p>We tested how phantom costs influenced people's choices to accept or reject overly generous economic offers.</p>

<p>Each study gave people an offer. They had to decide whether to accept or not, and then explain why.</p>

<p>One study asked participants to imagine they were a truck driver and looking online for a job. All the jobs were described the same way, but we varied the wages. People offered the normal US$15 per hour were perfectly willing to take the job.</p>

<p>Others were offered more than the normal wage. The participants in this group imagined phantom costs. And the higher the wage they were offered, the worse the costs they imagined.</p>

<p>When offered $20 or $25 per hour, participants imagined the role involved more responsibilities or harder work. But they considered this to be worth it. Most people preferred a job that paid a bit more than normal, despite the expectation of phantom costs.</p>

<p>However, when we offered way too much money – more than $900 per hour – most people rejected the job they were willing to do for $15.</p>

<p>Why? They imagined far worse phantom costs: driving for the mob, carrying dangerous radioactive waste or smuggling drugs across the border. A suspiciously high hourly rate or wage can end up putting people off.</p>

<h3><strong>Suspicion is global</strong></h3>

<p>We repeated this experiment with different jobs, different normal wages, and in different countries.</p>

<p>In both the US and Iran, despite very different types of economy, people showed the same pattern of suspicion and rejected very high wages. The only difference was that in Iran the expected wages were lower, so the wages didn't have to be high by US standards to become suspicious.</p>

<p>Another experiment tested how phantom costs could affect purchases of plane tickets involving a hypothetical choice between three flights.</p>

<p>One cost $235, another $275. When the third option was $205, most people chose that. However, if the third option was $15, hardly anyone chose the cheapest flight. They rejected it because they imagined horrible phantom costs such as terrorists and plane crashes.</p>

<p>However, when we provided a reason for the low price – very uncomfortable seats – most people preferred the $15 flight. Uncomfortable seats are not usually a selling point. But they explained the cheap price, so people didn't search for other, dangerous explanations.</p>

<p>Sufficient explanations for something being a great deal remove people's tendency to imagine phantom costs.</p>

<h3><strong>A good offer, not a suspicious one</strong></h3>

<p>Businesses face a balancing act when it comes to offering customers a good deal.</p>

<p>On the one hand, the expectation of phantom costs decreases interest in the offer. On the other hand, price-sensitive consumers are often looking for ways to get the best deal.</p>

<p>To avoid the pitfalls of phantom costs, businesses need to communicate their reasons for offering a particularly good deal. A “holiday sale” or “end-of-season sale”, for example, may explain why items are discounted.</p>

<p>In the job market, identifying “good performance” as a reason for an employee's pay raise can sidestep the expectation of hidden downsides – such as an increased workload.</p>

<p>It's clear people are not merely self-interested economic beings. We're savvy, psychological beings capable of reading into the motivations of others to protect ourselves from offers that seem too good to be true.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238869/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/andrew-vonasch-1322239">Andrew Vonasch</a>, Senior Lecturer in Psychology, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/university-of-canterbury-1004">University of Canterbury</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/too-good-to-be-true-new-study-shows-people-reject-freebies-and-cheap-deals-for-fear-of-hidden-costs-238869">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/2lbllqmg_cookies-_625x300_08_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The cookies study was just one of ten experiments involving 4,205 participants in the US and Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maye-elon-musk-s-mother-sparks-controversy-with-post-suggesting-voter-fraud-6741864]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Mother Faces Backlash For Suggesting Voter Fraud Before US Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/maye-elon-musk-s-mother-sparks-controversy-with-post-suggesting-voter-fraud-6741864]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:29:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Maye Musk, the mother of billionaire Elon Musk, has sparked controversy after she appeared to encourage voter fraud a month ahead of the US elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maye Musk, the mother of billionaire Elon Musk, has sparked controversy after she appeared to encourage voter fraud a month ahead of the US elections. On October 5, she wrote on X, “The Democrats have given us another option. You don't have to register to vote. On Election Day, have 10 fake names, go to 10 polling booths and vote 10 times. That's 100 votes, and it's not illegal. Maybe we should work the system too.”<br />
<br />
However, X's community notes flagged the tweet, saying, “This is, in fact, illegal,” citing the US elections code of conduct. Investigations into voter fraud have also consistently shown it to be exceedingly rare, with no evidence supporting organised fraud by Democrats as Maye Musk suggested.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The Democrats have given us another option. You don't have to register to vote. On Election Day, have 10 fake names, go to 10 polling booths and vote 10 times. That's 100 votes, and it's not illegal. Maybe we should work the system too. <a href="https://t.co/GZ5DlaoFPs">https://t.co/GZ5DlaoFPs</a></p>
— Maye Musk (@mayemusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/mayemusk/status/1842637728946544839?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The internet also&nbsp;erupted in disbelief.</p>

<p>“Is this supposed to be a joke?” a user commented under Maye Musk's&nbsp;post.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Is this supposed to be a joke?</p>
— TheRealThelmaJohnson (@TheRealThelmaJ1) <a href="https://twitter.com/TheRealThelmaJ1/status/1842762864433500230?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A lawyer wrote, “This tweet constitutes the solicitation of a crime and is in itself a fully completed criminal act. If at least one person acts on your solicitation, you could also be charged with conspiracy. You should retract this tweet immediately.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">This tweet constitutes the solicitation of a crime and is in itself a fully completed criminal act. If at least one person acts on your solicitation, you could also be charged with conspiracy. You should retract this tweet immediately.</p>
— Olav Mitchell Underdal (@omunderdal) <a href="https://twitter.com/omunderdal/status/1842784774597067072?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“FBI and DOJ, if you're listening,” a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">FBI and DOJ, if you're listening.</p>
— Janice Hough (@leftcoastbabe) <a href="https://twitter.com/leftcoastbabe/status/1842732705504747686?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone said it was “voter fraud, and that gets prosecuted.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">That's voter fraud and that gets prosecuted</p>
— Robbin ¯\(ツ) ⁄ ¯ (@RaeMargaret61) <a href="https://twitter.com/RaeMargaret61/status/1842727756703969397?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Experts have weighed in on the legality of her statements. Nate Persily, a Stanford Law School election expert and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/elon-mukss-mother-maye-appears-encourage-voter-fraud-x-post-rcna174307 ">NBC News</a> contributor, noted that if individuals were to act on her advice, they would likely violate election laws. He pointed out that Title 52 of the US Code prohibits using false information to register to vote, with potential penalties, including fines up to $10,000 or imprisonment for up to five years.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Simply using a fake name also does not suffice for voter registration. Individuals must provide proof of identity, which typically includes a driver's licence number or the last four digits of their Social Security number. Election officials verify this information, and voters without proper documentation could be required to present utility bills or other proof of residency, depending on state regulations.<br />
<br />
Hours after her initial post, Maye Musk posted again, advising users to “ignore her previous post.” “In Butler, Pennsylvania, we just heard that the Republicans will make sure no illegals vote,” she clarified.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In Butler, Pennsylvania, we just heard that the Republicans will make sure no illegals vote. Ignore my previous post. <a href="https://t.co/syxMCHPeKN">https://t.co/syxMCHPeKN</a></p>
— Maye Musk (@mayemusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/mayemusk/status/1842683141573718442?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>In yet another tweet, the 76-year-old said that critics “don't understand sarcasm” and claimed her remarks were a response to California Governor Gavin Newsom's Senate Bill 1174, which prohibits local governments from imposing voter ID requirements in elections.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Actually, this comes from Gavin Newsom. What you are saying is that he should be jailed for his new law that prevents ID when voting, so illegal immigrants can vote many times. I guess you don't understand sarcasm. <a href="https://t.co/mw7dnyB7GX">https://t.co/mw7dnyB7GX</a></p>
— Maye Musk (@mayemusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/mayemusk/status/1843044164306715021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>As the crucial November 5 elections approach, Elon Musk has publicly endorsed Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his running mate JD Vance against Democrats Kamala Harris and Tim Walz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m21gu4b8_maye-musk-elon-musk-_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Experts have weighed in on the legality of Maye Musk's statements.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-speaks-up-on-the-kind-of-gun-she-uses-its-a-glock-6741862]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Speaks Up On The Kind Of Gun She Uses. It's A Glock.]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-speaks-up-on-the-kind-of-gun-she-uses-its-a-glock-6741862]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 12:26:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential candidate Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris revealed in an interview broadcast Monday that she owns a Glock semi-automatic pistol -- and said that "of course" she'd fired it on a shooting range.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential candidate Kamala Harris revealed in an interview broadcast Monday that she owns a Glock semi-automatic pistol -- and said that "of course" she'd fired it on a shooting range.</p>

<p>Speculation has swirled about the US vice president's weapon of choice ever since she told television star Oprah Winfrey recently that she was a gun owner and that she would shoot anyone who broke into her house.</p>

<p>"I have a Glock, and I've had it for quite some time," Harris said in an interview on the primetime CBS show 60 Minutes when asked what kind of firearm she packed.</p>

<p>"My background is in law enforcement. And -- so there you go," added the former prosecutor and California attorney general.</p>

<p>Interviewer Bill Whitaker then asked if Harris had ever fired the Glock. Harris replied with a laugh: "Of course I have. At a shooting range. Yes, of course, I have."</p>

<p>Austrian manufacturer Glock makes one of America's best-selling handguns. Widely used by police, Glocks have also attained cult status from their appearance in films and hip-hop culture.</p>

<p>Until recently Harris had rarely mentioned her status as a firearms owner, in line with her party's emphasis on curtailing access to guns in a country regularly rocked by armed crime and mass shootings.</p>

<p>But in a tight election with Republican Donald Trump, the 59-year-old Democrat has begun to play up her gun-owning credentials.</p>

<p>Trump has repeatedly claimed that Harris wants to confiscate Americans' guns in violation of the US Constitution's Second Amendment -- including in their only televised debate last month.</p>

<p>Harris fiercely rejected that charge, noting that she and her running mate, Tim Walz, are both gun owners.</p>

<p>"I'm a gun owner," she then told Winfrey in September. "If someone breaks into my house, they're getting shot," she added with a chuckle.</p>

<p>Her Glock revelation in was the most eye-catching in an interview that saw Harris carefully navigate tough questioning on hot-button topics like immigration and the economy.</p>

<p>Trump backed out of a 60 Minutes encounter last week, bucking what the program said was a half-century tradition of both US presidential candidates sitting down with the show before an election.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e1uoi98_kamala-harris-reuters-_625x300_03_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump has repeatedly claimed that Kamala Harris wants to confiscate Americans' guns. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-1-6-billion-fortune-taylor-swift-world-s-richest-female-musician-with-1-6-billion-fortune-6741613]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taylor Swift Surpasses Rihanna In Music Rich List, Her Net Worth Is...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/with-1-6-billion-fortune-taylor-swift-world-s-richest-female-musician-with-1-6-billion-fortune-6741613]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 11:59:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pop sensation Taylor Swift is now the world's richest female musician. As of October 8, 2024, Swift has an estimated net worth of $1.6 billion, surpassing another singing superstar Rihanna, Forbes reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pop sensation Taylor Swift is now the world's richest female musician. As of October 8, 2024, Swift has an estimated net worth of $1.6 billion, surpassing another singing superstar Rihanna, Forbes reported. The only musician with a higher net worth is hip-hop icon Jay-Z, valued at $2.5 billion.</p>

<p>What sets Swift apart in her financial journey is the source of her wealth. Unlike many of her peers who rely on lucrative brand partnerships and lifestyle ventures, Swift has primarily built her fortune through her music career. She is the first musician to achieve billionaire status predominantly through her musical achievements, including significant earnings from her record-breaking Eras Tour and the valuation of her extensive music catalogue -- valued at approximately $600 million -- according to Forbes.</p>

<p>Additionally, her income from royalties and touring is nearly $600 million, complemented by around $125 million in real estate assets, the magazine reported. In a bid to reclaim ownership of her earlier work, Swift began re-recording her first six albums in 2021. She will resume her Eras tour on October 18 in Miami.</p>

<p>A Washington Post report noted that many of Swift's contemporaries have accumulated their wealth through external ventures and not just music. For example, despite high demand, Rihanna has not released a studio album since 2016's 'Anti,' but her cosmetics brand, Fenty Beauty, launched in 2017, significantly boosted her fortune. Forbes estimated her net worth at approximately $1.4 billion.</p>

<p>Jay-Z, the first billionaire in hip-hop and the wealthiest musician globally with a net worth of $2.5 billion, also derives much of his wealth from business ventures outside of music, according to The Washington Post report. His last studio album, a collaboration with his wife Beyonc&amp;#233; in 2018 titled 'Everything Is Love,' did not contribute significantly to his current wealth. Jay-Z's riches largely stem from his various business interests, including his champagne brand, Armand de Brignac (often referred to as Ace of Spades), and his cognac brand, D'Uss&amp;#233;, along with investments in companies like Uber, Block (the parent company of CashApp), and the music streaming service Tidal.</p>

<p>Apart from rocking the stage, Swift isn't shy about making her political stance clear to her fans and the American electorate. In September, she endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris and praised her running mate, Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, for their commitment to issues such as abortion rights, IVF access and LGBTQ+ rights. "She fights for the rights and causes I believe need a warrior to champion them," Swift wrote about Harris in an <a href="https://www.instagram.com/taylorswift/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/">Instagram post</a>.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ppmudgjg_taylor-swift_625x300_08_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Taylor Swift has primarily built her fortune through her music career.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regional-tensions-mount-as-israel-trades-strikes-with-gaza-lebanon-on-anniversary-war-with-hamas-6741677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Trades Strikes With Gaza, Lebanon On Anniversary Of War With Hamas]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/regional-tensions-mount-as-israel-trades-strikes-with-gaza-lebanon-on-anniversary-war-with-hamas-6741677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 11:52:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A barrage of rockets were fired at Israel from Gaza and Lebanon on Tuesday as its war with Hamas completed a year on October 7.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A barrage of rockets were fired at Israel from Gaza and Lebanon on Tuesday as its war with Hamas, which completed a year on October 7, continues to threaten a wider regional conflict.</p>

<p>Iran-backed Lebanese group Hezbollah said it had targeted an Israeli military intelligence base near Tel Aviv on Monday, according to news agency&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-targeted-israeli-military-base-near-tel-aviv-6739716"><em>A</em></a><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-says-it-targeted-israeli-military-base-near-tel-aviv-6739716"><i>FP</i></a>. The Iran-backed group said it fired "a salvo of rockets at the Glilot base of military intelligence unit 8200 on the outskirts of Tel Aviv". Further, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/hezbollah-strikes-israel-gaza-war-anniversary-fears-grow-over-middle-east-2024-10-07/"><em>Reuters</em></a> reported that Hezbollah said it targeted a military base south of Haifa with "Fadi 1" missiles and launched another strike on Tiberias, 65 km (40 miles) away.</p>

<p>Hezbollah fighters in Lebanon fired about five rockets at Israel, setting off sirens around Tel Aviv but causing no casualties, according to Israeli authorities. Local residents reported hearing explosions in the sky over Israel. The Israeli military said several rockets were intercepted, while others landed in open areas.</p>

<p>Earlier on Monday, Israeli warplanes conducted extensive airstrikes in Lebanon, the Beqaa area, and Beirut, targeting over 120 Hezbollah targets which included infrastructure sites, launchers, command and control centres, and a weapons storage facility.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/earthquakes-in-iran-and-israel-sparks-speculation-of-nuclear-tests-6735904"><strong>Earthquakes In Iran And Israel Fuel Theories Of Covert Nuclear Testing</strong></a></p>

<p>Meanwhile, the armed wings of Hamas and the Islamic Jihad said fighters had attacked Israeli forces in the north with anti-tank rockets, and that there were casualties among the Israeli troops. The Hamas' Al-Qassam Brigades claimed they had targeted an Israeli armoured personnel carrier with a Yassin 105 missile in the Tuwam area, north of Gaza City.</p>

<p>On the other hand, the Israeli military launched targeted raids against Hezbollah in southwest Lebanon, expanding its ground operations along the country's coastline after deploying more troops.</p>

<p>Israel also sent tanks deeper into Jabalia in the northern Gaza Strip and advised people to leave as it pounded a Palestinian refugee camp from the air. Palestinian health officials did not immediately provide new casualty figures but said dozens had been killed in the Gaza Strip in the past 24 hours. Israel's military said one soldier had been killed in combat in northern Gaza. The Israeli military said it had killed many Palestinian militants, located weapons, and dismantled military infrastructure in its operations in Jabalia.</p>

<p>Memorials in the region and around the world mourned the loss of lives on both sides in the October 7 Hamas attack last year, when Hamas fighters targeted communities and security outposts. According to the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, over 41,000 people, the majority civilians, have been killed since the start of the war. Around 100 of 250 hostages have not been released.</p>

<p>A large chunk of Gaza remains in ruins, with tens of thousands dead, over half among them women and children. Nearly the entire Gaza population of 2.3 million has been displaced, most of them forced to live in dire conditions in refugee camps. The Lebanese fear the same fate as Israeli airstrikes have displaced 1.2 million people so far.</p>

<p>Meanwhile,&nbsp;Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Israel “will continue to fight” against its enemies.&nbsp;“As long as the enemy threatens our existence and the peace of our country, we will continue to fight. As long as our hostages are in Gaza, we will continue to fight. We will not give up on any of them. I won't give up," he said.</p>

<p><strong>No ceasefire in sight?</strong></p>

<p>Ceasefire deals between the warring sides have fallen through repeatedly, despite intervention from various countries. Recently, French Foreign Minister Jean-Noël Barrot pleaded for ceasefires in Gaza and Lebanon, adding that his country was ready to work for&nbsp; de-escalation in the region.</p>

<p>Barrot reiterated France's commitment to Israel's security as “unwavering,” but said “force alone cannot guarantee Israel's security". His comments come days after French President Emmanuel Macron called for “a halt to arms exports for use in Gaza".</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Displaced men sleep on mattresses in the open air on central Beiruts Ain al-Mreisseh seaside promenade" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0hhutafg_lebanon-displaced-people_625x300_08_October_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Displaced men sleep on mattresses in the open air on central Beiruts Ain al-Mreisseh seaside promenade" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Displaced men sleep on mattresses in the open air on central Beirut's Ain al-Mreisseh seaside promenade<br />
<span class="ins_instory_span_credit">Photo Credit: AFP</span></p>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/10/07/politics/us-not-currently-pushing-revive-israel-hezbollah-deal/index.html"><em>CNN</em></a> reported the US is not actively trying to revive the ceasefire deal and is trying to shape and limit Israeli operations in Lebanon and against Iran rather than halting hostilities.&nbsp;The earlier proposal had called for a 21-day pause in the fighting between Israel and Hezbollah to allow Israeli and Lebanese civilians to return home.</p>

<p><strong>China to provide medical supplies to Lebanon</strong></p>

<p>China will provide emergency medical supplies to Lebanon, China's official foreign aid agency, the China International Development Cooperation Agency, said. &nbsp;"At the request of the Lebanese government, the Chinese government has decided to provide emergency humanitarian medical supplies to Lebanon to help Lebanon carry out medical assistance," the statement said.</p>

<p><strong>World leaders remember “dark day”</strong></p>

<p>US President Joe Biden reiterated his commitment to Israel's security, but also described October 7 as a "dark day for the Palestinian people".</p>

<p>The&nbsp;United States has spent $22.76 billion to support Israel's offensive on Gaza and operations against the Houthis in Yemen, according to a report by Brown University's Watson Institute.&nbsp;The $17.9 billion military aid to Israel since the war in Gaza started is the highest annual total ever. It&nbsp;is a mix of military financing, and transfers from US weapons stockpiles, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/10/7/us-spends-more-than-20bn-in-aid-to-israel-middle-east-conflicts-report"><em>Al Jazeera</em></a>.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer called for renewed diplomatic efforts to bring calm to the region. "The region cannot endure another year of this, civilians on all sides have suffered too much. All sides must now step back from the brink and find the courage of restraint," Starmer said.</p>

<p>In Strasbourg, Members of European Parliament observed a minute of silence. "There is nothing that could ever justify the indiscriminate mass murder, rape, kidnapping and torture that occurred a year ago," said European Parliament President Roberta Metsola.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/60trf72o_lebanon-strike_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Smoke rises from the site of an Israeli airstrike that targeted a neighborhood in Beirut]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-tourist-attacks-winnie-the-pooh-mascot-at-disneyland-6741670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Tourist Attacks Winnie The Pooh Mascot At Disneyland]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-tourist-attacks-winnie-the-pooh-mascot-at-disneyland-6741670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 11:50:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the footage, a middle-aged man is seen rushing towards the Disney character, Winnie the Pooh, and slapping the performer, who then collapses to the ground.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Winnie the Pooh, the beloved and endearing creation of A A Milne, has brought joy to generations. However, a recent incident involving the cartoon character at Shanghai Disneyland has led to widespread outrage on social media.<br />
<br />
Last month, a tourist assaulted an actor dressed as Winnie the Pooh during a parade in Disneyland, leaving bystanders stunned. The altercation was captured on video, and it quickly went viral. In the footage, a middle-aged man is seen rushing to the Disney character and slapping the performer, who then collapses to the ground. Bystanders told the South China Morning Post (<a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3280493/outrage-china-tourist-strikes-winnie-pooh-actor-shanghai-disneyland-causing-fall">SCMP</a>) that they heard a “loud thud” as the actor fell, clutching their head and struggling to regain their footing.<br />
<br />
Disneyland staff swiftly intervened, stopping the man and assisting the performer.<br />
<br />
Watch the video here:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">上海ディズニーでプーさんが！???? <a href="https://t.co/7iC246dCp8">pic.twitter.com/7iC246dCp8</a></p>
— 山谷剛史　アジア中国ITライター＆異国飯 (@YamayaT) <a href="https://twitter.com/YamayaT/status/1837996286794232314?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The internet was furious about how the actor was treated.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
A user commented, “It's one thing if it's a child grinning and hitting someone in a costume, but it's adults, or rather old men... They have a low level of civility.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">ニヤニヤしながら着ぐるみの人叩くのが子供ならまだしも大人というかおっさんというか…。民度が低いですね。</p>
— ルシファ－???????????????? (@snow_pubgmobile) <a href="https://twitter.com/snow_pubgmobile/status/1838156522414874816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another said, “This is damn dangerous. The headgear alone weighs 8kg, and it's hard enough just to support it with your neck, but if you add an external shock to it, in the worst case scenario, you could suffer cervical spine damage.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">これクソ危ない。頭の被り物の重さだけで8kgあり、それを首で支えるだけでも大変なのに、そこに外部から衝撃を加えたら最悪の場合頚椎損傷もありうる。</p>
— 板橋ラーメン@保守アカウント (@banqiaoramen) <a href="https://twitter.com/banqiaoramen/status/1838011775306043614?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“The person who hit the head probably doesn't have a brain,” a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">さすが中国。<br />
頭を叩いたほうは脳みそ入ってないんだろうな。</p>
— へびいち☆ (@hebiichi) <a href="https://twitter.com/hebiichi/status/1838142194047230290?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“Are you okay?” someone asked.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">大丈夫ですか????<br />
消されないでしょうか????</p>
— うどん (@udon_invest) <a href="https://twitter.com/udon_invest/status/1838181909018689804?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The theme park released a statement confirming the performer was physically unharmed, reported SCMP. They also mentioned that the tourist was “dealt with”, although specific details of any penalties were not disclosed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1jvh3io_winnie-the-pooh_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-us-men-receive-prison-sentence-for-2-5-million-apple-iphone-scam-6741339]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Men Tricked Apple Into Sending iPhones Worth $2.5 Million. Here's How]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/two-us-men-receive-prison-sentence-for-2-5-million-apple-iphone-scam-6741339]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:56:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two men were sentenced this week for orchestrating a sophisticated scheme, tricking Apple into shipping thousands of iPhones and defrauding the tech giant of $2.5 million.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two men were sentenced this week for orchestrating a sophisticated scheme, tricking Apple into shipping thousands of iPhones and defrauding the tech giant of $2.5 million. Haotian Sun, 33, a Chinese national living in Baltimore, received a 57-month prison sentence, reported the <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-dc/pr/two-maryland-residents-found-guilty-multimillion-dollar-scheme-defraud-apple-inc-out ">US Justice Department</a>. His accomplice Pengfei Xue, also 33, who lived in Germantown, Maryland, was sentenced to 54 months.<br />
<br />
Both men were ordered to pay restitution to Apple, with Sun responsible for over $1 million and Xue required to repay $397,800. The scheme, which ran between 2017 and 2019, involved shipping approximately 6,000 counterfeit iPhones to Apple, falsely claiming they needed repairs. The Justice Department described their operation as “sophisticated,” relying on fake serial numbers and bogus warranty claims.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
According to the affidavit from postal inspector Stephen Cohen, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-sentenced-to-jail-for-trafficking-fake-iphones-ipads-that-cost-apple-6-million-5326846">fraudulent activities </a>came to light after an Apple employee tipped off law enforcement. Investigators managed to intercept packages and confirm that counterfeit phones were being sent from China to various Apple retail locations and licensed service providers.<br />
<br />
Apple's standard one-year warranty for iPhones created a loophole for the scam. Sun and Xue shipped devices that either were out of warranty or contained counterfeit parts, leading Apple to mistakenly accept these fraudulent returns. Cohen said that Apple “wrongly” processed dozens of these bogus phones in single shipments.<br />
<br />
To cover their tracks, the two men used multiple aliases and opened various mailboxes to conceal their identification. Federal agents carefully documented the serial numbers of intercepted packages, allowing the shipments to reach their intended recipients before making arrests. The investigation involved surveillance, with police examining trash outside men's homes and tracking them when they returned intercepted packages to Apple Stores.<br />
<br />
Haotian Sun submitted over 1,000 repair requests using several email accounts, some linked to his real identity.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/i74e42q8_iphone-16-reuters_625x300_20_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple's standard one-year warranty for iPhones created a loophole for the scam. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youtuber-jack-doherty-crashes-his-200-000-maclaren-while-driving-on-livestream-6741163]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[YouTuber Crashes His $200,000 MacLaren While Driving On Livestream]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/youtuber-jack-doherty-crashes-his-200-000-maclaren-while-driving-on-livestream-6741163]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:28:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mr Doherty, 20, who has nearly 15 million subscribers, is known for his controversial prank videos and displays of wealth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>YouTuber Jack Doherty crashed his $200,000 McLaren sports car during a livestream this weekend after seemingly looking at his phone while driving in the rain. Mr Doherty, 20, who has nearly 15 million subscribers, is known for his controversial prank videos and displays of wealth. He was streaming the incident on Kick, where his channel was later banned following the crash.</p>

<p>A clip circulating online appeared to show Mr Doherty speeding on a wet highway while glancing at his phone before shouting, "No, no, no!" as he lost control of the car and crashed into a guardrail.</p>

<p>Mr Doherty also shared videos of the aftermath, including one of him calling for help from inside the vehicle. In the clip, he asked a bystander to hold the camera as others pulled him out of the window.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Jack Doherty just crashed his brand new McLaren on stream ? <a href="https://t.co/WNnKGbmHbD">https://t.co/WNnKGbmHbD</a></p>
— FearBuck (@FearedBuck) <a href="https://twitter.com/FearedBuck/status/1842601300070224243?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Viewers criticized Mr Doherty for seemingly showing more concern for his wrecked McLaren than for his injured cameraman, who remained in the passenger seat clutching his arm and bleeding from the head.</p>

<p>A user wrote, "Your friend's face is gushing blood but you make sure he stays filming from all angles.... nice."</p>

<p>Another user wrote, "I don't know who this idiot is but if you're whining about your car on video for likes while a person in the car is hurt and bleeding you're a garbage person."</p>

<p>"You were looking at your phone while driving, reading your chat. Let's be honest, you weren't concerned about your friend at all. You just kept crying about the car and when your friend asked where he was bleeding from, you repeatedly ignored him and made him keep filming you," the third user wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Crashed my McLaren… glad we're both ok?❤️ <a href="https://t.co/Rn3u961Rqp">pic.twitter.com/Rn3u961Rqp</a></p>
— Jack Doherty (@dohertyjackk) <a href="https://twitter.com/dohertyjackk/status/1842653680870506735?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Mr Doherty later posted a video from a hospital room, where his cameraman was getting stitches. Some noted he didn't re-upload the full footage showing his actions leading up to the crash.</p>

<p>A separate clip showed Mr Doherty lamenting his damaged car while handing the camera to his injured cameraman, asking him to continue filming.</p>

<p>This isn't Mr Doherty's first on-camera crash. In March, he flipped his new Can-Am off-road vehicle shortly after getting it, and in November, he crashed a golf cart with his girlfriend inside, flipping it toward her, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nbcnews.com/pop-culture/pop-culture-news/influencer-jack-doherty-crashes-200k-mclaren-driving-livestream-rcna174183" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Doherty had purchased the now-totaled McLaren for over $200,000 last year, just weeks after buying a Lamborghini and a Tesla. In a video posted at the time, he joked that he would "crash this car, mark my words."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6vrjm578_youtuber-jack-doherty_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Doherty speeding on a wet highway while glancing at his phone]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-science-behind-a-good-nights-sleep-sleep-wake-cycles-explained-6741021]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[The Science Behind A Good Night's Sleep: Sleep-Wake Cycles Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-science-behind-a-good-nights-sleep-sleep-wake-cycles-explained-6741021]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 10:10:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What do you imagine a good night's sleep to be?

Often when people come into our sleep clinic seeking treatment, they share ideas about healthy sleep.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="theconversation-article-title">What do you imagine a good night's sleep to be?</p>

<div class="theconversation-article-body">
<p>Often when people come into our sleep clinic seeking treatment, they share ideas about healthy sleep.</p>

<p>Many think when their head hits the pillow, they should fall into a deep and restorative sleep, and emerge after about eight hours feeling refreshed. They're in good company – many Australians hold <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2014.09.011">the same belief</a>.</p>

<p>In reality, healthy sleep is cyclic across the night, as you move in and out of the different stages of sleep, often waking up several times. Some people remember one or more of these awakenings, others do not. Let's consider what a healthy night's sleep looks like.</p>

<p>Adults usually move through five or six sleep cycles in a night, and it is entirely <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2014.09.011">normal</a> to wake up briefly at the end of each one. That means we might be waking up five times during the night. This can increase with older age and still be healthy. If you're not remembering these awakenings that's OK – they can be quite brief.</p>

<h3><strong>What does getting a ‘good' sleep actually mean?</strong></h3>

<p>You'll often hear that adults <a href="https://www.sleephealthfoundation.org.au/sleep-topics/how-much-sleep-do-you-really-need#:%7E:text=Sleep%20requirements%20stabilise%20in%20early,their%20best%20the%20next%20day">need between seven and nine hours</a> of sleep per night. But good sleep is about more than the number of hours – it's also about the quality.</p>

<p>For most people, sleeping well means being able to fall asleep soon after getting into bed (within around 30 minutes), sleeping without waking up for long periods, and waking feeling rested and ready for the day.</p>

<p>You shouldn't be feeling excessively sleepy during the day, especially if you're regularly getting at least seven hours of refreshing sleep a night (this is a rough rule of thumb).</p>

<p>But are you noticing you're feeling physically tired, needing to nap regularly and still not feeling refreshed? It may be worthwhile touching base with your general practitioner, as there a range of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/screen-time-in-bed-is-worse-than-screen-time-before-bed-study-6488051">possible reasons</a>.</p>

<h3><strong>Common issues</strong></h3>

<p>Sleep disorders are common. Up to <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35478719/">25% of adults</a> have insomnia, a sleep disorder where it may be hard to fall or stay asleep, or you may wake earlier in the morning than you'd like.</p>

<p>Rates of common sleep disorders such as insomnia and <a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/sleep-apnea/symptoms-causes/syc-20377631">sleep apnoea</a> – where your breathing can partially or completely stop many times during the night – also increase with age, affecting <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32280974/">20% of early adults</a> and 40% of people in <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35082023/">middle age</a>. There are effective treatments, so asking for help is important.</p>

<p>Beyond sleep disorders, our sleep can also be disrupted by chronic health conditions – such as <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0012369218311139">pain</a> – and by <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jsr.13075">certain medications</a>.</p>

<p>There can also be other reasons we're not sleeping well. Some of us are woken by children, pets or traffic noise during the night. These “<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07420528.2021.2003375">forced awakenings</a>” mean we may find it harder to get up in the morning, take longer to leave bed and feel less satisfied with our sleep. For some people, night awakenings may have no clear cause.</p>

<p>A good way to tell if these awakenings are a problem for you is by thinking about how they affect you. When they cause feelings of frustration or worry, or are impacting how we feel and function during the day, it might be a sign to seek some help.</p>

<p>We also may struggle to get up in the morning. This could be for a range of reasons, including not sleeping long enough, going to bed or waking up at irregular times – or even your own <a href="https://www.sleephealthfoundation.org.au/sleep-categories/circadian-rhythm-disorders#:%7E:text=The%20circadian%20rhythms%20throughout%20the,regulation%20of%20our%20sleeping%20patterns">internal clock</a>, which can influence the time your body prefers to sleep.</p>

<p>If you're regularly struggling to get up for work or family needs, it can be an indication you may need to seek help. Some of these factors can be explored with a sleep psychologist if they are causing concern.</p>

<h3><strong>Can my smart watch help?</strong></h3>

<p>It is important to remember that sleep-tracking devices can <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41746-024-01016-9">vary in accuracy</a> for looking at the different sleep stages. While they can give a rough estimate, they are not a perfect measure.</p>

<p>In-laboratory <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31277862/">polysomnography</a>, or PSG, is the best standard measure to examine your sleep stages. A PSG examines breathing, oxygen saturation, brain waves and heart rate during sleep.</p>

<p>Rather than closely examining nightly data (including sleep stages) from a sleep tracker, it may be more helpful to look at the patterns of your sleep (bed and wake times) over time.</p>

<p><a href="https://jcsm.aasm.org/doi/10.5664/jcsm.8356">Understanding your sleep patterns</a> may help identify and adjust behaviours that negatively impact your sleep, such as your bedtime routine and sleeping environment.</p>

<p>And if you find viewing your sleep data is making you feel worried about your sleep, this may not be useful for you. Most importantly, if you are concerned it is important to discuss it with your GP who can refer you to the appropriate specialist sleep health provider.<!-- Below is The Conversation's page counter tag. Please DO NOT REMOVE. --><img alt="The Conversation" height="1" referrerpolicy="no-referrer-when-downgrade" src="https://counter.theconversation.com/content/238069/count.gif?distributor=republish-lightbox-basic" style="border: none !important; box-shadow: none !important; margin: 0 !important; max-height: 1px !important; max-width: 1px !important; min-height: 1px !important; min-width: 1px !important; opacity: 0 !important; outline: none !important; padding: 0 !important" width="1" /><!-- End of code. If you don't see any code above, please get new code from the Advanced tab after you click the republish button. The page counter does not collect any personal data. More info: https://theconversation.com/republishing-guidelines --></p>

<p><em><span><a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/amy-reynolds-424346">Amy Reynolds</a>, Associate Professor in Clinical Sleep Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/claire-dunbar-1651340">Claire Dunbar</a>, Research Associate, Sleep Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/gorica-micic-187159">Gorica Micic</a>, Postdoctoral Research Fellow, Clinical Psychologist, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a>; <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/hannah-scott-424633">Hannah Scott</a>, Research Fellow in Sleep Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a>, and <a href="https://theconversation.com/profiles/nicole-lovato-60684">Nicole Lovato</a>, Associate Professor, Adelaide Institute for Sleep Health, <a href="https://theconversation.com/institutions/flinders-university-972">Flinders University</a></span></em></p>

<p><em>This article is republished from <a href="https://theconversation.com">The Conversation</a> under a Creative Commons license. Read the <a href="https://theconversation.com/an-unbroken-nights-sleep-is-a-myth-heres-what-good-sleep-looks-like-238069">original article</a>.</em></p>
</div><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ui52aejg_sleepmaxxing_625x300_24_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Healthy sleep is cyclic across the night, as you move in and out of different stages. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-5-hurricane-milton-approaches-florida-2nd-major-storm-in-weeks-6740696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Category 5 Hurricane Milton Approaches Florida, 2nd Major Storm In Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/category-5-hurricane-milton-approaches-florida-2nd-major-storm-in-weeks-6740696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 09:03:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hurricane Milton exploded in strength Monday to become a potentially catastrophic Category 5 storm bound for Florida, threatening the US state with a second ferocious hurricane in as many weeks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hurricane Milton exploded in strength Monday to become a potentially catastrophic Category 5 storm bound for Florida, threatening the US state with a second ferocious hurricane in as many weeks.</p>

<p>The back-to-back hurricanes have whipped up a US election storm, with Vice President Kamala Harris slamming her White House rival Donald Trump and Florida's Republican governor Ron DeSantis for "political gamesmanship" and for spreading misinformation about the federal response.</p>

<p>Milton, which is forecast to batter Mexico's Yucatan peninsula as it churns eastward, rapidly intensified to the highest category on a scale of five, triggering evacuation orders and warnings of savage conditions on Florida's west coast.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/33-dead-in-us-from-hurricane-helene-officials-6666374">National Hurricane Center (NHC)</a> said the storm's maximum sustained winds were near 180 miles (285 kilometres) per hour, and that air pressure at the centre of the storm was at a "near record low."</p>

<p>Communities hit by Hurricane <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hurricane-helene-rips-through-florida-town-people-left-to-start-from-scratch-6681187">Helene</a>, which slammed Florida late last month, raced to remove debris that could become dangerous projectiles as Milton barrels in.</p>

<p>"Last time, people's cars were underwater... but the bigger issue this time is going to be the wind," said David Levitsky, a retired homeowner on Treasure Island, in Pinellas County.</p>

<p>Residents on the low-lying island have been piling up debris from Helene's flooding in their front yards for removal.</p>

<p>"All this stuff is just wind fodder that's going to just be blowing down the street and hitting who knows what," the 69-year-old told AFP.</p>

<p>Amid the wreckage, DeSantis, a conservative known to clash with the federal government, found himself under fire after broadcaster NBC reported he was ignoring phone calls from Harris on the Helene recovery.</p>

<p>DeSantis did speak to President Joe Biden about the preparations, the White House said late Monday.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Harris slammed the Republican governor for "playing political games."</p>

<p>"It is about political gamesmanship, instead of doing the job you took an oath to do, which is to put the people first," she told reporters, while also criticizing Trump as "extraordinarily irresponsible."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The former president has tapped into real frustration about the federal response after Helene and fueled it with disinformation, falsely claiming federal disaster money had been misappropriated and spent instead on migrants.</p>

<h3><strong>Worst hit in 100 years&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>As Milton barreled toward Florida, state authorities have issued mandatory evacuation orders for areas including some parts of Tampa, a metropolitan area of more than three million people that could take a direct hit.</p>

<p>"If the storm stays on the current track, it will be the worst storm to impact the Tampa area in over 100 years," the National Weather Service said.</p>

<p>A major storm surge for Florida's west coast is forecast for Tuesday night or early Wednesday, and Tampa could suffer an influx of water between eight and 12 feet (2.4 to 3.6 meters) above ground level.</p>

<p>Rainfall of 10 inches (25 centimetres), with localized spots of up to 15 inches, is expected to cause severe flash flooding.</p>

<p>In the central city of Orlando, under grey skies, hundreds of cars lined up to collect sandbags.</p>

<p>"We might<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-helene-florida-orders-evacuations-as-hurricane-milton-strengthens-6736892"> evacuate</a>, me and my pets, we might go to Georgia," Tony Carlson, 32, told AFP. "People think it's going to be pretty bad."</p>

<p>Maria Torres, 29, said her family was not planning to leave but had prepared with a generator, food and water.</p>

<p>In Mexico's Yucatan, workers boarded up glass doors and windows, fishermen hauled boats ashore and schools were suspended.</p>

<p>In the southeastern United States, emergency workers are still struggling to provide relief in the aftermath of Helene, which killed at least 230 people across several states.</p>

<p>Helene hit the Florida coastline on September 26 as a Category 4 hurricane, dumping rain and causing massive flooding in remote inland towns in states further north, including North Carolina and Tennessee.</p>

<p>Deanne Criswell, head of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), also dismissed the claims about money being diverted to migrants as false and slammed the misinformation as "dangerous."</p>

<p>She warned Monday that "these storms are bringing more water than they ever have and so while we have the wind risk, the water is what's killing people."</p>

<p>Researchers say climate change likely plays a role in the rapid intensification of hurricanes because there is more energy in warmer oceans for them to feed on.</p>

<p>Helene was the deadliest natural disaster to hit the US mainland since 2005's Hurricane Katrina, with the death toll still rising.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pujnvd9o_hurricane-milton-afp-_625x300_08_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As Milton barreled toward Florida, state authorities have issued mandatory evacuation orders for areas.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/qantas-flight-plays-adult-film-due-to-technical-error-apologises-later-6740543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Qantas Flight Plays Adult Film Due To Technical Error, Apologises Later]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/qantas-flight-plays-adult-film-due-to-technical-error-apologises-later-6740543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:30:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Passengers aboard a flight to Tokyo last week got more inflight entertainment than they bargained for last week when an explicit film featuring sex talk and explicit images was broadcast to every screen.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Passengers aboard a flight to Tokyo last week got more inflight entertainment than they bargained for last week when an explicit film featuring sex talk and explicit images was broadcast to every screen.</p>

<p>Technical problems meant individual movie selection was not available on a Qantas flight from Sydney to Haneda, leaving the crew to pick one film to be broadcast to the whole cabin.</p>

<p>Their selection of Dakota Johnson and Sean Penn's racy drama "Daddio" was a surprise to many, and to the airline, which apologised Tuesday.</p>

<p>According to one review, the movie features "references to oral sex, masturbation" as well as a "brief but clear photo of erect penis on phone screen. Photos of a woman's naked breasts. Explicit sex-related dialogue and texting".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The movie was clearly not suitable to play for the whole flight and we sincerely apologise to customers for this experience," a Qantas spokesperson said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Once the mistake was clear, "all screens were changed to a family-friendly movie for the rest of the flight," Qantas added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"We are reviewing how the movie was selected."&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sggmgs1g_qantas_625x300_07_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The selection of Dakota Johnson and Sean Penn's "Daddio" was a surprise to many passengers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>