<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 04:04:40 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-urges-evacuation-of-southern-beirut-ahead-of-attack-on-hezbollah-targets-6696402]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Urges Evacuation Of New Areas Ahead Of Attack On Hezbollah Targets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-urges-evacuation-of-southern-beirut-ahead-of-attack-on-hezbollah-targets-6696402]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 04:04:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military on Tuesday issued a new call for residents in southern Beirut to evacuate ahead of a likely strike on alleged Hezbollah targets in the Lebanese armed group's bastion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military on Tuesday issued a new call for residents in southern Beirut to evacuate ahead of a likely strike on alleged Hezbollah targets in the Lebanese armed group's bastion.</p>

<p>"You are located near dangerous Hezbollah facilities, which the IDF (Israeli military) will act against with force in the near future," military spokesman Avichay Adraee said on X, specifically mentioning the area of Haret Hreik in south Beirut.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/aisdake_lebanon-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The Israeli military is planning to attack alleged Hezbollah facilities in southern Beirut."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-iran-destabilising-dangerous-force-in-middle-east-6696316]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Calls Iran "Destabilising, Dangerous" Force In Middle East]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-calls-iran-destabilising-dangerous-force-in-middle-east-6696316]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 03:34:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential candidate, said on Tuesday that Iran was a "dangerous" and "destabilizing" force in the Middle East and Washington was committed to Israel's security.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic presidential candidate, said on Tuesday that Iran was a "dangerous" and "destabilizing" force in the Middle East and Washington was committed to Israel's security.</p>

<p><strong>WHY IT'S IMPORTANT</strong></p>

<p>The comments from Harris, who faces Republican former President Donald Trump in the Nov. 5 U.S. election, came hours after Iran fired ballistic missiles at Israel in retaliation for Israel's military campaign in Lebanon, drawing vows of a sharp response from Israel and the U.S.</p>

<p>No injuries were reported in Israel and Washington called Iran's attack ineffective.</p>

<p><strong>KEY QUOTES</strong></p>

<p>"I'm clear-eyed Iran is a destabilizing, dangerous force in the Middle East," Harris said. "I will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself against Iran and Iran-backed terrorist militias."</p>

<p>"I fully support President (Joe) Biden's order for the U.S. military to shoot down Iranian missiles targeting Israel," Harris said. "Initial indications are that Israel, with our assistance, was able to defeat this attack."</p>

<p>Harris added that Washington will work with its allies to disrupt what she called Iran's "aggressive behavior."</p>

<p><strong>CONTEXT</strong></p>

<p>Israel has escalated its military campaign in Lebanon in recent days, killing hundreds and displacing more than a million due to operations that Israel says are targeting Lebanese Iran-backed Hezbollah militants.</p>

<p>Israel's military campaign in Lebanon is in addition to its war in Gaza that followed a deadly Oct. 7 attack on Israel by Palestinian Hamas militants. Israeli's military assault on Gaza has killed tens of thousands according to Palestinian health authorities, displaced nearly everyone there, caused a hunger crisis and prompted genocide allegations that Israel denies.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/pq4qlj0o_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_18_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris promised her "unwavering" commitment to the security of Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-iran-made-a-big-mistake-and-will-pay-for-it-6696140]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Netanyahu Says "Iran Made A Big Mistake And Will Pay For It"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-says-iran-made-a-big-mistake-and-will-pay-for-it-6696140]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 02:31:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Iran's missile attack on Israel failed and vowed retaliation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said Iran's missile attack on Israel failed and vowed retaliation.</p>

<p>"Iran made a big mistake tonight - and it will pay for it," he said at the outset of a political-security meeting. "The regime in Iran does not understand our determination to defend ourselves and our determination to retaliate against our enemies."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p5hltaio_benjamin-netanyahu-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli PM Benjamin Netanyahu said Iran's missile attack on Israel failed and vowed retaliation.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-will-irans-missile-attack-lead-to-a-full-scale-war-israeli-spokesperson-guy-nir-gives-a-hint-6696110]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Will Iran's Attack Lead To Full-Scale War? Israeli Spokesman Gives A Hint]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-exclusive-will-irans-missile-attack-lead-to-a-full-scale-war-israeli-spokesperson-guy-nir-gives-a-hint-6696110]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 02:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel Defense Forces or IDF is currently assessing the missile attack by Iran today and an appropriate response will be given to Tehran, said Guy Nir, spokesperson of the Israeli embassy in India, speaking exclusively to NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel Defense Forces or IDF is currently assessing the missile attack by Iran today and an appropriate response will be given to Tehran, said Guy Nir, spokesperson of the Israeli embassy in India, speaking exclusively to NDTV.</p>

<p>Iran today fired a barrage of missiles at Israel - nearly 200 of them - in its attempt to send a message to Tel Aviv in the aftermath of the killings of the Hamas and Hezbollah chiefs. While Israel was able to block out most of the missiles, there were some that hit regions across the north and south of the country.</p>

<p>This has been the sharpest escalation in tensions in West Asia (Middle East) since the start of the Israel Hamas war in Gaza nearly a year ago. Iran's Supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who is currently sheltered in a safe house at an undisclosed location, was the one who reportedly gave the green signal for the missile attack on Israel today.</p>

<p>Speaking to NDTV, The Israel Embassy spokesperson warned that "If he (Ayatollah Ali Khamenei) plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them (Iran)." He went on to say that Israel's response to Tuesday's attack will be a strategic, pin-pointed one. "Israel's response is going to be something strategic and pin-pointed, and not a full-scale war. I don't think any side wants that," he said.</p>

<p>The Israeli spokesperson also cautioned any other nation which might consider joining Iran to attack Israel. "If any country is wanting to join Iran, all I can hope is that they don't, because if they do, the outcome will be devastating for them too," he warned.</p>

<p>Speaking about Israel's top-notch defence mechanism, the Israeli spokesperson said that it is not just renowned 'Iron Dome', but other systems too, but did not give more details on what they are. "It is not just the Iron Dome, we have many other defence systems in place that I cannot elaborate on for security reasons, which were helping us to bring this situation under control. The systems are very precise and out of over 180 missiles, most of them were not able to penetrate through these," he said.</p>

<p>The spokesperson further confirmed that at the moment "there are no casualties in Israel, but there is one in Palestinian territories". This he said, was because Iran targeted the entire region. He also explained how every Israeli national is prepared and trained for such scenarios, thereby preventing the loss of lives across the country.</p>

<h2><strong>Here is Israeli Embassy spokesperson Guy Nir's full interview to NDTV:</strong></h2>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NDTVExclusive?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NDTVExclusive</a> | "Iran launched 181 missiles at Israel. Citizens out of bunkers now. Israel will respond to these attacks": Israeli Embassy in India Spokesman (<a href="https://twitter.com/IsraelinIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IsraelinIndia</a>) Guy Nir (<a href="https://twitter.com/GuyNirIL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@GuyNirIL</a>) <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NDTVWorld?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NDTVWorld</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Iran?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Iran</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Israel?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Israel</a> <a href="https://t.co/1krD80lqIr">pic.twitter.com/1krD80lqIr</a></p>
— NDTV (@ndtv) <a href="https://twitter.com/ndtv/status/1841190373533602023?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p><strong>Q) Will it be an all-out war? Or is there a possibility that it will be contained?</strong><br />
A) Right now IDF is saying they are trying to understand, assess and calculate the next steps to take this forward. We have confirmed that 181 missiles have been fired at Israel by Iran. It seems like the attack is complete now and Israeli citizens are out of their bunkers and shelters.</p>

<p><strong>Q) What is the situation in Israel at the moment?</strong><br />
A) Two hours ago, the Israel Defence Force of IDF had asked all citizens to go into shelters and bunkers to prepare for this attack. Around an hour ago we began to see missiles in the air and also falling all across Israel. All together, over 180 missiles were fired on Israel. As of now, the attack is finished and people are out of their shelters.</p>

<p><strong>Q) Video footage shows that these missiles have hit many targets and there might by casualties. Do you have an update on this?</strong><br />
A) So what we are seeing is that missiles have fallen across north and south Israel. These missiles have hit either buildings or in open areas. Up to now, we do not have any Israeli casualties as all Israelis went into their bunkers and safe rooms. However, there is one casualty in Palestinian territories as Iran launched missiles across the region. So currently we have confirmation of this one Palestinian person being killed in the Iran attack.</p>

<p><strong>Q) How efficient has the Iron Dome system been for Israel?</strong><br />
A) It is not just the Iron Dome, we have many other defence systems that I cannot elaborate on for security reasons, which were helping us to bring this situation under control. The systems are very precise and out of over 180 missiles, most of them did not go through.</p>

<p><strong>Q) Do you think Israel will now attack Iran as well and this will turn into an all-out war?</strong><br />
A) So, at the moment I want to be very cautious of what I am going to say. The IDF is currently assessing the situation to see what is going to be the proper way to respond. Will it be an all-out war or will it be something more strategic? Well, I guess Israel's response is going to be something more strategic and pin-pointed and not a full-scale war. I don't think any side wants that.</p>

<p><strong>Q) As per reports, the Supreme leader of Iran, Ayatollah Khameni, is the one who had given the green signal for this missile attack. What is your take on this?</strong><br />
A) I believe that if he plans to initiate a full-scale war with Israel, it will be a mistake for them.</p>

<p><strong>Q) It is believed that many other nations will join Iran in this war. Is Israel prepared for that?</strong><br />
A) Israel is prepared for many scenarios. Israel is not alone. We have a number of our allies who will help us too. As for any country wanting to join Iran, all I can hope is that they don't, because if they do, the outcome will be devastating for them too.</p>

<p><strong>Q) According to you, which countries might join Iran in this offensive against Israel?</strong><br />
A) I hope none.</p>

<p><strong>Q) How is your family in Israel? Hope they are safe after this attack?</strong><br />
A) I have spoken to my family after all this began. All of them are fine. I have a friend who lives very close to one of the areas that was attacked. I called her right away to make sure she was okay. All my family and relatives are fine.</p>

<p><strong>Q) What is the kind of drill that most people in Israel are trained for, for such situations?</strong><br />
A) So, every single person in Israel has a bunker or safe room in their homes - which have a double-sided wall which is unpenetrable for such missile attacks. All Israelis know and are trained that when there are alarms, they must get into their safe rooms within a specific time period given to them - which is usually 60 seconds to 120 seconds, depending on where you live. And we let them know in advance when they need to be close to a safe room as within the next hour or so there might be an alarm. The Israeli people always adhere to this. They are always prepared. They listen to these instructions very carefully. So, even today, when the final call happened, everyone was already close to a safe room, so they could go in fast and close the door.</p>

<p><strong>Q) So, every home or building across Israel has a safe home within it or attached to it?</strong><br />
A) Yes, a majority of the homes in Israel have them. Since 1991 we have a law which requires all buildings, all homes and apartments have a room like this. So, all new buildings and apartments have them. Older buildings usually have safe rooms at the ground level (covered bunkers). So everyone goes down to the ground level and sits there.</p>

<p><strong>Q) After today's attack by Iran, is there any chance of containing this war in the next two or three days, or even the week ahead?</strong><br />
A) I hope so.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-08/tvu49qh8_iran-missile-afp-650_625x300_20_August_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran fired a barrage of missiles at Israel to avenge the killings of Hamas and Hezbollah chiefs.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-bidens-complete-failure-in-middle-east-russia-after-iran-attacks-israel-6696047]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden's "Complete Failure" in Middle East: Russia After Iran Attacks Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-bidens-complete-failure-in-middle-east-russia-after-iran-attacks-israel-6696047]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 02:04:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia on Tuesday said the United States' approach in the Middle East was a "complete failure" after Iran launched a massive missile attack on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia on Tuesday said the United States' approach in the Middle East was a "complete failure" after Iran launched a massive missile attack on Israel.</p>

<p>"Complete failure of the Biden administration in the Middle East," foreign ministry spokeswoman Maria Zakharova said in a post on Telegram.</p>

<p>"A bloody drama that is only gaining momentum. The White House's incomprehensible statements demonstrate its complete helplessness in resolving crises."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kk0gd2t_iran-missile-attack-on-israel_625x300_02_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia slammed US after Iran's missile attacks on Israel on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-masoud-pezeshkian-hails-irans-missile-attacks-against-israel-6695969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Decisive Response Has Been Made": Iran President After Attacks On Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-president-masoud-pezeshkian-hails-irans-missile-attacks-against-israel-6695969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 01:41:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian hailed Tuesday night's missile attack against Israel as a "decisive response" to what he called Israeli "aggression".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian hailed Tuesday night's missile attack against Israel as a "decisive response" to what he called Israeli "aggression".</p>

<p>"In accordance with legitimate rights and with the aim of (establishing) peace and security in Iran and the region, a decisive response has been made to the Zionist regime's aggression," Pezeshkian posted on X.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r7jspoh_masoud-pezeshkian_625x300_16_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iranian President hailed Tuesday night's missile attack against Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-attack-on-israel-was-defeated-and-ineffective-us-6695843]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iranian Attack On Israel Was "Defeated And Ineffective': US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iranian-attack-on-israel-was-defeated-and-ineffective-us-6695843]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 01:03:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's ballistic missile assault on Israel was "defeated and ineffective", the White House said on Tuesday, warning that Tehran could expect severe consequences for the attacks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's ballistic missile assault on Israel was "defeated and ineffective", the White House said on Tuesday, warning that Tehran could expect severe consequences for the attacks.</p>

<p>"Based on what we know at this point, this attack appears to have been defeated and ineffective," Jake Sullivan, US President Joe Biden's national security advisor, told reporters.</p>

<p>Sullivan hailed US efforts to repel some of the attacks, which involved American naval destroyers shooting down some of the missiles.</p>

<p>Iran's attack was however a "significant escalation" of tensions in the Middle East, Sullivan said -- adding that it was an "ongoing situation" that meant he could only answer a few questions before getting back to his desk.</p>

<p>"Obviously, this is a significant escalation by Iran, a significant event, and it is equally significant that we were able to step up with Israel," Sullivan told the briefing.</p>

<p>The White House official would not say what consequences Tehran could expect to face, saying it would discuss "next steps" with Israel.</p>

<p>"We have made clear that there will be consequences, severe consequences, for this attack, and we will work with Israel to make that the case," Sullivan said.</p>

<p>US Secretary of State Antony Blinken said separately that Iran's missile attack was "unacceptable" and that the entire world should condemn it.</p>

<p>"Initial reports suggest that Israel, with the active support of the United States and other partners, effectively defeated this attack," Blinken told reporters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/e9qjrljg_iran-attacks-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US said that there will be severe consequences after Iran's attacks on Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-fired-around-180-missiles-at-israel-says-israeli-military-6695737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Fired Around 180 Missiles At Israel, Says Israeli Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-fired-around-180-missiles-at-israel-says-israeli-military-6695737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:31:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military said Iran fired roughly 180 missiles at the country on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military said Iran fired roughly 180 missiles at the country on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"IDF (Israeli army) systems have identified approximately 180 missiles fired towards Israeli territory from Iran," the military said. A security official also confirmed the figure to AFP.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/m0vbup5c_iran-attacks-israel_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel vowed to retaliate after Iran fired hundreds of missiles on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-says-us-bases-would-be-targets-if-it-joins-any-response-against-iran-amid-war-against-israel-6695617]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Will Target US Bases If...': Iraq Armed Group After Iran Attacks Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iraq-says-us-bases-would-be-targets-if-it-joins-any-response-against-iran-amid-war-against-israel-6695617]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:07:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. bases in Iraq and the region will be targets if the United States joins any response to Iranian strikes on Israel or if Israel uses Iraqi airspace against Tehran, Iranian-backed Iraqi armed groups said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>U.S. bases in Iraq and the region will be targets if the United States joins any response to Iranian strikes on Israel or if Israel uses Iraqi airspace against Tehran, Iranian-backed Iraqi armed groups said on Tuesday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-09/us-army-reuters_650x400_81504721306.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Iraqi military has warned the US that it will be a target if there is any response against Iran.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jimmy-carter-100th-birthday-jimmy-carter-turns-100-1st-ever-us-president-to-reach-century-mark-6695558]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Jimmy Carter Turns 100 - 1st Ever US President To Reach Century Mark]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jimmy-carter-100th-birthday-jimmy-carter-turns-100-1st-ever-us-president-to-reach-century-mark-6695558]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 23:52:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jimmy Carter celebrated his 100th birthday on Tuesday - the first ever US president to reach the century mark and another extraordinary milestone for the one-time peanut farmer who found his way to the White House.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jimmy Carter celebrated his 100th birthday today - the first ever US president to reach the century mark and another extraordinary milestone for the one-time peanut farmer who found his way to the White House.</p>

<p>Carter's longevity - he began hospice care at his home in Plains, Georgia, more than 19 months ago - has defied all expectations.</p>

<p>No longer regularly appearing in public, the Democratic ex-president is spending his birthday in the home he and his late wife Rosalynn had built in Plains in the 1960s. Celebrations include a lunch with some 20 members of his extended family, according to the Atlanta Journal-Constitution.</p>

<p>President Joe Biden, in a video posted on his official X account, hailed Carter as a "beloved friend" and "one of the most influential statesmen" in US history.</p>

<p>"Your unwavering belief in the power of human goodness continues to be a guiding light for all of us," he said.</p>

<p>The White House lawn was decorated Tuesday with a sign that read "Happy Birthday President Carter."</p>

<p>Britain's King Charles III sent a private message of congratulations expressing "great admiration for the president's lifetime of duty and public service," a Buckingham Palace spokesperson said.</p>

<p>And Georgia Governor Brian Kemp, currently overseeing the response to a major storm disaster, proclaimed "Jimmy Carter Day" across the state.</p>

<h3><strong>LITTLE TOWN</strong></h3>

<p>Beyond serving as commander in chief for a single term from 1977 to 1981, Carter worked as a global mediator, rights activist and elder statesman, founding the well-respected Carter Center in 1982 to pursue his vision of world diplomacy.</p>

<p>His presidency included the 1978 Camp David Accords between Israel and Egypt, the establishment of diplomatic relations with China following a rapprochement initiated by president Richard Nixon, and the return of control of the Panama Canal to Panama.</p>

<p>But his administration hit numerous snags, including the Iran hostage crisis and a renewed oil crisis in 1979-1980, which saw Ronald Reagan sweep into power in a landslide.</p>

<p>"We are thrilled that the president from this little town is going to be the only president to ever live to be 100 years old," Jill Stuckey, superintendent of the National Park Service's Jimmy Carter historical site and longtime family friend, told AFP.</p>

<p>She spoke from Plains High School, where Carter graduated in 1941 and which now serves as the visitor center for the national park that features sites from his early life, including the nearby peanut farm where he grew up.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, the school held a naturalization ceremony for 100 new US citizens, who placed hands over their hearts and recited the pledge of allegiance.</p>

<p>"He did so much for America," said Adriana Vickers, 46, originally from Brazil.</p>

<p>"He's for all nations," Carlene Ford, another newly naturalized citizen, from Jamaica, told AFP. "He's for everybody, he's for the people."</p>

<p>A flyover of four F-18 jets and two vintage planes graced the skies over Plains as part of the town's celebrations.</p>

<h3><strong>'ALWAYS' POLITICAL</strong></h3>

<p>A devout Baptist and self-described "born-again" Christian, Carter is remembered for a moralistic streak, but also his civility, admired even by detractors across the aisle.</p>

<p>According to family, Carter remains keenly interested in politics and was highly motivated to make it to 100 and to vote in the November election for fellow Democrat Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>"He will be voting by mail-in ballot," Stuckey told AFP, adding "he's always been very politically active, and nothing has changed with that respect."</p>

<p>At the naturalization ceremony, attended by the mayor, those in attendance were encouraged to register to vote.</p>

<p>In Plains, like in many rural places with strong evangelical Christian leanings, far more yard signs support Republican Donald Trump than Harris.</p>

<p>But it is also not uncommon to see a sign celebrating Carter's centennial birthday next to one supporting Trump.</p>

<p>Carl Lowell, who has lived in Plains since infancy, said he tries not to get involved in politics because it is "so divisive" right now.</p>

<p>Like most residents of Plains, the 59-year-old retired firefighter is linked to Carter in various ways -- he says his grandfather helped build the Carters' house and that he himself even went dove hunting with him once.</p>

<p>"Jimmy's a good man, he's a godly man, and that's what people like about him," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-11/hd7irc7c_jimmy-carter-reuters_625x300_12_November_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Jimmy Carter celebrated his 100th birthday today - first ever US president to reach the century mark]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-orders-us-military-to-shoot-down-iranian-missiles-targeting-israel-6695308]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Orders US Military To Shoot Down Iranian Missiles Targeting Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-orders-us-military-to-shoot-down-iranian-missiles-targeting-israel-6695308]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 23:03:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Joe Biden has ordered the US military to "aid Israel's defence" and shoot down any and all Iranian missiles targeting Israel, the White House said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Joe Biden has ordered the US military to "aid Israel's defense" and shoot down any and all Iranian missiles targeting Israel, the White House said.</p>

<p>President Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris, the Democratic nominee in next month's US presidential election, are both monitoring Iran's attack on Israel from the White House situation room, it said.</p>

<p>"President Biden directed the US military to aid Israel's defense against Iranian attacks and shoot down missiles that are targeting Israel," the White House said in a statement.</p>

<p>A call that Joe Biden had scheduled with rabbis today ahead of the Jewish high holiday season - which begins later this week with Rosh Hashanah, the Jewish new year - had been postponed to another day, a White House official said.</p>

<p>The United States and other western allies also stepped in to help defend Israel against a combined Iranian missile and drone attack in April, which Tehran launched in retaliation for an Israeli strike on the Iranian consulate in Damascus.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/vj7m4c84_joe-biden-afp-joe-biden-white-house-afp_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[President Joe Biden has ordered the US military to "aid Israel's defence" as Iran fires rockets.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israels-air-defence-system-in-action-to-intercept-iranian-missiles-6695307]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Israel's Air Defence System In Action To Intercept Iranian Missiles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-israels-air-defence-system-in-action-to-intercept-iranian-missiles-6695307]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 23:02:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has attacked Israel with missiles and rockets today after tensions escalated in West Asia following artillery and air strikes on Lebanon to target Hezbollah, a Shia militant outfit and a strong ally of Iran.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran has attacked Israel with missiles and rockets today after tensions escalated in West Asia following artillery and air strikes on Lebanon to target Hezbollah, a Shia militant outfit and a strong ally of Iran.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said today's attack is in response to the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah last week as well as that of the Hamas leader.</p>

<p>Israel's formidable air defence systems were in action to intercept rockets and missiles launched from Iran. Videos show the night sky lighting up with explosions after air raid sirens echoed across the country. The missiles were detected over the Jordanian air space, the flight path followed by the missiles when fired toward Israel. Jordan has announced a suspension of air traffic after the attack on Israel.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-iran-on-israel-civilians-hiding-in-bomb-shelters-says-israel-defence-forces-6694961">missiles were raining down</a> on Israel and the Iron Dome and Arrow air defence system were in action to intercept and neutralise the targets. Iran fired over 100 missiles, Israeli media reported and several videos showed intercepted missile debris falling over Israeli cities.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?? ???? ???'? ? ??????? ??????? ?????.<br />
<br />
This is Israel right now.<br />
<br />
RT this so the entire world knows. <a href="https://t.co/ok8CxCXxnP">pic.twitter.com/ok8CxCXxnP</a></p>
— Israel ישראל (@Israel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel/status/1841166147112354264?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Meanwhile, President Joe Biden has ordered the US military to "aid Israel's defence" and shoot down Iranian missiles targeting Israel. Both Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris are monitoring Iran's attack on Israel from the White House situation room, it said in a statement.</p>

<p>This is the second Iranian attack on Israel in less than six months. In April, Iran launched a swarm of explosive drones and fired missiles at Israel. The Iranian salvo amounted to more than 200 drones and missiles. Iran has vowed retaliation for what it called an Israeli strike on its Damascus consulate on April 1 that killed seven Guards officers including two senior commanders.</p>

<h3><strong>Israel's Multi-Tier Air Defence System</strong></h3>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-iran-war-explained-how-israel-countered-irans-aerial-attack-with-arrow-missiles-5437654">The Arrow Defence System</a> is a surface-to-surface missile system forming an upper tier in Israel's multi-layered air defence system.</p>

<p>Iron Dome has shot down thousands of rockets since 2011 but is limited to a short range. Israel also has a medium-to-long-range interceptor known as David's Sling.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-hamas-gaza-iron-dome-how-israel-defends-its-skies-from-rocket-attacks-4460636">Iron Dome</a>, David's Sling, and the Arrow Defence System create a layered defence system. The Iron Dome system, which has been battle-tested in the past, was actively deployed to intercept drones and short-range threats.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/parsp3u8_israel-defence-system_625x300_14_April_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The radar of Arrow 2 - used against long-range ballistic missiles - has an effective range of 2,400 kilometres and can strike altitudes of 100 kilometres.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The radar constantly detects incoming threats towards the territory. Once a target is detected, real-time information is relayed to the control centre regarding the estimated trajectory of the target, its speed, and if the missile is heading toward a strategic target like cities or military establishments, the missile is launched.</p>

<p>The Arrow 3 Air Defence System neutralize targets in the exo-atmosphere before the ballistic missile enters the re-entry stage. In April, when Iran launched an unprecedented attack on Israel with ballistic and cruise missiles, the Arrow 3 system intercepted the missiles before the re-entry stage in the atmosphere.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The United States has funded roughly half of the annual development costs of the Arrow 2 system. By 2020, the total U.S. financial contribution toward the Arrow Weapon System exceeded $3.7 billion.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/6cb3f9qo_iran-attack-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's formidable air defence systems were in action to intercept rockets and missiles.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-guards-say-attack-on-israel-response-to-killing-of-hezbollah-chief-hamas-leader-6695237]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Guards Threaten "Crushing Attacks" If Israel Responds To Missiles]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-guards-say-attack-on-israel-response-to-killing-of-hezbollah-chief-hamas-leader-6695237]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 22:53:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's Revolutionary Guards threatened to carry out "crushing attacks" against regional foe Israel if it retaliated for a missile attack under way on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards threatened to carry out "crushing attacks" against regional foe Israel if it retaliated for a missile attack under way on Tuesday.</p>

<p>"If the Zionist regime reacts to Iranian operations, it will face crushing attacks," the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps said in a statement carried by the Fars news agency.</p>

<p>On Tuesday evening, Iran launched a missile attack targeting Israel's commercial hub Tel Aviv, state media reported.</p>

<p>The United States had spoken of an imminent Iranian ballistic missile attack against Israel and warned it would have "severe" consequences for Tehran.</p>

<p>Iranian media carried online footage of what they said were missiles being launched against Israel.</p>

<p>State television played joyful songs over the footage and its anchor congratulated "the brave Iranian people".</p>

<p>Tuesday's attack was Iran's second on Israel after a a missile and drone attack in April in retaliation for a deadly Israeli air strike on the Iranian consulate in Damascus.</p>

<p>Nearly all the munitions fired in that attack were intercepted by Israel or its allies.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike on Beirut on Friday killed Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah, whose Lebanese militant group has been armed and financed by the Islamic republic for years.</p>

<p>Nasrallah was killed alongside General Abbas Nilforoushan, a top commander of the Quds Force, the Guards' foreign operations arm.</p>

<p>Iran vowed Nilforoushan's killing "will not go unanswered".</p>

<p>At the UN General Assembly in New York last month, Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian accused Israel of warmongering while Iran had exercised restraint.</p>

<p>He suggested Iran had held back retaliation for the killing of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran in July, fearing it could derail US-backed efforts for a Gaza ceasefire.</p>

<p>"We tried to not respond. They kept telling us we were within reach of peace, perhaps in a week or so," he said.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Pezeshkian said promises by the US and its allies of a "ceasefire in exchange for Iran's non-reaction to Haniyeh's killing were completely false".</p>

<p>He added that "giving these criminals (Israel) a chance would only encourage them to commit more crimes."</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/1af807s_iran-attack-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-fires-over-100-rockets-at-israel-indian-embassy-issues-advisory-for-all-indian-nationals-6695139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Iran Fires Over 180 Missiles At Israel, Indian Embassy Issues Advisory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-iran-fires-over-100-rockets-at-israel-indian-embassy-issues-advisory-for-all-indian-nationals-6695139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 22:40:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid escalating tensions in West Asia (Middle East), the Indian Embassy in Israel has cautioned all Indians to stay vigilant and follow safety protocols advised by local authorities.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid escalating tensions in West Asia (Middle East), the Indian Embassy in Israel has cautioned all Indians to stay vigilant and follow safety protocols advised by local authorities. The advisory was issued within hours of Iran threatening an attack on Israel in the aftermath of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah being killed in an Israeli missile attack.</p>

<p>Iran followed up on the threat by launching over 180 missiles at Israel, Iran's state media confirmed. Israel's defence forces said that its nationals were already in bunkers, taking shelter from the attack.</p>

<p>The nearly year-long conflict between Israel and Hamas in the Gaza strip has intensified with Tel Aviv going after Hezbollah - an Iran-backed militant organisation which supports Hamas. Iran had vowed to avenge the killing of Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, killed last week, and had warned Israel of an imminent ballistic missile attack against it.</p>

<p>"In view of the prevailing situation in the region, all Indian nationals in Israel are advised to stay vigilant and adhere to safety protocols as advised by the local authorities," The Indian Embassy in Tel Aviv said in its advisory.</p>

<p>"Please exercise caution, avoid unnecessary travel within the country and stay close to safety shelters," it added.</p>

<p>The Embassy also shared round-the-clock helpline numbers where Indian nationals can call in case of emergency. "The Embassy is closely monitoring the situation and remains in regular touch with Israeli authorities to ensure the safety of all our nationals," it said, adding, "In case of any emergency, please contact the 24x7 helpline of the Embassy - +972-547520711 and +972-543278392."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?*IMPORTANT ADVISORY FOR INDIAN NATIONALS IN ISRAEL*<br />
<br />
Link : <a href="https://t.co/OEsz3oUtBJ">https://t.co/OEsz3oUtBJ</a> <a href="https://t.co/llt83IwIZ0">pic.twitter.com/llt83IwIZ0</a></p>
— India in Israel (@indemtel) <a href="https://twitter.com/indemtel/status/1841144622845661470?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The Embassy also shared an e-mail ID - cons1.telaviv@mea.gov.in - for Indian nationals to reach out, urging those "who are yet to register with the Embassy" to please do so immediately. It attached the form along with the message.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/miheqeto_israel-people-taking-shelter-in-bunkers-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[People take shelter in bunkers in Tel Aviv as Iran fires over 180 missiles at Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-live-updates-iran-launches-rockets-at-israel-civilians-flee-for-shelters-6695096]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live: "This Will Have Consequences": Israel After Iran Missile Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-attacks-israel-live-updates-iran-launches-rockets-at-israel-civilians-flee-for-shelters-6695096]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 22:32:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran launched missiles at Israel as alarms sounded across the country and Israelis rushed for shelter. Iran said the attack on Israel was a response to the killings of Guards commander and other leaders.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran launched missiles at Israel on Tuesday as alarms sounded across the country and civilians rushed for shelter. Iran said the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-iran-on-israel-civilians-hiding-in-bomb-shelters-says-israel-defence-forces-6694961">attack on Israel </a>was a response to the killings of Guards commander and other leaders.</p>

<p>The Israel's military later sounded the all-clear and said Israelis were free to leave their shelters. It vowed retaliation against Iran "at place and time we decide".</p>

<p>The Iran Guards, meanwhile, threatened 'crushing attacks' if Israel responded to the missile attack.</p>

<p>Earlier, the Israel military had announced that any ballistic missile strike from Iran was expected to be widespread and told the public to shelter in safe rooms in the event of an attack.</p>

<p>The firing of missiles came after Israeli troops launched ground raids into Lebanon, in the biggest escalation of regional warfare since fighting erupted in Gaza a year ago.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<h2 style="margin: 0;
padding: 8px  5px;
width: 100%;
line-height: 30px;
color: #b7223b;
font-weight: 600 !important;">Here are the updates on Iran's attack on Israel:</h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/so9l7ptg_iran-missile-attacks-on-israel-reuters_625x300_02_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran fired over 180 missiles at Israel in one of the sharpest escalations amid Middle East tensions]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-iran-on-israel-civilians-hiding-in-bomb-shelters-says-israel-defence-forces-6694961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Will Operate At Time, Place We Decide": Israel To Iran After Missile Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rockets-fired-from-iran-on-israel-civilians-hiding-in-bomb-shelters-says-israel-defence-forces-6694961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 22:11:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran has fired missiles at Israel and all civilians in the country are in bomb shelters, the Israeli military said on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a sharp escalation of the conflict in the Middle East, Iran launched a massive missile attack on Israel on Tuesday, with the Israeli military saying around 180 projectiles were fired. The attack came amid Israel's ground offensive in Lebanon to target Hezbollah and days after the militant outfit's commander Hassan Nasrallah and a top official from Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps were killed in Israeli strikes in Beirut. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The Israeli foreign ministry said at 10.08 pm IST that the missiles were fired a "short while ago". An hour later, around 11.10 pm, the Israel Defence Forces (IDF) said there was no more threat from Iran "for now" and civilians could leave bomb shelters, adding that there were a few "hits" during the barrage.</p>

<p>Confirming the attack, Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps&nbsp;said it was in response to the killing of Nasrallah, Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh and its own senior commander Abbas Nilforoushan.</p>

<p>The Revolutionary Guards also threatened to carry out "crushing attacks" against Israel if it retaliated after the attack. "If the Zionist regime reacts to Iranian operations, it will face crushing attacks," it said in a statement carried by Iranian news agency Fars, according to news agency AFP.&nbsp;The Revolutionary Guards claimed the attacks were "in accordance with the United Nations Charter" and came "after a period of restraint".</p>

<p>Iran-backed Iraqi armed groups said US bases in Iraq and the region would be targeted if the United States joined any response to Iranian strikes on Israel or if Israel used Iraqi airspace against Tehran, news agency Reuters reported. Hamas praised the attacks as "heroic" and celebrations were reported in Beirut.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>'Will Have Consequences'</strong></p>

<p>Israel vowed to retaliate to the Iranian attack, with IDF Spokesperson Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari&nbsp;saying the country would respond at a time and place of its choosing.</p>

<p>"This attack will have consequences. We have plans, and we will operate at the place and time we decide," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>While the attack was taking place, US President Joe Biden ordered the country's military to "aid Israel's defence" and shoot down Iranian missiles targeting its ally. A White House statement said&nbsp; Biden and Vice President Kamala Harris, who is the Democratic nominee in next month's US presidential election, were both monitoring Iran's attack on Israel from the White House situation room, AFP reported. The agency said some missiles had also been intercepted by neighbouring Jordan.</p>

<p>Videos showed debris from missiles intercepted by Israel's famed Iron Dome and Arrow defence systems raining down on Tel Aviv. The Israeli Defence Forces also confirmed that blasts had been heard in "Jerusalem and elsewhere".</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">RAW FOOTAGE: Watch as Iranian missiles rain over the Old City in Jerusalem, a holy site for Muslims, Christians and Jews.<br />
<br />
This is the target of the Iranian regime: everyone. <a href="https://t.co/rIqUZWN3zy">pic.twitter.com/rIqUZWN3zy</a></p>
— Israel Defense Forces (@IDF) <a href="https://twitter.com/IDF/status/1841167289984397726?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p></p>

<p>"Currently, there are no reports of injuries from the fire towards Israel, except for two light injuries from shrapnel in the Tel Aviv area and some minor injuries nationwide while moving to safe spaces," a statement from Israeli emergency services said. A local governor in the West Bank said a Palestinian had been killed after being hit by shrapnel from an Iranian missile.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Air traffic was halted at Israel's Ben Gurion airport and the country closed its airspace and diverted flights, a spokesman from the airport authority said. The aviation authorities in Jordan and Iraq also announced the suspension of air traffic while&nbsp;Iran suspended flights at Tehran International Airport.</p>

<p><strong>'Remain Alert'</strong></p>

<p>As the attack began, the Israeli foreign ministry's handle said in a post on X, "A short while ago, missiles were launched from Iran towards the State of Israel. Israelis are instructed to remain alert and precisely follow the Home Front Command's instructions."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"In the last few minutes, the Home Front Command has distributed life-saving instructions in various areas across the country. The IDF is doing and will do everything necessary to protect the civilians of the State of Israel," it said.</p>

<p>IDF Spokesperson Hagari asked citizens to remain vigilant and asked them to enter a protected space as soon as they heard a siren and remain there until they got further instructions.</p>

<p>"The air defense system is fully operational, detecting and intercepting threats wherever necessary, even at this moment. However, the defense is not hermetic, and therefore it is essential to follow the Home Front Command's instructions. You may hear explosions, which could be the result of interceptions or impacts," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The IDF is doing and will continue to do everything necessary to protect the civilians of Israel. The IDF is fully prepared for both defense and offense at peak readiness," he added.</p>

<p>The news of the missiles being launched came shortly after reports of a suspected "terror" shooting in Israel's commercial capital Tel Aviv. Police in the city said at least six people were killed.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Broadening Conflict</strong></p>

<p>After Iran's attack, UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres condemned the "broadening conflict in the Middle East".</p>

<p>Expressing concern over "escalation after escalation" in the region, Mr Guterres said: "This must stop. We absolutely need a ceasefire."</p>

<p>Iran had also launched missiles and drones at Israel on 13 April in retaliation for the Israeli bombing of its embassy in Damascus, in which two Iranian generals were killed. The projectiles were shot down by Israeli, American, British, French and Jordanian air forces. The strike did not cause much damage and, the next day, Iran said the attacks could be "deemed concluded".</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f6igt62g_iran-attack-on-israel_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Videos showed debris from intercepted missiles raining down on Tel Aviv.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspected-terror-shooting-in-tel-aviv-on-border-with-jaffa-with-a-number-of-casualties-israeli-police-6694890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Killed In Suspected Shooting, Stabbing Terror Attack In Tel Aviv]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/suspected-terror-shooting-in-tel-aviv-on-border-with-jaffa-with-a-number-of-casualties-israeli-police-6694890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 22:01:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least six people were killed and nine wounded in a suspected shooting and stabbing terror attack in Tel Aviv on Tuesday, Israeli police said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least six people were killed and nine wounded in a suspected shooting and stabbing terror attack in Tel Aviv on Tuesday, Israeli police said.</p>

<p>They said two "terrorists" started a killing spree on the Tel Aviv light rail and continued on foot before being killed by civilians and inspectors using personal pistols. There has been no claim of responsibility but Israeli Finance Minister Bezalel Smotrich said they were Palestinians from the West Bank city of Hebron.</p>

<p>The hardline Smotrich said he will demand of the cabinet that members of the suspects' families be deported to Gaza and their homes destroyed.</p>

<p>The attack took place minutes before Iran launched a barrage of missiles at Israel.</p>

<p>TV footage showed gunmen getting off at a light rail station and opening fire.</p>

<p>Israel's MDA ambulance service said it received a report at 7:01 p.m. (1601 GMT) of people injured by gunfire.</p>

<p>Medics and paramedics provided on-site treatment to a number of wounded people with varying degrees of injuries, including some who were unconscious, MDA said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/36c2iruo_tel-aviv-shooting_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack took place minutes before Iran launched a barrage of missiles at Israel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-turns-out-to-be-an-original-picasso-worth-over-rs-50-crore-6694443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Painting Found In Cellar Turns Out To Be Original Picasso Worth Rs 50 Crore]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-turns-out-to-be-an-original-picasso-worth-over-rs-50-crore-6694443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:55:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[It's believed that the portrait is of Dora Maar, a French photographer and painter who was Picasso's mistress and muse.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A junk dealer's discovery in a Capri cellar has turned out to be an original Picasso portrait. According to a <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2024/oct/01/painting-found-by-junk-dealer-in-cellar-is-original-picasso-experts-claim">Guardian</a></em> report, Luigi Lo Rosso found the painting in 1962, took it home to Pompeii, and hung it in his living room despite his wife's distaste for it. For decades, the painting remained a mystery, until Lo Rosso's son Andrea started researching art history and noticed the distinctive signature in the top left corner.&nbsp;The family then sought the advice of a team of experts, including a well-known art detective, Maurizio Seracini.&nbsp;Cinzia Altieri, a graphologist and member of the Arcadia Foundation's scientific committee, confirmed the painting's distorted style as classic Picasso. The art piece is now valued at 5 million pounds (Rs&nbsp;55,71,18,527).</p>

<p>''After all the other examinations of the painting were done, I was given the job of studying the signature. I worked on it for months, comparing it with some of his original works. There is no doubt that the signature is his. There was no evidence suggesting that it was false,'' Mr Altieri told the <em>Guardian.</em>&nbsp;</p>

<p>It's believed that the portrait is of Dora Maar, a French photographer and painter who was Picasso's mistress and muse.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lo Ross died, but his son Andrea, who is 60 now, pursued his quest to discover the artist behind the painting.</p>

<p>''My father was from Capri and would collect junk to sell for next to nothing. He found the painting before I was even born and didn't have a clue who Picasso was. He wasn't a very cultured person. I kept telling my father it was similar, but he didn't understand. But as I grew up, I kept wondering,''&nbsp;Andrea Lo Rosso told The <em>Guardian.</em></p>

<p>Mr Rosso also revealed that his family considered disposing of the painting due to his mother's strong dislike. "She found it repulsive and repeatedly urged us to get rid of it," he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His quest to validate his father's discovery faced a significant hurdle when the Picasso Foundation in Málaga repeatedly dismissed his claims as false. Despite this setback, experts, including graphologist Cinzia Altieri, have now confirmed the painting's authenticity.</p>

<p>Notably, Picasso frequently visited Capri, where the painting was discovered, and the estimated creation period between 1930 and 1936 aligns with his stylistic evolution. Notably, Picasso created over 14,000 works during his lifetime, leaving room for unknown pieces to emerge.</p>

<p>The painting, now stored in a Milan vault, awaits official recognition from the Picasso Foundation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/f1asd9c_picasso-painting_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The painting's distorted style is classic Picasso, and Italian experts have confirmed its authenticity.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israeli-jets-hit-beirut-people-flee-to-sleep-on-the-beach-6694424]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Israeli Jets Hit Beirut, People Flee To Sleep On The Beach]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/as-israeli-jets-hit-beirut-people-flee-to-sleep-on-the-beach-6694424]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:52:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The repeated blasts in Beirut's southern suburbs where Israel has been carrying out airstrikes this week have driven Zeina Nazha and her young daughter to camp on a city beach seeking safety from the war in Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The repeated blasts in Beirut's southern suburbs where Israel has been carrying out airstrikes this week have driven Zeina Nazha and her young daughter to camp on a city beach seeking safety from the war in Lebanon.</p>

<p>She and some others from those suburbs, known as Dahiyeh, a stronghold of Israel's Iran-backed foe Hezbollah, are sleeping on blankets either under the open sky or in tents and other makeshift shelters with no safer place to go.</p>

<p>Israel's stepped-up military campaign in Lebanon over the past two weeks has driven a million people from their homes in the south, in Beirut and in the Bekaa valley in the east, according to the Lebanese government.</p>

<p>Israel says its campaign is necessary to make its own northern regions safe from Hezbollah rocket fire and allow thousands of its citizens home.</p>

<p>"There was bombing in al-Sallem neighbourhood. We stayed for a while there and my family fled," said Nazha.</p>

<p>"The situation we're living in is very difficult... people are dying," she added.</p>

<p>She and her daughter spent a night sleeping on the corniche, the seaside walk around central areas of Beirut that in peaceful times is a hub of city life, filled with families strolling or sitting and eating.</p>

<p>The government and private or charitable bodies have set up numerous shelters in schools and other facilities to accommodate people displaced by the fighting. But Nazha said all those she had visited were full up.</p>

<p>Nearby, Mohamed Terkmene, a Syrian man living in Lebanon who has also been displaced by the conflict, said he had been sleeping at the beach for four days. He said soldiers had come to tell him and his neighbours to evacuate their Dahiyeh homes.</p>

<p>"We are not able to sleep and we don't know for how long we will stay here. A month, two months, a week or two, until this war is resolved," he said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ndh6hb2g_beirut-beach-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-the-quad-faces-a-big-challenge-by-china-led-unnamed-bloc-6694211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: How 'The Quad' Faces A Big Challenge By China-Led Unnamed Bloc]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/explained-how-the-quad-faces-a-big-challenge-by-china-led-unnamed-bloc-6694211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 01 Oct 2024 20:24:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Quad, a strategic security grouping which was formed to maintain peace, stability and freedom of navigation in the Indo-Pacific region, is facing a major challenge from an unofficial, unnamed alliance led by China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Quad, a strategic security grouping which was formed to maintain peace, stability and freedom of navigation in the Indo-Pacific region, is facing a major challenge from an unofficial, unnamed alliance led by China, especially after the chronology of events in recent months leading up to, and beyond the latest Quad Summit in the United States.</p>

<p>The Quad, short for the Quadrilateral, is a group comprising India, the United States, Japan, and Australia. The grouping was formed with an aim to maintain security and freedom of navigation in the Indian Ocean and the Pacific Ocean. The Quad was first set up in 2007, but ceased to exist in 2008 following the withdrawal of Australia. The group was re-established in 2017 by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, then US President Donald Trump, then Japanese PM Shinzo Abe, and then Australian PM Malcolm Turnbull.</p>

<p>China, which considers the grouping a threat to its expansionist policies in the South China Sea, Indian Ocean and Pacific Ocean regions, is now leading an unofficial, unnamed group to counter the Quad. The group comprises of China, Russia, Iran and North Korea.</p>

<p>Russia, which is facing an isolation from the West, especially United States and most of Europe over the Ukraine war, finds itself in a situation where it is heavily dependant on China, both economically as well as supply of select weaponry. Iran and North Korea too, find itself under heavy US sanctions and find itself in depending significantly on China.</p>

<p>Beijing, which aims to replace the United States as the leading global power, is leading its assertive, aggressive and expansionist policies by leveraging the ally's which are dependant on it.</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the chronology of provocative events led by China to send a message to the Quad:</strong></h2>

<h3><strong>MESSAGE TO THE UNITED STATES</strong></h3>

<p>China launched an intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) from its territory deep into the Pacific Ocean on September 25, the first such test since 1980. The launch came days after the annual Quad Leaders' Summit was held in Delaware in the US. The ICBM can reportedly target any location in the US in less than 30 minutes.</p>

<p>Beijing has downplayed the incident calling the test - a first in 44 years - "routine".</p>

<p>China's Ministry of National Defence or MND said, "The People's Liberation Army Rocket Force (PLARF) launched an ICBM carrying a dummy warhead to the high seas in the Pacific Ocean at 08:44 on September 25th, and the missile fell into expected sea areas. This test launch is a routine arrangement in our annual training plan. It is in line with international law and international practice, and is not directed against any country or target."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ja1odglo_china-icbm-reuters-_625x300_01_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The missile hit the desired target near the exclusive economic zone of French Polynesia, not far from the Marquesas Islands. China sent its Yuan Wang 5 tracking ship near the landing site to collect data. New Zealand described the ICBM test as an "unwelcome and concerning development". The US Air Force too deployed an RC-135S Cobra Ball aircraft to collect optical and electronic data on the missile and its warhead about halfway along its flight path.</p>

<p>The ICBM's desired target was 12,000km from the launch site. The distance between China's Hainan Island and Los Angeles in the US is just 12,100km. China therefore effectively demonstrated its ability to reach the US with this type of nuclear weapon in under 30 minutes. Beijing's newer DF-41 has an even longer range.</p>

<p>This latest provocative test came at a time of heightened tensions with neighbours like Japan, the Philippines and Taiwan.</p>

<p>Taiwan's Ministry of Foreign Affairs immediately tweeted, "PLA's 1st ICBM launch in 44 years exposes the regime's expansionist ambitions &amp; malign nature. Taiwan vehemently condemns the PRC for its reckless moves destabilising the region &amp; urges China to exercise restraint &amp; cease all actions that undermine global efforts for peace." This was more than a routine test. China was sending a signal, an intimidating one at that, Teipei said.</p>

<p>China has a 2009 agreement with Russia for each side to notify the other of ballistic missile launches, but so far China has rejected all such suggestions for a similar mechanism with the US.</p>

<h3><strong>MESSAGE TO JAPAN</strong></h3>

<p>On September 21 - the day that the Quad Summit was held in the US - China began joint naval exercises in the Sea of Japan. Russia's Pacific Fleet had said, "A joint detachment of warships of the Pacific Fleet and Chinese Navy set out from Vladivostok to conduct the joint Russian-Chinese "Beibu/Interaction - 2024" naval exercise," adding that the naval exercises will include anti-aircraft and anti-submarine weapons.</p>

<p>Two days into the joint naval exercise near Japan, Tokyo protested a major provocation by Moscow, when a Russian patrol aircraft entered Japan's airspace - not once, not twice, but three times. Japan's Defence Minister Minoru Kihara had said, "We confirmed today that a Russian Il-38 patrol aircraft has violated our airspace over our territorial waters north of Rebun Island, Hokkaido, on three occasions."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/i1j8rtds_f35-fighter-jet-f-35-lightning-ii-jet_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Japan had scrambled its F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military. (Photo: Lockheed Martin)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Japan had scrambled its F-15 and F-35 fighter jets to warn the Russian military over radio during the first two airspace breaches. Finally the Japanese Air Force jets had to resort to firing flares when the third incursion happened. This even prompted Tokyo to call Moscow through diplomatic channels to ensure such provocation doesn't happen again. The Russian government has not commented on the air incursions.</p>

<p>A similar incident happened a month earlier, in August, when Japan had to fly out its air force jets when Chinese military aircraft entered its airspace. Tokyo had warned Beijing, calling it a "serious violation of our sovereignty."</p>

<p>The China-Russia joint naval drill was also the "largest of its kind for three decades," Vladimir Putin had said.</p>

<p>In the aftermath of these China-backed provocations, Japan, Australia and New Zealand sent a strong message to Beijing as their naval ships passed through the Taiwan Strait. JS Sazanami's, a destroyer of the Japan Maritime Self-Defense Force and a navel vessel each from Australia and New Zealand - the HMAS Sydney (DDG 42) and HMNZS Endeavour (A11) - transited the Strait of Taiwan. This was the first ever that such an incident by Japan, Australia and New Zealand took place.</p>

<p>China reportedly sent five of its naval ships to close proximity of the Australian and New Zealand ships and carried out surveillance activity.</p>

<p>With regard to the incident by Japan, Beijing issued a statement via its foreign office spokesperson, who said, "China's response to Japanese Maritime SDF vessel's passing through the Taiwan Strait: The Taiwan question is a red line that must not be crossed. Japan must honor its commitment and be prudent on this issue, and not create disturbance for China-Japan ties and cross-Strait peace."</p>

<h3><strong>CHALLENGE TO FREEDOM ON NAVIGATION IN INDIAN OCEAN</strong></h3>

<p>China, Russia and Iran have also increased their cooperation and activities in West Asia (Middle East). Last year, Beijing brokered a deal between Saudi Arabia and Iran, highlighting its presence in the Middle East. Both Beijing and Moscow have also condemned the killing of Iran-backed Hezbollah chief Hassan Nasrallah, in a stand against Israel.</p>

<p>Russia and Iran are also reportedly negotiating terms to arming Houthis in Yemen who are targeting merchant shipping vessels in and around the Red Sea and the Gulf of Aden. However, they are not targeting Chinese and Russian ships, reports suggest. With a rise in the number of attacks by Houthis, it poses a massive threat to freedom of navigation in the Indian Ocean.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/898n5gj8_houthis-target-merchant-ships-in-red-sea-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>Flames and smoke rise from an oil tanker which was attacked by Iran-backed Houthis in the Red Sea. (Photo: Reuters)</em></p>
</div>

<p>Iran-backed and Yemen-based Houthi terrorists have attacked and hijacked ships in the region for many months, affecting the global trade and maritime operations. These incidents are on the rise amid Israel's ongoing war against Hamas and Hezbollah, both backed by Iran.</p>

<p>According to the US Maritime Administration, Houthis have launched over 50 attacks on shipping, resulting in casualties, vessel seizures, and disruptions to global trade routes. The campaign has forced shipping firms to seek alternative routes, impacting approximately 12 per cent of global trade that traverses the Red Sea.</p>

<h3><strong>THE NORTH KOREA THREAT</strong></h3>

<p>In the last few months, North Korea, which is reportedly backed by Beijing, has fired multiple ballistic missiles at the US, Japan and South Korea.</p>

<p>The projectiles were believed to have fallen into the sea. The development comes in the wake of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un seen inspecting a uranium enrichment facility in mid-September.</p>

<p>The US Indo-Pacific Command in statement said it was aware of Pyongyang's "ballistic missile launches and are consulting closely" with South Korea and Japan, as well as other regional allies and partners.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="(Photo Credit: Reuters)" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oe9qbqdo_north-korea-missile-launcher-reuters_625x300_01_October_24.jpg" title="(Photo Credit: Reuters)" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption"><em>(Photo Credit: Reuters)</em></p>
</div>

<p>"The United States condemns these actions and calls on the DPRK to refrain from further unlawful and destabilizing acts. While we have assessed that this event does not pose an immediate threat to US personnel, or territory, or to our allies, we continue to monitor the situation," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>A New York Times report has said that US President Joe Biden had in March this year approved a classified document ordering US forces to prepare for possible coordinated nuclear confrontations with Russia, China and North Korea.</p>

<p>Amid these developments, Japanese Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba has said that Japan faces its "most severe" regional security situation in the post-WWII era. "The security environment surrounding our country is the most severe since the end of World War II," he said last month in his first speech as prime minister.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2018-01/china-aircraft-carrier-afp_650x400_71516190344.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Recent events suggest that China is leading an unnamed bloc which poses a challenge to the Quad]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>