<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 05:32:57 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-warns-protesters-in-rotherham-you-will-regret-taking-part-in-this-6264460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["You Will Regret Taking Part In This": UK PM Keir Starmer Warns Protesters]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-pm-keir-starmer-warns-protesters-in-rotherham-you-will-regret-taking-part-in-this-6264460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 04:49:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Unrest related to misinformation about the mass stabbing last Monday in the northwestern English seaside town of Southport has hit multiple towns and cities, with anti-immigration demonstrators clashing with police.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer warned far-right protesters on Sunday they would "regret" participating in England's worst rioting in 13 years, as disturbances linked to the murder of three children earlier this week flared across the country.</p>

<p>Masked anti-immigration demonstrators smashed several windows at a hotel that has been used to house asylum seekers in Rotherham, South Yorkshire.</p>

<p>Unrest related to misinformation about the mass stabbing last Monday in the northwestern English seaside town of Southport has hit multiple towns and cities, with anti-immigration demonstrators clashing with police.</p>

<p>The violence is a major challenge for Starmer, elected only a month ago after leading Labour to a landslide win over the Conservatives.</p>

<p>"I guarantee you will regret taking part in this disorder. Whether directly or those whipping up this action online, and then running away themselves," Starmer said in a TV address.</p>

<p>There was "no justification" for what he called "far-right thuggery", he added, promising to bring the perpetrators "to justice".</p>

<h3><strong>Shops looted, burnt</strong></h3>

<p>Footage aired on the BBC showed rioters forcing their way into a Holiday Inn Express in Rotherham. They also pushed a burning bin into the building. It was not clear whether asylum seekers were inside.</p>

<p>Ten officers were injured there, but local police said none of the hotel staff or its clients had been hurt.</p>

<p>In the northeastern English city of Middlesbrough, hundreds of protesters squared up to riot police carrying shields. Some threw bricks, cans and pots at officers.</p>

<p>Protesters there seized a camera from an AFP crew and broke it. The journalists were not injured.</p>

<p>The fresh disturbances came after police said more than 150 people had been arrested since Saturday following skirmishes at far-right rallies in Liverpool, Manchester, Bristol, Blackpool and Hull, as well as Belfast in Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>Rioters threw bricks, bottles and flares at police -- injuring several officers -- and looted and burnt shops, while demonstrators shouted anti-Islamic slurs as they clashed with counter-protesters.</p>

<p>The violence is the worst England has seen since summer 2011, when widespread rioting followed the police killing of a mixed-race man in north London.</p>

<p>Christian, Muslim and Jewish religious leaders in Liverpool issued a joint appeal for calm.</p>

<p>"We're now seeing it (trouble) flooding across major cities and towns," said Tiffany Lynch of the Police Federation of England and Wales.</p>

<p>Late Sunday, Staffordshire police said another hotel known to have sheltered asylum seekers was targeted near Birmingham.</p>

<p>"A large group of individuals" have been "throwing projectiles, smashing windows, starting fires and targeting police" at the hotel in the town of Tamworth, with one officer injured, said the statement.</p>

<p>Riots first flared in Southport late Tuesday following Monday's frenzied knife attack at a Taylor Swift-themed dance party in the northwest coastal city, before spreading up and down England.</p>

<p>They were fuelled by false rumours on social media about the background of British-born 17-year-old suspect Axel Rudakubana, who is accused of killing a six, seven, and nine-year-old, and injuring another 10 people.</p>

<p>Police have blamed the violence on supporters and associated organisations of the English Defence League, an anti-Islam organisation founded 15 years ago whose supporters have been linked to football hooliganism.</p>

<p>Agitators have targeted at least two mosques, and the UK interior ministry announced Sunday it was offering new emergency security to Islamic places of worship.</p>

<p>The rallies have been advertised on far-right social media channels under the banner "Enough is enough".</p>

<p>Participants have waved English and British flags while chanting slogans like "Stop the boats" -- a reference to irregular migrants crossing the Channel to Britain from France.</p>

<p>Anti-fascist demonstrators have held counter-rallies in many cities, including Leeds where they shouted, "Nazi scum off our streets", as the far-right protesters chanted, "You're not English any more".</p>

<p>Not all the gatherings have turned violent. A peaceful one in Aldershot, southern England, on Sunday saw participants hold placards that read "Stop the invasion" and "We're not far right, we're just right".</p>

<p>"People are fed up with being told you should be ashamed if you're white and working class but I'm proud white working class," 41-year-old Karina, who did not give her surname, told AFP in Nottingham on Saturday.</p>

<p>At last month's election, the Reform UK party led by Brexit cheerleader Nigel Farage captured 14 percent of the vote -- one of the largest vote shares for a far-right British party.</p>

<p>Carla Denyer, co-leader of the left-wing Green party, said the unrest should be "a wake-up call to all politicians who have actively promoted or given in" to anti-immigration rhetoric.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t9g1dung_uk-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anti-immigration protest in Rotherham]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mali-cuts-ties-with-ukraine-over-alleged-involvement-in-rebel-attack-6264455]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Mali Cuts Ties With Ukraine Over Alleged Involvement In Rebel Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mali-cuts-ties-with-ukraine-over-alleged-involvement-in-rebel-attack-6264455]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 04:40:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mali is immediately cutting diplomatic ties with Ukraine over comments by a spokesperson for Ukraine's military intelligence agency (GUR) about fighting in its north that killed Malian soldiers and Wagner fighters in late July, it said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mali is immediately cutting diplomatic ties with Ukraine over comments by a spokesperson for Ukraine's military intelligence agency (GUR) about fighting in its north that killed Malian soldiers and Wagner fighters in late July, it said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Mali's northern Tuareg rebels say they killed at least 84 Russian Wagner mercenaries and 47 Malian soldiers over days of fierce fighting in the north of the West African country in what appears to be Wagner's heaviest defeat since it stepped in two years ago to help Mali's military authorities fight insurgent groups.</p>

<p>GUR spokesperson Andriy Yusov has not confirmed Kyiv's involvement in the fighting, but in comments published on public broadcaster Suspilne's website on Monday, July 29, he said the Malian rebels had received the "necessary" information to conduct the attack.</p>

<p>"The rebels received all the necessary information they needed, and not just the information, which allowed (them) to conduct a successful military operation against Russian perpetrators of war crimes. We certainly won't go into details now - you will see more of this in the future," he said.</p>

<p>Mali said it had learned "with deep shock of the subversive remarks."</p>

<p>It said Yusov had "admitted Ukraine's involvement in a cowardly, treacherous and barbaric attack by armed terrorist groups that resulted in the death of members of the Malian Defence and Security Forces."</p>

<p>"The actions taken by the Ukrainian authorities violate the sovereignty of Mali, go beyond the scope of foreign interference, which is already condemnable in itself, and constitute a clear aggression by Mali and support for international terrorism," the Malian government said.</p>

<p>It also cited comments by Ukraine's ambassador to Senegal, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Ivory Coast and Liberia.</p>

<p>Senegal's foreign minister summoned Ukrainian Ambassador Yurii Pyvovarov on Friday over a video it said the Ukrainian embassy had posted on its Facebook page in which Pyvovarov provided "unequivocal and unqualified support for the terrorist attack" in Mali.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/dv237uqo_malian-armed-force-650_625x300_15_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-donald-trumps-offer-to-shift-presidential-debate-6263809]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Rejects Donald Trump's Offer To Shift Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-rejects-donald-trumps-offer-to-shift-presidential-debate-6263809]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:57:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has rejected her Republican rival Donald Trump's offer to shift the presidential debate to the Fox News channel, media reports said on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris has rejected her Republican rival Donald Trump's offer to shift the presidential debate to the Fox News channel, media reports said on Sunday.</p>

<p>Trump, 78, and President Joe Biden -- who was then in the race to the White House -- agreed in May to participate in two presidential debates. The first was in June, hosted by CNN, and the second - to be hosted by ABC News - was scheduled for September 10.</p>

<p>Biden withdrew from the race last month, following which Vice-President Harris, who is of Indian and African heritage, was declared the 2024 presidential nominee of the ruling Democratic Party after she won enough votes from Democratic delegates in a virtual roll call.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Trump said that he has agreed to an offer from Fox News to hold a debate with Vice President Harris on September 4, shifting from the original plan, CBS News reported.</p>

<p>"I have agreed with FoxNews to debate Kamala Harris on Wednesday, September 4th. The debate was previously scheduled against Sleepy Joe Biden on ABC, but has been terminated in that Biden will no longer be a participant, and I am in litigation against ABC Network and George Slopadopoulos, thereby creating a conflict of interest," he said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Harris took to X to turn down Trump's debate offer on Fox News.</p>

<p>"It's interesting how "any time, any place" becomes "one specific time, one specific safe space." I'll be there on September 10th, like he agreed to. I hope to see him there," Harris said.</p>

<p>The Harris campaign also said it will stick to the original plan for an ABC News debate.</p>

<p>It said that "Donald Trump is running scared" hoping that Fox News will "bail him out" of the debate he had already agreed to with ABC News, according to the report.</p>

<p>"He needs to stop playing games and show up to the debate he already committed to on Sept. 10," the report quoted Michael Tyler, the Harris campaign communication director, as saying.</p>

<p>"The Vice President will be there one way or the other to take the opportunity to speak to a prime-time national audience," Tyler said, adding that the campaign is open to discussing further debates but only after the one both campaigns have already agreed to takes place.</p>

<p>Last month, Harris challenged Trump to a debate, provoking him to say whatever he had "to say to her face".</p>

<p>Harris would face Trump in the general elections on November 5.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/knofc75_donald-trump-kamala-harris_625x300_31_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris would face Donald Trump in the general elections on November 5.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-after-fresh-violence-kills-90-6263773]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Issues Advisory For Nationals In Bangladesh After Fresh Violence]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/indians-abroad/india-issues-advisory-for-nationals-in-bangladesh-after-fresh-violence-kills-90-6263773]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:42:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 90 people, including 14 policemen, were killed on Sunday in fierce clashes between security forces personnel and anti-government protesters in different parts of Bangladesh, according to reports from Dhaka.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Sunday night strongly advised all its nationals presently residing in Bangladesh to exercise "extreme caution" and restrict their movements in the wake of fresh waves of violence in the neighbouring country.</p>

<p>In its latest advisory, India also asked its citizens not to travel to Bangladesh till further notice.</p>

<p>At least 90 people, including 14 policemen, were killed on Sunday in fierce clashes between security forces personnel and anti-government protesters in different parts of Bangladesh, according to reports from Dhaka.</p>

<p>The protesters are demanding the resignation of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>"In view of ongoing developments, Indian nationals are strongly advised against travelling to Bangladesh till further notice," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said in the advisory.</p>

<p>"All Indian nationals presently in Bangladesh are advised to exercise extreme caution, restrict their movements and remain in contact with the High Commission of India in Dhaka," it said.</p>

<p>The student protests in Bangladesh started last month against a controversial job quota scheme. The protests now have turned into an anti-government agitation.</p>

<p>On July 25, the MEA said around 6,700 Indian students returned from Bangladesh in view of the situation in that country.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lo91fvag_bangladesh-protests_625x300_05_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The protesters are demanding the resignation of Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-first-attack-on-shipping-lanes-in-2-weeks-6263601]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Yemen's Houthis Claim First Attack On Shipping Lanes In 2 Weeks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yemens-houthis-claim-first-attack-on-shipping-lanes-in-2-weeks-6263601]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:59:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yemen's Iran-aligned Houthi movement said on Sunday that it targeted a Liberia-flagged container vessel in the Gulf of Aden, claiming its first attack on shipping lanes since Israel carried out a retaliatory airstrike in Hodeidah port on July 20.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yemen's Iran-aligned Houthi movement said on Sunday that it targeted a Liberia-flagged container vessel in the Gulf of Aden, claiming its first attack on shipping lanes since Israel carried out a retaliatory airstrike in Hodeidah port on July 20.</p>

<p>Houthi military spokesperson Yahya Saree said in a televised statement that the MV Groton was attacked by ballistic missiles.</p>

<p>British maritime agency UKMTO and British security firm Ambrey said on Saturday that the vessel was targeted by a missile 125 nautical miles east of Yemen's port of Aden. Both said that no water entry or oil leaks were observed.</p>

<p>Built in 2002, the ship was heading to Djibouti, according to Refinitiv data.</p>

<p>The attack is the first since an apparent lull following Israel's attack on Hodeidah, which occurred a day after a drone launched by the Iranian-backed group hit Israeli economic hub Tel Aviv.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/hkp49t58_houthis-reuters-_625x300_11_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack is the first since an apparent lull following Israel's attack on Hodeidah]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/neuralink-successfully-implanted-in-2nd-patient-working-well-elon-musk-6263559]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Neuralink Successfully Implanted In 2nd Patient, Working Well: Elon Musk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/neuralink-successfully-implanted-in-2nd-patient-working-well-elon-musk-6263559]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:48:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Neuralink has successfully implanted in a second patient its device designed to give paralyzed patients the ability to use digital devices by thinking alone, according to the startup's owner Elon Musk.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Neuralink has successfully implanted in a second patient its device designed to give paralyzed patients the ability to use digital devices by thinking alone, according to the startup's owner Elon Musk.</p>

<p>Neuralink is in the process of testing its device, which is intended to help people with spinal cord injuries. The device has allowed the first patient to play video games, browse the internet, post on social media and move a cursor on his laptop.</p>

<p>Musk, in comments made during a podcast released late on Friday that ran more than eight hours, gave few details about the second participant beyond saying the person had a spinal cord injury similar to the first patient, who was paralyzed in a diving accident. Musk said 400 of the implant's electrodes on the second patient's brain are working. Neuralink on its website states that its implant uses 1,024 electrodes.</p>

<p>"I don't want to jinx it but it seems to have gone extremely well with the second implant," Musk told podcast host Lex Fridman. "There's a lot of signal, a lot of electrodes. It's working very well."</p>

<p>Musk did not disclose when Neuralink performed the second patient's surgery. Musk said he expects Neuralink to provide the implants to eight more patients this year as part of its clinical trials.</p>

<p>The first patient, Noland Arbaugh, was also interviewed on the podcast, along with three Neuralink executives, who gave details about how the implant and the robot-led surgery work.</p>

<p>Before Arbaugh received his implant in January, he used a computer by employing a stick in his mouth to tap the screen of a tablet device. Arbaugh said with the implant he now can merely think about what he wants to happen on the computer screen, and the device makes it happen. He said the device has given him a modicum of independence and reduced his reliance on caregivers.</p>

<p>Arbaugh initially faced issues after his surgery when the tiny wires of his implant retracted, resulting in a sharp reduction in the electrodes that could measure brain signals. Reuters has reported Neuralink was aware of this issue from its animal trials.</p>

<p>Neuralink has said it restored the implant's ability to monitor Arbaugh's brain signals by making changes that included modifying its algorithm to be more sensitive. Arbaugh has improved on his previous world record for the speed at which he can control a cursor with thoughts alone "with only roughly 10, 15% of the electrodes working," Musk said on the podcast.</p>

<p>Musk also said he has spoken with Republican candidate Donald Trump, who he has endorsed in the U.S. presidential race, about forming a commission aimed at improving "government efficiency" through reduced business regulation, and would be willing to participate. Musk said that in his view U.S. regulations hamper innovation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/pnvon14o_elon-musk-neuralink_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk said he expects Neuralink to provide the implants to eight more patients this year. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-be-foolish-not-to-have-good-relations-with-army-says-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-6263380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Would Be "Foolish" Not To Have Good Relations With Army, Says Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/would-be-foolish-not-to-have-good-relations-with-army-says-ex-pak-pm-imran-khan-6263380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 23:12:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, Imran Khan, who blames the military for his ouster and 12-month-old imprisonment on what he calls trumped-up charges, said on Sunday it would be "foolish" not to have "excellent" relations with the army.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>Pakistan's jailed former prime minister, Imran Khan, who blames the military for his ouster and 12-month-old imprisonment on what he calls trumped-up charges, said on Sunday it would be "foolish" not to have "excellent" relations with the army.</p>

<p>Ahead of Monday's anniversary of his jailing on dozens of charges ranging from corruption to leaking state secrets, Khan also said in written responses to Reuters questions that he held no grudges against the United States, whom he has also blamed for his 2022 ouster from office.</p>

<p>"Given Pakistan's geographical position and the military's significant role in the private sector, it would be foolish not to foster such a relationship," Imran Khan wrote in replies relayed by his media and legal team.</p>

<p>"We are proud of our soldiers and armed forces," he said.</p>

<p>Imran Khan said his criticisms since his ouster had been directed at individuals, not the military as an institution. "The miscalculations of the military leadership shouldn't be held against the institution as a whole."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, Imran Khan offered to hold "conditional negotiations" with the South Asian nation's military - if "clean and transparent" elections were held and the "bogus" cases against his supporters were dropped.</p>

<p>Pakistan's army and government did not immediately respond to requests for comment on Imran Khan's remarks to Reuters. They have both repeatedly denied his assertions.</p>

<p>The United States denies any role in his ouster.</p>

<p>In his replies, the 71-year-old former cricket star did not specify what he wanted to discuss with the military.</p>

<p>'OPEN TO ANY DIALOGUE' WITH ARMY</p>

<p>The army, which has ruled Pakistan for more than half its 76-year independent history, plays an oversized role in the politics and governance of the nation of 240 million people.</p>

<p>No Pakistani prime minister has completed a full five-year term in office, and most have served time in jail. Analysts say most of those secured their release after striking deals with the military, a claim the army denies.</p>

<p>Imran Khan, who lost power in a parliamentary vote of no confidence after falling out with the generals, has said the army has been backing what he calls the politically motivated cases against him, which the military has denied.</p>

<p>Still, he said, there would be "no harm" in engaging with the generals if he should be released from jail and seek to return to power.</p>

<p>"We are open to any dialogue that could help improve the dire situation in Pakistan," he said, adding that it was useless to open any such talks with the coalition government of Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif, which he says does not enjoy public backing because he claims it won a stolen election in February.</p>

<p>Rather, Imran Khan said, it would be "more productive to engage with those who actually wield power".</p>

<p>The military - which says Imran Khan and his party were behind attacks on military installations last year during widespread protests against his detention - has previously ruled out any talks with him.</p>

<p>Imran Khan's imprisonment has added to the political volatility in Pakistan, which has experienced a prolonged economic crisis and last month received a bailout from the International Monetary Fund.</p>

<p>The political instability since Imran Khan's ouster from power helped force Islamabad to accept the IMF's painful fiscal consolidation requirements, which have burdened the people with heavy taxes, analysts say.</p>

<p>The IMF has called for political stability to help put the $350 billion economy on a recovery path.</p>

<p>Imran Khan rejected the idea of reaching an out-of-court settlement with the government or military, unless they accepted that his PTI party had won a majority in February's election.</p>

<p>"The elections were the most rigged in Pakistan's history," Imran Khan told Reuters.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jbg3lne_imran-khan-reuters_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The elections were the most rigged in Pakistan's history," said Imran Khan (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-2-schools-says-gaza-agency-6262853]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[30 Killed After Israeli Strike Hits 2 Schools, Says Gaza Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/30-killed-after-israeli-strike-hits-2-schools-says-gaza-agency-6262853]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 21:36:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli strike hit two schools in Gaza City on Sunday, killing at least 30 people, while the military reported it had struck Hamas command centres.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli strike hit two schools in Gaza City on Sunday, killing at least 30 people, while the military reported it had struck Hamas command centres.</p>

<p>These bring to at least 11 the number of schools in Gaza to be struck since July 6, killing around 150 people, based on a tally of tolls previously given by officials in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>"The number of martyrs in the massacre of the Hassan Salameh and Al-Nasr schools' bombing has risen to 30. Dozens were also wounded," civil defence spokesman Mahmud Bassal told AFP.</p>

<p>Bassal said most of the dead and wounded were women and children.</p>

<p>He said the schools were housing Palestinians displaced from their homes in the ongoing war between Israel and Hamas operatives.</p>

<p>Israel's military confirmed the strike targeting the two schools.</p>

<p>"The schools were used by Hamas' Al-Furqan Battalion as a hiding place for its terrorist operatives and as command centres," the military said in a statement.</p>

<p>On Saturday, a similar Israeli strike hit another school compound in Gaza City, killing at least 17 people, according to the civil defence agency.</p>

<p>The Israeli military has repeatedly accused Hamas of using civilian facilities as command and control centres or to hide their commanders and operatives. The Palestinian group denies the accusation.</p>

<p>The war in Gaza began when Hamas operatives attacked Israel on October 7, resulting in the death of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 people, 111 of whom are still held hostage in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory military campaign has killed at least 39,583 people, according to the territory's health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza, which does not give details of civilian and operative deaths.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mahmud Bassal said most of the dead and wounded were women and children. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-f-16-fighter-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-zelensky-says-we-did-it-6262746]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: F-16 Fighter Jets Arrive In Ukraine, Zelensky Says "We Did It"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-f-16-fighter-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-zelensky-says-we-did-it-6262746]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 21:19:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukrainian pilots have started flying F-16s for operations within the nation, President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said on Sunday, confirming the long-awaited arrival of the U.S.-made fighter jets more than 29 months since Russia's invasion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukrainian pilots have started flying F-16s for operations within the nation, President Volodymyr Zelensky said on Sunday, confirming the long-awaited arrival of the U.S.-made fighter jets more than 29 months since Russia's invasion.</p>

<p>The Ukrainian leader announced the use of F-16s, which Kyiv has long lobbied for, as he met military pilots at an air base flanked by two of the jets with two more flying overhead.</p>

<p>"F-16s are in Ukraine. We did it. I am proud of our guys who are mastering these jets and have already started using them for our country," Zelensky said at a location that authorities asked Reuters not to disclose for security reasons.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We are now in a new phase of development for the Air Force of the Armed Forces of Ukraine. We have done a lot to transition the Ukrainian Air Force to a new aviation standard – Western combat aviation. From the beginning of this war, we have been talking with our partners about… <a href="https://t.co/z21yTU0Hjo">pic.twitter.com/z21yTU0Hjo</a></p>
— Volodymyr Zelenskyy / Володимир Зеленський (@ZelenskyyUa) <a href="https://twitter.com/ZelenskyyUa/status/1820097797556765019?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The arrival of the jets is a milestone for Ukraine after many months of waiting, though it remains unclear how many are available and how much of an impact they will have in enhancing air defences and on the battlefield.</p>

<p>Russia has been targeting bases that may house them and vowed to shoot them down so they will not impact the war.</p>

<p>Built by Lockheed Martin, the F-16s had been on Ukraine's wish list for a long time because of their destructive power and global availability. They are equipped with a 20mm cannon and can carry bombs, rockets and missiles.</p>

<p>Talking to reporters on the tarmac of an airfield, Zelenskiy said Ukraine still did not have enough pilots trained to use the F-16s or enough of the jets themselves.</p>

<p>"The positive thing is that we are expecting additional F-16s ... many guys are now training," he said.</p>

<p>It was important, he said, that Kyiv's allies found ways to expand training programmes and opportunities for both Ukrainian pilots and engineering teams.</p>

<p><strong>'NEW AVIATION STANDARD'</strong></p>

<p>Ukraine has previously relied on an ageing fleet of Soviet-era warplanes that are outgunned by Russia's more advanced and far more numerous fleet.</p>

<p>Russia has used that edge to conduct regular long-range missile strikes on targets across Ukraine and also to pound Ukrainian front line positions with thousands of guided bombs, supporting its forces that are slowly advancing in the east.</p>

<p>"This is the new stage of development of the air force of Ukraine's armed forces," Zelensky said.</p>

<p>"We did a lot for Ukrainian forces to transition to a new aviation standard, the Western combat aviation," he added, citing hundreds of meetings and unrelenting diplomacy to obtain the F-16s.</p>

<p>"We often heard 'it is impossible' as an answer but we still made our ambition, our defensive need, possible," he said.</p>

<p>It remains unclear what missiles the jets are equipped with. A longer range of missile would allow them to have a greater battlefield impact, military analysts say.</p>

<p>Zelensky said he also hoped to lobby allied neighbouring countries to help intercept Russian missiles being launched at Ukraine through conversations at the Ukraine-NATO Council platform.</p>

<p>"This is another tool, and I want to try it, so that NATO countries can talk to Ukraine about the possibility of a small coalition of neighbouring countries shooting down enemy missiles," he said.</p>

<p>"I think this decision is probably difficult for our partners, they are always afraid of excessive escalation but we are fighting that."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q99mffu8_zelenskiy-fighter-jet_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["I am proud of our guys who are mastering these jets," said Volodymyr Zelenskiy.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-reveals-steve-jobs-called-for-investment-tips-ignored-advice-6262623]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Warren Buffett Reveals Steve Jobs Called For Investment Tips, Ignored Advice]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/warren-buffett-reveals-steve-jobs-called-for-investment-tips-ignored-advice-6262623]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 20:57:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Jobs decided not to follow Mr Buffett's advice. "He didn't do anything, and of course, he didn't want to do anything. He just liked having the cash."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following the release of Apple's Q3 earnings report, which exceeded expectations, a story from 2012 has resurfaced about Steve Jobs seeking investment advice from legendary American investor Warren Buffett regarding Apple's cash reserves.</p>

<p>In a 2012 interview with <em>CNBC</em>, Mr Buffett recalled a memorable phone call he had with Mr Jobs two years prior. "It was an interesting conversation because I hadn't talked to him in a long time," said the Berkshire Hathaway chairman. Mr Jobs had reached out for advice on managing Apple's significant cash reserves. "He said, 'We've got all this cash. What should we do with it?' So we went over the options."</p>

<p>Mr Buffett explained that companies typically have four choices for utilizing cash: stock buybacks, dividends, acquisitions, or holding onto it. Mr Jobs made it clear that Apple wouldn't pursue large acquisitions requiring substantial cash.</p>

<p>"I went through the logic of each option. He told me they would not have the opportunity for big acquisitions that would require lots of money," Mr Buffett said during the interview. When Buffett suggested stock buybacks if Apple believed its stock was undervalued, Mr Jobs replied, "I think my stock is very undervalued."</p>

<p>Ultimately, Mr Jobs decided not to follow Mr Buffett's advice. "He didn't do anything, and of course, he didn't want to do anything. He just liked having the cash," Mr Buffett said with a laugh. "It was very interesting to me because I later learned that he said I agreed with him to do nothing with the cash."</p>

<p>Earlier this year, Bill Gates, the founder of Microsoft in an interview with Dax Shepard said, "Steve Jobs was a natural. It was always fun to watch him rehearse because part of his genius was when he would finally do it, he would make it look like he's just thinking it up right there," he said. &nbsp;"I'll never achieve that level," Mr Gates added.</p>

<p>During the podcast, Mr Gates stated that he and Mr Jobs were travelling the world in their respective capacities as representatives of Microsoft and Apple and that their task was to convince individuals and organisations of the potential benefits that tools like spreadsheets and email could have for their daily lives and careers.</p>

<p>"We even called it evangelization. Some people might not like that we stole a term of religion, but telling the story of the magic of software is something that - certainly by the time I was in my 30s - was a big part of the job," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l6ul7j_steve-jobs-and-warren-buffet_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Mr Buffett recalled a memorable phone call he had with Mr Jobs]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/atlantic-oceans-current-system-could-collapse-by-2030-heres-why-its-bad-news-6262328]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Atlantic Ocean's Current System Could Collapse By 2030. Why It's Bad News]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/atlantic-oceans-current-system-could-collapse-by-2030-heres-why-its-bad-news-6262328]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 19:56:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scientists emphasize the urgent need for immediate and drastic action to mitigate climate change and potentially stave off this catastrophic tipping point.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New scientific research paints a stark and alarming picture: the Atlantic Meridional Overturning Circulation (AMOC), a crucial oceanic current system regulating global climate, is on the brink of collapse. This impending disaster, accelerated by human-induced climate change, could occur as early as the late 2030s, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/08/02/climate/atlantic-circulation-collapse-timing/index.html"><em>CNN </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The consequences of an AMOC shutdown are profound and far-reaching. A dramatic shift in global weather patterns is expected, including extreme weather events, altered precipitation patterns, and disruptions to agriculture. Europe and North America could experience significant temperature drops, while regions like the Amazon rainforest face drastic changes in seasonal weather.</p>

<p>"This is really worrying," said Rene van Westen, a marine and atmospheric researcher at the University of Utrecht in the Netherlands and study co-author.</p>

<p>"All the negative side effects of anthropogenic climate change, they will still continue to go on, like more heat waves, more droughts, more flooding," he told CNN. "Then if you also have on top of that an AMOC collapse ... the climate will become even more distorted."</p>

<p>The implications for ecosystems and human societies are equally severe. Marine life reliant on the AMOC for nutrient distribution will be jeopardized, and coastal communities face increased risks from rising sea levels and intensified storms.</p>

<p>An AMOC collapse “is a really big danger that we should do everything we can to avoid,” said Stefan Rahmstorf, a physical oceanographer at Potsdam University in Germany who was not involved in the latest research.</p>

<p>Scientists emphasize the urgent need for immediate and drastic action to mitigate climate change and potentially stave off this catastrophic tipping point. The world is at a crossroads, and the decisions made today will determine the planet's future.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e83ofc6g_atlantic-ocean_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The consequences of an AMOC shutdown are profound and far-reaching.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-immigration-protests-rage-in-uk-northern-ireland-dozens-arrested-6262282]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Anti-Immigration Protests Rage In UK, Northern Ireland, Dozens Arrested]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/anti-immigration-protests-rage-in-uk-northern-ireland-dozens-arrested-6262282]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 19:48:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Police arrested dozens of people after protests across parts of England and Northern Ireland turned violent on Saturday, as the government pledged tough action against those it said were exploiting the murder of three girls to stir up disorder.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Police arrested dozens of people after protests across parts of England and Northern Ireland turned violent on Saturday, as the government pledged tough action against those it said were exploiting the murder of three girls to stir up disorder.</p>

<p>Violent protests involving hundreds of anti-immigration groups have erupted in towns and cities across Britain after three girls were killed in a knife attack at a children's dance class in Southport in north-west England last week.</p>

<p>The murders were seized on by anti-immigrant and anti-Muslim groups as misinformation spread that the suspect was a radical Islamist migrant. Police have said the suspect was born in Britain. Media reports have said his family was Christian.</p>

<p>On Saturday, violent disorder broke out in cities around the country, including Liverpool, Bristol, Hull and Stoke-on-Trent, as well as the town of Blackpool, with local police saying they had arrested at least 87 people. There was also unrest in Manchester and Belfast.</p>

<p>Shops and businesses were vandalised and looted, a library in Liverpool was set on fire and several police were injured, police statements said.</p>

<p>"Criminal violence and thuggery on our streets will not be tolerated," interior minister Yvette Cooper said late on Saturday.</p>

<p>"Police forces have my full support in ensuring that those who engage in criminal disorder face the strongest possible penalties."</p>

<p>Saturday's protests were the most widespread after several days of disorder following the murders. Prime Minister Keir Starmer has said they are the result of deliberate actions by the far-right, co-ordinated by a "group of individuals who are absolutely bent on violence," rather than legitimate protest.</p>

<p>The last time violent protests erupted across Britain was in 2011 when thousands of people took to the streets after police shot dead a Black man in London.</p>

<p>There are more demonstrations planned for Sunday, based on messages circulating on social media.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/mnqb6i4g_uk-protests_625x300_04_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On Saturday, violent disorder broke out in cities around the country]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-was-banned-from-being-alone-with-interns-at-microsoft-claims-book-6261910]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bill Gates Was Banned From Being Alone With Interns, Claims Book]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bill-gates-was-banned-from-being-alone-with-interns-at-microsoft-claims-book-6261910]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 18:39:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The book claims that Mr Gates "flirted with some of the interns at the Gates Foundation, putting them in an uncomfortable position."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A forthcoming book is set to ignite controversy surrounding Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates. Author Anupreeta Das alleges that Mr Gates engaged in inappropriate behaviour towards multiple women, prompting Microsoft to institute measures to protect young interns from being alone with him, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/02/business/bill-gates-tell-all-book-claims-microsoft-banned-young-interns-from-being-alone-with-flirty-mogul-before-divorce-kid-in-a-candy-store/"><em>New York Post </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The book paints a picture of a man who, despite his philanthropic image, exhibited a pattern of unwanted advances and flirtatious conduct towards employees and interns alike.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The book claims that Bill Gates “flirted with some of the interns at the Gates Foundation, putting them in the uncomfortable position of having to think about their career prospects while not wanting to be hit on by the boss."</p>

<p>However, a former Microsoft executive told the author that Mr Gates did not “prey on” women or ask for sexual favours in exchange for career advancement. “He's not Harvey Weinstein… I know of no real situation in which anyone got anything for sleeping with Bill.”</p>

<p>A spokesperson for Bill Gates denied the allegations. “Relying almost exclusively on second- and third-hand hearsay and anonymous sources, the book includes highly sensationalized allegations and outright falsehoods that ignore the actual documented facts our office provided to the author on numerous occasions,” the spokesperson said in a statement provided to the New York Post.</p>

<p>These alleged actions are said to have deeply impacted Mr Gates' marriage to Melinda French Gates. The book claims that she grew increasingly concerned about her husband's behaviour, leading her to take proactive steps, including a reorganization of his security detail and restrictions on his access to personal contact information.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The couple's eventual divorce is partly attributed to the ongoing strain caused by these issues, as well as Gates' continued association with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</p>

<p>The allegations have been met with staunch denial from Gates and his representatives, who characterize the book's claims as sensationalized and unfounded. However, the accusations are likely to spark intense public scrutiny and debate about the behaviour of powerful figures.</p>

<p>The book is set to hit stores on August 13.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/28nkia78_bill-gates-reuters_625x300_10_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A spokesperson for Bill Gates denied the allegations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-stabbed-to-death-in-israel-hamas-calls-it-natural-response-to-attacks-6261833]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Stabbed To Death In Israel, Hamas Calls It "Natural Response" To Attacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-stabbed-to-death-in-israel-hamas-calls-it-natural-response-to-attacks-6261833]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 18:24:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Palestinian attacker killed two people and wounded two others in a stabbing spree in central Israel on Sunday before being shot dead by police, Israeli authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Palestinian attacker killed two people and wounded two others in a stabbing spree in central Israel on Sunday before being shot dead by police, Israeli authorities said.</p>

<p>The stabbings took place during morning rush hour in the city of Holon, near Tel Aviv. The attacker stabbed people near a gas station and a park, Israel's ambulance service said.</p>

<p>Two senior citizens, a man and woman, were killed and two other people were wounded and rushed to hospital, medical officials said.</p>

<p>"The terrorist was quickly neutralized by one of our officers at the scene and prevented him from carrying out an even worse attack," police spokesperson Eli Levi said on Israel's Channel 12.</p>

<p>A police statement said police were present in force at the scene and were "conducting extensive searches with a helicopter and additional resources".</p>

<p>The Islamist group Hamas, which is at war with Israel in Gaza, said in a statement that the stabbing attack was a "natural response" to Israeli attacks on Palestinians and to the assassination of the group's leader, Ismail Haniyeh, last week in Tehran.</p>

<p>However, it stopped short of claiming responsibility for Sunday's attack.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/h5v249s_israeli-emergency-responders_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The stabbing attack was a "natural response" to Israeli attacks on Palestinians, said Hamas]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/highly-volatile-situation-foreign-nationals-urged-to-leave-lebanon-6261722]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Highly Volatile" Situation: Foreign Nationals Urged To Leave Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/highly-volatile-situation-foreign-nationals-urged-to-leave-lebanon-6261722]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 18:05:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Urgent calls for foreign nationals to leave Lebanon grew on Sunday with France warning of "a highly volatile" situation as Iran and its allies ready their response to high-profile killings blamed on Israel.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Urgent calls for foreign nationals to leave Lebanon grew on Sunday with France warning of "a highly volatile" situation as Iran and its allies ready their response to high-profile killings blamed on Israel.</p>

<p>Lebanon's Iran-backed Hezbollah movement, which has traded near-daily fire with Israeli forces since the Gaza war broke out in October, announced its fighters had fired a barrage of rockets at Israel's north overnight.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said 30 projectiles were launched from Lebanon, with most of them intercepted.</p>

<p>With Israel on high alert anticipating major military action from Tehran-aligned armed groups including Hezbollah and Hamas, medics and police said two people were killed on Sunday in a stabbing attack in a Tel Aviv suburb.</p>

<p>The assailant, a Palestinian from the occupied West Bank, was "neutralised" by police and taken to hospital, where he was pronounced dead.</p>

<p>Israeli forces meanwhile kept bombarding the Gaza Strip, witnesses and officials in the besieged Hamas-ruled territory said, with no end in sight to the nearly 10-month war triggered by the Palestinian group's October 7 attack on southern Israel.</p>

<p>France, Canada and Jordan were among the latest governments to call for their citizens to leave Lebanon.</p>

<p>"In a highly volatile security context", French nationals were "urgently asked" to avoid travelling to Lebanon, and those already in the country "to make their arrangements now to leave... as soon as possible", the foreign ministry in Paris said.</p>

<p>The United States and Britain have issued similar warnings.</p>

<p>France on Sunday also urged its nationals living in Iran to "temporarily leave", warning Iranian airspace and airports could close.</p>

<p>Several Western airlines have suspended flights to Lebanon and other airports in the region.</p>

<p>On Sunday Qatar Airways said the Doha-Beirut route would "operate exclusively during daylight hours" at least until Monday.</p>

<p>The killing Wednesday of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran, hours after the Israeli assassination of Hezbollah's military chief in Beirut, has triggered vows of vengeance from Iran and the so-called "axis of resistance" of Tehran-backed armed groups.</p>

<p>Israel, accused by Hamas, Iran and others of carrying out the attack that killed Haniyeh, has not directly commented on it.</p>

<p><strong>Tents for displaced hit</strong></p>

<p>Israel has vowed to destroy Hamas in retaliation for its unprecedented October 7 attack which resulted in the deaths of 1,197 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.</p>

<p>Operatives also seized 251 hostages, 111 of whom are still held captive in Gaza, including 39 the military says are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's campaign against Hamas has killed at least 39,583 people in Gaza, according to the territory's health ministry, which does not give details of civilian and operative deaths.</p>

<p>Haniyeh, Hamas's political chief, was the group's lead negotiator in efforts to end the war.</p>

<p>His killing raised questions about the continued viability of efforts by Qatari, Egyptian and US mediators to broker a truce and exchange of hostages and prisoners.</p>

<p>On the ground in Gaza, fighting continued on Sunday, with strikes, shelling and gunfire reported in and around Gaza City and in the territory's south.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said its air forces had struck "approximately 50 terror targets throughout the Gaza Strip" in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Red Crescent said eight bodies had been recovered from a residential building in north Gaza's Jabalia refugee camp after an Israeli air strike.</p>

<p>Medics at central Gaza's Al-Aqsa Martyrs hospital said at least five people were killed and 16 wounded in an Israeli drone strike on tents housing displaced Palestinians at the medical complex, with a separate attack on a house nearby in the same area killing three.</p>

<p>On Saturday, an Israeli strike on a school turned displacement shelter killed at least 17 people, the civil defence agency said. Israel said the facility was used by operatives.</p>

<p><strong>War 'without constraints'</strong></p>

<p>Analysts have told AFP that a joint but measured action from Iran and its allies was likely, while Tehran said it expects Hezbollah to hit deeper inside Israel and no longer be confined to military targets.</p>

<p>Israeli ally the United States said it would move warships and fighter jets to the region.</p>

<p>US President Joe Biden, asked by reporters if he thought Iran would stand down, said: "I hope so. I don't know."</p>

<p>Jordanian Foreign Minister Ayman Safadi was due in Tehran for a rare visit to discuss "the situation in the region", Amman said.</p>

<p>The Israeli military was "determined to continue fighting until we fundamentally change the security situation in the north", said Home Front Command chief Rafi Gilo.</p>

<p>"We... are prepared for any scenario and any response", Gilo said according to an army statement.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's killing "has brought the Middle East to its moment of greatest peril in years", the International Crisis Group (ICG) think tank said in a report issued on Saturday.</p>

<p>The potential for a miscalculation that would trigger a war "without constraints... is likely greater now than it was in April", it added.</p>

<p>On April 13, Iran fired a barrage of drones and missiles at Israel -- most of which were intercepted -- after a deadly strike on Tehran's consulate in Damascus.</p>

<p>The ICG said that securing "a long overdue ceasefire" in Gaza was "the best way of meaningfully reducing tensions in the region".</p>

<p>Hamas officials but also some analysts as well as protesters in Israel have accused Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu of prolonging the war to safeguard his ruling hard-right coalition.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Netanyahu told his cabinet he was "making every effort" to return the hostages and was prepared "to go a long way" to do so.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t3sveco8_lebanon-airport_625x300_03_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The United States and Britain have also issued warnings. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-warned-benjamin-netanyahu-in-heated-phone-call-stop-bulls-ting-6261171]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Stop Bulls***ting," Biden Warned Netanyahu In Heated Phone Call: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-warned-benjamin-netanyahu-in-heated-phone-call-stop-bulls-ting-6261171]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 16:26:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden reportedly told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to "stop bulls***ting me" during a tense phone conversation on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">US President Joe Biden reportedly told Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to “stop bulls***ting me” during a tense phone conversation on Thursday.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The sharp exchange came after Mr Netanyahu informed Joe Biden that Israel was proceeding with negotiations on a hostages-for-ceasefire deal with Hamas, despite months of unfruitful talks. Biden has previously expressed suspicions that Netanyahu has been intentionally stalling for internal political reasons, <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/stop-bullshitting-me-biden-said-to-scold-netanyahu-in-call-on-truce-hostage-deal/ ">Channel 12</a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">At the end of the call, Mr Biden added a stern warning, “Don't take the president for granted.” Joe Biden also reportedly criticised the timing of the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh in Iran, calling it “poorly timed.”&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The US President reportedly was concerned that the operation jeopardised the potential culmination of ceasefire and hostage release negotiations, the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/03/us/politics/us-israel-hamas-assassination.html ">NY Times</a> reported. An unnamed US official indicated that Biden warned the assassination could lead to a broader regional conflict which Biden had been putting efforts to prevent.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Netanyahu's office issued a<a href="http:// https://www.timesofisrael.com/stop-bullshitting-me-biden-said-to-scold-netanyahu-in-call-on-truce-hostage-deal/ "> statement</a> on Saturday night that said that “Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu does not discuss what was said in closed conversations with the President of the US.”&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Tensions in the Middle East have surged to a boiling point following the recent killings of senior Hezbollah leader Faud Shukr and Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh. Iran-backed Hezbollah retaliated by launching dozens of rockets at northern Israel on Sunday, with some breaching defenses in the Beit Hillel region.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">A clip shared on X shows Israel's Iron Dome batteries firing multiple Tamir interceptors at Hezbollah rockets targeting the Jewish State.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">An amazing clip from earlier tonight when Israel's Iron Dome batteries fired multiple Tamir interceptors at Hezbollah rockets targeting northern Israel. <a href="https://t.co/lcbIH9shwM">pic.twitter.com/lcbIH9shwM</a></p>
— Joe Truzman (@JoeTruzman) <a href="https://twitter.com/JoeTruzman/status/1819901637890326699?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>US defense officials have arrived in Israel, bracing for potential retaliation from Iran and its allies. The Pentagon has bolstered its regional military presence in anticipation of further escalation.</p>

<p>Israel has neither confirmed nor denied involvement in the killings, which have sparked fears of a coordinated attack by Iran and Hezbollah. Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu has warned of "challenging days ahead" and vowed to be "prepared for any scenario."&nbsp;US President Biden hopes Iran will stand down despite its threats.</p>

<p>Meanwhile the Indian Embassy in Beirut has advised Indian nationals against travelling to or staying in Lebanon until further notice.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/r1f2pcco_biden-netanyahu-_625x300_05_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden also reportedly criticised the timing of the killing of Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh(FILE)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-killed-in-bangladesh-in-fresh-clashes-between-protesters-and-ruling-party-supporters-centre-asks-indians-to-stay-alert-6261104]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[91 Killed In Bangladesh Clashes, Centre Asks Indians To "Be In Touch"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/18-killed-in-bangladesh-in-fresh-clashes-between-protesters-and-ruling-party-supporters-centre-asks-indians-to-stay-alert-6261104]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 16:11:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has asked its citizens living in Bangladesh to be in touch and remain alert after 91 people died in fresh clashes between protesters and supporters of the ruling Awami League. Dozens were also injured in fierce clashes today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>"All Indian nationals including students living in the jurisdiction of the Assistant High Commission of India, Sylhet are requested to be in touch with this office and are advised to remain alert. In case of emergencies, please contact +88-01313076402," the Assistant High Commission said in a post on X.</li>
	<li>The protests over government jobs quota restarted today with demands for Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's resignation. Fourteen policemen were among those killed, news agency AFP reported.</li>
	<li>Just days ago, over 200 people were killed in violent clashes between the police and mostly student protesters demanding an end to the controversial quota system that reserved 30 per cent of government jobs for relatives of veterans who fought in Bangladesh's War of Independence in 1971.</li>
	<li>The clashes broke out this morning when protesters attending a non-cooperation programme to demand the government's resignation faced opposition from the supporters of the Awami League, Chhatra League, and Jubo League activists, news agency PTI reported.</li>
	<li>The Bangladesh Home Ministry decided to impose an indefinite countrywide curfew from 6 pm today. Prime Minister Hasina said that those engaging in sabotage across Bangladesh in the name of protests are not students but terrorists and asked people to suppress them with a firm hand.</li>
	<li>Ms Hasina called a meeting of the National Committee on Security Affairs at Ganabhaban. "I appeal to the countrymen to suppress these terrorists with a firm hand," she said. The meeting was attended by the chiefs of the army, navy, air force, police and other agencies.</li>
	<li>In Rangpur, four Awami League supporters were killed and over 100 people injured while two people were killed each in Bogra and Magura, where a Chhatra Dal leader was among the dead, local media reported,</li>
	<li>The protesters under the banner of the Anti-Discrimination Students Movement chanted slogans calling for Ms Hasina's resignation and justice for those killed in the recent violence surrounding the quota reform protests, Bdnews24 news portal reported.</li>
	<li>According to the Daily Star newspaper, several vehicles at Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University (BSMMU) were torched on Sunday by unidentified people. People carrying sticks were seen vandalising cars, ambulances, motorcycles, and buses.</li>
	<li>The protesters have dismissed Ms Hasina's invitation for dialogue aimed at quelling escalating violence and consolidated their demands into a unified call for the government's resignation.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>With inputs from PTI</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/hkmffbl8_bangladesh_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fresh protests began today over a controversial quota in Bangladesh]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-asks-its-nationals-to-remain-alert-in-bangladesh-as-student-protests-resume-6260752]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Be In Touch, Stay Alert: Centre To Indians In Bangladesh Amid New Protests]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-asks-its-nationals-to-remain-alert-in-bangladesh-as-student-protests-resume-6260752]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 15:08:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian Embassy in Bangladesh on Sunday issued an advisory urging Indian nationals residing in the country to "remain alert" as the student protests resumed in Sylhet, in which an unspecified number of people have got injured.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Indian Embassy in Bangladesh on Sunday issued an advisory urging Indian nationals residing in the country to "remain alert" as the student protests resumed in Sylhet, in which an unspecified number of people have got injured.</p>

<p>One of the protesters was hit by a bullet amid the clashes and was immediately taken to the hospital, local media reported.</p>

<p>"All Indian nationals including students living in the jurisdiction of Assistant High Commission of India, Sylhet are requested to be in touch with this office &amp; are advised to remain alert," the Assistant High Commission of India (AHCI) said in a post on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Advisory:<br />
<br />
All Indian nationals including students living in the jurisdiction of Assistant High Commission of India , Sylhet are requested to be in touch with this office &amp; are advised to remain alert.<br />
<br />
In case of emergencies,please contact +88-01313076402<a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MEAIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/ihcdhaka?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@ihcdhaka</a></p>
— India in Sylhet (@ahcisylhet) <a href="https://twitter.com/ahcisylhet/status/1820011209736741172?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>A helpline number was also shared for emergencies.</p>

<p>The AHCI is a representative office of the Government of India in Sylhet and is responsible for the issuance of visas and the welfare of Indian nationals in its Consular jurisdiction (Districts of Sylhet, Moulvibazar, Sunamganj, Habiganj, Kishoreganj &amp; Netorokona), promotion of bilateral trade, culture etc.</p>

<p>AHCI functions under the general supervision of the High Commission of India, Dhaka.</p>

<p>The advisory followed after the protestors assembled around the Court Point area of Sylhet at around 11 a.m. to demonstrate against the reservation quota for the families of veterans, local media reported.</p>

<p>In order to disperse the protesters, police fired tear gas shells and sound grenades, which triggered the clash between the students and the personnel.</p>

<p>The police have not yet commented on the incident.</p>

<p>Outraged by the high unemployment rate in the country, students in Bangladesh have been protesting to quash the 30 per cent reservation quota for the families of veterans of the 1971 Independence War.</p>

<p>The quota system in government jobs was scrapped in 2018 after a major student movement but was reinstated by a court in June.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8c86snag_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A helpline number was also shared for emergencies (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-dead-in-israel-stabbing-palestinian-attacker-from-west-bank-killed-6260739]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[2 Dead In Israel Stabbing, Palestinian Attacker From West Bank Killed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/2-dead-in-israel-stabbing-palestinian-attacker-from-west-bank-killed-6260739]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 15:05:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Two people were killed Sunday and two others wounded in a stabbing attack near Tel Aviv, Israeli medics said, with police reporting a Palestinian suspect was "neutralised" and later died in hospital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two people were killed Sunday and two others wounded in a stabbing attack near Tel Aviv, Israeli medics said, with police reporting a Palestinian suspect was "neutralised" and later died in hospital.</p>

<p>The Magen David Adom emergency service said in a statement that the "terrorist attack" took place in several locations in Holon, a southern suburb of Israel's commercial hub of Tel Aviv.</p>

<p>It comes at a moment of heightened tension in Israel and the wider Middle East, nearly 10 months into the Israel-Hamas war in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>The stabbing suspect, from the Israeli-occupied West Bank, was "neutralised" by a police officer who arrived at the scene, the force said in a statement without elaborating.</p>

<p>The Shamir Medical Centre said the assailant was pronounced dead shortly after being taken to the hospital near Holon in a critical condition.</p>

<p>A 66-year-old woman and a man aged around 80 were badly wounded and died from their injuries shortly after the attack, the Wolfson hospital in the city said.</p>

<p>Israeli news website Ynet said the pair, whose ages Magen David Adom earlier gave as 70, were married.</p>

<p>Two other men were wounded, the emergency service said.</p>

<p>A 68-year-old was in serious condition and a 26-year-old was moderately wounded.</p>

<p>"This was a complex and difficult terrorist attack, with the victims located in three different places, around 500 metres (yards) from each other," Magen David Adom said.</p>

<p>Regional tensions have soared as Iran and Middle East armed groups it backs threatened retaliation for the assassination of Hamas political chief Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran on Wednesday, which they blame on Israel, and an Israeli strike in Beirut hours earlier that killed top Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr.</p>

<p>Israel's National Security Minister Itamar Ben-Gvir visited the scene of Sunday's attack, where he told journalists: "Our war is not only against Iran, but also here in the streets".</p>

<p>"This is why we have armed the Israeli population with more than 150,000 gun permits," said the far-right politician who has loosened gun laws and repeatedly called on ordinary Israelis to carry arms.</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/rh6748ho_tel-aviv-stabbing-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A 68-year-old was in serious condition and a 26-year-old was moderately wounded.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protesters-demand-pms-resignation-army-by-the-people-6260677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Protesters Demand PM's Resignation, Army "By The People"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protesters-demand-pms-resignation-army-by-the-people-6260677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 04 Aug 2024 14:51:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of Bangladeshi protesters, many wielding sticks, crowded into a central Dhaka square Sunday for mass protests demanding Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resign following a deadly police crackdown.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of Bangladeshi protesters, many wielding sticks, crowded into a central Dhaka square Sunday for mass protests demanding Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina resign following a deadly police crackdown.</p>

<p>Asif Mahmud, one of the key protest leaders in a nationwide civil disobedience campaign, asked supporters to be ready to fight.</p>

<p>"Prepare bamboo sticks and liberate Bangladesh," he wrote on Facebook on Sunday.</p>

<p>While the army stepped in to help restore order in the wake of earlier protests, some former military officers have since joined the student movement, and ex-army chief General Ikbal Karim Bhuiyan turned his Facebook profile picture red in a show of support.</p>

<p>Current army chief Waker-uz-Zaman spoke to officers at military headquarters in Dhaka on Saturday, telling them the "Bangladesh Army is the symbol of trust of the people".</p>

<p>"It always stood by the people and will do so for the sake of people and in any need of the state," he said, according to an army statement issued late Saturday.</p>

<p>The statement did not give further details, and did not explicitly say whether the army backed the protests.</p>

<p>Rallies against civil service job quotas sparked days of mayhem in July that killed more than 200 people in some of the worst unrest of Hasina's 15-year tenure.</p>

<p>Troops briefly restored order but crowds returned to the streets in huge numbers this week in an all-out non-cooperation movement aimed at paralysing the government.</p>

<p>On Saturday, when hundreds of thousands of protesters marched in Dhaka, the police were largely bystanders watching the rallies.</p>

<p>'Live freely'</p>

<p>The protests have grown into a wider anti-government movement across the South Asian nation of some 170 million people.</p>

<p>The mass movement includes people from all strata of Bangladesh society, including film stars, musicians and singers, and rap songs calling for people's support have spread widely on social media.</p>

<p>"It is no longer about job quotas," said Sakhawat, a young female protester who gave only one name, as she scrawled graffiti on a wall at a protest site in Dhaka calling Hasina a "killer".</p>

<p>"What we want is that our next generation can live freely in the country."</p>

<p>Counter-protests supporting the government are also expected.</p>

<p>Obaidul Quader, general secretary of Hasina's ruling Awami League, has called on party activists to gather in "all wards in Dhaka city" and "in every district" nationwide to show their support for the government.</p>

<p>"We don't want to engage in any kind of confrontation," Quader said.</p>

<p>The capital Dhaka was tense on Sunday, with fewer cars and buses on the normally congested streets of the megacity of 20 million people.</p>

<p>Hundreds of thousands of protesters are expected to rally in Dhaka and nationwide.</p>

<p>'Take all preparations'</p>

<p>Students Against Discrimination, the group responsible for organising the initial protests, called for rallies across the country.</p>

<p>Protests will be held at entry points to Dhaka, with the main rallies held in Dhaka's central Shahbagh Square, where crowds gathered on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>"We will hold our protests and rallies peacefully," the group said in a statement late Saturday. "But if anyone attacks us, we urge (all) to take all preparations."</p>

<p>Students Against Discrimination have asked their compatriots to stop paying taxes and utility bills from Sunday to pile pressure on the government.</p>

<p>They have also asked government workers and labourers in the country's economically vital garment factories to strike.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, has ruled Bangladesh since 2009 and won her fourth consecutive election in January after a vote without genuine opposition.</p>

<p>Her government is accused by rights groups of misusing state institutions to entrench its hold on power and stamp out dissent, including through the extrajudicial killing of opposition activists.</p>

<p>Demonstrations began in early July over the reintroduction of the quota scheme, which reserved more than half of all government jobs for certain groups. It has since been scaled back by Bangladesh's top court.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8c86snag_bangladesh-protests-afp-_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rallies against civil service job quotas sparked days of mayhem in July.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>