<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:09:20 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-this-florida-couple-stole-peoples-properties-using-just-a-dollar-6836406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How This Florida Couple Stole People's Properties Using Just A Dollar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-this-florida-couple-stole-peoples-properties-using-just-a-dollar-6836406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:09:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Florida couple is facing charges of stealing properties through a simple scam that costs less than a dollar to execute]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida couple is facing charges of stealing properties through a simple scam that costs less than a dollar to execute. Victor Rodriguez, 50, and his wife Michelle Cherry, 33, allegedly forged “quitclaim deeds” to illegally transfer ownership of homes, including a property owned by Rodriguez's ex-father-in-law, in Tampa and Miami-Dade County, <a href="https://www.fox13news.com/news/property-fraud-investigation-extends-from-bay-area-south-florida-court-documents ">Fox News</a> reported.</p>

<p>Caroline Sauer, Rodriguez's ex-wife, discovered the scam when she found that her father's properties had changed ownership through quitclaim deeds. “We questioned, how did this happen?” Ms Sauer said. “Who forges a deceased person's signature? Who does that?”</p>

<p>According to authorities, the scam involved forging signatures on quitclaim deeds – a legal document that transfers property ownership with the owner's consent. These documents, however, can be easily manipulated. Fraudsters only need a notary and two signatures to process the transaction, often for as little as 70 cents in Florida.</p>

<p>Rodriguez and Cherry allegedly used the same scam on another Tampa property belonging to Larry and Dreama Bilby. The Bilbys were stunned when they learned in February that someone forged their signatures and transferred ownership of their home, which was unoccupied and under construction at the time.</p>

<p>“I was so angry, I almost couldn't talk,” Dreama Bilby told Fox13.</p>

<p>Hillsborough County Clerk Cindy Stuart explained how easy it was to commit the fraud. “It only requires a notary and two signatures with an address listed next to them,” she said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Caroline Sauer and her family are battling her ex-husband in court. “The hardest thing for us emotionally has been, we've just tried to protect my father and his legacy,” she told the outlet.</p>

<p>To prove the forgery, Ms Sauer's family hired a handwriting expert and incurred significant legal fees.</p>

<p>Rodriguez and Cherry were arrested in March and pleaded not guilty. Rodriguez's legal team maintains his innocence. “Mr. Rodriguez maintains his innocence, and our office is entrusted with the responsibility of protecting his rights,” his lawyers said in a statement, adding that they are committed to ensuring “justice and fairness in legal proceedings.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/mts5qgco_canada-house-generic-_625x300_04_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The couple was arrested in March and pleaded not guilty.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-lidia-thorpe-give-our-land-back-says-lawmaker-to-king-charles-at-australian-parliament-6836254]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Give Our Land Back": Australian Lawmaker Heckles King Charles At Parliament]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/king-charles-lidia-thorpe-give-our-land-back-says-lawmaker-to-king-charles-at-australian-parliament-6836254]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 09:23:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indigenous senator Lidia Thorpe, known for her fierce opposition to the monarchy, shouted anti-colonial slogans at King Charles during his visit to the Australian parliament on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indigenous senator Lidia Thorpe shouted anti-colonial slogans at King Charles during his visit to the Australian parliament on Monday, shocking assembled lawmakers and other dignitaries.</p>

<p>"Give us our land back! Give us what you stole from us!" Thorpe screamed in an almost minute-long diatribe, after the 75-year-old king's speech.</p>

<p>"This is not your land, you are not my king," the independent lawmaker said, decrying what she described as a "genocide" of Indigenous Australians by European settlers.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Not the reception King Charles was hoping for in Australia as he receives an almighty heckling<br />
“Give us our land back. Give us what you stole from us.”? <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AlwaysWasAlwaysWillbe?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AlwaysWasAlwaysWillbe</a> <a href="https://t.co/JEYJ5Y7BEd">pic.twitter.com/JEYJ5Y7BEd</a></p>
— stranger (@strangerous10) <a href="https://twitter.com/strangerous10/status/1848203654060290438?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 21, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Australia was a British colony for more than 100 years, during which time thousands of Aboriginal Australians were killed and entire communities displaced.</p>

<p>The country gained de facto independence in 1901, but has never become a fully fledged republic. King Charles is the current head of state.</p>

<p>Charles is on a nine-day jaunt through Australia and Samoa, the first major foreign tour since his life-changing cancer diagnosis earlier this year.</p>

<p>Thorpe is known for her attention-grabbing political stunts and fierce opposition to the monarchy.</p>

<p>When she was sworn into office in 2022, Thorpe raised her right fist as she begrudgingly swore to serve Queen Elisabeth II, who was then Australia's head of state.</p>

<p>"I sovereign, Lidia Thorpe, do solemnly and sincerely swear that I will be faithful and I bear true allegiance to the colonising Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II," she said before being rebuked by a Senate official.</p>

<p>"Senator Thorpe, Senator Thorpe, you are required to recite the oath as printed on the card," said the chamber's president Sue Lines.</p>

<p>In 1999, Australians narrowly voted against removing the queen, amid a row over whether her replacement would be chosen by members of parliament, not the public.</p>

<p>In 2023 Australians overwhelmingly rejected measures to recognise Indigenous Australians in the constitution and to create an Indigenous consultative assembly.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/486o395o_king-charles-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles is on a nine-day jaunt through Australia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/looking-forward-to-addressing-ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-6836251]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Looking Forward To Addressing NDTV World Summit": PM Modi]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/looking-forward-to-addressing-ndtv-world-summit-pm-modi-6836251]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 09:22:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Sunday that he is looking forward to addressing the 'NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century' which will take place today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi said on Sunday that he is looking forward to addressing the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://special.ndtv.com/ndtv-world-summit-2024-167/">'NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century' </a>which will take place today.</p>

<p>"At 10 AM tomorrow morning, I look forward to addressing the #NDTVWorldSummit on 'The India Century.' India's growth trajectory has truly captured global attention. Our Yuva Shakti is taking our nation to new heights. I will be talking about India's key strides and why we remain a global bright spot," the Prime Minister wrote on X.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">At 10 AM tomorrow morning, I look forward to addressing the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NDTVWorldSummit?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#NDTVWorldSummit</a> on ‘The India Century.' India's growth trajectory has truly captured global attention. Our Yuva Shakti is taking our nation to new heights. I will be talking about India's key strides and why we remain a…</p>
— Narendra Modi (@narendramodi) <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi/status/1848042562214355194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The two-day NDTV World Summit will see PM Modi speak on his vision for a developed India by 2047.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The "NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century" will also feature former UK Prime Minister David Cameron and External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, among a host of other dignitaries, to discuss key global issues.</p>

<p>The NDTV World Summit will also see the participation of Tshering Tobgay, Prime Minister of Bhutan; Mia Mottley, Prime Minister of Barbados; Prof. Paul Romer, Nobel Laureate, Economics, 2018 &amp; Former Chief Economist, World Bank and William Dalrymple, Author &amp; Historian.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ui2un49o_narendra-modi-pti-modi-namaste-pti_625x300_23_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The NDTV World Summit is a two-day meet scheduled for October 21 and 22.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-hamas-israel-cash-cologne-private-shower-inside-ex-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwars-bunker-6836007]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash, Cologne, Private Shower: Inside Ex Hamas Chief Yahya Sinwar's Bunker]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-hamas-israel-cash-cologne-private-shower-inside-ex-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwars-bunker-6836007]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 08:27:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military has released footage of what it claims to be the bunker of ex Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, which he occupied during the first half of the ongoing Gaza conflict.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military has released footage of what it claims to be the bunker of ex Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, which he occupied during the first half of the ongoing Gaza conflict. Sinwar, known as the mastermind behind the brutal October 7 attacks, was allegedly prepared to ride out the war with a stash of cash, cologne, and personal comforts in a fully-stocked bunker under the ravaged city of Khan Younis.</p>

<p>The Israeli Defense Forces (IDF) shared video footage that details the inside of Sinwar's underground hideout. The video shows a well-equipped bunker, complete with modern showers, several bathrooms, and a fully functional kitchen, stocked with food rations labelled with the United Nations Palestinian Refugee Agency (UNRWA) logo.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sinwar, 61, had taken refuge in the bunker with his guards and close associates as the war above ground escalated. The footage shows a bag of UNRWA-supplied food, reinforcing Israel's longstanding accusation that Hamas steals from international agencies, exacerbating the already dire humanitarian crisis in Gaza.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The IDF has released footage showing their entry into Sinwar's bunker, where UNWRA bags and millions of shekels were found.<br />
<br />
Sinwar and other Hamas leaders have been siphoning billions from the people of Gaza, allegedly with <a href="https://twitter.com/UNWRA?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@UNWRA</a>'s involvement.<br />
<br />
<a href="https://t.co/ZRcr5UWKmF">pic.twitter.com/ZRcr5UWKmF</a></p>
— David Saranga (@DavidSaranga) <a href="https://twitter.com/DavidSaranga/status/1847915812285284355?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The bunker contained multiple bottles of cologne, hygiene supplies, and even a private shower. According to an IDF soldier giving the tour of the bunker, Sinwar's personal quarters included a large safe filled with millions of Israeli shekels.</p>

<p>Next to the door of the bunker, soldiers found lockers filled with a cache of weapons, ammunition, and explosives.</p>

<p>Sinwar had fled the bunker before the IDF could capture him. Reports suggest that Sinwar initially stayed in Khan Younis before being forced to flee further south to Rafah as the Israeli military closed in on his position. It was in Rafah, where Sinwar's luck finally ran out. Last Thursday, Israeli soldiers killed him in a strike during what they described as a "routine operation". The IDF initially believed they had encountered just another Hamas fighter before later identifying Sinwar as one of the casualties.</p>

<p>According to Israeli sources, Sinwar had spent much of the war hiding underground, directing Hamas operations and attempting to evade capture. Sinwar's wife, Abu Zamar, was reportedly carrying a Rs 28 lakh ($32,000) Hermes Birkin bag during their escape.</p>

<p>After months of searching, Sinwar's fate was sealed when an IDF patrol stumbled upon him in Rafah. Sinwar, cornered and injured in a demolished building, was caught on drone footage in his final moments. The video showed Sinwar, covered in dust and with one hand severely injured, hurling an object-believed to be a stick-at an approaching Israeli drone.</p>

<p>An Israeli autopsy confirmed that Sinwar died from a gunshot wound to the head.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/sfcs6dp8_yahya-sinwar-bunker-_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bunker contained multiple bottles of cologne, hygiene supplies, and even a private shower.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-india-century-live-updates-pm-narendra-modi-david-cameron-s-jaishankar-to-speak-6830644]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: PM Modi Speaks At NDTV World Summit On 'The India Century']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-world-summit-2024-india-century-live-updates-pm-narendra-modi-david-cameron-s-jaishankar-to-speak-6830644]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:38:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bhutan Prime Minister Dasho Tshering Tobgay, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, and Airtel Chairperson Sunil Bharti will also speak at the two-day event.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NDTV proudly presents its flagship event, NDTV World Summit 2024 - The India Century, where Prime Minister Narendra Modi will speak in the inaugural session, followed by former UK PM David Cameron and other global leaders.</p>

<p>Bhutan Prime Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-my-mentor-my-guru-bhutan-pm-tshering-tobgay-to-ndtv-5862175" target="_blank">Dasho Tshering Tobgay</a>, External Affairs Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankars-huddle-with-indian-diplomats-in-pak-includes-a-morning-walk-planting-a-tree-6805874" target="_blank">S Jaishankar</a>, Bharti Airtel Chairperson Sunil Bharti Mittal, Actors Shraddha Kapoor and Kareena Kapoor Khan will also be among the guests who will speak during the two-day event.</p>

<p>Ahead of the Summit, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/odisha-tribal-woman-sends-pm-modi-rs-100-to-convey-thanks-he-responds-6829354" target="_blank">PM Modi</a> said he will be talking about "India's key strides and why we remain a global bright spot".</p>

<p>"I look forward to addressing the NDTV World Summit on ‘The India Century.' India's growth trajectory has truly captured global attention. Our Yuva Shakti is taking our nation to new heights," he posted on X.</p>

<p>Continuing NDTV's legacy of pioneering media, we will also launch NDTV World at the Summit, with the tagline: "The World From Where India Stands."</p>

<h2><strong>Here are the live updates on NDTV World Summit 2024:</strong></h2>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/lqertino_ndtv-world-summit_625x300_21_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NDTV is hosting a two-day World Summit 2024 - The India Century]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luiz-inacio-lula-da-silva-brazil-president-cancels-russia-brics-trip-after-minor-brain-hemorrhage-from-fall-in-bathroom-6835794]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Brazil President Cancels BRICS Trip After Minor Brain Hemorrhage From Fall]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/luiz-inacio-lula-da-silva-brazil-president-cancels-russia-brics-trip-after-minor-brain-hemorrhage-from-fall-in-bathroom-6835794]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:22:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Brazilian PresidentLuizInacioLuladaSilva, 78, will now participate in the BRICS meeting in Russia via videoconference.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian President&nbsp;Luiz&nbsp;Inacio&nbsp;Lula&nbsp;da&nbsp;Silva&nbsp;on Sunday canceled his trip to Russia for the BRICS summit, following medical advice to temporarily avoid long-haul flights after a head injury at home that caused a minor brain hemorrhage. In a statement, the presidential office said&nbsp;Lula, 78, will now participate in the BRICS meeting via videoconference. He was initially scheduled to depart at 5 p.m. on Sunday.</p>

<p>Lula's doctor, Roberto Kalil, said in an interview with GloboNews TV channel that the president suffered a fall that caused "great" trauma to the back of his head, requiring stitches for the injury and resulting in a "small brain hemorrhage" in the temporal-frontal region.</p>

<p>"It's a condition that will require repeat tests throughout the week. Any brain hemorrhage, theoretically, can worsen in the following&nbsp;days, so observation is important," he said.</p>

<p>Kalil added that&nbsp;Lula&nbsp;is doing well and can engage in normal activities.</p>

<p>According to a medical report issued earlier on Sunday by the Sirio Libanes Hospital in Brasilia,&nbsp;Lula&nbsp;suffered a laceration to the "occipital region" in the back of his head on Saturday.</p>

<p>The report said&nbsp;Lula&nbsp;"was advised to avoid long-distance air travel but is otherwise able to carry out his regular duties."</p>

<p>The government said in a post on X that Foreign Minister Mauro Vieira has been designated to lead the Brazilian delegation in the BRICS summit, departing later on Sunday.</p>

<p>The diplomatic forum founded 15 years ago by major emerging markets Brazil, Russia, India, China has since expanding to include South Africa, Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran and the United Arab Emirates.</p>

<p>Congresswoman Gleisi Hoffmann, president of&nbsp;Lula's Workers Party, posted on social media that she had spoken with the president and that "he is doing very well, just avoiding a long trip."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/t5k2u19o_luizinacioluladasilva_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Lula's doctor said he is doing well and can engage in normal activities (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-yahya-sinwars-wife-spotted-with-rs-26-lakh-hermes-birkin-bag-in-gaza-tunnel-6835729]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Yahya Sinwar's Wife Spotted With 26-Lakh Hermes Bag In Gaza Tunnel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-yahya-sinwars-wife-spotted-with-rs-26-lakh-hermes-birkin-bag-in-gaza-tunnel-6835729]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 07:05:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed in an Israeli operation in southern Gaza last week, was seen moving inside a tunnel with his wife and children, hours before the deadly October 7 attack on Israel last year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former Hamas chief Yahya Sinwar, who was killed in an Israeli operation in southern Gaza last week, was seen moving inside a tunnel with his wife and children, hours before the deadly October 7 attack on Israel last year. The now-dead Hamas leader was carrying pillows, mattresses, television, and bags inside the tunnel located under their family in Khan Younis, a CCTV footage showed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Meanwhile, his wife was seen carrying a Hermes bag, which Israel claims is worth $32,000.</p>

<p>Israel said, "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-yahya-sinwar-the-hamas-leader-killed-by-israel-6819037">Yahya Sinwar</a>'s wife was caught sneaking to the tunnels the night before the October 7 attack," claiming she was carrying a Hermes Birkin bag worth $32,000 (Rs 26.88 lakh).&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sinwar's wife caught in this photo sneaking to the tunnels the night before October 7th - get this - clutching a $32,000 Hermes Birkin bag!<br />
<br />
While Gazans endured hardship under Hamas, Sinwar and his family were shamelessly living in luxury, indulging while sending others to die. <a href="https://t.co/Q9fTqhqxo8">pic.twitter.com/Q9fTqhqxo8</a></p>
— Israel ישראל (@Israel) <a href="https://twitter.com/Israel/status/1847835520216252872?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"While Gazans endured hardship under Hamas, Sinwar and his family were shamelessly living in luxury, indulging while sending others to die," Israel said.</p>

<p>Israel shared a screengrab from the video, where Sinwar's wife holds a bag. In the hazy picture, the design on the bag 'appears to be similar' to the Hermes Birkin 40 Black Togo Gold Hardware edition. The Palestinian militant group is yet to contest Israel's claim.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-releases-footage-showing-yahya-sinwar-hours-ahead-of-hamas-oct-7-attack-6829387">The footage was released</a> following Sinwar's death in the southern Gaza city of Rafah, in an armour-infantry assault. Israel's 828th Brigade conducted "intelligence-based targeted raids and operations," the Israel Defence Forces said, giving details of the damage assessment, where they found assault rifles and snipers in the hideout and Sinwar's body.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">?DECLASSIFIED FOOTAGE:<br />
<br />
Sinwar hours before the October 7 massacre: taking down his TV into his tunnel, hiding underneath his civilians, and preparing to watch his terrorists murder, kindap and rape. <a href="https://t.co/wTAF9xAPLU">pic.twitter.com/wTAF9xAPLU</a></p>
— LTC Nadav Shoshani (@LTC_Shoshani) <a href="https://twitter.com/LTC_Shoshani/status/1847704609156190441?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 19, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Israeli army spokesman Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari showed photos of the underground compound with toilets, showers, and a kitchen. Food, cash, and documents were also found there.</p>

<p>Hamas, meanwhile, said Sinwar died heroically engaging in battle, calling Hagar's remarks "blatant lies".</p>

<p>Drone footage from earlier this week showed Sinwar critically wounded in his last moments, throwing an object at the drone. The autopsy found that Sinwar was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bullet-in-head-finger-cut-off-chilling-details-of-yahya-sinwars-autopsy-6822817">killed by a gunshot to the head</a>, and also found one of his fingers was cut off.</p>

<p>During a year of the Israel-Hamas conflict, the Israel Defence Forces had often closed in on Sinwar, but the latter managed to escape. Israel had identified Sinwar's final hiding after the military found "his DNA sample on a tissue with which he blew his nose," said Hagari.</p>

<p>Yahya Sinwar was the mastermind of the October 7, 2023 attack on Israel in which over 1,200 people were killed, resulting in a year-long Israeli operation in Gaza, killing over 40,000 including children.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/9pkgv86_yahya-sinwar-wife-hermes-bag_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel shared a screengrab from the video, where Sinwar's wife holds a bag.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-turns-chef-at-mcdonalds-ahead-of-us-presidential-elections-2024-says-worked-more-than-kamala-harris-6835696]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Donald Trump Makes Fries At McDonald's, Then A Jibe At Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-turns-chef-at-mcdonalds-ahead-of-us-presidential-elections-2024-says-worked-more-than-kamala-harris-6835696]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 21 Oct 2024 06:58:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican Donald Trump on Sunday visited a McDonald's and served french fries while he was campaigning in Pennsylvania ahead of the US presidential elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican Donald Trump on Sunday visited a McDonald's and served french fries while he was campaigning in Pennsylvania ahead of the US presidential elections.</p>

<p>The 78-year-old former president, who is tied in the race to the White House with his Democrat rival <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-now-60-questions-78-year-old-donald-trumps-fitness-to-be-us-president-6834417" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a>, wore a black-and-yellow apron over his white shirt and red tie and was seen dipping wire baskets of potatoes in sizzling oil before salting them.&nbsp;</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-obama-harris-trump-you-would-be-worried-if-barack-obamas-grandpa-jibe-at-donald-trump-6831233" target="_blank">Trump</a> was then seen handing fries out to some of his supporters through the drive-through window of the McDonald's franchise outside of Philadelphia.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Fries: BAGGED ✅ <a href="https://t.co/oj3T5KSazz">pic.twitter.com/oj3T5KSazz</a></p>
— Trump War Room (@TrumpWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1848063436455833969?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">It's called we do a little serving <a href="https://t.co/NuHjN0AdVo">pic.twitter.com/NuHjN0AdVo</a></p>
— Trump War Room (@TrumpWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1848091385519296556?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"I like this job," Trump said. "I'm having a lot of fun here."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I've always wanted to work at Mcdonald's," he said in a video posted on his official X (formerly Twitter) account.</p>

<p>The campaign stop was intended as a jibe at Harris, who has often talked about working at the fast-food chain in her youth.</p>

<p>Taking a swipe at Harris, who turned 60 on Sunday, he said he is running against somebody who said she worked at Mcdonald's, but it turned out to be a "phoney story".</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/MWEUVcY6YG">pic.twitter.com/MWEUVcY6YG</a></p>
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1848134050570969490?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"I've now worked for 15 minutes more than Kamala" at McDonald's, he said.</p>

<p>Told by reporters it was also Harris's birthday, Trump wished her well and said, "I think I'll get her some flowers."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Maybe I'll get her some fries," he quipped.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESIDENT TRUMP: "I've now worked for 15 minutes more than Kamala" at McDonald's ? <a href="https://t.co/RMeivIPPd0">pic.twitter.com/RMeivIPPd0</a></p>
— Trump War Room (@TrumpWarRoom) <a href="https://twitter.com/TrumpWarRoom/status/1848066228465619111?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>With the US presidential election just over two weeks away, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-turns-60-as-age-plays-key-role-in-2024-us-presidential-election-6830910" target="_blank">Trump and Harris</a> are spending their final campaign days in pivotal states.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/cpkrtl0g_trump-mcdonalds_625x300_21_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump worked at a McDonald's franchise outside of Philadelphia]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/once-bursting-with-life-beirut-now-lies-in-ruins-6834474]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Once Bursting With Life, Beirut Now Lies In Ruins]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/once-bursting-with-life-beirut-now-lies-in-ruins-6834474]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:55:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Just a month ago, south Beirut's bustling streets were packed with traffic, families strolling about and youths in cafes, but now silence dominates the abandoned Hezbollah bastion, interrupted only by the sound of Israeli bombs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just a month ago, south Beirut's bustling streets were packed with traffic, families strolling about and youths in cafes, but now silence dominates the abandoned Hezbollah bastion, interrupted only by the sound of Israeli bombs.</p>

<p>Escalating Israeli attacks since late September, after nearly a year of low-intensity cross-border exchanges, have reduced much of the Lebanese capital's once densely-packed southern suburbs to rubble and sent many of its residents fleeing.</p>

<p>Braving the smell of rotting flesh that reeks from razed buildings, a few young men stood guard, dressed in black civilian clothes and occasionally driving around the ruins on their motorbikes.</p>

<p>They observed the odd car and the handful of displaced residents who come on foot, hastily checking on their apartment or collecting some belongings before heading back to safety.</p>

<p>"The young people told me not to stay too long because drones were constantly flying over and could strike at any time," said 32-year-old Mohammed, on a brief visit home to get more clothes.</p>

<p>Giving his first name only for security concerns, he said he first left on September 27, days into Israel's intense air campaign on Lebanon.</p>

<p>That day, massive Israeli strikes killed Hezbollah's elusive leader Hassan Nasrallah in the heart of the Iran-backed group's south Beirut stronghold, toppling several apartment buildings and spreading fear of even greater violence.</p>

<p>"We left in a hurry and thought we would never see our house again," said Mohammed, adding that his neighbours had also fled.</p>

<p>The building was still standing, but many others have been damaged or destroyed.</p>

<p><strong>Attacks on infrastructure</strong></p>

<p>Cracks snaked down nearby buildings as torn-off asphalt and burst pipes leaked sewage and tap water.</p>

<p>Generators that long made up for daily power cuts after five years of economic crisis had also been blown to bits.</p>

<p>"About 320 buildings were destroyed in Beirut and its suburbs" in less than a month of war, Mona Fawaz of the Beirut Urban Lab told AFP.</p>

<p>The devastation has surpassed the damage caused by Israel's last war with Hezbollah in 2006, said Fawaz, who records cases of "urbicide", the destruction of cities in conflict, focusing now on Lebanon and the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>She accused Israel of "deliberate targeting of what allows life to continue," including vital infrastructure unrelated to Hezbollah.</p>

<p>Hezbollah had completely rebuilt Beirut's south based on the existing urban plans from before the 2006 war, which had displaced about 100,000 people from the area.</p>

<p>During that 33-day war, "surveys list 1,332 severely damaged multi-storey apartment buildings, of which 281 were completely razed to the ground" in an area of about 20 square kilometres (eight square miles), said Fawaz.</p>

<p>The Burj al-Barajneh neighbourhood, unscathed in 2006, has been heavily damaged in the bombardment this time around.</p>

<p><strong>Childhood memories</strong></p>

<p>Once again, families from south Beirut are forced to seek refuge elsewhere in the country or abroad.</p>

<p>Many live in rented apartments or with relatives, while others are crammed in schools-turned-shelters.</p>

<p>Hassan, 37, grew up in the Mraijeh district of Beirut's south, where Israeli jets targeted Hashem Safieddine, widely seen as Nasrallah's most likely successor.</p>

<p>Despite the bloodshed, he said Mraijeh will always remind him of his "friends, the games we used to play as children, the smell of freshly-baked bread in the morning, neighbours chatting and Ramadan festivities".</p>

<p>The supermarket he used to shop at is in ruins, with nearby shops, schools and buildings also reduced to rubble.</p>

<p>Hassan, who also asked to be identified by first name only, was told his favourite record store was no more.</p>

<p>As the war shows no signs of abating, greater losses are all but certain.</p>

<p>"We are afraid to return after the war only to discover how many of our friends have died, like in 2006," said Hassan with a sigh.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oisd6ts_beirut-reuters_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[As the war shows no signs of abating, greater losses are all but certain.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-wrecked-canada-india-ties-says-indian-envoy-6834429]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau Wrecked Canada-India Ties, Says Indian Envoy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/justin-trudeau-wrecked-canada-india-ties-says-indian-envoy-6834429]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:41:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian envoy to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma - now withdrawn by New Delhi -- has accused Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of wrecking bilateral ties with India and reiterated that Ottawa's allegations are politically motivated. O]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian envoy to Canada Sanjay Kumar Verma - now withdrawn by New Delhi -- has accused Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of wrecking bilateral ties with India and reiterated that Ottawa's allegations are politically motivated. Ottawa has accused Mr Verma of having links to the murder of Khalistani separatist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<p>India's response to the allegations was to withdraw the diplomats. It was followed by Canadian government's move to formally expel them. India reiterated by ordering out six Canadian diplomats.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In an interview to CTV aired on Sunday, Mr Verma said, "On the basis of intelligence, if you want to destroy a relationship, be my guest. And that's what he did".</p>

<p>Justin Trudeau had specifically tied the Indian diplomats to the murder of Nijjar that took place last year in British Columbia.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked whether he had had anything to do with Nijjar's murder, Mr Verma said: "Nothing at all. No evidence was presented. (This is) politically motivated."</p>

<p>"On what basis do they want to question me... If you are a defendant, for example, which I am not, then evidence would be shared and that happens even if you are caught for a petty crime. If I'm going for an interrogation I need to know what I am interrogated for. I need to know what evidence you have so I go prepared," Mr Verma told the Canadian network when asked about India's refusal to join the so-called ongoing investigations.</p>

<p>Ties between the two nations - on a downward spiral since September last year -- have nosedived after the series of fresh allegations.</p>

<p>The Foreign Ministry has slammed Ottawa for its allegations against Mr Verma -- one of the country's senior-most diplomats who has served in Japan, Sudan, Italy, Turkey, Vietnam and China.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The allegations, India said, were "ludicrous" and deserved to be treated with contempt. New Delhi said it has "no faith in the current Canadian Government's commitment to ensure their security".</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/oftq3iv_pm-modi-justin-trudeau-modi-trudeau-ani_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-now-60-questions-78-year-old-donald-trumps-fitness-to-be-us-president-6834417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris, Now 60, Questions 78-Year-Old Trump's Fitness To Be President]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-now-60-questions-78-year-old-donald-trumps-fitness-to-be-us-president-6834417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:40:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris turned 60 on Sunday in the final stretch of a knife-edge election battle with 78-year-old Donald Trump, as she urged a Black congregation in Georgia to embrace compassionate values while others "spread hate, sow fear and cause chaos."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris turned 60 on Sunday in the final stretch of a knife-edge election battle with 78-year-old Donald Trump, as she urged a Black congregation in Georgia to embrace compassionate values while others "spread hate, sow fear and cause chaos."</p>

<p>Harris, speaking at a Baptist megachurch near Atlanta, did not mention Trump by name but the crowd -- after spontaneously serenading her with "Happy Birthday" -- nodded knowingly to her allusions to her Republican rival.</p>

<p>Georgia is one of the key states that are expected to decide the November 5 election. Both candidates were planning events later Sunday in another of those states, Pennsylvania, which both sides see as a must-win.</p>

<p>With just over two weeks before Election Day, the Democratic vice president and the Republican billionaire are in a fierce race.</p>

<p>Harris, addressing the enthusiastic Black churchgoers -- normally a strongly Democratic demographic -- delivered a temperate speech, telling the tale of the Good Samaritan but also using it to exhort the crowd to vote and "shine the light in moments of darkness."</p>

<p>Indeed, Trump is using increasingly angry and dark language in the campaign.</p>

<p>He has likened undocumented migrants to animals, threatened revenge against his perceived enemies, praised autocrats like Vladimir Putin of Russia and described America as a ruined nation only he can fix.</p>

<p>"Where we go from here is up to us as Americans and as people of faith," Harris said. "What kind of country do we want to live in -- a country of chaos, fear and hate, or a country of freedom, compassion and justice?"</p>

<p>In other events, Harris has increasingly raised questions about Trump's fitness to be president.</p>

<p>"Now he's ducking debates and canceling interviews because of exhaustion," Harris told a rally Saturday in Atlanta, mocking his rambling, off-script speeches.</p>

<p>The former president himself has surprised attendees at his rallies with sometimes bizarre references, including a ribald allusion Saturday to the anatomy of a famous golfer.</p>

<p>But Trump's age and spontaneous remarks have not appeared to be a deal-breaker for voters, as polls show a close battle ahead.</p>

<p><strong>'Across the finish line'</strong></p>

<p>Harris had also sought to goad Trump with a report on October 12 that described her "excellent health", but the ex-president's campaign insisted he, too, is "in perfect and excellent health to be Commander-in-Chief".</p>

<p>The Republican running for a second go in the White House countered Harris's accusations with a marathon speech in Pennsylvania on Saturday, a day after saying she "doesn't have the energy of a rabbit."</p>

<p>Both candidates are spending their final campaign days in pivotal states, but so are their surrogates.</p>

<p>Tesla and SpaceX boss Elon Musk has personally hit the campaign trail in Pennsylvania, holding a series of events in the must-win state.</p>

<p>Speaking in the southeastern city of Harrisburg, he announced he would start to randomly distribute cash awards -- $1 million each day until the November 5 vote -- to a registered voter in the state who signed his organization's petition.</p>

<p>Harris deployed surrogates in the form of pop stars Lizzo and Usher to make her case to voters.</p>

<p>Lizzo drew cheers when telling a Detroit rally that America was more than ready for its first woman president, dropping a reference to her own hit song: "It's about damn time!"</p>

<p>One of Atlanta's major stars, Usher, told voters there that "I'm counting on you" to get Harris's "campaign across the finish line" in Georgia.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ou6o95ig_kamala-harris-donald-trump_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Harris has increasingly raised questions about Trump's fitness to be president (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-should-be-on-un-security-council-permanently-russias-top-diplomat-sergey-lavrov-6834363]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Should Be On UN Security Council Permanently: Russia's Top Diplomat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-should-be-on-un-security-council-permanently-russias-top-diplomat-sergey-lavrov-6834363]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:29:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia's top diplomat has said that his country believes that India, Brazil and African countries should be represented in the UN Security Council on a permanent basis, state-owned TASS news agency reported on Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia's top diplomat has said that his country believes that India, Brazil and African countries should be represented in the UN Security Council on a permanent basis to ensure the representativeness of the global majority, state-owned TASS news agency reported on Sunday.</p>

<p>"Countries such as India, Brazil, as well as representatives of Africa should have been on a permanent basis in the Security Council for a long time. This is necessary to ensure representativeness, representation of the global majority," Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov told aif.ru. in an interview, TASS reported.</p>

<p>India has been at the forefront of years-long efforts calling for reform of the Security Council, including expansion in both its permanent and non-permanent categories, saying the 15-nation Council, founded in 1945, is not fit for purpose in the 21st Century and does not reflect contemporary geo-political realities. Delhi has underscored that it deserves a permanent seat at the horse-shoe table.</p>

<p>Last month, British Prime Minister Keir Starmer joined US President Joe Biden and French President Emmanuel Macron in backing India's bid for a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council (UNSC).</p>

<p>India last sat at the UN high table as a non-permanent member in 2021-22. There has been a growing demand to increase the number of permanent members to reflect the contemporary global reality.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/ccd2a8hg_sergey-lavrov-afp_625x300_16_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India last sat at the UN high table as a non-permanent member in 2021-22 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-digital-revolution-an-example-for-world-nobel-laureate-paul-romer-6834252]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India's Digital Revolution An Example For World: Nobel Laureate Paul Romer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indias-digital-revolution-an-example-for-world-nobel-laureate-paul-romer-6834252]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 23:05:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel Laureate Professor Paul Michael Romer on Sunday hailed India's digital revolution as one of the most inspiring and interesting success stories and said that it has set a new benchmark for world powers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel Laureate Professor Paul Michael Romer on Sunday hailed India's digital revolution as one of the most inspiring and interesting success stories and said that it has set a new benchmark for world powers.</p>

<p>Prof Paul Michael Romer, also the former Chief Economist of World Bank, is currently in India and will be one of the lead speakers at the two-day NDTV World Summit, starting from October 21.</p>

<p>Professor Paul, sharing his views on India's digital prowess, pointed out a unique aspect of India's digital transformation and said that the South Asian nations can benefit heavily by emulating it.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch: Professor Paul Michael Romer says, "Well, this is what makes the digital revolution in India so interesting, is that it's been used by the government to actually provide benefits to all members of society. It hasn't just created benefits for the lucky few, and this I think… <a href="https://t.co/BPZCwjeZXH">pic.twitter.com/BPZCwjeZXH</a></p>
— IANS (@ians_india) <a href="https://twitter.com/ians_india/status/1847971584146817391?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 20, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He said that India's digital revolution not only made the lives of people easier and simpler, but it has also emerged as an example for the rest of the world.</p>

<p>Ahead of his participation in the discourse at NDTV platform, the Nobel Laureate lauded Prime Minister Narendra Modi-led government for successfully leading the digital penetration into masses and pushing it to every nook and corner of the country.</p>

<p>"Digital revolution here is very interesting because it is being used by the government to provide benefits to all members of society. This is very different from most countries of the world, where the target is only a lucky few beneficiaries. India's story is unique because it is providing benefits to all," he said.</p>

<p>When questioned on how India's digital success could become a model for South Asian nations, he said that online services like UPI, DBT, Digilockers and more have shown tremendous success and the Southern nations could emulate it for writing a similar success story for them.</p>

<p>"Other countries, particularly in the South should believe that if India can do it, we can also do it. They can draw inspiration and confidence from India and harbour an ambition to create a success story. They don't need to be dependent on rich countries, rather should initiate work based on their own ground realities," he told the mediapersons.</p>

<p>When questioned about India's astounding success in digitising the economy despite very limited online literacy, he said that he has always been a strong votary of technology as a great enabler.</p>

<p>"In 1980s, I strongly vouched for technology to be a life-changing enabler. Technology can improve the quality of life - and is visible in countries like Singapore, South Korea and more. When China grew faster than any other country, some attributed it to its size. However, in democracy what matters is the country's capacity, its ambition and vision to achieve," he remarked.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vhv38spo_paul-romer_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Professor Paul lauded PM Modi-led government for successfully leading digital penetration into masses]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-reveals-the-science-behind-childrens-short-attention-span-6834157]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Study Reveals The Science Behind Children's Short Attention Span]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/study-reveals-the-science-behind-childrens-short-attention-span-6834157]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:49:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new study reveals that kindergarten-aged children tend to over-explore during tasks, not due to lack of understanding or attention, but possibly due to curiosity or underdeveloped working memory.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The reasons behind young children's frequent struggles with focusing on particular tasks have been clarified by a recent study. It was found by researchers that although children as young as kindergarten are able to comprehend and carry out instructions, their natural tendency is to explore their environment.</p>

<p>The four, five, and six-year-old youngsters in the study showed a tendency to scatter their attention widely, gathering too many details that divert them from their main objective. The researchers claim that this behaviour is caused by their innate curiosity and the constraints of their working memory at this developmental stage rather than a lack of comprehension or attention span.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.osu.edu/why-children-cant-pay-attention-to-the-task-at-hand/"><em>release by the Ohio State University</em></a>, it now appears that kids distribute their attention broadly either out of simple curiosity or because their working memory isn't developed enough to complete a task without "overexploring."</p>

<p>"Children can't seem to stop themselves from gathering more information than they need to complete a task, even when they know exactly what they need," said Vladimir Sloutsky, co-author of the study and professor of psychology at The Ohio State University.</p>

<p>Sloutsky conducted the study, published recently in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/09567976241258146"><em>journal Psychological Science</em></a>, with lead author Qianqian Wan, a doctoral student in psychology at Ohio State.</p>

<p>The findings suggest that while young children may have difficulty focusing on a single task, it is a normal and expected part of their cognitive development. As their brains mature, they will gradually develop better concentration skills and learn to prioritise relevant information.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/41g26ck_kindergarten_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A new study reveals why kindergarten-aged children tend to overexplore.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-daily-1-million-payouts-at-trump-rally-draw-legal-scrutiny-6834146]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's Daily $1 Million Payouts At Trump Rally Draw Legal Scrutiny]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-daily-1-million-payouts-at-trump-rally-draw-legal-scrutiny-6834146]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:45:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Elon Musk promised on Saturday to give away $1 million each day until November's election to someone who signs his online petition, with the first prize awarded at a PAC event supporting Donald Trump, raising questions about legality of the payments.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Billionaire Elon Musk promised on Saturday to give away $1 million each day until November's election to someone who signs his online petition, with the first prize awarded at a PAC event supporting Republican Donald Trump, raising questions about the legality of the payments.</p>

<p>Musk gave a $1 million check to an attendee of his America PAC event in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, aimed at rallying supporters behind presidential candidate Trump. The winner was a man named John Dreher, according to event staff.</p>

<p>"By the way, John had no idea. So anyway, you're welcome," the Tesla founder said as he handed Dreher the check.</p>

<p>The money is the latest example of Musk using his extraordinary wealth to influence the tightly-contested presidential race between Trump and his Democratic rival Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p>Musk started America PAC, a political action organization he founded in support of Trump's presidential campaign. The group is helping mobilize and register voters in battleground states, but there are signs it is having trouble meeting its goals.</p>

<p><strong>'DEEPLY CONCERNING'</strong></p>

<p>Pennsylvania Governor Josh Shapiro said on Sunday on NBC's "Meet the Press" that Musk's plan to give money to registered voters in Pennsylvania is "deeply concerning" and "it's something that law enforcement could take a look at."</p>

<p>Questions about the legality of these cash payments abounded on Saturday night, as election law experts pointed to various provisions in federal law that prohibited making cash payments to voters.</p>

<p>It is a federal crime to pay people with the intention of inducing or rewarding them to cast a vote or to get registered, an offense punishable by prison time. The prohibition covers not only monetary expenditures, but also anything of monetary value like liquor or lottery chances, a Justice Department election-crimes manual says.</p>

<p>The Harrisburg event was the third in as many days in Pennsylvania, where Musk is painting November's election in stark terms and encouraging supporters to vote early and get others to do the same.</p>

<p>He said on Saturday that if Harris wins, it will be "the last election."</p>

<p>He also said the two assassination attempts against Trump prove he is ruffling feathers and upending the status quo.</p>

<p>The petition Musk is asking people to sign reads: "The First and Second Amendments guarantee freedom of speech and the right to bear arms. By signing below, I am pledging my support for the First and Second Amendments."</p>

<p>Attendees of Saturday's event had to sign the petition, which allows America PAC to garner contact details for more potential voters that it can work to get to the polls for Trump.</p>

<p>Musk, ranked by Forbes as the world's richest person, so far has supplied at least $75 million to America PAC, according to federal disclosures, making the group a crucial part of Trump's bid to regain the White House.</p>

<p>The entrepreneur behind carmaker Tesla and rocket and satellite venture SpaceX has increasingly supported Republican causes and this year became an outspoken Trump supporter.</p>

<p>Trump in turn has said if elected he would appoint Musk to head a government efficiency commission.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/83r3597g_donald-trumpelon-musk-reuters_625x300_19_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk so far has supplied $75 million to America PAC, according to federal disclosures (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/87-killed-in-israels-attack-on-gaza-after-yahya-sinwars-killing-6834084]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[87 Killed In Israel's Attack On Gaza After Yahya Sinwar's Killing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/87-killed-in-israels-attack-on-gaza-after-yahya-sinwars-killing-6834084]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:32:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel said it hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in its latest strikes on the Lebanese capital Beirut on Sunday, while officials in Gaza said rescuers were still recovering people from the rubble after an Israeli strike that killed dozens.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel said it hit Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in its latest strikes on the Lebanese capital Beirut on Sunday, while officials in Gaza said rescuers were still recovering people from the rubble after an Israeli strike that killed dozens.</p>

<p>At least 87 people were dead or missing following the air strike on Beit Lahiya in northern Gaza late on Saturday, the health ministry in the Palestinian territory said, one of the highest death counts for months from a single attack. Israel said it was investigating reports of the incident.</p>

<p>It marked an intensification of Israel's offensives against Palestinian group Hamas in Gaza and Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon, days after the killing of Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar raised hopes of an opening for ceasefire negotiations to end more than a year of conflict in the Middle East.</p>

<p>With US elections approaching, officials, diplomats and other sources in the region say Israel is seeking through military operations to try to shield its borders and ensure its rivals cannot regroup.</p>

<p>Israel is also preparing to retaliate for an Iranian missile barrage earlier this month, though Washington has pressed it not to strike Iranian energy facilities or nuclear sites.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he was the subject of an assassination attempt by "Iran's proxy Hezbollah" on Saturday when a drone was directed at his holiday home. In a call with former US President Donald Trump, the prime minister reiterated that Israel would make decisions based on its own interests, according to a statement from Netanyahu's office.</p>

<p>Israel's government has spurned several attempts by the United States, its main ally and military backer, at brokering ceasefires in both Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p><strong>EVACUATION ORDERS</strong></p>

<p>In Gaza, the health ministry said rescue operations following the strike in Beit Lahiya were being hindered by communications problems and by ongoing Israeli military operations.</p>

<p>The strike came two weeks into a major assault around Jabalia, just south of Beit Lahiya, where Israel says its troops backed by tanks have been trying to root out remaining Hamas fighters.</p>

<p>Israel said the strike hit a Hamas target, questioning an earlier death count of 73 released by the Hamas media office.</p>

<p>As the fighting has continued, two of the three remaining hospitals in northern Gaza have been hit and patients, medical staff and displaced people injured, according to the United Nations. The UN has been urgently seeking access.</p>

<p>Israel says militants use civilian areas including schools and hospitals for cover, a charge Hamas denies.</p>

<p>Over 5,000 Palestinians left Jabalia via designated routes, Israeli military spokesperson Avichay Adraee said on social media platform X.</p>

<p>Evacuation orders have fuelled fears among many Palestinians that the operation is intended to clear them from northern Gaza to enable Israeli control of the area after the war.</p>

<p>Israel has denied this, saying it is trying to protect civilians and separate them from Hamas fighters.</p>

<p>Palestinians were also shocked by footage appearing to show a group of people in a street in Jabalia being hit by a strike as they approached to rescue someone who had already been hit. Reuters verified the location of the footage, but not the date. Israeli officials had no immediate comment.</p>

<p>The Israeli offensive, triggered by the Oct. 7, 2023 Hamas attack on Israel, has made most of Gaza's 2.3 million people homeless, caused widespread hunger and destroyed hospitals and schools.</p>

<p>"Horrifying scenes unfolding in Gaza, amidst conflict, relentless Israeli strikes &amp; an ever-worsening humanitarian crisis," UN Middle East peace envoy Tor Wennesland posted on X.</p>

<p><strong>BEIRUT STRIKES</strong></p>

<p>In Beirut, Israel said its air force had followed strikes on Saturday with an attack on Hezbollah's intelligence headquarters in the capital as well as an underground weapons workshop.</p>

<p>Fighter jets killed three Hezbollah commanders, the Israeli military said in a statement.</p>

<p>Reuters witnesses saw smoke rising from Beirut's southern suburbs, once a densely populated zone that also housed Hezbollah offices and underground installations.</p>

<p>Hezbollah made no immediate comment on the strikes, but said it had fired missiles at Israeli forces in Lebanon and at a base in northern Israel.</p>

<p>Cross-border fighting between Israel and Hezbollah erupted a year ago when the Iranian-backed group began launching rockets in support of Hamas.</p>

<p>At the start of October, Israel launched a ground assault inside Lebanon in an attempt to stabilise the border region for its citizens who had fled rocket attacks in northern Israel.</p>

<p>On Sunday in southern Lebanon, security and civil defence sources said two aid workers were killed in an Israeli strike on a house being used as a clinic, while the Lebanese military said three of its soldiers were killed in a strike on an army vehicle.</p>

<p>Over the last year, Lebanese officials estimate that more than 2,400 people have been killed and more than 1.2 million people displaced. Fifty-nine people have been killed in northern Israel and the occupied Golan Heights over the same period, say Israeli authorities.</p>

<p>Hamas-led militants killed some 1,200 people and took 250 hostages in the attack that sparked the war, according to Israeli tallies. Israel's military response in Gaza has left more than 42,500 people dead, Palestinian officials say.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/icbt1l1_gaza-reuters_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel-Gaza war has been going on since October 7, 2023 (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-cubans-still-without-power-after-3rd-grid-failure-6833795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Millions Of Cubans Still Without Power After 3rd Grid Failure]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/millions-of-cubans-still-without-power-after-3rd-grid-failure-6833795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 21:34:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Millions of Cubans awoke on Sunday to find their homes still without power after another partial grid failure overnight, deepening a crisis that has raised questions over the viability of the government's efforts to reestablish electrical service.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Millions of Cubans awoke on Sunday to find their homes still without power after another partial grid failure overnight, deepening a crisis that has raised questions over the viability of the government's efforts to reestablish electrical service.</p>

<p>The country's top electricity official, Lazaro Guerra, confirmed a partial grid collapse in the western provinces of Cuba, which includes Havana, late on Saturday.</p>

<p>Technicians were working to resolve the issue, Guerra said, but did not provide a timeline for when power would be restored to the region.</p>

<p>The capital of nearly two million residents appeared to be entirely without electricity early on Sunday, as many Cubans formed lines for subsidized rations and mulled the situation outside their homes.</p>

<p>State-run digital news outlet CubaDebate reported that the country's largest power plant, Antonio Guiteras, was back online Sunday and would begin contributing to a restoration of service over the course of the day.</p>

<p>A third grid failure late on Saturday marked a major setback in the government's efforts to quickly restore power to exhausted residents already suffering from severe shortages of food, medicine and fuel.</p>

<p>The clock was ticking as Hurricane Oscar bore down on northeastern Cuba early on Sunday, threatening to further complicate the government's plans to restore power.</p>

<p>Cuba's meteorological survey warned of "an extremely dangerous situation" in eastern Cuba. The entire region was largely without electricity or communication ahead of the storm, which packed winds as high as 100 miles per hour (161 kph) by midmorning Sunday.</p>

<p>Cuba's national electrical grid first crashed around midday on Friday after the island's largest power plant shut down, sowing chaos. The grid collapsed again on Saturday morning, state-run media reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By early evening on Saturday, authorities reported some progress restoring power before announcing another partial grid collapse.</p>

<p>"The process of reestablishing the electrical system continues to be complex," Cuba's energy ministry said on X.</p>

<p><strong>RISING TENSIONS</strong></p>

<p>Reuters reporters witnessed two small protests overnight after a grid failure left Havana in the dark late Saturday, one on the outskirts of the capital in Marianao and the other in the more central Cuatro Caminos. Various videos of protests elsewhere in the capital began to crop up on social media late on Saturday, though Reuters was not able to verify their authenticity.</p>

<p>Internet traffic dropped off sharply in Cuba on Saturday, according to data from internet monitoring group NetBlocks, as vast power outages made it all but impossible for most island residents to charge phones and get online.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Network data show that Cuba remains largely offline as the island experiences a second nationwide power outage," Netblocks said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Even before the grid failures, a dire electricity shortfall on Friday had forced Cuba's Communist-run government to send non-essential state workers home and cancel school as it sought to conserve fuel.</p>

<p>The government has blamed weeks of worsening blackouts - as long as 10 to 20 hours a day across much of the island - on deteriorating infrastructure, fuel shortages and rising demand.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Cuba also blames the US trade embargo, as well as sanctions instituted by then-President Donald Trump, for ongoing difficulties in acquiring fuel and spare parts to operate and maintain its oil-fired plants.</p>

<p>The US has denied any role in the grid failures.</p>

<p>Cuba produces little of its own crude oil. Fuel deliveries to the island have dropped significantly this year as Venezuela, Russia and Mexico, once important suppliers, have reduced their exports to Cuba.</p>

<p>Ally Venezuela slashed by half its deliveries of subsidized fuel to Cuba this year, forcing the island to search for more costly oil on the spot market. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/fhttkrmo_cuba-power-outage_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cuba's national electrical grid first crashed around midday on Friday]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-address-backlog-of-modern-slavery-cases-amid-50-million-globally-trapped-6832670]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK To Address Backlog Of Modern Slavery Cases Amid 50 Million Trapped]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-to-address-backlog-of-modern-slavery-cases-amid-50-million-globally-trapped-6832670]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:14:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UK Government has announced the recruitment of 200 additional Home Office staff to address a backlog of 23,300 modern slavery cases inherited from the previous administration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Government of the United Kingdom has recruited 200 additional Home Office staff to clear a backlog of 23,300 modern slavery cases left by the last government. The cases could be "eliminated" within two years, according to an official statement. This step will be giving thousands of women, men, and children who may have suffered traumatic sexual, physical, and economic abuse the clarity needed to assist with their recovery.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/modern-slavery-victims-to-be-supported-in-fresh-measures#:~:text=For%20the%20first%20time%2C%20the,to%20assist%20with%20their%20recovery.">UK government,</a> currently, many victims face long delays in having their status as a victim of modern slavery confirmed through the national referral mechanism via a conclusive grounds decision. This can lead to prolonged uncertainty and mental health suffering.</p>

<p>"For too long, modern slavery survivors and the harrowing experiences they have lived through have not been given the attention and support they deserve," Minister for Safeguarding, Jess Phillips, said. "This is going to change. The actions I have announced today are a first step towards putting survivors first, eradicating the backlog of modern slavery cases to give victims the clarity and peace of mind they need to move on with their lives."</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ilo.org/resource/news/50-million-people-worldwide-modern-slavery-0">International Labour Organisation,</a> an estimated fifty million people were living in modern slavery as of 2021, based on the latest Global Estimates of Modern Slavery. Of this number, 28 million individuals were in forced labour, while 22 million were trapped in forced marriage.</p>

<p>The number of people in modern slavery has risen significantly in the last 10 years. 10 million more people were in modern slavery in 2021 compared to 2016 global estimates. Women and children remain disproportionately vulnerable.</p>

<p>Modern slavery occurs in almost every country in the world and cuts across ethnic, cultural, and religious lines. More than half (52 percent) of all forced labour and a quarter of all forced marriages can be found in upper-middle-income or high-income countries.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/23mproco_modern-slavery_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The average wait for a conclusive decision is more than 500 days.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/maggots-slime-and-disease-worlds-dirtiest-cruise-ships-named-and-shamed-6832109]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Maggots, Slime, And Disease": World's Dirtiest Ships Named And Shamed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/maggots-slime-and-disease-worlds-dirtiest-cruise-ships-named-and-shamed-6832109]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:38:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Center for Disease Control (CDC) has revealed the top 10 filthiest cruise ships of 2024 after health officials randomly inspected 114 different ships.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the national public health agency of the United States, has released a troubling list of the top 10 dirtiest cruise ships of 2024, based on health inspections carried out on 114 vessels.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://wwwn.cdc.gov/inspectionquerytool/inspectionsearch.aspx">results showed unhygienic conditions</a> with sludge, maggots, and other health risks. It was discovered that these ships, which were intended to provide tourists with a relaxing escape, had severe hygiene problems that can cause disease outbreaks.</p>

<p>When making a cruise reservation, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/vessel-sanitation/site.html#gen">CDC</a> advises guests to review the health inspection record of the ship. In order to protect travellers' safety and wellbeing and avoid any unpleasant shocks while on vacation, these inspections are crucial.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-indian-origin-man-faces-hate-in-canada-told-to-return-to-india-6831667#pfrom=home-ndtv_lateststories"><strong>Also Read: Indian-Origin Man Faces Hate In Canada, Told To 'Return To India'</strong></a></p>

<p>The findings of the CDC's Vessel Sanitation Program, which rates cruise ships on a scale of 0 to 100 for cleanliness in an effort to prevent gastrointestinal illnesses, were released. Of these, 10 ships scored worse than 89. A score of 85 or lower is considered "not satisfactory," according to the organisation.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cdc.gov/vessel-sanitation/about/index.html"><em>CDC,</em></a> travelling on cruise ships exposes people to new environments and high volumes of people, including other ravelers. This exposure can create the risk for illness from contaminated food or water or, more commonly, through person-to-person contact. The agency helps the cruise ship industry prevent and control gastrointestinal (GI) illnesses on cruise ships.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/uqpe2hb_hanseatic-inspiration_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The CDC urges travelers to check a ship's health inspection history before booking a cruise.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-comedian-to-president-of-ukraine-all-about-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6831990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Comedian To President Of Ukraine: All About Volodymyr Zelenskyy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-comedian-to-president-of-ukraine-all-about-volodymyr-zelenskyy-6831990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Oct 2024 16:22:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is actively seeking support from Western allies for his "Victory Plan," which aims to end the ongoing war with Russia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is actively seeking support from Western allies for his "Victory Plan," which aims to end the ongoing war with Russia. Central to this plan is Ukraine's desire to become NATO's 33rd member with continued arms shipments for security guarantees. The primary goal is to strengthen the nation and facilitate a diplomatic resolution to the conflict which began with Russia's invasion in 2022.</p>

<p>"Either Ukraine will have nuclear weapons and that will be our protection or we should have some sort of alliance. Apart from NATO, today we do not know any effective alliances," Zelenskyy <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cbwyuBGIIJs">said</a> at the European Council summit in Brussels on Thursday.</p>

<p>In response, Russian President Vladimir Putin issued a stern warning. "Any step in this direction will meet an adequate response," he said, claiming that "under no circumstances" would Russia allow such developments to happen.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy later clarified his remarks during a joint press conference with NATO chief Mark Rutte. "We are not building nuclear weapons. What I meant is that today, there is no stronger security guarantee for us than NATO membership," he said.</p>

<h2><strong>Who Is Volodymyr Zelenskyy?</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Volodymyr Zelenskyy is the 6th President of Ukraine. The 45-year-old transitioned from a comedian and TV star to a politician who would go on to lead the nation in the war against Russia.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Early Life And Education</strong></h2>

<p>Born on January 25, 1978, in Kryvyi Rih, Ukraine, Volodymyr Oleksandrovytch Zelenskyy grew up in a Jewish family. Both his parents - Oleksandr Zelenskyy and Rymma Zelenska - are engineers.</p>

<p>Before starting elementary school, Volodymyr Zelenskyy lived for four years in Erdenet, Mongolia, where his father worked to help build a copper mine. Zelenskyy grew up speaking Russian.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy's early life was marked by a strong interest in comedy and acting. He graduated from the Kyiv National Economic University with a degree in law but pursued a career in entertainment instead.</p>

<h2><strong>Career in entertainment</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy began his career in entertainment as an actor, scriptwriter, and producer for the stand-up comedy team KVARTAL 95 from 1997 to 2003. He then became the executive producer of KVARTAL 95, LLC until 2011, and served as Chief Executive at PJSC Inter TV Station from 2011 to 2012. He returned to KVARTAL 95 from 2013 to 2019, founding the NGO 'The League of Laughter' and producing 10 feature films, winning over 30 awards from Ukraine's National Television Award, <em>Teletriumph</em>.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy also supported the armed forces during the Donbas conflict by providing funds, equipment for soldiers. He gained fame for his role in the 2015 TV series <em>Servant of the People</em>, where he played a high school history teacher who becomes President of Ukraine. The show led to the creation of a political party of the same name in March 2018.</p>

<h2><strong>The Unlikely President&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">In 2019, Volodymyr Zelenskyy announced his candidacy for the Ukrainian presidency. Despite being a political novice, he won the election with a landslide victory, securing 73 percent of the vote, against incumbent Petro Poroshenko. His campaign focused on anti-corruption, economic reform and Ukrainian nationalism.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Presidency</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy was inaugurated as Ukraine's president on May 20, 2019. He is the first Jewish president of the country. He dissolved the parliament in his inaugural address, calling for early elections, but faced opposition from his coalition partner, the People's Front. On May 28, he restored the former president of Georgia, Mikheil Saakashvili's Ukrainian citizenship.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy's proposals to change the electoral system and reintroduce criminal liability for illegal enrichment were rejected by parliament. However, on September 3, he succeeded in stripping lawmakers of legal immunity, fulfilling a key campaign promise.</p>

<p>He cancelled the annual Kyiv Independence Day Parade in July 2019, redirecting funds to support veterans. In 2020, his party proposed reforms to media laws aimed at reducing oligarchs' influence but faced criticism for potential censorship.</p>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy also focused on updating referendum laws, fulfilling another campaign promise, and introduced a bill to create a public registry of Ukraine's oligarchs, which passed in September 2021 despite concerns about consolidating presidential power.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Zelenskyy's Efforts To End The Donbas Conflict</strong></h2>

<p>The Donbas conflict began in 2014 when Russian-backed separatists seized parts of eastern Ukraine. Resolving this conflict was a key promise of Zelenskyy's campaign.</p>

<p>In June 2019, he appointed former President Leonid Kuchma for peace talks and spoke with Russian President Vladimir Putin to push for EU-mediated discussions and prisoner exchanges.</p>

<p>In October 2019, Volodymyr Zelenskyy proposed a deal to respect elections in Donbas if Russia withdrew troops, but the plan faced backlash from nationalists and critics. The agreement failed to reduce violence as separatists continued their attacks.</p>

<p>By December 2019, Zelenskyy resumed peace talks with Russia through the Normandy Format, with France and Germany as mediators. A ceasefire was declared in July 2020, but despite fewer violations, the conflict remained unresolved.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Controversies</strong></h2>

<p><strong>Trump-Ukraine Scandal:</strong> Volodymyr Zelenskyy found himself at the centre of the 2019 impeachment controversy involving then-US President Donald Trump. In a July 2019 phone call, Trump allegedly pressured Zelenskyy to investigate Joe Biden, a key political rival, in exchange for releasing military aid to Ukraine. Despite being drawn into the scandal, Zelenskyy maintained he faced no pressure from Trump. Trump supporters have alleged that Joe Biden used his influence to stop Ukraine from a criminal investigation that could have implicated Hunter Biden, the US President's son, who worked for an Ukrainian energy company. These were just allegations, though, and there was no evidence of any wrongdoing by Hunter Biden or of any move by Joe Biden to benefit his son.</p>

<p><strong>UIA Flight 752 Crash:</strong> In January 2020, Volodymyr Zelenskyy ended a trip to Oman early after the crash of Flight 752 in Iran. In January 2020, the plane was shot down by Iranian forces, killing all on board. Zelenskyy's administration faced criticism for not acting quickly enough to evacuate Ukrainian citizens from Iran.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Russia-Ukraine War</strong></h2>

<p>Volodymyr Zelenskyy has been at the forefront of Ukraine's resistance against Russia since the invasion began in February 2022. "Ukrainians are not ready to give away their land, to accept that these territories belong to Russia," he told CNN in 2023. "This is our land," he declared.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy has firmly rejected any territorial concessions, maintaining that Ukraine must retain its internationally recognised borders. He has also repeatedly advocated for Ukraine's membership in NATO, seeing it as crucial for long-term security.</p>

<p>Zelenskyy received strong backing from Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan who said, "Without a doubt, Ukraine deserves to be in NATO."</p>

<p>NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organisation) is a military alliance established in 1949 to provide collective defence against potential security threats. It follows an open-door policy, allowing any country to join if it meets the alliance's principles. It must be noted that any current member can block a new country's entry under NATO's accession rules.</p>

<h2 dir="ltr"><strong>Personal Life</strong></h2>

<p dir="ltr">Volodymyr Zelenskyy has been married to Olena Zelenska since 2003. They have two children together - Oleksandra (2004) and Kyrylo (2013).</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/kb55urb_zelensky-afp_625x300_20_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Volodymyr Zelenskyy is the 6th President of Ukraine.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>