<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:17:08 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reacts To Video Of Injured Palestinian Tied To Israeli Military Jeep]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reacts-to-video-of-injured-palestinian-tied-to-israeli-military-jeep-5967378]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:15:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US State Department on Monday said a video of a wounded Palestinian man strapped on a military jeep by Israeli forces was "shocking" and urged a swift investigation to hold those responsible to account.</p>

<p>At a State Department news briefing, a reporter asked: "Isn't that basically the army using Palestinians as human shields?"</p>

<p>State Department spokesperson Matthew Miller responded: "I will say we saw that video. It was shocking. The practice was absolutely unacceptable. Humans should never be used as human shields."</p>

<p>"The IDF should swiftly investigate what happened, hold people accountable," Miller said, using an acronym for the Israel Defense Forces.</p>

<p>On Saturday, Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian man to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest raid in the occupied West Bank city of Jenin, the Israeli military said.</p>

<p>The video circulating on social media and verified by Reuters showed a Palestinian resident of Jenin, Mujahed Azmi, on a military jeep that passed between two ambulances.</p>

<p>The Israeli military in a statement said Israeli forces were fired at and exchanged fire, wounding a suspect and detaining him.</p>

<p>Soldiers then violated military protocol, the statement said.</p>

<p>The military said the "conduct of the forces in the video of the incident does not conform to the values" of the Israeli military and the incident will be investigated and dealt with. The military said the man was transferred to medics for treatment.</p>

<p>"I saw the statement they put out that the actions were inconsistent with the orders those soldiers received and that is being investigated and the people involved will be dealt with accordingly. That is absolutely appropriate," Miller said.</p>

<p>Violence in the West Bank, already on the rise before the Israel-Hamas war in Gaza began in October, has escalated since then with frequent army raids on Palestinian groups, rampages by Jewish settlers in Palestinian villages, and deadly street attacks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/14eup9ns_palestinian-man-jeep_625x300_23_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli forces tied a wounded Palestinian to the hood of a military jeep during an arrest.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kenya Protesters Breach Parliament Barricade, Enter Compound: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenya-protesters-breach-parliament-barricade-enter-compound-report-5967290]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 18:02:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kenyan protesters breached parliament barricades on Tuesday and entered the complex where lawmakers were debating contentious tax hike proposals that have sparked widespread anger, AFP journalists saw.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kenyan protesters breached parliament barricades on Tuesday and entered the complex where lawmakers were debating contentious tax hike proposals that have sparked widespread anger, AFP journalists saw, as police fired live bullets.</p>

<p>Hundreds of protesters broke through barriers erected by the police outside parliament in the capital Nairobi, with police firing live rounds and leaving "many wounded", according to Amnesty International Kenya.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/flna2alo_kenya-protests_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Several have been wounded in police firing, Amnesty International said.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: What Pilot Does After Plane's Canopy Bursts Open Mid-Air]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/watch-what-pilot-does-after-planes-canopy-bursts-opens-mid-air-5966411]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:42:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a dangerous situation during her aerobatic training flight when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dutch pilot Narine Melkumjan faced a frightening situation when her aircraft's canopy unexpectedly opened mid-air. A video she shared on social media showed the terrifying moment Melkumjan grappled to maintain control of her Extra 330LX aircraft.</p>

<p>Melkumjan, on her second aerobatic training flight a couple of years ago, appeared visibly distraught in the clip, toiling to keep her eyes open against the wind. After the canopy, a transparent enclosure that protects the cockpit of an aircraft, unexpectedly burst open, she applied all her skills to land the two-seater safely.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">*PLEASE MIND WHEN WATCHING. AT 2:17 MINUTE MARK VIDEO FOOTAGE BECOMES RATHER INTENSE*<br />
<br />
A couple of years ago during my second aerobatic training flight of that day, on a very hot summer day, the canopy of the Extra 330LX that I was flying opened in flight and shattered. As you… <a href="https://t.co/nLhvDqVnII">pic.twitter.com/nLhvDqVnII</a></p>
— Narine Melkumjan (@NarineMelkumjan) <a href="https://twitter.com/NarineMelkumjan/status/1804507833506931086?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 22, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Reflecting on the ordeal, Melkumjan acknowledged that the experience could have been avoided had she conducted proper pre-flight checks.</p>

<p>She admitted that the canopy locking pin was not properly secured before takeoff.</p>

<p>“I also made the mistake of going to the training camp right after recovering from COVID, without allowing my body enough time to fully regain strength. Additionally, flying without any eye protection made the flight even more challenging than it already was,” she wrote in a lengthy post on X.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She said she experienced some “buffet and controllability challenges,” revealing the “most difficult part was to keep the power in, thus trading my vision and breathing for kinetic energy.”</p>

<p>Amid the chaos, communication with her coach became almost impossible due to the noise, yet she distinctly remembered the crucial advice – "Just keep flying."</p>

<p>She described the distressing aftermath, including the overwhelming noise, difficulties breathing and impaired visibility that followed.</p>

<p>"It took me nearly 28 hours to fully recover my vision," Melkumjan revealed.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Melkumjan, known for her frequent posts of flying videos on social media, revealed that sharing the footage of her dramatic flight served as a "cautionary tale" for other pilots and that she regretted not sharing it sooner.</p>

<p>“If you are a pilot watching this, I hope that my story serves as a cautionary tale and that you will learn from my mistakes,” she wrote.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/28rqijuo_plane-canopy-opens_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Narine Melkumjan was on her second aerobatic training flight.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delay-in-starliners-return-adds-to-doubts-whistleblowers-make-a-big-claim-5967062]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delay In Starliner's Return Adds To Doubts, Whistleblowers Make A Big Claim]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delay-in-starliners-return-adds-to-doubts-whistleblowers-make-a-big-claim-5967062]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:29:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is stuck on the International Space Station (ISS) after glitches were found in the Boeing spaceship they travelled in.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian-origin astronaut Sunita Williams is stuck on the International Space Station (ISS) after glitches were found in the Boeing spaceship they travelled in. Earlier set to return on June 26, it's not known now when the astronauts will attempt their journey back to the earth.</p>

<p>The Boeing Starliner, which is on its maiden trip, has been facing a series of glitches that had delayed its launch twice. The constant delays have raised doubts, but what aggravates their troubles are allegations that the issues with the spaceship were known beforehand.</p>

<p>The ISS is a "mini city in space" about the size of a football field that astronauts from multiple space agencies use for research.</p>

<p>Ms Williams and her crewmate Butch Wilmore reached there on June 5 and were set to start their return journey on June 26. NASA, the space agency of US, confirmed on June 22 it had extended Ms Williams and Mr Wilmore's stay on the space station.</p>

<p>The Starliner had five helium leaks and five of its 28 thrusters were having issues, NDTV had reported two days ago. Experts say at least 14 thrusters are needed for a safe return.</p>

<p>Steve Stich, manager of NASA's commercial crew program, said the spaceship was performing well while docked to the space station and they were using the extra time to clear a path for some critical station activities while preparing for the two astronauts' departure.</p>

<p>Ms Williams, who is on her third space trip, had earlier described it a "fantastic spacecraft".</p>

<p>But allegations of neglect continue against Boeing.</p>

<p>Whistleblowers have alleged that Boeing and NASA managers involved in the mission knew of the technical faults with the Starliner, but went ahead as they considered was issues were too minor to further delay its launch, according to multiple reports.</p>

<p>At least 20 whistleblowers have now accused NASA of being casual about the issues and ignoring their concerns since the beginning.</p>

<p>Whistleblowers had raised safety allegations against Boeing in the past too.</p>

<p>Santiago Paredes, a former quality inspector at Spirit, told BBC earlier this month that plane bodies made by them regularly left their factory with serious defects. When he flagged his concerns, he was mocked for slowing down their production, he claimed.</p>

<p>Spirit AeroSystems, the Kansas-based company, "strong disagreed" with the allegation.</p>

<p>Boeing CEO David Calhoun too had defended his firm, telling a recent Congressional hearing, "we are proud of our safety record."</p>

<p><strong>Other Concerns For Starliner</strong></p>

<p>What adds to the concerns is that the astronauts have only 27 days of fuel left for the return voyage, according to a Business Today report. But NASA says they are not pressed for time to leave the station since they have enough supplies in the orbit.</p>

<p>Another headache for the residents of ISS is a "superbug" - a multi-drug resistant bacteria named 'Enterobacter bugandensis', which has evolved to be more potent in the closed environment of the ISS. The bacteria affects the respiratory system.</p>

<p>Boeing had also faced issues while manufacturing the Starliner, ending up spending about $5.7 million against its $4.2 billion contract.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/a4dr27to_boeing-starliner_625x300_10_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Boeing Starliner is on its maiden trip.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elated-wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-wife-on-landmark-plea-deal-5966956]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Elated": WikiLeaks Founder Julian Assange's Wife On Landmark Plea Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elated-wikileaks-founder-julian-assanges-wife-on-landmark-plea-deal-5966956]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:12:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's wife Stella said she was "elated" that he will be a "free man" after a US judge signs off on his landmark plea deal on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange's wife Stella said she was "elated" that he will be a "free man" after a US judge signs off on his landmark plea deal on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Stella Assange said the end of the years-long legal drama that saw him board a plane from London to Bangkok on Monday had been a "whirlwind of emotions".</p>

<p>"I'm just elated. Frankly, it's just incredible," the South African-born rights campaigner told BBC radio.</p>

<p>"We weren't really sure until the last 24 hours that it was actually happening."</p>

<p>Assange was on Monday freed on bail from a high-security prison in southeast London ahead of a plea hearing expected to take place in remote US territory.</p>

<p>He had been held in jail for five years as he fought extradition to the United States which sought to prosecute him for revealing military secrets.</p>

<p>He has agreed to plead guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information, according to a document filed in court in the Northern Mariana Islands in the Pacific where the hearing is expected to take place.</p>

<p>Stella Assange said the plea deal involved her husband pleading guilty to the single charge.</p>

<p>"The charge concerns the Espionage Act and obtaining and disclosing national defence information," she said.</p>

<p>"The important thing here is that the deal involved time served, that if he signed it, he would be able to walk free," she added.</p>

<p>- Extradition call to be withdrawn -</p>

<p>A charter plane flew the 52-year-old Australian publisher from London to Bangkok, where it made a scheduled stop to refuel.</p>

<p>From there it is set to fly to Saipan, the capital of the US territory where Assange is due in court on Wednesday morning.</p>

<p>"What there is, is an agreement in principle between Julian and the Department of Justice, and that has to be signed off by a judge in these Northern Mariana territories... in the Pacific Ocean where he is going to be headed," she said.</p>

<p>"He will be a free man once it has been signed off... and that will happen some time tomorrow."</p>

<p>Assange is later due to return to Australia under the deal.</p>

<p>Stephen Parkinson, chief prosecutor at Britain's Crown Prosecution Service (CPS), said a court hearing paving the way for Assange's departure was held last Thursday.</p>

<p>It was held in private at Assange's request, he said.</p>

<p>"Thirteen-and-a-half years and two extradition requests after he was first arrested, Julian Assange left the UK yesterday," he said.</p>

<p>The CPS said that since March it had worked closely with the UK's National Crime Agency to help put in place "the necessary practical arrangements to enable Mr Assange to leave the jurisdiction safely, and in accordance with his wishes and those of the US government".</p>

<p>"Following the sentencing by the US Federal Judge, the government of the USA is expected to formally withdraw the extradition request, bringing the English extradition proceedings to a formal and immediate conclusion," a CPS statement added.</p>

<p>Stella Assange told Britain's domestic Press Association news agency that her husband was paying $500,000 (£390,000) for the flights taking him from London to Australia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3pumrucg_julian-assange-2024-afp_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Stella Assange said the plea deal involved her husband pleading guilty to the single charge. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/chatgpt-meta-ai-google-gemini-what-technology-powers-chatgpt-google-gemini-and-meta-ai-5966894]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Tech That Powers ChatGPT, Google Gemini And Meta AI]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/chatgpt-meta-ai-google-gemini-what-technology-powers-chatgpt-google-gemini-and-meta-ai-5966894]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 17:04:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI Explainer:  Understanding how Large Language Models (LLMs) are responsible for running ChatGPT, Gemini and the most recently launched in India- Meta AI.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered how ChatGPT works? The short answer to this complex question lies in Large Language Models or LLMs which are foundational models that are trained using large amounts of textual data. These models do not process words as humans do. They instead use a long series of numbers, representing a single word. This data is fed to computers in the form of Word Vectors.</p>

<p>These sequences of numbers are known as Word Vectors and can be imagined as a single point in an imaginary space, with words that have similar meaning placed closer to each other. The scale of each model is massive and almost impossible to envision, but for reference, GPT4 has a staggering 1.76 trillion parameters, with millions of unique word vectors, according to a June 28, 2023 report by SemiAnalysis, a US-based independent AI research and analysis company. Processing such a huge number of vectors with trillions of parameters has been possible due to the dramatic advancement of computing power over the last few years. Most recently, on June 19, Nvidia became the largest public company in the world based on market capitalisation, surpassing Microsoft and Apple, as a result of surging demand on their AI capable chipsets.</p>

<p>ChatGPT, Google Gemini and Meta AI are all LLMs that work by predicting the next word, using word vectors. This prediction is done by transforming word vectors fed by the user as "prompts" into predictions, using Transformers.</p>

<p><strong>How Is Text Prediction Done In LLMs?</strong></p>

<p>LLMs are multi-layered. Each layer consists of a neural network architecture (imagine artificial neurons) known as transformers. These transformers process the input text - each word vector individually - and inside each transformer, words in the form of vectors look around and interact for relevant information. This process is repeated over and over again, not just for a single prompt, but even for the next time a user feeds a prompt with similar words into the LLMs. This enables efficiency in the future searches for better prediction of "the next word' in the sequence.</p>

<p><strong>How Are LLMs Trained?</strong></p>

<p>LLMs are trained using unsupervised learning, eliminating the need for human labelling of data. Data from web pages, books, and other textual sources is used to feed LLMs before going public. These have also courted controversy as it reflected human biases in some cases. Most notably, Microsoft's Twitter Chatbot Tay, Google's Gemini and OpenAI's Sora (text-to-video converter) have courted controversy over the years for giving bigoted, racial and gender discriminatory responses. To its credit, the industry has responded to the challenge and is constantly evolving to negate human biases from LLMs.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-12/g3gv78ps_artificial-intelligence-generic-pixabay_625x300_11_December_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[ChatGPT, Google Gemini and Meta AI are all LLMs that work by predicting the next word, using word vectors]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-kills-her-2-children-because-she-didnt-want-husband-to-have-them-5966439]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Woman Kills Her 2 Children "Because She Didn't Want Husband To Have Them"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-kills-her-2-children-because-she-didnt-want-husband-to-have-them-5966439]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 16:08:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the trial-of-facts hearing, it was revealed that Mrs John stabbed Ethan over 20 times and caused brain damage to her daughter Elizabeth.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A woman named Veronique John, 50, dialled 999 and confessed "I just killed my two kids" after stabbing them with a knife, Nottingham Crown Court was told. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/article/2024/jun/24/mother-killed-her-two-children-and-stabbed-husband-after-erupting-in-rage"><em>Guardian</em></a>, Mrs John killed her 7-year-old daughter Elizabeth and 11-year-old son Ethan because she did not want her husband to have their custody.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She stabbed her son, Ethan, more than 20 times and inflicted brain damage on her daughter, Elizabeth, before tracking down her husband, Nathan John, and stabbing him in the stomach.</p>

<p>During the trial-of-facts hearing, it was revealed that Mrs John stabbed Ethan over 20 times and caused brain damage to her daughter Elizabeth. She then went to a car wash wearing a dressing gown and stabbed her partner, Nathan John, in the stomach.</p>

<p>She then returned home, dialled 999 and said: "I am calling to report I just killed my two kids."</p>

<p>The charity shop worker allegedly told police who arrived at her Stoke-on-Trent home on June 11 last year, "If you have a gun, shoot me. I am not a monster - he was going to take them from me."</p>

<p>The day before the fatal attacks, John was arrested for assaulting her husband with a piece of wood while their children were getting ready for bed, suspecting him of having an affair.</p>

<p>The court heard that John and her husband had significant difficulties in their relationship, and she did not want him to have an internet-enabled phone.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Peter Grieves-Smith stated that Mrs John's "rage was boiling just under the surface" in the hours leading up to the children's deaths.</p>

<p>"What happened on 11 June didn't come out of the blue. Tension grew in the days before. That day she just erupted, killed her children and attacked Nathan," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Grieves-Smith stated that Mrs John killed her children just hours after conducting a "chilling" internet search, asking, "Can a foreigner be charged with murder in the UK?"</p>

<p>Ethan was pronounced dead after being found in a bedroom with a 17cm-long neck wound, while Elizabeth was discovered in the living room with head trauma and "three areas of sharp force," including one to her stomach.</p>

<p>The jury heard that a neighbour reported hearing "high-pitched screaming and crying that lasted for a little while" just minutes before John walked to the car wash where her husband had stayed the night.</p>

<p>The court heard how the 50-year-old later told interviewing officers: "I didn't want my husband to get them [the children]."</p>

<p>She continued: "It's something I was thinking about for a long time - just kill myself and the kids. Unless you guys are offering me the death penalty I have nothing else to say.</p>

<p>"I did it because I love my children - to protect the children. If there's any possible way I could be put to death, I would like that. I mean it 100%."</p>

<p>Mrs John is charged with two counts of murder, attempted murder and an alternative count of wounding, but has been ruled unfit to plead, Sky News reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She is currently being treated at a secure hospital and was not present in the dock to hear the Crown's opening statement.</p>

<p>The trial is ongoing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-02/dpt9q2q8_arrest-generic-istock-650_625x300_23_February_20.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The court heard that Mrs John and her husband had difficulties in their relationship]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-air-strike-kills-10-family-members-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-gaza-officials-5966327]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Air Strike Kills 10 Family Members Of Hamas Chief: Gaza Officials]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israeli-air-strike-kills-10-family-members-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-gaza-officials-5966327]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 15:51:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli air strike early Tuesday killed 10 family members of Hamas's Qatar-based chief Ismail Haniyeh, including his sister.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gaza's civil defence agency said an Israeli air strike early Tuesday killed 10 family members of Hamas's Qatar-based chief Ismail Haniyeh, including his sister.</p>

<p>The Israeli military, which is on a campaign to destroy Hamas over the October 7 attack, told AFP that it "was aware of the reports but we cannot confirm" them.</p>

<p>The strike hit the Haniyeh family home in the Al-Shati refugee camp, in the northern Gaza Strip, said Mahmud Basal, spokesman for the Hamas-ruled territory's civil defence.</p>

<p>"There are 10 martyrs... as a result of the strike, including Zahr Haniyeh, sister of Hamas political bureau chief Ismail Haniyeh," Basal told AFP.</p>

<p>He said a number of bodies were likely still under the rubble but "we do not have the necessary equipment" to extract them.</p>

<p>Civil defence crews transferred the bodies to Al-Ahli hospital in nearby Gaza City, Basal added, also reporting "several wounded" in the attack.</p>

<p>Hamas, the Islamist terrorist group that rules Gaza, is considered a terrorist organisation by Israel and key Western allies, including the United States.</p>

<p>Hamas in a statement named the Haniyeh family home as being bombed in a list of "massacres" it said were committed by Israel in the Palestinian territory.</p>

<p>It said the alleged bombing showed Israel "continues to defy all international laws, human norms and values by deliberately targeting innocent civilians and committing the most horrific massacres against them".</p>

<p>Haniyeh lost three sons and four grandchildren in an Israeli strike in April in central Gaza, with the military accusing them of "terrorist activities".</p>

<p>Haniyeh at the time said that about 60 members of his family had been killed since the war broke out on October 7.</p>

<p>The war began after Hamas's unprecedented attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Israel's withering air, land and sea campaign since then has killed at least 37,626 people in Gaza, also mostly civilians, according to the territory's health ministry.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/jq2p0l6g_ismail-haniyeh_625x300_21_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The strike hit the Haniyeh family home in the Al-Shati refugee camp. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sedentary-non-coffee-drinkers-at-60-more-risk-of-dying-study-finds-5965600]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sedentary, Non-Coffee Drinkers At 60% More Risk Of Dying, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sedentary-non-coffee-drinkers-at-60-more-risk-of-dying-study-finds-5965600]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 15:45:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Non-coffee drinkers who sat for six or more hours a day were at almost 60 per cent higher risk of dying compared to coffee drinkers sitting for less than six hours, according to a research.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Non-coffee drinkers who sat for six or more hours a day were at almost 60 per cent higher risk of dying compared to coffee drinkers sitting for less than six hours, according to a research published in the journal BioMed Central (BMC) Public Health.</p>

<p>This indicated an increased risk of dying in sedentary people not consuming coffee, but not among those drinking coffee, researchers following over 10,000 adults in the US for up to 13 years said.</p>

<p>The researchers at the Medical College of Soochow University's School of Public Health in China also found that sedentary coffee drinkers were at a 24 per cent lower risk of death compared to non-coffee drinkers sitting for at least six hours a day.</p>

<p>The result, not featuring in the study, was calculated at The Washington Post's request, according to the media website's report.</p>

<p>"The benefits of coffee consumption in improving overall survival in adults compared to sedentary behaviour are manifold," the authors wrote in the study.</p>

<p>Consuming coffee lowers risk of metabolic problems known to worsen inflammation, which contributes to heightening death risks because of sedentary behaviour, they said.</p>

<p>In their study, the authors found that the risk of dying from any cause significantly lowered -- by 33 per cent -- among a fourth of all the participants consuming highest amounts of coffee compared to non-coffee drinkers.</p>

<p>The results were consistent with those from previous studies, which have found a link between drinking more coffee and a lowered risk of dying from any cause and heart disease, they said.</p>

<p>Compounds present in coffee, including caffeine and polyphenols, are anti-inflammatory in nature. However, how exactly coffee works in the body to lower risk of dying is still unclear, the researchers said.</p>

<p>Further, the team also found that sitting for more than eight hours a day was linked with over 40 per cent higher risk of death from any cause and almost 80 per cent higher risk of dying due to heart disease.</p>

<p>For their analysis, the researchers used data from the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES), which follows Americans' health and nutrition.</p>

<p>"Given that coffee is a complex compound, further research is needed to explore this miracle compound," the authors wrote.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/nmu4jtlo_laptop-generic_625x300_03_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Non-coffee drinkers who sit for six or more hours a day are at 60% higher risk of dying]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-top-court-rules-army-must-draft-ultra-orthodox-jewish-students-5965827]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's Top Court Rules Army Must Draft Ultra-Orthodox Jewish Students]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israels-top-court-rules-army-must-draft-ultra-orthodox-jewish-students-5965827]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:46:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel's Supreme Court ruled on Tuesday that the government must draft ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students to the conscript military, a decree likely to send shockwaves through Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's coalition.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel's Supreme Court ruled on Tuesday that the government must draft ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students to the conscript military, a decree likely to send shockwaves through Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's coalition.</p>

<p>Netanyahu's coalition relies for its survival on two ultra-Orthodox parties that regard longstanding conscription exemptions as key to keeping their constituents in religious seminaries and away from a melting-pot military that might test their conservative customs.</p>

<p>The ultra-Orthodox conscription waiver has become especially charged as Israel's armed forces, made up mostly of teenage conscripts and older civilians mobilised for reserve duty, are overstretched by a multi-front war, in Gaza and Lebanon.</p>

<p>"At the height of a difficult war, the burden of inequality is more than ever acute," the court's unanimous ruling said.</p>

<p>Most Israelis are bound by law to serve in the military, whereas ultra-Orthodox Jewish seminary students have been largely exempt for decades.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/58dhodfo_israel-ultraorthodox-jewish-students-reuters-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Most Israelis, except the ultra-Orthodox Jewish students, have been law-bound to serve in the military.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-hajj-routes-claim-hundreds-of-lives-a-grave-warning-to-pilgrims-5965749]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Illegal Hajj Routes Claim Hundreds Of Lives: A Grave Warning To Pilgrims]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/illegal-hajj-routes-claim-hundreds-of-lives-a-grave-warning-to-pilgrims-5965749]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:35:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hundreds of people died during this year's Hajj pilgrimage due to the extreme heat in Mecca with temperatures soaring past 50 degrees Celsius.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hundreds of people died during this year's Hajj pilgrimage due to the extreme heat in Mecca with temperatures soaring past 50 degrees Celsius. An alarming 83% of these victims were those who took illegal routes, highlighting the perilous risks involved with the pilgrimage.</p>

<p>The Saudi government disclosed that many of the victims had paid exorbitant sums to illegal tour operators, hoping to circumvent official channels. Instead of being transported comfortably in air-conditioned buses and housed in safe, regulated accommodations, these pilgrims found themselves exposed to the scorching desert heat, walking for miles amid extreme heat.</p>

<p><strong>What Are Hajj Permits</strong></p>

<p>The Hajj is one of the five pillars of Islam that all Muslims with the means must complete at least once in their lives.</p>

<p>Hajj permits are allocated to countries on a quota system and distributed to individuals by lottery.</p>

<p>Why Do Pilgrims Take Illegal Routes?</p>

<p>Cost: Some experts say that travelling without a permit is a cheaper alternative to official permits, each of which can cost thousands of dollars.</p>

<p>Convenience: Others seek to avoid lengthy application processes and waiting lists.</p>

<p>Lack of awareness: Some pilgrims may be unaware of the risks and legal requirements.</p>

<p>What Are The Risks Associated With Illegal Hajj Visit</p>

<p>Physical harm: Pilgrims may face harsh desert conditions, dehydration, and exhaustion while traversing treacherous terrain.</p>

<p>Arrest and deportation: Those caught taking illegal routes may be detained, fined, and deported.</p>

<p>Health risks: Unverified vaccinations and medical screenings increase the risk of contracting and spreading diseases.</p>

<p>Exploitation: Pilgrims may fall prey to human traffickers, scams, and extortion.</p>

<p>What Is The Government Doing</p>

<p>On Saturday, Egyptian Prime Minister Mostafa Madbouly ordered 16 tourism companies stripped of their licences and referred their managers to the public prosecutor over illegal pilgrimages to Mecca, Egypt's cabinet said.</p>

<p>It said the rise in the number of deaths of unregistered Egyptian pilgrims stemmed from some companies which "organised the Hajj programmes using a personal visit visa, which prevents its holders from entering Mecca" via official channels.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/e1r8ouk8_hajj-afp_625x300_28_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-fresh-israeli-airstrikes-kill-24-in-gaza-as-tanks-deepen-incursion-into-rafah-5965552]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Airstrikes Kill 24 In Gaza As Tanks Deepen Incursion Into Rafah]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-fresh-israeli-airstrikes-kill-24-in-gaza-as-tanks-deepen-incursion-into-rafah-5965552]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 14:05:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces killed at least 24 Palestinians in three separate airstrikes on Gaza City early on Tuesday, health officials said, while tanks deepened their incursion into the town of Rafah in the south of the enclave.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces killed at least 24 Palestinians in three separate airstrikes on Gaza City early on Tuesday, health officials said, while tanks deepened their incursion into the town of Rafah in the south of the enclave.</p>

<p>Two of the strikes hit two schools in Gaza City, killing at least 14 people, medics said. Another strike on a house in the Shati (Beach) camp, one of the Gaza Strip's eight historic refugee camps, killed 10 others.</p>

<p>The house in Shati belonged to the extended family of Hamas political chief, Ismail Haniyeh, who is based in Qatar, killing one of his sisters along with other relatives too, family members and medics said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh, who leads Hamas' diplomacy and is the public face of the group that has been running Gaza, has lost many of his relatives in Israeli air strikes since Oct. 7, including three of his sons.</p>

<p>Israel's military said its forces had targeted militants overnight in Gaza City who had been involved in the planning of attacks on Israel. The operatives included some involved in holding hostages captive and some who had taken part in Hamas' cross-border attack on Oct. 7.</p>

<p>The Israeli Air Force struck two structures "used by Hamas terrorists in Shati and Daraj Tuffah in the northern Gaza Strip. The terrorists operated inside school compounds that were used by Hamas as a shield for its terrorist activities", the military statement said.</p>

<p>Hamas denies using civilian facilities such as schools and hospitals for military purposes.</p>

<p>More than eight months into the fighting, international mediation backed by the United States has so far failed to bring a ceasefire agreement. Hamas says any agreement must bring an end to the war, while Israel says it will agree to only temporary pauses in fighting until Hamas is eradicated.</p>

<p>SHORTAGES OF MEDICINE</p>

<p>Israel's ground and air campaign in Gaza was triggered when Hamas-led operatives stormed into southern Israel on Oct. 7, killing around 1,200 people and seizing more than 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>The Israeli offensive in retaliation has killed almost 37,600 people, according to Palestinian health authorities, and has left the tiny, densely populated Gaza Strip in ruins.</p>

<p>Gaza's health ministry said on Tuesday that hospitals and medical centres in the enclave were experiencing a severe shortage of medicines and medical supplies due to the continued Israeli offensive, Israel's control and closure of all crossings and its targeting of the health sector in Gaza.</p>

<p>In particularly short supply are medications needed for emergency, anaesthesia, intensive care and operations, the ministry said in a statement, while cancer patients were unable to travel to hospitals.</p>

<p>Since early May, fighting has focused on Rafah, on Gaza's southern edge abutting the border with Egypt, where around half of the enclave's 2.3 million people have been sheltering after fleeing other areas.</p>

<p>Residents said fierce fighting had taken place overnight in western areas of Rafah, where tanks have extended their incursion in recent days, blowing up several homes in the area.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bdgi79g8_israel-airstrike-on-gaza-reuters_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gaza's health ministry said that hospitals and medical centres are experiencing a shortage of medicines.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hr-employee-in-singapore-jailed-for-giving-herself-148-000-in-unauthorised-pay-raise-5965425]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Singapore HR Jailed For Giving Herself $148,000 In Unauthorised Pay Raise]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hr-employee-in-singapore-jailed-for-giving-herself-148-000-in-unauthorised-pay-raise-5965425]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:48:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A human resource employee in Singapore has been jailed for 18 months for making bogus pay claims for herself involving $148,000.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A human resource employee in Singapore has been jailed for 18 months for making bogus pay claims for herself involving $148,000. According to the <em>South China Morning Post (SCMP)</em>, Tan Lee Nah, 53, was in charge of the payroll system at D'Perception Singapore, an interior design firm. In May 2017, just two months after joining the company, she started to submit false claims for expenses, up until she was caught in November 2019. In these 2.5 years, she managed to give herself $148,000 in unauthorised pay rise to fund her child's tuition fee and her parent's medical bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/article/3265427/singapore-hr-boss-jailed-giving-herself-us148000-fake-pay-rises-fund-childs-tuition"><em>SCMP</em></a>, a judge said that Ms Tan treated the company's coffers like her "personal piggy bank". The court found that she claimed false travel expenses, ranging from $750 to $7,300 each month.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From January to November 2019, she added mobile phone expenses, paid holiday allowances and some extra expenses to her claims. In 2017, she was asked to transfer money to the Central Provident Fund (CPF) as two month's contributions for a new employee. However, she misappropriated the cheques and put them in her account, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Notably, Ms Tan was the sole person with the password to the company's payroll system, and it was routine practice for her to input all the staff's salaries into the system.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/contact-me-if-thief-in-china-leaves-note-for-owner-after-stealing-watch-and-laptop-5965077">"Contact Me If...": Thief In China Leaves Note For Owner After Stealing Watch And Laptop</a></strong></p>

<p>Her scheme was exposed when an employee saw a copy of Ms Tan's salary statement on the printer, which showed she had received allowances in addition to her basic salary. The employee alerted the management which then launched an investigation and called the police a month later.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The 53-year-old told the court that the money she had misappropriated was spent on her child's education and her parents' medical bills. She pleaded guilty on June 3 this year to two charges of sham reimbursement and one of criminal breach of trust for cashing two cheques. She had not compensated her employer because she lacked the financial means to do so.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-07/jail-generic_650x400_61469651050.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The employee pleaded guilty on June 3 this year. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-change-6-probe-carrying-samples-from-far-side-of-moon-returns-to-earth-5965227]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: China Probe Carrying Samples From Far Side Of Moon Returns To Earth]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-change-6-probe-carrying-samples-from-far-side-of-moon-returns-to-earth-5965227]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:19:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[China's Chang'e-6 lunar probe landed on Tuesday in the northern Chinese region of Inner Mongolia, making the country the first to bring back samples from the moon's far side.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China's Chang'e-6 lunar probe landed on Tuesday in the northern Chinese region of Inner Mongolia, making the country the first to bring back samples from the moon's far side.</p>

<p>The reentry capsule touched down at 2:07 p.m. Beijing time (0607 GMT), according to state broadcaster CCTV, carrying lunar soil collected earlier in the month by the probe after a successful landing on the moon's South Pole-Aitken Basin, an impact crater on the side of the Moon that always faces away from Earth.</p>

<p>Soon after the capsule landed, Zhang Kejian, head of the China National Space Administration, announced the successful completion of the Chang'e-6 lunar mission. Chinese President Xi Jinping said the mission's completion was a "landmark achievement" in China's quest to become a space and scientific powerhouse.</p>

<p>The Chang'e-6 probe was launched on May 3 on a Long March 5 rocket from the Wenchang Satellite Launch Center on the southern island of Hainan. According to CCTV, the samples will be transported by air to Beijing for analysis.</p>

<p>While it is yet not known whether the planned 2kg of samples were successfully returned, whatever the amount, the samples will be closely analysed by Chinese and foreign scientists, who believe that they will reveal new details about the formation of the Earth, moon, and solar system.</p>

<p>Samples from the Chang'e-5 mission, which brought back lunar samples from the near side of the moon, led to the discovery of new minerals and more accurate ranges for the moon's geological age.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">A recap of 53-day Chang'e-6 lunar mission. Launch, lunar landing, sampling, ascending, and returning back to earth! Full HD:<a href="https://t.co/X8PllBJAzY">https://t.co/X8PllBJAzY</a> <a href="https://t.co/L8Vyt4vgFN">pic.twitter.com/L8Vyt4vgFN</a></p>
— CNSA Watcher (@CNSAWatcher) <a href="https://twitter.com/CNSAWatcher/status/1805506974257143838?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The success of the Chang'e-6 mission could give China's lunar and space exploration program, already in close competition with the United States, greater pull among foreign governments and scientists.</p>

<p>China's retrieval of samples from the moon's far side comes as the exploration of lunar resources and the militarization of space are becoming increasingly pressing questions shaped by geopolitical tensions.</p>

<p>NASA administrator Bill Nelson this year expressed concern at China's lunar exploration program and described an intensifying "space race" between the two superpowers.</p>

<p>"I'm glad there has been a resurgence in this (space) race, but of course, I would like to see us racing alongside each other and together," said Neil Melville-Kenney, a technical officer at the European Space Agency (ESA) who is working with Chinese researchers on one of the Chang'e-6 payloads.</p>

<p>As the European Union and China are at loggerheads over a wide range of geopolitical issues, from trade to the war in Ukraine, European space agencies and scientists are working closely with Chinese counterparts on data and samples collected by China's lunar missions.</p>

<p>"We know that (the far side of the moon) is literally a different place, it is made of different materials than the near side of the moon, it has a different history... it's really of fundamental scientific importance to get these samples back," Melville-Kenney said.</p>

<p>The engineer added that the ESA will meet with the China National Space Administration in October to discuss further collaboration.</p>

<p>"This collaboration that we have at the moment (with China) is a small step, this was started quite a while ago, perhaps the situations were a little bit different then. Going forward I hope there will be more collaboration," he added.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/kb98208o_china-lunar-probe-x-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Chang'e-6 probe was launched on May 3 from the southern island of Hainan.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/greater-expectations-why-china-is-going-nuclear-faster-than-ever-5965117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Greater Expectations: Why China Is Going Nuclear 'Faster Than Ever']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/greater-expectations-why-china-is-going-nuclear-faster-than-ever-5965117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 13:00:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As per the US Defense Department's estimate, China will likely have over 1,000 operational warheads by 2030.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/jfceq2jo_xi-jinping-reuters-_625x300_07_December_23.jpeg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Recent data from the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nuclear-warheads-being-kept-operational-worldwide-watchdog-5905625">Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI)</a> shows that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-has-more-nuclear-weapons-than-pakistan-report-5909387">the world's nuclear powers</a> are continuing to expand investment in strengthening their arsenals. While the total number of warheads around the world is declining, the number of operational nuclear warheads is increasing. The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-putin-friends-are-helping-russia-upend-the-us-led-world-order-5691040">US and Russia</a>, of course, account for an overwhelming majority of nuclear warheads.</p>

<p>However, it is China that is reportedly expanding its nuclear arsenal "faster than any other country". SIPRI's researchers estimated the Chinese arsenal to be around 500 warheads, as of January 2024. As per the US Defense Department's estimate, China will likely have over 1,000 operational warheads by 2030. More importantly, the SIPRI report argues that for the first time, China is believed to have some warheads on high operational alert. In addition, over the past few years, there have been increasing reports on Chinese efforts to expand the number of its land-, sea-, and air-based delivery platforms and infrastructure, such as Intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM) silos.</p>

<h2><strong>"Assured Retaliation"</strong></h2>

<p>The Chinese nuclear strategy centres around deterrence through "assured retaliation", which is the ability to survive an initial attack and retaliate with nuclear strikes that inflict unacceptable damage on the aggressor. Moreover, like India, China has a long-standing no-first-use policy. Despite this, as detailed above, there has been a steady effort by Beijing to expand and modernise its nuclear forces. Three factors are important to grasp to understand why this has been the case.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-1-year-chinas-nuclear-arsenal-up-by-11-times-that-of-indias-5915463">Also Read |&nbsp;Explained: India Has More Nukes Than Pak, But China Races Ahead</a></strong></p>

<p>First, Chinese assessments of the international security landscape, particularly US policy, have undergone tremendous changes over the past decade. China's 2019 defence white paper was critical of adjustments in the American national security and defence strategies, while also warning of arms races. The Sino-US relationship has only worsened since. Increasingly, Beijing has come to believe that the US is pursuing a strategy of containment. Part of this approach entails strengthening American conventional military superiority while modernising strategic forces. Of particular concern has been the American discourse around 'low-yield' or tactical nuclear weapons. Chinese analysts have argued that US policy appears to be lowering the threshold for the use of nuclear weapons. Moreover, the concern in Beijing appears to be that American missile defence capabilities and new conventional systems, along with improvements in cyber and electronic warfare, could undermine China's retaliatory strike capability.</p>

<h2><strong>"Maintain Readiness"</strong></h2>

<p>The 2019 defence white paper, therefore, called on the People's Liberation Army (PLA) to "maintain the appropriate level of readiness and enhance strategic deterrence capability". Subsequently, in March 2021, Xi Jinping directed the military to "accelerate the construction of advanced strategic deterrent" capabilities. Finally, in his work report to the 20th Party Congress, Xi committed to establishing "a strong system of strategic deterrence" and increasing "the proportion of new-domain forces with new combat capabilities". This is particularly critical given the heightened tensions around Taiwan. A modernised Chinese nuclear force potentially provides greater room for manoeuvre for Beijing in case of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-could-take-control-of-taiwan-without-firing-a-shot-warns-report-5949602">conflict in the Taiwan Strait.</a></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-increases-defence-budget-by-7-2-amid-rising-regional-tensions-5179889"><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;China Increases Defence Budget By 7.2% Amid Rising Regional Tensions</strong></a></p>

<p>Second, as per the 2019 defence white paper, one of the goals of enhancing strategic deterrence capability is to "maintain international strategic stability". This, of course, is a significant expansion of the goals of Chinese defence policy from simply safeguarding national sovereignty and security. It also is indicative of what Beijing views as necessary instruments of power that great powers must possess. In other words, there is an element of status-seeking that is driving the Chinese nuclear modernisation programme. For instance, early in his reign in December 2012, Xi had termed the Second Artillery Corps, which was later upgraded to the PLA Rocket Force, as "a strategic pillar of China's great power status". This does not mean that Beijing desires nuclear parity with the US or Russia. Rather, it implies that nuclear power is being viewed as an instrument of power that needs to be cultivated to achieve political equality among major powers.</p>

<h2><strong>The Stalled US-China Talks</strong></h2>

<p>This dovetails into the third and final point, i.e., building negotiation power and setting global rules. After an extremely long hiatus, China and the US resumed official nuclear dialogue in November last year. Both sides described the dialogue as "candid" and "in-depth", but there were no significant outcomes. The US side demanded greater "transparency" and "substantive engagement" from China, while Beijing stressed the importance of "mutual respect" and the need to adhere to "the vision of common, comprehensive, cooperative and sustainable security". More substantive talks have since not progressed, although the first Track II dialogue between the two sides in five years was held in March. China, meanwhile, has moved to call on nuclear-armed states to negotiate a no-first-use treaty or political declaration. Beijing understands that shaping new rules can only be done from a position of strength.</p>

<p>From an Indian perspective, therefore, it is important to not view China's nuclear force modernisation simply from the prism of parity and asymmetry. There are broader issues, such as great power conflagrations leading to a nuclear exchange, which must be taken into account. Some of these issues, such as the threat of increased proliferation and support for Pakistan, are a matter of deeper concern. Others, meanwhile, such as the call for a no-first-use treaty, can provide opportunities for making common cause.</p>

<p><em>(Manoj Kewalramani is the Chairperson of the Indo-Pacific Studies Programme at the Takshashila Institution.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/jfceq2jo_xi-jinping-reuters-_625x300_07_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-daughter-suri-drops-cruise-adopts-mother-katie-holmes-middle-name-5964969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Brad Pitt's Children, Tom Cruise's Daughter Suri Drops Father's Name]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-daughter-suri-drops-cruise-adopts-mother-katie-holmes-middle-name-5964969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:38:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Suri Cruise, the daughter of Hollywood icons Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes, has dropped her father's surname.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Suri Cruise, the daughter of Hollywood icons Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes, has dropped her father's surname. The 18-year-old graduated from LaGuardia High School with her mother, Katie Holmes, by her side, under the name "Suri Noelle". This name was also adopted earlier in the year for a school production of the play ‘Head Over Heels'. "Noelle" is Katie Holmes' middle name, reported <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/06/22/parents/suri-cruise-celebrates-high-school-graduation-with-mom-katie-holmes/">Page Six</a>.<br />
<br />
Her father, Tom Cruise reportedly missed the graduation weekend to attend Taylor Swift's Eras tour in London, where he is filming for the next ‘Mission: Impossible' film, reports say.<br />
<br />
Tom Cruise's relationship with his children, especially Suri, has been complex following his divorce from Katie Holmes in 2012.<br />
<br />
Amid rumours suggesting Tom Cruise had distanced himself from Suri, the actor vehemently denied these claims in a <a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment/gossip/la-et-mg-tom-cruise-suri-abandoned-lawsuit-20131106-story.html ">2013 defamation lawsuit</a>, stating he had not abandoned his daughter in any way – emotionally, physically, financially or otherwise. He called these claims “patently false.”<br />
<br />
The <em>Jack Reacher</em> actor stated that he “spoke on the phone nearly every day” with Suri, then 6 years old, and claimed that he “regularly asked for and received updates concerning her friends and school life.”<br />
<br />
The 61-year-old also has two adopted children, Isabella and Connor, from his previous marriage to Nicole Kidman. He was seen in public with them last year, reportedly for the first time in 15 years.<br />
<br />
Suri's decision comes just weeks after Brad Pitt's children, Shiloh and Vivienne, also dropped their famous surname, now going by <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/angelina-jolie-and-brad-pitts-daughter-shiloh-files-to-drop-pitt-from-name-5794688#:~:text=Angelina%20Jolie%20and%20Brad%20Pitt's%20daughter%20Shiloh%20Jolie%2DPitt%20has,is%20Shiloh%20Nouvel%20Jolie%2DPitt. ">Shiloh Nouvel Jolie </a>and Vivienne Jolie, respectively.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/3nel9jpc_suri-cruise_625x300_25_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-diplomat-says-need-chinese-students-in-humanities-indian-for-sciences-5961852]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Need Chinese Students In Humanities, Indian For Sciences: US Diplomat]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-diplomat-says-need-chinese-students-in-humanities-indian-for-sciences-5961852]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:27:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US should welcome more students from China, but to study the humanities rather than sciences, the second-ranked US diplomat said on Monday]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US should welcome more students from China, but to study the humanities rather than sciences, the second-ranked US diplomat said on Monday, noting that US universities are limiting Chinese students' access to sensitive technology given security concerns.</p>

<p>Deputy Secretary of State Kurt Campbell said not enough Americans were studying science, technology, engineering and mathematics. He said the US needed to recruit more international students for those fields, but from India - an increasingly important US security partner - not China.</p>

<p>For years, Chinese students have made up the largest foreign student body in the US and totaled nearly 290,000 in the 2022/23 academic year. But some in academia and civil society argue that deteriorating US-China relations and concerns about theft of US expertise, have derailed scientific cooperation and subjected Chinese students to unwarranted suspicion.</p>

<p>"I would like to see more Chinese students coming to the United States to study humanities and social sciences, not particle physics," Campbell told the Council on Foreign Relations think-tank.</p>

<p>Campbell was asked about the China Initiative introduced by the Trump administration, intended to combat Chinese espionage and intellectual property theft, which ended under the Biden administration after critics said it spurred racial profiling of Asian Americans.</p>

<p>Campbell said US universities had made "careful attempts" to support continuing higher education for Chinese students, but had also been "careful about the labs, some of the activities of Chinese students."</p>

<p>"I do think it is possible to curtail and to limit certain kinds of access, and we have seen that generally, particularly in technological programs across the United States," he said.</p>

<p>Campbell said some had suggested that China was the only source to make up the shortage of science students.</p>

<p>"I believe that the largest increase that we need to see going forward would be much larger numbers of Indian students that come to study in American universities on a range of technology and other fields."</p>

<p>Campbell said the US had to be careful to not eliminate links between China and the US, but officials in Beijing were largely to blame for any withering in academic, business or non-profit sector ties.</p>

<p>"It really has been China that has made it difficult for the kinds of activities that we would like to see sustaining," Campbell said, adding that foreign executives and philanthropists were wary about long-term stays in China due to concerns about personal security.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/fgv3ukm8_university-of-north-carolina-generic-reuters_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US diplomat said US had to be careful to not eliminate links between China and US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-unique-mini-city-in-space-the-international-space-station-5964898]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[As Big As A Football Field, 16 Orbits Of Earth In 24 Hours: All About ISS]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-unique-mini-city-in-space-the-international-space-station-5964898]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:26:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The International Space Station (ISS), a remarkable feat of human engineering and international collaboration, has been orbiting Earth for 25 years. Here are ten fascinating facts about this cosmic outpost:]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The International Space Station (ISS), a remarkable feat of human engineering and international collaboration, has been orbiting Earth for 25 years. Here are ten fascinating facts about this cosmic outpost:</p>

<p><strong>Size and Weight: </strong>The ISS, akin to a mini-city in space, weighs a staggering 419 tonnes and spans the length of a football field, measuring 109 meters end to end.</p>

<p><strong>Scientific Hub: </strong>It serves primarily as a research laboratory where scientists from around the world conduct experiments in microgravity conditions, invaluable for advancements in biology, physics, astronomy, and materials science.</p>

<p><strong>Costly Endeavor: </strong>Constructing and maintaining the ISS has been a monumental financial effort, surpassing $150 billion since its inception.</p>

<p><strong>Operational Dynamics: </strong>Circling the Earth at an astounding speed of 28,165.00 kilometers per hour, the ISS completes 16 orbits daily, providing astronauts aboard with 16 sunrises and sunsets within 24 hours.</p>

<p><strong>International Collaboration: </strong>A partnership involving five space agencies from 15 countries manages the ISS, although India remains outside this consortium.</p>

<p><strong>Human Presence: </strong>Since November 2000, the ISS has continuously housed astronauts, offering a living and working environment larger than a typical six-bedroom house. It includes amenities like two bathrooms, a gymnasium, and a panoramic bay window for a breathtaking 360-degree view of Earth.</p>

<p><strong>Sustainable Living: </strong>To ensure self-sufficiency, the ISS employs advanced recycling systems that purify sweat and urine into potable water, a crucial innovation for prolonged space missions.</p>

<p><strong>Microbial Evolution:</strong> Despite its sterile appearance, the closed environment of the ISS fosters the development of resilient microorganisms dubbed 'super bugs,' posing unique challenges for crew health and station maintenance.</p>

<p><strong>Visible Wonder:</strong> As it orbits overhead, the ISS is visible to the naked eye from Earth. Enthusiasts can track its path through the night sky using resources provided by NASA.</p>

<p><strong>Future Prospects:</strong> While no Indian has yet visited the ISS, plans are underway for an Indian astronaut to embark on a mission there soon. India also aims to establish its own space station, the Bhartiya Antariksha Station, by 2040, reflecting a growing ambition in space exploration.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/bp8pog74_international-space-station-getty_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-at-candidates-competing-for-irans-presidential-vote-after-ebrahim-raisis-death-5964742]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Look At Candidates Competing For Iran's Presidential Vote This Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-look-at-candidates-competing-for-irans-presidential-vote-after-ebrahim-raisis-death-5964742]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 12:01:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iranians will choose between mostly hardline candidates in an early presidential election on June 28 following the death of Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash last month.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iranians will choose between mostly hardline candidates in an early presidential election on June 28 following the death of Ebrahim Raisi in a helicopter crash last month.</p>

<p>Only six candidates from over 80 hopefuls survived screening by the hardline Guardian Council, a panel of clerics and jurists which is overseen by the Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, who has the final say in all matters of state.</p>

<p>The president, who runs the government day-to-day and has a particular responsibility for Iran's struggling economy, ultimately answers to the Supreme Leader.</p>

<p>Following are brief sketches of five hardliners and one moderate candidate for the upcoming election:</p>

<h3><strong>MOHAMMAD BAQER QALIBAF</strong></h3>

<p>A former Iran Revolutionary Guards commander and ally of Khamenei, Qalibaf is the current speaker of the hardline-dominated parliament. He previously ran unsuccessfully for president twice and was compelled to withdraw from a third bid in 2017 to prevent a divided hardline vote in Raisi's initial failed presidential attempt.</p>

<p>In 2005, Qalibaf resigned from the Guards to run for president. Following his unsuccessful campaign, he assumed the position of Tehran mayor with the supreme leader's endorsement, a role he occupied for 12 years.</p>

<p>In 2009, Qalibaf took credit as Tehran mayor for helping suppress months of bloody unrest that rocked the establishment after a presidential vote that opposition candidates said was rigged to secure hardline Mahmoud Ahmadinejad's re-election.</p>

<p>To civil rights activists, he is known as someone who crushed protests as national police chief, personally beating demonstrators in 1999, and also played an active role in repressing unrest in 2003. Qalibaf did not reply to a request for comment on those allegations.</p>

<h3><strong>SAEED JALILI</strong></h3>

<p>Jalili is a hardline diplomat who lost his right leg in the 1980s when fighting for the Guards in the Iran-Iraq war. Holder of a PhD in political science, Jalili has declared being a pious believer in Iran's "velayat-e faqih", or rule by supreme jurisprudence, a system of Islamic government that provides the basis for Khamenei's position.</p>

<p>Appointed by Khamenei, Jalili served as secretary of the Supreme National Security Council for five years from 2007, a position that automatically made him chief nuclear negotiator. Jalili also served for four years in Khamenei's office and was an unsuccessful candidate in the 2013 presidential election.</p>

<p>A former deputy foreign minister, Jalili was appointed by Khamenei in 2013 as a member of the Expediency Council, a body that mediates disputes between parliament and the Guardian Council.</p>

<h3><strong>MASSOUD PEZESHKIAN</strong></h3>

<p>An Iranian lawmaker of Azeri ethnicity, Pezeshkian is the only moderate candidate approved by the Guardian Council and backed by the pro-reform camp. His prospects depend on attracting millions of disillusioned voters who have stayed home in elections since 2020.</p>

<p>A physician by profession, Pezeshkian served as the health minister under reformist President Mohammad Khatami from 2001 to 2005 and has held a seat in parliament since 2008.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian has been vocal in his criticism of the Islamic Republic for its lack of transparency about the death in custody of Mahsa Amini, a young Iranian Kurdish woman in 2022 that sparked several months of unrest.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian was barred from the 2021 presidential election.</p>

<h3><strong>MOSTAFA POURMOHAMMADI</strong></h3>

<p>The only cleric in the race, Pourmohammadi served as interior minister during the first term of hardline former president Mahmoud Ahmadinejad from 2005 until 2008.</p>

<p>He was deputy intelligence minister from 1990 to 1999, and rights groups have alleged that he played a role in the assassinations inside Iran of several prominent dissident intellectuals in 1998. He has not commented on the allegations but an Intelligence Ministry statement in 1998 said: "A small number of irresponsible, deviant and rogue agents of the ministry who were most likely puppets of others committed these assassinations that were in the interest of foreigners."</p>

<p>Human Rights Watch, in a 2005 report, documented Pourmohammadi's alleged role in the execution of hundreds of political prisoners in the Iranian capital in 1988.</p>

<p>Pourmohammadi has never publicly addressed allegations about his role in a so-called "death committee" in 1988 comprising religious judges, prosecutors, and intelligence ministry officials who oversaw the executions.</p>

<h3><strong>ALIREZA ZAKANI</strong></h3>

<p>Tehran's hardline mayor and a former lawmaker, Zakani was disqualified in 2013 and 2017 from running for president.</p>

<p>The former commander of the Guards' affiliated volunteer Basij militia, Zakani withdrew from the 2021 presidential race to endorse Raisi's candidacy. But in a post on X, Zakani said "In the 2024 election, I will stay and compete until the end to continue the path of (Raisi)."</p>

<h3><strong>AMIRHOSSEIN GHAZIZADEH-HASHEMI</strong></h3>

<p>Incumbent vice president and head of the Martyrs' Foundation, Ghazizadeh-Hashemi is a hardline former lawmaker who received a low vote tally in the 2021 presidential election.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/506kg01o_iran-presidential-candidates_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Only six candidates from over 80 hopefuls survived screening by the hardline Guardian Council.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sends-more-trash-filled-balloons-towards-south-korea-5964570]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Sends More Trash-Filled Balloons Towards South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-sends-more-trash-filled-balloons-towards-south-korea-5964570]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 25 Jun 2024 11:39:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea has sent hundreds more trash-filled balloons southward, Seoul's military said Tuesday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have sparked a tit-for-tat propoganda campaign.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea has sent hundreds more trash-filled balloons southward, Seoul's military said Tuesday, the latest in a series of border barrages that have sparked a tit-for-tat propaganda campaign.</p>

<p>Pyongyang launched about 350 balloons Monday evening, Seoul's Joint Chiefs of Staff said, adding that around 100 had landed in the South, mainly in northern Gyeonggi province and the capital Seoul.</p>

<p>The bags attached to the balloons contained "mostly paper waste", the military said, adding that they posed no safety risk to the public, according to their analysis.</p>

<p>"The South Korean military is ready to carry out its psychological warfare immediately," the JCS said, adding the response "all depends on North Korea's actions".</p>

<p>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol said the North's latest round of trash-carrying balloons was a "despicable and irrational provocation" in a speech marking the anniversary of the start of the Korean War.</p>

<p>He slammed a deal between Pyongyang and Moscow, signed last week by Russian President Vladimir Putin during a state visit to North Korea, as a "blatant violation of UN Security Council resolutions",</p>

<p>"Our military will maintain a steadfast readiness to ensure that North Korea does not dare to challenge South Korea under any circumstances and will respond overwhelmingly and decisively to any provocations from the North," Yoon added.</p>

<p>Pyongyang has already sent more than a thousand balloons carrying trash southward in what it says is retaliation for balloons carrying anti-regime propaganda floated north by activists.</p>

<p>In response, Seoul has fully suspended a tension-reducing military deal and restarted some propaganda broadcasts from loudspeakers along the border.</p>

<p>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un's sister and key government spokeswoman Kim Yo Jong warned earlier this month that if the leaflet drops and loudspeaker broadcasts continued, Seoul would "undoubtedly witness the new counteraction of the DPRK".</p>

<p>Experts said border tensions could potentially escalate quickly.</p>

<p>"Since the South has met the first condition -- which is the leaflet scattering -- if the government were to resume loudspeakers, we would likely see the 'new counteraction' that was mentioned," said Park Won-gon, a professor at Ewha Womens University.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/8nf5v9cg_trash-balloons-north-korea-reuters-_625x300_25_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Pyongyang has already sent more than a thousand balloons carrying trash southward.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>