<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:47:39 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-un-peacekeepers-injured-in-latest-israeli-airstrikes-on-lebanon-6966885]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed, UN Peacekeepers Injured In Latest Israeli Airstrikes On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-un-peacekeepers-injured-in-latest-israeli-airstrikes-on-lebanon-6966885]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:36:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Lebanese army said an Israeli strike on a vehicle near a checkpoint in the southern city of Sidon on Thursday killed three people and wounded troops and UN peacekeepers.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Lebanese army said an Israeli strike on a vehicle near a checkpoint in the southern city of Sidon on Thursday killed three people and wounded troops and UN peacekeepers.</p>

<p>"The Israeli enemy targeted a car while it was passing through the Awali checkpoint," the main northern entrance to Sidon, the army said.</p>

<p>With the exception of a few limited strikes, Sidon, a Sunni Muslim-majority city, has been relatively spared the deadly air raids targeting south Lebanon in Israel's war against the Iran-backed Hezbollah movement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The strike killed three people, all of them passengers in the targeted vehicle, the army said.</p>

<p>Three Lebanese soldiers manning the checkpoint were also wounded alongside members of the Malaysian contingent of UNIFIL, according to the army.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UNIFIL peacekeeping force said a "convoy bringing newly-arrived peacekeepers to south Lebanon was passing Sidon when a drone strike occurred nearby."</p>

<p>"Five peacekeepers were lightly injured and treated by the Lebanese Red Cross on the spot. They will continue to their posts," it said, urging warring parties "to avoid actions putting peacekeepers or civilians in danger."</p>

<h3><strong>UNIFIL has thousands of peacekeepers&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Lebanon's official National News Agency said a UNIFIL vehicle was on the "same lane" during the strike, which left UN peacekeepers with "minor injuries".&nbsp;</p>

<p>An AFP correspondent in the area saw the charred, mangled remains of the targeted vehicle which was only a few metres away from an army checkpoint.</p>

<p>The correspondent saw UNIFIL peacekeepers gathered on the sidewalk near the checkpoint, some of them bloodied and wounded after the raid, as paramedics attended to their injuries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UNIFIL convoy comprised a number of busses, the correspondent said.</p>

<p>Israeli raids have intensified in recent weeks on Haret Saida, a densely-populated Sidon suburb that has a significant population of Shiite Muslims.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel has also increasingly launched targeted strikes on vehicles. A woman was killed Thursday in an Israeli strike targeting a car on a key road linking the capital Beirut with the Bekaa Valley and Syria, a security source told AFP.</p>

<p>Lebanon's National News Agency reported earlier that "an enemy drone targeted a car in Araya," adding that the strike left the route blocked to vehicular traffic.</p>

<p>The highway links Beirut to the Syrian capital of Damascus, through the Lebanese mountains.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/vamtjmug_southern-lebanon-_625x300_28_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israeli raids have intensified in recent weeks on Haret Saida. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/go-work-for-another-company-amazon-group-firm-ceo-to-employees-protesting-end-of-wfh-6966800]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Go Work For...": Amazon CEO To Employees Protesting End Of WFH]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/go-work-for-another-company-amazon-group-firm-ceo-to-employees-protesting-end-of-wfh-6966800]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 20:24:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[523 Amazon employees protested the "return to office" policy and urged management to maintain remote work flexibility.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 500 Amazon Web Services (AWS) employees have petitioned the company to reconsider its new five-day in-office mandate, which is set to begin in January. In a letter to AWS CEO Matt Garman, 523 employees voiced opposition to the "return to office" policy and urged management to maintain remote work flexibility.</p>

<p>"AWS is not realizing its full potential with this mandate, and it is setting a discouraging path forward," the letter shared with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/amazon/amazon-employees-protest-5-day-a-week-office-return/"><em>The Seattle Times</em></a> stated. "While flexible and remote work does have its challenges, AWS has always been a company that tackles problems in innovative, forward-thinking ways, rather than falling back on outdated solutions that worked in the past. The cloud computing industry might not exist today if we had held onto such restrictive thinking in our early days."</p>

<p>Amazon CEO Andy Jassy previously announced in a memo that the policy would begin on January 2, 2025. Prior to this change, Amazon required employees to be in the office three days a week, a shift that sparked protests as well. About 15 months after that initial mandate, Amazon is now expanding the requirement to restore pre-pandemic work norms.</p>

<p>The recent letter from AWS employees responds to Garman's comments at an AWS town hall, where he suggested employees who don't wish to comply with the new five-day rule could explore other job options. Last week, Garman reiterated this stance in an interview, expressing confidence in the policy and stating that most employees he spoke to are supportive of the change. Garman and Jassy have acknowledged that while there may be flexibility under the new policy, such as managers occasionally working from home for specific tasks, the core requirement remains in place.</p>

<p>AWS employees argued in the letter that Garman's comments do not align with their own experiences, claiming, "You are silencing critical perspectives and harming our culture and future." They also contended that Amazon's decision lacked data-backed analysis, contradicting one of Amazon's key principles, and noted that the policy might hinder Amazon's goal of becoming "Earth's best employer."</p>

<p>The mandate is expected to particularly affect employees who depend on remote work flexibility, such as those with disabilities, caregiving duties, or visa restrictions. The employees also suggested that the mandate may drive senior staff members who often have the credentials and financial flexibility to seek other roles away from Amazon, potentially impacting the collaborative culture the company aims to foster.</p>

<p>The new policy will make Amazon one of the few major tech companies in Seattle with such a stringent in-office requirement. Starbucks recently implemented a similar approach, requiring corporate employees to work from the office three days a week starting in January, with non-compliance leading to potential job changes.</p>

<p>In their letter, AWS employees reiterated their desire for Amazon to reconsider its stance, emphasizing, "Remote and flexible work represents an opportunity for Amazon to lead, not a threat. We want to work for leaders who see this moment as a chance to reinvent how we work."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Amazon CEO Andy Jassy said at an all-hands meeting on Tuesday that the plan to require employees to be in-office five days per week is not meant to force attrition or satisfy city leaders, as many employees have suggested, Reuters reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A number of people I've seen theorized that the reason we were doing this is, it's a backdoor layoff, or we made some sort of deal with city or cities," said Jassy, according to a transcript of the meeting reviewed by Reuters.</p>

<p>"I can tell you both of those are not true. You know, this was not a cost play for us. This is very much about our culture and strengthening our culture," he said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/jhsuuj3o_amazon-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mandate is expected to particularly affect employees who depend on remote work flexibility]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-sees-window-to-end-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-after-donald-trumps-victory-6966511]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Sees 'Window' To End Wars In Gaza, Lebanon After Trump's Victory]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-sees-window-to-end-wars-in-gaza-lebanon-after-donald-trumps-victory-6966511]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:41:52 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot said Thursday in Jerusalem he saw prospects for ending Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon after Donald Trump was elected US president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrot said Thursday in Jerusalem he saw prospects for ending Israel's wars in Gaza and Lebanon after Donald Trump was elected US president.</p>

<p>"I believe a window has opened for putting an end to the tragedy in which Israelis, Palestinians, and the entire region have been immersed since October 7" last year, Barrot told reporters in Jerusalem.</p>

<p>Speaking alongside outgoing Israeli Foreign Minister Israel Katz, Barrot cited Trump's "wish to see the end of the Middle East's endless wars" as well as Israel's recent "tactical successes".</p>

<p>Barrot said he hoped a "diplomatic solution" would emerge "in the coming weeks".</p>

<p>"Force alone will not be enough to guarantee Israel's security," he said, adding that "military success could not be a substitute for a political perspective".</p>

<p>"It is time to move towards a deal that would allow for the liberation of all hostages, a ceasefire, and the mass entry of humanitarian aid into Gaza, and to prepare for the day after."</p>

<p>Barrot said "Israel has the right to defend itself" but pointed to "colonisation", "humanitarian aid restrictions" and "the continuation of air strikes in north Gaza" as risk factors for Israel's security.</p>

<p>Barrot is expected to speak with Palestinian Authority president Mahmud Abbas and his prime minister, Muhammad Mustafa.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/f78af2v8_-jeannoel-barrot-afp-_625x300_30_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Barrot said he hoped a "diplomatic solution" would emerge "in coming weeks".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-must-prepare-for-climate-calamity-un-chief-6966373]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["World Must Prepare For Climate Calamity": UN Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/world-must-prepare-for-climate-calamity-un-chief-6966373]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:25:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world is nowhere near ready for the "calamity" being caused by climate change and must urgently prepare for even worse in the future, UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world is nowhere near ready for the "calamity" being caused by climate change and must urgently prepare for even worse in the future, UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres said Thursday.</p>

<p>Global efforts to adapt to climate change -- from building defensive sea walls to planting drought-resistant crops -- have not kept pace as global warming accelerates the frequency and intensity of disasters.</p>

<p>Floods, fires and other climate shocks have affected nearly every continent in a year the EU climate monitor says is almost certain to be the hottest ever recorded.</p>

<p>The amount of money going to poorer countries for adaptation measures was barely one-tenth of what they needed to disaster-proof their vulnerable economies, the UN Environment Programme (UNEP) said in a new assessment looking at 2022, the latest year for which data is available.</p>

<p>"Climate calamity is the new reality. And we're not keeping up," said Guterres at the launch of UNEP's annual Adaptation Gap Report.</p>

<p>Rich nations are under pressure at this month's UN COP29 summit to substantially increase the $100 billion they pledged for climate action in developing countries, including for adaptation.</p>

<p>But some donor governments are under fiscal and political pressure, and major new commitments of public money are not expected at the conference in Azerbaijan.</p>

<p>A UN biodiversity meeting this month failed to reach a funding agreement and the election of Donald Trump -- who opposes global climate cooperation -- hangs over COP29.</p>

<h3><strong>No one immune</strong></h3>

<p>Most of the public money committed to climate change goes to reducing planet-warming emissions, not adapting to its long-term consequences.</p>

<p>Some $28 billion in public finance was paid to developing countries for climate adaptation in 2022.</p>

<p>This was an increase on the year prior, but still a drop in the ocean: UNEP estimates between $215 billion and $387 billion is needed annually for adaptation in developing countries.</p>

<p>Rich countries had pledged to double the amount by 2025 to roughly $40 billion a year but even this would leave an "extremely large" adaptation funding gap, UNEP said.</p>

<p>Climate disasters hit poorest communities hardest but the cost of inaction was no longer borne by them alone, said Patrick Verkooijen, CEO of the Global Center on Adaptation.</p>

<p>"From rising seas and extreme heat waves to relentless droughts and floods, the impacts of climate change now reach every corner of the globe. No nation, no community is immune," he said in a statement.</p>

<p>Spanish authorities were accused of being inadequately prepared when a major storm brought flooding that killed over 200 people last month.</p>

<p>Climate scientists say that global warming is fuelling more frequent and severe extreme weather.</p>

<p>"We can't postpone protection. We must adapt -- now," Guterres said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/otldtf18_antonio-guterres_625x300_19_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[loods, fires and other climate shocks have affected nearly every continent in a year.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-command-china-space-military-technology-china-is-common-adversary-in-space-military-race-warns-top-us-general-6966358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["China Is Common Adversary In Space-Military Race", Warns Top US General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-space-command-china-space-military-technology-china-is-common-adversary-in-space-military-race-warns-top-us-general-6966358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:22:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States wants to broaden cooperation and collaboration with India in space technology - particularly as it relates to militarisation of the 'final frontier' to deny common adversaries like China - a top US Space Command official told NDTV.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/united-states" target="_blank">United States</a> wants to broaden cooperation and collaboration with <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/india" target="_blank">India</a> in space technology - particularly as it relates to militarisation of the 'final frontier' to deny common adversaries like <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/china" target="_blank">China</a> - Major General Brian W Gibson, the strategy chief of the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/us-space-command" target="_blank">US Space Command</a>, told NDTV.</p>

<p>In Delhi to meet top military and space agency officials, Major Gibson red-flagged Beijing's space programme, saying, "China is advancing at a breath-taking pace in the military use of space tech."</p>

<p>"Conflict in space is not inevitable... just like every other domain. And one way we seek to deter (our enemies) is to not go it alone... we go together, we do it together. So that is my purpose here - to broaden our relationship, collaborate where we can and where we have shared interests."</p>

<p>The reality of the world as it is today, the Major said, is that much of the focus is on the US and India, and the challenges the two countries face together from "potential adversaries like China".</p>

<p>"Their advance is breath-taking... in the military aspect of space alone, let alone the commercial."</p>

<p>The Major's visit to Delhi - which experts say signals a major shift in Washington, D.C.'s space command policy - comes on the heels of Donald Trump's big win in this week's election.</p>

<p>Mr Trump beat his Democrat rival, outgoing Vice President Kamala Harris, in the 2024 US Presidential election and will, in January, be installed as the 47th President of the United States.</p>

<p>Major Gibson's words of warning - re: China - are not a new development.</p>

<p>In September last year the US Space Force - the US military's space service, established during Mr Trump's first term - said it had <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-exploring-potential-hotline-with-china-to-prevent-space-crises-general-4422109" target="_blank">internal discussions about a 'hotline' to prevent space crises</a>.</p>

<p>The comments came as the Space Force looked into establishing a Japan branch; this was in response to China's continuing military ambitions in the Indo-Pacific and the Ukraine war.</p>

<p>The Space Force's commander, General Chance Saltzman, told Reuters then that close co-operation with "like-minded countries" would be crucial in being able to monitor and understand activity in the space domain, and to deter China and counter 'grey zone activities' like jamming satellite signals.</p>

<p>Further back, in 2022, the then Commander of the US Space Command, General James H Dickinson, said China is building facilities that could put most of his country's space assets at risk.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-08/satellite-generic-istock_650x400_61502957010.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-good-health-nasa-amid-reports-of-sunita-williams-declining-health-6966297]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["In Good Health": NASA Amid Reports Of Sunita William's Declining Health]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-good-health-nasa-amid-reports-of-sunita-williams-declining-health-6966297]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:14:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amid growing concerns over Sunita Williams' health, NASA recently clarified that all the astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) are in "good health".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid growing concerns over Sunita Williams' health, NASA recently clarified that all the astronauts aboard the International Space Station (ISS) are in "good health".</p>

<p>A spokesperson for NASA's Space Operations Mission Directorate, Jimi Russell, told Daily Mail that all the NASA astronauts aboard ISS undergo routine medical evaluations and are monitored by dedicated flight surgeons.</p>

<p>"All are in good health," he said.</p>

<p>The space agency's statement comes amid media reports claiming that <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nasa-astronaut-sunita-williams-sends-diwali-wishes-from-space-6896558">Williams</a> is facing a health crisis after a prolonged stay on the ISS.</p>

<p>A picture of the NASA astronaut assembling a pepperoni pizza is also doing rounds on social media wherein it looks like she has lost a significant amount of weight. According to a Seattle-based pulmonologist, Williams looks "gaunt" in the picture, adding that she seems to be experiencing the natural stresses of living at a very high altitude for extended periods.</p>

<p>"Her cheeks appear a bit sunken and usually it happens when you've had sort of total body weight loss. 'I think what I can discern by her face and her cheeks being sunken in is that she has probably been at a significant calorie deficit for a while," the doctor told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-14045511/health-concerns-NASA-astronauts-stranded-ISS.html" rel="nofollow,noindex">Daily Mail</a>.</p>

<p>Williams and her fellow astronaut Barry Wilmore have been at the ISS since June. What was supposed to be an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-days-to-8-months-sunita-williams-barry-wilmores-extended-stay-in-space-6715868">eight-day ISS mission</a>, stretched into months due to a Starliner spacecraft malfunction. The astronauts will now return home in February next year.</p>

<p>On October 26, a NASA astronaut - part of the Crew-8, was hospitalised after returning from a nearly eight-month deployment on the ISS. According to NASA, astronauts Matthew Dominick, Michael Barratt, Jeanette Epps, and Roscosmos cosmonaut Alexander Grebenkin were flown together to Ascension Sacred Heart Pensacola in Florida. After a medical evaluation at the hospital, one of the astronauts was kept under observation as a precautionary measure. However, the details of the astronaut were not revealed to protect the crew member's medical privacy, NASA said.</p>

<p>The astronaut was released a day after in "good health", the US space agency said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ot9m3458_sunita-williams-_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Williams and her fellow astronaut Barry Wilmore have been at the ISS since June.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reinstates-plea-deal-for-9-11-mastermind-other-suspects-6966231]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Reinstates Plea Deal For 9/11 Mastermind, Other Suspects]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-reinstates-plea-deal-for-9-11-mastermind-other-suspects-6966231]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:07:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US military judge has reinstated plea agreements for 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US military judge has reinstated plea agreements for 9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed and two other defendants, an official said Thursday, three months after the deals were scrapped by Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin.</p>

<p>The agreements -- which are understood to take the death penalty off the table -- had triggered anger among some relatives of victims of the 2001 attacks, and Austin said that both they and the American public deserved to see the defendants stand trial.</p>

<p>"I can confirm that the military judge has ruled that the pretrial agreements for the three accused are valid and enforceable," the US official told AFP on condition of anonymity.</p>

<p>The prosecution has the opportunity to appeal the decision, but it was not immediately clear if they would do so.</p>

<p>The plea deals with Mohammed and two alleged accomplices were announced in late July in a step that appeared to have moved their long-running cases toward resolution after years of being bogged down in pre-trial maneuverings while the defendants remained held at the Guantanamo Bay military base in Cuba.</p>

<p>But Austin withdrew the agreements two days after they were announced, saying the decision should rest with him given its significance.</p>

<p>He subsequently told journalists that "the families of the victims, our service members and the American public deserve the opportunity to see military commission trials carried out in this case."</p>

<p>Much of the legal jousting surrounding the men's cases has focused on whether they could be tried fairly after having undergone methodical torture at the hands of the CIA in the years after 9/11 -- a thorny issue that the plea agreements would have avoided.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1jmfn9g_khalid-sheikh-mohammed_625x300_02_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[9/11 mastermind Khalid Sheikh Mohammed.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/girl-3-goes-to-court-in-pakistans-lahore-as-air-quality-continues-to-be-hazardous-6966213]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Girl, 3, Goes To Court In Lahore As Air Quality Continues To Be Hazardous]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/girl-3-goes-to-court-in-pakistans-lahore-as-air-quality-continues-to-be-hazardous-6966213]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 19:03:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A three-year-old girl has filed a petition against the local government in Pakistan's Punjab as the province, especially its capital Lahore, continues to reel under the severe impact of smog, keeping the air quality in an extremely hazardous zone.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A three-year-old girl has filed a petition against the local government in Pakistan's Punjab as the province, especially its capital Lahore, continues to reel under the severe impact of smog, keeping the air quality in an extremely hazardous zone.</p>

<p>On Thursday morning, the Air Quality Index (AQI) of Lahore stayed on top of the global rankings with levels crossing much above the 800-mark, making the air seriously dangerous for the residents.</p>

<p>As per the Swiss air quality monitor IQAir, Lahore has been on top of the cities with the world's highest AQI. The levels have even exceeded the 1000 mark on many occasions.</p>

<p>The extended and prolonged bad weather has made it impossible for citizens to venture out of their homes. The hospitals too are getting filled up with people suffering from respiratory issues. The bad air quality has left thousands of citizens of the province vulnerable to respiratory diseases with the provincial government and doctors advising all to wear masks whenever they venture out of their homes.</p>

<p>The provincial government has imposed a smog emergency across the province and has shut down all educational institutions up to the higher secondary level in Lahore and other districts till November 17.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a three-year-old girl has reached out to the Lahore High Court (LHC) on Thursday, filing a case against the provincial government over its failure to control air pollution.</p>

<p>The petitioner, Amal Sekhera, through her lawyer maintained in the petition that young children and the elderly are severely affected by air pollution and sought justice for herself, friends and the future generations.</p>

<p>"Under Article 99-A of the Constitution, the government is obligated to provide citizens with a clean and healthy environment," the petition stated.</p>

<p>The petition criticised the Punjab government for failing to protect the fundamental rights guaranteed by the Constitution of Pakistan.</p>

<p>Punjab government's senior provincial minister Maryam Aurangzeb has said that the intensity of the smog is expected to continue for at least 10 more days, due to which the educational institutions have been shut down and people have been advised to wear masks.</p>

<p>Many other cities like Multan and Gujranwala are also severely impacted with the ongoing weather conditions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/pkq2c0g8_lahore_625x300_06_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The petition criticised the Punjab government for failing to protect the fundamental rights.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-sparks-outrage-after-sharing-video-of-son-urinating-on-familys-meal-6965987]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Woman Sparks Outrage With Video Of Son Urinating On Family Meal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/chinese-woman-sparks-outrage-after-sharing-video-of-son-urinating-on-familys-meal-6965987]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:38:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In China, a mothers social media post ignited a fierce debate when she shared an unusual family incident: her young son urinated on a dining table, and the family continued to eat the meal.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media is becoming a place where people move from being creative to cliched to filthy in their posts due to the competition to publish pictures and videos and acquire views, likes, and followers. Despite many regulations by the social media platforms, there are hundreds of disgusting posts on social media that need to be removed. A similar post where a mother in China sparked severe online backlash after sharing on social media that her son urinated on a table full of food, and her family continued to eat the meal.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285406/disgust-china-mother-posts-online-photo-toddler-son-urinating-over-family-meal"><em>South China Morning Post, </em></a>the incident came to light in a recent social media post by a mother from Beijing, who told how her young son, held by his grandmother next to the dining table, suddenly began to urinate. In the post, the mother "proudly" captured the moment when her toddler's urine arced onto the table, which appeared to be breakfast, including steamed buns, eggs, and vegetables.</p>

<p>Details about the toddler's age and family background were not disclosed.The post quickly drew attention on social media, with many netizens expressing disbelief and concern, with one online observer asking, "So, did you guys end up eating that food?" To the shock of the online community, the mother confirmed: "Yes, we did eat it."</p>

<p><strong>In China, Young Boys' Urine Holds Unique Cultural Significance</strong></p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3285406/disgust-china-mother-posts-online-photo-toddler-son-urinating-over-family-meal"><em>SCMP,</em></a> in traditional Chinese culture, it is believed that the urine of young boys possesses various "mysterious powers," from boosting yang energy and reducing fever to spiritual benefits such as warding off evil spirits and enhancing good fortune.</p>

<p>Urine from boys under the age of 10 is considered particularly potent, especially the first morning's urine collected on the day before a boy turns one month old.</p>

<p>A famous food recipe from southern China, known as "urine eggs," involves collecting urine from kindergartens or primary schools, cleaning fresh eggs, placing them in a pot, covering them with the urine, then cooking them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ttpi21ro_urinating-on-familys-meal_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident highlights longstanding cultural beliefs in China.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-win-will-affect-globalisation-s-jaishankar-explains-6965805]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Donald Trump's Win Will Affect Globalisation? S Jaishankar Explains]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-win-will-affect-globalisation-s-jaishankar-explains-6965805]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:17:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In a press briefing after his meeting with top business leaders and CEOs in Australia, S Jaishankar mentioned about "something that happened yesterday", referring to the US election result. Mr Jaishankar said India "perceives this as an opportunity".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a press briefing after his meeting with top business leaders and CEOs in Australia, S Jaishankar mentioned about "something that happened yesterday", referring to the US election result. Mr Jaishankar said India "perceives this as an opportunity".</p>

<p>Former US President and Republican candidate Donald Trump made a stunning comeback after a 4-year gap to get re-elected as the 47th President of the United States of America. Mr Trump's win will almost certainly have an effect on the global order and significantly impact policy and trade for most nations.</p>

<p>Mr Trump's win will have a big impact on globalisation. Sharing his views on this, Mr Jaishankar said there are four aspects on how India views this: Firstly, "There was already a reordering of supply chains which was taking place (globally). It is very likely that this will get accelerated after the election result in the US."</p>

<p>He went on to say that "I'll be very candid with you, that some of this will be somewhat disruptive, but we in India perceive it as an opportunity because having kind of missed the manufacturing bus in the 1990s, early 2000s, we do think that this reordering of supply chain gives us a sort of second bite of the apple. And maybe this time around, starting with Apple, we are doing better than we were doing earlier."</p>

<p>"Secondly, there will be, in a way, more geopolitical hedging. that, what will inevitably happen as a consequence of policies which we can, at least those parts of it we can safely predict, will be that many more of us would be seeking more relationships (globally) to keep life stable," he added.</p>

<p>The foreign minister went on to highlight the significance of the digital age we all live in, explaining that digital payment platforms will ultimately become very valuable.</p>

<p>"The third aspect pertains to the digital digital side, and the digital side now pretty much covers everything." Mr Jaishankar said, adding that "What has been happening and will continue to intensify is about trust, and what accompanies the digital aspect of a product or service or technology will come under greater scrutiny."</p>

<p>He further noted that "Digital payment platforms, for example, would become, in a sense, much more valuable." adding that "which platform to use and share with whom, becomes an important question."</p>

<p>The fourth aspect, he said, is mobility. Speaking about it Mr Jaishankar said, "I think the demographic unevenness of the world is beginning to bite us that there would be, economies where the demand would be high. In those countries, the talents may not be plentiful."</p>

<p>"It could be different in other places, and what will happen, and is already happening is that we will be moving, perhaps in the next few years, to a much more integrated global workplace that many countries -- even a United States under Donald Trump -- will make a distinction in immigration and mobility for them. An economically-justified mobility will have to be fostered by those countries," the foreign minister explained.</p>

<p>"Businesses can move as well. We've already seen in the last few years," Mr Jaishankar said.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/iltj1phg_s-jaishankar-_625x300_02_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar met CEOs and business leaders in Australia today. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-soldiers-get-internet-access-in-ukraine-hooked-on-porn-report-6965568]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korean Soldiers Get Internet Access In Ukraine, Hooked On Porn: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-soldiers-get-internet-access-in-ukraine-hooked-on-porn-report-6965568]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:47:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korean soldiers, who joined the war front in Ukraine on behalf of Russia recently, received access to unrestricted internet - a wildly exciting concept for them.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean soldiers, who joined the war front in Ukraine on behalf of Russia recently, received access to unrestricted internet - a wildly exciting concept for them. This has resulted in the military men taking advantage of the unfettered access and are hooked to pornographic content online, a report by The Financial Times said.</p>

<p>According to the report, the soldiers from the hermit country are "gorging" on adult content.</p>

<p>However, it did not provide further context on how they have details on the internet habits of North Korean soldiers sent by Kim Jong Un to Ukraine.</p>

<p>US Defense Department spokesperson Army Lt Col Charlie Dietz also said they could not confirm any "North Korean internet habits or virtual extracurriculars", reported The New York Post.</p>

<p>Amid the growing Moscow-North Korea ties, Russia deployed more than <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korean-troops-clashed-with-ukrainian-forces-in-russias-kursk-report-6955668">7,000 North Korean soldiers</a>, armed with AK-12 rifles, mortar rounds, and other assault weapons, to areas near the border with Ukraine on Monday. They underwent training at five different sites in Russia's Far East for potential support of Russia's war in Ukraine, the Defence Intelligence of Ukraine said.</p>

<p>Two days later, the North Korean troops reportedly clashed with Ukrainian forces for the first time and are occupying a portion of the Kursk region in Russia.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/p82j1as8_north-korean-troops-in-russia-afp_625x300_23_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean troops reportedly clashed with Ukrainian forces. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-the-facts-donald-trump-and-elon-musk-may-not-remain-bffs-for-long-6965492]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Musk Is The Risk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/now-the-facts-donald-trump-and-elon-musk-may-not-remain-bffs-for-long-6965492]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:35:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Musk, however, is also a risk to Trump as his business interests may clash with US foreign policy. For instance, Teslas largest factory is in Shanghai, and another one is in Berlin. Both countries are bracing for higher tariff barriers under Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/s6mrg66_musk_625x300_07_November_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Just before dawn broke on November 6 over the East Coast, Donald Trump clinched the 270 electoral votes needed to secure a second four-year term as President of the United States. He delivered his victory speech hours before when it became clear that his path to the White House was open and free.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the speech that lasted a little over 25 minutes, Trump spoke about unifying America. He thanked several people, including his family, campaign managers and voters. The presumed President-elect also picked out one man for special praise. “Let me tell you, we have a new star. A star is born…Elon,” <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zVMxxiVvl4E">he said of billionaire businessman</a> Elon Musk. Trump also spent the next four minutes gushing about the spectacle of Musk-owned spacefaring company SpaceX's robots successfully catching a rocket returning from space. “He is a super genius and we have to protect our super geniuses. We don't have many of them,” Trump said.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>Still Sinking In</b></h2>

<p>Musk has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fortune.com/2024/10/26/elon-musk-political-donations-132-million-donald-trump-republican-races/">reportedly spent</a> $132 million on and actively campaigned for Donald Trump in the elections. Trump has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-adopt-musks-proposal-government-efficiency-commission-wsj-reports-2024-09-05/">floated</a> the idea of making him in charge of a bureaucratic purge. He wants Musk to head an efficiency commission, whose main job will be to shrink government expenditure, including by potentially firing thousands of career bureaucrats. Trump wants to rid the US government of what he believes is a cabal of federal employees, a deep state that pursues its own agenda. One of his allies, Kash Patel, who is helping in the regime transition, is <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/11/06/politics/transition-donald-trump-jockeying/index.html">screening</a> people for potential positions in the Trump administration. Patel, who has written a book <em>Government Gangsters: The Deep State, the Truth, and the Battle for Our Democracy</em>&nbsp;himself, is said to be angling to be Trump's chief spook.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Musk responded to Trump's victory in typical style; a picture of himself carrying a kitchen sink with the Oval Office in the background and the line: ‘Let that sink in!' That was a throwback to when he bought Twitter and walked into its headquarters with a sink. &nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Biden's Battle With Big Tech</strong></h2>

<p>Trump's victory is arguably the most remarkable comeback in US political history. The epochal story's side track is the culmination of a not-so-quiet battle that Big Tech has been waging with Washington during the entire term of Joe Biden. The President's trusted lieutenant, Lina Khan, the chief of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), relentlessly pursued companies such as Facebook, Google and Apple, wielding the antitrust law like an electric whip. Billionaire CEOs sat shuddering before Congressional committees as combative members dragged them over coals. A Republican-led House Judiciary Committee <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/05/technology/election-2024-ftc-lina-khan.html">accused Khan</a> of weaponising the agency and pushing a far-left agenda. Khan and FTC occupied significant mind-space in the closing stages of the presidential campaign. She will be fired soon, Musk posted on X a day before the vote. &nbsp;</p>

<p>The entry of Musk, along with Vice-President JD Vance, signals the deepest incursion of Silicon Valley into US national politics. Vance, who once <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.businessinsider.in/politics/world/news/i-reread-jd-vances-hillbilly-elegy-he-hasnt-transformed-as-much-as-you-think-/articleshow/111845075.cms">derisively called</a> Trump “cultural heroin”, was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=dhtwitter&amp;utm_content=app.dashhudson.com/vanityfair/library/media/470296154">handpicked</a>, groomed and funded to first become Ohio governor and then Trump's running mate by libertarian founder of payment firm PayPal and data analytics company Palantir Technologies, Peter Thiel.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Reign Of The Unpredictables</strong></h2>

<p>To be sure, Trump has no love lost for entrepreneurs such as Mark Zuckerburg. His pals, Musk and Thiel, checked out of “Woke” California long ago. Trump has reversed his intention to ban Chinese social media app TikTok, a Meta rival, ostensibly after being persuaded by investor Jeffrey Yass, who owns a juicy slice of its parent Bytedance. The libertarian billionaire <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/republican-hedge-fund-owner-tiktok-investor-yass-emerges-top-donor-us-election-2024-03-21/">donated over</a> $46 billion to Republican causes. With the Senate and House also firmly packed with tens of elected legislators backed by billionaire tech entrepreneurs and investors, the power shift is all too evident.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Although Trump is seen as an uncontrollable wrecking ball, Musk has proven to be even more unpredictable. While countries the world over are bracing for the Trump impact, whether on tariffs, movement of professionals, technology transfer, or military deployment, Musk's influence if he joins the administration is an even bigger unknown. As the richest man on earth with a $286 billion fortune as of election day and business interests all over the world, Musk has close ties with many leaders, including Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin. Earlier this year, he abruptly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/india/india-shocked-musks-surprise-china-visit-leaves-them-spurned-2024-04-30/">cancelled a visit</a> to India at the last minute only to head to Beijing for confabulations with the Chinese leadership. That sojourn cleared Tesla's path in that country.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has refused Tesla and Starlink lower entry barriers and requests for special treatment. Trump is known to intervene with other countries on behalf of American businesses. In his previous term, he had pushed India for concessions to Harley Davidson motorcycles.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>BFFs, But Probably Not For Long</strong></h2>

<p>Musk, however, is also a risk to Trump as his business interests may clash with US foreign policy. For instance, Tesla's largest factory is in Shanghai, and another one is in Berlin. Both countries are bracing for higher tariff barriers under Trump. Musk also has been <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/world/russia/musk-putin-secret-conversations-37e1c187">reported</a> to have had secret dealings with Putin, who is said to have lobbied on behalf of his friend Xi to switch off Taiwan's access to Starlink. Musk has also made statements that are contradictory to US interests and publicly stated positions on Taiwan.</p>

<p>Trump's antipathy towards green initiatives and abiding faith in petroleum may not augur well for Tesla's electric cars, but <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/features/2024-11-03/election-2024-trump-may-let-musk-colonize-the-white-house">some believe</a> Musk may already be moving away from EVs. His future fortune and power rest on his other businesses, they say.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Given the contradictions, one as President of the United States and another as the founder of half a dozen futuristic enterprises, it is difficult to see Trump's and Musk's interests remaining aligned for very long. Both are individuals who brook no barrier to their personal agenda, and both are known to wear their opinion on their X handles.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(Dinesh Narayanan is a Delhi-based journalist and author of 'The RSS And The Making Of The Deep Nation'.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/cnltfv0g_musk_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/fictosexual-japan-man-celebrates-6-years-of-marriage-with-virtual-wife-admired-for-his-devotion-6965432]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['Fictosexual' Japan Man Celebrates 6 Years Of Marriage With Virtual Wife]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/fictosexual-japan-man-celebrates-6-years-of-marriage-with-virtual-wife-admired-for-his-devotion-6965432]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:29:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Akihiko Kondo, a Japanese man who married the fictional vocaloid character Hatsune Miku in 2018, recently celebrated his sixth anniversary with her.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The idea of traditional relationships is changing, from self-marriage rituals to robotic companions. The increasing acceptability of many manifestations of love and devotion is reflected in these unorthodox unions.This ongoing series has a fresh addition: a Japanese guy who married the fictitious vocaloid Hatsune Miku in 2018 is still happily married and looking forward to their sixth anniversary.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/gender-diversity/article/3284801/fictosexual-japan-man-anticipates-6th-wedding-anniversary-wife-praised-loyalty"><em>South China Morning Post,</em></a> on October 23, 41-year-old Akihiko Kondo shared on his Instagram the receipt for a cake he bought for their anniversary, which falls on November 4.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DB7zoxAykbB/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by 近藤 顕彦 (@akihikokondosk)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>The cake bears the message, "I like Miku very much. Happy six-year anniversary." Kondo told the Japanese news outlet The Mainichi Shimbun that he had been romantically interested in women before secondary school.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="ja">サボテンのあれです。 <a href="https://t.co/TNxbIHxAbC">pic.twitter.com/TNxbIHxAbC</a></p>
— 近藤 顕彦【⋈??】ミクさん大好き (@akihikokondosk) <a href="https://twitter.com/akihikokondosk/status/1853452513284092238?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>He confessed his love seven times, but all were rejected, and he was laughed at and bullied for being an otaku-a person obsessed with anime and manga. Kondo fell in love with Miku in 2007 soon after the character was released. He was bullied at work and, as a result, was diagnosed with adjustment disorder and took long sick leave, reported the news outlet.</p>

<p>The character, whose name is translated as "the first sound of the future" in English, is officially known as a vocaloid, a type of singing voice synthesiser software. Those who are fond of her recognise her as a 16-year-old pop singer with long, turquoise twintails.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/61v2cm0o_akihiko-kondo_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Fictosexual Akihiko Kondo is happily married to his synthesised wife.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-australia-today-india-calls-out-canadas-move-against-australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-6965431]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Calls Out Canada's Move Against Outlet That Interviewed S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-australia-today-india-calls-out-canadas-move-against-australian-outlet-that-interviewed-s-jaishankar-6965431]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:28:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Responding strongly to reports of social media handles and pages of an Australian news outlet being blocked in Canada, India has said such actions highlight the hypocrisy of Canada towards freedom of speech.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Responding strongly to reports of social media handles and pages of an Australian news outlet being blocked in Canada hours after it carried a press conference of External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar and Australian Foreign Minister Penny Wong as well as an interview of the Indian minister, India has said such actions highlight Canada's hypocrisy towards freedom of speech.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During his Australia visit, which ends on Thursday, Mr Jaishankar met Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and also co-chaired the 15th Foreign Ministers' Framework Dialogue with Ms Wong.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Asked about the social media handles of Australia Today being blocked in Canada, Ministry of External Affairs Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal said on Thursday, "We understand that social media handles and pages of this outlet, which is an important diaspora outlet, have been blocked and are not available for viewers in Canada. This happened a few hours after this particular handle carried the press conference of the External Affairs Minister with Penny Wong."</p>

<p>Stating that the outlet had carried an interview with Mr Jaishankar as well as several articles on his visit, Mr Jaiswal added, "We were surprised. It looks strange to us. But, nonetheless, these are actions that yet again highlight the hypocrisy of Canada towards freedom of speech. In his media interactions, the External Affairs Minister spoke about three things: a pattern of Canada making allegations without evidence, the surveillance of Indian diplomats - which he termed unacceptable - and the political space being given in Canada to anti-India elements. So you can draw your conclusions from that on why the Australia Today channel was blocked."</p>

<p>Last week, India had said some of its consular officials were informed by the Canadian government that they have been under audio and video surveillance. Terming the action a "flagrant violation" of diplomatic conventions, India had said Canada could not hide behind technicalities to justify its harassment and intimidation and that a protest had been lodged with the Canadian government.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Jaiswal also confirmed that some consular camps have been cancelled in Toronto because they did not get security assurance from Canada. The announcement came days after the attack on a Hindu temple in Brampton, where a consular camp was being held, on November 3. PM Narendra Modi had also condemned the attack and criticised "cowardly attempts" to intimidate Indian diplomats in Canada.&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;<br />
Ties between India and Canada have been strained since Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau claimed - without offering any evidence - last year that "Indian agents" were involved in the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar. The allegation has been rubbished by New Delhi several times and it has asked Canada to produce evidence to back up the claim.</p>

<p>The relationship hit a new low last month when the Indian High Commissioner was termed a "person of interest" in the killing. India dismissed the fresh charge as "ludicrous" and withdrew the High Commissioner and some diplomats while expelling six Canadian officials, including Canada's acting High Commissioner Stewart Ross Wheeler.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/d83eucg_s-jaishankar_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The ministry also confirmed that some consular camps have been cancelled in Toronto.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-entrepreneur-sells-chat-com-url-to-chatgpt-for-over-15-million-6965430]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Indian-Origin Man Sells Chat.com URL To ChatGPT For Over $15 Million]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/indian-origin-entrepreneur-sells-chat-com-url-to-chatgpt-for-over-15-million-6965430]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:28:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[This domain was previously owned by Dharmesh Shah, HubSpot's founder and CTO.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Wednesday, OpenAI CEO Sam Altman posted a simple URL on X: chat.com, which now redirects to ChatGPT.<br />
&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="zxx"><a href="https://t.co/n494J9IuEN">https://t.co/n494J9IuEN</a></p>
— Sam Altman (@sama) <a href="https://twitter.com/sama/status/1854238332534108188?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>This domain was previously owned by Dharmesh Shah, HubSpot's founder and CTO. In early 2023, Mr Shah bought chat.com for $15.5 million, and a few months later, he announced its sale without disclosing the buyer or final price, though he confirmed it was sold for more than he paid, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/6/24289768/openai-chat-chatgpt-sam-altman-hubspot" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Verge </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The reason I bought chat.com is simple: I believe Chat-based UX (#ChatUX) is the next big thing in software. Interacting with computers through natural language is more intuitive, made possible by Generative A.I.," Shah wrote on LinkedIn when he first announced the purchase. Initially, chat.com briefly redirected to this post before he resold it.</p>

<p>Mr Shah confirmed on X that OpenAI was the buyer, suggesting he received shares instead of cash as payment.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BREAKING NEWS: Secret acquirer of $15+ million domain chat .com revealed and it's exactly who you'd think.<br />
<br />
For those of you that have been following me for a while, you may recall that I announced earlier this year that I had acquired the domain chat .com for an "8 figure sum"… <a href="https://t.co/nv1IyddP5z">https://t.co/nv1IyddP5z</a></p>
— dharmesh (@dharmesh) <a href="https://twitter.com/dharmesh/status/1854307883304792294?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>This shift to "chat.com" aligns with OpenAI's rebranding strategy. In September, the company launched a new line of reasoning models starting with "o1," aiming for "more sane names" to better reflect its work, as former chief research officer Bob McGrew told The Verge.</p>

<p>The practice of securing "vanity domains" has a long history online. Recently, AI startup Friend spent $1.8 million on friend.com after raising $2.5 million in funding. For OpenAI, which recently raised $6.6 billion, a $10+ million purchase-whether in cash or stock- is a small investment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/12m60nfo_sam-altman-and-dharmesh-shah_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Chat.com now redirects to ChatGPT]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-india-cancels-consular-camp-in-toronto-over-inadequate-security-6965349]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Cancels Consular Camp In Toronto Over 'Inadequate Security']]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-canada-ties-india-cancels-consular-camp-in-toronto-over-inadequate-security-6965349]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 17:14:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Days after the attack on a Hindu temple in Canada's Brampton, the Minister of External Affairs announced the cancellation of consular camps in Toronto over security issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Days after the attack on a Hindu temple in Canada's Brampton, the Minister of External Affairs announced the cancellation of consular camps in Toronto over security issues.</p>

<p>Consular camps are routine operations organized by the Indian diplomatic missions in Canada, including the High Commission in Ottawa and the Consulates in Vancouver and Toronto, to assist Indian nationals with various services, such as life certificates.</p>

<p>MEA Spokesperson Randhir Jaiswal today said, "You would have seen the message posted by our consulate in Toronto that they had to cancel the consular camp they were planning to organize over the weekend because they did not receive adequate security or security assurance from the host government."&nbsp;</p>

<p>"That was the reason these consular camps had to be cancelled. As you know, we have a large diaspora in Canada. Many of these people, especially around November and December, need several documents for the continuation of their pensions and other activities here in India. So, this consular camp we do is helpful to the community, to both people of Indian nationality and people of Indian origin who may now be nationals of other countries," Mr Jaiswal said.</p>

<p>The Consulate General of India in Toronto earlier said, "In view of the security agencies conveying their inability to provide minimum security protection to the community camp organizers, the Consulate has decided to cancel some of the scheduled consular camps."</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">In view of the security agencies conveying their inability to provide minimum security protection to the community camp organizers, Consulate has decided to cancel some of the scheduled consular camps.<a href="https://twitter.com/HCI_Ottawa?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@HCI_Ottawa</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MEAIndia</a></p>
— IndiainToronto (@IndiainToronto) <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainToronto/status/1854347535399420405?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 7, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi strongly condemned the "deliberate attack on a Hindu temple in Canada" - referring to a shocking incident last week when men breached the gates of a temple in Brampton, Ontario, while the Indian High Commission held a consular camp.</p>

<p>Read more:&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/strongly-condemn-deliberate-attack-on-hindu-temple-in-canada-pm-modi-6942819">"Cowardly Attempts To Intimidate Diplomats": PM's 1st Comments On Canada Row</a></p>

<p>The PM also criticised "cowardly attempts" to intimidate Indian diplomats in that country.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/justin-trudeau-india-canada-relations-deeply-disappointing-canada-temple-attack-disrupts-india-consular-camp-6938544">Shortly after the attack on the temple</a>, the Indian High Commission in Ottawa said a consular camp was disrupted.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">PRESS RELEASE<br />
<br />
"Violent disruption outside consular camp in Brampton, Ontario (Nov 3)"<a href="https://twitter.com/MEAIndia?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@MEAIndia</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/IndianDiplomacy?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IndianDiplomacy</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/diaspora_india?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@diaspora_india</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/cgivancouver?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@cgivancouver</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/IndiainToronto?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@IndiainToronto</a> <a href="https://t.co/V7QNMmA4eR">pic.twitter.com/V7QNMmA4eR</a></p>
— India in Canada (@HCI_Ottawa) <a href="https://twitter.com/HCI_Ottawa/status/1853268151108010113?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 4, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"We have seen violent disruption today (Nov 3) orchestrated by anti-India elements outside the consular camp. Co-organized with the Hindu Sabha Mandir, Brampton, near Toronto. It is deeply disappointing to see such disruptions being allowed for routine consular work being organized by our Consulates with the fullest cooperation of local co-organizers. We also remain very concerned for the safety of applicants, including Indian nationals, on whose demand such events are organized in the first place," it added.</p>

<p>"Despite these efforts by anti-India elements, our Consulate was able to issue more than 1000 life certificates to the Indian and Canadian applicants. There were also attempts to disrupt similar camps held in Vancouver and Surrey on Nov 2-3," the High Commission said.</p>

<p>"In case any camp is infeasible to be held due to such disruptions, alternative arrangements will be made to render those services, which may unfortunately inconvenience local users of these services," the High Commission said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/c9jfo90o_canada-consular-camp_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Indian High Commission in Ottawa said a consular camp was disrupted.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/hope-for-cancer-patients-new-treatment-strategy-targets-rogue-dna-6965172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hope For Cancer Patients, New Treatment Strategy Targets Rogue DNA]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/hope-for-cancer-patients-new-treatment-strategy-targets-rogue-dna-6965172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 16:51:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The research, which analyzed data from over 15,000 UK cancer patients, identifies ecDNA as a key factor in cancer progression and drug resistance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US and UK scientists have conducted a groundbreaking study that has ignited hope for treating some of the most aggressive forms of cancer. The research, published in Journal Nature Genetics, has identified a novel approach to targeting rogue DNA fragments that fuel tumour growth and resistance to chemotherapy.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://medicine.yale.edu/news-article/specific-type-of-dna-could-be-a-target-of-future-cancer-therapies/">Scientists discovered</a> that many difficult-to-treat cancers contain extrachromosomal DNA (ecDNA), small loops of genetic material that are essential for tumor survival and treatment resistance. By analyzing data from nearly 15,000 UK cancer patients across 39 different tumor types, researchers found that over 16% of these cancers exhibited ecDNA.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-07802-5">This discovery</a> sheds light on how ecDNA drives cancer progression and resistance. Encouragingly, the study also identified a promising drug candidate that is currently undergoing early-stage clinical trials. This drug has the potential to selectively eliminate cancer cells containing ecDNA, preventing the rapid development of drug resistance.</p>

<p>"Our research suggests that ecDNA helps tumors become more aggressive. EcDNA has a distinct mechanism and plays an important role, not just for breast or lung cancer, but across many cancer types," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241015/Extrachromosomal-DNA-in-more-aggressive-cancers-could-be-targets-for-future-therapies.aspx">said Roel Verhaak,</a> senior author of the paper, the Harvey and Kate Cushing Professor of Neurosurgery at Yale School of Medicine and member of Yale Cancer Center.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.news-medical.net/news/20241015/Extrachromosomal-DNA-in-more-aggressive-cancers-could-be-targets-for-future-therapies.aspx">release by Yale University</a>, the study found that ecDNA is detected more often after taxol-based therapies such as docetaxel and paclitaxel, which is used for treatment of many cancer types. The researchers also noticed that when they looked at the same cancer over time, ecDNA was more likely to stick around than DNA changes on the regular chromosomes.</p>

<p>In the advanced cancers that were studied, ecDNA was prone to rapid mutations. Researchers say these "hypermutations" could be one of the reasons why cancer becomes so aggressive and difficult to treat as time goes on. The mutations in ecDNA may help cancer cells adapt and survive better than their normal counterparts. The hope is that this research can aid in the development of better cancer treatments.</p>

<p>"In the lab, we're using drug libraries to find out what can specifically target ecDNA-containing cells," said Verhaak. "We want to find vulnerabilities in tumors that have ecDNA, as ecDNA-targeting therapies could benefit as many as a third of all cancer patients."</p>

<p>Verhaak said there are ongoing clinical trials involving therapies that are designed to specifically target ecDNA in tumors.</p>

<p>This breakthrough offers a new avenue for cancer treatment and could significantly improve outcomes for patients with aggressive forms of the disease.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/28k793a_cancer-patients_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A promising drug targeting ecDNA is currently undergoing early-stage clinical trials.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dropped-fiances-baby-on-his-head-and-squeezed-him-to-stop-crying-arrested-6964795]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Dropped Fiance's Baby On His Head, Squeezed Him To Stop Crying]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-dropped-fiances-baby-on-his-head-and-squeezed-him-to-stop-crying-arrested-6964795]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 16:07:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The child was taken to a nearby hospital and then transferred to a children's hospital in Kansas City, Missouri, about two hours away.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A tragic incident occurred when a 10-month-old baby was left critically injured after allegedly being thrown into the air and bearhugged by his mother's fiance. Jordan Boggess has been arrested on a felony child abuse charge after the toddler was found in critical condition in Newtonia, Missouri, on September 14, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/06/us-news/infant-left-fighting-for-life-after-moms-fiance-dropped-hi-on-head-and-squeezed-him-to-stop-crying-cops/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>New York Post</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Newton County Sheriff's Office responded to the family's home around 8 p.m. following a report of a baby struggling to breathe. When first responders arrived, they found the baby unconscious but breathing, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://lawandcrime.com/crime/reset-to-a-newborn-moms-fiance-bear-hugged-her-infant-son-to-get-him-to-stop-crying-police-say/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>Law &amp; Crime</em></a>.</p>

<p>The child was taken to a nearby hospital and then transferred to a children's hospital in Kansas City, Missouri, about two hours away. Medical examinations revealed bruises on his forehead and ear, along with collapsed lungs and two brain bleeds.</p>

<p>Officers later returned to speak with Boggess, 28, who was found sleeping. He told authorities that he had been lying in bed watching TV when the boy's mother left the room to use the bathroom. According to Boggess, the child began to vomit and scream. To calm him, Boggess claimed he tossed the baby in the air, but on the second toss, the child fell and landed on his head.</p>

<p>The probable cause affidavit, obtained by the media, states that Boggess admitted he panicked and tightly "bearhugged" the child after he fell, potentially injuring him further. Medical professionals diagnosed the baby with "abusive head trauma" and signs of physical abuse.</p>

<p>Boggess remains in the Newton County Jail without bond. The baby was discharged from the hospital on October 24 and is now recovering at home with his mother. The child's father told <em>NBC affiliate KY3</em> that the injuries are likely to have long-term effects on his son's life.</p>

<p>"He basically took my son's life. He took my son's future. You don't toss a baby into the air," Tyler Burbridge told the outlet.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/kb716t68_jordan-boggess_625x300_07_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Newton County Sheriff's Office responded to the family's home around 8 p.m.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/natos-big-warning-on-north-korea-russia-ties-threat-to-us-security-6964596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Threat To US Security": NATO's Big Warning On North Korea-Russia Ties]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/natos-big-warning-on-north-korea-russia-ties-threat-to-us-security-6964596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:38:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The strengthening ties between Russia and North Korea are not only a threat to European security, but also to the United States, NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The strengthening ties between Russia and North Korea are not only a threat to European security, but also to the United States, NATO Secretary-General Mark Rutte said on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Russia is delivering the latest technology into North Korea in return for North Korean help with the war against Ukraine and this is a threat not only to the European part of NATO but also to the US," Rutte said before a meeting with European leaders in Budapest.</p>

<p>"I look forward to sit down with Donald Trump to discuss how we face these threats collectively."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/q4a0gp8o_kim-jong-un-putin-afp_625x300_12_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NATO's warns on growing North Korea-Russia ties.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysia-announces-restart-of-mh370-search-based-on-credible-proposal-6964563]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Malaysia Announces Restart Of MH370 Search Based On "Credible" Proposal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/malaysia-announces-restart-of-mh370-search-based-on-credible-proposal-6964563]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 07 Nov 2024 15:32:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Interestingly, the search will follow a "no find, no fee" structure, ensuring that Malaysia only incurs costs if the wreckage is located.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Malaysia is all set to restart the search for the ill-fated Malaysia Airlines Flight MH370, which mysteriously vanished in 2014 with 239 people on board. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/southeast-asia/mh370-flight-malaysia-airlines-search-ocean-infinity-b2642150.html">Independent,</a></em> this new development is sparked by a "credible" proposal that identifies a fresh search area in the southern Indian Ocean.&nbsp;The proposal, submitted by US-based marine exploration company Ocean Infinity in June 2024, outlines a search plan for a 15,000 sqkm zone off the coast of Western Australia. Interestingly, the search will follow a "no find, no fee" structure, ensuring that Malaysia would only bear costs if the wreckage is found.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Malaysia's Transport Minister Anthony Loke confirmed the advanced talks with Ocean Infinity to parliament on November 5.</p>

<p>''Based on the latest information and analysis from experts and researchers, Ocean Infinity's search proposal is credible and can be considered by the Malaysian government as the flight's official registrar. The terms and costs requested are in the same draft agreement currently being negotiated between the government and Ocean Infinity. Should it be finalised, cabinet approval will be required, and I will make a public announcement,” said Mr Loke</p>

<p>He also informed that the company is requesting a fee of $70m if successful.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ocean Infinity, a marine robotics company based in Texas, previously claimed that they have<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-company-claims-to-have-scientific-evidence-in-search-for-missing-flight-mh370-5182122"> scientific evidence of the missing flight's final r</a>esting place and also&nbsp;submitted a proposal to the Malaysian government.&nbsp;Ocean Infinity had last attempted to find the missing plane in 2018.</p>

<p>The company's chief executive officer Oliver Plunkett said, ''We now feel in a position to be able to return to the search for MH370, and have submitted a proposal to the Malaysian government. Finding MH370 and bringing some resolution for all connected with the loss of the aircraft has been a constant in our minds since we left the southern Indian Ocean in 2018.''</p>

<p>The search for Malaysia Airlines Flight 370 has been a long and challenging one. After the plane went missing in 2014 with 227 passengers and 12 crew members on board, satellite data analysis suggested it likely crashed in the southern Indian Ocean, off the coast of Western Australia. Despite two major searches, one led by Malaysia, China, and Australia, and another by Ocean Infinity, no significant findings were made.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The initial search area was massive, covering Southeast Asia, and later expanded to the Indian Ocean. Various nations joined the search effort, including the US, UK, China, and Australia, with nearly 60 ships and 50 aircraft involved. Unfortunately, the search was suspended in 2017, and Ocean Infinity's 2018 search also ended without success.</p>

<p>Malaysia's renewed search effort for the missing flight comes at a time when a Beijing court is currently reviewing compensation claims from over 40 families of Chinese passengers who were on board.&nbsp;The Chinese foreign ministry has expressed appreciation for Malaysia's ongoing commitment to resolving the case, with spokesperson Wang Wenbin welcoming the collaboration.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-04/g6haansk_malaysia-airline-mh370_625x300_25_April_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The plane went missing in 2014 with 227 passengers and 12 crew members on board]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>