<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:50:23 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-forces-capture-new-village-in-ukraines-donetsk-amid-raging-war-6986600]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russian Forces Capture New Village In Ukraine's Donetsk Amid Raging War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russian-forces-capture-new-village-in-ukraines-donetsk-amid-raging-war-6986600]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:39:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Russian defence ministry said Sunday that its forces had captured a new village in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Russian defence ministry said Sunday that its forces had captured a new village in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region where the army has been making advances in recent weeks.</p>

<p>"Units of the Centre armed group have liberated the town of Voltchenka," the ministry said, using the Russian spelling of the Ukraine village Vovchenko, around five kilometres (three miles) from the industrial city of Kurakhove.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/50a9boq_donetsk-ukraine_625x300_20_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russian army has been making advances in the region since recent weeks. (Representational image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violence-outside-sheikh-hasina-party-office-after-rally-call-dhaka-tense-6986068]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Violence Outside Sheikh Hasina Party Office After Rally Call, Dhaka Tense]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/violence-outside-sheikh-hasina-party-office-after-rally-call-dhaka-tense-6986068]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 15:43:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's capital Dhaka remains tense on Sunday as several Awami League supporters were reportedly beaten following the party's decision to hold a protest march at Shaheed Noor Hossain Square in commemoration of Noor Hossain Day.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's capital Dhaka remains tense on Sunday as several Awami League supporters were reportedly beaten following the party's decision to hold a protest march at Shaheed Noor Hossain Square in commemoration of Noor Hossain Day.</p>

<p>The incident took place in front of Sheikh Hasina's party's central office on Bangabandhu Avenue, local media reported.</p>

<p>A political activist and leader of Awami League's youth front, the Jubo League, Noor Hossain was killed on November 10, 1987 during the anti-Ershad movement.</p>

<p>The Awami League's announcement to hold a rally on Sunday afternoon to mark the occasion was its first significant decision since the government led by former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina was brought down by an uprising on August 5.</p>

<p>In a social media post, the party invited common people and activists, who believe in the "values of the Liberation War and democratic principles", to join the march at Noor Hossain Chattar (Zero Point). It also called for removal of anti-democratic forces and the reestablishment of democratic governance under the leadership of the Bangladesh Awami League.</p>

<p>Immediately after the announcement, Bangladesh's interim government led by Chief Advisor Muhammad Yunus made it clear that it will not grant permission to hold the protest rally.</p>

<p>"The Awami League in its current form is a fascist party. There is no way this fascist party will be allowed to hold protests in Bangladesh," said Yunus' Press Secretary Shafiqul Alam.</p>

<p>The anti-discrimination student movement is also holding a counter-gathering at the same venue, demanding trial of the Awami League leaders.</p>

<p>Anticipating violence, the Border Guard Bangladesh (BGB) said that 191 platoons of the border security forces have been deployed in the country's capital and across the country to maintain law and order on Noor Hossain Day.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/3t9m083o_bangladesh-violence_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-trumps-trade-policies-mean-for-asian-countries-amid-us-china-rivalry-6986129]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump's China Policies To Benefit India, Asian Countries: Ratings Agency]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-trumps-trade-policies-mean-for-asian-countries-amid-us-china-rivalry-6986129]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 15:11:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[With Donald Trump set to become the next US president after the recently closely contested presidential polls, India and other Asian countries are expected to benefit due to rising US-China tensions and potential investment restrictions.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With Donald Trump set to become the next US president after the recently closely contested presidential polls, India and other Asian countries are expected to benefit due to rising US-China tensions and potential investment restrictions in strategic sectors, as per Moody's Ratings.</p>

<p>"In the Asia-Pacific region, trade and investment flows might be further diverted away from China as the US tightens investments in strategic sectors, which would negatively affect China's economy and consequently dampen regional growth. However, this shift might benefit India and ASEAN countries," the global rating agency said.</p>

<p>The global agency anticipated a significant shift under the Trump administration across fiscal, trade, climate, and immigration issues, departing from the approach of the administration of the current US President Joe Biden.</p>

<p>The rating agency added that Trump could have both legislative and executive avenues to advance his agenda on every front.</p>

<p>It further added that as a candidate, Trump promised tax reform, with plans to make the 2017 Tax Cuts and Jobs Act permanent, lower the corporate tax rate, and implement income tax relief. These initiatives, along with targeted and broad tariffs, including steep tariffs on Chinese imports, are expected to increase federal deficits.</p>

<p>It highlighted that the US under Trump will adopt a protectionist trade policy, which would be more disruptive and increase the risks to global growth.</p>

<p>"Protectionist measures could disrupt global supply chains and negatively affect sectors that rely on imported materials and goods, such as manufacturing, technology, and retail," it added.</p>

<p>Trump's trade policy approach would likely bring immediate impacts to the manufacturing sector, the credit rating agency said, adding that although a divided Congress might slow down or adjust the scope of such measures.</p>

<p>The climate initiatives of the US are also likely to see reversals as Trump seeks to boost fossil fuel production under the banner of "American energy dominance."</p>

<p>Reduced funding for clean energy projects and a possible withdrawal from the Paris Agreement would undermine the US's commitments to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</p>

<p>While federal support for green technologies may wane, private-sector initiatives and state-level mandates, particularly in renewable energy, are expected to partially offset this shift.</p>

<p>Some industry experts believe market-driven growth in wind and solar could continue, as these energy sources have become cost-competitive in many parts of the country.</p>

<p>"The shift would likely result in renewed support for the fossil fuel industry, reduced funding for clean energy and green technologies, and loosened environmental regulations, including the Environmental Protection Agency's efforts to reduce emissions in the power and auto sectors. It is likely that the Trump administration will withdraw from the Paris Agreement again and reverse commitments to meeting net-zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050," the agency said.</p>

<p>On the regulatory front, Trump is expected to pursue a lighter approach, as per the Moody's, which will include relaxed rules for small and midsized banks, potentially reducing their capital requirements but also exposing creditors to higher risks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/leckf9eo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump's trade policy approach is likely to bring immediate impact to manufacturing sector. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cops-arrest-banned-groups-member-over-hindu-temple-attack-6985737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Cops Arrest Banned Group's Member Over Hindu Temple Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-cops-arrest-banned-groups-member-over-hindu-temple-attack-6985737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 15:01:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Canadian police have arrested a 35-year-old Brampton resident on charges of assault with a weapon during a violent demonstration at a Hindu temple in the city, authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canadian police have arrested a 35-year-old Brampton resident on charges of assault with a weapon during a violent demonstration at a Hindu temple in the city, authorities said.</p>

<p>On November 3, a protest occurred at the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton and unverified videos circulating on social media appeared to show demonstrators holding Khalistani flags. The videos showed fistfights and people striking each other with poles on what appears to be the grounds surrounding the temple.</p>

<p>The Peel Regional Police responded to the altercation during the demonstration at the mandir. As tensions between opposing sides increased, the demonstrations became physical and assaultive, a statement said on Saturday.</p>

<p>Police began investigating several offences that occurred during the demonstration, many of which were captured on video; including individuals using flags and sticks to assault people, it said.</p>

<p>Investigators from the 21 Division Criminal Investigations Bureau and Strategic Investigation Team (SIT) have arrested and charged Inderjeet Gosal of Brampton, the Peel Police statement said.</p>

<p>Gosal is the Canada coordinator for the banned group Sikhs for Justice, the Toronto Star reported.</p>

<p>On November 8, 2024, he was arrested and charged with assault with a weapon. He was released on conditions and is to appear at the Ontario Court of Justice in Brampton at a later date, it said.</p>

<p>A SIT dedicated to investigating incidents of criminality during the November 3 and 4 incidents has since been formed.</p>

<p>On November 3, the protesters carrying Khalistani flags clashed with people and disrupted a consular event co-organised by the temple authorities and the Indian Consulate.</p>

<p>The Sunday incident was condemned by Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau who said every Canadian has the right to practise their faith freely and safely.</p>

<p>India condemned the attack with an expectation that those indulging in violence "will be prosecuted".</p>

<p>In a statement, the Ministry of External Affairs said that New Delhi remains "deeply concerned" about the safety and security of Indian nationals in Canada.</p>

<p>The relations between India and Canada came under severe strain following Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's allegations in September last year of a "potential" involvement of Indian agents in Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar's killing. New Delhi rejected Trudeau's charges as "absurd".</p>

<p>India has been maintaining that the main issue between the two countries is that of Canada giving space to Khalistani elements operating from Canadian soil with impunity.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/tpgieni_brampton-temple-attack_625x300_04_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[On November 3, a protest occurred at the Hindu Sabha Mandir in Brampton. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-climate-summit-in-baku-in-a-first-taliban-officials-to-attend-un-climate-conference-in-azerbaijan-report-6985924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In A First, Taliban Officials To Attend UN Climate Conference: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cop29-climate-summit-in-baku-in-a-first-taliban-officials-to-attend-un-climate-conference-in-azerbaijan-report-6985924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 14:35:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Afghan Taliban officials will attend a major United Nations climate conference that starts next week, the Afghan Foreign Ministry said on Sunday, the first time they have attended since the former insurgents took power in 2021.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Afghan Taliban officials will attend a major United Nations climate conference that starts next week, the Afghan Foreign Ministry said on Sunday, the first time they have attended since the former insurgents took power in 2021.</p>

<p>The COP29 climate summit in Azerbaijan's capital Baku will be among the highest-profile multilateral events attended by Taliban administration officials since they took control in Kabul after 20 years of fighting NATO-backed forces.</p>

<p>The UN has not allowed the Taliban to take up Afghanistan's seat at the General Assembly, and Afghanistan's government is not formally recognised by U.N. member states, largely due to the Taliban's restrictions on women's education and freedom of movement.</p>

<p>Afghan Foreign Ministry spokesman Abdul Qahar Balkhi said officials from the National Environmental Protection Agency had arrived in Azerbaijan to attend the COP conference. The Taliban took over the agency when they returned to power as U.S.-led forces withdrew.</p>

<p>Taliban officials have taken part in U.N.-organised meetings on Afghanistan in Doha, and Taliban ministers have attended forums in China and Central Asia in the past two years.</p>

<p>But the U.N. Framework Convention on Climate Change's Bureau of the COP has deferred consideration of Afghanistan's participation since 2021, in effect freezing the country out of the talks.</p>

<p>Afghan NGOs have also struggled to attend climate negotiations in recent years.</p>

<p>Host Azerbaijan invited the Afghan environment agency officials to COP29 as observers, enabling them to "potentially participate in periphery discussions and potentially hold bilateral meetings," a diplomatic source familiar with the matter told Reuters.</p>

<p>Because the Taliban are not formally recognised within the U.N. system as the legitimate government of Afghanistan, the source said, the officials cannot receive credentials to take part in the proceedings of full member states.</p>

<p>Azerbaijan's presidency declined to comment.</p>

<p>The Taliban has closed schools and universities to female students over the age of around 12. It also announced a set of wide-ranging morality laws this year that require women to cover their faces in public and restrict their travel outside the home without a male guardian.</p>

<p>The Taliban says it respects women's rights in accordance with its interpretation of Islamic law.</p>

<p>Afghanistan is considered one of the countries worst affected by climate change. Flash floods have killed hundreds this year, and the heavily agriculture-dependent country has suffered through one of the worst droughts in decades. Many subsistence farmers, who make up much of the population, face deepening food insecurity.</p>

<p>Some advocates have criticised international isolation of the Taliban, saying it only hurts the Afghan people.</p>

<p>"Afghanistan is one of the countries that is really left behind on the needs that it has," said Habib Mayar, deputy general secretary of the g7+, an intergovernmental organisation of countries affected by conflict.</p>

<p>"It is a double price that they are paying," Mayar said. "There is lack of attention, lack of connection with the international community, and then there are increasing humanitarian needs."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/hdq6n34g_un-climate-conference_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The COP29 climate summit is taking place in Azerbaijan's capital Baku]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-bar-shooting-10-dead-7-injured-as-gunmen-open-fire-at-mexico-bar-6985279]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[10 Dead, 7 Injured As Gunmen Open Fire At Mexico Bar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mexico-bar-shooting-10-dead-7-injured-as-gunmen-open-fire-at-mexico-bar-6985279]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 12:34:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The attackers arrived in a pickup truck and opened fire inside the bar in the central Mexican city of Queretaro.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gunmen attacked a bar in central Mexican city of Queretaro killing 10 people on Saturday, a local security official said. The attackers opened fire inside the Los Cantaritos bar in the city's historic district, according to the head of Queretaro's public security department Juan Luis Ferrusca.</p>

<p>"Emergency services arrived at the scene and confirmed that at least four people armed with long weapons had arrived on board a pickup truck," he said in a video posted on social media.</p>

<p>"Inside, 10 people were reported dead and at least seven more were injured so far," he added.</p>

<p>One suspect was detained and the vehicle used in the attack was found abandoned and set on fire, Ferrusca said.</p>

<p>Queretaro is considered one of the safer cities in Mexico, where spiralling violence, much of it linked to drug trafficking and gangs, has seen more than 450,000 people murdered since 2006.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/oppfosa8_mexico-police_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-launches-drone-attack-on-moscow-two-airports-shut-6985121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Moscow Airports Shut, 1 Injured After Ukraine's Biggest-Ever Drone Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-ukraine-launches-drone-attack-on-moscow-two-airports-shut-6985121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 12:02:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine's biggest drone strike on the Russian capital since the start of the war forced flights to be diverted from three of the city's major airports.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ukraine attacked Moscow on Sunday with at least 32 drones, the biggest drone strike on the Russian capital since the start of the war in 2022, forcing flights to be diverted from three of the city's major airports and injuring at least one person.</p>

<p>Russian air defences shot down 32 drones flying towards Moscow over the Ramenskoye and Kolomensky districts of the Moscow region, as well as in Domodedovo city, home to one of the city's biggest airports, Moscow Mayor Sergei Sobyanin said.</p>

<p>"32 drones flying to Moscow have been destroyed," Sobyanin said. He reported no major damage, though Russia's federal air transport agency said the airports of Domodedovo, Sheremetyevo and Zhukovo had diverted flights.</p>

<p>One person was injured.</p>

<p>The airports have since resumed their operations, Russia's aviation watchdog Rosaviatsia said.</p>

<p>Moscow and its surrounding region, with a population of at least 21 million people, is one of the biggest metropolitan areas in Europe, alongside Istanbul.</p>

<p>The Ramenskoye district, some 45 km (30 miles) southeast of the Kremlin, was last targeted in September in what was then Ukraine's biggest attack on the Russian capital, when Russian air defence units destroyed 20 drones.</p>

<p>Unverified video posted on Russian Telegram channels showed drones buzzing across the skyline. Russian officials reported multiple Ukrainian drone attacks in other regions, among them the Kaluga, Bryansk and Orlov regions.</p>

<p>The 2-1/2-year-old war in Ukraine is entering what some officials say could be its final act after Moscow's forces advanced at the fastest pace since the early days of the war and Donald Trump was elected 47th president of the United States.</p>

<p>Trump, who takes office in January, said during campaigning that he could bring peace in Ukraine within 24 hours, but has given few details on how he would seek to do this.</p>

<p>When Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy called Trump to congratulate him on his presidential election victory, Tesla CEO and Trump supporter Elon Musk joined the call, according to media reports. Musk owns SpaceX, which provides Starlink satellite communication services that are vital for Ukraine's defense effort.</p>

<p>MOSCOW 'UMBRELLAS'</p>

<p>Kyiv, itself the target of repeated mass drone strikes from Russian forces, has tried to strike back against its vastly larger eastern neighbour with repeated drone strikes against oil refineries, airfields and even the Russian strategic early-warning radar stations.</p>

<p>While the 1,000 km (620 mile) front has largely resembled grinding World War One trench and artillery warfare for much of the war, one of the biggest innovations of the conflict has been drone warfare.</p>

<p>Moscow and Kyiv have both sought to buy and develop new drones, deploy them in innovative ways, and seek new ways to destroy them - from using farmers' shotguns to advanced electronic jamming systems.</p>

<p>Moscow has developed a series of electronic "umbrellas" over Moscow, with additional advanced internal layers over strategic buildings, and a complex web of air defences which shoot down the drones before they reach the Kremlin at the heart of the Russian capital.</p>

<p>Both sides have turned cheap commercial drones into deadly weapons while ramping up their own production. Soldiers on both sides have reported the visceral fear of drones - and both sides have used macabre video footage of fatal drone strikes in their propaganda.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin, who has sought to insulate Moscow from the grinding rigours of the war, has called Ukrainian drone attacks that target civilian infrastructure such as nuclear power plants "terrorism" and has vowed a response.</p>

<p>Moscow, by far Russia's richest city, has boomed during the war, buoyed by the biggest defence spending splurge since the Cold War.</p>

<p>There was no sign of panic on Moscow's boulevards. Muscovites walked their dogs while the bells of the onion-domed Russian Orthodox churches rang out across the capital.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/a1ftjatg_moscow-drone-attack_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[File photo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-could-put-more-money-in-americans-pockets-with-tax-code-changes-experts-6985076]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Donald Trump Plans To Put More Money In Americans' Pockets]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-could-put-more-money-in-americans-pockets-with-tax-code-changes-experts-6985076]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 11:51:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During the campaign trail, Donald Trump heavily focused on slashing taxes on tips as well as other social security benefits.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">In the recently concluded US presidential election 2024, economic problems were a driving factor for voters, resulting in Donald Trump's return to the White House.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Now, experts have predicted that the President-elect may put more money into the pockets of the Americans through major <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/factbox-what-new-proposals-did-trump-make-during-his-economic-speech-6501352">tax code changes</a>.</p>

<p dir="ltr">During his campaign trail, Mr Trump put major emphasis on slashing taxes on tips as well as other social security benefits, suggesting a total overhaul of income taxes with the hope of replacing the revenue with tariffs.</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to the <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/09/us-news/trump-plans-ambitious-tax-agenda-with-insiders-revealing-how-it-could-put-more-money-in-americans-pockets/" rel="nofollow,noindex">New York Post</a>, the extension and expansion of tax changes are high on Donald Trump's agenda.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Among the wish-list items of the expanded tax cut program, the key focus would be on cutting down corporate tax rates. Earlier, Mr Trump had slashed the corporate tax rate from 35% to 21% in 2017. He now plans to bring it down to 15%.</p>

<p dir="ltr">“When you reduce the corporate rate by 2% wages go up 1%, corporations have more money to invest for workers,” the report quoted Grover Norquist, an activist and president of Americans for Tax Reform, as saying.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Not just that, Mr Trump has even promised his voters to reverse a provision of his 2017 <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/president-donald-trump-tax-overhaul-under-intensifying-fire-as-congress-readies-bill-1768800">tax cut package</a> — the $10,000 cap on the famous state and local tax deductions, known as 'SALT'.</p>

<p dir="ltr">This cap majorly targets residents of high-tax 'blue' states wherein the soaring state and local taxes support bloated state bureaucracies. Hence, the promise by Donald Trump to repeal this has the potential to be an early bipartisan win, the New York Post report said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Long Island Democratic Representative Tom Suozzi, a critic of the cap, said he takes Donald Trump at his word, holding him accountable for the promise to eliminate the SALT cap.</p>

<p dir="ltr">"I will work with him and anyone to get things done on behalf of the people,” Mr Suozzi was quoted as saying.</p>

<p dir="ltr">However, insiders have suggested that this repeal can be a significantly heavier lift. “The major problem is it pits high tax states against low tax states. Phil Magness, an economic historian at the Independent Institute, said.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Noting that regions like New York, California and New Jersey have high state and local tax rates, Magness said it gives those who live there an advantage in their deductions against the ones who are residing in low-tax areas like Florida or Texas.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/dmlqqgeo_donald-trump_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-youtuber-kisses-comfort-woman-statue-in-korea-apologises-later-6984866]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[American Youtuber Kisses Korean Wartime Memorial Statue. Then This Happens]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-youtuber-kisses-comfort-woman-statue-in-korea-apologises-later-6984866]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 11:12:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 24-year-old American YouTuber, named Johnny Somali, has apologised after getting involved in a highly controversial incident in Korea.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A 24-year-old American YouTuber, named Johnny Somali, has apologised after getting involved in a highly controversial incident in Korea.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mr Somali sparked massive outrage when he kissed the statue of a girl, symbolising Korean victims of wartime sexual slavery, during his visit to Changdong History and Culture Park in Seoul's Dobong district, <a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/nation/2024/11/113_385960.html" rel="nofollow noindex">The Korea Times</a> reported.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The apology was shared on the YouTube channel Company on Thursday. In the video, Mr Somali can be seen standing next to the girl's statue and apologising to the Korean public.</p>

<p dir="ltr">"I want to apologise to Koreans. I didn't understand the significance of the statue," Mr Somali said.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">Further, Mr Somali explained that his actions were to entertain his viewers in the US. While bowing down, he added in Korean, "I'm truly sorry for being disrespectful."</p>

<p dir="ltr">Mr Somali has also expressed his interest in learning more about the history of Japan's wartime sex slavery and the victims, who are also known as the "comfort women". In the video, Mr Somali shared his willingness to meet the survivors in person and interview them to learn more about their history.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MkCLSon5kAo?si=VEMG0qhzJLmxysZa" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p dir="ltr">Despite the apology many viewers have expressed doubt on Mr Somali, noting that he has shared multiple controversial photographs and videos on his social media accounts.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Several people have highlighted that Mr Somali hasn't deleted the images and videos of his controversial actions from social media.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">This is not the first time when Mr Somali faced criticism for his actions. A while back, he shared a photograph of himself holding an image of former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe and said, "I defeated Koreans for you, Shinzo Abe."&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">While the post on YouTube was later deleted, it continued to be visible on Instagram with the caption, "RIP Shinzo Abe, I defeated the Koreans for you!"</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBq45ZwPdQp/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBq45ZwPdQp/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBq45ZwPdQp/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DBq45ZwPdQp/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Johnny Somali ???????? (@johnnysomalia)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p dir="ltr">In another post on Instagram, Mr Somali can be seen lying down and dancing in a local metro in Korea.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBe2IJWPQn6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBe2IJWPQn6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBe2IJWPQn6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DBe2IJWPQn6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Johnny Somali ???????? (@johnnysomalia)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p dir="ltr">On October 31, the Seoul Mapo Police informed that Mr Somali was being investigated for obstruction of business over his behaviour at a convenience store. In addition to this, police are also looking into allegations of alleged assault and drug use as Somali is currently on an "exit ban" that prevents him from leaving the country.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/me7qv0to_johnny-somalia_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The apology was shared on the YouTube channel Company on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-new-tariff-policies-can-affect-asian-economies-including-india-6984737]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Trump's New Tariff Policies Can Affect Asian Economies Including India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-donald-trumps-new-tariff-policies-can-affect-asian-economies-including-india-6984737]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 10:46:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some Asian countries stand to gain if US president-elect Donald Trump pushes ahead with his promised massive tariffs on China and triggers a new wave of factory relocations to the rest of the region.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some Asian countries stand to gain if US president-elect Donald Trump pushes ahead with his promised massive tariffs on China and triggers a new wave of factory relocations to the rest of the region.</p>

<p>But a trade war between the world's biggest economies would also destabilise markets everywhere, with Asia -- which contributes the largest share of global growth -- the most affected.</p>

<p>Trump, who won a crushing presidential victory this week, vowed during his campaign to slap 60 per cent tariffs on all Chinese goods entering the United States in an attempt to balance trade between the two nations.</p>

<p>Analysts however question whether the new president will stick to such a high figure, and dispute the blow such tariffs could inflect on the Chinese economy, estimating GDP could be lowered by between 0.7 per cent and 1.6 per cent.</p>

<p>The cooling effect would also make waves throughout Southeast Asia, where production chains are closely linked to China and enjoy significant investment from Beijing.</p>

<p>"Lower US demand for Chinese goods due to higher tariffs on China will translate into lower demand for ASEAN exports, even if there aren't US tariffs levied directly onto those economies," said Adam Ahmad Samdin, of Oxford Economics.</p>

<p>Indonesia is particularly exposed through its strong exports of nickel and minerals, but China is also the top trading partner of Japan, Taiwan and South Korea.</p>

<p>In addition to China, Donald Trump has also warned of an increase of 10 to 20 per cent on duties for all imports, as part of his protectionist policies and fixation that other countries take advantage of the US.</p>

<p>"The extent of these effects likely depends on the direct exposure of each economy to the US," said Samdin, who added that America accounts for a 39.1 per cent share of Cambodian exports, 27.4 per cent from Vietnam, 17 per cent from Thailand and 15.4 per cent from the Philippines.</p>

<h3><strong>India to be targeted?&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Trump first slapped China with heavy tariffs in 2018 during his first administration, leading to the emergence of "connector countries", through which Chinese companies passed their products to avoid American taxes.</p>

<p>Those countries could be in the line of fire now.</p>

<p>"Vietnam's electronics exports to the US could also be targeted by Trump, in a bid to halt the diversion of Chinese electronic products to the US via Vietnam since 2018," said Lloyd Chan, a senior analyst at MUFG, Japan's largest bank.</p>

<p>"This is not inconceivable. Trade rewiring has notably gained traction in the region's electronics value chain."</p>

<p>"India could itself become a target of protectionist measures by the US due to the large share of Chinese components in Indian products," added Alexandra Hermann, an economist with Oxford Economics.</p>

<p>Trump could also impose higher tariffs on Indian goods in sectors such as "automobiles, textiles, pharmaceuticals and wines, which could make Indian exports less competitive in the US", said Ajay Srivastava of the New Delhi-based Global Trade Research Initiative.</p>

<p>A trade war would be dangerous for India, said Ajay Sahai, director of the Federation of Indian Export Organisations.</p>

<p>"Trump is a transactional person. He may target higher tariffs on certain items of Indian exports so he can negotiate for lower tariffs for US products in India," he told AFP.</p>

<h3><strong>Supply chain rejig&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>In the medium term, these negative effects could be counterbalanced by establishing factories outside China to escape the fallout.</p>

<p>The "China+1" strategy initiated during Donald Trump's first term saw production shifts to India, Malaysia, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>

<p>With its geographical position and cheap skilled labour, Vietnam has already been one of the main beneficiaries.</p>

<p>The country has notably received investments from Taiwanese Apple subcontractors Foxconn and Pegatron and South Korea's Samsung, becoming the second-largest exporter of smartphones in the world behind China.</p>

<p>"The likelihood increases that even more businesses will want to... have a second, or third, production base outside China," said Bruno Jaspaert, chairman of the European Chamber of Commerce in Vietnam.</p>

<p>Chinese firms themselves are investing massively from Vietnam to Indonesia in sectors including solar, batteries, electric vehicles and minerals.</p>

<p>"American companies and investors are very interested in opportunities in Vietnam and this will continue under the incoming Trump Administration," said Adam Sitkoff, executive director of the American Chamber of Commerce in Hanoi.</p>

<p>But whether it is low-end or high-tech production, China's competitive advantage in terms of price, scale and quality is difficult to reproduce, warns Nomura Bank.</p>

<p>A reorganisation of production chains could lead to a "loss of efficiency" and increased prices, "with a negative impact on global growth", Thomas Helbling, deputy director of the IMF for Asia, recently explained to AFP.</p>

<p>Asian countries could therefore gain export market share but ultimately see their situation deteriorate amid weakening global demand.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/v5klevj8_donald-trump-afp_625x300_02_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump vowed to slap 60 per cent tariffs on all Chinese goods entering the US. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-to-be-his-friend-or-watch-from-sidelines-6984734]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Trump: To Be His Friend Or Watch From Sidelines?]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/trump-to-be-his-friend-or-watch-from-sidelines-6984734]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 10:44:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The undeniable fact is that Trumps America subscribes to the notion of a clash of civilisations and champions Christian causes. Hindu nationalism cannot align with Trumps Christian nationalism without undermining the very ideology of Hindutva.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/6i6vlv8o_pm-modi-trump-howdy-modi-event-afp-650_650x400_23_September_19.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A political analyst in the US called Donald Trump's victory ‘magic realism'. Intellectuals in America are in shock. They are aghast to see the margin of Trump's victory and are trying to figure out the reason. They are struggling to understand if it is the defeat of elite politics or a rejection of democracy as was being played out in America. But what surprised me more was the reaction of certain sections in India. Instead of mourning the defeat of an Indian-origin candidate, they are celebrating the victory of an American Christian, supported by an evangelical church. These are the same people who were angry when Hindus were targeted in Bangladesh and in Canada by the ‘forces of evil'.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Kamala Harris is the daughter of a Hindu mother. She is proud of her Hindu origin. A Hindu woman who went on to become the Vice President of America and finally a candidate for the post of president, is a remarkable story. Unlike Hillary Clinton, she is not the product of entitlement or member of American establishment; she is an outlier who rose from humble background to become the Vice President of America by sheer grit, talent and hard work.</p>

<h2><strong>Why Are Indians Happy?</strong></h2>

<p>But why are these people happy in her defeat? Is it because she did not pay any lip service to Bangladeshi Hindus, like Trump did? Or is it because the politics of Kamla Harris—she is not divisive and she talks about democracy and constitutionalism—makes these people uncomfortable? Is it because she does not support the politics of majoritarianism? Or that she speaks for people of all faiths and does not discriminate between people on the basis of their race and gender? Or is it because she does not crack crass and sexist jokes like Trump does?&nbsp;</p>

<p>Those who are celebrating Trump assuming that he is a friend of India and that India will benefit from his presidency are living in a fool's paradise. They are victims of false consciousness and prisoners of a fantasy. It is important to remember that Trump is an American and the President of the United States. His promise is to make America great again—not India. Any steps Trump takes to fulfil his promise of making America great again will likely come at India's expense, as well as that of the rest of the world. If taking strong measures against India becomes necessary, he will not hesitate to do so.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump Politics Is Transactional</strong></h2>

<p>We must remember that his politics is not doctrinaire but purely transactional. India will soon face the impact of his cynicism. He will likely impose restrictions on the entry of Indians into the United States, with the H1B visa program being the first casualty. Trade with the US will become more challenging as he will pressure the Indian government to "cut tariffs" and may even "impose higher tariffs on Indian goods". Even before his election, he had grouped India with Brazil and China on the issue of tariffs and called India a "very big abuser of tariffs". If he follows through on his promise to expel immigrants—a major commitment to his American voters—Indians will not be exempt.</p>

<p>However, the situation would have been similar with Kamala Harris too. Had she been elected president, she would have also prioritised America's interests, despite her Indian heritage. Therefore, regardless of who wins, India has no reason to celebrate. India must focus on protecting its national interests, and it is always preferable to deal with a leader who is predictable and stable. Trump, however, is an unpredictable figure with an unstable character and did not have a clean record during his first term as president.</p>

<h2><strong>Trump's Biggest Supporters?&nbsp;Conservative Christians&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>I am sure those who are rejoicing Trump's victory must be aware that Trump represents a revival of ‘Christian nationalism', which many like Bishop Michael Curry called a ‘threat to America's soul'. The&nbsp;<em>New York Times</em> reported, “He (Trump) says he will affirm that God made only two genders, male and female. He will create a task force to fight anti-Christian bias. And he will give enhanced access to conservative Christian leaders, if they elect him.” He says, “We have to save religion.” The New York Times writes, “And for nearly a decade, right-wing Christian power has intensified, largely under Mr Trump's watch. He won the White House in 2016 promising that “Christianity will have power.”</p>

<p>Trump's strongest support comes from Middle America, a bastion of conservative Christians. In this election, evangelical churches were especially active among Latin American Christians—who traditionally vote for the Democratic Party—convincing them to support Trump. And they succeeded. More than 40% of Latinos backed Trump, contributing significantly to his substantial victory margin.</p>

<p>Does this mean that those in India who champion Hindu nationalism are now endorsing the rise of Christian nationalism? If so, why do proponents of Hindutva decry Christianity, alongside Islam, as an inimical force threatening India's unity and integrity, alleging that it channels millions of dollars to convert Hindus to Christianity?</p>

<h2><strong>What Golwalkar Said</strong></h2>

<p>It is worth remembering that long ago, Golwalkar, a father figure of Hindutva, named Christians as one of the three enemies of India and accused Christian missionaries of working under the guise of humanitarian aid to make India a Christian land. He wrote, “Such is the role of Christian gentlemen residing in our land today, out to demolish not only the religious and social fabric of our life but also to establish political domination in various pockets and, if possible, all over the land.” He further stated, “Wherever they have stepped, they have drenched those lands with the blood and tears of the natives and liquidated whole races. Do we not know the heart-rending stories of how they annihilated the natives in America, Australia, and Africa?”</p>

<p>I don't know whether the RSS has changed its stance on Christian missionaries or their ideology. Nor do I know if the RSS has reached some form of truce with Christian nationalism. The undeniable fact is that Trump's America subscribes to the notion of a clash of civilisations and champions Christian causes. Despite its best intentions, Hindu nationalism cannot align with Trump's Christian nationalism without undermining the very ideology of Hindutva. This raises the question: why is there so much support for Trump?</p>

<p>Is it not ironic that, on one hand, followers of Hindutva issue a clarion call in India for Hindu unity, while on the other, they are unwilling to support a woman of Hindu origin who has achieved significant success abroad—something that should inspire pride among Hindus? Does this not point to a kind of ideological confusion and contradiction within the movement that claims to make India great and position it as a&nbsp;<i>Vishwaguru</i>? This deserves serious contemplation.</p>

<p><em>(Ashutosh is the author of 'Hindu Rashtra' and co-founder of&nbsp;SatyaHindi.com)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-09/6i6vlv8o_pm-modi-trump-howdy-modi-event-afp-650_650x400_23_September_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-why-official-residence-of-us-president-is-called-the-white-house-6984590]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Why Official Residence Of US President Is Called The White House]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-election-2024-why-official-residence-of-us-president-is-called-the-white-house-6984590]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 10:14:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Many people believe that the White House is named after its 'white' colour.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The White House, one of the most iconic buildings worldwide, has served as the official residence and workplace of the US President for more than 200 years. President-elect Donald Trump will be moving into the White House with his family in January next year. The 78-year-old defeated Democrat Kamala Harris in the November 5 elections.</p>

<p dir="ltr">A question that keeps doing rounds is why this famous building has been termed as "The White House"? While many believe that it must be due to its white colour, this does not fully explain the logic.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>War of 1812</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">There is a misconception that the building was painted white for the first time to cover the marks left by British soldiers, who had burned it down on August 24, 1814, two years after the war broke out.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The often-told story suggests that the building was painted white to hide these marks. Though it looks like an interesting story, it is not true.</p>

<p dir="ltr">The colour of the White House has been white since the very beginning when the first US President George Washington selected the location for the White House in 1791. The cornerstone was laid the following year with its design being given by Irish-born architect James Hoban. After eight years of construction, President John Adams and his wife Abigail became the first to move in -- though it was still unfinished at that time.</p>

<p dir="ltr">According to the White House Historical Association, the building received a lime-based whitewash in 1798 to protect its "sandstone exterior from moisture and cracking during winter freezes."&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Official name</strong></p>

<p dir="ltr">While there was no official name for the building in the beginning, the term “White House” was occasionally used by many throughout the nineteenth century, besides other names like “President's House” and the “Executive Mansion.”</p>

<p dir="ltr">This term became official on October 17, 1901, when then US President Theodore Roosevelt's secretary George Cortelyou sent a letter to Secretary of State John Hay.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">On Roosevelt's direction, the official was asked to change headings or date lines of all official papers and documents requiring the president's signature, from ‘Executive Mansion' to ‘White House'.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Since then, the 'White House' has been the official name of the US President's residence, which after multiple expansions now has 132 rooms, 35 bathrooms as well as six levels.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/qq91uo5_white-house_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-floods-thousands-protest-in-spain-over-handling-of-deadly-floods-6984587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Protest In Spain Over Handling Of Deadly Floods]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spain-floods-thousands-protest-in-spain-over-handling-of-deadly-floods-6984587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 10:11:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Devastating floods in Spain killed more than 220 people in one of Europe's worst natural disasters for decades.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tens of thousands of people demonstrated in the eastern Spanish city of Valencia on Saturday over regional authorities' handling of devastating floods that killed more than 220 people in one of Europe's worst natural disasters for decades.</p>

<p>In the latest demonstration over the floods, protesters filled the centre of Valencia demanding the resignation of regional government leader Carlos Mazon and chanting "Killers!".</p>

<p>"Our hands are stained with mud, yours with blood," read one banner. Some demonstrators dumped dirty boots outside the government building while others plastered it with mud.</p>

<p>Residents in stricken areas accuse Mazon of issuing an alert too late, at 8 p.m. on Oct. 29, well after water was already pouring into many nearby towns and villages.</p>

<p>The Valencian leader has said he would have issued an earlier alarm earlier if authorities had been notified of the seriousness of the situation by an official water monitoring body. Mazon did not respond to Reuters' requests for comment.</p>

<p>"We want to show our indignation and anger over the poor management of this disaster which has affected so many people," said Anna Oliver, president of Accio Cultural del Pais Valenciano, one of about 30 groups that organised the protest.</p>

<p>Though the demonstration was largely peaceful, police charged stone-throwing protesters at one point and objects hurled at the city council building caused minor damage.</p>

<p>Following days of storm warnings from the national weather service from Oct. 25 onward, some municipalities and local bodies raised the alarm much earlier than the regional government.</p>

<p>For example, Valencia University told its staff on Oct. 28 not to come to work. Several town halls suspended activities, shut down public facilities and told people to stay home.</p>

<p>Weather service AEMET raised its threat level for heavy rains in the area to a red alert at 7:36 a.m. on Oct. 29.</p>

<p>Nearly 80 people are still missing in what is the most deadly deluge in a single European country since floods in Portugal in 1967 killed around 500.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/gfh481i_spain-floods_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nearly 80 people are still missing]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-official-who-told-relief-workers-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-sacked-6984548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Official Who Told Relief Workers To Avoid Homes With Trump Signs Sacked]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-official-who-told-relief-workers-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-sacked-6984548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 10:03:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[EMA Administrator Deanne Criswell announced the sacking a day after Daily Wire published a copy of Washington's message.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marn'i Washington, a Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) supervisor, has been sacked after she advised her disaster relief team to avoid homes with signs supporting President-elect Donald Trump when Hurricane Milton ravaged the area last month. FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell announced the sacking a day after <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/realDailyWire/status/1854999583790911770?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1855030970140770445%7Ctwgr%5Eae4413ffe6ae67fdb63d087d77a1ba0441c8dc67%7Ctwcon%5Es3_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ndtv.com%2Fworld-news%2Frelief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914" rel="nofollow, noindex">Daily Wire</a></em> published a copy of Ms Washington's message to her employees regarding the rescue effort. Criswell said Washington had violated the FEMA values which intended to help people regardless of their political affiliations.</p>

<p>"This is a clear violation of FEMA's core values and principles to help people regardless of their political affiliation. This employee has been terminated and we have referred the matter to the Office of Special Counsel," said Criswell on Saturday (Nov 9).</p>

<p>"More than 22,000 FEMA employees every day adhere to FEMA's core values and are dedicated to helping people before, during and after disasters, often sacrificing time with their own families to help disaster survivors," she added.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">More than 22,000 FEMA employees every day adhere to FEMA's core values and are dedicated to helping people before, during and after disasters, often sacrificing time with their own families to help disaster survivors. <a href="https://t.co/hPc0zyTBCM">https://t.co/hPc0zyTBCM</a></p>
— Deanne Criswell (@FEMA_Deanne) <a href="https://twitter.com/FEMA_Deanne/status/1855322112719741197?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Ms Washington's sister April Brown said she was shocked to hear about the allegations levelled against her sibling.</p>

<p>"I'm completely shocked. I can tell you that she set out to help and serve all people. With her being in that position with FEMA I can't see her doing anything like that," Ms Brown told <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/09/us-news/fema-official-who-allegedly-told-workers-to-avoid-florida-homes-with-trump-signs-fired-report/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NY Post.</em></a></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/relief-workers-directed-to-avoid-homes-with-trump-signs-during-hurricane-milton-report-6977914" rel="nofollow, noindex"><strong>Also read | Relief Workers Told To Avoid Homes With Trump Signs During Hurricane Milton: Report</strong></a></p>

<h3><strong>What did Washington order?</strong></h3>

<p>Ms Washinton passed the perplexing order to her workers both verbally and in a Microsoft Teams chat. "Avoid homes advertising Trump," she wrote in the "best practices" memo. As many as 20 homes displaying signs for the Republican leader - a common sight during the election season, were ignored between the end of October and into November, as part of the directive by Washington.</p>

<p>After the incident came to light, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis took to X (formerly Twitter) and called Washington's order a "blatant weaponization of government by partisan activists".</p>

<p>"At my direction, the Division of Emergency Management is launching an investigation into the federal government's targeted discrimination of Floridians who support Donald Trump," wrote Mr DeSantis.</p>

<p>"New leadership is on the way in DC, and I'm optimistic that these partisan bureaucrats will be fired," he added.</p>

<p>Notably, as many as 16 people lost their lives when Hurricane Milton dumped around 229 mm of rainfall in just three hours in Florida, causing flash flooding last month. The tropical storm spiralled across the Gulf of Mexico as a Category-5 hurricane before making landfall on Florida's coastline as a Category-3 hurricane, just two weeks after Hurricane Helene had caused devastation.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/583ov6dg_donald-trump_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-reports-first-case-of-bird-flu-in-a-person-rare-event-6984418]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Rare Event": Canada Reports First Case Of Bird Flu In A Person]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/canada-reports-first-case-of-bird-flu-in-a-person-rare-event-6984418]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:36:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The teenager likely caught the virus from a bird or animal and was receiving care at a children's hospital.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Canada has detected its first presumptive case of H5 bird flu in a person, a teenager in the western province of British Columbia, health officials said on Saturday.</p>

<p>The teenager likely caught the virus from a bird or animal and was receiving care at a children's hospital, the province said in a statement.</p>

<p>The province said it was investigating the source of exposure and identifying the teenager's contacts. The risk to the public remains low, Canada's Health Minister Mark Holland said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"This is a rare event," British Columbia Health Officer Bonnie Henry said in a statement. "We are conducting a thorough investigation to fully understand the source of exposure here in B.C."</p>

<p>H5 bird flu is widespread in wild birds worldwide and is causing outbreaks in poultry and US dairy cows, with several recent human cases in US dairy and poultry workers.</p>

<p>There has been no evidence of person-to-person spread so far. But if that were to happen, a pandemic could unfold, scientists have said.</p>

<p>Earlier in November, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention asked for farm workers who have been exposed to animals with bird flu to be tested for the virus even if they do not have symptoms.</p>

<p>Bird flu has infected nearly 450 dairy farms in 15 U.S. states since March, and the CDC has identified 46 human cases of bird flu since April.</p>

<p>In Canada, British Columbia has identified at least 22 infected poultry farms since October, and numerous wild birds tested positive, according to the province.</p>

<p>Canada has had no cases reported in dairy cattle and no evidence of bird flu in samples of milk.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/eulu15t8_bird-flu_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[H5 bird flu is widespread in wild birds worldwide]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meat-alcohol-at-diwali-party-hosted-by-uk-pm-offends-british-hindus-6984305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meat, Alcohol At Diwali Party Hosted By UK PM Offends British Hindus]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meat-alcohol-at-diwali-party-hosted-by-uk-pm-offends-british-hindus-6984305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:10:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Meat and alcohol were allegedly served at the Diwali party hosted by UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer at 10, Downing Street, offending some British Hindus.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meat and alcohol were allegedly served at the Diwali party hosted by UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer at 10, Downing Street, offending some British Hindus. The celebration at the PM's official residence, attended by community leaders and top politicians, included lighting diyas, a Kuchipudi dance performance, and a speech by Starmer.</p>

<p>Some British Hindus, however, expressed shock when they found out the dinner menu included liquor and non-vegetarian dishes. Lamb kebabs, beer, and wine were served to the guests, reports suggest.</p>

<p>Meat and liquor were not on the menu when Rishi Sunak hosted the Diwali celebration last year.</p>

<p>Satish K Sharma, a prominent British Hindu pandit, accused the Prime Minister's office of a "complete lack of sensitivity and simple consultation".</p>

<p>"For the last 14 years or so, the Diwali celebration at 10, Downing Street has been without meat and alcohol. I am disappointed and quite shocked that this year's celebration seemed to be an inebriated meat-induced stupor-dominated event. It's a tragedy that the prime minister's advisers would have been so careless and negligent," he said in a video statement posted on X.</p>

<p>If it was accidental, it was still disappointing, and if deliberate, the Prime Minister has sent a message to the British Hindu community, read Mr Sharma's post as he called on Starmer to issue a statement.</p>

<p>Insight UK, a social movement of British Hindus and Indians, said the "sacred celebration was marred by meat and alcohol" and has offered to advise 10, Downing Street officials on religious sentiments.</p>

<p>The choice of menu displayed an appalling lack of understanding or respect for the religious traditions associated with Diwali, it said in an online post, urging greater consideration for future events.</p>

<p>10, Downing Street is yet to respond.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/ec28pufg_starmer-diwali_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Meat and liquor were not on the menu at last year's celebrations.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sues-egyptair-for-5mn-after-scalding-beverage-falls-on-her-6984294]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Sues EgyptAir For $5 Million After Scalding Beverage Falls On Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sues-egyptair-for-5mn-after-scalding-beverage-falls-on-her-6984294]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:04:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hezains attorney, Abram Bohrer informed that his client had suffered second-degree burns to her lower abdomen, her right inner thigh and buttocks.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A New York woman has sued EgyptAir for $5 million in damages, claiming that a "scalding beverage" was splashed on her as she boarded the flight from John F. Kennedy Airport to Cairo, according to a report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/11/09/us-news/nyc-woman-sues-egyptair-for-5m-over-scalding-beverage-on-defective-seat-tray/" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>NY Post</em></a>. The woman has been identified as 35-year-old Esraa Hezain who said she suffered "second-degree burns" from the hot liquid. As per the Brooklyn federal court documents, the incident took place in February earlier this year as the beverage, kept in a "lidless cup" of tea flew off a "defective" seat tray and splashed over her.</p>

<p>After the beverage was served, the flight encountered "significant turbulence" that led to the incident. The suit alleged that the flight crew "failed to suspend service prior to the turbulence or issue a warning of the impending turbulence".</p>

<p>Hezain's attorney, Abram Bohrer informed the outlet that his client had suffered second-degree burns to her lower abdomen, her right inner thigh and buttocks. "For the price of a lid this didn't have to happen," he said.</p>

<p>EgyptAir had not commented on the incident as of the last update.</p>

<h3><strong>Previous case</strong></h3>

<p>The case bears similarities to a 2019 incident when a four-year-old girl suffered second-degree burns after a flaming-hot McDonald Chicken McNugget fell on her thigh in Florida, USA. Philana Holmes had taken her son and daughter to Tamarac McDonald's and bought the Happy Meals when she received the order but was not warned of the scalding nature of the food.</p>

<p>After receiving the food package, Ms Holmes passed it along to her daughter and son in the back seat of the car and drove away. A few moments later, her daughter, identified in court as Olivia Caraballo, an autistic child, started screaming immediately, forcing Ms Holmes to pull up in a parking lot.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-girl-awarded-800-000-after-she-was-severely-burned-by-mcdonalds-chicken-nugget-4226834" rel="nofollow, noindex">Also read | US Girl Awarded $800,000 After She Was Severely Burned By McDonald's Chicken Nugget</a></strong></p>

<p>After four years of legal battle, a South Florida jury in July 2023, awarded $800,000 in damages to Caraballo after the family initially sought $15 million in damages.</p>

<p>"I'm actually just happy they listened to Olivia's voice and she, the jury was able to decide a fair judgement, I'm happy with that," Ms Holmes said at the time.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-08/egypt-air_650x400_71470307829.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[EgyptAir has been sued by the Manhattan woman.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/behind-the-scenes-video-reveals-how-donald-trump-composes-social-media-posts-6984222]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Behind-The-Scenes Video Reveals How Trump Crafts His Social Media Posts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/behind-the-scenes-video-reveals-how-donald-trump-composes-social-media-posts-6984222]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 08:46:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In the video, viewers get to see Trump live-reacting to Kamala Harris' speech at the Democratic National Convention back in August.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A viral video has been making the rounds, showcasing how Donald Trump crafts his social media posts in real time. The video, part of the documentary series "Art of the Surge: The Donald Trump Comeback" from Tucker Carlson Network,&nbsp;promises to give viewers a glimpse into Trump's campaign, including his reactions to key events and his social media strategy. In the second episode, viewers get to see Trump live-reacting to Kamala Harris' speech at the Democratic National Convention back in August. The episode also reveals how Trump posts his thoughts to Truth Social where he has more than 8 million followers.</p>

<p>In the video, Trump is seen watching Vice President Kamala Harris' speech on Fox News with his campaign team including Matt Gaetz, Tulsi Gabbard, Dan Scavino, Stephen Miller and Susie Wiles. As Harris repeatedly says "Thank you," Trump opens a Coke and remarks, "Is she crazy? Too many Thank yous...Must be 35". Interestingly, Trump doesn't do any of the typing or posting himself, but dictates the posts and has his assistant Natalie Harpe type them out and post for him.</p>

<p>Responding to a section of Ms Harris's speech discussing her upbringing, Mr Trump says: “A lot of talk about childhood, we've got to get to the Border, Inflation, and Crime,” before commanding his team to “send these out”.</p>

<p>In a separate post, he dictates, ''She's talking about how great San Francisco was before she destroyed it, probably not a good idea!'' The videos confirm that Trump's social media posts are all still his own words, even if he doesn't physically type them out himself.</p>

<p><strong>Here's the video:</strong></p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">I used to think there was no way Trump was coming up with all his posts by himself, but the "Art of the Surge" documentary proves IT'S ALL HIM. He literally controls everything to the last detail ?<br />
<br />
He really is just built different.<br />
<br />
Also, those are some great typing skills… <a href="https://t.co/KwG5PKOOE0">pic.twitter.com/KwG5PKOOE0</a></p>
— George (@BehizyTweets) <a href="https://twitter.com/BehizyTweets/status/1851419171420045524?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The series also reveals that Trump watches news coverage, gets feedback from his campaign advisers, and then re-words their ideas into his posts.</p>

<p>Notably, Trump's posting style has been consistent across platforms, whether it's X or his own social media platform, Truth Social. His posts often feature odd capitalisation, insults directed at his political rivals, and stream-of-consciousness rants.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/leckf9eo_donald-trump-afp_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The video is part of a documentary 'Art of the Surge: The Donald Trump Comeback']]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-wins-arizona-sweeps-all-7-swing-states-against-kamala-harris-in-us-elections-2024-6984153]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Wins Arizona, Sweeps All 7 Swing States]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-wins-arizona-sweeps-all-7-swing-states-against-kamala-harris-in-us-elections-2024-6984153]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 08:24:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Saturday won Arizona, completing the Republican's sweep of all seven swing states in the November 5 election US presidential elections.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Saturday won Arizona, completing the Republican's sweep of all seven swing states in the November 5 US presidential elections. He retained the state and its 11 electoral votes to the Republican column after Democrat Joe Biden's 2020 victory.</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/putin-congratulates-trump-on-big-win-says-ready-to-hold-talks-with-him-6968279" target="_blank">Trump's win</a> over Democratic Vice President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-a-hard-fought-loss-will-kamala-harris-chart-a-new-course-6973556" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a> also marks the 78-year-old's second victory in Arizona since 2016.</p>

<p>According to the latest figures, Trump has so far got 312 electoral votes, well past the 270 needed to win the race to the White House. During his successful presidential campaign in 2016, he received 304 electoral votes.</p>

<p>US media have declared <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/insight-donald-trumps-2024-red-wave-explained-in-graphs-and-where-harris-fell-short-6981103" target="_blank">Trump</a> the winner in more than half of the 50 states, including swing states of Georgia, Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin, all of which voted Democratic in the last election. He also won the battleground states of North Carolina and Nevada.</p>

<p>He won wider margins than before, despite a criminal conviction and two impeachments while in office.</p>

<p>On the other hand, Harris, who replaced 81-year-old Biden as the Democrat nominee in July, stands at 226.</p>

<p>With <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-ukraine-war-european-troops-800-mile-buffer-zone-in-donald-trumps-ukraine-peace-plan-report-6984111" target="_blank">Donald Trump's defeat of Kamala Harris</a>, Republican and Democratic presidents will alternate control of the White House for the fourth straight term, a level of volatility between the parties not seen in the United States since the late 19th century.</p>

<p>Biden, who dropped out of the race over age concerns, will meet Trump at the Oval Office on Wednesday.</p>

<h3><strong>Trump 2.0</strong></h3>

<p>Ahead of his inauguration on January 20, Donald Trump has started to assemble his second administration and named campaign manager Susie Wiles to serve as his White House chief of staff.</p>

<p>Wiles, 67, is the first woman to be named to the high-profile role.</p>

<p>Other candidates who could find a place in Trump 2.0 are Elon Musk, the world's richest man who could get a job auditing government waste, former ambassador to Germany Ric Grenell, who is seen as a frontrunner for the secretary of state position and Robert F Kennedy Jr, whom Trump has pledged a "big role" in health care.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/05nbefig_donald-trump_625x300_07_November_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sets-guinness-world-record-by-donating-over-2-600-litres-of-breastmilk-6984147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Sets World Record By Donating Over 2,600 Litres Of Breast Milk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-woman-sets-guinness-world-record-by-donating-over-2-600-litres-of-breastmilk-6984147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 10 Nov 2024 08:21:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She wants to spread the word about donating breastmilk, as she thinks that like her, other women might not realize they could be in a position to help other mothers and their babies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Texas resident Alyssa Ogletree has shattered her own record for the largest individual breastmilk donation, supplying an astonishing 2,645.58 litres to those in need. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2024/nov/09/texas-woman-breastmilk-donation-record">Guardian</a></em>, Ms Ogletree, 36, previously held the Guinness World Record in 2014 with a donation of 1,569.79 litres, and has now surpassed her achievement, earning recognition from the esteemed organization for her incredible contribution. According to the Mothers' Milk Bank of North Texas, a single litre of breastmilk can sustain 11 premature babies.&nbsp;Based on this calculation, she estimated that her donations to the organization have helped over 350,000 babies.</p>

<p>''I have a big heart, [but] at the end of the day, I'm not made of money and can't give away money to good causes over and over because I have a family to support. But donating milk was a way I could give back,'', she said in an interview recently published on <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/most-breastmilk-donated">Guinness World Records' website.</a></em></p>

<p>She added: “If the three per ounce is accurate, I've helped over 350,000 babies. This record is for just under 89,000 ounces, but I also did around 37,000 to Tiny Treasures, and probably another couple hundred to close friends.''</p>

<p>Ms Ogletree started donating breast milk in 2010 when she gave birth to her son Kyle, now 14. After discovering she was producing an unusually large amount of milk., a nurse suggested donating the excess to help mothers struggling to feed their babies. This sparked Ogletree's passion for helping others through breastmilk donation, paving the way for her record-breaking contributions.</p>

<p>After Kyle, she continued donating milk following the births of her two younger sons, Kage (12) and Kory (7). She also donated milk after serving as a surrogate mother.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She now has four children and continued to pump after her babies stopped drinking milk from the bottle. "I pumped every 3 hours, even overnight, for 15-30 minutes. After pumping, I froze my milk until my freezer was full. Next, I took it to the milk bank, where they would measure the frozen milk on a specially calibrated scale," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Ogletree was never diagnosed with any condition that would explain her overproduction of milk.&nbsp;She said: ''I drank lots of water all the time, I stayed consistent with my pumping schedule, I ate healthy, I worked hard to pump like I did because I loved knowing how many babies I would be helping.''</p>

<p>She now wants to spread the word about donating breastmilk, as she thinks that like her, other women might not realize they could be in a position to help other mothers and their babies.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-11/epirv3rg_-alyssa-ogletree_625x300_10_November_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[With this accomplishment, she is happy to bring awareness to the importance of donating milk.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>