<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 20:18:31 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-update-israel-strikes-northern-lebanon-killing-18-escalates-war-with-hezbollah-6787976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel's War With Hezbollah Escalates After 18 Killed In Strikes On Lebanon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-update-israel-strikes-northern-lebanon-killing-18-escalates-war-with-hezbollah-6787976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 19:09:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel expanded its targets in its war with the Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon on Monday, killing at least 18 people in its first strike on the Christian-majority town of Aitou in the north, the Lebanese Red Cross said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israel expanded its targets in its war with the Iran-backed Hezbollah in Lebanon on Monday, killing at least 18 people in its first strike on the Christian-majority town of Aitou in the north, the Lebanese Red Cross said.</p>

<p>So far the main focus of Israel's military operations in Lebanon has been in the south, the eastern Bekaa Valley and the suburbs of Beirut.</p>

<p>The strike in the northern region hit a house that had been rented to displaced families, Aitou Mayor Joseph Trad told Reuters. In addition to the deaths, four people were injured, the Red Cross said.</p>

<p>Israel on Monday ordered residents of 25 villages to evacuate to areas north of the Awali River, which flows through southern Lebanon, as it intensifies its attacks in the region.</p>

<p>An Israeli strike killed Muhammad Kamel Naim, the commander of the anti-tank missile unit of Hezbollah's elite Radwan Force, in the Nabatieh area of south Lebanon, the military said.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has not immediately commented.</p>

<p>The operations come amidst high tensions between Israel and the UN peacekeeping force UNIFIL in south Lebanon, with Israeli Energy Minister Eli Cohen on Monday repeating a call by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for the UN troops to leave.</p>

<p>Israel and the United Nations have been trading accusations over the peacekeepers in south Lebanon, as Israel keeps pushing its forces through the area in an attempt to wipe out Iran-backed Hezbollah and its military infrastructure while it battles Hamas in Gaza.</p>

<p>The UN said Israeli tanks had burst into its base on Sunday, the latest allegations of Israeli violations against peacekeeping forces, that have been condemned by Hezbollah and by Israel's allies.</p>

<p>Israel disputed the UN account and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called for the peacekeepers to withdraw, saying they were providing "human shields" for Hezbollah during an upsurge in hostilities.</p>

<p>Hezbollah denies it uses the proximity of peacekeepers for protection.</p>

<p>The Middle East, meanwhile, remains on high alert for Israel to retaliate against Iran for an October 1 barrage of long-range missiles launched in response to Israel's assaults on Lebanon.</p>

<p>The Pentagon said on Sunday it would send US troops to Israel along with an advanced US anti-missile system, as Israel weighs its expected retaliation against Iran.</p>

<p>The Israeli military took foreign journalists into southern Lebanon on Sunday and showed them a Hezbollah tunnel shaft that was less than 200 metres away (650 feet) from a UNIFIL position, as well as weapon stashes that the troops found.</p>

<p>Brigadier General Yiftach Norkin said the tunnels were built a few years ago.</p>

<p>"We are actually standing in a military base of Hezbollah very close to the UN," Norkin said, pointing to the shaft's trap door in an area covered by undergrowth and overlooked by a UN observation post.</p>

<p>Since announcing its ground operation near the border, the Israeli military says that it has destroyed dozens of Hezbollah tunnel shafts, rocket launchers and command posts.</p>

<p>"We found several days ago a huge quantity of weapons originally coming from Iran and Russia. Brand new," said Colonel Olivier Rafowicz. "They were prepared for attacking us and (launching) a large invasion into the north of Israel," Rafowicz said, showing the journalists crates of weapons.</p>

<p>Reuters could not immediately verify these claims.</p>

<p><strong>EXTENSIVE TUNNEL NETWORK</strong></p>

<p>Hezbollah possesses an extensive tunnel network in southern Lebanon, both the group and Israel say. Israel estimates they extend for hundreds of kilometres. A Hezbollah field commander told Reuters last week that the tunnels "are the foundation of the battle." Hezbollah has not immediately commented.</p>

<p>UNIFIL has said previous Israeli attacks on a watchtower, cameras, communications equipment and lighting had limited its monitoring abilities. UN sources say they fear any violations of international law in the conflict will be impossible to monitor.</p>

<p>The European Union's member states have taken too long to condemn Israel's attacks on UNIFIL soldiers in Lebanon, the European Union's foreign policy chief Josep Borrell said on Monday, describing the attacks as "completely unacceptable".</p>

<p>EU countries, led by Italy, France and Spain, have thousands of troops in the 10,000-strong peacekeeping mission in southern Lebanon, which has said it has repeatedly come under attack from Israeli forces in recent days</p>

<p>On Monday, Spanish Prime Minister Pedro Sanchez urged European Union members to respond to a request by Madrid and Ireland to suspend the bloc's free trade agreement with Israel over its attacks in Lebanon and Gaza.</p>

<p>The conflict between Israel and Hezbollah resumed a year ago when the operator group began firing rockets at Israeli positions in support of Hamas at the start of the Gaza war and has sharply escalated in recent weeks.</p>

<p>Israel says its operations in Lebanon are aimed at securing the return of tens of thousands of its residents displaced from their homes in northern Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/71d78qio_israel-strike-lebanon_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A view shows a damaged site in the aftermath of an Israeli strike in southern Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-headless-bodies-found-on-road-in-mexico-remains-discovered-in-plastic-bags-6787834]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Headless Bodies Found In Mexico, Remains Discovered In Plastic Bags]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-headless-bodies-found-on-road-in-mexico-remains-discovered-in-plastic-bags-6787834]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:48:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["A report was received indicating that, on the asphalt strip of the road (...) there were several bags that looked like human silhouettes," the state prosecutor's office said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The decapitated bodies of five men were discovered on a road in central Mexico, in a region controlled by the powerful Jalisco New Generation Cartel. Police were alerted to the scene near the town of Ojuelos, in Jalisco state, on Sunday morning, after drivers reported seeing plastic bags containing human remains, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c148yy7yxyno" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>BBC </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"A report was received indicating that, on the asphalt strip of the road (...) there were several bags that looked like human silhouettes," the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://fiscalia.jalisco.gob.mx/comunicacion-social/boletines-de-prensa/boletin-2542-20241013" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em>state prosecutor's office</em></a> said.&nbsp;Officials said forensic teams are working to identify the victims.</p>

<p>The gruesome nature of the murders and the public disposal of the bodies strongly suggest cartel involvement.&nbsp;National Guard troops also arrived at the scene, where they found the remains wrapped in black plastic bags, according to a statement from the Jalisco state prosecutor's office.</p>

<p>The victims' ages have not yet been determined, and an investigation is underway, the statement added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In Jalisco, official statistics show that 1,415 people were murdered between January and September this year.</p>

<p>More than 30,000 people are killed annually in Mexico, which has one of the highest murder rates in the world.</p>

<p>Last week, the mayor of a Mexican city plagued by drug violence was assassinated just days after taking office.</p>

<p>Alejandro Arcos was murdered in Chilpancingo, a city of about 280,000 people in the southwestern state of Guerrero.</p>

<p>President Claudia Sheinbaum, who took office last week, has ruled out a return to the previous administration's war on drugs.</p>

<p>She stated that her security strategy would focus on gathering intelligence on cartels and addressing the root causes of violence- a policy known as "hugs not bullets," introduced by her predecessor Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador.</p>

<p>However, the opposition is pushing for a tougher stance against the cartels.</p>

<p>Since the government began deploying the Mexican military against the drug cartels in 2006, hundreds of thousands of people have been killed, and tens of thousands more have gone missing.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/g8c1smno_mexico-police-_625x300_01_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The victims' ages have not yet been determined]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-halts-indirect-us-talks-amid-middle-east-crisis-cites-regional-instability-6787799]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["No Ground" For Indirect Talks With US, Says Iran Amid West Asia Tensions]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-halts-indirect-us-talks-amid-middle-east-crisis-cites-regional-instability-6787799]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:41:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran said Monday it currently sees "no grounds" for its indirect talks with the United States via intermediary Oman, citing the crisis in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran said Monday it currently sees "no grounds" for its indirect talks with the United States via intermediary Oman, citing the crisis in the Middle East.</p>

<p>Iran said in June that it had held indirect talks with the United States via Oman, despite having no diplomatic relations with its foe.</p>

<p>"Currently we don't see any ground for these talks, until we can get past the current crisis," Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araghchi told reporters in Oman's capital Muscat.</p>

<p>The process, he said, had been halted "due to the specific conditions of the region".</p>

<p>Iran fired 200 missiles at Israel on October 1 in what it said was retaliation for the killing of Tehran-aligned operator leaders in the region and a general in Iran's Revolutionary Guards.</p>

<p>Israel has vowed to respond.</p>

<p>The Gulf sultanate of Oman has long mediated between Iran and the United States, which cut ties after the 1979 Islamic revolution.</p>

<p>The United States is Israel's close ally and top provider of military assistance, while Iran backs the Palestinian operator group Hamas and Lebanese Hezbollah which are fighting Israel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-10/a1r42eko_iran-us-flags_625x300_16_October_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Iran said in June that it had held indirect talks with the United States via Oman. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-pics-chinas-new-base-near-pangong-lake-unlike-any-other-site-6787676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Satellite Pics: China's New Base Near Pangong Lake "Unlike Any Other Site"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/satellite-pics-chinas-new-base-near-pangong-lake-unlike-any-other-site-6787676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:28:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Senior Indian military sources who have analysed satellite imagery of a new Chinese base on the North bank of the Pangong Lake say that the site ''is unlike any other site'' that lies on the Chinese side of the Line of Actual control.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Senior Indian military sources who have analysed satellite imagery of a new Chinese base on the North bank of the Pangong Lake say that the site ''is unlike any other site'' that lies on the Chinese side of the Line of Actual control.</p>

<p>The site in question, images of which have been published in this report, lies 36 kilometres East of the LAC on territory China holds. It is approximately 15 km East of a new bridge that China has constructed across the high-altitude Pangong Lake in Ladakh and marks Beijing's latest effort at stepping up pressure in areas near the Line of Actual Control which were previously unoccupied. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Military sources say the site, which features upwards of 70 permanent structures, ''has been dispersed over a wide area. &nbsp;This has been done to reduce the potential impact of missile attacks.'' The site appears to have two primary functions - to accommodate soldiers and porters who are involved in China's construction activity in the area. &nbsp;And to store logistics for potential transfer to locations along the LAC with India. &nbsp;''Each structure can accommodate 6-8 soldiers or up to 10 tonnes of logistics,'' say military experts. This can include ammunition, including artillery shells. &nbsp;</p>

<p>''A major development initiative appears to be underway at this village, evidenced by the heavy machinery, including cranes, and substantial supply depots,'' says the geospatial imagery expert Damien Symon. ''The settlement is witnessing the development of multiple double-storey buildings alongside village administrative offices and emerging town centres. Electrification efforts are progressing as power lines are drawn from the southern highway. Furthermore, to secure the water supply, a potential pumping station is being constructed to the north, drawing fresh water from an adjacent riverbed. Thanks to these preparations, the village, once established, is likely to be well-shielded from the area's extreme and unforgiving climate.''</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="In April 2022, the site was clear. However, the construction started in March, 2024." id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jcuppj5g_pangong-lake-maxar_625x300_14_October_24.jpg" title="In April 2022, the site was clear. However, the construction started in March, 2024." /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">In April 2022, the site was clear. However, the construction started in March 2024.</p>
</div>

<p>Lt. General DS Hooda (retired), the former Northern Army Commander who speared India's surgical strikes on Pakistani territory, says the site under construction has dual uses. ''It enables China to say that they are only improving facilities for the civilian population, but this is clearly dual-use infrastructure that would be utilised by the military in a conflict.''&nbsp;</p>

<p>&nbsp;The construction of this site also changes facts on the ground. &nbsp;''Article VII of the 2005 agreement between India and China on the political parameters and guiding principles for the settlement of the boundary question states that 'in reaching a boundary settlement, the two sides shall safeguard due interests of the settled population in border areas.' &nbsp;However, by creating these villages in areas claimed by India, where there was no settled population, China is attempting to strengthen its claims and weaken our bargaining position,'' says Lt. General Hooda. ''This is a long game.''</p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/heavy-military-fortifications-near-chinas-now-complete-pangong-lake-bridge-6226235">An NDTV report published</a> in July showed Chinese vehicles crossing its Pangong Lake bridge, 15 km from the new site.</p>

<p>The report also identified fortified sites to the North of the bridge, including a likely air defence site which could house a surface-to-air missile battery. This site would likely protect this new Chinese base from aerial attacks.</p>

<p>"The issue of concern is the size and scale of construction and infrastructure so close to the LAC in conjunction with the bridge across Pangong Tso which connects the North and South banks," says Lt. General Satish Dua (retired), a former Chief of the Integrated Defence Staff. "The bridge allows lateral switching of forces and this dual-use village could be used as a logistic hub. We will have to keep a close watch over their activities in the region, which should give us an advance warning of any malafide activities."</p>

<p>Damien Symon, perhaps the closest international observer of fresh developments along the India-China frontier says that construction activity at the new site appears to replicate similar activity in Chinese-held areas on the South bank of the Pangong Lake. "Similar construction activity has recently also been noted near Spanggur Lake's eastern region where another sizeable settlement is under construction approximately 18 kilometres from Rezang La, where Indian forces outmanoeuvred the Chinese during the 2020 border standoff."</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/5kih6mcg_pangong-lake-maxar_625x300_14_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs, which was forwarded these images by NDTV last week, has chosen not to respond specifically to the new Chinese construction activity. However, India has dramatically ramped up infrastructure development along the China frontier. This includes the construction of roads, tunnels, and other military facilities to ensure that Indian forces are well-prepared and can swiftly respond to any challenges posed by Chinese actions along the LAC.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India's Vibrant Villages programme, for which Rs 4,800 crore has been allocated from 2022-'23 to 2025-'26, is aimed at the comprehensive development of villages along the Northern border. The project, which promotes infrastructure development, livelihood opportunities and cultural and heritage promotion targets 2,967 villages in total. The project has a broader strategic goal of maintaining an Indian presence along the border which is seen as a deterrent against territorial encroachments.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/bh1amp9g_pangong-lake-maxar_625x300_14_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The construction of this site also changes facts on the ground.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-drone-attack-in-israel-injures-60-kills-4-soldiers-6787593]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[People Near Israeli Army Base Shaken By Hezbollah Drone Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hezbollah-drone-attack-in-israel-injures-60-kills-4-soldiers-6787593]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:14:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[People living near an Israeli army base hit by a Hezbollah drone strike described a loud explosion then multiple ambulances arriving, as fresh rocket fire and air raid sirens sent them rushing to shelters on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People living near an Israeli army base hit by a Hezbollah drone strike described a loud explosion then multiple ambulances arriving, as fresh rocket fire and air raid sirens sent them rushing to shelters on Monday.</p>

<p>Four soldiers were killed Sunday night by a Hezbollah drone at the base in the Binyamina area -- the deadliest strike on Israeli soil since the war between Israel and the Lebanese armed group intensified last month.</p>

<p>Emergency services that helped transport the wounded to hospital said more than 60 were injured.</p>

<p>"Last night was crazy," Yousef, the manager of a local restaurant in the village of Kfar Kara, told AFP, declining to give his full name for safety reasons. "There was a huge boom and then suddenly ambulances started driving past, first one, then two, then three and more and more.</p>

<p>"There were so many police cars and paramedics," he added.</p>

<p>Yousef said that at first he thought the explosion was related to organised crime, which is high in some Israeli Arab villages. But he soon realised that the boom was from the nearby army base, which sits less than a kilometre (mile) away from his restaurant.</p>

<p>"We've been open here for two years and didn't realise that we were next to such an important base," Yousef told AFP. "How did Hezbollah know it was here?"</p>

<p>"Now they know where that base is, what if next time they fire and are slightly off target?"</p>

<p>The village sits along one of the main thoroughfares to the base and other witnesses described seeing ambulances and private cars whisking away dozens of injured soldiers Sunday night.</p>

<p>According to residents interviewed by AFP, there were no sirens or advanced warning of an incoming drone.</p>

<p>On Kibbutz Regavim, a few kilometres from the base, residents said they did not hear the explosion but recognised that it was nearby from television images.</p>

<p>"The kibbutz's security team was immediately alerted," Eyal Nabet, a resident of the kibbutz, told AFP.</p>

<p>"Sadly, afterwards, we heard the ambulances and helicopters heading to and from the base."</p>

<p>Nabet said the residents of the kibbutz were shaken but bomb shelters had been renovated recently and new concrete structures added in locations, giving people "the feeling they are secure and someone is watching out for us".</p>

<p>The Israeli military has pledged a full investigation into the incident.</p>

<p>"This was a difficult event with painful results. We must investigate it, study the details, and implement lessons in a swift and professional manner," said Defence Minister Yoav Gallant during a visit to the base that was targeted.</p>

<p>"We are concentrating significant efforts in developing solutions to address the threat of UAV attacks."</p>

<p>Following the strike, Hezbollah threatened to continue targeting Israel with more attacks if its offensive in Lebanon is not stopped.</p>

<p>The Iran-backed group "promises the enemy that what it witnessed today (Sunday) in southern Haifa is nothing compared to what awaits it if it decides to continue its aggression against our noble and dear people," it said in a statement after the attack on the base.</p>

<p>Hezbollah has been regularly firing rockets, drones and missiles into Israel for more than a year in support of Hamas militants in Gaza. But the salvos have begun to reach further into Israel since September 23, when the Israel-Hezbollah war escalated.</p>

<p>Israel's sophisticated air defences, however, have intercepted most of the projectiles, with few casualties caused by the barrages or the subsequent falling debris.</p>

<p>But for those on the ground near the Binyamina base in north Israel, a feeling of helplessness is palpable.</p>

<p>"What can we do?" asked a proprietor of a kiosk at the entrance to the village of Kfar Kara, who did not provide her name for security reasons.</p>

<p>"We are afraid but there is nothing we can do about it."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/t0r39do4_israel-hezbollah-war_625x300_28_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Israeli military has pledged a full investigation into the incident. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-summons-canada-envoy-as-diplomatic-row-escalates-massively-6787530]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Summons Canada Envoy In Massive Escalation Of Diplomatic Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/india-summons-canada-envoy-as-diplomatic-row-escalates-massively-6787530]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:09:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has summoned Canada's charge d' affairs in New Delhi after the diplomatic relations between the two countries witnessed a new low today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has summoned Canada's charge d' affairs in New Delhi after the diplomatic relations between the two countries witnessed a new low today. Foreign Ministry's summons to&nbsp;Stewart Wheeler followed the government's criticism of Canada for investigating the Indian ambassador and other diplomats as "persons of interest" over the killing of Khalistani terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar.</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said India received a "diplomatic communication from Canada yesterday suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other diplomats are 'persons of interest' in a matter related to an investigation in that country".</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660">government called the allegations "preposterous"</a> and a "strategy of smearing India for political gains".</p>

<p>&nbsp;"The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Trudeau Government that is centred around vote bank politics," the government said in a sharp rebuttal.</p>

<p>"India now reserves the right to take further steps in response to these latest efforts of the Canadian Government to concoct allegations against Indian diplomats," the foreign ministry added.</p>

<p>The 2023 murder of Nijjar crashed diplomatic ties between New Delhi and Ottawa after Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said there were "credible allegations" linking Indian intelligence to the crime. India, which had designated Nijjar as a terrorist in 2020, dismissed the charges as "absurd".</p>

<p>Canada has now reportedly named the Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma as a 'person of interest' in its investigation. India accused Canada of maligning its officials without evidence and using "preposterous" claims to justify its failure to curb Khalistani extremism on its soil.</p>

<p>"High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma is India's senior-most serving diplomat with a distinguished career spanning 36 years. He has been an Ambassador in Japan and Sudan, while also serving in Italy, Turkiye, Vietnam and China. The aspersions cast on him by the Government of Canada are ludicrous and deserve to be treated with contempt," the foreign ministry said.</p>

<p>It said Canadian Prime Minister Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence. In 2018, his visit to India, "which was aimed at currying favour with a vote bank, rebounded to his discomfort".</p>

<p>"His Cabinet has included individuals who have openly associated with an extremist and separatist agenda regarding India," the ministry said.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi recently met Justin Trudeau on the sidelines of the ASEAN Summit in Laos, almost a year after his Canadian counterpart accused India of involvement in the death of a Khalistani terrorist.</p>

<p>Even as sources in New Delhi said there was no substantive discussion between the two leaders, Trudeau termed the meeting a "brief exchange".</p>

<p>"I won't go into details about what we talked about but what I've said many times is that the safety of Canadians and upholding the rule of law is one of the fundamental responsibilities of any Canadian government and that's what I'll stay focused on," Trudeau told a press conference at Vientiane.</p>

<p>Canada is home to around 7,70,000 Sikhs, who make up about two percent of the country's population.</p>

<p>India has been maintaining that the main issue between the two countries is that of Canada giving space to pro-Khalistan elements operating from Canadian soil with impunity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j6npjp8g_mea-_625x300_14_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 2023 murder of Nijjar crashed diplomatic ties between New Delhi and Ottawa. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-vows-to-rip-red-tape-as-he-urges-foreign-investors-to-back-uk-6787288]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Keir Starmer Vows To Cut Red Tape, Urges Foreign Investors To 'Back' UK]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keir-starmer-vows-to-rip-red-tape-as-he-urges-foreign-investors-to-back-uk-6787288]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:39:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Keir Starmer - treading a tricky path to be both pro-business and also pro-worker, with a series of new workplace safeguards for employees -- has placed great importance on the International Investment Summit in London.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer on Monday told global business leaders it was "time to back Britain", as he hosted a major summit aimed at securing much-needed funds to fuel economic growth after post-Brexit chaos.</p>

<p>Starmer told captains of industry that his recently elected Labour government would "rip out the bureaucracy that blocks investment" and pledged to slash red tape.</p>

<p>The premier - treading a tricky path to be both pro-business and also pro-worker, with a series of new workplace safeguards for employees -- has placed great importance on the International Investment Summit in London.</p>

<p>He is hoping that the announcement of billions of pounds (dollars) of foreign investment in UK projects will overshadow its chaotic build-up.</p>

<p>Starmer won a thumping majority in July's election but has seen his government's popularity plummet following a series of missteps, with a recent YouGov poll showing only 18 per cent of the public approved of its performance.</p>

<p>The prime minister said his focus is "not the days or hours of the news grid" but on the "golden opportunity" that his electoral mandate presents for delivering his central mission of growing the UK economy.</p>

<p>"Private sector investment is the way we rebuild our country and pay our way in the world. Make no mistake, this is a great moment to back Britain," Starmer said.</p>

<p>He promised that where regulation is currently "stopping us building the homes, the data centres, warehouses, grid connectors, roads, train lines, you name it, then mark my words -- we will get rid of it".</p>

<p>"We will rip out the bureaucracy that blocks investment," he added, promising that his administration "will make sure that every regulator in this country" takes growth "as seriously as this room does".</p>

<p>Starmer said he was "determined to repair Britain's brand as an open, outward-looking, confident trading nation".</p>

<p>Ministers are set to announce billions worth of major investment deals in AI, life sciences and infrastructure, having already unveiled £24 billion pounds ($31.4 billion) in green energy projects, including £12 billion by Spanish giant Iberdrola and £8.0 billion by Danish firm Orsted.</p>

<p><strong>- P&amp;O row -</strong></p>

<p>The build-up to the summit was dominated by criticism over its organisation, a failure to attract top names and a row involving shipping company P&amp;O's Dubai owners DP World that put a £1 billion investment project in jeopardy.</p>

<p>Sultan Ahmed bin Sulayem, the chairman DP World, threatened not to attend the summit after transport minister Louise Haigh and Deputy Prime Minister Angela Rayner called P&amp;O's employment practices "unscrupulous" and "exploitative".</p>

<p>Last-ditch talks with the UK government ensued and DP World revealed that the P&amp;O investment to expand a London container port would go ahead.</p>

<p>While around 200 private sector executives were expected to attend, many multinational bosses and tech titans decided to give it a miss.</p>

<p>Even the opportunity to meet Britain's head of state King Charles III at the closing reception on Monday evening failed to entice them.</p>

<p>The Financial Times partly attributed the summit's poor turnout to concerns over its "quality and organisation".</p>

<p>Five days before the event, the start time and venue had still not been confirmed.</p>

<p>Two foreign companies seeking urgent information were reportedly astonished to receive an "out-of-office" message from the organisers, the business daily said.</p>

<p>Then the highly secret guest list was revealed by mistake, when the organisers sent an email to all confirmed participants without hiding their addresses.</p>

<p>The timing of the summit -- two days after Labour clocked its 100th day in office -- has also caused unease.</p>

<p>In two weeks' time finance minister Rachel Reeves delivers Labour's first budget, when businesses are steeling themselves for a possible rise in capital gains tax.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/r20darb8_keir-starmer_625x300_25_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Keir Starmer won a thumping majority in July's election.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-drones-swarmed-a-us-military-base-for-17-days-pentagon-was-not-able-to-stop-them-report-6787287]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Drones Flew Over US Military Base For 17 Days, Puzzling Pentagon]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/mysterious-drones-swarmed-a-us-military-base-for-17-days-pentagon-was-not-able-to-stop-them-report-6787287]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:38:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The drone sightings continued for 17 days, raising suspicions that they might be the work of Russian or Chinese agents seeking to spy on American military assets.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mysterious drones have been surveilling some of America's most sensitive military sites, and the Pentagon is struggling to respond, according to a report by the<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/drones-military-pentagon-defense-331871f4" rel="nofollow, noindex"><em> Wall Street Journal</em></a>. The report states that these drones have been observed flying over military bases in Virginia and Nevada over the past year, including the secret base of the Navy's elite SEAL Team Six and Naval Station Norfolk, the world's largest naval port.</p>

<p>Federal laws currently prevent the military from shooting down these drones due to the risk they could pose to troops and civilians. The Wall Street Journal also reported that high-level White House meetings ruled out jamming the drones' signals, citing concerns that it might interfere with 911 systems, WiFi networks, and commercial airlines.</p>

<p>Former U.S. Air Force Gen. Mark Kelly revealed to the Wall Street Journal that he first learned about the drone sightings in December 2023, when officials at Langley Air Force Base in Virginia reported seeing dozens of drones flying over the base at night. Langley is home to the F-22 Raptor, one of America's most advanced stealth fighter jets.</p>

<p>The drone sightings continued for 17 days, raising suspicions that they might be the work of Russian or Chinese agents seeking to spy on American military assets. However, since the drones did not pose an immediate threat, military law prohibited any action to shoot them down.</p>

<p>The option of directed jamming attacks was also deemed too risky, as it could disrupt commercial air traffic, especially during the peak of the holiday travel season, according to an FAA official. Analog methods proved ineffective as local police assisting in the investigation lost sight of the drones during nighttime pursuits, the Wall Street Journal reported.</p>

<p>The sightings ended on December 23, with authorities still unsure of the drones' origin or who was controlling them. The complexity and coordination of the operation led officials to dismiss the idea that amateur drone pilots were responsible.</p>

<p>A significant clue emerged in January when a Chinese student named Fengyun Shi, studying at the University of Minnesota, was caught flying a drone near Langley Air Force Base. Shi's drone got stuck in a tree, which he abandoned before flying to California. The drone was later retrieved by the FBI, who discovered it had taken photos of Navy ships docked at the base.</p>

<p>Shi was arrested as he prepared to board a one-way flight to China and was charged with unlawfully taking photographs of classified naval installations, marking the first such case involving a drone. Magistrate Judge Lawrence Leonard rejected Shi's claim that he was merely a student flying a drone for fun, and Shi pleaded guilty to espionage charges on October 2.</p>

<p>Despite these incidents, U.S. officials have confirmed that similar drone swarms have recently been observed near Edwards Air Force Base in Nevada. The Defense Department has not yet publicly identified the source behind these surveillance drones.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-02/b5lt4tn4_pentagon_625x300_03_February_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[High-level White House meetings ruled out jamming the drones' signals]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-will-have-to-chart-its-own-path-in-middle-east-6787033]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: India Will Have To Chart Its Own Delicate Path As Middle East Explodes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-will-have-to-chart-its-own-path-in-middle-east-6787033]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:08:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As India continues to expand and enhance its labour-trade-energy engagement with West Asia, it'll have to be careful on the diplomatic front.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/alm3ih48_middle-east_625x300_14_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Does the highly volatile situation in West Asia put a premium on multipolarity? This question needs to be addressed beyond the foreign policy of America. For John Mearsheimer, a leading political scientist, the battle between Democrats and the Republicans is akin to a choice between “Tweedledum and Tweedledee”. It is the deep state that operates the American foreign policy, with the primary intent of maximising power and being a global hegemon. It is what has been articulated by Samuel Huntington in his Clash of Civilizations, where he warned that the inability of the West to adapt to the increasing power and influence of other civilisations will bring about the decline of its own power and influence, and will be the greatest threat to world peace.</p>

<p>The global order had largely been unipolar since the Cold War, until Russia put its foot down in Damascus during the Syrian Civil War following the Arab Spring. Since then, this world order has been constantly challenged. With the rise of the Global South, today's world order has upended the hegemonic power structure and is ostensibly shuffling towards multipolarity. The Tehran-Beijing-Moscow Axis poses a formidable challenge to American global ambitions.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India and China have emerged as the two key contenders for leadership in the Global South. However, the nature of their approach varies significantly. While China presents a direct conflict to the Global North, India has a more accommodating approach.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As understood by analysts, these gradual yet changing realities are also visible in the American deep state. As the Balance of Power theory suggests, Washington has chosen to bank behind and strengthen New Delhi's position. The renewed excitement for the Quad and I2U2 groupings and its further extension into the building of the India-Middle East-Europe Economic Corridor (IMEC) are examples. However, herein lies the key challenge to the Indian foreign policy, which has to juggle its various priorities—in the Global South, in managing its regional geopolitical compulsions, and in its strategic partnership with prominent members of the Global North.</p>

<h2><strong>Peace Was Not To Be</strong></h2>

<p>The churn in the politics of West Asia predates the ongoing war. Since the Arab Spring, when the United States decided to withdraw and pivot towards East Asia, the regional regimes gradually abandoned their ‘clienthood' to explore other options. Over the years, the region had started seeing some semblance of settlement with Syria back in the Arab League, a peace process initiated between Damascus and Ankara, and the Abraham Accords formally facilitating the normalisation of ties with Israel. If not for a Chinese-brokered deal between Riyadh and Tehran, the final closing picture could have been a handshake between Crown Prince Mohammad bin Salman and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu with an American President in the centre.&nbsp;</p>

<p>However, Hamas's October 7 attack upset all this. Washington, which had seen its share of misadventures in Ukraine, has also been pulled back into the turmoil in West Asia.<br />
Further, Israel's disregard for the rules of war and the observation of the International Court of Justice (ICJ) and United Nations (UN) Resolutions has forced even Riyadh to publicly denounce Tel Aviv and pause any talks for normalisation until the establishment of a Palestinian State.</p>

<h2><strong>India Will Have To Chart Its Own Path</strong></h2>

<p>As India continues to expand and enhance its labour-trade-energy engagement with West Asia, it'll have to be careful on the diplomatic front. Considering its geo-strategic importance, it needs to recalibrate its position in Iran and be cautious about its relations with the United States in the region. Iran's October 1 attack on Israel and an imminent response from the latter has opened a pandora's box. A possible escalation will profoundly alter the balance of power in the region and threaten India's strategic interests.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Further, the Central Investigation Agency's (CIA) alleged involvement in India's friendly neighbour, Bangladesh, its secondary sanctions on Indian entities for doing business with Russia, and Republican candidate Donald Trump's recent remarks on India's import policy are only the latest examples of the intricate nature of American foreign policy. Therefore, non-alignment will continue to be a key component of India's foreign policy, even if just as pragmatic strategic autonomy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Also, India's world image is crucial for its leadership ambitions in the Global South. Though India supports the two-state solution in the Israel-Palestine conflict, her decision to abstain from the United Nations General Assembly Resolution asking Israel to withdraw from Palestinian territories may impact its position.</p>

<p>Regarding competition with China, the popular discourse is largely misplaced. India is not in a state of competition with China in Middle East, primarily because their interest varies in the region. India, unlike China, is not looking to be the United States' power alternative. To argue that the IMEC will challenge the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) is also inaccurate and unfounded.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In brief, foreign policy is not a zero-sum game. Beyond America and China, New Delhi has its own case in the Middle East and the Global South.</p>

<p><em>[Mohammad Gulrez, former VC and PVC of Aligarh Muslim University (AMU), is a Professor of Political Science at the Dept. of West Asian &amp; North African Studies, AMU]</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/828fn9jo_middle-east_625x300_14_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-and-james-robinson-win-2024-nobel-prize-in-economics-for-work-on-wealth-inequality-6786725]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trio Wins 2024 Nobel Prize In Economics For Work On Wealth Inequality]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-and-james-robinson-win-2024-nobel-prize-in-economics-for-work-on-wealth-inequality-6786725]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 16:33:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Nobel Prize in Economics was awarded on Monday to Turkish-American Daron Acemoglu and British-Americans Simon Johnson and James Robinson for research into wealth inequality between nations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Nobel Prize in Economics was awarded on Monday to Turkish-American Daron Acemoglu and British-Americans Simon Johnson and James Robinson for research into wealth inequality between nations.</p>

<p>By examining the various political and economic systems introduced by European colonisers, the three have been able to demonstrate a relationship between institutions and prosperity, the jury said.</p>

<p>"Reducing the vast differences in income between countries is one of our time's greatest challenges," Jakob Svensson, chair of the Committee for the Prize in Economic Sciences, said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The laureates have demonstrated the importance of societal institutions for achieving this," Svensson added.</p>

<p>Acemoglu, 57, is a professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), as is Johnson, 61.</p>

<p>Robinson, 64, is a professor at the University of Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The jury highlighted the laureates' work illuminating how societal institutions play a role in explaining why some countries prosper, while others do not.</p>

<p>"I am delighted. It's just a real shock and amazing news," Acemoglu told reporters via telephone as the award was announced in Stockholm.</p>

<p>The Economics prize is the only Nobel not among the original five created in the will of Swedish scientist Alfred Nobel, who died in 1896.</p>

<p>It was instead created through a donation from the Swedish central bank in 1968, leading detractors to dub it "a false Nobel".</p>

<p>However, like for the other Nobel science prizes, the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences decides the winner and follows the same selection process.</p>

<p>The Economics Prize wraps up this year's Nobel season, which honoured achievements in artificial intelligence for the physics and chemistry prizes, while the Peace Prize went to Japanese group Nihon Hidankyo, committed to fighting nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>South Korea's Han Kan won the literature prize -- the only woman laureate so far this year -- while the medicine prize lauded discoveries in understanding gene regulation.</p>

<p>The Nobel Prizes consist of a diploma, a gold medal and a one-million-dollar sum.&nbsp;</p>

<p>They will be presented at ceremonies in Stockholm and Oslo on December 10, the anniversary of the 1896 death of scientist and prize creator Alfred Nobel.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b93ffs7g_2024-economics-nobel-prize_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Economics prize is the only Nobel not among the original five created in the will of Alfred Nobel.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-economics-goes-to-daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-james-robinson-6786223]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Economists Get Nobel Prize For Study On Institutions And Prosperity]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nobel-prize-in-economics-goes-to-daron-acemoglu-simon-johnson-james-robinson-6786223]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 15:23:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson and James Robinson won the 2024 Nobel economics prize "for studies of how institutions are formed and affect prosperity", the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br />
US-based academics Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson and James Robinson won the 2024 Nobel economics prize "for studies of how institutions are formed and affect prosperity", the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences said on Monday.<br />
The prestigious award, formally known as the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel, is the final prize to be given out this year and is worth 11 million Swedish crowns ($1.1 million).</p>

<p>"Reducing the vast differences in income between countries is one of our time's greatest challenges. The laureates have demonstrated the importance of societal institutions for achieving this," said Jakob Svensson, Chair of the Committee for the Prize in Economic Sciences.</p>

<p>"Societies with a poor rule of law and institutions that exploit the population do not generate growth or change for the better," the award organisers added on their website.</p>

<p>Daron Acemoglu and Simon Johnson work at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, while James Robinson is at the University of Chicago.</p>

<p>Acemoglu and Johnson recently collaborated on a book surveying technology through the ages which demonstrated how some technological advances were better at creating jobs and spreading wealth than others.</p>

<p>The economics award is not one of the original prizes for science, literature and peace created in the will of dynamite inventor and businessman Alfred Nobel and first awarded in 1901, but a later addition established and funded by Sweden's central bank in 1968.</p>

<p>Past winners include a host of influential thinkers such as Milton Friedman, John Nash - played by actor Russell Crowe in the 2001 film "A Beautiful Mind" - and, more recently, former U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Ben Bernanke.</p>

<p>Last year, Harvard economic historian Claudia Goldin won the prize for her work highlighting the causes of wage and labour market inequality between men and women.</p>

<p>The economics prize has been dominated by US academics since its inception, while U.S.-based researchers also tend to account for a large portion of winners in the scientific fields for which 2024 laureates were announced last week.</p>

<p>That crop of prizes began with US scientists Victor Ambros and Gary Ruvkun winning the prize for medicine on Monday and concluded with Japan's Nihon Hidankyo, an organisation of survivors from Hiroshima and Nagasaki who campaigned for the abolition of nuclear weapons landing the award for peace on Friday.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/35q9f3_the-nobel-prize-in-economics-2024_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nobel Economics Goes To Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson, James Robinson.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-adds-first-mpox-vaccine-to-its-list-expected-to-speed-up-distribution-6786012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[WHO Adds First Mpox Vaccine To Its List, Expected To Speed Up Distribution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-adds-first-mpox-vaccine-to-its-list-expected-to-speed-up-distribution-6786012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:55:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The WHO said Friday it had for the first time prequalified a mpox vaccine -- a move expected to speed up access to the jabs to fight an epidemic raging in Africa.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The WHO said Friday it had for the first time prequalified a mpox vaccine -- a move expected to speed up access to the jabs to fight an epidemic raging in Africa.</p>

<p>The announcement came on the heels of the arrival of the first MVA-BN vaccines to the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), the epicentre of the epidemic.</p>

<p>"This first prequalification of a vaccine against mpox is an important step in our fight against the disease, both in the context of the current outbreaks in Africa and in future," WHO chief Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said in a statement.</p>

<p>"We now need urgent scale up in procurement, donations and rollout to ensure equitable access to vaccines where they are needed most... to prevent infections, stop transmission and save lives."</p>

<p>WHO's prequalification listing is used to evaluate the quality, safety and efficacy of medical products like vaccines, paving the way for the United Nations and other international agencies to procure them.</p>

<p>The list is also used by lower-income countries without the means to carry out their evaluations to fast-track procurement approvals.</p>

<p>"The WHO prequalification of the MVA-BN vaccine will help accelerate ongoing procurement of the mpox vaccines by governments and international agencies... on the frontlines of the ongoing emergency in Africa and beyond," said Yukiko Nakatani, WHO's assistant chief in charge of access to medicines and health products.</p>

<p>Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is caused by a virus transmitted to humans by infected animals but can also be passed from human to human through close physical contact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>It causes fever, muscular aches and large boil-like skin lesions, and can in some cases be deadly.</p>

<p>The WHO declared an international emergency over <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-approves-first-diagnostic-test-for-mpox-amid-rising-outbreaks-in-africa-6713877">mpox</a> last month, concerned by the surge in cases of the new Clade 1b strain in the DRC that spread to nearby countries.</p>

<p>DRC has recorded nearly 22,000 cases and 716 deaths linked to the virus since January.</p>

<p>So far, some 200,000 vaccine doses have been delivered to the DRC by the European Union, along with about 50,000 from the United States.</p>

<h3><strong>Safe and effective&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>WHO said it had based its prequalification assessment on information submitted by the manufacturer of the MVA-BN vaccine, Bavarian Nordic A/S, and a review by the European Medicines Agency.</p>

<p>"Good safety profile and vaccine performance has been consistently demonstrated in clinical studies, as well as in real-world use," it said.</p>

<p>According to the prequalification, the vaccine can be administered to people over the age of 18 as a two-dose injection given four weeks apart.</p>

<p>With a majority of mpox cases and deaths in the DRC in children, WHO stressed that the vaccine could be used "off-label" in infants, children and adolescents, as well as in pregnant and immunocompromised people.</p>

<p>"This means vaccine use is recommended in outbreak settings where the benefits of vaccination outweigh the potential risks," WHO said.</p>

<p>The agency also recommends single-dose use in outbreak settings where the supply of the vaccine is constrained, although it stressed that more data was needed on vaccine safety and effectiveness in such circumstances.</p>

<p>The currently available data, it said, shows that a single dose of the MVA-BN vaccine given before exposure has an estimated 76 per cent effectiveness in protecting against mpox, while two doses are estimated to be 82 per cent effective. &nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1n5d9p5_mpox-reuters_625x300_24_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO recommends single-dose use of the vaccine in outbreak settings where the supply. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Trudeau Government's Political Agenda": India's Full Statement On Canada]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:22:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has strongly rejected Canada's allegations linking top Indian diplomats to an investigation in their country, calling it a "political agenda of the Trudeau government".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has strongly <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660">rejected Canada's allegations</a> linking top Indian diplomats to an investigation in their country, calling it a "political agenda of the Trudeau government". India-Canada ties have been strained since Prime Minister Justin Trudeau claimed last year that "Indian agents" were involved in terrorist Hardeep Singh Nijjar's killing. India has rejected the claim multiple times in the past. In a statement today, the central government said Canada has not shared a "shred of evidence" with India and that the charges were centered around the Trudeau government's "vote bank politics".</p>

<p><strong>Read the full statement here:</strong></p>

<p>"India's response to diplomatic communication from Canada</p>

<p>October 14, 2024</p>

<p>We have received a diplomatic communication from Canada yesterday suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other diplomats are 'persons of interest' in a matter related to an investigation in that country. The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Trudeau Government that is centered around vote bank politics.</p>

<p>Since Prime Minister Trudeau made certain allegations in September 2023, the Canadian Government has not shared a shred of evidence with the Government of India, despite many requests from our side. This latest step follows interactions that have again witnessed assertions without any facts. This leaves little doubt that on the pretext of an investigation, there is a deliberate strategy of smearing India for political gains.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence. In 2018, his visit to India, which was aimed at currying favour with a vote bank, rebounded to his discomfort. His Cabinet has included individuals who have openly associated with an extremist and separatist agenda regarding India. His naked interference in Indian internal politics in December 2020 showed how far he was willing to go in this regard. That his Government was dependent on a political party, whose leader openly espouses a separatist ideology vis-a-vis India, only aggravated matters. Under criticism for turning a blind eye to foreign interference in Canadian politics, his Government has deliberately brought in India in an attempt to mitigate the damage. This latest development targeting Indian diplomats is now the next step in that direction. It is no coincidence that it takes place as Prime Minister Trudeau is to depose before a Commission on foreign interference. It also serves the anti-India separatist agenda that the Trudeau Government has constantly pandered to for narrow political gains.</p>

<p>To that end, the Trudeau Government has consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats and community leaders in Canada. This has included death threats to them and to Indian leaders. All these activities have been justified in the name of freedom of speech. Some individuals who have entered Canada illegally have been fast-tracked for citizenship. Multiple extradition requests from the Government of India in respect of terrorists and organized crime leaders living in Canada have been disregarded.</p>

<p>High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma is India's senior most serving diplomat with a distinguished career spanning 36 years. He has been Ambassador in Japan and Sudan, while also serving in Italy, Turkiye, Vietnam and China. The aspersions cast on him by the Government of Canada are ludicrous and deserve to be treated with contempt.</p>

<p>The Government of India has taken cognizance of the activities of the Canadian High Commission in India that serve the political agenda of the current regime. This led to the implementation of the principle of reciprocity in regard to diplomatic representation. India now reserves the right to take further steps in response to these latest efforts of the Canadian Government to concoct allegations against Indian diplomats."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/seuhqis_pm-modi-justin-trudeau-ani_625x300_22_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Indian government said Justin Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poorest-countries-face-highest-debt-burden-for-18-years-world-bank-6785781]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Poorest Countries Face Highest Debt Burden For 18 Years: World Bank]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/poorest-countries-face-highest-debt-burden-for-18-years-world-bank-6785781]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:21:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The world's 26 poorest economies are facing the most significant debt burden since 2006, the World Bank announced in a new report published Sunday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world's 26 poorest economies are facing the most significant debt burden since 2006, the World Bank announced in a new report published Sunday.</p>

<p>Government debt in these countries, which are home to around 40 percent of the world's population, now stands at an average of 72 percent of GDP -- an 18-year high -- the Washington-based development lender said.</p>

<p>At the same time, the amount of international aid they receive as a share of their economic output has shrunk to a two-decade low.</p>

<p>"There is much that low-income economies can -— and must -— do for themselves," the World Bank's deputy chief economist, Ayhan Kose, said in a statement. "But these economies also need stronger help from abroad."</p>

<p>Low-income economies borrowed heavily during the Covid-19 pandemic, causing primary deficits to triple, the Bank said, adding that many countries had been unable to "fully unwind" these deficits.</p>

<p>Nearly half of the world's 26 poorest economies now find themselves in debt distress or at high risk of it -- double the figure it was in 2015.</p>

<p>The World Bank said its concessional lending arm, the International Development Association (IDA), had provided "nearly half" of all the development aid these economies received in 2022 from multilateral organizations.</p>

<p>"At a time when much of the world simply backed away from the poorest countries, IDA has been their main lifeline," the Bank's chief economist Indermit Gill said.</p>

<p>"But if they are to rise out of a state of chronic emergency and meet key development goals, low-income economies will need to accelerate investment to a pace without precedent," he added.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-10/poor-people-homeless-people-in-brazil_650x400_51476241928.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nearly half of the world's 26 poorest economies now find themselves in debt distress.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Preposterous Imputations": Trudeau's Escalation, India's Strong Rebuttal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/reject-preposterous-imputations-india-strongly-hits-back-at-canada-6785660]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:03:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India on Monday issued a sharp rebuttal to Canada, rejecting allegations of its High Commissioner being a 'person of interest' in a murder investigation, describing them as "preposterous imputations."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India on Monday issued a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786">sharp rebuttal to Canada</a>, rejecting allegations of its High Commissioner being a 'person of interest' in a murder investigation, describing them as "preposterous imputations."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ties between India and Canada have been thorny ever since Justin Trudeau alleged India's involvement in the killing of Hardeep Singh Nijjar, a Canadian Khalistani terrorist, in June 2023. India has repeatedly refuted these claims as "absurd" and "motivated," accusing Trudeau's government of indulging in vote-bank politics by pandering to pro-Khalistan elements within Canada.</p>

<p>The diplomatic row took a sharp turn when Canada reportedly named the Indian High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma as a 'person of interest' in its investigation into Nijjar's death. India swiftly hit back, accusing Canada of maligning its officials without evidence and using "preposterous" claims to justify its failure to curb Khalistani extremism on its soil.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/political-agenda-of-trudeau-government-indias-full-statement-slamming-canada-6785786">"Political Agenda Of Trudeau Government": India's Full Statement Slamming Canada</a></p>

<p>In a strongly worded statement, New Delhi condemned Canada's diplomatic communication suggesting that the Indian High Commissioner and other Indian diplomats were implicated in a sensitive investigation. The Ministry of External Affairs issued a sharp rebuttal, stating, "The Government of India strongly rejects these preposterous imputations and ascribes them to the political agenda of the Trudeau Government that is centered around vote bank politics."</p>

<p>"Since Prime Minister Trudeau made certain allegations in September 2023, the Canadian government has not shared a shred of evidence with the Government of India, despite many requests from our side. This latest step follows interactions that have again witnessed assertions without any facts. This leaves little doubt that on the pretext of an investigation, there is a deliberate strategy of smearing India for political gains," the Centre's statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"High Commissioner Sanjay Kumar Verma is India's senior most serving diplomat with a distinguished career spanning 36 years. He has been Ambassador in Japan and Sudan, while also serving in Italy, Turkiye, Vietnam and China. The aspersions cast on him by the Government of Canada are ludicrous and deserve to be treated with contempt," it added.</p>

<p>The latest exchange follows a brief encounter between Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Justin Trudeau on the sidelines of the ASEAN Summit in Laos recently. While sources in New Delhi described the meeting as inconsequential, Trudeau painted it as a "brief exchange" in which he reiterated his concerns about the safety of Canadians and upholding the rule of law. "I won't go into details about what we talked about... the safety of Canadians is one of the fundamental responsibilities of any Canadian government," Trudeau said at a press conference.</p>

<p>"Prime Minister Trudeau's hostility to India has long been in evidence. In 2018, his visit to India, which was aimed at currying favour with a vote bank, rebounded to his discomfort. His Cabinet has included individuals who have openly associated with an extremist and separatist agenda regarding India. His naked interference in Indian internal politics in December 2020 showed how far he was willing to go in this regard. That his Government was dependent on a political party, whose leader openly espouses a separatist ideology vis-a-vis India, only aggravated matters," Centre's statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has repeatedly highlighted its concerns over the flourishing pro-Khalistan movement in Canada, demanding that Canada take firm and verifiable action against those advocating violence and extremism. Indian officials have warned that the nexus between Khalistani extremists, organised crime, drug syndicates, and human trafficking should be a matter of concern for Canada as well.</p>

<p>"To that end, the Trudeau Government has consciously provided space to violent extremists and terrorists to harass, threaten and intimidate Indian diplomats and community leaders in Canada. This has included death threats to them and to Indian leaders. All these activities have been justified in the name of freedom of speech. Some individuals who have entered Canada illegally have been fast-tracked for citizenship. Multiple extradition requests from the Government of India in respect of terrorists and organized crime leaders living in Canada have been disregarded," the statement read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India has made it clear that repairing relations with Canada hinges on Ottawa's willingness to act against pro-Khalistan elements operating freely within its borders. Despite India's repeated diplomatic overtures, no concrete action has been forthcoming from Canada. In turn, Ottawa has expressed frustration over India's reluctance to participate in its investigation into Nijjar's death.</p>

<p>Canadian Foreign Minister Melanie Joly, in a recent testimony before the Public Inquiry into Foreign Interference, described the current state of relations with India as "tense" and "very difficult," further fueling speculation that ties between the two nations could worsen.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/122o7v0g_modi-trudeau-afp_625x300_23_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has repeatedly highlighted its concerns over the flourishing pro-Khalistan movement in Canada.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-military-encircles-taiwan-us-calls-it-unwarranted-6785647]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China's Military Encircles Taiwan, US Calls It "Unwarranted"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinas-military-encircles-taiwan-us-calls-it-unwarranted-6785647]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 14:00:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States said China's actions were "unwarranted" and risk "escalation" as it called on Beijing to act with restraint.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>China deployed fighter jets and warships to encircle Taiwan on Monday in drills Beijing said were aimed at sending a "stern warning" to "separatist" forces on the self-ruled island.</p>

<p>Beijing has not ruled out using force to bring Taiwan under its control and Monday's drills represent its fourth round of large-scale war games in just over two years.</p>

<p>The United States said China's actions were "unwarranted" and risk "escalation" as it called on Beijing to act with restraint.</p>

<p>President Lai Ching-te, who took office in May, has been more outspoken than his predecessor Tsai Ing-wen in defending Taiwan's sovereignty, angering Beijing, which calls him a "separatist".</p>

<p>Lai vowed on Monday to "protect democratic Taiwan and safeguard national security", while the defence ministry said it dispatched "appropriate forces" in response to the drills.</p>

<p>Chinese foreign ministry spokeswoman Mao Ning hit back, saying "Taiwan independence and peace in the Taiwan Strait are irreconcilable".</p>

<p>AFP journalists near the Hsinchu air force base, in the north of Taiwan, saw 12 fighter jets take off on Monday.</p>

<p>Outlying islands administered by Taipei were on "heightened alert" and "aircraft and ships will respond to enemy situations in accordance with the engagement rules", Taiwan's defence ministry said.</p>

<p>Beijing said its exercises served as a "stern warning to the separatist acts of 'Taiwan Independence' forces".</p>

<p>The drills, dubbed Joint Sword-2024B, are testing troops' "joint operations capabilities" according to Captain Li Xi, spokesman for the Chinese military's Eastern Theater Command.</p>

<p>They are taking place in "areas to the north, south and east of Taiwan Island", he said.</p>

<p>The drills are "focusing on subjects of sea-air combat-readiness patrol, blockade on key ports and areas", Li said.</p>

<p>They also practised an "assault on maritime and ground targets".</p>

<p>The Liaoning aircraft carrier group "with its troops of army, navy, air force and rocket force" was also involved, Li said.</p>

<p>The previous large-scale drills held in May, three days after Lai's inauguration, were called "Joint Sword-2024A" and lasted two days.</p>

<p><strong>China coast guard 'inspections'</strong></p>

<p>China's coast guard was also sent to conduct "inspections" around the island.</p>

<p>A diagram released by the coast guard showed four fleets encircling Taiwan and moving in an anti-clockwise direction around the island.</p>

<p>The coast guard of the eastern province of Fujian -- the closest area on the mainland to Taiwan -- also said it was conducting "comprehensive law enforcement patrols" in waters near the Taipei-controlled Matsu islands.</p>

<p>Taiwan said four "formations" of China coast guard ships were patrolling the island, but they had not entered its prohibited or restricted waters.</p>

<p>China has ramped up military activity around Taiwan in recent years, sending warplanes and other military aircraft while its ships maintain a near-constant presence around the island's waters.</p>

<p>"In the face of enemy threats, all officers and soldiers of the country are in full readiness," Taiwan's defence ministry said on Monday.</p>

<p>Lai convened a high-level security meeting over the drills, said Joseph Wu, secretary-general of the National Security Council, who described the exercises as "inconsistent with international law".</p>

<p>In his National Day speech on Thursday, Lai vowed to "resist annexation" and insisted that Beijing and Taipei were "not subordinate to each other".</p>

<p>Lai's Democratic Progressive Party has long defended the sovereignty and democracy of Taiwan, which has its own government, military and currency.</p>

<p>Beijing said on Monday the drills were "a legitimate and necessary operation for safeguarding state sovereignty and national unity".</p>

<p><strong>'Feel a bit numb'</strong></p>

<p>Lieutenant Colonel Fu Zhengnan, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences, said in a video shared by state media that the drills could "switch from training to combat at any time".</p>

<p>"If Taiwan separatists provoke once, the PLA's operation around the island will make their first move," Fu said, referring to China's People's Liberation Army.</p>

<p>Taiwan's coast guard said on Monday it had detained a Chinese man on one of its outlying islands after a possible "grey zone intrusion", referring to tactics that fall short of a direct act of war.</p>

<p>In Taipei, people appeared to be largely unperturbed.</p>

<p>"I won't panic too much because they quite often have drills," 34-year-old engineer Benjamin Hsiao told AFP.</p>

<p>"It's not the first time in recent years anyway, so I feel a bit numb."</p>

<p>AFP journalists on Monday afternoon saw about five military jeeps mounted with machine guns patrolling around Taipei Songshan Airport, which is also a military air base.</p>

<p>The dispute between China and Taiwan dates back to a civil war in which the nationalist forces of Chiang Kai-shek were defeated by Mao Zedong's communist fighters and fled to the island in 1949.</p>

<p>China and Taiwan have been ruled separately since then.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/pkjtugtg_china-military-drill-in-taiwan_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China deployed fighter jets and warships to encircle Taiwan on Monday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unacceptable-eu-slams-israel-attacks-on-lebanon-peacekeepers-6785537]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Completely Unacceptable": EU Slams Israel Attacks On Lebanon Peacekeepers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unacceptable-eu-slams-israel-attacks-on-lebanon-peacekeepers-6785537]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:44:30 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A series of Israeli attacks have injured United Nations peacekeepers in southern Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The European Union's foreign policy chief Josep Borrell Monday denounced as "completely unacceptable" a series of Israeli attacks that have injured United Nations peacekeepers in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>"The 27 (EU) members agreed on asking (the) Israelis to stop attacking UNIFIL," Borrell told reporters ahead of a meeting of the bloc's foreign ministers in Luxembourg. "It's completely unacceptable attacking United Nations troops," he said.</p>

<p>At least five peacekeepers have been wounded in recent days as Israel targets Hezbollah in southern Lebanon.</p>

<p>UNIFIL, a mission of about 9,500 troops of various nationalities created following Israel's 1978 invasion of Lebanon, has accused the Israeli military of "deliberately" firing on its positions.</p>

<p>"Many European members are participating in this mission," Borrell noted. "Their work is very important."</p>

<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called on UN chief Antonio Guterres Sunday to move peacekeepers deployed in south Lebanon out of "harm's way", saying Hezbollah was using them as "human shields".</p>

<p>UNIFIL has refused to leave its positions.</p>

<p><b>Also Read:&nbsp;</b><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/move-lebanon-peacekeepers-out-of-harms-way-right-now-netanyahu-to-un-6783635">"Move Lebanon Peacekeepers Out Of Harm's Way, Right Now": Netanyahu To UN</a></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/7241fc6g_un-peacekeepers-in-lebanon_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UNIFIL has refused to leave its positions in Lebanon.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-destroys-russian-military-transport-plane-6785471]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukraine Destroys Russian Military Transport Plane]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukraine-destroys-russian-military-transport-plane-6785471]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:18:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Ukraine has stepped up attacks inside Russian territory in recent months, targeting military sites and energy facilities, aiming to upend Russian military logistics.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kyiv said Monday its forces had destroyed a Russian military transport plane stationed at an airfield deep inside Russian territory over the weekend, the latest Ukrainian claim of an attack behind Moscow's lines.</p>

<p>Ukraine has stepped up attacks inside Russian territory in recent months, targeting military sites and energy facilities, aiming to upend Russian military logistics.</p>

<p>Kyiv's military intelligence agency said it had destroyed the Tu-134 transport aircraft overnight between Saturday and Sunday at a military airfield in the Orenburg region, which lies around 1,000 kilometres (620 miles) from the border with Ukraine.</p>

<p>"These Soviet-built airplanes are used mainly to transport leadership of the Russian defence ministry," the Defence Intelligence of the Ministry of Defence of Ukraine said on social media.</p>

<p>The agency posted footage of what Ukraine said was an arson attack, showing a blaze burning inside an aircraft, but it did not provide details of how the alleged attack was carried out.</p>

<p>There was no immediate comment on the specific claims from Moscow.</p>

<p>Since the start of its invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, Moscow has detained hundreds of people for alleged sabotage and arson attacks on military, railway and other infrastructure sites.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-11/riijiu7g_plane-generic_625x300_24_November_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kyiv's military intelligence agency destroyed Tu-134 transport aircraft. (Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-looks-at-new-immigration-law-in-2025-6785677]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[French Government Looks At New Immigration Law In 2025]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/french-government-looks-at-new-immigration-law-in-2025-6785677]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:07:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The French authorities want to adopt a new immigration law next year, a spokeswoman said, as the new right-wing government seeks to crack down on immigration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The French authorities want to adopt a new immigration law next year, a spokeswoman said, as the new right-wing government seeks to crack down on immigration.</p>

<p>"There will be a need for a new law," government spokeswoman Maud Bregeon told broadcaster BFMTV on Sunday.</p>

<p>The government's plan to tighten immigration policies and border controls is emblematic of the rightward shift in French politics following this summer's legislative elections that resulted in a hung parliament.</p>

<p>Michel Barnier's government hopes the bill will be submitted to parliament at the beginning of 2025.</p>

<p>In September, a Paris student was raped and murdered in a case that has further inflamed a French debate on migration after a Moroccan was named as the suspected attacker.</p>

<p>The government wants to extend the detention period for undocumented migrants deemed to be dangerous in order to better enforce expulsion orders.</p>

<p>One of the options under consideration is to increase the maximum period of detention from 90 to 210 days, which is now only possible for terrorist offences.</p>

<p>"We don't rule out the possibility of considering other provisions", said Bregeon, adding that there should be "no taboos when it comes to protecting the French."</p>

<p>Last December, France already passed an immigration law.</p>

<p>The bill was hardened to gain the support of the far-right and right-wing MPs.</p>

<p>But the country's highest constitutional authority censured most of the new amendments which were dropped before President Emmanuel Macron signed it into law.</p>

<p>The measures struck down by the Constitutional Council "will serve as a basis for the new immigration bill", a government source told AFP. "Some of them could be modified and there will be additions."</p>

<p>The most hardline member of the government, Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau, has vowed to crack down on immigration. He has stirred controversy just days into the job, saying that "the rule of law is neither intangible nor sacred".</p>

<p>Retailleau, who previously headed the Republicans party in the Senate, was seen as the driving force behind the tough legislation last year.</p>

<p>He wants to reinstate the offense of illegal residence, among other measures.</p>

<p>Gabriel Attal, Barnier's predecessor and now leader in parliament of Macron's Renaissance party, said on Monday that a new law on immigration did not seem a "total priority."</p>

<p>"Adopting a law for the sake of a law makes no sense," he told broadcaster France inter.</p>

<p>He said "the priority is to act so that the state can truly control who enters and leaves" France.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/jioolhm_france-immigration-law_625x300_14_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[France Interior Minister Bruno Retailleau, has vowed to crack down on immigration.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-in-4-adults-suspect-undiagnosed-adhd-due-to-social-media-influence-study-6785298]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 In 4 Adults Suspect Undiagnosed ADHD Due To Social Media Influence: Study]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-in-4-adults-suspect-undiagnosed-adhd-due-to-social-media-influence-study-6785298]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Oct 2024 13:04:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder -- also known as ADHD -- is typically thought of as a childhood condition, a new study on Monday showed that one in four or 25 per cent of adults in America suspect they may have it but is undiagnosed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder -- also known as ADHD -- is typically thought of as a childhood condition, a new study on Monday showed that one in four or 25 per cent of adults in America suspect they may have it but is undiagnosed.</p>

<p>The study based on a national survey of 1,000 American adults showed that social media videos helped adults to realise that their struggles with attention, focus, and restlessness could, in fact, be undiagnosed ADHD.</p>

<p>Worryingly, only 13 per cent of survey respondents have shared their suspicions with their doctor.</p>

<p>That's raising concerns about the consequences of self-diagnosis leading to incorrect treatment, said the team</p>

<p>"Anxiety, depression, and ADHD -- all these things can look a lot alike, but the wrong treatment can make things worse instead of helping that person feel better and improving their functioning," said psychologist Justin Barterian, clinical assistant professor in Ohio State University's Department of Psychiatry and Behavioural Health.</p>

<p>An estimated 4.4 per cent of people ages 18 to 44 have ADHD, and some people aren't diagnosed until they're older, Barterian said.</p>

<p>"There's definitely more awareness of how it can continue to affect folks into adulthood and a lot of people who are realising, once their kids have been diagnosed, that they fit these symptoms as well, given that it's a genetic disorder," Barterian said.</p>

<p>Further, more than the older generations, younger adults were more likely to believe they have undiagnosed ADHD.</p>

<p>Barterian said while social media videos can help educate and bring awareness, "seek a psychologist or a psychiatrist or a physician" can help in proper diagnosis and further aid in the treatment of the condition.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/eblsc4h_adhd-generic-_625x300_14_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Younger adults were more likely to believe they had undiagnosed ADHD. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>