<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 22:43:44 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-pakistan-likely-to-privatize-national-flag-carrier-report-5975786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Cash-Strapped Pakistan Likely To Privatize National Flag Carrier: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/cash-strapped-pakistan-likely-to-privatize-national-flag-carrier-report-5975786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 20:00:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Cash-strapped Pakistan is likely to privatize its national flag carrier by the first week of August, a media report said on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cash-strapped Pakistan is likely to privatize its national flag carrier by the first week of August, a media report said on Wednesday.</p>

<p>The much-anticipated privatization of Pakistan International Airline (PIA) has been on top of the agenda of the government after the groundwork was completed by the caretaker government that was in place to organize elections.</p>

<p>Citing sources close to the development, private television channel ARY News reported that six companies have been shortlisted for the privatization of the national flag carrier.</p>

<p>The shortlisted companies have sought details related to PIA and asked for time till July to review the financial issues of the national airline.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the authorities are providing the required information to the consortium of shortlisted companies.</p>

<p>It is pertinent to mention here that a consortium of six companies has been pre-qualified for privatizing Pakistan International Airlines (PIA).</p>

<p>According to the details, the companies that lie in the pre-qualified consortium will now be eligible to participate in the bidding process for the PIA.</p>

<p>The decision was made during the Privatisation Commission Board meeting this week which was chaired by Privatization Minister Aleem Khan, who emphasized the government's commitment to ensuring a transparent and efficient privatisation process for all loss-making state-owned companies.</p>

<p>To maintain transparency and foster confidence, Khan proposed broadcasting the privatisation proceedings live on media platforms to assure all stakeholders about the integrity of the process.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-05/59fovsso_pia-aircraft_625x300_08_May_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/scientists-develop-speech-recognition-tool-to-predict-alzheimers-onset-5974976]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Scientists Develop Speech Recognition Tool To Predict Alzheimer's Onset]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/scientists-develop-speech-recognition-tool-to-predict-alzheimers-onset-5974976]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:46:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new AI-based model could predict the onset of Alzheimer's disease by analysing an individual's speech, the developers said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new AI-based model could predict the onset of Alzheimer's disease by analysing an individual's speech, the developers said.</p>

<p>Trained on audio recordings of patients with mild cognitive impairment -- early stages of memory loss, the model achieved 78.5 per cent accuracy in forecasting whether patients would remain stable or progress to dementia within six years, according to the researchers.</p>

<p>Alzheimer's disease is the most common form of dementia and impacts one's everyday activities by impairing memory and thinking.</p>

<p>The researchers at Boston University, US, used recordings of initial interviews of 166 patients aged 63-97 and trained the model using machine learning to discern patterns between speech, demographics, diagnosis, and how their condition was worsening.</p>

<p>The model analyses interview content such as spoken words and sentence structure, rather than speech features such as enunciation or speed, showed the study published in the journal Alzheimer's and Dementia.</p>

<p>"We combine the information we extract from the audio recordings with some very basic demographics - age, gender, and so on - and we get the final score," said Ioannis C. Paschalidis, a professor of engineering and the study's corresponding author.</p>

<p>"You can think of the score as the likelihood, the probability, that someone will remain stable or transition to dementia. It had significant predictive ability," said Paschalidis.</p>

<p>The researchers said that the model was able to perform well, despite challenges like low-quality recordings and background noise.</p>

<p>The researchers emphasised that early prediction is crucial as current diagnostic tests often identify Alzheimer's disease only after significant cognitive decline has occurred such as memories starting to slip away and personality traits beginning to shift.</p>

<p>The team aims to make their model accessible through an app to make it accessible for patients in remote areas, potentially increasing the number of people getting screened.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/i248cja_alzheimers-glance_625x300_07_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Alzheimer's disease is the most common form of dementia and impacts one's everyday activities]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lets-sit-down-and-talk-shehbaz-sharifs-olive-branch-to-imran-khan-5975108]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Let's Sit Down And Talk": Pakistan PM Extends Olive Branch To Imran Khan]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lets-sit-down-and-talk-shehbaz-sharifs-olive-branch-to-imran-khan-5975108]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:28:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Pakistan Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif on Wednesday extended an olive branch to his predecessor and political rival Imran Khan, offering to hold talks with him if was facing "troubles" in jail.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pakistan Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharif on Wednesday extended an olive branch to his predecessor and political rival Imran Khan, offering to hold talks with him if was facing "troubles" in jail.</p>

<p>Mr Khan, the founder of his Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf party, has been in jail since August last year after being convicted in some of the nearly 200 cases slapped on the 71-year-old cricketer-turned-politician since his ouster from power in April 2022.</p>

<p>"If their [PTI] founder is facing troubles [in jail], then I reiterate: come, let's sit down and talk," Mr Sharif said while addressing the National Assembly.</p>

<p>“Let us sit together to take the country ahead. Let us talk for the betterment of the country. There is no other way forward,” he said.</p>

<p>The Nawaz Sharif-led Pakistan Muslim League-Nawaz (PML-N) and Khan's Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf have been at loggerheads for years, particularly after the February 8 elections, which Mr Khan's party claims it had won.</p>

<p>Commenting on the 2018 elections won by Mr Khan's PTI, Mr Sharif said: "We joined Parliament despite the [rigged] polls. The sort of slogans that were raised during my first speech will always be remembered as a dark chapter in the history books."</p>

<p>"If someone is facing any injustice, then I believe that the scales of justice should be in favour of those [being victimised], there is no difference over it — whether it be any politician or anyone from any walk of life," Geo News quoted Sharif as saying.</p>

<p>Mr Sharif lamented that he had once again, while he was in the opposition, proposed to Mr Khan to sit for a dialogue but such slogans were raised again.</p>

<p>"So who is responsible for this bitterness [between politicians]. We don't even shake hands now," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Sharif, 72, also recounted his ordeal of facing victimisation by Mr Khan's government and that he was in jail when his mother passed away. He said that despite being a cancer survivor and with a backbone issue, he used to be taken to courts on the ordinary prison van just to exacerbate the condition, but he never complained.</p>

<p>In response to Prime Minister Sharif's remarks, Leader of the Opposition in the National Assembly Omar Ayub reiterated that the PTI would talk with the government only when Mr Khan and other incarcerated leaders and workers are released from jail.</p>

<p>"This should be in your minds: you torture our workers, you've kept our lady workers in prison vans at 45°C. My prime minister Imran Khan was kept in a death cell, there's an oven-like environment over there," he said, amidst sloganeering from the treasury benches.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/7dlm1n8_imran-khan-afp-_625x300_09_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shehbaz Sharif offered to hold talks with Imran Khan if he is facing troubles in jail (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-security-body-seeks-pact-with-india-to-end-rescreening-of-passengers-5972701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Security Body Seeks Pact With India To End Rescreening Of Passengers]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/us-security-body-seeks-pact-with-india-to-end-rescreening-of-passengers-5972701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 19:07:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US transport security body has sought a unique "one-stop agreement" with India to end the rescreening of passengers, asserting that the "really powerful" concept will raise global aviation security standards.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US transport security body has sought a unique "one-stop agreement" with India to end the rescreening of passengers, asserting that the "really powerful" concept will raise global aviation security standards.</p>

<p>Addressing the India US Aviation Summit here on Tuesday, David Pekoske, Administrator of the US Transportation Security Administration (USTSA) said that the one-stop security concept is "very reachable" between the countries.</p>

<p>"I think very tangible and very reachable between India and the United States is one-stop security," he said.</p>

<p>"It's a concept that expedites the flow of passengers and baggage to their destinations by eliminating the duplication of security controls at transfer points," Pekoske said.</p>

<p>He said in the case of a one-stop agreement, passengers who reach an airport in another country and have a connecting domestic flight would not need to be rescreened and their checked bags would go from aircraft to aircraft.</p>

<p>Terming it a "really powerful" concept, Pekoske said it raises global aviation security standards.</p>

<p>"Flights inbound to the United States are more secure. If there's a reverse agreement between the United States and India where US screening satisfies Indian requirements, that means that flights to India would also be more secure. It does require the regular exchange of information," he said.</p>

<p>"It requires improvements to security processes to maintain the agreement. It yields a reduction in security costs through better allocation of resources, reduces flight connection times and missed connections, and improves the passenger experience," he said.</p>

<p>Pekoske said the two countries should consider signing a memorandum of agreement to share sensitive security information.</p>

<p>"We have a category of classification of information that is not classified in the true sense of classified material, but it is sensitive enough that it needs additional protections," he said.</p>

<p>He said that whenever there is a sharing of sensitive security information -- which is critical to a growing partnership -- there is a need to have a memorandum of agreement which covers the aspects of that sharing arrangement.</p>

<p>He noted that both the TSA and India's transportation security posture were born of cruel tragedy.</p>

<p>For India, it was the bombing of Air India 'Kanishka' Flight 182 in 1985, while for the TSA, it was the 9-11 attacks in 2001.</p>

<p>"These tragic events were paradigm shifts in how we both thought about transportation security that continues today," he said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, addressing the summit, US Federal Aviation Administrator Michael Whitaker said that India and the United States need to work together on issues like aviation safety.</p>

<p>Asserting that safety is a team sport, he said that sharing data between the two countries can allow better identification and mitigation of risks in the sector.</p>

<p>"Our (US and India's) national systems of aviation are inextricably linked into a single global network," he said, adding that the two counties have adjoining air spaces, integrated supply chains, and international services that connect their economies and people.</p>

<p>"We need to work together on issues like safety, we need to share ideas and share innovations, especially in how to safely incorporate some of these new technologies into our airspace," he said.</p>

<p>Noting that the two countries have different systems that will take different approaches to solving challenges, he said, "We can and should work together to share best practices and learn from one another." "We all have an interest in increasing safety within our respective countries, but we must work together to increase the level of safety in the global aviation system," he added.</p>

<p>"This means sharing data. Sharing information allows us to better identify and mitigate risks before those risks become accidents and even before they become failures to the safety layers in our system," he added.</p>

<p>"When I started in aviation, accidents were unfortunately not uncommon. They were almost annual events, and safety regulators learned from those accidents and made the system safer," he said.</p>

<p>"For the past couple of decades, we've moved beyond that model, and accidents are now extremely rare, and they are simply unacceptable as an outcome," Whitaker said.</p>

<p>"Our challenge is to bring safety to the next level, and that means we need to proactively analyse data and find those risks of failure and mitigate those risks before they happen," he said.</p>

<p>Asserting that all the job categories in the aviation sector are highly sought after, he said that "for regulators, it means new questions about how we oversee those operations".</p>

<p>"We have to find a safe yet nimble way to regulate these new entrants who are operating at the speed of a startup while we are operating at the speed of government, he said.</p>

<p>He added that there is a need to figure out how to close the gap, identify these risks and leverage technology to incorporate them safely into the airspace.</p>

<p>"In the US, we've seen the public perception of safety and risk in the system evolve over time. As more people have access to aviation, the expectation grows that the system will be completely safe," he asserted.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-11/delhi-airport-security-twitter-650_650x400_81510601779.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US transport security body seeks one-stop pact with India to end rescreening of passengers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-tesla-car-flips-7-times-after-crash-but-all-passengers-survive-5975160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Tesla Car Flips 7 Times After Crash, All Passengers Survive]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/viral-video-tesla-car-flips-7-times-after-crash-but-all-passengers-survive-5975160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 18:29:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla CEO Elon Musk has reacted to a video showing a terrifying accident involving his company's Model Y car.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla CEO Elon Musk has reacted to a video showing a terrifying accident involving his company's Model Y car. The footage, shared on X, captured the electric SUV rolling over several times before landing. Miraculously, all passengers survived without serious injuries.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The billionaire reposted the video, writing, “Safety is our primary design goal.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Safety is our primary design goal</p>
— Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1805664298347511919?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>“That's why I bought my wife a Tesla. A little more than some sedans but it's saved the difference in gas savings and the car is the safest I could get!” a user wrote under the video.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">That's why I bought my wife a Tesla. A little more than some sedans but it's saved the difference in gas savings and the car is the safest I could get!</p>
— Scott (@ScottPolhamus) <a href="https://twitter.com/ScottPolhamus/status/1805664609010934050?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user commented, “We love it, you care so much about your customers &amp; you keep on improving Tesla safety further with FSD.”</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We love it you care so much about your customers &amp; you keep on improving Tesla safety further with FSD.</p>
— Tahreem Hussain (@tahreem57) <a href="https://twitter.com/tahreem57/status/1805665447549022363?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Mr Musk's reaction came after a recent crash in Orange County, California, where a Tesla driver was reportedly speeding and crashed, causing the vehicle to flip into oncoming traffic, reported KTLA News.</p>

<p>Three people, including the Tesla driver, were hospitalised; their conditions were not immediately available.</p>

<p>Witnesses said the Tesla driver was driving at an estimated over 100 miles per hour. The crash involved six vehicles, with two overturning and trapping people inside. First responders extricated the victims, including the Tesla driver, and rushed them to the hospital.</p>

<p>An eye witness, who was waiting at a red light, recalled the car approaching at "over 100 miles" per hour.</p>

<p>"She smacked the cars right next to me. I don't know how she missed me," the witness said, stressing that the Tesla driver caused the crash.</p>

<p>A worker heard the tyres screech and saw the crash unfold. Recounting the "scary" experience, he said, "Cars are flipping over right outside the window, and it takes you a little bit out of reality."</p>

<p>Police are investigating the cause of the crash, saying it was possible that alcohol or drugs could also be involved.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u3p97l8_tesla-crash_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-committed-to-partnering-with-maldives-to-ensure-free-indo-pacific-5974409]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Says Committed To Partnering With Maldives To Ensure Free Indo-Pacific]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-says-committed-to-partnering-with-maldives-to-ensure-free-indo-pacific-5974409]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 18:19:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US has reaffirmed its commitment to partnering with the Maldives to promote a free, open, and secure Indo-Pacific region, a senior state department official has said, amidst the archipelagic nation in the Indian Ocean moving closer to China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US has reaffirmed its commitment to partnering with the Maldives to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region, a senior state department official has said, amidst the archipelagic nation in the Indian Ocean moving closer to China.</p>

<p>This message was conveyed when US Secretary of State Antony Blinken met with visiting Maldivian Foreign Minister Moosa Zameer on Tuesday in Washington, DC.</p>

<p>Secretary Blinken reaffirmed the US commitment to partnering with Maldives to promote a free, open, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region, state department spokesperson Matthew Miller said.</p>

<p>Ever since Maldivian leader Mohamed Muizzu, known for his pro-China leanings, assumed charge as President in November last year, the Maldives has stepped up ties with Beijing and inked several bilateral agreements, including a defence cooperation deal.</p>

<p>Blinken's reference to the Indo-Pacific is also significant since China is vehemently opposed to the US and other countries getting involved in a region where Beijing has major maritime territorial disputes with countries such as the Philippines and Vietnam.</p>

<p>Blinken highlighted the US donation of eight patrol boats to the Maldives and, working with Congress, the planned provision of $2 million in hydrographic support to help the country mitigate the impact of rising sea levels, Miller said in a statement.</p>

<p>Blinken and Zameer discussed additional opportunities to enhance cooperation on addressing the climate crisis, economic growth, maritime security, and other bilateral priorities, it said.</p>

<p>In Male, the foreign ministry said Zameer and Blinken discussed matters in the area of defence and security cooperation, commitment to economic growth and adapting to climate change among other issues and expressed their commitment to regional stability and maritime security.</p>

<p>"Met with Maldivian Foreign Minister @MoosaZameer to enhance the US-Maldives partnership and cooperation on climate, economic growth, and maritime security," posted Blinken on his X handle with the photos of the meeting.</p>

<p>Almost echoing the sentiment, Zameer posted on his X handle, "I am delighted to meet with the Honourable @SecBlinken, Secretary of State of the US, today. I reaffirmed our commitment to further strengthen the partnership between the Maldives and US in tackling climate change, promoting democracy and cooperation in maritime security."</p>

<p>A statement from the Maldives Foreign Ministry said that the Maldives and the United States reaffirmed their commitment to explore new avenues "to strengthen the partnership" and acknowledged the importance of upholding a rules-based international order and expressed their commitment to regional stability, maritime security and promoting peace.</p>

<p>"Secretary Blinken congratulated the Maldives on the successful Presidential and Parliamentary elections and acknowledged the Maldives' leadership in the international fora towards combating climate change and promoting environmental sustainability," the statement said.</p>

<p>News portal Sun.mv said that earlier on Tuesday, Zameer met with Samantha Power, the Administrator of the US Agency for International Development (USAID).</p>

<p>"The two deliberated on various themes related to economical advancements and protecting the environment in addition to consolidating Maldivian associations with the agency's assistance," Edition.mv said.</p>

<p>Zameer had left for Washington on Sunday night, in a visit that the Foreign Ministry said seeks to "further strengthen the Maldives - US partnership and reaffirm commitment to multilateralism," Sun.mv said.</p>

<p>Zameer will also travel to New York, where he will meet with the UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres and the UN Under-Secretary-General for Economic and Social Affairs, Li Junhua, media reports said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/cf4tqnig_antony-blinken-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Antony Blinken met with the visiting Maldivian Foreign Minister on Tuesday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-volleyball-player-jailed-for-raping-12-year-old-girl-to-compete-at-paris-olympics-5974996]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Volleyball Player, Jailed For Raping A Minor, To Compete At Paris Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dutch-volleyball-player-jailed-for-raping-12-year-old-girl-to-compete-at-paris-olympics-5974996]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 18:08:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Steven van de Velde was sentenced in March 2016 to four years in prison after admitting to three counts of rape against a child he met on Facebook]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Dutch beach volleyball player, who raped a 12-year-old British girl, has qualified for next month's Paris Olympics despite being told by a judge that his dream of representing the Netherlands was "shattered."</p>

<p>Steven van de Velde was sentenced in March 2016 to four years in prison after admitting to three counts of rape against a child he met on Facebook. In August 2014, at the age of 19, he flew from the Netherlands to the UK to meet his victim, the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/volleyball/2024/06/25/volleyball-steven-van-der-velde-raped-british-12-olympics/"><em>Telegraph </em></a>reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Judge Francis Sheridan told him, "Prior to coming to this country you were training as a potential Olympian. Your hopes of representing your country now lie as a shattered dream."</p>

<p>However, Van de Velde, who was released after serving only 12 months in a Dutch prison, has since been permitted to rehabilitate his Olympic career. This month, he secured his spot in the national pair for the Paris Games alongside Matthew Immers.</p>

<p>Upon sentencing at Aylesbury Crown Court after being extradited from his homeland, his defense lawyer, Linda Strudwick, commented on the verdict: "The headlines say it all: 'A sex monster.' It's plainly a career end for him."</p>

<p>It has proven otherwise, as Van de Velde, now 29, has successfully rebuilt his beach volleyball career to the extent that he and Immer are now ranked as the 11th team in the world heading to Paris next month.</p>

<p>Van de Velde's resurgence poses a significant ethical dilemma for the International Olympic Committee. Each Paris Olympian is required to sign an Athletes' Rights and Responsibilities Declaration, which includes a mandate to "act as a role model."</p>

<p>Having travelled from Amsterdam to Milton Keynes to engage in sexual activity with a 12-year-old girl, a fact acknowledged in strong terms by the judge in 2016, Van de Velde had previously communicated with the victim on social media before arranging the visit, during which he took her virginity while her mother was away.</p>

<p>"Your actions have wrecked your life and you could, had you never come to England and committed these offences, have been a leader in your sport," Judge Sheridan said. "A young, naive, foolish child had formed the view that you loved her. In reality, you only knew her on the internet, had never met her before and were fully aware of the age difference."</p>

<p>Upon his release in 2017, having served only a quarter of his sentence, Van de Velde, who had cried in court upon learning about the girl's subsequent self-harm and overdose, stated: "I want to correct all the nonsense that has been written about me while I was imprisoned. I deliberately didn't read any of it, but I understand it was quite severe, branding me as a sex monster, as a paedophile. That I am not, really not.</p>

<p>"Everyone is entitled to their opinion about me, but it's only fair if they also hear my side of the story."</p>

<p>These remarks elicited a scathing response from the National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, which stated: "Van de Velde's lack of remorse and self-pity is astonishing, and we can only imagine how distressed his victim must feel upon seeing his comments.</p>

<p>"Grooming can leave a child feeling ashamed or even guilty, because they believe they have somehow willingly participated when, in reality, an adult has preyed upon them for sexual exploitation."</p>

<p>The Dutch Olympic committee has not yet commented on Van de Velde's qualification for Paris. According to The Australian, the country's volleyball federation has yet to finalize its athlete selections. The IOC has been contacted for a response.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u7tumaf8_steven-van-de-velde_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Van de Velde, who was released after serving only 12 months in a Dutch prison]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-closed-door-trial-for-us-reporter-on-spy-charges-5974825]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Begins Closed-Door Trial For US Reporter On Spy Charges]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-begins-closed-door-trial-for-us-reporter-on-spy-charges-5974825]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:44:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A shaven-headed Evan Gershkovich went on trial behind closed doors on Wednesday in a Russian court where the US journalist is facing accusations of espionage.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A shaven-headed Evan Gershkovich went on trial behind closed doors on Wednesday in a Russian court where the US journalist is facing accusations of espionage.</p>

<p>Prosecutors say the Wall Street Journal reporter gathered secret information on the orders of the US Central Intelligence Agency about a company that manufactures tanks for Russia's war in Ukraine. If convicted, he faces a sentence of up to 20 years.</p>

<p>Gershkovich, his newspaper and the US government all reject the allegations and say that he was just doing his job as a reporter accredited by Russia's Foreign Ministry to work there.</p>

<p>"His case is not about evidence, procedural norms, or the rule of law. It is about the Kremlin using American citizens to achieve its political objectives," the US embassy in Moscow said in a statement, calling for Gershkovich's immediate release.</p>

<p>After several hours of closed proceedings, the court said the next session would take place on Aug. 13 - an indication the case will drag on for months. The reason for the long interval was not clear.</p>

<p>Journalists were briefly allowed to film the 32-year-old Gershkovich before the start of the trial, from which the media are barred. Wearing an open-necked shirt and standing in a glass box, he smiled faintly and nodded at colleagues he recognised.</p>

<p>Prosecutor Mikael Ozdoyev later summarised the charges for reporters.</p>

<p>"The investigation established and documented that... Gershkovich, on instructions from the CIA, in September 2023, in the Sverdlovsk region, collected secret information about the activities of a defence enterprise regarding the production and repair of military equipment," Ozdoyev said.</p>

<p>"Gershkovich carried out the illegal actions while observing painstaking conspiratorial measures," he added.</p>

<p>Ozdoyev later told reporters he had misspoken, and the alleged offence was actually in March 2023 - the month of the reporter's arrest.</p>

<h2><strong>Closed Hearing</strong></h2>

<p>Closed trials are standard procedure in Russia for cases of alleged treason or espionage involving classified state material, which typically can last several months.</p>

<p>The Kremlin says the case, and the arrangements for it, are a matter for the court, but has stated - without publishing evidence - that Gershkovich was caught "red-handed".</p>

<p>Against the background of the Ukraine war, Gershkovich and other Americans detained in Russia have been caught up in the gravest crisis between Moscow and Washington for more than 60 years.</p>

<p>President Vladimir Putin has said Russia is open to the idea of a prisoner exchange involving Gershkovich and that contacts with the United States have taken place, but they must remain secret.</p>

<p>The US has accused Russia of conducting "hostage diplomacy". It has designated Gershkovich and another jailed American, Paul Whelan, as "wrongfully detained" and says it is committed to bringing them home.</p>

<p>The US embassy statement said Russian authorities had failed to provide evidence supporting the charges against Gershkovich or to explain why his work as a journalist constituted a crime.</p>

<p>The trial is taking place in the city of Yekaterinburg, where officers of the FSB security service arrested Gershkovich on March 29, 2023, while he was eating in a steakhouse. Since then he has spent nearly 16 months in Moscow's Lefortovo prison.</p>

<p>The Wall Street Journal has declined to comment on the purpose of his reporting trip to Russia's Urals region or on the specific allegation by prosecutors that Gershkovich was trying to gather information on Uralvagonzavod, a supplier of tanks for Russia's war in Ukraine.</p>

<p>"He was there as an accredited journalist, doing his job," Wall Street Journal publisher Almar Latour told Reuters in a phone interview before the trial.</p>

<p>Many Western news organisations pulled staff out of Russia after Putin sent his army into Ukraine in February 2022. Russia then passed laws that set long prison terms for "discrediting" the armed forces or spreading "fake news" about them.</p>

<p>Gershkovich was one of a small number of Western reporters, also including journalists from Reuters, who continued to report from inside Russia.</p>

<p>Another journalist, Russian-American Alsu Kurmasheva, was arrested last year and is awaiting trial on charges of violating Russia's "foreign agent" law and spreading false information about the armed forces, which she denies.</p>

<p>Earlier this month a French researcher, Laurent Vinatier, was arrested and accused of failing to register as a foreign agent while gathering information about Russia's military.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/nik4i1vo_evan-gershkovich-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[If convicted, Evan Gershkovich faces a sentence of up to 20 years.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-wife-requests-privacy-he-needs-to-recuperate-5974782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Julian Assange's Wife Requests Privacy: "He Needs To Recuperate"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-wife-requests-privacy-he-needs-to-recuperate-5974782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 17:39:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Wikileaks founder Julian Assange needs privacy and time to recover after more than five years in a high-security London prison, his wife Stella said Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wikileaks founder <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/search?searchtext=Julian-Assange">Julian Assange</a> needs privacy and time to recover after more than five years in a high-security London prison, his wife Stella said after his return to Australia Wednesday.</p>

<p>Assange wanted to attend a news conference soon after his arrival in the Australian capital but "you have to understand, he needs time, he needs to recuperate, and this is a process," she told reporters, apparently close to tears.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">JULIAN ASSANGE IS FREE!!<br />
<br />
Watch here: <a href="https://t.co/7PlI9fnSMG">https://t.co/7PlI9fnSMG</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AssangeFreed?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AssangeFreed</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/JournalismIsNotACrime?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#JournalismIsNotACrime</a> <a href="https://t.co/Kpbh63CCCB">pic.twitter.com/Kpbh63CCCB</a></p>
— Free Assange - #FreeAssange (@FreeAssangeNews) <a href="https://twitter.com/FreeAssangeNews/status/1805905965788594201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>"I ask you please to give us space, to give us privacy, to find our place, to let our family be a family before he can speak again at a time of his choosing."</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-talks-in-us-led-to-julian-assange-deal-says-australia-pm-anthony-albanese-5974505">Secret Talks In US Led To Julian Assange Deal, Says Australia PM</a></p>

<p>Assange landed on a chilly Canberra evening in a private jet hours after being freed by a court in the US Pacific territory of Northern Mariana Islands.</p>

<p>He admitted to one count of revealing US defence secrets in exchange for being sentenced by the US judge to time already served in London's Belmarsh prison -- five years and two months.</p>

<p>The agreement allowed him to walk free and return home to Australia.</p>

<p>"He just arrived in Australia after being in a high-security prison for over five years and a long 72-hour flight, or something like that -- it's premature," Stella Assange said.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-quiet-diplomacy-led-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-freedom-5974456">How Australia's Quiet Diplomacy Led WikiLeaks' Julian Assange To Freedom</a></p>

<p>"Julian has to recover, that's the priority, and the fact is that Julian will always defend human rights, will always defend victims, and that is just part of who he is," she said.</p>

<p>Assange's lawyer Jen Robinson said he had spoken to Prime Minister Anthony Albanese when his plane touched down and "told the prime minister that he had saved his life".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/22g6nbkg_julian-assange-with-wife_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange spent over five years in a high-security London prison.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-talks-in-us-led-to-julian-assange-deal-says-australia-pm-anthony-albanese-5974505]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Secret Talks In US Led To Julian Assange Deal, Says Australia PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/secret-talks-in-us-led-to-julian-assange-deal-says-australia-pm-anthony-albanese-5974505]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:59:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Australia's Prime Minister said Wednesday a string of recent non-disclosed missions to the United States helped to forge the plea deal that freed Julian Assange.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia's Prime Minister said Wednesday a string of recent non-disclosed missions to the United States helped to forge the plea deal that freed Julian Assange.</p>

<p>The 52-year-old WikiLeaks founder landed in Canberra hours earlier, after earning his liberty by pleading guilty to a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate US national defence information.</p>

<p>He was sentenced by a court in the US Pacific territory of Northern Mariana Islands to time already served in London's high-security Belmarsh prison -- five years and two months -- and allowed to walk free.</p>

<p>The US Department of Justice had to make a "range of decisions" for the plea deal to proceed, Anthony Albanese told a news conference in Canberra, stressing that the US department was independent and "not subject to political influence".</p>

<p>A "whole range of people" had visited the United States as the deal was worked out, the Australian leader told reporters.</p>

<p>"I am surprised that some of it was missed by the people in this room -- some of the visits -- but it's not up to me to indicate that," Albanese said.</p>

<p>He advised journalists to "go back and look at some diaries and who has travelled to the United States in recent months".</p>

<p>Albanese said he had exchanged "directly" with Assange's lawyers during the negotiations.</p>

<p>Australia's high commissioner to the United Kingdom, Stephen Smith, also acted as a conduit for communication, visiting Assange in Belmarsh, the prime minister said.</p>

<p>"The details of the plea deal were worked through over a period of time," he said.</p>

<p>"This was the only way that I could see a resolution being achieved -- and the objective here was to conclude these matters."</p>

<p>Albanese said he had never met with Assange but spoke with him the moment his jet touched down in Canberra as part of a mutually agreed plan.</p>

<p>"I had a very warm discussion with him this evening. He was very generous in his praise of the Australian government's efforts," he added.</p>

<p>"The Australian government stands up for Australian citizens. That's what we do."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/ajvkrgf8_julian-assange-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anthony Albanese said he had exchanged "directly" with Julian Assange's lawyers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-quiet-diplomacy-led-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-freedom-5974456]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[How Australia's Quiet Diplomacy Led WikiLeaks' Julian Assange To Freedom]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-australias-quiet-diplomacy-led-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-to-freedom-5974456]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:51:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[After Julian Assange was released by a court on the remote US Pacific territory of Saipan, ending a 14-year legal battle, the WikiLeaks founder's lawyer first thanked Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese for making the outcome possible.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After Julian Assange was released by a court on the remote US Pacific territory of Saipan on Wednesday, ending a 14-year legal battle, the WikiLeaks founder's lawyer first thanked Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese for making the outcome possible.</p>

<p>Jennifer Robinson, the Australian attorney of Assange, said diplomacy and intense lobbying with the highest authorities in the US played a big role in Assange walking free, after spending five years in a high-security British prison and seven years holed up in the Ecuadorean embassy in London.</p>

<p>"At every opportunity, and when Australian officials were making outreach to the US, they knew that they were acting with the full authority of the prime minister of Australia," Robinson told reporters outside the courtroom in Saipan.</p>

<p>Albanese has claimed Assange's release as a win for the country, which leveraged its security ties with Washington and London to strengthen its case to resolve the plight of an Australian citizen.</p>

<p>"This work has been complex and it has been considered. This is what standing up for Australians around the world looks like," Albanese, leader of a centre-left Labor government, told parliament on Wednesday.</p>

<p>Assange, who landed in Australia on Wednesday evening, had faced a maximum jail sentence of 175 years after being charged with 17 counts of breaching the US Espionage Act and a hacking-related charge. Under a deal revealed on Tuesday, he pled guilty to a single charge of espionage and walked free.</p>

<p>The deal gained momentum as the US faced growing challenges in the UK over the legality of extraditing Assange, while Australian lawmakers and diplomats raised the heat in Washington and London.</p>

<h2><strong>Political Shift</strong></h2>

<p>A decade ago under a conservative government, there was little political will in Canberra to back Assange's case. But things changed in 2023 when dozens of lawmakers across the political spectrum swung in behind the campaign to bring him home, his father, John Shipton, told Reuters.</p>

<p>That swing culminated in the passage of a parliamentary motion in February this year calling for Assange's release.</p>

<p>Shipton told Reuters the Australian government had been "nothing short of magnificent" and praised former prime minister Kevin Rudd and former defence minister Stephen Smith, Australia's top envoys to the US and Britain.</p>

<p>Australian conservative lawmaker Barnaby Joyce, a former deputy prime minister, was among a cross-party group of politicians who travelled to Washington in September to lobby for a resolution.</p>

<p>Joyce said on Wednesday the trip made the case on Capitol Hill that Australian politicians wanted to "get this thing done", because it was a distraction to Australia's security alliance with the United States.</p>

<p>Long-time advisor to the Australian campaign for Assange, lawyer Greg Barns, said US politicians saw on that trip that "this wasn't a party political issue".</p>

<p>One government official who did not want to be identified said the first big break for Assange came in January 2021, when then shadow Attorney General Mark Dreyfus issued a statement calling for the case against Assange to end after a British court found that it would be unjust to extradite him to the US.</p>

<p>"This was the first indication that a major political party in Australia was supporting the cause to free Assange," the official said.</p>

<h2><strong>Enough Is Enough</strong></h2>

<p>When Labor won power in May 2022, Assange finally had state diplomatic support behind him. Later that year Albanese called for his release on the floor of the House of Representatives, the first time a Prime Minister had mentioned Assange in parliament since 2012.</p>

<p>"Enough is enough, it is time for this matter to be brought to a conclusion," he said.</p>

<p>"My position is clear and has been made clear to the US administration that it is time that this matter be brought to a close. This is an Australian citizen."</p>

<p>Behind the scenes, Albanese and senior cabinet colleagues including Foreign Minister Penny Wong and Attorney General Dreyfus used visits to the US to lobby their counterparts, according to the government official.</p>

<p>The appointment of Smith and Rudd to the top diplomatic jobs in London and Washington in late 2022 added two more sympathetic lobbyists for Assange's cause.</p>

<p>Smith visited Assange in Belmarsh prison in April 2023, the first such visit by Australia's top UK diplomat since he was imprisoned four years earlier.</p>

<p>Deeper ties between Australia and the US through the AUKUS security pact helped push diplomatic efforts along, said Mark Kenny, a professor at Australian National University.</p>

<p>"It looks pretty odd if we're getting ever closer to the US and yet we don't have a special relationship with the US such that we can advocate and get concessions for an Australian citizen," Kenny said.</p>

<h2><strong>Final Details</strong></h2>

<p>As recently as last July, US officials appeared determined to prosecute Assange. Secretary of State Antony Blinken said that month Australia needed to understand US concerns over the issue.</p>

<p>However, a month later, US Ambassador to Australia Caroline Kennedy said a deal was possible.</p>

<p>After the cross-party delegation of Australian politicians travelled to Washington in September to speak to Republican and Democrat lawmakers about the Assange case, the Biden administration appeared to be softening its response.</p>

<p>Joe Biden said in April, "We are considering it," when asked by media about Australia's request to end Assange's prosecution.</p>

<p>But it was the UK High Court's decision in May to allow Assange to appeal against his extradition that triggered the breakthrough in negotiations over a plea deal according to his wife Stella.</p>

<p>The court's decision meant the legal battle over extradition would likely be delayed for months more to make time for appeals.</p>

<p>An early plan to have Assange fly to New York or Washington to enter his plea was changed to Saipan because of Assange's opposition to entering the continental United States, according to an Australian government official.</p>

<p>The deal marks the end of a legal saga following WikiLeaks' mass release of secret US documents in 2010 - one of the largest security breaches in US military history.</p>

<p>As Assange was moved from Belmarsh prison to London's Stansted airport in the dead of night on Monday, the secrecy was such that his children weren't told in case they spilled details about his release, according to his wife Stella Assange.</p>

<p>In a global outpouring of support following the news, a crowdfunding campaign to raise the $520,000 owed to the Australian government for the flights had already raised almost 330,000 pounds ($418,000) by Wednesday evening.</p>

<p>"I don't think that would have happened if it hadn't been for the incredible support that there has been for Julian, and which has been building over the years, which is global, which is across all sectors, all politics," she said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/7d6e6b88_julian-assange-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anthony Albanese has claimed Julian Assange's release as a win for the country.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-music-sony-music-suno-udio-tensions-between-music-labels-and-generative-ai-reach-us-courts-5974329]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tensions Between Music Labels And Generative AI Reach US Courts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-music-sony-music-suno-udio-tensions-between-music-labels-and-generative-ai-reach-us-courts-5974329]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 16:35:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Some of the world's biggest music production companies, including Sony Music Entertainment, are suing two US-based artificial intelligence (AI) platforms Suno and Udio that generate songs based on text prompts, news agency Associated Press reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some of the world's biggest music production companies, including Sony Music Entertainment, are suing two US-based artificial intelligence (AI) platforms Suno and Udio that generate songs based on text prompts, news agency Associated Press reported.</p>

<p>The lawsuit was announced by the Recording Industry Association of America on Tuesday, stating Universal Group Recordings and Warner Records are also plaintiffs in the lawsuit. The case against Suno AI has been filed in Boston federal court, and of Udio AI in New York.</p>

<p>The case seeks damages of $150,000 per song infringement, alleging some popular songs like Mariah Carey's Christmas classic "All I Want for Christmas Is You" have been replicated by the AI music generators.</p>

<p>Suno AI came under the limelight in December last year when Microsoft partnered with it, integrating it inside Microsoft's own chatbot Copilot.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">V3 is coming in 3… <a href="https://t.co/0oLxbkKCYX">pic.twitter.com/0oLxbkKCYX</a></p>
— Suno (@suno_ai_) <a href="https://twitter.com/suno_ai_/status/1770126482762830028?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 19, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Udio AI was launched in April this year and is known for its ability to realistically emote lyrics. Both Suno and Udio's free versions offer basic features, with paid subscription unlocking advanced features, including increased number of songs generated in a day.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Today we're announcing a set of updates, starting with a new experimental feature for paid subscribers, audio uploads. You can upload an audio clip of your choice, and extend this clip either forward or backward by 32 seconds using up to 2 minutes of context.<br />
<br />
Audio uploads… <a href="https://t.co/3X62kTJGij">pic.twitter.com/3X62kTJGij</a></p>
— udio (@udiomusic) <a href="https://twitter.com/udiomusic/status/1798369297758077066?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Music artists have expressed apprehensions over AI-generated music. Over 200 artists from across genres, including Billie Elish, Nikki Minaj and Zayn Malik, signed an open letter on 1 April, asking developers, tech companies and music platforms "to cease the use of AI to infringe upon and devalue the rights of human artists." The letter expressed concern of AI-generated content flooding platforms and diluting royalty pools.</p>

<p>According to the Financial Times, Sony Music in May sent warning letters to 700 AI developers and music streaming platforms, asking them to not use data owned by Sony for training, developing or commercialising AI systems.</p>

<p>In India, AR Rehman has embraced the use of AI to produce music, using it to recreate the voice of late singers Bamba Bakya and Shahul Hameed in the song 'Thimiri Yezhuda' that released on January 26 for the movie 'Lal Salaam'. The Oscar winning singer and composer took to X (formerly Twitter) at the time to clarify that technology can be used to enhance the musical experience ethically.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We took permission from their families and sent deserving remuneration for using their voice algorithms ..technology is not a threat and a nuisance if we use it right…<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/respect?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#respect</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/nostalgia?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#nostalgia</a> ? <a href="https://t.co/X2TpRoGT3l">https://t.co/X2TpRoGT3l</a></p>
— A.R.Rahman (@arrahman) <a href="https://twitter.com/arrahman/status/1751980004206862403?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 29, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Indian Music Industry, a non-commercial body representing the interests of the likes of Sony Music (India), Saregama India Ltd, Tips, and T-Series, acknowledged the potential of AI in assisting music production, publishing a position paper authored by its president, in October last year. However, the paper advocated for a human-centric AI that respects India's rich musical traditions and safeguards creativity.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tl5eajco_music-ai_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Artists and music production companies take generative AI to US Court]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-lands-in-australia-as-a-free-man-5973852]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Julian Assange's Tight Hug For Wife As He Returns Home A Free Man]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assange-lands-in-australia-as-a-free-man-5973852]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 15:32:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange returned home to Australia to start life as a free man Wednesday after admitting he revealed US defence secrets in a deal that unlocked the door to his London prison cell.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WikiLeaks founder <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/search?searchtext=Julian-Assange">Julian Assange</a> returned home to Australia to start life as a free man Wednesday after admitting he revealed US defence secrets in a deal that unlocked the door to his London prison cell.</p>

<p>Assange landed on a chilly Canberra evening in a private jet, the final act of an international drama that led him from a five-year stretch in the high-security Belmarsh prison in Britain to a courtroom in a US Pacific island territory and, finally, home.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">JULIAN ASSANGE IS FREE!!<br />
<br />
Watch here: <a href="https://t.co/7PlI9fnSMG">https://t.co/7PlI9fnSMG</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AssangeFreed?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AssangeFreed</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/JournalismIsNotACrime?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#JournalismIsNotACrime</a> <a href="https://t.co/Kpbh63CCCB">pic.twitter.com/Kpbh63CCCB</a></p>
— Free Assange - #FreeAssange (@FreeAssangeNews) <a href="https://twitter.com/FreeAssangeNews/status/1805905965788594201?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 26, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>His white hair swept back, the Australian raised a fist as he emerged from the plane door, striding across the tarmac to give a hug to his wife Stella that lifted her off the ground, and then to embrace his father.</p>

<p>Dozens of television journalists, photographers, and reporters peered through the airport fencing to see Assange, who wore a dark suit, white shirt, and brown tie.</p>

<p>WikiLeaks said on X that it would hold a press conference in the Australian capital at 9:15 pm (1115 GMT) on Wednesday, but did not say if Assange would be present.</p>

<p>"He will be able to spend quality time with his wife Stella, and his two children, be able to walk up and down on the beach and feel the sand through his toes in winter -- that lovely chill," said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543">Assange's father, John Shipton</a>.</p>

<p>Assange's long battle with US prosecutors came to an unexpected end in the Northern Mariana Islands where a judge accepted his guilty plea on a single count of conspiracy to obtain and disseminate national defence information.</p>

<p>The remote courtroom was chosen because of the 52-year-old's unwillingness to go to the continental United States and because of its proximity to Australia.</p>

<h2><strong>'A free man'</strong>&nbsp;</h2>

<p>As part of a behind-the-scenes legal negotiation with the US Justice Department he was sentenced to the time he had already served in London -- five years and two months -- and given his liberty.</p>

<p>"You will be able to walk out of this courtroom <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wikileaks-founder-julian-assange-freed-in-us-plea-deal-hearing-5971114">a free man</a>," the judge told him.</p>

<p>Assange had published hundreds of thousands of confidential US documents on the whistleblowing website from 2010.</p>

<p>He became a hero to free speech campaigners but a villain to those who thought he endangered US security and intelligence sources.</p>

<p>"Working as a journalist, I encouraged my source to provide material that was said to be classified," Assange told the court.</p>

<p>Assange's lawyer Jen Robinson told reporters it was a "historic day" that "brings to an end 14 years of legal battles".</p>

<p>"It also brings to an end a case which has been recognised as the greatest threat to the First Amendment in the 21st century," she said.</p>

<h2><strong>'Too long'</strong></h2>

<p>Australian Prime Minster Anthony Albanese said he was "very pleased" by the outcome.</p>

<p>"Regardless of your views about his activities, and they will be varied, Mr Assange's case has dragged on for too long," he told parliament in Canberra.</p>

<p>The United Nations also hailed Assange's release, saying the case had raised human rights concerns.</p>

<p>But former US vice president Mike Pence slammed the plea deal on social media platform X as a "miscarriage of justice" that "dishonors the service and sacrifice of the men and women of our Armed Forces."</p>

<p>The US Justice Department said after the hearing that Assange was banned from returning there without permission.</p>

<p>US authorities had wanted to put Assange on trial for divulging military secrets about the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>He was indicted by a US federal grand jury in 2019 on 18 counts stemming from WikiLeaks' publication of a trove of national security documents.</p>

<p>The material he released through WikiLeaks included videos showing civilians being killed by fire from a US helicopter gunship in Iraq in 2007. The victims included a photographer and a driver from Reuters.</p>

<h2><strong>'Can't stop crying'</strong></h2>

<p>In 2019, he was arrested and held in Belmarsh prison while fighting extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>He had spent seven years in Ecuador's embassy in London to avoid being extradited to Sweden, where he faced accusations of sexual assault that were eventually dropped.</p>

<p>He met his wife Stella Assange while holed up in the embassy, and the pair married in a ceremony in London's Belmarsh prison. They have two young children.</p>

<p>"I can't stop crying," Stella, who was waiting for him in Australia, said on X.</p>

<p>"I am beyond excited," she later told reporters as she left a Canberra hotel together with Assange's father to see her husband at the airport.</p>

<p>The announcement of the plea deal came two weeks before Assange was scheduled to appear in court in Britain to appeal against a ruling that approved his extradition to the United States.</p>

<p>Washington had accused Assange under the 1917 Espionage Act and supporters warned he risked being sentenced to 175 years in prison.</p>

<p>The plea deal was not entirely unexpected. US President Joe Biden had been under growing pressure to drop the long-running case against Assange.</p>

<p>The Australian government made an official request to that effect in February and Biden said he would consider it, raising hopes among Assange supporters that his ordeal might end.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/a7hil7g8_julian-assange-with-his-wife-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Julian Assange has landed in Canberra to start life as a free man.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["My Faith Never, Ever, Ever Died": Julian Assange's Father On His Return]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/julian-assanges-father-awaits-his-arrival-in-australia-says-my-faith-never-ever-ever-died-5973543]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:50:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Julian Assange's father, John Shipton, could breathe a massive sigh of relief on Wednesday after a decade-long campaign to free his son.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Julian Assange's father, John Shipton, could breathe a massive sigh of relief on Wednesday after a decade-long campaign to free his son.</p>

<p>The WikiLeaks founder on Wednesday was released by a court on the U.S. Pacific island territory of Saipan after pleading guilty to violating U.S. espionage law.</p>

<p>Assange's family, including his father, children and wife, Stella, gathered in Australia's capital Canberra ahead of his expected evening arrival by private jet, marking the end of a long legal fight tied to WikiLeaks' release of hundreds of thousands of classified U.S. defence documents in 2010.</p>

<p>Shipton said he planned to ask his son in a low-key Australian way when he arrives: "Where have you been?"</p>

<p>"My faith has never, ever, ever died," he told Reuters in an interview at parliament.</p>

<p>"That Julian can come home to Australia and see his family regularly and do the ordinary things of life is a treasure. Life measured amongst the beauty of the ordinary is the essence of life," Shipton said.</p>

<p>He said he was "divided in two" on the deal that saw Assange plead guilty to one charge of espionage, saying his release meant he would have precious time with his sons.</p>

<p>He was nonetheless concerned about the "political and legal circumstances surrounding it".</p>

<p>"I think it is going to be a problem for journalists and publishers anywhere in the world to publish criticism of the United States government," he said.</p>

<p>Assange's release was cause for celebration in Canberra, where politicians who had campaigned for Assange gathered around Shipton in a hall outside the parliament chamber.</p>

<p>"We want to give you a hug," said lawmaker Sophie Scamps.</p>

<p>Assange will need time to recover from his "monastic life" in self-exile in the Ecuadorian embassy in London for seven years, and then prison for five years, Shipton said.</p>

<p>He looked forward to being involved in his son's "practical everyday human life, not the sweep of politics."</p>

<p>"The American Secret Service in 2011 published their review saying we must hound him and his family to the end of the earth and bankrupt them. Its been expensive but I've got no complaints - the results are there for everyone to see," he said.</p>

<p>He said the Australian government had been "nothing short of magnificent".</p>

<p>Assange has previously said he got his "rebel gene" from his father. Shipton said he considers his son to be personally conservative and polite.</p>

<p>"It is his understanding of the capacity of the internet to bring to us information that can be the foundation of knowledge that is revolutionary," he said.</p>

<p>"He is only 52 I imagine he will find something to do. He will be 53 next week. The momentum he has got ... he will conjure forth those things that he can do."</p>

<p>Shipton said the family had devoted the last decade to doing everything in its capacity to see Assange free.</p>

<p>"We Australians managed to turn around a superpower in its attempt to destroy an Australian citizen," he said.</p>

<p>Shipton learned of the plea deal from his son Gabriel.</p>

<p>Gabriel told Reuters on Wednesday he was "feeling extremely relieved that this ordeal is finally over and that Julian can move on with his life."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tn6a32q_assange-father-reuters-_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The WikiLeaks founder on Wednesday was released by a court]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyas-anti-tax-protests-turn-deadly-13-killed-military-deployed-5973443]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[13 Killed In Kenya's Anti-Tax Protests, Military Deployed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kenyas-anti-tax-protests-turn-deadly-13-killed-military-deployed-5973443]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:32:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The death count from protests in Kenya has climbed to 13, an official from the main doctors' association told AFP Wednesday, after anti-tax hike rallies turned violent and police opened fire at demonstrators who ransacked parliament.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The death count from protests in Kenya has climbed to 13, an official from the main doctors' association told AFP Wednesday, after anti-tax hike rallies turned violent and police opened fire at demonstrators who ransacked parliament.</p>

<p>The unprecedented scenes that left parts of parliament ablaze and destroyed and injured scores of people on Tuesday have shocked Kenyans and prompted President William Ruto's government to deploy the military.</p>

<p>The mainly youth-led rallies began mostly peacefully last week, with thousands of demonstrators marching in the capital Nairobi, and across the country against the tax increases.</p>

<p>But tensions flared sharply on Tuesday afternoon, as police officers fired live rounds on crowds that later ransacked the parliament complex.</p>

<p>Hours later, Defence Minister Aden Bare Duale announced that the government had deployed the army to support the police in tackling "the security emergency" in the country.</p>

<p>"So far, we have at least 13 people killed, but this is not the final number," Simon Kigondu, president of the Kenya Medical Association said, adding that he had never seen "such level of violence against unarmed people."</p>

<p>"Deaths, mayhem", read the front-page headline on the Standard newspaper, while the Daily Nation described the situation as "Pandemonium", saying: "The foundations of the country have been shaken to the core."</p>

<p>An official at Kenyatta National Hospital in Nairobi said Wednesday that medics were treating "160 people... some of them with soft tissue injuries, some of them with bullet wounds".</p>

<p>In a late-night press briefing, Ruto warned that his government would take a tough line against "violence and anarchy", likening some of the demonstrators to "criminals".</p>

<p>"It is not in order or even conceivable that criminals pretending to be peaceful protesters can reign terror against the people, their elected representatives, and the institutions established under our constitution and expect to go scot-free," he said.</p>

<p>The government has been taken by surprise by the intensity of opposition to its tax proposals -- mostly led by young, Gen-Z Kenyans -- which culminated in the scenes at parliament that played out live on television.</p>

<p>Images shared on local TV stations after crowds broke through the barricades showed the building ransacked, with burnt furniture and smashed windows.</p>

<p>As police fired at the angry crowds, leaving several bodies strewn on the ground, protest organisers urged people to walk home together and "stay safe".</p>

<h3><strong>'Madness'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>A heavy police presence was deployed around parliament early on Wednesday, according to an AFP reporter, the smell of tear gas still in the air.</p>

<p>A policeman standing in front of the broken barricades to the complex told AFP he had watched the scenes unfold on TV.</p>

<p>"It was madness, we hope it will be calm today," he said.</p>

<p>Earlier on Tuesday, the rallies in various Kenyan cities had been largely peaceful.</p>

<p>However, tensions escalated in Nairobi later in the day, with some protesters hurling stones at police, who deployed tear gas and water cannons before firing live bullets.</p>

<p>AFP journalists saw three people bleeding heavily and lying motionless on the ground near parliament.</p>

<h3><strong>'Brute force'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The unrest has alarmed the international community, with the White House appealing for calm and more than 10 Western nations -- including Canada, Germany, and Britain -- saying they were "especially shocked by the scenes witnessed outside the Kenyan Parliament".</p>

<p>UN chief Antonio Guterres and the head of the African Union Commission, Moussa Faki Mahamat, have also expressed deep concern.</p>

<p>Veteran opposition leader Raila Odinga, who heads the Azimio coalition, accused the government of unleashing "brute force on our country's children".</p>

<p>Rights watchdogs have also accused the authorities of abducting protesters.</p>

<p>The police have not responded to any AFP requests for comment.</p>

<h3><strong>Cost of living&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>Long-running grievances over the rising cost of living spiraled last week as lawmakers began debating proposed tax hikes in the 2024 finance bill.</p>

<p>The cash-strapped government says the increases are needed to service the country's massive debt of some 10 trillion shillings ($78 billion), equal to roughly 70 percent of Kenya's GDP.</p>

<p>After rolling back some of the more controversial proposals -- which would have affected bread purchases, car ownership, and financial and mobile services -- the government now intends to increase fuel prices and export duties.</p>

<p>Kenya's treasury has warned of a gaping budget shortfall of 200 billion shillings, following Ruto's decision to roll back some of the tax hikes.</p>

<p>While Kenya is among East Africa's most dynamic economies, a third of its 52 million population live in poverty.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/lea5bi88_kenya-protest_625x300_21_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions flared sharply on Tuesday afternoon, as police officers fired live rounds on crowds]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-appoints-dutch-pm-mark-rutte-as-new-secretary-general-5973417]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NATO Appoints Dutch PM Mark Rutte As New Secretary General]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nato-appoints-dutch-pm-mark-rutte-as-new-secretary-general-5973417]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:30:17 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[NATO allies on Wednesday selected Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as NATO's next boss, as the war in Ukraine rages on its doorstep and uncertainty hangs over the United States' future attitude to the transatlantic alliance.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NATO allies on Wednesday selected Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as NATO's next boss, as the war in Ukraine rages on its doorstep and uncertainty hangs over the United States' future attitude to the transatlantic alliance.</p>

<p>Rutte's appointment became a formality after his only rival for the post, Romanian President Klaus Iohannis, announced last week that he had quit the race, having failed to gain traction.</p>

<p>"The North Atlantic Council decided to appoint Dutch Prime Minister Mark Rutte as the next Secretary General of NATO, succeeding Jens Stoltenberg," NATO said in a statement.</p>

<p>"Mr Rutte will assume his functions as Secretary General from 1 October 2024, when Mr Stoltenberg's term expires after ten years at the helm of the Alliance," it added.</p>

<p>After declaring his interest in the post last year, Rutte gained early support from key members of the alliance including the United States, Britain, France and Germany.</p>

<p>Others were more reticent, particularly Eastern European countries which argued the post should go to someone from their region for the first time.</p>

<p>But they ultimately rowed in behind Rutte, a fierce critic of Russian President Vladimir Putin and a staunch ally of Ukraine.</p>

<p>Stoltenberg said he warmly welcomed the selection of Rutte as his successor.</p>

<p>"Mark is a true transatlanticist, a strong leader, and a consensus-builder," he said. "I know I am leaving NATO in good hands."</p>

<p>NATO takes decisions by consensus so Rutte, who is bowing out of Dutch politics after nearly 14 years as prime minister, could only be confirmed once all 32 alliance members gave him their backing.</p>

<p>Rutte will face the challenge of sustaining allies' support for Ukraine's fight against Russia's invasion while guarding against NATO's being drawn directly into a war with Moscow.</p>

<p>He will also have to contend with the possibility that NATO-sceptic Donald Trump may return to the White House after November's U.S. presidential election.</p>

<p>Trump's possible return has unnerved NATO leaders as the Republican former president called into question the U.S. willingness to support other members of the alliance if they were attacked.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/vs3p8h9g_dutch-pm-mark-rutte-reuters_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rutte's appointment comes after his only rival for the post, Romanian President Klaus Iohannis, quit.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-family-seeks-compensation-from-nasa-after-space-junk-destroys-home-5973158]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Family Seeks Compensation From NASA After Space Junk Destroys Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-family-seeks-compensation-from-nasa-after-space-junk-destroys-home-5973158]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:53:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A US family whose home was hit by space debris earlier this year is seeking compensation from the American space agency NASA for property damage and mental anguish.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A US family whose home was hit by space debris earlier this year is seeking compensation from the American space agency NASA for property damage and mental anguish. The metallic cylinder slab punched a hole in the roof through two layers of ceiling in Alejandro Otero's home in Naples in March. Back then, NASA said that the object was part of a 2.9-ton pallet of used batteries jettisoned from the International Space Station in March 2021. Mr Otero said his son was nearly injured by the impact.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now, law firm Cranfill Summer said in a press release that it filed a claim on behalf of Mr Otero and his family. It listed damages including non-insured property damage loss, business interruption, emotional/mental anguish and the costs for assistance from third parties.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9www02e49zo"><em>BBC</em></a>, Attorney Mica Nguyen Worthy said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-confirms-object-that-destroyed-florida-home-was-space-junk-5452204">space debris </a>"is a real serious issue because of the increase in space traffic in recent years". "My clients are seeking adequate compensation to account for the stress and impact that this event had on their lives," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Separately, speaking to <em>CBS</em> affiliate <em>Wink-TV </em>Mr Otero said that the space junk created a tremendous sound" as it blasted into his home. "I was shaking. I was completely in disbelief. What are the chances of something landing on my house with such force to cause so much damage," Mr Otero said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/science/nasa-shares-stunning-pic-of-rare-gigantic-jets-spotted-over-himalayas-5971658">NASA Shares Stunning Pic Of Rare "Gigantic Jets" Spotted Over Himalayas</a></strong></p>

<p>The US space agency confirmed that the debris was from its flight support equipment. It was a metal support used to hold old batteries on a disposal pallet jettisoned from the station in 2021. While most of the pallet was expected to burn up in the atmosphere, this particular piece survived the fiery re-entry.</p>

<p>&nbsp;"The hardware was expected to fully burn up during entry through Earth's atmosphere on March 8, 2024. However, a piece of hardware survived and impacted a home in Naples, Florida," the agency said. The ISS will "perform a detailed investigation" on how the debris survived burn-up, according to Nasa.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>The BBC</em> reported that the agency now has 6 months to respond to Mr Otero's claims.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/dtgu3318_space-object_625x300_16_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[NASA has 6 months to respond to Mr Otero's claims.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-missile-explodes-midair-after-launch-says-s-korea-military-5972990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Missile Explodes Midair After Launch, Claims S Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-missile-explodes-midair-after-launch-says-s-korea-military-5972990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:27:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile off its east coast on Wednesday, but it exploded in midair, South Korea's military said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea test-fired what appeared to be a hypersonic missile off its east coast on Wednesday, but it exploded in midair, South Korea's military said.</p>

<p>The missile was launched from near the capital, Pyongyang, South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff said. Japan's Defence Ministry said the missile flew to an altitude of about 100 km (62 miles) and a range of more than 200 km.</p>

<p>Senior officials of South Korea, the United States and Japan held a phone call and condemned the launch as a violation of multiple U.N. Security Council resolutions and a serious threat to the peace and stability of the region and beyond.</p>

<p>South Korea's marine corps said its troops staged firing drills near the maritime border with the North for the first time since Seoul scrapped an inter-Korean military pact early this month. The drills were announced earlier in June.</p>

<p>U.S. Indo-Pacific Command also issued a condemnation and called on Pyongyang to refrain from further unlawful and destabilising acts.</p>

<p>"While we have assessed that this event does not pose an immediate threat to U.S. personnel, or territory, or to our allies, we continue to monitor the situation," it said in a statement.</p>

<p>North Korea's last missile launch was on May 30.</p>

<p>North Korea this week criticised the deployment of a U.S. aircraft carrier to joint drills with South Korea and Japan, and warned of an "overwhelming, new demonstration of deterrence".</p>

<p>The missile launch comes a day after the 74-year anniversary of the beginning of the Korean War.</p>

<p>Last week, North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and Russian President Vladimir Putin held a summit and signed a mutual defence pact. Seoul, Washington and Tokyo criticised the two countries' deepening military cooperation, with South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol calling the pact "anachronistic".</p>

<p>North Korean state media KCNA said on Wednesday a mass rally in Pyongyang was held to commemorate the war anniversary, calling it a day of "struggle against U.S. imperialism" and calling the United States the archenemy.</p>

<p>Recently, North Korea has flown hundreds of balloons carrying trash toward the South, including on Tuesday, while Pyongyang deployed a large group of soldiers to build new fortifications within the heavily armed border between the two Koreas, according to the South's military, occasionally drawing warning shots from South Korean counterparts.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hnfrjjs_north-korea-hyperonic-missile-launch-afp_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korea's hypersonic missile seems to have exploded midair.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-crew-union-strikes-deal-with-major-studios-pay-hikes-and-ai-safeguards-5972924]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hollywood Crew Union Strikes Deal With Major Studios On Pay Raise, AI Use]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hollywood-crew-union-strikes-deal-with-major-studios-pay-hikes-and-ai-safeguards-5972924]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:17:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A union representing Hollywood film and television crew said on Tuesday it has reached a tentative three-year deal with major studios that includes agreed-on pay hikes and guardrails against the use of artificial intelligence (AI).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A union representing Hollywood film and television crew said on Tuesday it has reached a tentative three-year deal with major studios that includes agreed-on pay hikes and guardrails against the use of artificial intelligence (AI).</p>

<p>The International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) members, which include lighting technicians and costume designers, are to ratify the deal with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers (AMPTP), which represents Disney, Netflix, and others.</p>

<p>The terms of the agreement include scale-rate increases of 7%, 4%, and 3.5% over the three-year term, the union said.</p>

<p>On the AI front, the deal includes "language that ensures no employee is required to provide Al prompts in any manner that would result in the displacement of any covered employee."</p>

<p>In late 2023, the SAG-AFTRA actors union and the studios reached a labor agreement which ended a near six-month dispute that had halted film and TV production.</p>

<p>That contract also provided for pay raises and streaming bonuses that union leaders said amounted to more than $1 billion over three years, and also included protection around the use of AI in filmmaking.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/b217rvgg_hollywood_625x300_26_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[IATSE members are to ratify the deal with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-florida-online-gaming-feud-turns-violent-as-man-attacks-rival-with-hammer-5972791]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[New Jersey Gamer Flies To Florida To Attack Online Rival With Hammer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-florida-online-gaming-feud-turns-violent-as-man-attacks-rival-with-hammer-5972791]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:55:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Edward Kang faces serious charges, including attempted second-degree murder and armed burglary with a mask.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An online gaming rivalry turned violent when a 20-year-old man travelled from New Jersey to Florida and assaulted another player with a hammer. Despite never having met in person, Edward Kang reached Fernandina Beach on Sunday and allegedly attacked the victim, the police said.</p>

<p>Kang now faces serious charges, including attempted second-degree murder and armed burglary with a mask, according to court records from Nassau County.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In a press conference, Nassau County Sheriff Bill Leeper said that Kang and the victim - also around the same age - played ArcheAge, a mediaeval fantasy multiplayer online role-playing game. The Sheriff called the case a “weird one.”</p>

<p>“Some things you just can't make up,” he added.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aLf32Et9L1A?si=0q46pQgVxBkQNTjV" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe><br />
<br />
Kang flew from New Jersey to Florida, telling his mom he was visiting a friend he met online, reported authorities. After landing, Kang purchased a hammer from a local hardware store before heading to the victim's house, which was reportedly left unlocked.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Kang confronted the victim inside the home around 2 am and hit him on the head with the hammer. The victim suffered multiple head wounds but managed to call for help. As the victim struggled with Kang, his stepfather intervened and helped restrain the attacker until police arrived at the scene.<br />
<br />
The victim survived the assault and received medical treatment for his injuries, described as serious but not life-threatening, reported ABC News.<br />
<br />
In custody, Kang called the victim a "bad person online". He asked deputies how much jail time he would get for breaking and assault. An official replied, "It's going to be long before you play video games again."<br />
<br />
Kang is being held without bond and does not have an attorney listed.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6itt21co_us-gamer_625x300_26_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Edward Kang attacked his opponent after losing in a mediaeval fantasy multiplayer online game]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>