<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 09:30:15 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-joe-biden-is-ignoring-fellow-democrats-calls-to-leave-race-6087324]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: Why Biden Is Ignoring Fellow Democrats' Calls To Leave Race]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-joe-biden-is-ignoring-fellow-democrats-calls-to-leave-race-6087324]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 06:56:39 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shortly after President Joe Biden's halting debate with Donald Trump on June 27, his exit from the 2024 U.S. presidential race seemed all but inevitable to some longtime allies.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after President Joe Biden's halting debate with Donald Trump on June 27, his exit from the 2024 U.S. presidential race seemed all but inevitable to some longtime allies.</p>

<p>Donors called it a disaster and held frantic calls to discuss next steps. Newspaper columnists demanded he bow out. Some Democratic lawmakers said plainly their party leader must step aside.</p>

<p>Two weeks later, Biden hasn't budged.</p>

<p>While acknowledging that at 81, he is no longer a young man and blaming exhaustion for his performance, he failed in a defiant follow-up televised interview to quell concerns it was more than just one bad debate night.</p>

<p>More Democrats are expected to ask Biden to leave the race in coming days. For now, the White House says it plans to "turn the page" on the incident, despite some opinion polls showing Trump's lead widening and swing states leaning Republican.</p>

<p>Why is Biden ignoring fellow Democrats and insisting he will beat Trump, 78, in the Nov. 5 election?</p>

<p>The reasons range from the deeply personal to party politics, interviews with more Democratic officials, aides, strategists and donors show.</p>

<p><strong>BIDEN BELIEVES IN BIDEN</strong></p>

<p>Biden's decision to run for reelection in the first place, despite his age, centered around his belief that he was the best Democratic candidate to defeat Trump, officials and allies told Reuters at the time.</p>

<p>Biden was skeptical about the ability of his vice president, Kamala Harris, to win over middle-of-the road voters, especially in critical swing states, and also of the ability of any of the deep bench of Democratic governors and lawmakers who are likely to be the party's future leaders, these sources said.</p>

<p>Explaining his decision to stay the course, Biden told George Stephanopoulos of ABC News last week: "I'm the most qualified person to beat him (Trump)." He later added that only the "Lord almighty" could convince him differently.</p>

<p>A defining principle of Biden's grief-stricken personal life and long political career has been perseverance, which he says he learned from his parents.</p>

<p>"My dad, who fell on hard times, always told me, though, 'Champ, when you get knocked down, get up. Get up," he told the 2008 Democratic National Convention when he accepted the nomination as Barack Obama's running mate.</p>

<p>He said his mother taught him: "Failure at some point in your life is inevitable, but giving up is unforgivable."</p>

<p>Actor George Clooney echoed the concerns of many Democrats about this principle, writing in a New York Times opinion piece on Wednesday that it was time for Biden to leave the race. Clooney said that "the one battle he cannot win is the fight against time. None of us can."</p>

<p><strong>BIDEN'S CLOSEST AIDES ARE DUG IN</strong></p>

<p>Biden's inner circle of top aides has reinforced his determination to hold on, according to sources close to them.</p>

<p>Biden has surrounded himself for decades with a small cadre of senior aides, such as political adviser Mike Donilon, counselor Steve Ricchetti, and deputy chief of staff Bruce Reed, who have steered him through previous crises and urged him to hang on.</p>

<p>That dynamic has only been amplified since the fallout from the debate.</p>

<p>"I have heard that Steve and Bruce and Mike are more dug in than he is," said one former Biden aide with ties to the White House. "They have grown roots and are not moving."</p>

<p>A White House official confirmed that characterization and said the dug-in approach applied to Biden's full senior staff.</p>

<p>Many of his aides, including senior adviser Anita Dunn, reinforce a sense of grievance and resolve around Biden: that he has been treated unfairly by the media, that he does not get the credit he deserves for toppling Trump in 2020, and that he has been underestimated before and proven his critics wrong.</p>

<p>Many people in Biden's orbit feel that way, the White House official said.</p>

<p>A memo circulated on Thursday by Jen O'Malley Dillon and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, Biden's campaign chair and manager, respectively, said there was no better alternative to Biden.</p>

<p>"Surveys do not take into account the negative media environment that any Democratic nominee will encounter. The only Democratic candidate for whom this is already baked in is President Biden," they wrote.</p>

<p><strong>SOME DEMOCRATS FEAR CHANCES WITH HARRIS</strong></p>

<p>Biden's ability to beat back Democratic calls for him to exit the race may have less to do with his own candidacy than the lackluster feeling some Democrats have about the potential alternatives to replace him.</p>

<p>In interviews, about a dozen Democrats, including elected officials and activists, many of them in the battleground state of Pennsylvania, all expressed deep concerns about Biden's mental fitness and ability to beat Trump.</p>

<p>But they also had little trust in a bench of Democrats led by Harris.</p>

<p>If Biden were to step down, they believe the party could not bypass Harris – the nation's first Black vice president and first woman vice president – without risking the diverse coalition needed to win the White House.</p>

<p>"It has to be Harris and I don't think that puts us in a better position to win than with a hobbled Joe Biden," said one senior Democrat in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>On the other hand, some Democrats say Harris could bring new enthusiasm to the party and reenergize youth and Black voters.</p>

<p><strong>CONGRESS FEARS AND TRADITIONS</strong></p>

<p>Soon after Biden's debate, the leaders of both the Congressional Black Caucus and the Congressional Hispanic Caucus issued statements of support for Biden, which appeared to slow the trickle of criticism.</p>

<p>With their endorsement, rank-and-file Democrats were hard-pressed this week to publicly abandon Biden.</p>

<p>As of Thursday, only 11 of the 213 Democrats in the House of Representatives and one of the Senate's 51 Democrats had appealed to the president to withdraw from the race.</p>

<p>But multiple House members said they believed there was more to come, noting that they were expecting Democratic Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries to pass on the criticisms from within the party to Biden.</p>

<p>"I wish more people were less scared," said Democratic Representative Seth Moulton, one of the House members who have called for Biden to end his campaign.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden has been facing pressure to drop out of the presidential race since his debate against Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hed-still-be-able-to-deal-with-vladimir-putin-xi-jinping-in-3-years-6087166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Says He'd Still Be Able To "Deal" With Putin, Xi Jinping In 3 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/joe-biden-says-hed-still-be-able-to-deal-with-vladimir-putin-xi-jinping-in-3-years-6087166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 06:06:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Russian leader Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping well into a second term as he faced questions over his advancing years and fitness for office.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Russian leader Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping well into a second term as he faced questions over his advancing years and fitness for office.</p>

<p>"I'm ready to deal with them now and three years from now... there isn't any world leader that I'm not prepared to deal with," he told reporters at the White House.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/opt29ctk_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden said Thursday he would still be ready to deal with Vladimir Putin and China's Xi Jinping.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Great Job Joe": Trump Mocks Biden Gaffes In Middle Of NATO Press Meet]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/great-job-joe-donald-trump-mocks-joe-biden-gaffes-in-middle-of-nato-press-meet-6087136]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:54:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden while the US president, who is under huge pressure due to concerns over his mental fitness, made verbal slips during a high-stakes press conference.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden while the US president, who is under huge pressure due to concerns over his mental fitness, made verbal slips during a high-stakes press conference.</p>

<p>"Crooked Joe begins his 'Big Boy' Press Conference with, 'I wouldn't have picked Vice President Trump to be vice president... Great job, Joe!" Trump said on his Truth Social site.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/tif74i68_donald-trump-reuters_625x300_23_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Donald Trump on Thursday mocked Joe Biden after he made verbal slips during a press conference.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-putin-gaffe-joe-biden-calls-kamala-harris-vice-president-trump-at-nato-press-meet-6087106]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden calls Kamala Harris "Vice President Trump" At NATO Press Conference]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-putin-gaffe-joe-biden-calls-kamala-harris-vice-president-trump-at-nato-press-meet-6087106]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:43:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden, under intense scrutiny over his mental fitness to serve, mistakenly referred to his Vice President Kamala Harris on Thursday as "Vice President Trump."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden, under intense scrutiny over his mental fitness to serve, mistakenly referred to his Vice President Kamala Harris on Thursday as "Vice President Trump."</p>

<p>Biden, asked whether Harris could beat Donald Trump if he decided not to run again, said: "I wouldn't have picked Vice President Trump to be vice president if I did not think she was not qualified to be president."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/tk0vd5k4_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden holds news conference at the 2024 NATO summit on Thursday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-the-most-qualified-person-to-run-for-president-biden-at-key-press-meet-6087049]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA['I'M The Most Qualified Person To Run For President", Says Biden]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/im-the-most-qualified-person-to-run-for-president-biden-at-key-press-meet-6087049]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 05:30:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was the "most qualified" American to take on Donald Trump in November's presidential election as he faced growing calls from within his own party to step down.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden said Thursday he was the "most qualified" American to take on Donald Trump in November's presidential election as he faced growing calls from within his own party to step down.</p>

<p>"I think I'm the most qualified person to run for president. I beat him once, and I will beat him again," Biden said, adding that he is "not in this for my legacy" but to "complete the job I started."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/id1lgo5k_joe-biden-nato-press-meet_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Joe Biden said that he will beat Donald Trump again in Presidential elections.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emmanuel-macron-says-france-will-continue-to-support-ukraine-as-long-as-necessary-6086962]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Macron Says France Will Continue To Support Ukraine "As Long As Necessary"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/emmanuel-macron-says-france-will-continue-to-support-ukraine-as-long-as-necessary-6086962]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 04:56:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden was "in charge" and on top of matters at a NATO summit with fellow leaders in Washington, French President Emmanuel Macron said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden was "in charge" and on top of matters at a NATO summit with fellow leaders in Washington, French President Emmanuel Macron said Thursday.</p>

<p>"I was able to talk with President Biden at length yesterday at dinner," Macron told reporters. "I saw as always a president who is in charge, clear on the issues he knows well."</p>

<p>The French leader was also asked about a gaffe made by Biden just minutes earlier when he mistakenly introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian foe Vladimir Putin, before quickly correcting himself.</p>

<p>The blunder intensified concerns about Biden's age and mental acuity after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump two weeks ago.</p>

<p>"We all slip up sometimes," Macron said. "It's happened to me and it could happen again tomorrow. I would ask for your indulgence."</p>

<p>Macron also said that France will continue to support Ukraine "as long as necessary."</p>

<p>Asked about recent visits to Russia and China by Viktor Orban, Macron said the Hungarian prime minister did not go there with any "mandate" from the EU.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2c802dbc_macron-nato-summit_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Macron said that France will continue to support Ukraine "as long as necessary."]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-campaign-quietly-tests-kamala-harris-against-donald-trump-report-6086890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Biden Campaign Quietly Tests Kamala Harris Against Trump: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-president-joe-biden-campaign-quietly-tests-kamala-harris-against-donald-trump-report-6086890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 04:30:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[As President Joe Biden faces mounting pressure over the future of his candidacy, his campaign is quietly testing Vice President Kamala Harris's viability against former President Donald Trump through a voter survey, New York Times reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As President Joe Biden faces mounting pressure over the future of his candidacy, his campaign is quietly testing Vice President Kamala Harris's viability against former President Donald Trump through a voter survey, New York Times reported</p>

<p>This evaluation, shared anonymously due to its sensitive nature, occurs amid increasing pressure on Biden to reconsider his re-election bid.</p>

<p>Some of Biden's long-standing advisers are reportedly considering ways to convince him to withdraw from the race, as per New York Times.</p>

<p>Many Democrats were left deeply troubled by Biden's disastrous debate performance two weeks ago, and he has faced increasing calls from lawmakers and fund-raisers to step aside.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Democratic leaders challenged Joe Biden to provide convincing evidence of a viable path to reelection after his debate performance, bad battleground state polling and growing concerns that he cannot defeat former Donald Trump in the presidential elections</p>

<p>After the CNN debate with former US President Donald Trump on June 28, the leaders have been pushing Biden to step down from the presidential race despite this he has declared that he is staying and expressed confidence that he would defeat former Trump.</p>

<p>Recently, Biden told congressional Democrats in a letter on July 9 that he would continue his election bid despite mounting concerns about his mental fitness.</p>

<p>Further, he also stated that he will be "running this race to end" of the November election, despite private calls from Democrats to drop out. In the letter, Biden called for unity among his party, emphasising the need for a collective effort to defeat former President Donald Trump in the upcoming election.</p>

<p>"Any weakening of resolve or lack of clarity about the task ahead only helps Trump and hurts us. It's time to come together, move forward as a unified party, and defeat Donald Trump," said Biden</p>

<p>On July 8, a leadership call was organised by House Minority Leader Hakeem Jeffries, where several top House Democrats urged President Joe Biden to step aside from the 2024 campaign, expressing deep concerns about his potential impact on the Democratic Party's chances in the upcoming elections.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-11/jhmacdl_kamala-harris-afp_625x300_19_November_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Biden's campaign is quietly testing Vice President Kamala Harris's viability against Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-introduces-zelensky-as-putin-at-nato-press-meet-corrects-himself-6086831]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Watch: Biden Introduces Zelensky As "President Putin" In Another Gaffe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/biden-introduces-zelensky-as-putin-at-nato-press-meet-corrects-himself-6086831]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 04:15:06 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[U.S. President Joe Biden on Thursday mistakenly referred to Ukrainian President Volodymr Zelenskiy as "President Putin" before correcting himself at the NATO summit in Washington.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US President Joe Biden mistakenly introduced Ukraine's President Volodymyr Zelensky as his Russian foe Vladimir Putin at a NATO summit Thursday in a blunder just hours before a press conference that could decide the fate of his reelection bid.</p>

<p>The 81-year-old quickly corrected himself, and Zelensky quipped that he was "better" than Putin, but the gaffe intensified concerns about Biden's mental acuity after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump two weeks ago.</p>

<p>"And now I want to hand it over to the president of Ukraine, who has as much courage as he has determination, ladies and gentlemen, President Putin," Biden said as he announced a NATO-Ukraine compact at the summit in Washington.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">BIDEN: "Ladies and gentlemen, President Putin" ? <a href="https://t.co/pId2QZ3Ao0">pic.twitter.com/pId2QZ3Ao0</a></p>
— RNC Research (@RNCResearch) <a href="https://twitter.com/RNCResearch/status/1811517532194435122?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Biden turned away from the lectern before coming back and exclaiming: "President Putin! He's going to beat President Putin. President Zelensky -- I'm so focused on beating Putin we gotta worry about it. Anyway, Mr President."</p>

<p>The error drew gasps from the room but Zelensky, Ukraine's wartime leader against Russia's 2022 invasion, laughed it off.</p>

<p>Fellow leaders at the summit have fielded questions about Biden, and their answers have largely been supportive.</p>

<p>"Slips of the tongue happen, and if you keep a close enough eye on everyone, you will find enough," German Chancellor Olaf Scholz said after the president's latest gaffe.</p>

<p>French President Emmanuel Macron said Biden had appeared "in charge," while British Prime Minister Keir Starmer said he "was on good form."</p>

<p>But his latest verbal slip could not have come at a worse time as Biden is due&nbsp; later Thursday to give what the White House has called a "big boy" press conference, his first major appearance since the debate.</p>

<p>The solo appearance, a rare unscripted encounter with reporters, comes amid growing calls in his Democratic Party for him to step aside.</p>

<p>The press conference was due to start at 6:30 pm (2230 GMT) but is expected to run around an hour late.</p>

<p>- Growing pressure -</p>

<p>There has been a steady drumbeat of Democrats calling for Biden to abandon his 2024 candidacy.</p>

<p>Hollywood actor and well-connected Democratic supporter George Clooney called on Biden to exit the race, and party grandee Nancy Pelosi has stopped short of fully backing him.</p>

<p>Around 14 Democratic members of the House of Representatives have openly urged the man who beat Trump four years ago to drop out, along with one Democratic senator.</p>

<p>A poll released on Thursday showed more than half of Democrats say Biden should end his bid for a second term, and two-thirds of Americans believe he should quit the race.</p>

<p>But the former president and the incumbent remain in a dead heat on 46 percent, according to the Washington Post-ABC News-Ipsos survey.</p>

<p>Biden's campaign was however quietly testing the strength of Vice President Kamala Harris in a potential match-up against Trump, The New York Times reported.</p>

<p>Some of the president's longtime aides are meanwhile discussing how to persuade him that he should step aside, the paper also said, citing anonymous sources.</p>

<p>The White House said the report was "unequivocally" false.</p>

<p>The once-talkative Biden has given fewer news conferences than his predecessors, and recent ones have only been with foreign leaders, restricted to two questions each.</p>

<p>Coupled with a lack of interviews, it has led critics to accuse the White House of shielding the effects of age on America's oldest president.</p>

<p>Biden has called his debate meltdown a "bad night," blaming it on a cold and jet lag.</p>

<p>But Clooney tried to torpedo the narrative that it was a one-off, saying it was "devastating" to admit but the signs were also clear at a June 15 fundraiser in Los Angeles he hosted.</p>

<p>Biden has insisted he is committed to running in November, and with the Democratic party primary votes under his belt there is no real way of forcing him out.</p>

<p>His campaign fought back Thursday with a new ad campaign on the last day of the NATO summit portraying Trump as a "lap dog" of Putin.</p>

<p>NATO allies have also been seeking reassurance about Biden's leadership abilities and over their fears that a return of the isolationist, Putin-praising Trump could spell trouble for the alliance.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/9aqp0cnk_biden_625x300_12_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Ladies and gentlemen, President Putin," Biden said, referring to Zelenskiy before correcting himself.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-still-kills-1-700-a-week-around-world-who-6086548]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Covid Still Kills 1,700 A Week Around World: WHO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-still-kills-1-700-a-week-around-world-who-6086548]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 02:30:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Covid-19 is still killing around 1,700 people a week around the world, the World Health Organization said Thursday, as it urged at-risk populations to keep up with their vaccinations against the disease.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Covid-19 is still killing around 1,700 people a week around the world, the World Health Organization said Thursday, as it urged at-risk populations to keep up with their vaccinations against the disease.</p>

<p>WHO director-general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus sounded a warning on declining vaccine coverage.</p>

<p>Despite the continued death count, "data show that vaccine coverage has declined among health workers and people over 60, which are two of the most at-risk groups," the UN health agency's chief told a press conference.</p>

<p>"WHO recommends that people in the highest-risk groups receive a Covid-19 vaccine within 12 months of their last dose."</p>

<p>More than seven million Covid deaths have been reported to the WHO, though the true count of the pandemic is thought to be far higher.</p>

<p>Covid-19 also shredded economies and crippled health systems.</p>

<p>Tedros declared an end to Covid-19 as an international public health emergency in May 2023, more than three years on from when the virus was first detected in Wuhan, China, in late 2019.</p>

<p>The WHO has urged governments to maintain virus surveillance and sequencing, and to ensure access to affordable and reliable tests, treatments and vaccines.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-05/kq6omf8_covid19-swab-sticks-generic_625x300_06_May_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[WHO director-general Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus sounded a warning on declining vaccine coverage.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-us-missiles-in-germany-signal-cold-war-6086361]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Says US Missiles In Germany Signal Cold War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-says-us-missiles-in-germany-signal-cold-war-6086361]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 01:36:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States' plan to periodically station long-range missiles in Germany will lead to Cold War-style confrontation between Russia and the West, the Kremlin said Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States' plan to periodically station long-range missiles in Germany will lead to Cold War-style confrontation between Russia and the West, the Kremlin said Thursday.</p>

<p>The White House announced the decision on Wednesday during a NATO summit in Washington, arguing the stationing of long-range weapons including Tomahawk cruise missiles in Europe acts as a deterrent.</p>

<p>"We are taking steady steps towards the Cold War," Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told a state TV reporter.</p>

<p>"All the attributes of the Cold War with the direct confrontation are returning," he said.</p>

<p>He added Washington's decision gave Russia "a reason to pull together" and "fulfil all the goals" of its military campaign in Ukraine.</p>

<p>NATO countries spearheaded by the United States have bolstered their defences in Europe in the wake of Russia's 2022 offensive against neighbouring Ukraine.</p>

<p>German Chancellor Olaf Scholz hailed the planned deployment of the US weapons in his country, calling the move a "necessary and important decision at the right time".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/gd3cjdk8_putin_625x300_09_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia said that Washington's decision gave ussia "a reason to pull together".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-confident-ukraine-will-one-day-enter-nato-6086194]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Zelensky "Confident" Ukraine Will One Day Enter NATO]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/zelensky-confident-ukraine-will-one-day-enter-nato-6086194]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:37:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[President Volodymyr Zelensky said Thursday he was confident Ukraine would eventually join NATO after the alliance said the Russian-invaded country had an "irreversible" path to membership.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Volodymyr Zelensky said Thursday he was confident Ukraine would eventually join NATO after the alliance said the Russian-invaded country had an "irreversible" path to membership.</p>

<p>"We have strong wording regarding the irreversibility of Ukraine's movement towards NATO. Every step truly brings us closer to membership," Zelensky told a news conference at a NATO summit alongside the alliance's chief Jens Stoltenberg.</p>

<p>"We are doing and will continue to do everything to ensure that the day comes when Ukraine is invited and becomes a NATO member, and I am confident we will achieve this," he said.</p>

<p>Zelensky's reaction was significantly warmer than a year ago at the NATO summit in Lithuania where he was visibly upset that there was not a firmer promise on membership.</p>

<p>NATO, formed in the Cold War, is a collective defense pact in which an attack on one ally is an attack on all.</p>

<p>The United States and Germany have led concerns about quickly bringing Ukraine into NATO, believing it would effectively put them at war with nuclear-armed Russia.</p>

<p>A declaration issued Wednesday at the 75th anniversary NATO summit in Washington said leaders supported Ukraine on "its irreversible path to full Euro-Atlantic integration, including NATO membership."</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has cited Ukraine's NATO aspirations as a reason to attack the former Soviet republic, rejecting the idea that the country has a separate historical identity.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/kkg64p4o_volodymyr-zelensky_625x300_29_January_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zelensky said that every step truly brings us closer to membership.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-adds-putin-critic-alexei-navalnys-wife-to-list-of-terrorists-6086112]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Adds Putin Critic Alexei Navalny's Wife To List Of "Terrorists"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-adds-putin-critic-alexei-navalnys-wife-to-list-of-terrorists-6086112]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:10:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia on Thursday added opposition figure Yulia Navalnaya to its list of "terrorists" and "extremists," two days after it issued an arrest warrant for the exiled dissident.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia on Thursday added opposition figure Yulia Navalnaya to its list of "terrorists" and "extremists," two days after it issued an arrest warrant for the exiled dissident.</p>

<p>Navalnaya has vowed to continue the work of her husband Alexei Navalny, Russian leader Vladimir Putin's main opponent who died in an Arctic prison in unclear circumstances in February.</p>

<p>Her personal details appeared Thursday in an online blacklist maintained by Rosfinmonitoring, a state agency designed to combat the financing of people and organisations Moscow deems "terrorists" or involved in "extremist activity".</p>

<p>Russian officials frequently apply such labels to opposition figures and those who campaign against the Kremlin or its offensive on Ukraine.</p>

<p>Navalny's organisations were outlawed in Russia and are labelled "extremist".</p>

<p>The opposition leader himself was sentenced to 19 years in prison on charges of "extremism."</p>

<p>A court in the capital Moscow on Tuesday ordered Navalnaya arrested in absentia, also on charges of "extremism."</p>

<p>Following her husband's death, Navalnaya, 47, vowed to take up his work and has lobbied against Putin's government from abroad.</p>

<p>"If they're making such a fuss, then Yulia is doing everything right," Kira Yarmysh, Navalnaya's press secretary said on social media after she was added to the blacklist.</p>

<p>Navalnaya, an economist, stood by her husband as he galvanised mass protests in Russia, flying him out of the country when he was poisoned before defiantly returning to Moscow with him in 2021, knowing he would be jailed.</p>

<p>Like much of Russia's opposition, Navalnaya lives in exile and would be detained if she set foot in Russia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/7v3it1_yulia-navalnaya_625x300_20_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yulia Navalnaya, an economist, stood by her husband as he galvanised mass protests in Russia (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-detects-record-66-chinese-aircraft-around-island-in-24-hours-6086056]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Taiwan Detects Record 66 Chinese Aircraft Around Island In 24 Hours]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/taiwan-detects-record-66-chinese-aircraft-around-island-in-24-hours-6086056]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:57:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Taiwan's defence ministry said Thursday it had detected 66 Chinese military aircraft around the island in a 24-hour window, a record-high this year, a day after it said Beijing was conducting exercises in nearby waters.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taiwan's defence ministry said Thursday it had detected 66 Chinese military aircraft around the island in a 24-hour window, a record-high this year, a day after it said Beijing was conducting exercises in nearby waters.</p>

<p>China -- which maintains a near-daily military presence around Taiwan -- claims the self-ruled island as part of its territory and has said it will never renounce the use of force to bring it under its control.</p>

<p>Thursday's record comes a day after Taipei spotted Chinese aircraft around the island that it said were headed to the western Pacific for exercises with the PLA aircraft carrier Shandong.</p>

<p>"66 PLA aircraft and seven PLAN vessels operating around Taiwan were detected up until 6 am (2200 GMT Wednesday) today," the defence ministry said in Thursday's statement, adding it has "responded accordingly".</p>

<p>Fifty-six of the Chinese aircraft crossed the sensitive median line bisecting the Taiwan Strait -- a narrow 180-kilometre (110-mile) waterway separating the island from China.</p>

<p>An illustration it released showed some of the aircraft came within 33 nautical miles (61 kilometres) of Taiwan's southern tip.</p>

<p>The year's previous record was in May, when Beijing sent 62 military aircraft and 27 naval vessels around Taiwan.</p>

<p>That occurred in the middle of war games Beijing launched on the heels of the inauguration of Taiwan President Lai Ching-te, who Beijing regards as a "dangerous separatist".</p>

<p>Military expert Su Tzu-yun said China's latest show of force was a reaction to recent political developments, including Washington's new de facto ambassador to Taiwan meeting with and expressing support for Taipei during a meeting with Lai on Wednesday.</p>

<p>"Beijing puts pressure on Taiwan in order to express its displeasure at the support it enjoys," said Su of Taiwan's Institute for National Defence and Security Research.</p>

<p>Defence minister Wellington Koo on Wednesday noted that the Shandong had not passed "through the Bashi Channel", the area off Taiwan's southern tip where Chinese ships typically transit en route to the Pacific Ocean.</p>

<p>Instead, it "went further south through the Balintang Channel towards the Western Pacific," he said, referring to a waterway just north of the Philippines' Babuyan Island -- about 250 kilometres south of Bashi.</p>

<p>Neighbouring Japan on Tuesday confirmed that four PLA navy vessels -- including the Shandong -- were sailing 520 kilometres southeast of Miyako island.</p>

<p>The Philippines' military public affairs chief said they had received reports of a China-Russia exercise taking place in the Philippine Sea but did not comment about the Shandong directly.</p>

<p><strong>'Restricted waters'</strong></p>

<p>China has in recent years ramped up political and military pressures around Taiwan, sending in record-breaking numbers of jets, drones and ships while upping the rhetoric of "unification" being "inevitable".</p>

<p>Lin Jian, spokesman of the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, reiterated Thursday that "Taiwan is an inalienable part of China's territory".</p>

<p>"The determination and resolve of the Chinese people to safeguard national sovereignty and territorial integrity are unwavering," he said during a regular press briefing.</p>

<p>The largest number of aircraft ever seen around Taiwan came last September when Beijing sent in 103 warplanes and aircraft.</p>

<p>Experts call these "grey zone tactics", which stop short of outright acts of war but serve to exhaust the island's military.</p>

<p>Lai has repeatedly made overtures of dialogue to China, but has been largely rebuffed.</p>

<p>Besides deploying a military show of force, China has also increasingly sent coast guard ships around Taiwan's outlying islands this year.</p>

<p>On Thursday, four Chinese coast guard ships "sailed into (Taiwan's) waters" at 7 am, Taipei's coast guard said, adding that the vessels left after two hours.</p>

<p>Then at 10 am, the four ships "once again sailed in Kinmen's restricted waters at multiple points, and our patrol boats immediately moved forward to monitor", and they left around noon.</p>

<p>"So far this year the incursions into waters controlled by our side have reached 31 times," they said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-08/2f9gk8ro_taiwan-china-afp_625x300_09_August_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[China has in recent years ramped up political and military pressures around Taiwan. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-foiled-russian-plot-to-assassinate-ukraines-german-arms-supplier-report-6085972]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Foiled Russian Plot To Assassinate Ukraine's German Arms Supplier: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-foiled-russian-plot-to-assassinate-ukraines-german-arms-supplier-report-6085972]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:44:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States foiled a Russian plot earlier this year to assassinate the chief executive of a major German arms maker supplying weaponry to Ukraine, CNN reported on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States foiled a Russian plot earlier this year to assassinate the chief executive of a major German arms maker supplying weaponry to Ukraine, CNN reported on Thursday.</p>

<p>The US cable television network, citing five unidentified US and Western officials, said the United States informed Germany of the Russian government's plan to kill Armin Papperger, the head of Rheinmetall, and he was given protection by German security services.</p>

<p>It said the assassination plot was one of a series of Russian plans discovered by US intelligence to kill European defense industry executives supporting Ukraine's war effort.</p>

<p>Rheinmetall produces 155mm artillery shells and plans to begin manufacturing armored vehicles in Ukraine, according to CNN.</p>

<p>The CNN report comes as NATO leaders are holding meetings in Washington to mark the 75th anniversary of the defense bloc.</p>

<p>German Foreign Minister Annalena Baerbock said: "In view of the latest reports on Rhinmetall, this is what we have actually been communicating more and more clearly in recent months.</p>

<p>"Russia is waging a hybrid war of aggression," Baerbock said. "With sabotage, with cyber attacks, with the paralysis of GPS so that Baltic aircraft can no longer land in neighbouring countries.</p>

<p>"We have seen that there have been attacks on people on European territory," the foreign minister said. "We have seen that there have been attacks on factories.</p>

<p>"And this emphasizes once again that we as Europeans must protect ourselves as best we can and not be naive."</p>

<p>A German interior ministry spokesman declined to comment directly on the Rheinmetall report but said the "German government takes the threats from the Russian regime very seriously.</p>

<p>"Our security authorities are very vigilant and act accordingly, in close cooperation with our international partners," the spokesman said. "We cannot comment on details, concrete protection measures and intelligence findings."</p>

<p>Rheinmetall spokesman Oliver Hoffmann said the company was "unable to comment on issues relating to corporate security."</p>

<p>"The necessary measures are always taken in regular consultation with security authorities," Hoffmann added.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-02/r0oc5cbs_ukraine-army-tanks-afp_625x300_19_February_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rheinmetall plans to begin manufacturing armored vehicles in Ukraine: Report (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/siding-with-putin-joe-bidens-campaign-slams-donald-trump-in-new-advertisement-6085927]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Siding With Putin": Biden's Campaign Slams Trump In New Advertisement]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/siding-with-putin-joe-bidens-campaign-slams-donald-trump-in-new-advertisement-6085927]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:32:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Embattled US President Joe Biden's campaign released a new advertisement on Thursday, hitting out at his rival and former president Donald Trump for "siding with Putin," and calling him a "lap dog for a dictator."]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Embattled US President Joe Biden's campaign released a new advertisement on Thursday, hitting out at his rival and former president Donald Trump for "siding with Putin," and calling him a "lap dog for a dictator." The advertisement - released to coincide with the last day of this week's high-profile NATO summit here - is part of a larger USD 50 million paid media buy for July, ahead of the November 5 presidential election.</p>

<p>The ad also comes as Biden, 81, faces a huge task to reassure fellow Democrats and voters about his fitness for office following a disastrous debate performance against 78-year-old Trump.</p>

<p>The advertisement slams Trump for suggesting Russia "do whatever the hell they want" to NATO members who do not meet defence spending targets, warning that the Republican Party's presumptive candidate is "a lapdog for a dictator who blames 'America first.'" "Donald Trump is an unhinged wannabe dictator. If he's reelected, he'll be Vladimir Putin's lap dog, giving him the green light to steamroll Europe and potentially spark World War III," CNN quoted Biden campaign spokesperson Lauren Hitt as saying on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Democracy and American security are on the ballot this November, and President Biden is the only candidate in this race committed to protecting and promoting it at home and abroad," it said.</p>

<p>Congressional Democrats are worried about Biden's chances to win reelection, particularly in the wake of his disastrous debate on CNN last month, and that having him at the top of the ticket could also hurt the party in the election.</p>

<p>Most Democrats have been reluctant to publicly call on Biden to step aside, but a growing number are saying so out loud, even after Biden has gone on the offensive this week to shore up support for a second term in the White House.</p>

<p>Biden wrote to congressional Democrats on Monday that he will continue his reelection bid despite mounting concerns.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Biden is scheduled to hold a closely watched news conference on Thursday at the end of the Nato summit, marking another high-stakes moment for him to show off his skill in answering questions in an unscripted setting.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8bbas48_donald-trump-joe-biden_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Congressional Democrats are worried about Joe Biden's chances to win reelection. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-could-have-its-own-parliament-in-the-future-putin-6085883]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BRICS Could Have Its Own Parliament In Future: Russian President Putin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/brics-could-have-its-own-parliament-in-the-future-putin-6085883]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:27:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The BRICS could establish their own parliament in the future, Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The BRICS could establish their own parliament in the future, Russian President Vladimir Putin said on Thursday.</p>

<p>"Thus far, BRICS does not have its own institutionalised parliamentary structure. But I believe that in the future this idea will definitely be realised," he said, in his address at the tenth parliamentary forum of the bloc here, RT reported.</p>

<p>He also said events such as the group's parliamentary forum strengthen the influence of BRICS on global affairs and help "make the world safer and more harmonious".</p>

<p>The Russian President stated that, by acting together, the recently-expanded group would be able to unlock its potential in economic, investment, and technology cooperation.</p>

<p>The group's priorities include the achievement of "positive changes" in the world economy through the development of reliable financial instruments for settling payments within BRICS, he said.</p>

<p>Noting that the number of participants had increased this year, he said Russia, as the current chair of the group, would ramp up efforts to ensure that the four new members of the bloc were effectively integrated following their accession earlier this year.</p>

<p>BRICS was founded in 2006 by Brazil, Russia, India, and China, with South Africa joining in 2011. The group expanded this year when Egypt, Ethiopia, Iran, and the United Arab Emirates became full members.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/qrtlde4_vladimir-putin_625x300_06_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Putin noted that the number of participants had increased this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-releases-first-probe-into-its-security-failures-during-hamas-attack-6085872]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel Releases First Probe Into Its Security Failures During Hamas Attack]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-releases-first-probe-into-its-security-failures-during-hamas-attack-6085872]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:22:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israeli military published on Thursday the findings of a first probe into its own security failings during the devastating Oct. 7 Hamas attack, acknowledging it hadn't protected the citizens of one of the worst hit communities, Kibbutz Be'eri.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israeli military published on Thursday the findings of a first probe into its own security failings during the devastating Oct. 7 Hamas attack, acknowledging it hadn't protected the citizens of one of the worst hit communities, Kibbutz Be'eri.</p>

<p>More than 100 people were killed in the attack on Be'eri, a community of about 1,000 people, and 32 taken hostage to Gaza, 11 of whom are still there.</p>

<p>The probe examined the day's chain of events, fighting and security forces' conduct, the military said. Some of the details have already been revealed by Reuters and other media in the weeks after the attack.</p>

<p>While acknowledging its own failure in protecting the kibbutz civilians, the military hailed the bravery of Be'eri residents, including its rapid response team, who despite being vastly outnumbered, tried to repel the militants who invaded.</p>

<p>Israel's military was unprepared for the scenario of a massive infiltration of militants into Israel, had inadequate forces in the area, did not have a clear picture of the events until noon, a few hours after the attack began, did not properly alert Be'eri's residents and its fighting was uncoordinated, the investigation found.</p>

<p>The probe, however, did not find fault in tank fire toward a house where militants were holding some 15 people hostage, an incident that has drawn criticism in Israel for having put civilians in harms way.</p>

<p>"After shooting was heard from the house and the terrorists announced their intent to kill themselves and the hostages, the forces decided to storm it in order to save the hostages," the military's summary said.</p>

<p>"The team found that the civilians inside the house were not hurt by the tank shells," the summary said, however, further investigation is needed to determine how hostages inside died, with signs pointing to them having been killed by the gunmen.</p>

<p>The military presented the report to Be'eri's residents, many of whom are among the tens of thousands of Israelis still displaced since Oct. 7.</p>

<p>"I didn't need all these details," said Miri Gad Mesika, a kibbutz member. "What matters to me is why what happened happened, how we can prevent it from happening again, how we can bring back our hostages and how we can feel secure again."</p>

<p></p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-10/2h0qb72o_israel-hamas-attack_625x300_12_October_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The military presented the report to Be'eri's residents. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-shining-actor-shelley-duvall-dies-at-75-6085741]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[ 'The Shining'  Actor Shelley Duvall Dies At 75]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/the-shining-actor-shelley-duvall-dies-at-75-6085741]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:00:43 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Shelley Duvall, the versatile actor known for her role in "The Shining" and collaboration with director Robert Altman, died Thursday aged 75.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shelley Duvall, the versatile actor known for her role in "The Shining" and collaboration with director Robert Altman, died Thursday aged 75.</p>

<p>Citing her partner Dan Gilroy, The Hollywood Reporter said Duvall died in her sleep at her home in Blanco, Texas following complications of diabetes.</p>

<p>Born July 7, 1949 in Fort Worth, Texas, Duvall was discovered by Altman -- the maverick filmmaker known for his rich characters, sharp social criticism and keen satire -- who cast her in 1970's dark comedy "Brewster McCloud."</p>

<p>The saucer-eyed actor developed a broad repertoire and captivated audiences, breaking through with 1975's "Nashville," and going on to portray memorable and eccentric characters that earned her a smattering of awards including at Cannes for her role in the acclaimed 1977 drama "3 Women."</p>

<p>Her career was defined by her work with Altman, who she said she kept coming back to because "he offers me damn good roles."</p>

<p>"None of them have been alike," she told The New York Times in 1977.</p>

<p>"He has a great confidence in me, and a trust and respect for me, and he doesn't put any restrictions on me or intimidate me, and I love him."</p>

<p>In a 1977 interview Altman praised Duvall for being able "to swing all sides of the pendulum: charming, silly, sophisticated, pathetic -- even beautiful."</p>

<p><strong>'She's free'</strong></p>

<p>But it was her work on the 1980 film adaptation of Stephen King's "The Shining" that would become her highest profile role, which she played opposite Jack Nicholson.</p>

<p>Director Stanley Kubrick put her through the ringer to perform the part of Wendy Torrance in the horror classic that sees a writer husband descend into homicidal madness and terrorize his wife and young son.</p>

<p>Duvall has voiced admiration for Kubrick but also has publicly discussed how arduous the role was, telling People in 1981 the 13-month job was grueling and that Kubrick had her "crying 12 hours a day for weeks on end."</p>

<p>"I will never give that much again. If you want to get into pain and call it art, go ahead, but not with me."</p>

<p>In one famous scene Nicholson's character tortures Duvall's with a baseball bat, which reportedly took 127 takes to satisfy Kubrick.</p>

<p>Duvall also made a cameo in 1977's "Annie Hall" by Woody Allen, and played opposite Robin Williams in Altman's 1980 live-action rendition of "Popeye."</p>

<p>Later in the 1980s she made her way into children's programming.</p>

<p>Her last film was 2023's "The Forest Hills," an independent horror-thriller she played in after a two-decade hiatus from professional acting.</p>

<p>Duvall's fade from Hollywood prompted much speculation, over both her mental health and her aged appearance. In a 2024 interview with The New York Times both she and Gilroy voiced exasperation at such treatment.</p>

<p>She indicated she felt betrayed by the industry in which she excelled, even as her body of work continues to earn her new fans.</p>

<p>"I was a star; I had leading roles," she said in the rare interview. "People think it's just aging, but it's not. It's violence."</p>

<p>"How would you feel if people were really nice, and then, suddenly, on a dime... they turn on you?"</p>

<p>Gilroy -- a musician who was part of the Breakfast Club band and had dated Madonna -- was Duvall's longtime partner after the pair met on the 1990 Disney Channel Movie "Mother Goose Rock 'n' Rhyme."</p>

<p>"My dear, sweet, wonderful life partner and friend left us. Too much suffering lately, now she's free. Fly away, beautiful Shelley," Gilroy said in a widely published statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/umipoc4_shelley-duvall_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shelley Duvall's last film was 2023's "The Forest Hills" (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/difficult-situation-over-70-pilot-whales-found-stranded-on-scotland-island-6085516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Difficult Situation": Over 70 Whales Found Stranded On Scotland Island]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/difficult-situation-over-70-pilot-whales-found-stranded-on-scotland-island-6085516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:22:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Scores of whales washed ashore in a "mass stranding" in Scotland's Orkney archipelago on Thursday, a British marine life rescue charity said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scores of whales washed ashore in a "mass stranding" in Scotland's Orkney archipelago on Thursday, a British marine life rescue charity said.</p>

<p>A total of 77 long-finned pilot whales were found on the island of Sanday in Orkney, off the northeastern coast of Scotland, after the British Divers Marine Life Rescue (BDMLR) received a report.</p>

<p>When the BDMLR arrived, only a dozen whales were still alive, having been "stranded for several hours already", the animal rescue charity said.</p>

<p>First aid was being provided to the surviving animals as the "incoming tide approaches them", it added.</p>

<p>"Our team continues to work hard to manage this incredibly difficult situation", BDMLR said in the statement on its website, adding that help was also coming from the Scottish Marine Animal Strandings Scheme to probe the incident.</p>

<p>While such mass strandings are not uncommon among pilot whales who tend to travel in tightly-knit groups, this one is larger than in previous years.</p>

<p>Last year, 55 pilot whales washed ashore and died on the island of Lewis, off northwest Scotland.</p>

<p>Much bigger strandings have taken place in other parts of the world, with the largest in parts of New Zealand and Australia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/doadcf_pilot-whales_625x300_25_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last year, 55 pilot whales washed ashore and died on the island of Lewis. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airport-evacuated-after-grenades-discovered-in-mans-baggage-6084876]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hawaii Airport Evacuated After Grenades Discovered In Man's Baggage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-airport-evacuated-after-grenades-discovered-in-mans-baggage-6084876]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 11 Jul 2024 20:41:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Akito Fukushima, of Kanazawa, Japan, was taken into custody on a charge of first-degree terroristic threats.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a shocking incident, Hawaii Airport in the United States was evacuated after grenades were found in a carry-on luggage of a man, as per a report in CBS News. The Transportation Security Administration said that they found two items resembling grenades were detected during x-ray screening in a bag belonging to a male Japanese national departing the country.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, officers emptied the terminal as the bomb squad investigated the suspicious items discovered during X-ray scanning. The police said, "The Hilo International Airport experienced a brief halt in operations" for a little over an hour.</p>

<p>According to police, the bomb squad "determined the items to be inert grenades," meaning they posed no threat. As per the authorities, Akito Fukushima, of Kanazawa, Japan, was taken into custody on a charge of first-degree terroristic threats.</p>

<p>"Responding to the 5:44 a.m. call, officers secured and evacuated the terminal area as a precautionary safety measure while the department's bomb squad arrived on scene and determined the items to be inert grenades. At 6:45 a.m., police arrested 41-year-old Akito Fukushima of Kanazawa, Japan, for first-degree terroristic threatening. Fukushima was transported to HPD's East Hawaii Detention Facility and remains in custody while Detectives of the Area I Criminal Investigation Section continue the investigation. The airport resumed operations at 6:50 a.m," the Hawaii Police Department in a press release.</p>

<p>The flight he was trying to board was to a destination outside the US, police noted, however, they didn't say which country it was heading to or what his ultimate destination was. "Police remind the public that replicas of explosives, such as hand grenades, are prohibited in checked and carry-on baggage," they said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/dch7nmu_grenades_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The flight he was trying to board was to a destination outside the US.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>