<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 04:32:37 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-2-ballistic-missiles-at-south-korea-6006054]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[North Korea Fires 2 Ballistic Missiles At South Korea]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-korea-fires-2-ballistic-missiles-at-south-korea-6006054]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 04:32:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[North Korea on Monday launched two ballistic missiles, South Korea's military confirmed -- the latest in a series of weapons tests by Pyongyang that have soured relations with Seoul.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korea on Monday launched two ballistic missiles, South Korea's military confirmed -- the latest in a series of weapons tests by Pyongyang that have soured relations with Seoul.</p>

<p>A short-range ballistic missile was launched in the early morning hours, the South's military Joint Chiefs of Staff said in a statement. About 10 minutes later, a second missile, this one as yet unidentified, was detected, it added.</p>

<p>"Our military has strengthened surveillance and vigilance in preparation for further launches," the JCS said, adding it had shared information about the incidents with the United States and Japan.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The North's official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) did not offer immediate confirmation of the launches.</p>

<p>Last week, North Korea claimed to have successfully tested a multiple warhead missile, but the South said that launch ended in a mid-air explosion.</p>

<p>Relations between the two Koreas are at one of their lowest points in years, with the North ramping up weapons testing while bombarding the South with balloons full of trash.</p>

<p>Pyongyang says those missives are in retaliation for balloons loaded with anti-regime propaganda leaflets sent northwards by activists in the South.</p>

<p>In response to the North's repeated launches, South Korea has fully suspended a tension-reducing military treaty. It also resumed propaganda loudspeaker broadcasts and live-fire drills near the border.</p>

<p>South Korea also has grown anxious over the North's warming relations with its isolated neighbour Russia.</p>

<p>North Korea is accused of breaching arms control measures by supplying weapons to Russia to use in its war in Ukraine, and Russian President Vladimir Putin held a summit with leader Kim Jong Un in Pyongyang in June in a show of unity.</p>

<p>On Sunday, Pyongyang condemned joint military drills by South Korea, Japan and the United States, calling them an "Asian version of NATO" and warning of "fatal consequences".</p>

<p>The three-day "Freedom Edge" exercises included preparation in ballistic missile and air defences, anti-submarine warfare and defensive cyber training.</p>

<p>Pyongyang has always decried similar combined exercises as rehearsals for an invasion, but Seoul said Sunday the latest exercises were a continuation of defensive drills held regularly for years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-government-formed-after-tough-coalition-deal-with-opposition-6005888]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Africa Government Formed After Tough Coalition Deal With Opposition]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-africa-government-formed-after-tough-coalition-deal-with-opposition-6005888]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 03:37:55 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South African president Cyril Ramaphosa announced his new government on Sunday with the opposition receiving 12 out of 32 portfolios following tough coalition negotiations after the ruling ANC lost its outright parliamentary majority.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South African president Cyril Ramaphosa announced his new government on Sunday with the opposition receiving 12 out of 32 portfolios following tough coalition negotiations after the ruling ANC lost its outright parliamentary majority.</p>

<p>The African National Congress, which has governed the country since the advent of democracy in 1994, retained 20 out of 32 cabinet positions, including key ministries such as foreign affairs, finance, defence, justice and police.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The largest coalition partner, the Democratic Alliance (DA), will hold six portfolios including home affairs, environment and public works.</p>

<p>The DA's leader John Steenhuisen, 48, was appointed Minister of Agriculture.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Zulu nationalist Inkatha Freedom Party (IFP) and other smaller parties scored six in total including land reform, correctional services, sports, tourism and public service.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The establishment of the Government of National Unity in its current form is unprecedented in the history of our democracy," the 71-year-old Ramaphosa said, speaking from Pretoria in a televised speech.&nbsp;</p>

<p>He was re-elected for a second full term last week, to lead what his humbled ANC calls a government of national unity (GNU) after losing its outright majority in the May 29 general election.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The incoming government will prioritise rapid, inclusive and sustainable economic growth and a creation of a more just society by tackling poverty and inequality as well as unemployment," he said.</p>

<p>Adding that he had to "ensure all the parties are able to participate meaningfully in the national executive as well as various parliamentary positions".</p>

<p>The only other time South Africa has opted for a national unity government was at the end of apartheid, with Nelson Mandela and FW de Klerk, the former leader of the government, overseeing the transition to democracy as executive deputy presidents.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>Tough negotiations</h2>

<p>The ANC's fall from grace came against a backdrop of high violent crime rates, a lacklustre economy and a crippling energy crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ramaphosa's highly anticipated announcement comes after weeks of tough negotiations between the ANC and the DA, which won 87 parliamentary seats (22 percent of the popular vote) compared to the ANC's 159 (40 percent).&nbsp;</p>

<p>The turbulent build-up to the country's new government was met with criticism from the country's leftist parties, including the uMkhonto weSizwe (MK) party, a new grouping formed a few months ahead of the poll by the country's former president Jacob Zuma, 82.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The MK party came out of nowhere to win more than 14 percent of votes nationwide in the tense poll and now well be the country's official opposition after refusing to join the ANC's broad coalition.</p>

<p>Along with the leftist firebrand party the Economic Freedom Fighters (EFF), it shunned the ANC's broad coalition with the DA as a "white-led unholy alliance".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The ANC had previously accused the DA of making "outrageous demands" for key cabinet positions in documents leaked to the press following weeks of closed-doors negotiations.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ramaphosa has called for the opening of the new parliament on July 18 to address MPs and outline guidelines of how his new coalition government, involving 11 parties, will work.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-06/2isgta2_cyril-ramaphosa-_625x300_19_June_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-way-run-offs-and-horse-trading-what-happens-next-in-french-elections-6005596]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3-Way Run-Offs And Horse-Trading: What Happens Next In French Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-way-run-offs-and-horse-trading-what-happens-next-in-french-elections-6005596]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 01:55:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Here's how the second round of France's parliamentary election on July 7 will work and the possible scenarios after exit polls showed Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally (RN) party had won Sunday's first round.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here's how the second round of France's parliamentary election on July 7 will work and the possible scenarios after exit polls showed Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally (RN) party had won Sunday's first round.</p>

<p>HOW DOES IT WORK?</p>

<p>Elections for the 577 seats in France's National Assembly are a two-round process.</p>

<p>In constituencies where no candidate won outright in the first round, the top two candidates, as well as any candidate with more than 12.5% of the total number of registered voters in that constituency, move to a second round.</p>

<p>Whoever gets the most votes in the second round wins the seat.</p>

<p>The high turnout on Sunday means some 300 constituencies are now facing potential three-way run-offs which, in theory, favour the RN.</p>

<p>To prevent these three-way run-offs and block the RN, France's centre-right and centre-left politicians have long practiced what they call a "republican front," whereby the third-placed candidate drops out of the race and urges voters to rally behind the second-placed candidate.</p>

<p>All candidates through to the run-off have until Tuesday evening to decide whether to stand down or run the second round.</p>

<p>HOW IS IT LOOKING THIS TIME?</p>

<p>Many political leaders gave guidance to candidates and voters on Sunday evening.</p>

<p>President Emmanuel Macron urged a "wide-ranging rally behind republican and democratic" candidates for the second round, effectively guiding against both the far-right Nationaly Rally and the hard-left France Unbowed (LFI) party.</p>

<p>His former Prime Minister, Edouard Philippe, explicity called on the candidates from his party to drop out if they were in third position and rally behind candidates from the centre-left to the centre-right, excluding the RN and LFI.</p>

<p>On the left, the Socialist and LFI leaders also called on their third-placed candidates to drop out to block the RN.</p>

<p>The conservative Republicans party, which split ahead of the vote with a small number of its lawmakers joining forces with the RN, gave no guidance.</p>

<p>WHAT WILL HAPPEN NOW?</p>

<p>The effectiveness of the "republican front" has weakened over the years, and many voters no longer heed the advice of party leaders.</p>

<p>It is also possible that candidates will refuse to drop out despite guidance from political HQs in Paris.</p>

<p>But talks over the next 48 hours will be crucial and could swing the results significantly, potentially deciding whether the RN reaches an outright majority in parliament or not.</p>

<p>That makes the result of the second round extraordinarily hard to predict. Even pollsters have urged caution on their own seat projections.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/i8k1tjkc_france-generic_625x300_01_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Exit polls showed Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally party had won Sunday's first round.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isolated-macron-stung-by-french-voters-revenge-in-snap-elections-6005595]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Isolated Macron Stung By French Voters' Revenge In Snap Elections]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/isolated-macron-stung-by-french-voters-revenge-in-snap-elections-6005595]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Jul 2024 01:54:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Emmanuel Macron has taken many risks in a political career marked by countless crises but his decision to call snap elections may be one too many, marring his legacy and ushering in an era of extremes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Emmanuel Macron has taken many risks in a political career marked by countless crises but his decision to call snap elections may be one too many, marring his legacy and ushering in an era of extremes.</p>

<p>The tremors from Macron dissolving the National Assembly after his centrist party suffered a drubbing in European polls remain strong, with even figures close to the president acknowledging unease over the political turmoil.</p>

<p>The far-right National Rally (RN) on Sunday won the first round of legislative elections.</p>

<p>Next week's second-round results on July 7 could give the party of Macron's longtime rival Marine Le Pen the post of prime minister for the first time, forcing a tense "cohabitation".</p>

<p>Macron's popularity has sunk to the extent that allies suggested he take a back seat in the campaign, with Prime Minister Gabriel Attal leading the way.</p>

<p>For one of Macron's most loyal supporters, some of the resentment stems from his unexpected rise to the presidency.</p>

<p>"There's a desire for revenge on the part of politicians who resent his success," said Francois Patriat, head of the pro-Macron deputies in the upper house Senate.</p>

<p>Always defiant, Macron insisted in a statement as the first results were published on "the importance of this vote for all our compatriots and the desire to clarify the political situation".</p>

<h2>'Hopeless optimist'</h2>

<p>Born in Amiens to two doctors, Macron met his future wife Brigitte when she was his teacher and 25 years his senior.</p>

<p>"He fell in love with his drama teacher when he was 16, and he said he was going to marry her, and then he married her. That's pretty strong stuff," said a former classmate from the elite graduate school ENA.</p>

<p>With that same self-confidence, he quit the government of former president Francois Hollande in August 2016 to prepare his run for the presidency, a risky move at the time.</p>

<p>He went on to create En Marche (On the Move), a political movement with the same initials as its leader and won the presidential election in 2017 at the age of 39.</p>

<p>Calling himself a "hopeless optimist," Macron later said he was able to break through "because France was unhappy and worried".&nbsp;</p>

<p>Optimism over the former Rothschild investment banker, who once promoted "Revolution" in his book, quickly soured over his economic policies once in office.</p>

<p>The former economy minister under a Socialist government earned the reputation as "president of the rich" after announcing early in his tenure that he would abolish a tax on high earners.</p>

<p>Then, last year, his move to raise the retirement age from 62 to 64 sparked mass protests and reinforced the perception that Macron is out of touch with public opinion.</p>

<p>"There are a lot of people who think I'm haughty," he said. Early quips haunted him, including one when he said the unemployed only needed to "cross the street" to find a job.</p>

<p>The now 46-year-old is convinced that his economic track record speaks for itself, with France considered Europe's most attractive country for foreign investment and an end to mass unemployment.</p>

<p>But for many, Macron's promise of centrism has not withstood pressure from a wave of domestic and international crises -- or from the far right.</p>

<h2>'Lack of humility'</h2>

<p>The anti-government "yellow vest" movement, the Covid-19 pandemic, and the war in Ukraine are just a few of the challenges Macron has faced during his tenure.</p>

<p>Even as his support buckles at home, Macron has remained a key voice in European politics.</p>

<p>"We shouldn't quibble. He's the great European of his time," said Franco-German ecologist Daniel Cohn-Bendit, while adding that Macron's problem was that he was "convinced of being right".</p>

<p>Macron aligned with allies offering support to Ukraine after Russia's 2022 invasion, but he irritated many by continuing to engage with Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>

<p>Two years later however, some criticise him for his hawkish stance. Macron refuses to rule out sending troops to Ukraine, a move criticised by other Western countries as unnecessarily inflammatory.</p>

<p>The late Gerard Collomb, former mayor of Lyon, was more direct in his criticism, calling out Macron's "hubris" and a "lack of humility" in the government.</p>

<p>The perception that Macron is increasingly isolated is part of the problem, said one former advisor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"He has no grassroots network... the people around him are the same, they don't express the mood of the times," they added.</p>

<p>While the first lady is seen as a moderating figure, Macron has shifted rightward, with some accusing the president of opportunism.&nbsp;</p>

<h2>'Shifting opinion'</h2>

<p>On the evening of his 2017 victory, Macron pledged in front of the Louvre museum to do "everything" in his power to ensure the French "no longer have any reason to vote for the extremes".</p>

<p>For many, though, the young centrist whom they voted for has shifted further and further right, opening the door for other extremes to take hold.</p>

<p>The same man who drew inspiration from an anti-capitalist party slogan to win re-election in 2022 later adopted the words of extreme right-wing figure Eric Zemmour "so that France remains France".&nbsp;</p>

<p>For Le Pen, who senses a chance to take the presidency in 2027, Macron has "a plasticity, an incredible self-confidence which is both his strength and his weakness".</p>

<p>A former special advisor sees that plasticity differently.</p>

<p>"He's turning his back on ... 2017 and humanist values," said Philippe Grangeon. "There is no right-wing turn... the president is adapting to shifting opinion."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Macron dismisses these criticisms, saying he ultimately relies on himself. "You make the toughest decisions on your own," he said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/tvo5kai8_emmanuel-macron_625x300_05_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/far-right-leads-first-round-of-france-election-show-exit-polls-6005166]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Far-Right Leads First Round Of France Election, Show Exit Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/far-right-leads-first-round-of-france-election-show-exit-polls-6005166]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 23:38:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally (RN) party emerged ahead in the first round of France's parliamentary elections on Sunday, exit polls showed, but the unpredictable final result will depend on days of horsetrading before next week's run-off.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marine Le Pen's far-right National Rally (RN) party emerged ahead in the first round of France's parliamentary elections on Sunday, exit polls showed, but the unpredictable final result will depend on days of horsetrading before next week's run-off.</p>

<p>The RN was seen winning around 34% of the vote, exit polls from Ipsos, Ifop, OpinionWay and Elabe showed.</p>

<p>That was ahead of leftist and centrist rivals, including President Emmanuel Macron's Together alliance, whose bloc was seen winning 20.5%-23%. The New Popular Front, a hastily assembled left-wing coalition, was projected to win around 29% of the vote, the exit polls showed.</p>

<p>The results from the high-turnout vote, which were in line with polls ahead of the election, provided little clarity on whether the anti-immigrant, eurosceptic RN will be able to form a government alongside the pro-EU Macron.</p>

<p>A week of political bargaining now lies ahead of the July 7 run-off. The final result will depend on how parties decide to join forces in each of France's 577 constituencies for the second round. In the past, France's centre-right and centre-left parties have teamed up to keep the RN from taking power, but that dynamic, called the "republican front" in France, is less certain than ever.</p>

<p>The French president's decision this month to call snap elections plunged his country into political uncertainty, sent shockwaves around Europe and prompted a sell-off of French assets on financial markets.</p>

<p>Participation in Sunday's vote was high, underlining how France's rumbling political crisis has energised the electorate.</p>

<p>By 1500 GMT, turnout was nearly 60%, compared with 39.42% two years ago - the highest comparable turnout figures since the 1986 legislative vote, Ipsos France's research director Mathieu Gallard said.</p>

<p>A longtime pariah, the RN is now closer to power than it has ever been. Le Pen has sought to detoxify a party known for racism and antisemitism, a tactic that has worked amid voter anger at Macron, the high cost of living and growing concerns over immigration.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/u9latg0g_marine-le-pen_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Participation in Sunday's vote was high]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-in-light-aircraft-crash-on-motorway-outside-paris-cops-6005142]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Killed In Light Aircraft Crash On Motorway Outside Paris: Cops]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-killed-in-light-aircraft-crash-on-motorway-outside-paris-cops-6005142]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 23:32:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three people were killed on Sunday when their light aircraft crashed onto a motorway east of Paris, the police and gendarmerie said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three people were killed on Sunday when their light aircraft crashed onto a motorway east of Paris, the police and gendarmerie said.</p>

<p>No car was hit in the crash of the plane onto the A4 motorway in Noisiel east of Paris which appeared to have been caused by the aircraft hitting an electric power cable, said a police source, asking not to be named, adding that the road had been blocked in both directions.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-12/sg8ktf4g_france-police-generic_625x300_23_December_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-geniune-threat-biden-seeks-to-repair-debate-damage-with-fiery-speech-6005009]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Trump Geniune Threat: Biden Seeks To Repair Debate Damage With Fiery Speech]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-geniune-threat-biden-seeks-to-repair-debate-damage-with-fiery-speech-6005009]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 23:05:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A fired-up Joe Biden came out swinging Friday as he tried to make up for a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump, insisting he was the right man to win November's US presidential election.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fired-up Joe Biden came out swinging Friday as he tried to make up for a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump, insisting he was the right man to win November's US presidential election.</p>

<p>Biden's appearance at a campaign rally in the battleground state of North Carolina came amid rumblings in his alarmed Democratic Party about replacing the 81-year-old as their nominee -- and shortly before the nation's most influential newspaper urged him to step aside.</p>

<p>"I don't walk as easy as I used to. I don't speak as smoothly as I used to. I don't debate as well as I used to," Biden admitted to supporters in unusually confessional remarks.</p>

<p>"But I know how to tell the truth. I know how to do this job," he said to huge cheers, vowing "when you get knocked down, you get back up."</p>

<p>Biden's team was in damage-control mode after Thursday's debate when he often hesitated, tripped over words and lost his train of thought -- exacerbating fears about his ability to serve another term.</p>

<p>He had hoped to allay qualms about his advanced age, and to expose Trump as a habitual liar.</p>

<p>But the president failed to counter his bombastic rival, who offered up a largely unchallenged reel of false or misleading statements about everything from the economy to immigration.</p>

<p>On Friday, Biden delivered the lines Democrats wished they had heard in the televised debate.</p>

<p>"Did you see Trump last night? My guess is he set -- and I mean this sincerely -- a new record for the most lies told in a single debate," Biden said.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is a genuine threat to this nation. He's a threat to our freedom. He's a threat to our democracy. He's literally a threat for everything America stands for."</p>

<p>Trump also returned to the campaign trail Friday, speaking at a rally in Virginia and launching his familiar attacks on Biden in a rambling speech.</p>

<p>"It's not his age, it's his competence," Trump said.</p>

<p>"The question every voter should be asking themselves today is not whether Joe Biden can survive a 90-minute debate performance, but whether America can survive four more years of crooked Joe Biden."</p>

<h3><strong>A new Democrat?</strong></h3>

<p>Trump addressed the chances of Biden being replaced by another candidate, saying "I don't really believe that because he does better in polls than any of the (other) Democrats."</p>

<p>So far, no senior Democratic figure has publicly called on Biden to withdraw, with most toeing a party line about sticking with the existing ticket.</p>

<p>"I will never turn my back on President Biden," California Governor Gavin Newsom, who has figured prominently on lists of possible replacement candidates, said immediately after the debate.</p>

<p>Forcing a change in the ticket would be politically fraught, and Biden would have to decide himself to withdraw to make way for another nominee before the party convention next month.</p>

<p>Biden overwhelmingly won the primary votes, and the party's 3,900 delegates heading to the convention in Chicago are beholden to him.</p>

<p>If he exits, the delegates would have to find a replacement.</p>

<p>"Bad debate nights happen," Biden's former boss, Barack Obama, wrote on X.</p>

<p>But the election is "still a choice between someone who has fought for ordinary folks his entire life and someone who only cares about himself."</p>

<p>A logical -- but not automatic -- candidate to take Biden's place would be his vice president, Kamala Harris, who also loyally defended his debate performance.</p>

<p>The show of Democratic loyalty and Biden's defiance in North Carolina were not enough for The New York Times, however.</p>

<p>The daily newspaper slammed Biden's campaign as a "reckless gamble" in the face of the threat posed by Trump, with its editorial board -- which is separate from the newsroom -- calling for the president to stand aside.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The "greatest public service Mr. Biden can now perform is to announce that he will not continue to run for re-election," it said.</p>

<p>Many election bettors, too, abandoned Biden, preferring to bet on Trump or other Democratic leaders.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Before the debate, bettors on the platform Smarkets were giving Biden a 35 percent chance of winning in November, but on Friday that figure dropped to below 20 percent.</p>

<p>A second debate is scheduled for September 10.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/257p3v2_joe-biden-ians_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[So far, no senior Democratic figure has publicly called on Biden to withdraw (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/caribbean-on-alert-for-extremely-dangerous-hurricane-beryl-6004969]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Caribbean On Alert For "Extremely Dangerous'" Hurricane Beryl]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/caribbean-on-alert-for-extremely-dangerous-hurricane-beryl-6004969]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 22:55:58 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Much of the southeast Caribbean was on alert Sunday as Beryl strengthened into the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, with forecasters warning of an "extremely dangerous" Category 4 storm.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much of the southeast Caribbean was on alert Sunday as Beryl strengthened into the first hurricane of the 2024 Atlantic season, with forecasters warning of an "extremely dangerous" Category 4 storm.</p>

<p>The US National Hurricane Center (NHC) said Beryl -- currently churning in the Atlantic Ocean about 465 miles (750 kilometers) east of Barbados -- was expected to bring "life-threatening winds and storm surge" when it reaches the Windward Islands early Monday.</p>

<p>Warning the storm is "continuing to rapidly intensify," the NHC forecast it would become an "extremely dangerous Category 4 hurricane" by the time it hit Caribbean communities.</p>

<p>Barbados, Saint Lucia, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, and Grenada were all under hurricane warnings, while tropical storm warnings or watches were in effect for Martinique, Tobago and Dominica, the NHC said in its latest advisory.</p>

<p>Cars were seen lined up at gas stations Saturday in the Barbadian capital Bridgetown, while supermarkets and grocery stores were crowded with shoppers buying food, water and other supplies. Some households were already boarding up their properties.</p>

<p>A Category 3 or higher on the Saffir-Simpson scale is considered a major hurricane, and a Category 4 storm packs sustained winds of at least 130 miles per hour (209 kilometers per hour).</p>

<p>The NHC said that by around 5:00 am (0900 GMT) Sunday, Beryl's maximum sustained winds had increased to nearly 100 mph, with higher gusts.</p>

<p>Such a powerful storm forming this early in the Atlantic hurricane season -- which runs from early June to late November -- is extremely rare, experts said.</p>

<p>"Only five major (Category 3+) hurricanes have been recorded in the Atlantic before the first week of July. Beryl would be the sixth and earliest this far east in the tropical Atlantic," hurricane expert Michael Lowry posted on social media platform X.</p>

<p>"Hurricane conditions are expected in the hurricane warning area beginning early on Monday," the NHC said, warning of heavy rain, flooding and storm surge that could raise water levels as much as nine feet (2.7 meters) above normal.</p>

<p>"Devastating wind damage is expected where the eyewall of Beryl moves through portions of the Windward Islands," the NHC said, indicating wind speeds in some locations could be 30 percent stronger than those listed in their advisory.</p>

<p>The US National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration said in late May that it expects this year to be an "extraordinary" hurricane season, with up to seven storms of Category 3 or higher.</p>

<p>The agency cited warm Atlantic ocean temperatures and conditions related to the weather phenomenon La Nina in the Pacific for the expected increase in storms.</p>

<p>Extreme weather events including hurricanes have become more frequent and more devastating in recent years as a result of climate change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/hhsloa28_beryl_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Cars were seen lined up at gas stations Saturday in the Barbadian capital Bridgetown]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-baby-among-9-injured-in-ukraine-post-office-bombing-6004782]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Dead, Baby Among 9 Injured In Ukraine Post Office Bombing]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-dead-baby-among-9-injured-in-ukraine-post-office-bombing-6004782]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 22:18:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[One person was killed and nine others including a baby were injured Sunday in a strike on a post office in Ukraine's second city Kharkiv, local authorities said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One person was killed and nine others including a baby were injured Sunday in a strike on a post office in Ukraine's second city Kharkiv, local authorities said.</p>

<p>The head of Kharkiv's regional administration, Oleg Synegubov, said an eight-month-old baby was among those injured.</p>

<p>"A man, a post office employee, was killed," he said on Telegram.</p>

<p>The city of Kharkiv has been regularly targeted by Russian troops, who launched a major ground offensive in the region on May 10.</p>

<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has said the offensive in Ukraine's northeast was intended to create a "buffer zone" to protect Russia's border Belgorod region from shelling.</p>

<p>On Saturday, seven people were also killed and nearly 40 injured in a Russian strike on Vilniansk, close to the regional hub of Zaporizhzhia.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/0318an2o_kharkiv_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The city of Kharkiv has been regularly targeted by Russian troops (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-rally-behind-biden-after-shaky-debate-performance-with-trump-6004687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Democrats Rally Behind Biden After Shaky Debate Performance With Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/democrats-rally-behind-biden-after-shaky-debate-performance-with-trump-6004687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 21:56:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Democratic leaders rallied Sunday behind US President Joe Biden following his poor debate performance last week, as the White House denied a report he was meeting with family to assess his candidacy.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Democratic leaders rallied Sunday behind US President Joe Biden following his poor debate performance last week, as the White House denied a report he was meeting with family to assess his candidacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p>No major party figures have broken ranks to call for Biden to step down, with prominent Democrats including past presidents Barack Obama and Bill Clinton voicing full-throated support amid a torrent of doubts from everyday Americans -- and even a call from the New York Times editorial board to move aside.</p>

<p>The wave of party backing follows the 81-year-old's stumbling performance Thursday in the debate against Republican candidate Donald Trump, in which Biden often hesitated, tripped over words and lost his train of thought, highlighting concerns about his age.</p>

<p>"It's not about performance in terms of a debate, it's about performance in a presidency," Representative Nancy Pelosi, the former House speaker, told CNN's "State of the Union" on Sunday.</p>

<p>On "one side of the screen, you have integrity, the other side you have dishonesty," she said, echoing a number of party figures attempting to shift the focus from what they say was Biden's unfortunate performance to the barrage of lies that came from Donald Trump during the debate.</p>

<p>According to a CBS News poll conducted in the two days following the debate, nearly three-quarters of registered voters now believe Biden should not be running for president, including 46 percent of Democrats.</p>

<p>Biden and his family traveled to the Camp David presidential retreat late Saturday, where NBC News reported he was expected to assess the future of his reelection campaign following his performance.</p>

<p>White House senior deputy press secretary Andrew Bates, however, posted on X that the trip had been planned since before the debate, questioning the publication and claiming it had failed to ask for comment on the matter.</p>

<h3><strong>'Only Democrat' for the job</strong></h3>

<p>The Biden campaign has meanwhile reported that it has raised $33 million since the debate, including $26 million from grassroots donors.</p>

<p>Biden should "absolutely not" drop out of the race, Georgia Senator Raphael Warnock told NBC's "Meet the Press" on Sunday.</p>

<p>"It's our assignment to make sure that he gets over the finish line come November. Not for his sake but the country's sake."</p>

<p>On Friday, Biden attempted to tamp down the nay-saying with a fiery campaign speech in North Carolina in which he pledged to keep fighting.</p>

<p>He appeared alongside his wife, First Lady Jill Biden, who has fiercely defended her husband amid calls for him to step aside.</p>

<p>"On that campaign stage in North Carolina, I saw a forceful, engaged and capable Joe Biden," Democratic Senator Chris Coons, from Biden's home state of Delaware, said Sunday on ABC's "This Week."</p>

<p>"I think it was a weak debate performance by President Biden," Coons said, adding that nonetheless "side by side, Donald Trump had a horrifying debate performance where, yes, he spoke plainly, but what he said was lie after lie after lie."</p>

<p>Biden, he added, is "the only Democrat who can beat Donald Trump."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/257p3v2_joe-biden-ians_625x300_29_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Biden campaign has meanwhile reported that it has raised $33 million since the debate]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/special-education-teacher-in-us-charged-with-sexually-assaulting-minor-student-6004272]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Special Education Teacher In US Charged With Sexually Assaulting Student]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/special-education-teacher-in-us-charged-with-sexually-assaulting-minor-student-6004272]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 20:32:07 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She was arrested after an investigation revealed that she allegedly began sexually abusing her student earlier this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A special education teacher at an intermediate school in New Jersey was arrested for an alleged sexual relationship with a student, according to authorities.&nbsp;43-year-old&nbsp;Allison Havemann-Niedrach&nbsp;at Freehold Intermediate School was charged with first-degree aggravated sexual assault and endangering the welfare of a child, Monmouth County <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://mcponj.org/2024/06/29/intermediate-school-teacher-charged-with-engaging-in-sexual-relationship-with-student/">Prosecutor Raymond S. Santiago announced.</a></p>

<p>According to the<em> <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/29/us-news/nj-special-ed-teacher-accused-of-sexually-assaulting-student-prosecutor/">New York Post</a></em>, she was&nbsp;arrested earlier this week after an&nbsp;investigation revealed that she allegedly began sexually abusing her student earlier this year. However, authorities did not say how the conduct came to light or how many times she had assaulted the student. The age of the alleged victim has also not been revealed,&nbsp;but grades six through eight attend Freehold Intermediate School.</p>

<p>She is currently being held at the Monmouth County jail in Freehold Township, pending a first appearance and detention hearing. A hearing will be conducted to determine whether she will continue to be detained while awaiting trial.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The prosecutor's office asked members of the public to provide more information about her activities. ''Anyone with information about Havemann-Niedrach's activities is being urged to contact MCPO Detective Dawn Correia at 800-533-7443,'' the release read.&nbsp;</p>

<p>As per her <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/allison-havemann-niedrach-b2108653/">LinkedIn profile</a>, Havemann-Niedrach has been a special education teacher at Freehold Intermediate School since March 2022. She has been a teacher or a substitute teacher at several schools dating back to 2008, according to her profile.</p>

<p>The teacher describes herself as: "Passionate, results-driven, and sincere educator. Poised and competent and thrives in performance-driven environments. Demonstrated history of a 'do what it takes' work ethic and truly differentiated instruction."</p>

<p>After the arrest, Asia Michael, the superintendent of the Freehold Borough School District&nbsp;sent an email to staff and parents that read, ''We have been informed that a former staff member has been arrested on allegations of third-degree aggravated sexual assault and inappropriate sexual conduct with a minor.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Please be assured that our district has been fully cooperative with the prosecutor's office since the outset of this investigation. The safety and well-being of our students and staff have been our top priority, and we took immediate measures to ensure their protection.''</p>

<p>The teacher's attorney, meanwhile, said in a statement that she ''maintains her innocence'' and refused to comment further.&nbsp;</p>

<p><br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/9rhebcr_allison-havemannniedrach_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The age of the alleged victim has not been revealed]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-discusses-trade-technology-global-issues-with-qatars-pm-mohammed-bin-abdulrahman-bin-jassim-al-thani-6004024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[S Jaishankar Discusses Trade, Technology, Global Issues With Qatar's PM]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/s-jaishankar-discusses-trade-technology-global-issues-with-qatars-pm-mohammed-bin-abdulrahman-bin-jassim-al-thani-6004024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 19:48:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday met Qatar's PM Mohammed bin Abdulrahman bin Jassim Al Thani and reviewed bilateral relationship, with a focus on political, trade, investment, energy, technology, culture and people-to-people ties.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar on Sunday met Qatar's Prime Minister Mohammed bin Abdulrahman bin Jassim Al Thani in Doha and reviewed bilateral relationship, with a focus on political, trade, investment, energy, technology, culture and people-to-people ties.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar, who arrived here on a day-long visit, also exchanged views on regional and global issues with Sheikh Mohammed, who also holds the portfolio as Foreign Minister.</p>

<p>"Delighted to meet PM and FM of Qatar @MBA_AlThani_ in Doha this afternoon. Conveyed the greetings and warm wishes of PM @narendramodi to H.H. The Amir and him," Mr Jaishankar said in a post in X.</p>

<p>"Reviewed our bilateral relationship focusing on political, trade, investment, energy, technology, culture and people-to-people ties. Exchanged views on regional and global issues. Appreciate his sharing insights on the Gaza situation," he said.</p>

<p>"Look forward to the further enhancement of India-Qatar relations and continued dialogue on issues of mutual interest," he added.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar's visit comes four-and-half months after Qatar released eight former Indian Navy personnel, who were sentenced to death after being arrested in August 2022.</p>

<p>Earlier in the day, Mr Jaishankar was received at the airport by Chief of Protocol Ibrahim Fakhroo.</p>

<p>The visit would "enable both sides to review various aspects of bilateral relations, including political, trade, investment, energy, security, cultural and people-to-people as well as the regional and international issues of mutual interest," the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) said in New Delhi on Saturday.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi visited Qatar from February 14 to 15 and held discussions with Qatar's Emir Sheikh Tamim bin Hamad Al Thani.</p>

<p>"India and Qatar share historic and friendly relations which are marked by regular exchange of high-level visits," the MEA said.&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/qhu3vijo_s-jaishankar-qatar-pm_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[S Jaishankar was received at the airport by Chief of Protocol Ibrahim Fakhroo.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swarm-of-ukrainian-drones-attack-russian-steel-mill-in-overnight-raid-6003961]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Swarm" Of Ukrainian Drones Attack Russian Steel Mill In Overnight Raid]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/swarm-of-ukrainian-drones-attack-russian-steel-mill-in-overnight-raid-6003961]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 19:36:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A "swarm" of Ukrainian drones targeted Russian steelmaker Novolipetsk Steel's facility in a raid in the early hours of Sunday, but it sustained no serious damage, a company spokesperson said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A "swarm" of Ukrainian drones targeted Russian steelmaker Novolipetsk Steel's facility in a raid in the early hours of Sunday, but it sustained no serious damage, a company spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The attack achieved no results other than causing extra welding work, the spokesperson said. Igor Artamonov, the governor of the Lipetsk region in western Russia where the steel mill is located, said in a separate statement that nine drones had been downed over the steel mill.</p>

<p>Kyiv does not officially confirm or deny such attacks, but says the facilities being hit are supporting Russia's war in Ukraine and are thus legitimate military targets.</p>

<p>NLMK denies cooperating with the defence ministry, saying that its Russian operations are not capable of producing military-grade heavy steels and it does not supply the military.</p>

<p>Russia's defence ministry said earlier that air defence systems had destroyed 36 drones launched by Ukraine overnight targeting several regions in Russia's southwest, including Lipetsk.</p>

<p>The ministry also said that Russian forces had taken over the villages of Spirne and Novooleksandrivka, which are in Ukraine's eastern Donetsk region, the Russian news agency RIA reported, the latest in a string of such incremental territorial claims.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/tht0vkjo_russia-ukraine_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The attack achieved no results other than causing extra welding work (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hostile-state-actors-uk-warns-of-russian-interference-in-general-election-6003526]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Hostile State Actors": UK Warns Of Russian Interference In General Polls]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hostile-state-actors-uk-warns-of-russian-interference-in-general-election-6003526]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 18:11:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Britain's deputy prime minister warned Sunday that the country's upcoming general election faces threats from hostile actors such as Russia seeking to influence the UK's democratic process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain's deputy prime minister warned Sunday that the country's upcoming general election faces threats from hostile actors such as Russia seeking to influence the UK's democratic process.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The country will go to the polls on Thursday, in an election expected to oust the governing right-wing Conservatives and put the opposition Labour party in power.&nbsp;</p>

<p>His comments came after the Australian Broadcasting Corporation reported that it had uncovered five Facebook pages spreading the same pro-Kremlin talking points.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Some of them encouraged support for the hard-right Reform UK party led by Brexiteer Nigel Farage -- a big challenger to the ruling Conservatives in Thursday's vote.</p>

<p>"There is a threat in all elections, and indeed we see it in this election from hostile state actors seeking to influence the outcome of the election campaign," Oliver Dowden told Sky News.</p>

<p>"Russia is a prime example of this, and this is a classic example from the Russian playbook," he added, noting however that the examples were "relatively typical, low-level stuff".</p>

<p>Farage -- an admirer of former US president Donald Trump -- dismissed claims that Russian bots might interfere in the election as "cobblers", using a British slang term for nonsense.</p>

<p>He has been criticised in the campaign for saying that the West provoked Russia's invasion of its neighbour Ukraine.</p>

<p>His anti-immigration party is tipped by pollsters to contribute to a landslide win by the centre left opposition Labour party by taking votes away from Prime Minister Rishi Sunak's Tories.</p>

<p>Labour has enjoyed poll leads of more than 20 points throughout the campaign, but Sunak insisted on Sunday that he will still be Prime Minister come Friday morning.</p>

<p>"I'm fighting very hard and I think people are waking up to the real danger of what a Labour government means," he told the BBC.</p>

<p>Labour, led by Keir Starmer, received another boost Sunday when the influential right-of-centre newspaper the Sunday Times endorsed his party. Music sensation Elton John also announced he was backing Labour.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/lpuf1at_oliver-dowden_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Russia is a prime example of this," Oliver Dowden said]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-lankan-fishermen-consume-contents-found-in-bottle-floating-in-sea-die-6003435]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[5 Lankan Fishermen Consume Contents Found In Bottle Floating In Sea, Die]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/5-lankan-fishermen-consume-contents-found-in-bottle-floating-in-sea-die-6003435]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:58:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Five Sri Lankan fishermen who had consumed the contents in a bottle floating in the sea on Saturday had died by Sunday afternoon, Navy Spokesman Captain Gayan Wickramasuriya said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five Sri Lankan fishermen who had consumed the contents in a bottle floating in the sea on Saturday had died by Sunday afternoon, Navy Spokesman Captain Gayan Wickramasuriya said.</p>

<p>The navy spokesman said the victims are a part of a six-man crew that sailed from the Tangalle Fisheries Harbour, reported Xinhua news agency.</p>

<p>They found the bottle around 320 nautical miles off the coast and had consumed its contents believed to be alcohol, he said.</p>

<p>Wickramasuriya said one survivor is in critical condition and currently receiving emergency treatment.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/ip1hsfag_fishermen-generic-pixabay-650_625x300_01_August_18.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bottle was around 320 nautical miles off the coast, said Navy Spokesman (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/part-of-tianlong-3-rocket-crashes-in-china-during-test-says-aerospace-firm-6003309]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Part Of Rocket Crashes In China During Test, Says Space Pioneer]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/part-of-tianlong-3-rocket-crashes-in-china-during-test-says-aerospace-firm-6003309]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:37:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Beijing Tianbing Technology Co said on Sunday that the first stage of its Tianlong-3 rocket under development had detached from its launch pad during a test due to structural failure and landed in a hilly area of the city of Gongyi in central China.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Beijing Tianbing Technology Co said on Sunday that the first stage of its Tianlong-3 rocket under development had detached from its launch pad during a test due to structural failure and landed in a hilly area of the city of Gongyi in central China.</p>

<p>There were no reports of casualties after an initial investigation, Beijing Tianbing, also known as Space Pioneer, said in a statement on its official WeChat account.</p>

<p>Parts of the rocket stage were scattered within a "safe area" but caused a local fire, according to a separate statement by the Gongyi Emergency Management Bureau.</p>

<p>The fire has since been extinguished and no one has been hurt, the bureau said.</p>

<p>The two-stage Tianlong-3 ("Sky Dragon 3") is a partly reusable rocket under development by Space Pioneer, one of a small group of rapidly growing private-sector rocket makers over the past five years.</p>

<p>Falling rocket debris in China after launches is not unheard of, but it is very rare for part of a rocket under development to make an unplanned flight out of its test site and crash.</p>

<p>According to Space Pioneer, the first stage of the Tianlong-3 ignited normally during a hot test but later detached from the test bench due to structural failure and landed in hilly areas 1.5 kms (0.9 miles) away.</p>

<p>The performance of Tianlong-3 is comparable to SpaceX's Falcon 9, according to Space Pioneer.</p>

<p>In April 2023, Space Pioneer launched a kerosene-oxygen rocket, the Tianlong-2, becoming the first private Chinese firm to send a liquid-propellant rocket into space.</p>

<p>Chinese commercial space companies have rushed into the sector since 2014 when private investment in the industry was allowed by the state.</p>

<p>Many started making satellites while others including Space Pioneer, focused on developing reusable rockets that can significantly cut mission costs.</p>

<p>The test sites of such companies can be found along China's coastal areas, located by the sea due to safety reasons.</p>

<p>But some are also sited deep in the country's interior such as Space Pioneer's test centre in Gongyi, a city of 800,000 people in the central province of Henan.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/pvolv39_china-rocket_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-hezbollah-members-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-lebanese-village-report-6003253]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[3 Hezbollah Members Killed In Israeli Strike On Lebanese Village: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/3-hezbollah-members-killed-in-israeli-airstrike-on-lebanese-village-report-6003253]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:25:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Three Hezbollah members were killed on Sunday in an Israeli airstrike in the southeast village of Houla, a media report said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three Hezbollah members were killed on Sunday in an Israeli airstrike in the southeast village of Houla, a media report said.</p>

<p>An Israeli drone targeted, with four air-to-surface missiles, a two-story building in Houla, killing three Hezbollah members and causing severe damage to neighbouring homes, Lebanese military sources told Xinhua.</p>

<p>The Israeli army conducted five air attacks on the villages of Taybeh, Rab El Thalathine, and Houla, and targeted eight towns and villages in the eastern and central regions with approximately 40 artillery shells, the sources added.</p>

<p>For its part, Hezbollah announced that it attacked the Israeli sites of Misqav Am, al-Motella, and Al-Alam.</p>

<p>Tensions along the Lebanon-Israel border escalated on October 8, 2023, following a barrage of rockets launched by Hezbollah toward Israel in solidarity with Hamas' attack on Israel the day before. Israel then retaliated by firing heavy artillery toward southeastern Lebanon.</p>

<p>Since the start of the confrontations on both sides of the border between Lebanon and Israel, 553 people have been killed, including 356 Hezbollah members and 100 civilians, according to Lebanese security and medical reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2021-10/6e8i71v_missile-generic_650x400_17_October_21.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Tensions along the Lebanon-Israel border escalated on October 8, 2023 (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-rapes-10-year-old-boy-in-pak-films-assault-for-blackmail-circulates-video-report-6003238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Man Rapes 10-Year-Old Boy In Pak, Films Assault, Circulates Video: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/man-rapes-10-year-old-boy-in-pak-films-assault-for-blackmail-circulates-video-report-6003238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:23:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A man allegedly raped a 10-year-old boy in Pakistan's Muzaffargarh, filmed the assault, and circulated the videos on social media to blackmail the child, the Dawn newspaper reported.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A man allegedly raped a 10-year-old boy in Pakistan's Muzaffargarh, filmed the assault, and circulated the videos on social media to blackmail the child, the Dawn newspaper reported. The police have registered a case and launched a manhunt to arrest the accused.</p>

<p>According to officials in Muzaffargarh's Bait Mir Hazar Khan police station, the accused lured the boy to a tubewell under the pretense of bathing. He then raped the boy and filmed the assault.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The videos were later used to coerce and blackmail the boy, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>In a separate incident near the Swabi-Haripur district in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, the police arrested two men accused of assaulting a girl. The survivor, identified as a relative of the suspects, underwent a medical examination which confirmed the assault, Dawn reported.</p>

<p>The police said an FIR was filed against the accused based on the survivor's statement before a magistrate. The suspects, Itikhar Khan and Sirtaj Khan are currently facing legal proceedings, they said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-06/rape-generic_650x400_41498025670.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The videos were used to coerce and blackmail the boy, Dawn reported (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-heavy-battles-bombardment-hit-gaza-city-shujaiya-for-fourth-day-6003121]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Heavy Battles, Bombardment Hit Gaza City Shujaiya For Fourth Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-heavy-battles-bombardment-hit-gaza-city-shujaiya-for-fourth-day-6003121]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 17:03:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Heavy battles and bombardment hit Gaza City's Shujaiya district for a fourth day on Sunday, months after the Israeli army declared Hamas's command structure dismantled in the northern area.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Heavy battles and bombardment hit Gaza City's Shujaiya district for a fourth day on Sunday, months after the Israeli army declared Hamas's command structure dismantled in the northern area.</p>

<p>Tens of thousands of Palestinians have fled the devastated neighbourhood, where the army said it has fought Hamas and Islamic Jihad operatives both "above and below ground" in tunnels.</p>

<p>The military said troops had "eliminated several terrorists, located weapons and conducted targeted raids on booby-trapped combat compounds" over the past 24 hours while the air force had "struck dozens" of the operatives' infrastructure sites.</p>

<p>It also reported clashes in central Gaza and the southern Rafah area, a week after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declared that the "intense phase" of the war raging since October 7 was nearing an end.</p>

<p>The United Nations humanitarian agency OCHA estimated that "60,000 to 80,000 people were displaced" from Shujaiya since new fighting broke out there on Thursday and the army issued evacuation orders.</p>

<p>Months of on-and-off talks towards a Gaza truce and hostage release deal have meanwhile made little progress, with Hamas saying Saturday there was "nothing new" in a revised plan presented by US mediators.</p>

<p>United States President Joe Biden late last month outlined what he called an Israeli plan for a six-week truce and exchange of some hostages for Palestinian prisoners held in Israel.</p>

<p>Washington last week presented "new language" for parts of the proposed deal, according to US news site Axios.</p>

<p>A Hamas official in Lebanon, Osama Hamdan, confirmed that the Islamist movement had received the latest proposal but said it presented "no real progress in the negotiations to stop the aggression".</p>

<p>Hamdan labelled the proposals "a waste of time" that aimed to give "additional time for the occupation (Israel) to practise genocide".</p>

<h3><strong>'Everything is rubble'</strong></h3>

<p>The war started with Hamas's October 7 attack on southern Israel which resulted in the deaths of 1,195 people, mostly civilians, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli figures.</p>

<p>The Hamas also seized 251 hostages, 116 of whom remain in Gaza although the army says 42 are dead.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,877 people, also mostly civilians, according to data from the health ministry in Hamas-run Gaza.</p>

<p>Six more people were killed in an air strike at dawn targeting a family house in Rafah, said medics at Nasser Hospital where the bodies were taken.</p>

<p>Artillery shelling also struck southern areas of Rafah city, witnesses said.</p>

<p>United Nations and other relief agencies have voiced alarm over the dire humanitarian crisis and threat of starvation the war and Israeli siege have brought for Gaza's 2.4 million people.</p>

<p>"It's really unbearable," said Louise Wateridge from UNRWA, the UN agency supporting Palestinian refugees, speaking Friday after returning to the city of Khan Yunis.</p>

<p>"Everything is rubble," she said. "And yet people are living there again... There's no water there, there's no sanitation, there's no food. And now, people are living back in these buildings that are empty shells."</p>

<p>In Israel, thousands of protesters again took to the streets of Tel Aviv on Saturday night, demanding greater efforts to return the remaining captives, and calling for early elections.</p>

<p>Former hostage Noa Argamani, 26, who was rescued in a special forces raid on June 8, said in a video address that "we can't forget about the hostages who are still in Hamas captivity, and we must do everything possible to bring them back home".</p>

<h3><strong>'An obliterating war'</strong></h3>

<p>The Gaza conflict has also led to soaring tensions on Israel's northern border with Lebanon, where the army has traded cross-border fire with the Hezbollah movement since October.</p>

<p>Hezbollah is part of the "axis of resistance" of Iran-backed armed groups against Israel and its Western allies. The grouping also includes&nbsp;operatives in Iraq and Yemen's Huthi rebels.</p>

<p>Israel's military said this month that its plans for a Lebanon offensive had been "approved and validated", prompting Hezbollah to respond that no part of Israel would be spared in a full-blown conflict.</p>

<p>Iran's mission to the UN, on social media Saturday, said it "deems as psychological warfare the Zionist regime's propaganda about intending to attack Lebanon".</p>

<p>It also warned its arch foe that, "should it embark on full-scale military aggression, an obliterating war will ensue".&nbsp;</p>

<p>"All options, incl. the full involvement of all Resistance Fronts, are on the table."</p>

<p>Iran, which backs Hamas, has praised the October 7 attack as a success but has denied any involvement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/6ehhjnoo_shujaiya_625x300_30_June_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel's retaliatory offensive has killed at least 37,877 people]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-woman-teen-daughter-bricked-into-wall-over-property-dispute-6003067]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistan Woman, Teen Daughter Bricked Into Wall Over Property Dispute]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistan-woman-teen-daughter-bricked-into-wall-over-property-dispute-6003067]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 30 Jun 2024 16:54:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A distressing incident unfolded in Hyderabad where a woman and her teenage daughter were allegedly bricked into a wall by their relatives following a property dispute, according to a report by ARY News.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A distressing incident unfolded in Hyderabad where a woman and her teenage daughter were allegedly bricked into a wall by their relatives following a property dispute, according to a report by ARY News.</p>

<p>The incident took place in the Latifabad No 5 area, prompting swift action from police and concerned neighbours who broke down the wall to rescue the trapped victims. The woman said that her brother-in-law, identified as Suhail, along with his sons, had confined them inside a room before constructing a wall outside to seal them in.</p>

<p>The victim further accused Suhail of persistent harassment and claimed he also possessed critical documents pertaining to their house, ARY News reported.</p>

<p>Law enforcement promptly responded by registering a case against the accused, assuring the public of their commitment to apprehending those responsible. Senior Superintendent of Police (SSP) Dr. Farrukh Linjar assured the public that legal proceedings were underway to hold accountable those who perpetrated such a heinous act of confinement.</p>

<p>On May 24, a tragic incident in the Chamkani area of Peshawar resulted in the deaths of at least five individuals due to a property dispute, according to police sources.</p>

<p>Authorities reported that the violence erupted when two factions engaged in gunfire, resulting in the fatalities. The police have filed a First Information Report (FIR), noting that the conflict had been ongoing between the groups for an extended period.</p>

<p>It is noteworthy that similar instances of violence stemming from personal animosity or land disputes have occurred in the past, ARY News reported.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/jst1efug_wall-generic_625x300_01_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>