<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:48:17 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-when-and-where-to-watch-the-us-presidential-debate-6505796]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Harris vs Trump: When And Where To Watch The US Presidential Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-when-and-where-to-watch-the-us-presidential-debate-6505796]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:47:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his Democratic rival Kamala Harris will take the stage for their first televised debate today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump and his Democratic rival Kamala Harris will take the stage for their first televised debate today. Ahead of the November 5 presidential election in the US, this will be the first and probably the only chance for around 240 million voters to watch their candidates debate and argue over policies of national and international concern.<br />
<br />
<strong>TRUMP-HARRIS PRESIDENTIAL DEBATE</strong></p>

<p>The June presidential debate between Donald Trump and Joe Biden was a disappointing one for the outgoing President. Weeks after that, President Biden decided to withdraw from the race, setting the stage for US Vice President Kamala Harris to run for the top office.</p>

<p>While today's debate is a chance for Harris to establish her political identity for millions of people who will tune in to watch, it also affords Trump yet another opportunity to showcase that he is prepared to lead the country again.</p>

<p>For Kamala Harris, it is an opportunity to lay out her priorities and prove her mettle against Trump, who has in recent times subjected her to racist and sexist attacks. The former US president will once again attempt to blunt Harris' momentum in the presidential race, which has tightened considerably after she was named the Democratic nominee, as per polls.</p>

<p><strong>WHEN AND WHAT TIME IS THE TRUMP-HARRIS DEBATE?</strong></p>

<p>Hosted by ABC News, the 90-minute debate is scheduled at 9 PM ET on September 10 (6:30 AM on September 11 in India) at the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>The debate will be moderated by David Muir and Linsey Davis.</p>

<p><strong>WHERE TO WATCH?</strong></p>

<p>The first presidential debate between Donald Trump and Kamala Harris will be aired on ABC and streamed across ABC News Live as well as Disney+ and Hulu. Besides them, several networks have also agreed to carry the event live.</p>

<p><strong>RULES OF THE DEBATE</strong></p>

<p>As far as the rules are concerned, ABC News will likely mirror the format used during the Trump- Biden debate in June by CNN.</p>

<p>The two candidates - Trump and Harris - will get two minutes to answer along with two-minute rebuttals. There will be an additional minute for each candidate for any clarifications and follow-ups.</p>

<p>This debate will also have no live audience, while the two candidates will stand for the entire debate.<br />
&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/ugf3uu1g_trump-harris-_625x300_22_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and Donald Trump will go head on in a debate ahead of the US Presidential election]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/these-are-the-5-rules-of-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-debate-6534850]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[These Are The 5 Rules Of Kamala Harris vs Donald Trump Debate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/these-are-the-5-rules-of-kamala-harris-vs-donald-trump-debate-6534850]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:21:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Top runners for the US presidential race, Kamala Harris and Donald Trump, will face off in their first-ever debate tomorrow. The much-anticipated debate has specific rules in place.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>The debate, hosted by US broadcaster ABC, will be aired live at 6:30 am IST with no audience present in the room. ABC anchors David Muir and Linsey Davis will moderate it. It will run for 90 minutes and have two commercial breaks.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>The candidates' mics will be on only when it is their turn to speak and will be muted otherwise. The questions will only be asked by the moderators and will not be shared with the candidates priorly.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>There will be no opening statements by the candidates. They will get two minutes each to answer every question and the opponent will get two minutes for a counter. They will also get an extra minute for "a follow-up, clarification, or response". Both the candidates will give a two-minute closing statement. Donald Trump will go last as decided after a virtual coin toss.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Both the candidates will be given a pen, pad of paper and water bottle with no props and pre-written notes allowed. They will stand behind their podiums throughout the debate.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>There will be no interaction between the candidates and their campaign staff during the commercial breaks.&nbsp;<br />
	&nbsp;</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/h6f1vgsg_harris-trump-split_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US Presidential elections will be held in November this year (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uae-inks-pact-for-india-to-operate-nuclear-power-plants-in-gulf-nation-6534555]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UAE Inks Pact For India To Operate Nuclear Power Plants In Gulf Nation]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uae-inks-pact-for-india-to-operate-nuclear-power-plants-in-gulf-nation-6534555]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:01:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United Aarb Emirates or UAE has inked an agreement with India that provides a framework for giving services for operation and maintenance of nuclear power plants in the emirate.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United Aarb Emirates or UAE has inked an agreement with India that provides a framework for giving services for operation and maintenance of nuclear power plants in the emirate.</p>

<p>The Memorandum of Understanding was signed by Bhuwan Chandra Pathak, Chairman and Managing Director of the Nuclear Power Corporation of India Limited (NPCIL), and Mohamed Al Hammadi, the Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer of the Emirates Nuclear Energy Corporation (ENEC) of the UAE.</p>

<p>The MoU was inked during the ongoing visit of Abu Dhabi Crown Prince Sheikh Khaled bin Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan to India.</p>

<p>The Crown Prince held India-UAE bilateral discussions with Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Monday.</p>

<p>"The MoU provides a general framework for the possible collaboration between the NPCIL &amp; ENEC in the relevant fields, which inter alia include developing supply chains, sharing experience and providing services for Operation &amp; Maintenance of Nuclear Energy Plants, providing nuclear consulting services, human resources development &amp; training, research and development etc," a statement by the NPCIL said.</p>

<p>The NPCIL is a Public Sector Enterprise of the Department of Atomic Energy and operates all civil nuclear power plants in the country.</p>

<p>The ENEC is wholly owned by the Abu Dhabi Development Holding Company PJSC, which in turn is wholly owned by the government of the UAE.</p>

<p>"The signing of this MoU marks a significant step in the growing cooperation between India and the UAE in peaceful uses of nuclear energy," the NPCIL statement said today.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2017-03/nuclear-reactor-istock_650x400_51490779852.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[UAE and India inked a pact for India to operate nuclear plants in the Gulf nation. (Reprensetational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-strollers-outsell-baby-strollers-in-country-with-worlds-lowest-birth-rate-report-6534440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dog Strollers Outsell Baby Strollers In Country With Lowest Birth Rate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/dog-strollers-outsell-baby-strollers-in-country-with-worlds-lowest-birth-rate-report-6534440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 19:23:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Data from Gmarket shows that 57% of strollers sold this year are for pets, highlighting a significant shift as the countrys fertility rate hits a record low of 0.72.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea is facing an urgent problem with its declining fertility rate as the world's population dynamics change. In South Korea, dog strollers are now more popular than baby strollers, according to recent studies. This result highlights a more general issue over the nation's fast diminishing birth rate, which as of 2023 fell to a historic low.</p>

<p>Citing a report from the Gmarket, an e-commerce platform operator, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/culture/2024/09/135_365753.html"><em>The Korea Times, </em></a>reported that sales of pet strollers have exceeded those of baby strollers this year for the first time. Data released on Sunday showed that 43 percent of the total number of strollers sold on the platform during the first three quarters of this year were for human infants, while the remaining 57 percent were strollers designed for animals, mainly dogs and cats.</p>

<p>The ratio of infant stroller sales among the total strollers kept falling from 67 percent in 2021 and 64 percent in 2020 to 43 percent this year, meaning the ratio for pet strollers continued to rise from 33 percent in 2021 to 36 percent in 2022 and 57 percent this year.</p>

<p>The news portal reported, citing data from Statistics Korea, that the total fertility rate-the average number of children that would be born per woman-was 0.78 in 2022, the lowest in the world. The figure is forecast to drop even further. The national statistical organisation said the fertility rate is expected to be 0.72 this year and fall below 0.7 to 0.68 in 2024 before rising again.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the number of households raising pets is increasing. Data from the Ministry of Agriculture, Food, and Rural Affairs shows that more than 6 million households had pets last year, compared to 3.6 million in 2012.</p>

<p>In South Korea, the situation is particularly acute, with the declining birth rate reflecting broader socio-economic challenges, including the high cost of living and housing. As South Korea grapples with these demographic shifts, the rising popularity of dog strollers over baby strollers serves as a symbolic indicator of the nation's struggle with low birth rates and changing societal priorities.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0ue9tc4o_pet-stroller_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The rise in pet stroller sales reflects broader socio-economic challenges.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/6-dangerous-asteroids-on-collision-course-with-earth-first-one-may-hit-in-october-6534117]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Asteroids On Collision Course With Earth, First One May Hit In October]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/6-dangerous-asteroids-on-collision-course-with-earth-first-one-may-hit-in-october-6534117]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 18:42:03 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Asteroid Bennu, discovered in 1999, currently poses the greatest risk of impacting our planet.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Wednesday, scientists across the world were surprised by the unexpected entry of a previously undetected asteroid into Earth's atmosphere. The small asteroid, designated 2024 RW1 and measuring just one meter (3ft) in width, was only identified a mere eight hours before it blazed across the sky above the Philippines. Fortunately, the asteroid was too tiny to pose any damage.&nbsp;However, this unexpected event serves as a stark reminder of the potential hazards lurking in our solar system, highlighting the need for monitoring and&nbsp;efforts to better prepare for future asteroid encounters.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Experts warn that several asteroids are at risk of smashing into Earth, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.livescience.com/space/asteroids/nasas-most-wanted-the-5-most-dangerous-asteroids-in-the-solar-system">Live Science</a></em> reported.</p>

<h3><strong>1. Bennu</strong></h3>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Meet Bennu.<br />
<br />
Bennu is a near-Earth asteroid that is being explored by NASA's OSIRIS-REx mission. OSIRIS-REx arrived on Bennu in Dec. 2018 and expected to find a surface similar to a sandy beach. Expectations did not match reality.<br />
<br />
Full episode: <a href="https://t.co/xH4Gz1RZJb">https://t.co/xH4Gz1RZJb</a> <a href="https://t.co/uUtLA2I6kf">pic.twitter.com/uUtLA2I6kf</a></p>
— NASA Artemis (@NASAArtemis) <a href="https://twitter.com/NASAArtemis/status/1234320058865913856?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 2, 2020</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>Asteroid Bennu, discovered in 1999, currently poses the greatest risk of impacting our planet.&nbsp;Measuring 1,574ft in diameter and weighing 67 million tonnes, it's wider than the Empire State Building and 200 times heavier. NASA observations indicate a 1 in 2,700 chance of impact on September 24, 2182. If Bennu collides with Earth, it would release energy equivalent to 1.4 billion tonnes of TNT, surpassing the combined energy of all nuclear weapons ever detonated.</p>

<h3><strong>2. 2023 DW - The Valentine's Day asteroid</strong></h3>

<p>Asteroid 2023 DW is predicted to have a significant chance of colliding with Earth on February 14, 2046. With a diameter of 166ft (50m), it's comparable in size to the asteroid that caused the destructive Chelyabinsk event in 2013. Travelling at 21.78 km/s relative to the sun, a potential impact could level an entire city. Initially, space agencies estimated a concerning 1 in 607 chance of collision. However, recent observations have significantly reduced the risk.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>3.&nbsp;1950 DA</strong></h3>

<p>Asteroid 1950 DA, measures a massive 4,265ft (1.3km) in diameter and weighs 71 million tonnes. Its massive size and potential impact make it the most significant threat to Earth, with a collision releasing energy equivalent to detonating 75 billion tons of TNT, capable of triggering a global catastrophe on the scale of the dinosaur extinction event. Currently, the asteroid has a 1 in 34,500 chance of impacting Earth on March 16, 2880. In 2032, it will safely pass within 6,959,357 miles (112,000,000 km). In preparation for potential future threats, NASA and ESA are already testing asteroid deflection methods, including high-speed satellite collisions, to push dangerous asteroids off course.</p>

<h3><strong>4. 2023 TL4</strong></h3>

<p>Asteroid 2023 TL4, discovered last year, has been identified as a potentially civilisation-ending threat due to its massive size and weight. Measuring 1,083ft (0.33km) in diameter and weighing 43 million tonnes, this space rock could unleash a blast 150 times more powerful than the Tsar Bomba. Fortunately, scientists have estimated a relatively low collision risk of 1 in 181,000 on October 10, 2119, providing ample time for space agencies to take action.</p>

<h3><strong>5.</strong>&nbsp;<strong>2007 FT3</strong></h3>

<p>Asteroid 2007 FT3 is classified as a "lost asteroid" since it was last observed in 2007. Despite the uncertainty, NASA estimates a low probability of impact, with a 1 in 10 million chance (0.0000096%) of striking Earth on March 3, 2030, and a slightly lower chance of 1 in 11.5 million (0.0000087%) on October 5, 2024. If an impact were to occur in either year, the asteroid's energy release would be equivalent to 2.6 billion tons of TNT, potentially causing regional devastation, but unlikely to trigger a global catastrophe.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 id="5-1979-xb-3"><strong>6. 1979 XB</strong></h3>

<p>Asteroid 1979 XB, unseen for approximately 40 years, is another "lost asteroid". Despite the uncertainty, scientists have estimated a 1 in 1.8 million chance (0.000055%) of impact on December 14, 2113, based on observations from its initial discovery on December 11, 1979. If 1979 XB were to collide with Earth, the impact would release an enormous amount of energy, equivalent to the detonation of 30 billion tons of TNT.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>Asteroids colliding with Earth</strong></h2>

<p>Asteroid collisions with Earth are surprisingly common, with NASA estimating 48.5 tonnes of meteoric material entering our atmosphere daily. Most burn up, producing shooting stars. However, larger objects that pierce the atmosphere and impact Earth are rare.&nbsp;Just because asteroid collisions are unlikely, it does not mean they are impossible.&nbsp;</p>

<p>To mitigate this risk, NASA and the European Space Agency operate programs to identify, categorise, and track Near Earth Objects (NEOs). These initiatives help monitor potential threats, ensuring we're better prepared for an asteroid impact.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/un15ft5k_asteroid-generic_625x300_06_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Just because asteroid collisions are unlikely, it does not mean they are impossible.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bmw-recalls-1-5-million-cars-over-faulty-brakes-6534079]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[BMW Recalls 1.5 Million Cars Over Faulty Brakes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bmw-recalls-1-5-million-cars-over-faulty-brakes-6534079]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 18:39:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[BMW said Tuesday it was recalling about 1.5 million vehicles due to problems with their brakes and cut its outlook for the year, sending the German luxury carmaker's shares tumbling.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>BMW said Tuesday it was recalling about 1.5 million vehicles due to problems with their brakes and cut its outlook for the year, sending the German luxury carmaker's shares tumbling.</p>

<p>The recall will have a "negative worldwide sales effect in the second half of the year," said the group, which also includes the Rolls-Royce and Mini brands.</p>

<p>The financial impact in the three months to the end of September will be in the "high three-digit million" euro range, it said.</p>

<p>It was further bad news for BMW, which has been hit by weakening demand in China, and for the broader German auto sector after Volkswagen said last week it was mulling the unprecedented step of closing factories in Germany.</p>

<p>The braking system behind the problems was supplied by Continental, a source close to the matter told AFP.</p>

<p>As well as the impact of the recall, "the ongoing muted demand in China is affecting sales volumes. Despite stimulus measures from the government, consumer sentiment remains weak," BMW said in a statement.</p>

<p>Munich-headquartered BMW now expects a slight decrease in vehicle deliveries this year compared to last, having previously forecast a slight increase.</p>

<p>It did not give a precise figure. In 2023 deliveries of BMW, Rolls-Royce and Mini vehicles stood at 2.56 million.</p>

<p>The automaker also trimmed its guidance for profitability, and expects margins this year between six and seven percent, down from eight to 10 previously.</p>

<p>The carmaker's shares were down nine percent on the Frankfurt Stock Exchange after the announcement.</p>

<p>Last month BMW also recalled 1.4 million vehicles in China due to faulty airbags, the country's market regulator announced.</p>

<p>BMW reported a drop in net profit in the second quarter, due to the impact of poorer business in China and higher manufacturing costs.</p>

<p>Net profit at the group declined by 8.6 percent to 2.7 billion euros ($2.9 billion) between April and June, on the back of revenues down 0.7 percent to just under 37 billion euros.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2022-01/1kcopsc_bmw-generic_625x300_15_January_22.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[BMW has also been hit by weakening demand in China (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-apple-launches-iphone-16-lineup-airpods-and-more-6533990]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Pics: Apple Launches iPhone 16 Lineup, AirPods And More]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-pics-apple-launches-iphone-16-lineup-airpods-and-more-6533990]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 18:25:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tech giant Apple on Monday introduced new the new iPhone 16 series enabled with artificial intelligence, larger display sizes, a new camera control button and a big leap in battery life.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tech giant Apple on Monday introduced new the new iPhone 16 series enabled with artificial intelligence, larger display sizes, a new camera control button and a big leap in battery life.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/4nf2lvmg_iphone-16-lineup-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/0530d5do_iphone-16-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/teljifc8_iphone-16-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><br />
The new models of the iPhone 16 being displayed after Apple's 'It's Glowtime' event in Cupertino, California. The iPhone 16 starts at ₹79,900 and iPhone 16 Plus starts at ₹89,900.&nbsp;</p>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/1rmm5n_iphone-16-pro-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>A person holds up the new iPhone 16 Pro following Apple's main event.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/30c6sb9g_iphone-16-pro-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mtf2gkio_iphone-16-pro-lineup-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The Pro models are equipped with the new A18 Pro chip, which have an increased memory bandwidth that enable the devices to undertake complex AI tasks.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/32402dqo_apple-watch-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The company also unveiled the new Apple Watch series 10, which boasts the largest-ever display on the standard Apple Watch lineup.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/qcbrpp4o_apple-watch-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>At 9.7mm, Apple says the device is its thinnest-ever Apple Watch.&nbsp;Another noticeable feature of the watch is the inclusion of a sleep apnoea detection feature.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/674h6bfo_airpods-4-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p></p>

<p>Apple also unveiled the new AirPods 4. This year's base model also includes the active noise cancellation feature.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rnb6uqbg_airpods-max_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/j8taqlq_airpods-max-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>&nbsp;The tech giant also introduced AirPods Max in new colours - Midnight, Blue, Purple, Orange and Starlight.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/7n02rtl_tim-cook-event-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Apple CEO Tim Cook shows the new iPhone 16 following the event at the company's headquarters.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ofh2h1kg_apple-event-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-rejects-9-5-jobs-76-aim-to-be-their-own-boss-poll-6533790]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Gen Z Rejects 9-5 Jobs, 76% Aim To Be Their Own Boss: Poll]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gen-z-rejects-9-5-jobs-76-aim-to-be-their-own-boss-poll-6533790]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:57:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A recent poll reveals that 76% of Generation Z, compared to 57% of millennials and lower percentages of Gen X and baby boomers, prefer entrepreneurship over traditional 9-5 jobs.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Confident and digitally savvy, Gen Z is set to outshine millennials with their entrepreneurial spirit. A new poll highlights a growing trend of young people choosing to start their own businesses rather than work for others.</p>

<p>The research by<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.santander.co.uk/about-santander/media-centre/press-releases/santander-shortlists-100-uk-start-ups-for-its-2024"> Santander UK </a>revealed that three quarters of Gen Z are seeking to "be their own boss" and are not planning to work a nine-to-five job for the rest of their career. 77 percent are confident in their ability to launch and run a successful business, and 39 percent back themselves to do so from their smartphone.</p>

<p>Half of those polled said that Gen Z and Millennials have an advantage when it comes to starting a business because they grew up in the digital age. In comparison, Gen X and Boomers say there were fewer opportunities to start a business in their younger years (34%) as there was more pressure to follow a traditional education and career path.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Gen Z is proving to be the most entrepreneurial generation yet, and it's no coincidence. Unlike previous generations, they've grown up fully immersed in the digital age, where information, tools, and global connections are just a click away. &nbsp;This constant exposure has fostered a mindset that values innovation and agility. &nbsp;With a deep understanding of digital landscapes, they're not just prepared to start their own ventures - they're uniquely positioned to outpace previous generations in turning ideas into reality," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.santander.co.uk/about-santander/media-centre/press-releases/santander-shortlists-100-uk-start-ups-for-its-2024">said Sam Jones,</a> Dragon's Den star and &nbsp;founder of Gener8.</p>

<p>"It's clear that digital-savvy Gen Z have a fantastic entrepreneurial spirit, but the qualities you need to succeed on your own aren't bound by age - entrepreneurship is driven by passion, curiosity, and the desire to create something meaningful. Some develop these attributes early on, often sparked by a need to solve a problem. While others may discover a business drive later in life, perhaps after spotting a gap in the market," said Mike Regnier, CEO, Santander UK.</p>

<p>The survey of 2,000 adults found that while Gen Z and millennials may be perceived as the most entrepreneurial, age is not a barrier to success.</p>

<p>This year, Santander saw more than 850 businesses apply for the awards, with Gen Z making up two-thirds of those that applied. The 100 that have been shortlisted cover a range of industries, including healthcare, sustainability, AI, and tech.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ma022ev8_social-media-influencer_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Of those surveyed, 39% of Gen Z believe they can start a business via smartphone.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-or-cop29-west-will-keep-choosing-politics-over-climate-6533701]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: G20 Or COP29, West Will Keep Choosing Politics Over Climate]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/g20-or-cop29-west-will-keep-choosing-politics-over-climate-6533701]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:42:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While US ambivalence on international commitments for climate change is known, the Europeans, who project themselves as champions of climate action, are now prevaricating too.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/00f2d6kg_climate_625x300_10_September_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Come November and climate activists get excited as the annual United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) Conference of Parties (COP) takes place. This year, the COP (29th edition) will be held in Baku, Azerbaijan, from November 11 to November 22. The month will also see the G20 Summit on November 18-19 in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. With the G20 also focussed on sustainable development and climate change, there is every reason for expectations to be raised.</p>

<p>In 2021, the G20 met in Italy just before the Glasgow COP, and it would be fair to surmise that the G7 pressure within the G20 for "Net Zero by 2050" saw both China and India also sign on to the Net Zero pledge, albeit for 2060 and 2070, respectively.</p>

<h2><strong>NCGQ: The Next 'Big' Goal</strong></h2>

<p>Among Brazil's overarching G20 priorities is "energy transitions and sustainable development". They have already established the G20 Task Force on Global Mobilization against Climate Change. Furthermore, they will host the COP in 2025, where the updated (target date for submission is early 2025) Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs), the voluntary goals on climate action taken by all countries, will be subject to a global stocktake.</p>

<p>The big-ticket item at Baku is a New Collective Quantified Goal (NCQG) on climate financing. At the Copenhagen COP in 2009, developed countries agreed to provide $100 billion a year for climate action to developing countries. A decade and a half later, and after stretching the data by all sorts of inclusions, the OECD has now declared that the developing countries met their target in 2022. Voila!</p>

<p>At its COP in Paris in 2015, the UNFCCC had agreed that a new and collective - not individual country commitments - quantified financing goal would be established. In the decade since, several key matters remain stalled, including the elusive number for the NCQG that developing countries want to know and are calling for. India has called for $1 trillion a year, and the Azeris have proposed &nbsp;$6 trillion till 2030.</p>

<h2><strong>Developed Nations Won't Assume Full Responsibility</strong></h2>

<p>Additionally, there are other critical unresolved issues, including who would contribute to this. Developed countries are unlikely to agree that it is their responsibility alone, putting China - rightly - on the mat, but also pressuring large developing countries like India to come on board the contributing side.</p>

<p>Presidential elections will be held in the US on November 5, and at this stage, former President Donald Trump stands an even chance of coming back. In 2016, soon after becoming President, he pulled the US out of the 2015 Paris Agreement on climate change. This despite Paris meeting the key US condition of jettisoning the cardinal UNFCCC principle of common and differentiated responsibilities and asking all countries to put forth NDCs. Years earlier, the US had not ratified the Kyoto Protocol on quantified emissions reductions by developed countries.</p>

<p>While US ambivalence on international commitments for climate change is known, the Europeans, who project themselves as champions of climate action, are now prevaricating too, with cutbacks on their domestic action and trade moves, all to penalise developing countries over their exports to the European Union (EU) for exceeding predetermined carbon limits in the products. The stress on their economies and energy security resulting from the Ukraine-Russia conflict are the articulated reasons for the European pullback on climate. But their thrust joins the US in the shirking of historical and capacity responsibilities and trying to shift the burden for climate action onto large developing countries.</p>

<h2><strong>Politics And Climate Can't Be Divorced</strong></h2>

<p>The G20 meeting is a summit and is expected to be attended by member countries at the level of heads of state or governments. But no matter its economic focus, it is intertwined with politics, as evidenced by references to the Russia-Ukraine conflict being the make or break of its declarations at Bali and New Delhi. Russian President Vladimir Putin didn't attend the G20 summits in Bali and New Delhi, but the Brazilians have been public in their urging of his presence at Rio. They are similarly pursuing President Xi of China.</p>

<p>The Brazilians have ace diplomats, but squaring their national, hemispheric and global interests could be a tall order. Indeed, with Ukraine being central to his administration's concern, could Rio see President Biden excuse himself? In any case, with US elections scheduled for November 5, Biden will either way be a "caretaker" till January 2025.</p>

<p>At Copenhagen, former US President Barack Obama had demurred on $30 billion per year till 2030 as the short-term financing goal, stating that budgets were Congress's domain. The world then got the expression "approaching" $30 billion. The US team at Baku would have an even better way out. In such circumstances, it is understandable that countries may not reveal their climate hands this fall. Will politics trump climate? Only November will tell, but the key date is neither COP nor the G20 Summit.</p>

<p><em>[The author is a former Indian ambassador to the European Union and a Distinguished Fellow, The Energy and Resources Institute (TERI)]&nbsp;</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/agc6ebco_climate_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/canada-man-spots-suspicious-pit-on-google-maps-experts-say-it-could-be-meteorite-impact-crater-6533521]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Canada Man Spots Suspicious Pit On Google Maps, Experts Say It Could Be...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/canada-man-spots-suspicious-pit-on-google-maps-experts-say-it-could-be-meteorite-impact-crater-6533521]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:21:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Experts now believe the suspicious pit may be a massive crater created by an ancient meteor.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a fascinating discovery, a Canadian man stumbled upon a mysterious, massive hole while browsing Google Maps. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/montreal/quebec-meteorite-impact-crater-1.7313418" rel="nofollow, noindex">CBS News,&nbsp;</a></em>Joel Lapointe discovered this while he was browsing the map of Quebec's Cote-Nord in Canada while planning a camping trip. As he zoomed in on the unusual feature,&nbsp;he stumbled upon a mysterious, spherical pit approximately 9.3 miles (15 km) across, surrounding Marsal Lake.&nbsp;The shape and symmetry of the formation caught his attention, and he wondered if it could be a natural phenomenon or something more extraordinary.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Lapoite then&nbsp;reached out to experts for guidance and connected with French geophysicist Pierre Rochette, who is now leading a team of scientists to investigate the site as a potential meteorite impact crater. "The topography is very suggestive of an impact," Mr Rochette noted.</p>

<p></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Potential meteorite impact crater discovered in Quebec's Côte-Nord region! Researchers are studying samples and hope to visit the 15 km-wide site in 2025. This could be a major find, as the last crater of this size was found in 2013. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Meteorite?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Meteorite</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Crater?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Crater</a> <a href="https://t.co/1DUDsAi8Nr">pic.twitter.com/1DUDsAi8Nr</a></p>
— Astron Verse (@AstronVerse) <a href="https://twitter.com/AstronVerse/status/1833455111554928707?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The team has already received samples from the site, and preliminary analysis reveals that at least one contains zircon, a mineral that transforms the intense pressure and heat of a meteorite impact.&nbsp;Mr Rochette said the discovery of such a site would be "major" since the last meteorite of this size was discovered in 2013.</p>

<p>While the initial findings suggest that the crater may have been formed by an ancient meteorite impact, experts are still waiting for the results of all the ongoing tests and analyses before making a definitive statement.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to <a data-wpel-link="external" href="https://spaceplace.nasa.gov/impact-crater/en/" rel="follow external noopener" target="_blank"><em>NASA</em>,</a>&nbsp;an impact crater is formed when an object like an asteroid or meteorite crashes into the surface of a larger solid object like a planet or a moon.&nbsp;Tara Hayden, a postdoctoral associate at Western University's Department of Earth Sciences, noted that some craters can have origins dating back millions or even hundreds of millions of years. The meteorites that form these craters can be diverse in type and may have originated from ancient planets or even some of the earliest materials from the solar system.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"It could tell us about when it was delivered to Earth. That's the wonderful thing about impact craters. We get to have this link between Earth and the outside universe,'' Ms Hayden said.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/9oee54kg_crater_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The last time such a crater was discovered was back in 2013.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/lotions-sunscreens-linked-to-hormonal-disruptions-in-children-study-finds-6533234]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lotions, Sunscreens Linked To Hormonal Disruptions In Children, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/lotions-sunscreens-linked-to-hormonal-disruptions-in-children-study-finds-6533234]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:49:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A new study links personal care products like lotions and hair conditioners to elevated levels of endocrine-disrupting chemicals called phthalates in young children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A recent study found a worrying correlation between the use of personal care products including lotions, hair oils, hair conditioners, ointments, and sunscreen, and higher levels of phthalates in young children, according to the new study by George Mason University College of Public Health.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://ehp.niehs.nih.gov/doi/10.1289/EHP13937">the study</a>, depending on the children's racial and ethnic origin, different quantities of these chemicals-known for their endocrine-disrupting qualities-were identified. Phthalates are frequently utilised in plastics to improve their flexibility and durability; they are also found in a lot of personal hygiene products.</p>

<p>Researchers are concerned about possible effects on children's development during important growth phases since these chemicals mimic, inhibit, or interact with the body's natural hormones.</p>

<p>"This is the first study to suggest that different skin care products used by young children may differentially increase exposure to endocrine-disrupting phthalates and phthalate replacements in young children," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://publichealth.gmu.edu/news/2024-09/new-study-finds-associations-between-use-skin-care-products-and-exposure-potential">said the primary investigator of the study, Michael S Bloom</a>, professor in the Department of Global and Community Health at George Mason University's College of Public Health.</p>

<p>The study collected medical data from 630 children between the ages of four and eight from 10 different sites across the United States, including a clinical examination and a urinalysis. The child's parent or guardian was also asked to complete a survey within 24 hours prior to the child's examination, which included questions regarding the child's sociodemographic information (race/ethnic identity, sex assigned at birth, etc.). It also asked parents to list all the skin care products, including lotions, soaps, shampoos, oils, and cosmetics, that were applied to the child's skin in the 24 hours prior to their examination, with as much specificity as possible regarding the product type and brand or generic name.</p>

<p>"We found associations between recent use of different skin care products and higher concentrations of phthalate and phthalate-replacement compounds," said Bloom. "There were different relationships between the use of skin care products and the endocrine-disrupting chemicals in children depending on their racial and ethnic identities and their sex assigned at birth. We also found that distinct patterns of using multiple skin care products were predictive of higher concentrations of phthalates and phthalate replacements."</p>

<p>"The results can inform policies to address the use of endocrine-disrupting chemicals in skin care products that may be used on children and to help advise parents' decisions about using products to limit their children's exposure to potential developmental toxicants," said Bloom.</p>

<p>The research emphasizes raising public awareness of the possible dangers associated with kids' regular exposure to these chemicals, especially in the early years when hormonal balance is crucial for healthy development.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jqos0g78_lotions-sunscreens_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The research also reveals that exposure varies among different racial and ethnic groups.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-no-longer-exists-as-a-military-formation-israel-defence-minister-6532886]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas No Longer Exists As A Military Formation: Israel Defence Minister]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-no-longer-exists-as-a-military-formation-israel-defence-minister-6532886]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 16:07:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant offered his support for a hostage release agreement in the first phase of a Gaza truce deal, saying it would give Israel a "strategic opportunity" to address other security challenges.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant offered his support for a hostage release agreement in the first phase of a Gaza truce deal, saying it would give Israel a "strategic opportunity" to address other security challenges.</p>

<p>Bringing the hostages home is "the right thing to do", Gallant told foreign journalists.</p>

<p>"Achieving an agreement is also a strategic opportunity that gives us a high chance to change the security situation on all fronts," he said.</p>

<p>Israel, which has been at war with Palestinian militants in Gaza since Hamas's October 7 attack, is also engaged in near-daily clashes with Lebanon's Hezbollah movement on its northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<p>Urging the international community to keep up the pressure on Hamas to reach an agreement, Gallant said he firmly supported the first stage of a three-phase ceasefire deal announced by US President Joe Biden on May 31, hoping to build on it for an eventual end to the war.</p>

<p>"Israel should achieve an agreement that will bring about a pause for six weeks and bring back hostages," Gallant told journalists at a sit-down on Monday at his office. His remarks were released for publication on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Gallant also said Hamas's military capabilities had been severely damaged after more than 11 months of war and that it no longer existed as a military formation in Gaza.</p>

<p>"Hamas as a military formation no longer exists. Hamas is engaged in guerrilla warfare and we are still fighting Hamas terrorists and pursuing Hamas leadership," he said.</p>

<p>His comments came as mediators from the United States, Qatar and Egypt struggle to reach an agreement between Israel and Hamas to end the war in Gaza, which has killed nearly 41,000 people.</p>

<p>The widespread destruction has produced a dire humanitarian situation in the besieged territory, underscored by the recent confirmation of its first polio case in 25 years.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/j16pmol_hamas-reuters-_625x300_11_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas is engaged in guerrilla warfare, Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-remote-surgery-conducted-9-000-km-away-using-game-controller-6532741]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Remote Surgery Conducted 9,000 KM Away Using Game Controller]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/video-remote-surgery-conducted-9-000-km-away-using-game-controller-6532741]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:48:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Researchers from ETH Zurich and CU Medicine successfully performed a teleoperated magnetic endoscopy on a swine model, with a remote specialist in Zurich using a video game controller.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Zurich (ETH Zurich), Switzerland, and the Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) Faculty of Medicine (CU Medicine) have successfully completed a teleoperated magnetic endoscopy surgery, marking a significant achievement in medical science. Using a remote-controlled device, a biopsy of the stomach wall was taken during the surgery on a swine model.</p>

<p>A clinician who was physically present in the operating room in Hong Kong and a remote specialist who was stationed 9,300 kilometres distant in Zurich, Switzerland, both participated in the process. Advanced technology was used by both experts to control the procedure; the distant expert used a game controller from an operator console in Zurich.</p>

<p><strong>Watch the video here:</strong></p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qy0F4xYLgOY?si=5HsQZCou0vAenHnF" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>This study demonstrates how this cutting-edge technology may be able to provide speciality surgical treatment in remote areas, particularly when access to local expertise may be limited. The research findings were released by <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aisy.202400522"><em>Advanced Intelligent Systems, </em></a>which is a peer-reviewed open access scientific journal.</p>

<p>“Teleoperated endoscopy offers not only remote surgical training and mentoring but also immediate diagnostic and surgical care in remote areas, particularly when local expertise is lacking. A remote expert can even instruct trained nurses to perform the procedures. Millions of patients worldwide will be able to be diagnosed and treated for gastrointestinal cancer in a timely manner as endoscopic technology becomes more accessible," <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.med.cuhk.edu.hk/press-releases/cuhk-and-eth-zurich-successfully-conduct-world-s-first-in-vivo-teleoperated-magnetic-endoscopy-using-an-animal-model-over-a-distance-of-9-300-km-between-zurich-and-hong-kong#:~:text=Featured%20is%20Dr%20Shannon%20Chan,live%20on%20the%20computer%20screen.">said Dr Shannon Melissa Chan</a>, Assistant Professor in the Department of Surgery at CU Medicine.</p>

<p>“In the next step of our research, we will be performing tele-endoscopy on a human stomach. In addition to endoscopic procedures, such as cancer screening, there is a lot of potential for this technology. This includes its application to other areas of the gastrointestinal tract, to the neurovascular system, and in foetal surgery,” <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.med.cuhk.edu.hk/press-releases/cuhk-and-eth-zurich-successfully-conduct-world-s-first-in-vivo-teleoperated-magnetic-endoscopy-using-an-animal-model-over-a-distance-of-9-300-km-between-zurich-and-hong-kong#:~:text=Featured%20is%20Dr%20Shannon%20Chan,live%20on%20the%20computer%20screen.">said Professor Dr Bradley Nelson</a>, Director of the Multi-Scale Robotics Lab, Head of the Institute of Robotics and Intelligent Systems, ETH Zurich.</p>

<p>A magnetic endoscope, controlled by an external magnetic field, was successfully tested on a sedated pig by a Zurich surgeon using a video game controller. Other tests have used a similar game controller. The endoscope made a U-turn and took a stomach biopsy, with low latency under 300 milliseconds. This experiment suggests that remote surgeries, potentially even for astronauts, could soon be feasible, particularly benefiting patients in remote areas.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/6lnelgso_dr-shannon-chan_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Dr Shannon Chan in Hong Kong, remotely operating the endoscopic system in Switzerland.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-plead-for-help-as-death-count-in-typhoon-hit-vietnam-rises-to-82-6532721]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Thousands Plead For Help As Death Count In Typhoon-hit Vietnam Rises To 82]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/thousands-plead-for-help-as-death-count-in-typhoon-hit-vietnam-rises-to-82-6532721]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:44:38 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Thousands of people were stranded on rooftops and posted desperate pleas for help on social media Tuesday after severe flooding in parts of typhoon-hit Vietnam, as the death count climbed to 82.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thousands of people were stranded on rooftops and posted desperate pleas for help on social media Tuesday after severe flooding in parts of typhoon-hit Vietnam, as the death count climbed to 82.</p>

<p>Typhoon Yagi struck Saturday bringing winds in excess of 149 kilometres (92 miles) per hour and a deluge of rain that has caused flooding not seen in decades, according to locals.</p>

<p>Some communities in Hanoi along the swollen and fast-moving Red River were inundated, with people forced to evacuate in boats and authorities warning more flooding was expected to hit the capital later Tuesday.</p>

<p>Phan Thi Tuyet, 50, who lives close to the river, said she had never experienced such high water.</p>

<p>"I have lost everything, all gone," she told AFP, clutching her two dogs.</p>

<p>"I had to come to higher ground to save our lives. We could not bring any of the furniture with us. Everything is under water now."</p>

<p>The storm downed bridges, tore roofs off buildings, damaged factories and triggered widespread flooding and landslides, leaving 64 people still missing.</p>

<p>Hanoi authorities said more than 25,000 trees in the city had been uprooted in the storm. Huge trunks blocked key roads in the city centre, creating large traffic jams.</p>

<p>The north of the country -- densely populated and a major manufacturing hub for global tech firms including Samsung -- was badly hit, with floodwaters in the city of Yen Bai at record levels, meteorologists said.</p>

<p>Authorities have issued flood and landslide warnings for 401 communes across 18 northern provinces.</p>

<p>One-storey homes in parts of Thai Nguyen and Yen Bai cities were almost completely submerged in the early hours of Tuesday, with residents waiting on the roofs for help.</p>

<p>Rescuers were trying to reach residential areas to retrieve old people and children. On social media, relatives of those stuck in floodwater posted desperate pleas for help and supplies in the early hours of the morning.</p>

<p>Crops including bananas, guavas and corn -- which are usually sold in nearby markets -- were all flooded.</p>

<h3><strong>Bridge collapsed</strong></h3>

<p>As well as the dead and missing, flooding and landslides have also injured at least 752 people, officials at the ministry of agriculture said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Authorities stopped heavy vehicles crossing a major bridge over the Red River in central Hanoi on Tuesday and suspended a train line across Long Bien bridge as the water level rose.</p>

<p>The action followed the dramatic collapse of a bridge higher up the river in northern Phu Tho province on Monday.</p>

<p>Pictures showed half of the 375-metre Phong Chau bridge gone.</p>

<p>Five people who were crossing the bridge at the time have been rescued, but eight others were still missing Tuesday, authorities said.</p>

<p>The storm has also caused power blackouts and major disruptions to factories in the country's north, which is a major production centre for a number of global tech firms.</p>

<p>Susumu Yoshida from the Japan Chamber of Commerce and Industry told AFP more than 80 Japanese companies had suffered some kind of damage from the typhoon, including to factory buildings, machinery, raw materials and products.</p>

<p>Some had suspended or partially suspended production, and would not resume operations until the end of the week, he said.</p>

<p>At least 24 people were killed as Yagi tore through southern China and the Philippines before hitting Vietnam.</p>

<p>Typhoons in the region are forming closer to the coast, intensifying more rapidly, and staying over land longer due to climate change, according to a study published in July.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/dcsjgt1o_typhoon-yagi_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The storm downed bridges, tore roofs off buildings, damaged factories]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-company-to-lose-rs-35-crore-after-washing-machine-pricing-error-6532652]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Chinese Company To Lose Rs 35 Crore After Washing Machine Pricing Error]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/chinese-company-to-lose-rs-35-crore-after-washing-machine-pricing-error-6532652]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:36:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident happened on the evening of August 28, when Little Swan's online shop received over 40,000 orders in just 20 minutes, after customers noticed exceptionally low prices on washing machines.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Chinese small business, Little Swan Dongshan Franchise Shop, is facing a potential loss of 30 million yuan (approximately Rs 35 crore) due to a pricing error. According to the <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/trending-china/article/3277651/china-shop-loses-us42-million-20-minutes-after-washing-machine-pricing-error" rel="nofollow, noindex">South China Morning Post</a></em>, an employee mistakenly labelled some washing machines with incorrect prices, sparking a surge in sales. The company, which operates both online and offline in Jixi county, Anhui province, has apologised for the mistake and is requesting customers to cancel their orders.</p>

<p>The incident happened on the evening of August 28, when Little Swan's online shop received over 40,000 orders in just 20 minutes, after customers noticed exceptionally low prices on washing machines. The company, a well-known domestic brand, attributed the chaos to a single employee's mistake. The error resulted in a massive surge in orders, putting the company at risk of a significant financial loss.</p>

<p>If the shop had fulfilled the orders, it would have lost 30 million yuan, as the total value of the products was 70 million yuan, but customers only paid 40 million yuan. A customer, surnamed Wang, said she discovered the drastically reduced prices on social media on August 28 and purchased three washing machines online. She bought two machines normally priced at 1,699 yuan (US$240) each for just 299 yuan, and a third machine normally priced at 2,499 yuan for 439 yuan. After seeing the store's apology and request to cancel orders, Ms Wang promptly cancelled her purchases.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The company acknowledged that, ''Due to the misunderstanding, we made a significant mistake. We recognise that this issue has caused confusion among the public and has seriously disrupted the market. We feel deeply guilty and upset.''</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The Little Swan Dongshan Franchise Shop, a small business with only six employees, has struggled to make a profit in recent years due to the economic downturn.&nbsp;Following the incident, the company issued a public apology and requested customers to cancel their orders.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">''Tens of thousands of orders and tens of millions of yuan are astronomical figures for us. We feel sincerely sorry for all the affected customers. We humbly beg you to understand our difficulties and to agree to withdraw orders. We will refund you as fast as we can,'' said a statement from the company.</p>

<p data-qa="Component-Component" datatype="p">The local market supervision authority has launched an investigation into the incident. According to Zhao Liangshan, a lawyer from Shaanxi Hengda Law Firm, if the company intentionally mispriced the products to attract attention or boost sales, they are legally required to fulfill the orders. However, if the incorrect pricing was genuinely an error, the company can petition the court to cancel the purchase contracts, allowing them to refund customers without having to deliver the goods.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a5c1omf_washing-machine_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The company has apologised for the mistake and is requesting customers to cancel their orders.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-trump-debate-kamala-harris-border-abortion-policies-in-spotlight-6532627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ahead Of Trump Debate, Kamala Harris' Border, Abortion Policies In Spotlight]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ahead-of-trump-debate-kamala-harris-border-abortion-policies-in-spotlight-6532627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:31:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris has unveiled a few centrist-leaning policies, abandoned some past positions and left much else vague as she gears up for a critical US presidential debate with Donald Trump.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris has unveiled a few centrist-leaning policies, abandoned some past positions and left much else vague as she gears up for a critical US presidential debate with Donald Trump.</p>

<p>The Democratic vice president unveiled a list of policies on her website on the eve of the clash, with Republicans accusing her of "flip-flopping" on key issues.</p>

<p>Here is where the White House hopeful stands in five key areas:</p>

<h2>'Opportunity economy'</h2>

<p>Harris has stressed her commitment to the United States' middle class, citing her own background of being raised by a single mother in California, and said she wants to create an "opportunity economy."</p>

<p>One of her most concrete policies so far is a child tax credit of $6,000 for families of newborn children. She has also promised tax cuts for 100 million Americans while raising taxes on the richest, and to bring down housing prices.</p>

<p>Tax is one of the few policy areas where she has broken with President Joe Biden. In a nod to moderate voters, she wants a 28 percent tax on capital gains, less than the 39.6 percent proposed by Biden.</p>

<p>Harris has also promised to end taxes on tips paid to service industry workers -- weeks after Trump announced a similar policy.</p>

<p>She has said she will take on "price gouging" by corporations to tackle high prices -- one of her main weak spots against Republican Trump -- but her plans on that front remain vague.</p>

<h2>Environmental flip-flops</h2>

<p>Harris has not set out a detailed environmental policy except on one key area: fracking.</p>

<p>She has vowed not to ban the practice, which uses high-pressure water to extract oil and gas -- despite previously saying that she was opposed to it.</p>

<p>In her first and only on-screen interview since becoming the Democratic candidate, she told CNN that her "values have not changed" even if her position had.</p>

<p>Harris has, according to the Axios news site, also backtracked on her opposition to plastic straws.</p>

<p>As vice president, she has strongly backed Biden's green energy transition under the so-called "Inflation Reduction Act."</p>

<h2>Border 'consequences'</h2>

<p>Illegal migration over the US-Mexican border is one of the most sensitive issues in the campaign.</p>

<p>Harris said in her CNN interview there would be "consequences" for people crossing illegally.</p>

<p>She supported Biden's bid to toughen migration policy and has backed investing in the border "wall" that Trump called for -- despite her criticizing it in the past.</p>

<p>Biden's proposals, however, have never made it through a divided Congress, with Republicans blocking them to cause Democrats political damage.</p>

<h2>Firm on abortion</h2>

<p>Harris's position on abortion, another key election issue, is not in doubt.</p>

<p>She has repeatedly criticized Trump for bragging that he enabled the US Supreme Court to overturn the federal right to terminate pregnancies.</p>

<p>Harris has said that if elected she would push to enshrine protections for abortion in US law.</p>

<h2>Gaza quagmire</h2>

<p>Harris has been more vocal than Biden on the issue of civilians killed by Israel in the war in Gaza, leading to speculation that she might take a tougher line with the US ally.</p>

<p>But during her CNN interview she said she would not halt arms deliveries to Israel, despite calls among Democrats and Arab American voters to do so, and pledged to help Israel defend itself.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/425dmocs_kamala-harris-reuters_625x300_30_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-top-court-triumphs-in-crackdown-on-apples-tax-deal-googles-practices-6532561]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[EU Top Court Triumphs In Crackdown On Apple's Tax Deal, Google's Practices]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/eu-top-court-triumphs-in-crackdown-on-apples-tax-deal-googles-practices-6532561]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:23:53 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The EU's top court on Tuesday delivered two major victories in the bloc's battle against tech giants by ruling against Apple and Google in separate legal sagas with billions of euros at play.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The EU's top court on Tuesday delivered two major victories in the bloc's battle against tech giants by ruling against Apple and Google in separate legal sagas with billions of euros at play.</p>

<p>The decisions give a boost to the bloc's outgoing competition chief, Margrethe Vestager, who had suffered a series of setbacks in EU courts against her decisions.</p>

<p>Concluding a long-running legal battle, the European Court of Justice ruled that the iPhone maker must pay 13 billion euros ($14.3 billion) in back-taxes to Ireland.</p>

<p>"The Court of Justice gives final judgment in the matter and confirms the European Commission's 2016 decision: Ireland granted Apple unlawful aid which Ireland is required to recover," the court said in a statement.</p>

<p>Minutes later, the court also upheld a 2.4-billion-euro fine against Google, one of a string of high-profile EU competition cases targeting the tech giant.</p>

<p>The court dismissed an appeal by Google and its parent company Alphabet against the fine, slapped on the search engine in 2017 for abusing its dominant position by favouring its own comparison shopping service.</p>

<p>Apple and Google said they were "disappointed" by the decisions.</p>

<h3><strong>Sweetheart tax arrangements</strong></h3>

<p>One of the most bitter legal battles between the European Commission and big tech, the Apple case dates back to 2016 when the EU's executive arm claimed Ireland allowed the iPhone maker to avoid billions of euros in taxes.</p>

<p>By the commission's calculations, Dublin allowed Apple to pay a tax rate of one percent of its European profits in 2003 which then dropped to 0.005 percent by 2014.</p>

<p>It was one of several investigations over the previous decade into sweetheart tax arrangements between major companies and several EU countries.</p>

<p>But Apple on Tuesday said there was no "special deal"</p>

<p>"We always pay all the taxes we owe wherever we operate and there has never been a special deal," the company said in a statement.</p>

<p>"The European Commission is trying to retroactively change the rules and ignore that, as required by international tax law, our income was already subject to taxes in the US," it added.</p>

<p>The decision is a blow for Apple as the iPhone maker had gained the upper hand in the Ireland case in 2020, when the EU's General Court annulled the order for it to pay the taxes owed.</p>

<p>Following an appeal by Brussels, the legal adviser of the higher European Court of Justice in November last year recommended scrapping that decision, saying it was peppered with legal errors.</p>

<p>But the top court, which could have sent the case back to the lower court, decided to rule that Apple should pay the back-taxes.</p>

<p>The decisions will offer relief for Brussels which has faced difficulty defending its tax enforcement moves in recent years, with previous cases lost against Amazon and Starbucks.</p>

<p>"This ruling exposes EU tax havens' love affair with multinationals. It delivers long-overdue justice after over a decade of Ireland standing by and allowing Apple to dodge taxes," said Chiara Putaturo at EU tax expert at anti-poverty organisation.</p>

<h3><strong>Google's vice tightening</strong></h3>

<p>The EU fine against Google was one of several record penalties imposed for violating EU competition rules, totalling around eight billion euros between 2017 and 2019.</p>

<p>"We are disappointed with the decision of the court," Google said. "We made changes back in 2017 to comply with the European Commission's decision."</p>

<p>Google faces yet another test next week when the top EU court will decide on the smallest of those fines, worth around 1.49 billion euros.</p>

<p>Legal headaches for Google are mounting across the Atlantic as well.</p>

<p>A trial began on Monday in the United States where the government accuses Google of dominating online advertising and stifling competition.</p>

<p>It comes after a US judge ruled last month that Google maintained a monopoly with its search engine.</p>

<p>Google's so-called ad tech -- the system that decides which online adverts people see and how much they cost -- is an area of particular concern for regulators worldwide.</p>

<p>Brussels in a preliminary finding last year accused Google of abusing its dominance of the online ad market and recommended the US company sell part of its ad services to ensure fair competition. Google had the right to respond and the probe remains open.</p>

<p>Separately, Britain's competition watchdog on Friday concluded Google employs "anti-competitive practices" with regards to online advertising after a two-year investigation.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/51f7esdg_apple-logo_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Apple and Google said they were "disappointed" by the decisions.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-launches-4-member-civilian-crew-polaris-dawn-mission-for-first-privately-funded-spacewalk-6532475]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[SpaceX Launches 4-Member Civilian Crew For First Privately-funded Spacewalk]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/spacex-launches-4-member-civilian-crew-polaris-dawn-mission-for-first-privately-funded-spacewalk-6532475]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:11:45 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[SpaceX launched its daring Polaris Dawn mission on Tuesday, a multiday orbital expedition carrying a four-member civilian crew for the first spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX launched its daring Polaris Dawn mission on Tuesday, a multiday orbital expedition carrying a four-member civilian crew for the first spacewalk by non-professional astronauts.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Watch live as Falcon 9 launches the <a href="https://twitter.com/PolarisProgram?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@PolarisProgram</a>'s Polaris Dawn crew on a multi-day mission orbiting Earth <a href="https://t.co/u1KqQx5AFr">https://t.co/u1KqQx5AFr</a></p>
— SpaceX (@SpaceX) <a href="https://twitter.com/SpaceX/status/1833358277805039800?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Liftoff of Polaris Dawn!" SpaceX said on X, alongside a photo of the rocket as it took off.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/97jehl5o_spacex_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/south-korea-summit-announces-blueprint-for-using-ai-in-the-military-6532240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea Summit Announces 'Blueprint' For Using AI In The Military]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-ai/south-korea-summit-announces-blueprint-for-using-ai-in-the-military-6532240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:42:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Among the details added in the document was the need to prevent AI from being used to proliferate weapons of mass destruction (WMD)]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A global summit in South Korea on Tuesday announced a "blueprint for action" to govern responsible use of artificial intelligence (AI) in the military, with more practical guidelines than a similar document last year, but still legally non-binding.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear how many of the 96 nations that sent government representatives to the summit, including the United States and China, are endorsing the document.</p>

<p>The Responsible AI in the Military Domain (REAIM) summit in Seoul, the second of its kind, follows one held in Amsterdam last year. At that time, around 60 nations endorsed a modest "call to action" without legal commitment.</p>

<p>Government representatives speaking at a roundtable on Tuesday said this year's "blueprint" was more action-oriented.</p>

<p>This is in keeping with advances in discussions about AI risk, and developments in military use of AI such as Ukraine's rollout of AI-enabled drones.</p>

<p>"We are making further concrete steps," Netherlands Defence Minister Ruben Brekelmans told Reuters. "Last year...was more about creating shared understanding, now we are getting more towards action."</p>

<p>This includes laying out what kind of risk assessments should be made, important conditions such as human control, and how confidence-building measures can be taken in order to manage those risks, he said.</p>

<p>Among the details added in the document was the need to prevent AI from being used to proliferate weapons of mass destruction (WMD) by actors including terrorist groups, and the importance of maintaining human control and involvement in nuclear weapons employment.</p>

<p>South Korean officials said the document covers much of the same ground as principles laid out elsewhere, such as the U.S. government's declaration on responsible use of AI in the military launched last year.</p>

<p>But the Seoul summit - co-hosted by the Netherlands, Singapore, Kenya and the United Kingdom - aims to ensure ongoing multi-stakeholder discussions not dominated by a single nation or entity.</p>

<p>The venue and timing for the next summit is still being discussed, officials said.</p>

<p></p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/rtdo9p8g_ai-korea-defense-summit_625x300_10_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The conference was held in Amsterdam last year, where 60 nations endorsed a modest "call to action"]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-typhoon-yagi-video-phong-chau-bridge-collapses-vehicles-plunge-into-river-6531982]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Bridge Collapses In Typhoon-Hit Vietnam, Vehicles Plunge Into River]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/vietnam-typhoon-yagi-video-phong-chau-bridge-collapses-vehicles-plunge-into-river-6531982]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:28:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A bridge in northern Vietnam's Phu Tho province collapsed on Monday morning as the region faced the devastating impact of typhoon Yagi.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">A bridge in northern Vietnam's Phu Tho province collapsed on Monday morning as the region faced the devastating impact of typhoon Yagi. At least 10 vehicles, including motorbikes and cars, plunged into the Red River after the collapse of the 375-metre-long Phong Chau Bridge, local media reported.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">WARNING - disturbing footage.<br />
In Vietnam, at least 13 people fell into the Hồng (Red) River after part of Phong Châu Bridge in Phú Thọ was swept away by floodwaters. About 10 vehicles and two motorbikes fell in. Rescue efforts are hindered by fast currents following Typhoon… <a href="https://t.co/TUZSnL5EIe">pic.twitter.com/TUZSnL5EIe</a></p>
— Volcaholic ? (@volcaholic1) <a href="https://twitter.com/volcaholic1/status/1833075237623132300?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p dir="ltr">Authorities have confirmed that 13 people are missing following the incident, though Deputy Prime Minister&nbsp;Ho Duc Phoc&nbsp;has said it is unclear if there have been any casualties. Rescue operations are ongoing, with part of the bridge still standing. Efforts are being made to construct a pontoon bridge to restore access to the area.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/apophis-asteroid-isros-newest-headache-how-to-ward-off-egyptian-god-of-chaos-6530873">Large Asteroid Hurtles Towards Earth, ISRO Warns Of "Worst Case Scenario"</a></p>

<p dir="ltr">The bridge collapse comes as Vietnam continues to reel from the effects of typhoon Yagi, the most powerful storm to hit the region in decades. The storm, which made landfall on Saturday, has killed at least 64, with severe flooding and landslides causing widespread damage in northern provinces.</p>

<p dir="ltr">In addition to the bridge collapse, a passenger bus carrying 20 people was swept away by a landslide in Cao Bang province. Rescue teams have also been hampered by blocked roads and ongoing heavy rains.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/c2jce6kg_vietnam-bridge-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p dir="ltr">Prime Minister Pham Minh Chinh has announced emergency aid packages and instructed the military to prioritise rescue and recovery efforts. Typhoon Yagi has also caused significant disruption to northern Vietnam's industrial hubs, with numerous factories experiencing power outages and severe damage.</p>

<p dir="ltr">Millions of households and businesses lost power, and telecommunications were cut off in many areas. Over 5.7 million customers were left without electricity, with more than 75 per cent of power restored by Monday.</p>

<p dir="ltr"><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/samsung-takes-jab-at-apples-iphone-16-let-us-know-when-it-folds-6531622">Samsung Takes Jab At Apple's iPhone 16: "Let Us Know When It Folds"</a></p>

<p dir="ltr">Industrial zones in Haiphong, a city with a population of two million, suffered extensive damage. Roofs of factories were torn off, and workers struggled to salvage equipment as heavy rains flooded production plants. Factories of South Korean conglomerate LG Electronics in Haiphong experienced significant damage, although no casualties were reported among employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p dir="ltr">The Vietnam Meteorological Agency has warned of continued risks of flooding and landslides, with rainfall in northern regions ranging between 208 and 433 mm in the past 48 hours.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/2t4cvlrg_vietnam-bridge-afp_625x300_10_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Authorities have confirmed that 13 people are missing following the bridge collapse.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>