<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:56:21 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-freed-day-after-rival-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6276150]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Ex PM Khaleda Zia Freed Day After Rival Sheikh Hasina's Ouster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-freed-day-after-rival-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6276150]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:38:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Khaleda Zia is in poor health, confined to a wheelchair with rheumatoid arthritis and struggling with diabetes and cirrhosis of the liver.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's uncompromising ex-prime minister Khaleda Zia has been released from years of house arrest after her bitter enemy Sheikh Hasina was ousted as premier and fled as protesters broke into her palace.</p>

<p>The ferocious rivalry between the two women -- born in blood and cemented in prison -- has defined politics in the Muslim-majority nation for decades.</p>

<p>Zia, 78, was sentenced to 17 years in prison for graft in 2018 under Hasina's rule.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, was ousted on Monday after mass protests, with the army chief declaring the military would form an interim government.</p>

<p>Orders were then issued for the release of prisoners from the protests, as well as Zia.</p>

<p>Zia is chairperson of the key opposition Bangladesh National Party (BNP). Party spokesman AKM Wahiduzzaman told AFP Tuesday that she "is now freed".</p>

<p>She is in poor health, confined to a wheelchair with rheumatoid arthritis and struggling with diabetes and cirrhosis of the liver.</p>

<p><strong>Decades-long feud</strong></p>

<p>The enmity between Zia and Hasina is known popularly in Bangladesh as the "Battle of Begums", with "begum" a Muslim honorific in South Asia for powerful women.</p>

<p>Their feud has its roots in the murder of Hasina's father -- the country's founding leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahman -- along with her mother, three brothers and several other relatives in a 1975 military coup.</p>

<p>Zia's husband Ziaur Rahman was then the deputy army chief and effectively took control himself three months later.</p>

<p>He kickstarted economic recovery in poverty-stricken Bangladesh with privatisations but was killed in another military coup in 1981.</p>

<p>The BNP mantle fell to his widow, then a 35-year-old mother of two young sons who was dismissed by critics as a politically inexperienced housewife.</p>

<p>Zia led opposition to dictator Hussain Muhammad Ershad, boycotting sham elections in 1986 and mounting street protests.</p>

<p>She and Hasina joined forces to push Ershad out in a wave of protests in 1990 and then faced off in Bangladesh's first free polls.</p>

<p>Zia won and led from 1991-96, and again in 2001-2006, as she and Hasina alternated in power.</p>

<p><strong>Mutual dislike</strong></p>

<p>Their mutual dislike was blamed for a January 2007 political crisis that prompted the military to impose emergency rule and set up a caretaker government. Both were detained for more than a year.</p>

<p>Hasina won elections in December 2008 by a landslide and led uninterrupted until she fled to India in a helicopter on Monday.</p>

<p>She had tightened her grip on power by detaining tens of thousands of BNP members. Hundreds also disappeared.</p>

<p>Zia was convicted and jailed in 2018 on graft charges her party rejected as politically motivated.</p>

<p>She was later released into house arrest on condition she neither took part in politics nor went abroad for medical treatment.</p>

<p><strong>Son in exile</strong></p>

<p>Zia's first cabinet was hailed for liberalising Bangladesh's economy in the early 1990s, sparking decades of growth.</p>

<p>However, her second term as the premier of an Islamist-allied coalition was marked by graft allegations against her government and sons.</p>

<p>There was also a series of Islamist attacks, one of which killed more than 20 people and almost claimed Hasina's life.</p>

<p>The anti-crime Rapid Action Battalion police unit Zia created has been accused of hundreds of extrajudicial killings.</p>

<p>Her eldest son Tarique Rahman led the BNP from exile in London while she was in jail but he was convicted in absentia and sentenced to life in prison over his alleged role in a bomb attack on a Hasina rally in 2004.</p>

<p>The BNP says the charges were a politically motivated attempt to expel Zia's dynasty from politics.</p>

<p>Zia won respect for her resolute attitude, although her inability to compromise left her unable to cut deals with important allies at home or abroad.</p>

<p>That defiance extended even to the death of her youngest son from a heart attack in Malaysia in 2015.</p>

<p>Hasina went to her home to offer sympathy and condolences but Zia did not open the door.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/2as3jkt_khaleda-zia_625x300_05_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Zia, 78, was sentenced to 17 years in prison under Sheikh Hasina's rule.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-loses-antitrust-case-all-you-need-to-know-6276139]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Explained: The Google Antitrust Case]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/google-loses-antitrust-case-all-you-need-to-know-6276139]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:36:11 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The ruling comes after a 10-week trial and is a major victory for the US Justice Department, which filed the lawsuit nearly four years ago. ]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a landmark decision, US District Judge Amit Mehta has ruled that Google's dominance in the search market is a result of illegal monopolistic practices. The judge found Google's actions have stifled competition and innovation, and that the company's default search agreements with device manufacturers and browsers are a key factor in its market dominance.</p>

<p>Here is a breakdown of what happened:</p>

<h2><strong>The case against Google</strong></h2>

<p>The ruling comes after a 10-week trial and is a major victory for the US Justice Department, which filed the lawsuit nearly four years ago. Google has announced plans to appeal the decision. The core accusation is that Google spent billions on exclusive deals to maintain its dominance in the search engine market, violating US antitrust laws.</p>

<h2><strong>What are antitrust laws?</strong></h2>

<p>Antitrust laws are regulations that promote fair competition by preventing monopolies, anti-competitive practices, and other activities that could harm consumers or other businesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the United States, key laws include the Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890, which prohibits monopolies and actions that restrain trade, and the Clayton Antitrust Act of 1914, which addresses specific unfair practices. The Federal Trade Commission Act of 1914 established the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to investigate and prevent unfair competition.</p>

<p>The FTC and the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice (DOJ) enforce these laws. They investigate companies and take action if they find any violations.</p>

<h2><strong>The DoJ's arguments</strong></h2>

<p>The DoJ argued that Google's agreements with wireless carriers, browser developers, and device manufacturers, especially Apple, were anti-competitive. In 2021, Google reportedly paid over $26 billion to companies like Apple to make its search engine the default option on devices like iPhones and browsers like Safari and Mozilla.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google's search-based advertising is a major revenue source, generating $175 billion in 2022. For comparison, Microsoft's Bing made about $12 billion. &nbsp;</p>

<p>Google has an 89.2 per cent share of the market for general search services, increasing to 94.9 per cent on mobile devices.</p>

<h2><strong>Google's defence</strong></h2>

<p>Google argued its dominance was due to the quality of its search engine. They plan to appeal the decision, stating that while the ruling recognises their search engine's quality, it restricts their ability to make it readily available.</p>

<h2><strong>District Judge's verdict</strong></h2>

<p>The trial spanned several months, with testimonies from Google CEO Sundar Pichai and other top executives. Judge Amit Mehta's 277-page decision labelled Google a "monopolist" and highlighted the sheer volume of Google's search queries compared to rivals. Mehta noted that Google "enjoys an 89.2% share of the market for general search services, which increases to 94.9% on mobile devices." He concluded that while Google violated antitrust laws, it did not have "anticompetitive effects."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The judge acknowledged that while Google's search engine is widely recognised as the best available, its market share is significantly bolstered by these agreements. The judge pointed out that other search engines, like Microsoft's Bing, can capture significant market share when not overshadowed by Google's default status. For instance, Bing holds an 80% share of the search market on the Microsoft Edge browser. He then ruled against the tech giant.&nbsp;</p>

<p>US Attorney General Merrick Garland called the decision an "historic win for the American people," saying that no company is above the law.</p>

<h2><strong>Implications</strong></h2>

<p>Following the ruling, Google's parent company Alphabet's shares fell by 4.6%.</p>

<p>The court will now decide on the remedies Google must undertake. This could include restrictions on Google's ability to enter into exclusive deals.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Google's president of global affairs, Kent Walker, said the company intends to appeal the decision.</p>

<p>Jonathan Kanter, head of the DoJ's antitrust division, believes the ruling will pave the way for innovation and protect access to information. Meanwhile, the Consumer Choice Centre, a lobbying group, criticised the decision as a step in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>The ruling is part of a broader crackdown on Big Tech. The DoJ has another pending case against Google related to digital advertising, and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has filed lawsuits against Amazon and Meta.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/l3dququ_google-logo_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-stands-to-lose-a-lot-if-middle-east-tensions-turn-into-a-full-blown-crisis-6276066]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Here's Everything India May Lose If Middle East Plunges Into A Full-Blown War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/india-stands-to-lose-a-lot-if-middle-east-tensions-turn-into-a-full-blown-crisis-6276066]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:27:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Modi's huge investment in West Asia diplomacy and increased engagements may come unhinged if tensions spread and engulf the region in a wider war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/emejv7eo_middle-east_625x300_06_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>When Prime Minister Narendra Modi came to power in 2014, it was clear that India's West Asia policy needed a facelift - even a reset. He made multiple official visits to the region over the next few years and managed to forge strong bilateral ties with the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Iran, and Israel. It is fair to say that he struck a fine balance between the Arab countries and Palestinians on the one hand and Israel on the other, though some might claim - without credible evidence - that he has tilted slightly towards Israel. The proof of his deft West Asia foreign policy is that India enjoys the goodwill of both sides.</p>

<p>However, Israel's campaign in Gaza in response to Hamas's October 2023 attacks overshadows Modi's Middle East policy. With the spectre of a wider war looming over the region, stiffer challenges are likely. The Middle East has been teetering on the brink of chaos as India watches holding its breath.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Brazen Act&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>It is believed that Iran and its regional armed groups, the so-called "Axis of Resistance", are preparing to respond to the assassination of Hamas chief Ismail Haniyeh. Though Israel has not commented on the assassination, Haniyeh's killing is being attributed to it; in any case, Israel has claimed responsibility for killing a senior Hezbollah leader in Beirut last week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Targeting a special guest of Iran in the heart of its capital barely hours after he had attended a ceremony to inaugurate the country's newly elected President, Masoud Pezeshkian, was an act as daring as it was provocative. It also proved to be extremely humiliating for Iran and its powerful Islamic Revolutionary Guards (IRGC), the force chiefly responsible for the country's security.</p>

<h2><strong>Iran In A Quandary</strong></h2>

<p>Iran is under compulsion to take action. But it doesn't appear to be interested in escalating the crisis. If it doesn't do anything, the country will be in danger of losing respect and prestige among its supporters. If it takes action, tensions may escalate and spiral out of control. Regardless of these complexities, the rhetoric for revenge is running strong within Iran. "This crime of the Zionist regime will face a harsh and painful response from the powerful and huge resistance front," the IRGC said in a statement. Iran's Supreme Leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, described Haniyeh's killing as a provocation to escalate the conflict in the region and said that it was his country's duty to avenge the assassination.</p>

<p>More than the timing of Iran's retaliation, it will be the scale of its attack that will determine Israel's response. According to Axios, a security analysis group, "US officials expect any Iranian retaliation to be from the same playbook as their April 13 attack on Israel, but potentially larger in scope, and it could also involve Hezbollah in Lebanon". Iran had on April 13 fired more than 200 missiles at Israel in retaliation for an airstrike in Syria that killed a top Iranian general. This was the first time Iran had attacked Israel from its soil. The latter retaliated, but it was a limited response.<br />
However, Haniyeh's killing is different, and his assassination under the protection of the powerful IRGC has embarrassed Iran deeply. Both a response and a non-response can prove to be costly.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><b>How India Will Be Affected</b></h2>

<p>It is nearly certain that the war in the region would unleash a maelstrom of consequences, threatening to upend India's economy, energy security, and strategic partnerships. With its 9 million-strong diaspora, trade ties, and its geopolitical interests deeply entrenched in the region, India cannot afford to remain a bystander.</p>

<p>Despite diversifying its energy purchase, India continues to rely heavily on the Gulf countries for its oil imports. They account for more than 50% of its oil needs. Disruptions in supply chains because of war would push the price up, which, in turn, would adversely affect India's economy. The instability could increase import costs, reduce economic growth, and create inflationary pressures, thereby undermining India's energy security.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The region is a vital trading partner for India. The bilateral trade with the UAE and Saudi Arabia alone amounts to over $100 billion annually. A widening conflict could disrupt both exports, such as textiles and machinery, and imports, notably oil and fertilizers. These disruptions would negatively impact India's GDP growth, employment in export-oriented industries, and the balance of payments. All of this makes for a substantial economic challenge.</p>

<h2><strong>Diaspora And Remittances</strong></h2>

<p>India currently receives the largest remittances sent to any country by its overseas population. According to the World Bank, remittances to India in 2023 crossed $120 billion, with 18% of it coming from Indian workers based in the UAE alone. If you add Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Bahrain, and Oman, their contributions go up to 30%. Escalating conflict could reduce these remittances and force many expatriates to return to India. This migration would strain India's social and economic infrastructure, creating additional challenges for the country's economy. Heightened border security concerns, and the potential for a refugee influx, all pose significant threats to India's stability. The humanitarian challenges would include providing adequate food, shelter, and medical care, as well as ensuring the safety and security of both the refugees and the host communities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Global trade and economic disruptions stemming from potential escalations would also affect India's economy as it would lead to reduced trade and investment and increasing economic uncertainty. These factors could exert recessionary pressures on India's economic landscape, complicating its growth prospects. In the longer term, it could also affect India's progress towards becoming the world's third-largest economy.</p>

<h2><strong>Strategic Partnerships</strong></h2>

<p>Under Prime Minister Narendra Modi's leadership, India has emerged as an influential partner of various Middle Eastern countries, such as Iran, Israel, the UAE, and Saudi Arabia. Conflicts in the region could impact energy cooperation, defence and security partnerships, and regional diplomatic efforts, potentially destabilising these strategic relationships.</p>

<p>Last year during the G20 summit in Delhi, the India-Middle East-Europe Corridor (IMEC) was announced ostensibly to counter China's Belt and Road Initiatives. But the project's future now appears to be in jeopardy. With tensions rising in the region, it might be difficult to take the programme forward. Its declared aim was to establish a seamless trade route connecting India, the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Israel, and Europe. The idea was that it would enhance economic integration, trade, investments, and cooperation. But for now, the priorities of the partner countries have shifted.</p>

<h2><strong>India Has Been Here Before, But That's Not Enough</strong></h2>

<p>India has the experience of dealing with crises emanating from wars in the region. During the Gulf Wars, India's handling of refugee crises and the airlifting of its citizens from Kuwait showcased its capacity for large-scale evacuation and crisis management. In 1990, following Iraq's invasion of Kuwait, around 1,70,000 Indians were stranded in Kuwait and Iraq. India undertook a massive airlift operation to evacuate its citizens, coordinating with airlines and using military and civilian aircraft. This operation, spanning nearly two months, became one of the largest civilian evacuations in history, demonstrating India's logistical and diplomatic capabilities.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the 2003 Iraq War, although the scale was smaller compared to the first Gulf War, India was again proactive in evacuating its nationals. The government, through its embassies in the region, provided support and facilitated the return of Indians. The evacuation efforts were undertaken with an express need to ensure the safety of Indian citizens, providing necessary travel documents and arranging transport back to India.</p>

<p>Modi's huge investment in West Asia diplomacy and increased engagements may come unhinged if tensions spread and engulf the region in a wider war. For now, India and the global community should hope that the crisis passes over soon. For that to happen, the ceasefire in Gaza could be a big first step.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/38u33fbo_middle-east_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-palestinians-killed-in-gaza-in-24-hours-as-heavy-fighting-continues-6276024]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[45 Palestinians Killed In Gaza In 24 Hours As Heavy Fighting Continues]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/45-palestinians-killed-in-gaza-in-24-hours-as-heavy-fighting-continues-6276024]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:20:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli forces killed 45 Palestinian fighters in Gaza over the past day, the military said on Tuesday, after heavy fighting in which Hamas said it destroyed two armoured personnel carriers during an ambush near the city of Rafah.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli forces killed 45 Palestinian fighters in Gaza over the past day, the military said on Tuesday, after heavy fighting in which Hamas said it destroyed two armoured personnel carriers during an ambush near the city of Rafah.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said the Hamas official in charge of smuggling operations was among those killed and that his death significantly hit their ability to bring weapons and military equipment into the besieged enclave.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, air strikes killed five Palestinians in the Al-Bureij camp, in the central Gaza Strip, medics said, while two others were killed in a separate air strike in Rafah, near the southern Gaza border with Egypt.</p>

<p>Hamas does not provide casualty numbers for its fighters.</p>

<p>The Islamist movement's armed wing said its fighters destroyed the two Israeli troop carriers in an ambush east of Rafah, where heavy fighting has been reported for weeks. There was no confirmation from the Israeli military.</p>

<p>With Israel braced for a possible attack in the north by Iran and the Iranian-backed Hezbollah group, it faces a multi-front threat, 10 months after the start of the war in Gaza.</p>

<p>The territory's health ministry said Israeli military strikes have killed at least 30 Palestinians and wounded 66 others in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>"Many victims are still under the rubble and on the roads, where the teams of the ambulance and civil emergency service can't reach," the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>In the larger Palestinian territory, the West Bank, Israeli forces also killed at least eight people on Tuesday and overnight.</p>

<h3><strong>Tank Shelling</strong></h3>

<p>Hamas-led fighters set off the Gaza war last year, when they rampaged through Israeli communities around the Gaza Strip, in a surprise attack, killing 1,200 Israelis and foreigners and seizing some 250 hostages, according to Israeli tallies, in the most deadly single day attack on Israel in its history.</p>

<p>In response, Israel has conducted a relentless assault on Gaza that has reduced much of the heavily populated coastal strip to ruins and killed more than 39,000 Palestinians, according to local health authorities.</p>

<p>The figure does not distinguish between fighters and civilians but Israeli authorities estimate their forces have killed or incapacitated some 14,000 fighters, around half the total Hamas force estimated at the start of the war.</p>

<p>Most of Gaza's population has been displaced multiple times since the start of the war and the fighting has brought misery to thousands trapped in overcrowded tent shelters.</p>

<p>Residents said Israeli tank shelling continued overnight in Bureij, Al-Maghazi, Nuseirat, and Deir Al-Balah, in the central Gaza Strip, where tens of thousands of displaced families from all over the enclave have sought temporary refuge.</p>

<p>Residents and Hamas media said tanks made a brief advance earlier on Tuesday in Al-Zahra City northwest of Nuseirat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ss9mn2t_israel-gaza-war_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Israel has conducted a relentless assault on Gaza]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-climbers-rescue-porters-body-a-year-after-k2-summit-6275998]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Pakistani Climbers Rescue Porter's Body A Year After K2 Summit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/pakistani-climbers-rescue-porters-body-a-year-after-k2-summit-6275998]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:17:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climbers recovered the body of a Pakistani porter from K2 mountain, a climbing federation confirmed Tuesday, a year after he died while other climbers made a record-breaking ascent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climbers recovered the body of a Pakistani porter from K2 mountain, a climbing federation confirmed Tuesday, a year after he died while other climbers made a record-breaking ascent.</p>

<p>Muhammad Hassan Shigri slipped and fell from the most dangerous pass during a night climb and was left dangling upside down on a rope before fellow climbers were able to pull him up and attempt to revive him.</p>

<p>He died on the pass known as the "Bottleneck" as dozens of climbers in different teams continued towards the summit.</p>

<p>The climbers included Norwegian record-breaker Kristin Harila who, along with her Nepali guide Tenjin "Lama" Sherpa, that night became the fastest person to summit the world's 14 highest mountains.</p>

<p>"The rescue team made history and turned the impossible into possible," Karrar Haidri, Secretary of the Alpine Club of Pakistan told AFP of the recovery of Shigri's body last Wednesday.</p>

<p>He said it was an "unprecedented rescue, the first of its kind on K2".</p>

<p>The recovery was completed by a team of five climbers led by Naila Kiani, a Pakistani high-altitude mountaineer who was contacted by Shigri's family and backed by the Pakistan army.</p>

<p>Shigri's body was returned to his family for burial.</p>

<p>"We want to thank Naila Kiani and the porters who did this great job. To bring the dead body back was a big wish of the family," his cousin Aslam Naz Shigri told AFP over the phone.</p>

<p>Climbers were criticised at the time for stepping over Shigri's body but Harila said she and her team "did everything we could for him".</p>

<p>An investigation by the Gilgit and Baltistan provincial government's tourism department found Shigri was not prepared with sufficient clothing and was an inexperienced high-altitude porter, and that despite the dangerous conditions, some climbers had attempted to save him -- but it was too late.</p>

<p>Porters, also called sherpas in the Himalayas, are highly skilled professionals who specialise in the logistics of mountain climbing.</p>

<p>Rescue missions are high-risk operations even on the most common routes on K2 and bodies can be left behind for months, or even years, until the weather allows for them to be recovered on foot.</p>

<p>K2, standing at 8,611 metres (28,251 feet) on the Pakistan-China border, is 238 metres shorter than Everest but is considered more technically challenging.</p>

<p>Pakistan is home to five of the world's 14 mountains above 8,000 metres. Four foreign climbers have fallen to their deaths in separate incidents on Pakistan mountains this summer climbing season.</p>

<p>French mountaineer Benjamin Vedrines made the fastest ascent of K2 in 10 hours, 59 minutes and 59 seconds in July, slashing by more than half the previous record for reaching the summit without bottled oxygen.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ktvvlcb_mountaineering_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Rescue missions on K2 are high-risk, and bodies can be left behind for years. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-remains-found-inside-a-crocodile-in-australia-believed-to-be-that-of-40-year-old-tourist-6275974]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Human Remains Found Inside Crocodile After Man Goes Missing In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/human-remains-found-inside-a-crocodile-in-australia-believed-to-be-that-of-40-year-old-tourist-6275974]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:14:08 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The incident occurred at a location known as Crocodile Bend, popular among tourists for crocodile sightings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Human remains have been found inside a 16-foot crocodile suspected of killing a man in Australia. According to <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/australasia/australia-cooktown-crocodile-attack-human-remains-b2591775.html">Independent</a></em>, the remains are believed to be of David Hogbin, a 40-year-old man from New South Wales, who went missing after falling into the Annan River in Queensland.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The incident occurred at a location known as Crocodile Bend, popular among tourists for crocodile sightings. Mr Hogbin&nbsp;was fishing on the banks of the Annan River in Cooktown with his wife and children about 2pm on Saturday when he slipped into the water.&nbsp;His wife attempted to rescue him but was unable to do so.</p>

<p data-apitype="text" data-contentid="K7KBYIXJX5CNJLGV75LEAZABQE" data-el="text" data-scroll-measured="true" data-scroll-pos="5" data-testid="drop-cap-letter" dir="null">''Dave's final, selfless act was to save the life of Jane, his wife of 10 years, and to ensure their three beautiful boys still had their mum. Dave fell down into the river below, and despite being tall, strong and fit, the conditions of the terrain meant Dave was unable to get himself out of the water. Dave's final, decisive act was to let go of Jane's arm when he realised she was falling in, despite knowing she was his only lifeline,'' Mr Hogbin's sister-in-law told&nbsp;<a href="https://www.news.com.au/national/queensland/news/dads-selfless-final-act-before-fatal-crocodile-attack-in-queensland/news-story/72a7140759ca5f22bb263ad1b0a390eb" rel="nofollow">news.com.au</a>.</p>

<p data-apitype="text" data-contentid="K7KBYIXJX5CNJLGV75LEAZABQE" data-el="text" data-scroll-measured="true" data-scroll-pos="5" data-testid="drop-cap-letter" dir="null">The crocodile was found 2.5 miles from where Mr Hogbin disappeared. Further testing is being conducted to confirm the identity of the remains.</p>

<p>Wildlife rangers later euthanized the crocodile, which had distinctive scars on its snout, matching witness descriptions.</p>

<p>''Wildlife officers have humanely euthanised a large crocodile that is believed to be responsible for the fatal attack on the Annan River. The animal had markings on its snout that were consistent with it being the target animal. Wildlife officers are removing the animal from the creek and will hand it over to the Queensland Police Service,'' said the Department of Environment, Science and Innovation.</p>

<p>A<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/support-dave-hogbins-family-after-tragic-crocodile-attack?attribution_id=sl:4660fe30-5c77-43a3-846c-0eb5df7b89e4&amp;utm_campaign=pd_ss_icons_ai&amp;utm_content=amp1v4&amp;utm_medium=customer&amp;utm_source=twitter"> GoFundMe</a> has been set up by family friend Alex Ward, to help Jane and the family in the aftermath of their loss.</p>

<p>There have been three fatal crocodile attacks in Australia this year. A 12-year-old girl was killed in a crocodile attack on July 2, and a 16-year-old boy was killed while swimming off a Queensland island on April 18.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The crocodile population has exploded across Australia's tropical north since the predators became a protected species in the early 1970s.&nbsp;</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/kjcmo3mg_crocodile_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Wildlife rangers later euthanised the crocodile]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-launches-drone-attack-at-israel-6275900]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Lebanon's Hezbollah Launches Swarm Of Drones At Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lebanon-launches-drone-attack-at-israel-6275900]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 16:05:49 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Lebanon's armed group Hezbollah said it launched a swarm of attack drones against military targets in northern Israel on Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lebanon's armed group Hezbollah said it launched a swarm of attack drones against military targets in northern Israel on Tuesday.</p>

<p>A source within the group told Reuters it was not the group's retaliation for Israel's killing of Hezbollah commander Fuad Shukr in Beirut last week. Hezbollah has vowed to avenge him, prompting worries of a major escalation that could tip into a full-blown war.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/m0rve7dg_hezbollah_625x300_04_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hezbollah launched swarm of attack drones in northern Israel (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-no-arrest-after-suspected-israeli-killing-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6275826]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iran Yet To Make Arrests After Suspected Israeli Killing Of Hamas Chief]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-says-no-arrest-after-suspected-israeli-killing-of-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-6275826]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:58:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran-Israel Conflict:The leader of the Palestinian militant group was killed last Wednesday during a visit for the swearing-in ceremony of Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian. The "necessary investigations" have begun and the results will be announce]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran has yet to make any arrests linked to the suspected Israeli killing of Hamas political chief <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-chief-ismail-haniyeh-killed-in-irans-capital-report-6228024" target="_blank">Ismail Haniyeh</a> in Tehran, the Iranian judiciary said Tuesday.</p>

<p>The leader of the Palestinian operatives group was killed last Wednesday during a visit for the swearing-in ceremony of Iranian President Masoud Pezeshkian.</p>

<p>The "necessary investigations" have begun and the results will be announced "as soon as the probe is completed," said judiciary spokesman Asghar Jahangir.</p>

<p>"Until today, no arrests have been made in connection with this case," he said, adding that the investigations involved Iranian military officials.</p>

<p>Iran's Revolutionary Guards said Haniyeh was killed using a "short-range projectile" launched from outside his accommodation in Tehran.</p>

<p>Iran and Hamas have blamed Israel and vowed to retaliate. Israel has declined to comment.</p>

<p>On Saturday, the New York Times reported that Iran had arrested more than two dozen people, including senior intelligence officers among others, in connection with Haniyeh's killing.</p>

<p>Jahangir dismissed the claims about any arrests as "rumours" and "false".</p>

<p>"Haniyeh's assassination will definitely be met with a courageous response by the Islamic Republic," he said.</p>

<p>Haniyeh's death came hours after an <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-vows-crushing-response-against-israel-after-hamas-chief-ismail-haniyehs-killing-6272459">Israeli strike in south Beirut</a> killed a senior commander of Hezbollah, the Lebanese operative group that Israel blamed for a deadly rocket strike on the Israeli-annexed Golan Heights.</p>

<p>The two high-profile killings are the latest of several major incidents that have inflamed regional tensions during the Gaza war, which has drawn in Iran-backed operative groups in Syria, Lebanon, Iraq and Yemen.</p>

<p>Late Monday, Pezeshkian said <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/iran-allies-vow-revenge-after-top-hamas-hezbollah-leaders-killed-6252277" target="_blank">Israel would "receive the response</a> for its crimes and arrogance," but insisted that Tehran "is in no way seeking to expand the scope of war and crisis in the region".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/un7jfe78_ismail-haniyeh-_625x300_01_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ismail Haniyeh was killed using a "short-range projectile" launched from outside his accommodation (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-sheikh-rehana-49-years-apart-sheikh-rehanas-second-fateful-flight-with-sister-hasina-6275820]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Sheikh Rehana, Hasina's Lifelong Shadow After Massacre Wiped Off Family]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-sheikh-rehana-49-years-apart-sheikh-rehanas-second-fateful-flight-with-sister-hasina-6275820]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:56:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Sheikh Rehana was with her elder sister Hasina in Europe when her father and Bangladesh president Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, mother Begum Fazilatunnesa and brothers Kamal, Jamal and Russel were massacred on August 15, 1975 during a military coup]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sheikh Rehana was with her elder sister Sheikh Hasina in Europe when her father and Bangladesh president Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, mother Begum Fazilatunnesa and brothers Kamal, Jamal and Russel were massacred on August 15, 1975 in a military coup. Forty-nine years later, as Sheikh Hasina was forced to quit as Prime Minister and flee the country amid nationwide protests, Rehana was again with her in the military aircraft that brought them to India.</p>

<p>Sixty-eight-year-old Sheikh Rehana, the fourth of Mujibur Rahman's five children, has often accompanied elder sister Sheikh Hasina on her official trips and is one of the prominent leaders of the Awami League. A constant companion, she also organised party meetings on Sheikh Hasina's behalf when she was imprisoned in 2007-2008 during an Emergency in the country.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Mujibur Rahman, wife Fazilatunnesa, daughters Hasina, Rehana and sons Kamal, Jamal, Russel. Courtesy: Somoy TV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/50bltqdo_mujib-family_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Mujibur Rahman, wife Fazilatunnesa, daughters Hasina, Rehana and sons Kamal, Jamal, Russel. Courtesy: Somoy TV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Mujibur Rahman, his wife Fazilatunnesa, daughters Hasina, Rehana and sons Kamal, Jamal, Russel. Courtesy: Somoy TV</p>
</div>

<p><strong>The 1975 Massacre</strong></p>

<p>On July 1975, Sheikh Hasina and her sister Rehana flew to Germany where Hasina's husband and physicist, late MA Wazed Miah, had been working. The whole family came to the airport to see them off. Little did the two sisters know that they won't see their parents, brothers and sisters-in-law again. Five decades later, Ms Hasina told ANI in an interview, "Because my husband was abroad, so I used to live in the same house. That day everybody was there: my father, mother, my three brothers, two newly-wedded sisters-in-law, everybody was there. That was the last day..."</p>

<p>A fortnight later, Mujibur Rahman, his wife, three sons and two daughters-in-law were massacred at their home in Dhanmondi. Along with the staff, a total of 36 people were killed by Bangladesh Army personnel. Hasina, her husband and children Sajeeb Wazed and Saima Wazed, and Rehana took refuge in India.</p>

<p>India, Sheikh Hasina had later recalled,&nbsp;was one of the first countries to extend help.&nbsp;"Mrs Indira Gandhi immediately sent information that she wanted to give us, I mean, security and shelter. So we received, especially from Marshal Tito from Yugoslavia, and Mrs Gandhi. We decided to come back here (Delhi) because we had in our mind that if we go to Delhi, from Delhi we'll be able to go back to our country. And then we'll be able to know how many members of family are still alive," she said.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Sheikh Rehana was with Sheikh Hasina in Europe when the massacre that wiped off their family took place. Courtesy: Somoy TV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/e8fpi36o_sheikh-rehana-sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Sheikh Rehana was with Sheikh Hasina in Europe when the massacre that wiped off their family took place. Courtesy: Somoy TV" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Sheikh Rehana was with Sheikh Hasina in Europe when the massacre that wiped off their family took place. Courtesy: Somoy TV</p>
</div>

<p><strong>Sheikh Rehana's Family</strong></p>

<p>A couple of years after the massacre, Rehana married Bangladeshi academic Shafique Ahmed Siddiqui. The wedding took place in London and Sheikh Hasina could not attend, reportedly due to lack of money. Sheikh Rehana has three children - Radwan Mujib Siddiq is a strategy consultant and also a trustee of Awami League's research wing, Centre for Research and Information. Daughter Tulip Siddiq is a Labour Party politician in the UK and currently holds positions of&nbsp;Economic Secretary to the Treasury and City Minister in the Keir Starmer dispensation. Rehana's third child, Azmina Siddiq Rupanti, works with a risk consultancy.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fhmq9jng_sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>The 2024 Escape</strong></p>

<p>Call it coincidence or fate, Sheikh Rehana was with sister Hasina in the second big escape of her life. This time, the two knew what was coming. The protesters were at their doorstep and time was running out. But the elder sister was adamant. Her advisors were urging her to let go and escape, warning that she may not get the chance later. But Hasina refused to budge. Helpless, they turned to Sheikh Rehana to help convince the Prime Minister, according to a report by Bangladesh newspaper Prothom Alo. Rehana spoke to Hasina, but she did not agree.</p>

<p>Eventually, it was a call from Hasina's son Sajeeb Wazed that convinced her. The two sisters, their fates intertwined by destiny, packed their bags and boarded a chopper as protesters stormed their home and vandalised the statues of their late father, Mujibur Rahman. Forty-nine years on, it's another exile for Hasina, and Rehana is with her this time too.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/lsckrs7o_sheikh-rehana-sheikh-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A file picture of Sheikh Rehana and Sheikh Hasina in happier times. Courtesy: Somoy TV]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-detains-italian-drone-pilot-in-moscow-for-kremlin-flyover-6275813]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Detains Italian Man For Flying A Drone Near The Kremlin]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-detains-italian-drone-pilot-in-moscow-for-kremlin-flyover-6275813]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:53:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An Italian man has been detained in Moscow after flying a drone near the Kremlin, state news agency TASS reported on Tuesday, citing law enforcement sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Italian man has been detained in Moscow after flying a drone near the Kremlin, state news agency TASS reported on Tuesday, citing law enforcement sources.</p>

<p>TASS said Russian law enforcement agencies detained the man, a flight attendant, for operating the drone over Zaryadye Park which sits just beside the Kremlin in central Moscow.</p>

<p>The Italian embassy in Moscow did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>

<p>The Italian man said that he did not know about a ban on flying drones in Moscow and just wanted to capture beautiful pictures of the capital, TASS said.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a73jd168_drone_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Italian man said that he did not know about ban on flying drones in Moscow (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lionel-messis-ibiza-mansion-targeted-by-climate-activists-futuro-vegetal-in-spain-6275595]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[''Help The Planet'': Climate Activists Spray-Paint Lionel Messi's Mansion]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/lionel-messis-ibiza-mansion-targeted-by-climate-activists-futuro-vegetal-in-spain-6275595]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:29:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Climate activists on Tuesday spray-painted a mansion on the Spanish holiday island of Ibiza belonging to Argentina football star Lionel Messi to highlight the "responsibility of the rich for the climate crisis".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate activists on Tuesday spray-painted a mansion on the Spanish holiday island of Ibiza belonging to Argentina football star Lionel Messi to highlight the "responsibility of the rich for the climate crisis".</p>

<p>Campaigners from the group Futuro Vegetal released a video showing two members standing in front of the house near the cove of Cala Tarida on Ibiza's western coast holding a banner that read: "Help the Planet -- Eat the Rich -- Abolish the Police."</p>

<p>The activists then sprayed the white facade of the building with red and black paint.</p>

<p>In a statement, the group said they wanted to show "the responsibility of the rich for the climate crisis" by targeting the mansion which they said was an "illegal construction".</p>

<p>Futuro Vegetal cited a 2023 Oxfam report that found that the richest one per cent of the world's population generated the same amount of carbon emissions in 2019 as the poorest two-thirds of humanity, despite the fact that the most vulnerable communities are the ones suffering the "worst consequences" of this crisis.</p>

<p>Messi, who currently plays for Inter Miami in the US, reportedly bought the property on the Mediterranean island -- which includes a spa with a sauna and a cinema room -- in 2022 from a Swiss businessman for around 11 million euros ($12 million).</p>

<p>But the mansion lacked a certificate of occupancy, a document issued by a local government agency certifying it is in a liveable condition, due to the construction of several rooms in the property without a licence, according to Spanish media reports.</p>

<p>Futuro Vegetal, which is linked to similar groups internationally, has staged dozens of similar protests, including one in 2022 where they glued their hands to frames of paintings by Spanish master Francisco de Goya at Madrid's Prado museum.</p>

<p>Last year activists from the group spray-painted a superyacht moored in Ibiza with red and black paint that reportedly belonged to Nancy Walton Laurie, the billionaire heiress of US retail giant Walmart.</p>

<p>Spanish police in January said they had arrested 22 members of the Futuro Vegetal, including the two who staged the protest at the Prado as well as the group's top three leaders.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/0aq1n3po_lionel-messi-ibiza_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The mansion lacked a certificate of occupancy due to the construction of rooms without a licence.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-president-dissolves-parliament-amid-protests-6275547]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Parliament Dissolved A Day After Sheikh Hasina's Ouster]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladeshs-president-dissolves-parliament-amid-protests-6275547]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:22:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's president dissolved parliament on Tuesday, a key demand of student protesters who led demonstrations that ousted long time ruler Sheikh Hasina, a statement read.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's president dissolved parliament on Tuesday, a key demand of student protesters who led demonstrations that ousted long time ruler <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a>, a statement read.</p>

<p>"The president has dissolved parliament," Shiplu Zaman, press secretary of President Mohammed Shahabuddin, said in a statement.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ng03u2to_bangladesh-parliament_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["The president has dissolved parliament," Shiplu Zaman, press secretary said in a statement.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-to-its-ban-citizens-going-to-border-areas-of-lebanon-and-israel-6275546]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korea To Ban Citizens Going To Border Areas Of Lebanon And Israel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korea-to-its-ban-citizens-going-to-border-areas-of-lebanon-and-israel-6275546]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 15:22:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[South Korea said on Tuesday it will issue a ban on its citizens travelling to the border areas of Israel and Lebanon after advising them to leave the countries amid escalating tensions in the Middle East.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea said on Tuesday it will issue a ban on its citizens travelling to the border areas of Israel and Lebanon after advising them to leave the countries amid escalating tensions in the Middle East.</p>

<p>The foreign ministry said the ban will start from Wednesday in areas near the Blue Line, referring to a demarcation line between Lebanon and Israel where parts of the international border are disputed.</p>

<p>The ministry also "strongly advised" its nationals in Lebanon and Israel to leave the countries as soon as possible.</p>

<p>A temporary advisory urging against travel to Iran was also set to be issued, the ministry said in a statement.</p>

<p>The travel advisory was issued after a commander of the Iran-aligned Lebanese group Hezbollah and the head of the political wing of Hamas, the group that runs the Gaza Strip, were killed, Lee Jae-woong, a ministry spokesperson said.</p>

<p>The assassinations came after a deadly rocket attack in the Israeli-occupied Golan Heights late last month.</p>

<p>"South Korea's government...hopes that diplomatic efforts to de-escalate tensions such as negotiations for a ceasefire and hostage release will not stop," Lee told a briefing.</p>

<p>Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh was killed in the Iranian capital Tehran last week, an attack that drew threats of revenge on Israel and fueled further concern that the conflict in Gaza was turning into a wider Middle East war.Washington has been urging other countries through diplomatic channels to tell Iran that escalation in the Middle East is not in their interest, a State Department spokesperson said on Monday.</p>

<p>More than 500 South Korean nationals are currently residing in Israel and around 120 in Lebanon, the ministry said. It warned that South Koreans travelling to the border areas could be subject to punishment under the passport law.</p>

<p>As of last summer at least four South Koreans had been convicted of violating a ban on travelling to Ukraine without permission, according to media reports.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/7kub9qo8_hezbollah-and-israeli-forces_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A temporary advisory urging against travel to Iran was also set to be issued]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-arch-rival-khaleda-zia-freed-from-house-arrest-6275323]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Sheikh Hasina Ouster, Arch-Rival Khaleda Zia Freed From House Arrest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/day-after-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-arch-rival-khaleda-zia-freed-from-house-arrest-6275323]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:56:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's ex-prime minister Khaleda Zia has been released from years of house arrest after her bitter enemy Sheikh Hasina was ousted as premier, her party said Tuesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's ex-prime minister Khaleda Zia has been released from years of house arrest after her bitter enemy Sheikh Hasina was ousted as premier, her party said Tuesday.</p>

<p>"She is now freed", a Bangladesh National Party (BNP) party spokesman, A.K.M Wahiduzzaman, told AFP, a day after orders to release her were given following the military taking control.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-04/khaleda-zia_650x400_61460897282.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/want-to-live-longer-german-firm-aims-to-bring-you-back-from-dead-6275304]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Want To Live Longer? German Firm Aims To Bring You Back From Dead]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/want-to-live-longer-german-firm-aims-to-bring-you-back-from-dead-6275304]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:52:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The company claims that the body can be willingly revived in the future and cause of death treated.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Death is inevitable, still many people across the world are busy finding ways to become immortal. Like 46-year-old Bryan Johnson, the CEO of a Silicon Valley company, who claims to have reversed his biological age by more than five years through an anti-ageing regimen. Taking it a step further, a start-up in Germany is offering to freeze people in cryopreservation and be revived when technology is advanced enough. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://in.mashable.com/science/79875/freeze-your-dead-body-at-rs18-crore-and-revive-it-in-the-future-german-startup-says-its-possible"><em>Mashable</em></a>, Tomorrow Bio is demanding Rs 1.8 crore to preserve the entire body after death and Rs 67.2 lakh if someone just wants their brain to be frozen.</p>

<p>Through cryopreservation, where temperature is minus 198 degrees Celsius, the company puts a body in 'biostasis' - a state where all biological processes are ceased indefinitely.</p>

<p>The company claims that the body can be willingly revived in the future and cause of death treated.</p>

<p>Tomorrow Bio said on its website that the company's vision is "to build a world where people can choose how long they want to live -Independent of where they are, who they are, and their financial resources".</p>

<p><em>Mashable</em> said that six people and five pets have already been put under cryopreservation, and more than 650 people who have paid for the service are waiting in line.</p>

<p>Company's co-founder Fernando Azevedo Pinheir said during his lifetime, "we may witness the safe cryopreservation and reanimation of complex organisms".</p>

<p>Mr Pinheir also said that his company starts the work as soon as a person dies. He explained that specially made ambulances available in different European cities carry the bodies to the main facility in Switzerland. The company has standby teams in Berline, Amsterdam and Zurich for the job.</p>

<p>The body is then kept in an isolated steel container filled with liquid nitrogen for 10 days to achieve the temperature of minus 198 degrees Celsius.</p>

<h3><strong>What is cryopreservation?</strong></h3>

<p>It is a process where biological material - cells, tissues, or organs - are frozen to preserve the material for an extended period of time.</p>

<p>However, cryopreservation is different from freezing. It involves a special cryoprotectant solutions (liquid nitrogen) to prevent ice crystals on the body, which can be detrimental for it.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jsp9f9h_cryopreservation-generic_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Under cryopreservation, cells, tissues, or organs are frozen for an extended period of time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-air-lines-ceo-ed-bastian-slams-microsoft-as-most-fragile-platform-after-global-outage-6275151]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Delta CEO Slams Microsoft As "Most Fragile" Platform After Global Outage]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/delta-air-lines-ceo-ed-bastian-slams-microsoft-as-most-fragile-platform-after-global-outage-6275151]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:40:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Delta Air Lines CEO Ed Bastian declared Microsoft "the most fragile" platform after a massive IT outage last month caused chaos across the world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Delta Air Lines CEO Ed Bastian declared Microsoft "the most fragile" platform after a massive IT outage last month caused chaos across the world. The outage, lasting five days, is estimated to have cost Delta $500 million in lost revenue, compensation and hotel expenses.</p>

<p>Mr Bastian's comments came in response to questions about the airline's ongoing relationship with Microsoft. In a CNBC interview, the Delta CEO said "Microsoft is probably the most fragile platform" and pointedly asked, "When was the last time you heard of a big outage at Apple?"&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mr Bastian spoke of the high valuations of big tech companies, fueled in part by the hype surrounding generative AI, and argued that these companies have a responsibility to ensure the stability of their current systems. "They are building the future, and they have to make sure they fortify the current," he said.</p>

<p><iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j2DbePHiH64?si=_DpIIGzk3PohEkAj" title="YouTube video player" width="560"></iframe></p>

<p>The outage, which affected Delta's website, mobile app, and check-in systems, resulted in thousands of refunds and reimbursement requests. While the exact number was not disclosed, a Delta spokesman confirmed it was in the "thousands." The outage, caused by a botched CrowdStrike software update, took thousands of Microsoft systems offline and required 40,000 servers to be manually reset. Delta's crew scheduling platforms were also affected, leading to further disruptions, the CEO said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"If you're going to be having access, priority access to the Delta ecosystem in terms of technology, you've got to test the stuff. You can't come into a mission-critical 24/7 operation and tell us we have a bug," Mr Bastian said.</p>

<p>CrowdStrike, the cybersecurity firm responsible for the problematic update, has yet to offer any financial assistance to Delta. The company has only provided free consulting advice on managing the fallout.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In response to the incident, Delta has hired attorney David Boies to seek compensation from both CrowdStrike and Microsoft. Mr Bastian said they needed to protect "shareholders, customers and employees" from the financial and "reputational damage" caused by the outage.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/i3otu9fg_delta-air-lines-ceo-ed-bastian_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ed Bastian spoke of the high valuations of big tech companies.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/we-are-in-close-touch-with-indian-community-in-bangladesh-s-jaishankar-in-parliament-6275167]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Sheikh Hasina Requested To Come, Situation Still Evolving": S Jaishankar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/we-are-in-close-touch-with-indian-community-in-bangladesh-s-jaishankar-in-parliament-6275167]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:36:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The government is in close touch with the nearly 19,000 Indian nationals - almost half of whom are students - in Bangladesh, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar told Parliament Tuesday afternoon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/sheikh-hasina" target="_blank">Sheikh Hasina</a> requested permission "at very short notice" to come to India following her forced resignation as Bangladesh Prime Minister, External Affairs Minister <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/s-jaishankar" target="_blank">S Jaishankar</a> said Tuesday.</p>

<p>Briefing Parliament on the "still evolving"&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-unrest-live-updates-pm-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-violence-bangladesh-violence-live-6267300" target="_blank">Bangladesh situation</a>, India's response, and the status of an estimated 19,000 nationals in that country, Mr Jaishankar said the government is in "close and continuous touch" with the Indian community and called on the host nation to provide required security.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar, who briefed leaders at an all-party meet this morning and <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/pm-modi" target="_blank">Prime Minister Narendra Modi</a> last night, said he sought "the understanding and support of the House" on this issue.</p>

<p>"On August 4 (protests in Bangladesh) took a very serious turn. Attacks on police, including police stations and government installations, intensified even as overall levels of violence escalated and properties of individuals associated with the regime were torched. What was worrying was that minorities and their businesses and temples also came under attack at multiple locations."</p>

<p>"On August 5 demonstrators converged in Dhaka despite a curfew. Our understanding is that after a meeting with leaders of the security establishment Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina made the decision to resign. At very short notice she requested approval to come, for the moment, to India. We simultaneously received a request for flight clearance... she arrived yesterday evening in Delhi."</p>

<p>He also referred to an address by Bangladesh Army chief General Waker-uz-Zaman - made Monday evening, shortly after Mrs Hasina stepped down - in which he said, "I have met opposition leaders... we have decided to form an interim government..." and appealed for the violent protests to end.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/jem8luuo_bangladesh-protest-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Add image caption here" /></div>

<p class="ins_instory_dv_caption">Over 400 people have reportedly died in violent protests in Bangladesh beginning last month.</p>
</div>

<p>"The situation in Bangladesh is still evolving. We are in close and continuous touch with the Indian community in Bangladesh through our diplomatic missions. There are an estimated 19,000 Indian nationals of which about 9,000 are students. The bulk of students returned in July..." he said.</p>

<p>"In the last 24 hours we have also been in regular touch with authorities in Dhaka. I seek the understanding and support of the House in regard to sensitive issues regarding an important neighbour on which there has always been strong national consensus," he said.</p>

<p>Mr Jaishankar also spoke about India's diplomatic missions in Chittagong, Rajshahi, Khulna and Sylhet, and said, "It is our expectation the host government will provide required security..."</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-security-meet-and-a-phone-call-the-hours-before-sheikh-hasinas-escape-6274604" target="_blank">What Went Down At Sheikh Hasina's Home Before She Fled</a></p>

<p>On the question of minorities (over 90 per cent of Bangladeshis are Muslims), he said, "We are monitoring the situation with regard to minorities. There are reports of initiatives to ensure their protection. We welcome that... but will remain deeply concerned till law and order is visibly restored."</p>

<p>The events in Bangladesh present a problem for India, particularly if the UK turns down Sheikh Hasina's asylum request. India also does not want to be seen as overtly backing the ousted leader because that may complicate the country's relationship with the new government in Bangladesh, whatever it may be.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protest-bangladesh-updates-india-faces-tightrope-walk-after-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6273466" target="_blank">India's Dilemma After Dhaka Power Shift, Sheikh Hasina's Ouster</a></p>

<p>New Delhi is keeping a wary eye on Bangladesh after the fall of Sheikh Hasina, who pursued a delicate balancing act of enjoying support from India while maintaining strong relations with China.</p>

<p>India's northeast states share a 4,096-km border with Bangladesh. Infiltration concerns prompted a 12-hour night curfew in Meghalaya, as well as putting Border Security Forces on high alert.</p>

<h3><strong>Sheikh Hasina In India</strong></h3>

<p>Mrs Hasina, 76, is in an undisclosed location in India after fleeing Dhaka - shortly before protesters overran and looted her residence. She has reportedly applied for asylum in the United Kingdom.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-no-provision-for-what-uk-said-on-sheikh-hasina-asylum-reports-6275013#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">"No Provision For...": What UK Said On Sheikh Hasina Asylum Reports</a></p>

<p>There are reports she resigned following an ultimatum by the Bangladesh Army.</p>

<p>Also, earlier today Mr Jaishankar spoke of a "conspiracy" to topple Mrs Hasina.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protests-rahul-gandhi-s-jaishankar-rahul-gandhis-pak-question-at-meeting-on-bangladesh-s-jaishankars-reply-6274003#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll" target="_blank">Rahul Gandhi's Bangladesh-Pak Question, S Jaishankar's Reply</a></p>

<p>This was in response to a question by Congress MP Rahul Gandhi, who asked if there could be an involvement of foreign powers, specifically Pakistan, in the developments in Dhaka.</p>

<h3><strong>What Next For Bangladesh?</strong></h3>

<p>A new "interim government" - to be advised, most likely, by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus - is believed to be taking shape in the crisis-hit country. This follows the release from jail - ordered by President Mohammed Shahabuddin - of former PM Khaleda Zia, who was convicted of corruption.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-violence-ex-pm-khaleda-zia-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-student-leader-nahid-islam-key-faces-in-new-bangladesh-government-6274762#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Ex-PM, Nobel Winner, Student Leader: Key Faces In New Government?</a></p>

<p>In speculation that has emerged (inevitably so) since Mrs Hasina quit, three key names or groups are at the forefront, two of whom are the Army, which took charge after Mrs Hasina quit, and which may have given her a 45-minute ultimatum; and her nemesis and former Prime Minister Khaleda Zia, who was jailed in 2018 on corruption charges and whose release was ordered by the President.</p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/9v7a4208_jaishankar-_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Bangladesh protests: S Jaishankar spoke on the Bangladesh issue in Parliament.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-sheikh-hasina-accused-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-of-sucking-blood-of-poor-6275083]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[When Sheikh Hasina Accused Nobel Winner Yunus Of "Sucking Blood Of Poor"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/when-sheikh-hasina-accused-nobel-winner-muhammad-yunus-of-sucking-blood-of-poor-6275083]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:23:33 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, the pioneer of the global microcredit movement who could shepherd Bangladesh's new interim government, was an arch foe of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina who has resigned and fled the country.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus, the pioneer of the global microcredit movement who could shepherd Bangladesh's new interim government, was an arch foe of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina who has resigned and fled the country.</p>

<p>Known as the "banker to the poor", Mr Yunus and the Grameen Bank he founded won the 2006 Nobel Peace Prize for helping lift millions from poverty by providing tiny loans of sums less than $100 to the rural poor who are too impoverished to gain attention from traditional banks.</p>

<p>Their lending model has since inspired similar projects around the world, including developed countries like the United States where Mr Yunus started a separate non-profit Grameen America.</p>

<p>As his success grew, Mr Yunus, now 84, flirted briefly with a political career, attempting to form his own party in 2007. But his ambitions were widely viewed as having sparked the ire of Hasina, who accused him of "sucking blood from the poor".</p>

<p>Critics in Bangladesh and other countries, including neighbouring India, have also said microlenders charge excessive rates and make money out of the poor. But Mr Yunus said the rates were far lower than local interest rates in developing countries or the 300% or more that loan sharks sometimes demand.</p>

<p>In 2011, Ms Hasina's government removed him as head of Grameen Bank, saying that at 73, he had stayed on past the legal retirement age of 60. Thousands of Bangladeshis formed a human chain to protest his sacking.</p>

<p>In January this year, Mr Yunus was sentenced to six months in prison for violations of labour law. He and 13 others were also indicted by a Bangladesh court in June on charges of embezzlement of 252.2 million taka ($2 million) from the workers' welfare fund of a telecoms company he founded.</p>

<p>Although he was not jailed in either case, Mr Yunus faces more than 100 other cases on graft and other charges. Mr Yunus denies any involvement and said, during an interview with Reuters, the accusations were "very flimsy, made-up stories".</p>

<p>"Bangladesh doesn't have any politics left," Mr Yunus said in June, criticising Ms Hasina. "There's only one party which is active and occupies everything, does everything, gets to the elections in their way."</p>

<p>He told Indian broadcaster Times Now that Monday marked the "second liberation day" for Bangladesh after its 1971 war of independence from Pakistan following the exit of Ms Hasina.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus is currently in Paris undergoing a minor medical procedure, his spokesperson said, adding he has agreed to the request of students who led the campaign against Mr Hasina to be the chief adviser of the interim government.</p>

<p>Mr Yunus was an economist teaching at the University of Chittagong when famine struck Bangladesh in 1974, killing hundreds of thousands of people and leaving him searching for better ways to help his country's vast rural population.</p>

<p>That opportunity came when Mr Yunus came across a woman in a village near he university who had borrowed from a moneylender. The amount was less than a dollar but in return the moneylender gained the exclusive right to buy everything she produced at a price to be determined by the moneylender.</p>

<p>"This to me was a way of recruiting slave labour," Mr Yunus said in his Nobel acceptance speech. He found 42 people who had borrowed a combined $27 from the moneylender and lent them the funds himself - the success of that endeavour spurring him on to do more and think of credit as a basic human right.</p>

<p>"When I gave the loans I was astounded by the results I got. The poor paid the loans on time every time."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/8kv81gqo_yunus-hasina_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[In 2011, Sheikh Hasina's government removed Muhammad Yunus as head of Grameen Bank]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/for-india-a-post-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-doesnt-seem-like-a-great-friend-6275022]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: A Post-Hasina Bangladesh Doesn't Seem Like A Great Friend For India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/for-india-a-post-sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-doesnt-seem-like-a-great-friend-6275022]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:15:32 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hasinas resignation is possibly one of the biggest strategic shocks for New Delhi in recent years. Her governments economic and foreign policy fostered a strong bond with India and made it a hub of regional connectivity and integration.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j76av12g_bangladesh_625x300_06_August_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-protest-bangladesh-updates-india-faces-tightrope-walk-after-bangladesh-turmoil-sheikh-hasinas-ouster-6273466">In Bangladesh</a>, what began as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-nahid-islam-the-student-leader-at-the-centre-of-the-bangladesh-protests-6274106">student demonstrations against job quotas</a> quickly turned into the downfall of the country's longest-serving Prime Minister, Sheikh Hasina. The protests, which began last month, turned violent on July 15 when the<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="0" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.dhakatribune.com%2Fbangladesh%2F352171%2F4-injured-in-clash-between-protesters-chhatra&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415530291%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=n6Sj%2BenDoqt%2FOqRU%2Bebvl6KBkk1YuWuNUd0jE4MWml4%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWAa6e4ec88-8b62-d091-57f8-b77be5c17326" originalsrc="https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/352171/4-injured-in-clash-between-protesters-chhatra" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="wOrc+9zF/8A8ZRenC/eqlNfSMN/sKngm6LEIlVd9Ba9YCL0DNUu/xBkslSEptfENfMXSSkgcrAEcok8+1V10LL0CHt04DxAFts7JsEaqoyHzmE/s+PIhIeuqnfmz2grY2uJ/wJwfY1JWl/rEGdE5Z/gGdbYeESMVcQVr2AG+RS8=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://www.dhakatribune.com/bangladesh/352171/4-injured-in-clash-between-protesters-chhatra. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>supporters&nbsp;of Hasina's Awami League clashed with the students, prompting the government to use tear gas shells, impose curfews, internet blockades, and shoot-at-sight orders. The opposition Bangladesh National Party (BNP) and Jamaat-e-Islami (JI) were also quick to join the movement, which further exacerbated the violence.</p>

<p>As of August 5, over&nbsp;300 people&nbsp;had been killed and hundreds injured. As an angry mob marched into Dhaka on the same day, the army “took responsibility” of the country, and Hasina resigned.</p>

<p>While an interim government will soon be in place, the future of the country now hangs by a thread, and this is no good news for South Asia.</p>

<h2><strong>Hasina's Had Been A Success Story</strong></h2>

<p>Hasina's Bangladesh saw significant economic growth and development. The country<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="3" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fforeignpolicy.com%2F2024%2F07%2F23%2Fbangladesh-protests-unrest-political-crisis-democracy-sheikh-hasina%2F%23%3A~%3Atext%3DBangladesh%2520has%2520made%2520impressive%2520economic%2Cthe%2520United%2520Nations%2520in%25202026.&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415555075%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gEKFVPQU7oHiiFxmHS%2FHhXEdnQMxaIv1TxjdAHiKImI%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA71bdf350-f1c4-304d-af69-2c19de6589c0" originalsrc="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/07/23/bangladesh-protests-unrest-political-crisis-democracy-sheikh-hasina/#:~:text=Bangladesh%20has%20made%20impressive%20economic,the%20United%20Nations%20in%202026." rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="tcbfGgtkOLadU7sOszQ//aqkosy1PDzxgQDcSNDsAct5jwMiXYpqBYFdI/oks5flmXDXj+slO/tHFEqHfca5mG7J+gD0/EBxR8+hLaTWAulr1/0FmB0yI883Ot4dqntUlVcFZLvsj7N3ldNWgsVwvFFZI4pNRbFSvYAVF1S9UOg=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/07/23/bangladesh-protests-unrest-political-crisis-democracy-sheikh-hasina/#:~:text=Bangladesh%20has%20made%20impressive%20economic,the%20United%20Nations%20in%202026.. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>managed&nbsp;to maintain an average GDP growth rate of 6.6% over the last decade, and its poverty decreased from 12% in 2008 to over 5% in 2022. Its GDP<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="5" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdata.worldbank.org%2Findicator%2FNY.GDP.MKTP.CD%3Flocations%3DBD&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415569273%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=BNLRRgJTgaRNxe3MHWaZTzNZ8F6pawHZRX90T2MFbmE%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA1c40dcbb-614f-65ad-61d1-ff823135791b" originalsrc="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.MKTP.CD?locations=BD" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="LJl6zyOXGuLVbjwGMOaYDPYQEJtyxSTTWxP683watl1QHb088bAD6Vmr8WCy6quc27PdiunSMThMd4mkhbBkyi9qn4wNYOfQh3MoLrLhSTuur01dxnIFaGo5+1nlCoUfvg7WdXnoENzp23NkmTlA+RNjdhFOttWOx3ofiya3NJ4=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.MKTP.CD?locations=BD. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>increased&nbsp;from $100 billion in 2009 to $460 billion in 2022. Given this trajectory, the country was expected to graduate from its Least Developed Country status by 2026.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/sheikh-hasina-and-family-when-the-hunted-is-also-the-hunter-6269970">Also Read | Sheikh Hasina: When The Hunted Is Also The Hunter</a></strong></p>

<p>The last few decades also ushered in some political stability. By suppressing the<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="7" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fscroll.in%2Farticle%2F1071067%2Fhow-the-indian-government-helped-sheikh-hasina-suppress-the-2009-revolt-of-the-bangladesh-rifles&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415581452%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=hXz12o01QZWbJpMlPZE4ZevnrUngEclsV3OmotxQknA%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA8fafc65c-20ea-4cc3-b61f-d73f2d6e6754" originalsrc="https://scroll.in/article/1071067/how-the-indian-government-helped-sheikh-hasina-suppress-the-2009-revolt-of-the-bangladesh-rifles" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="kA/kO8bYpQvlLB9Ee+uREsDcPsH99pWXxmau2aRgtlkgEkoxYWq05iP4QRvrxnWurR7IRcKmWJL7hHwGg7kWYUkFcxhieo3vmh03vuDCIHWn5LgjMdeBnGJ8bRZthQ/JN8Ly9GvFaURiQq5ByxDODngT53ic8HMWt1nc2L4GZgg=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://scroll.in/article/1071067/how-the-indian-government-helped-sheikh-hasina-suppress-the-2009-revolt-of-the-bangladesh-rifles. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>2009 mutiny&nbsp;of Bangladesh Rifles, Hasina had put to end the frequent military coups in the country and subordinated such forces to civilian authorities. She had also brought continuity and certainty to the country's external conduct, especially with the “Friendship to all, malice to none” foreign policy, which had been key in attracting investments and infrastructure from the West, India, Russia, China, and Japan alike.</p>

<p>A crucial aspect of her successful foreign policy had been winning India's trust and improving economic ties. Hasina respected India's three red lines, which the previous BNP and JI governments violated on multiple occasions. This included protecting Hindu minorities, clamping down on extremists and Northeast militants who targeted India from Bangladesh, and respecting Indian security sensitivities and concerns when engaging with hostile countries like Pakistan and China.</p>

<p>Under these robust ties, the trade between both countries grew from $2 billion in 2007 to $14 billion in 2022, and as of the following year, New Delhi had even offered Dhaka<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="9" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.orfonline.org%2Fpublic%2Fuploads%2Fposts%2Fpdf%2F20240430110935.pdf&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415593626%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=gOJ5uSmWYMN6jiqwTSbUOqTvARs%2FCnvvax1wbf%2FG8dQ%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWAa4232a63-f3ed-7711-e4cb-94d901e2c4a1" originalsrc="https://www.orfonline.org/public/uploads/posts/pdf/20240430110935.pdf" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="ls4HblN4XtFRj5Ww1uyudBY4iKm9HMb02zi6oyYACRkThJK1c3BDgd3B+95xfh6JmkQLlSwC3lbDjCDLkniiz+FprvDTx8M4Dmk+rn60CUycxTgyKUzwg+1VaXcH8j1xTPwfThycF7tCNFO0RCtV8nFxu+U/TAC0ZfpXyURBPMA=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://www.orfonline.org/public/uploads/posts/pdf/20240430110935.pdf. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>over $8 billion&nbsp;in credit lines.</p>

<p>Connectivity took precedence too with the reopening of rail lines, a push for transit and port access, and the construction of a diesel supply pipeline. Both countries also resolved their maritime disputes and ratified the land boundary pact, ushering in the “golden era of India-Bangladesh relations”.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>India's Quest for Connectivity&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>Notably, New Delhi's trust for Hasina incentivised India to promote regional integration and connectivity through its own territory, something Dhaka had long been calling for. This was done for two reasons: one, it would help India's neighbours to boost their economies by fostering economic cooperation with each other, and two, it would help Delhi deter increasing Chinese presence and investments in these countries.</p>

<p>Dhaka's stability and economic growth also made it an attractive market for South Asian countries like Nepal and Bhutan, both of which possess great energy potential, even as they have scant foreign reserves and are landlocked and over-dependent on India. Bangladesh has looked up to these countries for importing energy, exporting its products, and further fuelling its economic growth.</p>

<p><strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/months-before-ouster-sheikh-hasina-had-made-this-explosive-allegation-6274497">Also Read |&nbsp;Months Ago, Sheikh Hasina Had Claimed She Got An "Offer" From "White Man"</a></strong></p>

<p>As a result, in<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="11" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.orfonline.org%2Fexpert-speak%2Fdelhi-and-dhaka-are-bolstering-bhutan-s-vision-for-connectivity%23%3A~%3Atext%3DA%2520vision%2520for%2520connectivity%253A%2Cup%2520most%2520of%2520the%2520trade.&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415605402%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=SnwdvQjkF19bTBUx%2FU31urNj%2Fg19LCb%2BT7YYuAMuwmk%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA2d1f5e19-56b8-a6cb-d141-024b4232b1d4" originalsrc="https://www.orfonline.org/expert-speak/delhi-and-dhaka-are-bolstering-bhutan-s-vision-for-connectivity#:~:text=A%20vision%20for%20connectivity%3A,up%20most%20of%20the%20trade." rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="Z24I8WC+RUwAZp5AslQG6Rsev8G/BQuffLwfrmO70Fj7H7TBLIDDdwEdCISCyEtWN04xpcXisoswjiFOBFeopEh15/EmsfsCL/6YNYaYrD8AiWEarcERfhP+EkPZKzAs1oqMA1gh5h+0rIMVH85noTv1Ts9T/znwloIm78IAqhU=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://www.orfonline.org/expert-speak/delhi-and-dhaka-are-bolstering-bhutan-s-vision-for-connectivity#:~:text=A%20vision%20for%20connectivity%3A,up%20most%20of%20the%20trade.. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>2022, India offered — though this has not been implemented yet — free transit to Bangladeshi trucks headed for Nepal and Bhutan. In June, New Delhi and Dhaka also signed an MoU that enabled Bangladesh railways to reach Nepal and Bhutan using Indian railway lines. Bangladesh itself permitted Bhutan to&nbsp;build&nbsp;a special economic zone in its territory, which would be crucial to the latter's Gelephu Special Administrative Region project when linked through India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>India, meanwhile, had recently agreed to facilitate electricity trade from Nepal and Bhutan to Bangladesh through Indian energy grids and transmission lines.&nbsp;</p>

<p>All these agreements would have helped Nepal, Bhutan, and Bangladesh to tap into each others' resources and trade and save both time and cost, while also reducing their dependence on China.</p>

<h2><strong>No Good News For India Or Its Neighbors&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>However, the recent developments threaten to throw a massive spanner in the works. There are now new complexities to India-Bangladesh relations, and by extension, their ambitions for improving&nbsp;bilateral and regional&nbsp;connectivity.&nbsp;</p>

<p>First, the country's opposition, the BNP and the JI, are seeing a revival amid the protests and violence in the country. Both parties have historically advocated for close ties with Pakistan and China and have consistently violated India's red lines. Over the last decade, they have even furthered nationalist and religious sentiments against India by accusing Delhi of supporting Hasina. Protests by the BNP, the JI and hardline affiliates like Hefazat-e-Islam (HI)<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="15" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.bbc.com%2Fnews%2Fworld-asia-56586210&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415629962%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=fM4wMxzZKBnYiBy2zTm%2BFEGlRnDbheBWRyzadD88n3Y%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA22322e8c-a023-c336-2013-cd34b420ddd3" originalsrc="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-56586210" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="bfTA2og/uP79SxAajQPs8bchgp8EEnzvq/vxACMv3teej9/RP5W/8HgRo4fe1d6oI2i3EJ4VgAz6KKh9o8kcpfBOzLD4Ch7zN/jolMiUHNz/TNw0akkhIwO0/mmunNX2SvtqDCetp1EnctVaJ8Ct8MTR08wWYV54KChq2dGTeNg=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-56586210. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>against&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/centre-calls-for-all-party-meet-over-bangladesh-s-jaishankar-to-attend-6273367">Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit</a> to Bangladesh in 2021, the recent “India Out” campaign&nbsp;supported&nbsp;by BNP leaders, and&nbsp;the&nbsp;criticism&nbsp;towards the MoU on railway connectivity indicate the Bangladesh opposition's continued scepticism towards India and its initiatives.</p>

<p>Most recently, their cadres and supporters<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="21" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fbdnews24.com%2Fbangladesh%2F6e12f6a606b7&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415671034%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=jaVhPdbrBu74nUbw0JrSGXCpezh1670V4rU%2BkvsDDu8%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWAc948ef1b-7a86-add2-d8df-d1fac47391ea" originalsrc="https://bdnews24.com/bangladesh/6e12f6a606b7" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="Ny3/tHRnGLkRqHXwoXfhBOZMNeqvz/SobBg7bfOZB0zFITqc03D64RS1T7WiZbtEFbnZH5PIBJtp/Rj9Wo6HQcyuYSCa4qxxm3d/1oOSXSDx/UNcE5kzjsV7gEGa0FojwFrPVtbtKGqLQShMkPg4QyDZV7WLTg0CU5P7CsHmVGc=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://bdnews24.com/bangladesh/6e12f6a606b7. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>stormed the&nbsp;Narsingdi jail and freed around 800 prisoners, some of whom are trained militants. Soon after Hasina's resignation, they targeted the country's Hindu minority community and Awami League supporters. These developments not only underscore the opposition's lack of concern for Delhi's sensitivities but also point to the grim possibility of an exodus and of a revival of Delhi's scepticism for Bangladesh. The Indian National Security Advisor's meeting with Hasina after she fled to India demonstrates Delhi's security concerns about the ongoing developments.</p>

<h2><strong>Growing Mistrust</strong></h2>

<p>Second, the students and protesters opposing Hasina have often accused India of supporting her regime. To what extent this rhetoric and narrative will grow depends on India's response to the ongoing developments. In fact, several activists are already&nbsp;alleging&nbsp;that India will deploy its troops to undo their “hard-won freedom”. Such mistrust is bound to make it difficult for any government to foster strong ties with India and deepen economic engagements.</p>

<p>Third, with the army having taken control over the country's administration, questions are being raised about whether the force would be able to maintain stability, especially given its<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="23" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Findianexpress.com%2Farticle%2Fexplained%2Fexplained-global%2Frole-of-army-in-bangladesh-9496610%2F&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415686035%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=pQtk5WuUp5nLiBme1i4X7wVA33dKFGmHScyllqTQxyg%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWAa13f0c51-7556-fc0f-b268-d0633c5087f8" originalsrc="https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/role-of-army-in-bangladesh-9496610/" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="U8kgCTMDMEmpQR1WVO2kTAsoAQLucyCeCLk5Ig8IRF9Vg0WO9oSwx7s2Bel9ImE4fttbqCUppAq24u3Mpoc3Ibx05ax/60Te7OEp0EnPjgoOJJsRFbbIKm03OPgb8/bk4ZPOLtASK3lWKgZ8jBNWKy6qbHdKCbmG+5pYBh50wXw=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-global/role-of-army-in-bangladesh-9496610/. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>history&nbsp;in the early years of Bangladesh's formation. With an angry populace involved in arsoning and violence throughout the country today, some have even expressed concern and dissatisfaction about a military administration. If this anger and disenchantment persist, it will lead to political and economic instability, impacting Bangladesh's economy, investments, and connectivity efforts. This could also have spillover implications for India.</p>

<p>The army also aims to dissolve the current parliament and establish an interim government in<a data-auth="Verified" data-linkindex="25" href="https://apc01.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.news18.com%2Fworld%2Fwhos-who-in-bangladeshs-new-interim-govt-as-ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-flees-restive-nation-8991218.html&amp;data=05%7C02%7CHarshitaM%40ndtv.com%7C698647550f2646fff63008dcb5e77ed5%7C89e0013190cd478790cc5ded788d77de%7C0%7C0%7C638585256415699475%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C0%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=Chcgw%2FXaATMRHhmo1cMh%2FZtWs8RUuVTSZxpc%2BnxTl54%3D&amp;reserved=0" id="x_m_-7131637826883888488m_-1349298423950993725m_8122995676327292520m_3842840075032334920OWA2829cfa7-bb91-4129-37ae-095f55a2c2c4" originalsrc="https://www.news18.com/world/whos-who-in-bangladeshs-new-interim-govt-as-ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-flees-restive-nation-8991218.html" rel="noopener noreferrer" shash="wnly4ASTXmbvEJcxKEoZJHcOdtgENdCIw5ZYZnWLkDW5xH5E2dnZ5VLi8GpkuzRmmyJ2MGgCAhvlFbNTLk+KGcPbJtfA7NvcPv3wo3ySrv5d7/E5p9WCkTrsePWNtUYTyXClU7JydzJhcdMYZxbsAPMHk8iBX7kf+UnrZEOb58s=" target="_blank" title="Original URL: https://www.news18.com/world/whos-who-in-bangladeshs-new-interim-govt-as-ex-pm-sheikh-hasina-flees-restive-nation-8991218.html. Click or tap if you trust this link.">&nbsp;</a>consultation&nbsp;with political parties and stakeholders. However, the fact that the latest such consultations on August 5 included student organisations and members of the JI, the HI, and the BNP but excluded the Awami League is not very reassuring for Delhi. The release of BNP supremo and Hasina's arch-rival Khaleda Zia, within hours of the former's ouster<b>,</b>&nbsp;raises similar concerns on the direction, composition, and intention of a potential interim government.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>A Jolt For Delhi</strong></h2>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasinas-15-year-reign-ends-impact-on-india-bangladesh-ties-6269822">Hasina's resignation is possibly one of the biggest strategic shocks</a> for New Delhi in recent years. Her government's economic and foreign policy fostered a strong bond with India and made it a hub of regional connectivity and integration. With her ouster, all of this is at risk today. This is not to say that it would be entirely impossible for Delhi to find a way to work with a new regime, but any such initiative would be difficult given that it will require building trust and respecting each other's redlines — not an easy task given the history and politics of the two countries.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Until then, any good news from Dhaka will mostly elude Delhi and its neighbours.&nbsp;</p>

<p><em>(The author is Associate Fellow, Neighbourhood Studies, Observer Research Foundation)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/c7jmat0o_bangladesh_625x300_06_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-judge-amit-mehta-the-indian-origin-jurist-who-made-a-landmark-ruling-in-google-antitrust-case-6274946]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Amit Mehta, Indian-American Judge Behind Landmark Google Antitrust Ruling]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/meet-judge-amit-mehta-the-indian-origin-jurist-who-made-a-landmark-ruling-in-google-antitrust-case-6274946]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 06 Aug 2024 14:12:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Amit Mehta, an Indian-origin US judge, has handed Google a legal blow, ruling that the tech giant used exclusive agreements to make itself the "default" search engine and ad provider on devices, giving it a major advantage over its rivals.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amit Mehta, an Indian-origin US judge, has handed Google a legal blow, ruling that the tech giant used exclusive agreements to make itself the “default” search engine and ad provider on devices, giving it a major advantage over its rivals. The trial revealed that Google paid billions to companies like Apple to remain the default search engine on their devices.</p>

<p><strong>Who is District Court Judge Amit Mehta?</strong></p>

<p>1. Born in Patan, Gujarat, Amit Mehta moved to the United States with his parents at the age of one. Mr Mehta earned his BA degree in Political Science and Economics from Georgetown University in 1993 and later graduated with a J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1997.</p>

<p>2. After law school, Mr Mehta worked at the San Francisco office of Latham &amp; Watkins LLP. He also clerked for the Honourable Susan P. Graber of the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit. Mr Mehta joined Zuckerman Spaeder LLP in Washington, DC in 1999, where he worked until 2002. He then joined the District of Columbia Public Defender Service as a staff attorney from 2002 to 2007. In 2007, he returned to Zuckerman Spaeder, focusing on white-collar criminal defence, complex business disputes, and appellate advocacy.</p>

<p>3. During his time at Zuckerman Spaeder, Mr Mehta served on the Board of Directors of the Mid-Atlantic Innocence Project and co-chaired the District of Columbia Bar's Criminal Law and Individual Rights Section Steering Committee. He was also a Director of Facilitating Leadership in Youth, a non-profit organisation dedicated to after-school activities and mentoring for at-risk youth.</p>

<p>4. On December 22, 2014, he was appointed to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, making him a federal judge. He was appointed by former US President Barack Obama.&nbsp;</p>

<p>5. Amit Mehta has represented high-profile clients, including former US Representative Tom Feeney and Dominique Strauss-Kahn, the former president of the IMF. Mr Mehta helped Mr Strauss-Kahn defeat criminal assault charges in a New York court. As a judge, Mr Mehta has made significant rulings, including cases related to the January 6 Capitol riots. He denied former President Donald Trump's attempt to dismiss civil lawsuits holding him accountable for inciting the riot. Mr Mehta wrote that his decision was "consistent with the purposes behind such immunity", despite the gravity of holding a President accountable.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/fgconhto_amit-mehta-_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Judge Amit Mehta was born in Gujarat.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>