<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 18:19:02 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-yahya-sinwar-killed-by-israel-wont-free-hostages-until-6819238]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Confirms Yahya Sinwar Killed By Israel, Won't Free Hostages Until...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-confirms-yahya-sinwar-killed-by-israel-wont-free-hostages-until-6819238]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 18:10:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, architect of the group's cross-border raids in 2023 that became the deadliest day in Israel's history, was killed in combat, Khalil Al-Hayya, deputy Gaza Hamas chief and the group's chief negotiator, said on Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar, architect of the group's cross-border raids in 2023 that became the deadliest day in Israel's history, was killed in combat, Khalil Al-Hayya, deputy Gaza Hamas chief and the group's chief negotiator, said on Friday.</p>

<p>Sinwar's death, which follows Israeli assassinations of other Hamas leaders and commanders, will deal a huge blow to the Islamist group which has faced relentless air strikes since it attacked Israel on Oct. 7, 2023, killing 1,200 people, according to Israeli tallies.</p>

<p>It also dragged about 250 people back to Gaza, creating a hostage crisis for Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government which has vowed to eliminate Hamas.</p>

<p>Sinwar will be remembered as a ruthless enforcer among Palestinians who collaborated with Israel and an implacable enemy of the country which jailed him for many years. Sinwar was named the group's paramount leader on August 6, as a successor to former political chief Ismail Haniyeh, who was assassinated in Tehran on July 31.</p>

<p>Widely known as the architect of the Oct. 7, 2023 attack, the most devastating event for Israel in decades, Sinwar has been in Gaza, defying Israeli attempts to kill him since the start of the war.</p>

<p>Born in a refugee camp in the southern Gaza city of Khan Younis, Sinwar, 62, was elected as Hamas' leader in Gaza in 2017. The controversial leader, who spent half his adult life in Israeli prisons, was the most powerful Hamas leader left alive following the assassination of Haniyeh.</p>

<p><strong>With inputs from Reuters</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/atfa9a5o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was killed in combat]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Wakes Up On Operating Table As Doctors Prepare To Remove His Heart]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/organ-donor-in-us-wakes-up-on-operating-table-as-doctors-prepare-to-remove-his-heart-6819128]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:59:12 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A nightmarish incident unfolded at a US hospital when an organ donor woke up on the operating table just as doctors prepared to remove his heart.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A nightmarish incident unfolded at a US hospital when an organ donor woke up on the operating table just as doctors prepared to remove his heart. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, the incident took place in October 2021 when the organ donor, identified as Thomas T.J. Hoover, was taken to Baptist Health Richmond Hospital in Kentucky due to cardiac arrest following a drug overdose. Doctors declared him braindead and proceeded to conduct tests to see whether his organs were worth harvesting. However, when Mr Hoover was wheeled into the operating room, staff members noticed he was still showing signs of life.</p>

<p>"He was moving around - kind of thrashing. And then when we went over there, you could see he had tears coming down. He was crying visibly," Natasha Miller, a staffer involved in organ preservation, said, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/us-news/hospital-nearly-removes-living-mans-organs-for-donations-witnesses/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The donor's condition shocked several people in the operating room and caused two doctors tasked with the procedures to refuse to participate. But what was more shocking was when the case coordinator for Kentucky Organ Donor Affiliates (KODA) requested new doctors to proceed with the organ retrieval, Ms Miller claimed.</p>

<p>"So the coordinator calls the supervisor at the time. And she was saying that he was telling her that she needed to 'find another doctor to do it' - that 'we were going to do this case. She needs to find someone else'," Ms Miller said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Another KODA worker said that while reviewing Mr Hoover's case she made a jarring discovery. Nyckoletta Martin claimed that she was shocked to find out that the donor had previously shown signs of life as doctors examined his heart to see if it was viable for transplantation. "The donor had woken up during his procedure that morning for a cardiac catheterization. And he was thrashing around on the table," Ms Martin said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to case file records, the doctors merely sedated the struggling Mr Hoover when he started thrashing around and then proceeded with their plans to harvest his organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-travel-influencer-questioning-absence-of-women-on-islamabad-streets-sparks-debate-6818228">Video: Travel Influencer Questioning Absence Of Women On Islamabad Streets Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>Separately, the donor's sister, Donna Rhorer, said her brother opened his eyes while being wheeled from an intensive care unit and into an operating room, but were told that the moment was reflexive and didn't mean he was alive. "It was like it was his way of letting us know, you know, 'Hey I'm still here'," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The procedure was ultimately cancelled. The <em>Post </em>reported that this incident has caused several members of the KODA team to resign their positions. However, KODA officials have denied that any member of the organisation instructed doctors to proceed with an organ-harvesting operation on a living patient.</p>

<p>Kentucky's state attorney general said investigators were reviewing the matter. The Fed's Health Resources and Services Administration is also investigating the allegations.</p>

<p>Mr Hoover is currently living with his sister. He has made a full recovery but he still has some issues with his memory, walking, and talking.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/e5i30qh8_doctor-generic_625x300_17_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The case is being investigated. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-people-left-hanging-upside-down-after-carnival-ride-malfunctions-in-us-6818685]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[People Left Hanging Upside Down After Carnival Ride Malfunctions In US]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-people-left-hanging-upside-down-after-carnival-ride-malfunctions-in-us-6818685]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 17:05:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Visitors at an amusement park in the US were stuck upside down for about 15 minutes after their ride experienced a malfunction, according to the New York Post.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Visitors at an amusement park in the US were stuck upside down for about 15 minutes after their ride experienced a malfunction, according to the <em>New York Post.</em> The incident took place at the Arkansas State Fair on Saturday on the X-Drive, a 16-seater attraction that places riders on the other end of the spinning arm and features rotating seats that flip the riders freely. In a statement, North American Midway Entertainment Services VP Scooter Korek said that the "ride's computer received a fault" because of which it was stuck for about 10-12 minutes. Maintenance staff responded and eventually got the ride to spin, the outlet reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The ride's computer received a fault. What it does is when it finds something that it doesn't like, it shuts it down. So, the ride was in the air, not in its landing position, for about 10-12 minutes," Mr Korek, per the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/18/us-news/arkansas-mom-ally-metzger-left-panicked-as-her-kids-left-dangling-upside-on-state-fair-ride/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>. He also stated that he still trusts the ride's safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Let me break it down to you in a nutshell. Any of my family members can go on any of our rides any day. That's how good I feel about our programs, our safety programs, and the people who work for us to operate and take care of these rides," he said.</p>

<p>However, a mother, whose two children were stuck upside down on the ride, slammed the organisers. Sharing a video on Facebook, Ally Metzger claimed that her kids, 8 and 11, were raised several feet off the ground when the ride stopped working. "They're trying to get my kids down, they've been stuck upside down for 15 minutes at least," she wrote as workers attempted to manually spin the ride to help the stranded passengers.&nbsp;</p>

<p><iframe allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="true" frameborder="0" height="476" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2F61555637497452%2Fvideos%2F1334071007616573%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=267&amp;t=0" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" width="267"></iframe></p>

<p>"There's a bunch of people trying to get the ride to spin, and they would get it almost halfway down. Then it would go right back up to the very top, with my kids still upside down. So, I'm panicking. My partner's panicking," Ms Metzger told a local media outlet.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Metzger's 11-year-old separately said that she doesn't remember much of what happened. "She told me when she came home that she only remembered crying, and then, like, just got dizzy. Her legs were hurting. I guess because the circulation was out," the mother said.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/video-travel-influencer-questioning-absence-of-women-on-islamabad-streets-sparks-debate-6818228">&nbsp;Video: Travel Influencer Questioning Absence Of Women On Islamabad Streets Sparks Debate</a></strong></p>

<p>Following the incident, Ms Metzger railed against the fair, demanding her money back and calling out one of the employees. "After what was spent to get in this place? RUN ME MY REFUND," she wrote on Facebook. "Oh and I filled out a cute complaint," she added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The complaint was aimed at one ride attendant who allegedly told the parents to "calm down its only been four and a half minutes and you're making it worse." "Shout out to the nice lady at the med tent who made sure my babies were ok and gave us our money back. I remember why I don't come here," she added.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8qeb1qk_arkansas-state-fair-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place at the Arkansas State Fair on Saturday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-indian-americans-just-1-of-us-population-are-gaining-political-clout-6818240]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: How Indian Americans - Just 1% Of US Population - Are Gaining Political Clout]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/how-indian-americans-just-1-of-us-population-are-gaining-political-clout-6818240]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:08:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Indian American community is critical for both parties because even though they make up only 1% of the US population, about a third of them reside in Presidential battleground states like Michigan and Georgia.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ev2s0738_us-election_625x300_18_October_24.jpg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>The roughly 2.1 million Indian American voters are just a small section of the 161 million-plus-strong US electorate. Even then, they have emerged as a notable force in the country's politics. With one of their own, Kamala Harris, on the Presidential ballot, the deeply aspirational community is charged up. Having established themselves as an educated and affluent group, they understand that having their voice heard in the corridors of power is crucial. And their importance is growing not just as voters but also as candidates, mobilisers and fundraisers.</p>

<h2><strong>Unprecedented Fundraising</strong></h2>

<p>Political fundraisers are 'witnessing a remarkable surge' in terms of participation from Indian Americans. Ajay Bhutoria, a member of the Democratic National Finance Committee and fundraiser for over two decades, says, "More than ever, people are stepping up, contributing larger sums, and actively engaging in the political process."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The $145,000 median income of Indian American households is 21% higher than the overall US median. Shekar Narasimhan, founder and chairman of the AAPI Victory Fund, the largest Super PAC (political action committee) in the Asian American diaspora, says that even though it is not easy to find accurate data on how much finance Indian Americans are pumping into campaigns, there are huge donors in the community. This is evident from the fact that the Democratic National Finance Committee is 5% Indian-American even as their share in the US population is only 1%. At the same time, small-dollar donors are important too, adds Narasimhan.</p>

<p>M.R. Rangaswami, Indiaspora's Founder &amp; Chairman, also notes the remarkable volume of funds being generated. "Now we have two healthy PACs with the AAPI Victory Fund and the Indian American Impact Fund, so more and more money is coming in," he says. The Indian American Impact, the largest desi PAC, is also identifying and training the next batch of leaders.</p>

<p>Dr Sangay Mishra, associate professor of Political Science at Drew University and author of <em>Desis Divided: The Political Lives of South Asian Americans</em>, found in his research that since 2012, Indian Americans have been "very visible" in "bundling" contributions for campaigns. "We have seen that kind of outsized influence because of the number of very wealthy fundraisers organised in the community networks," he says.</p>

<p>It's a popular saying that the road to the White House goes through Silicon Valley - the hub of affluent Indians in tech. Harris's recent California fundraisers generated $55 million over a weekend; she has raised a billion dollars since becoming the nominee. Powerful fundraisers, including the one hosted by the billionaire AI investor and technologist Vinod Khosla for the Democratic campaign this election cycle, made news waves. There are more than 60 Indian names on the list of VCs for Kamala. Other business leaders and founders endorsing her include corporate leaders like Indra Nooyi.</p>

<h2><strong>The Enduring Republican Vote</strong></h2>

<p>While Harris's candidacy has further loosened the purse strings of enthused Democrats, Donald Trump's Indian American supporters, including Vivek Ramaswamy, have stayed loyal to the Republican Party.</p>

<p>Sampat Shivangi, an old-time Republican faithful and the only Indian American delegate at the Republican National Convention this year, has been elected to the body for the sixth time. He is sending a big cheque for Trump's campaign. Then there is hotelier Danny Gaekwad, who has contributed to the campaigns of every Republican Presidential candidate since George Bush. "The October event involved an insane amount of money. People known to me are calling me - Bhau, I want to go, my wife wants to go," Gaekwad says about a sold-out fundraiser.</p>

<p>Republicans like Shivangi say they support Trump because "Harris is not a friend of India". Along with accusations of "diluting" her Indian American identity, they point out that she failed to visit India during her years as Vice-President.</p>

<p>Republicans, however, do acknowledge that the fervour among Indian American supporters of the party, especially Hindus, has waned since 2020, when President Trump and Prime Minister Narendra Modi's friendly ties created a huge buzz. "{Perhaps because] he is a third-time candidate," Gaekwad reasons.</p>

<p>Though wooed by both parties, by and large, Indian Americans have voted for Democrats. A 2024 AAPI Data survey found that 55% of Indian Americans identify as Democrats, 25% as Republicans and 15% as Independents.</p>

<h2><strong>Sway In Swing States</strong></h2>

<p>The Indian American community is critical for both parties because even though they make up only 1% of the US population, about a third of them reside in Presidential battleground states like Michigan and Georgia, where they can play a huge role in shaping the results. Recalling the narrow Democratic victory in Georgia in 2020, Mishra says, "In a state like that, it matters because the margin was so thin. Indian Americans voted one way and the election went that way, if they had voted the other way results might have been different." The last few Presidential elections have been close calls, decided by narrow gaps in a handful of states. Polls show that the current one seems evenly poised. There are nearly 4,00,000 voters of South Asian descent in the 10 most contested swing states. "There is a sizeable number of Indian Americans who can make a difference," says Dr Mishra.</p>

<p>Thus, volunteers of the highly politically engaged community utilise their resources strategically in pivotal states. Based in the Democratic stronghold California, Sangeeta Ramakrishnan is They See Blue's 'lead' for swing state calls. She says, "There are more of us in blue states and because you don't need to knock those many doors here, it's better to use our resources effectively."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Every election, Pennsylvania's Buck's County gains the reputation of being the "swingiest county in the swingiest state". Rupa Mohan, a volunteer at They See Blue, says, "We have phone banks run by Gujarati volunteers, Malayalam speakers, Urdu speakers. We have a whole pile of different volunteers lined up."</p>

<p>Overall as well, the political participation of the 4.8 million-strong young immigrant community is soaring. In the last two presidential elections, they had the highest voter turnout among Asian Americans, on par with white voter turnout. As many as 71% of eligible Indian Americans voted in 2020, a 9-point increase from 2016. This trend is expected to continue. A recent Asian American voter survey shows that around 91% of Indian Americans plan to vote in this election.</p>

<h2><strong>Office Dreams</strong></h2>

<p>It's not only electoral numbers that elevate the Indian Americans' political profile - they also nurture strong ambitions for office. From the highest level - the Presidential post - to Congress, state senates, assemblies, district attorneys, city councils, to school boards, their numbers are huge.&nbsp;</p>

<p>No one really has a count of how many Indian American candidates are in the 2024 race. But there are five Indian Americans in the current US Congress, and, after the coming election, says Narasimhan, the community will likely have seven. Getting to that number took decades since the first Indian American was voted to the Congress in 1956. But the rise in the last 20 years has been exponential, thanks to second-generation Indian Americans and their education levels, which are far higher than the US average.</p>

<p>As for their numbers in administration, while Indian Americans constitute just 0.6% of the adult citizen population in the US, they hold about 4.4% of senior positions in government. There are over 150 Indian Americans in the Biden-Harris administration, and that is projected to increase by over 50 if Harris becomes President.</p>

<h2><strong>The Pursuit Of Influence</strong></h2>

<p>Having conquered every metric on the ladder of ascent - votes, money and candidates - Indian American leaders are aspiring for political representation similar to what the much older Jewish American population enjoys. Jews constitute about 2% of the American population but make up 10% of the US Congress. "In force, we have been here for about 30 years," says Rangaswami. "We are 7% of US physicians, 10% of the American IT sector and are well-represented in academia and government, so why not have clout."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Already, with early voting having begun, supporters of both parties are canvassing aggressively through door-to-door promotions, postcards, phone calls, and texts. "It's going to heat up in the next few weeks!" says Shobha Chokkalingam, Atlanta-based leader of the Georgia chapter of the American Hindu Coalition. But it's 'desi' Democratic supporters for whom this election is particularly special. With Kamala Harris in the race, the Indian American community is eager to play a part in making history. Rangaswami sums it up well: "If Kamala Harris becomes president - I mean keep in mind there's been no Jewish president in the US - this could be a huge thing. So let's see!"</p>

<p><em>(Savita Patel is a San Francisco Bay Area-based journalist and producer. She reports on the Indian diaspora, India-US ties, geopolitics, technology, public health, and the environment. She tweets at @SsavitaPatel.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/qemb10ng_us-election_625x300_18_October_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-silent-on-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-death-says-group-cant-be-eliminated-6818211]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Hamas Silent On Its Chief's Death, Says "Group Can't Be Eliminated"]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/hamas-silent-on-its-chief-yahya-sinwars-death-says-group-cant-be-eliminated-6818211]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 16:02:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A senior Hamas official said the Palestinian militant group cannot be eliminated with the killing of its leaders, but stopped short of confirming the death of its chief, Yahya Sinwar.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A senior Hamas official said the Palestinian group cannot be eliminated with the killing of its leaders, but stopped short of confirming the death of its chief, Yahya Sinwar.</p>

<p>"Hamas is a liberation movement led by people looking for freedom and dignity, and this cannot be eliminated," Basem Naim, senior member of Hamas's political bureau, told AFP.</p>

<p>In a statement, he listed several Hamas leaders killed in the past, and said their deaths had boosted the group's popularity.</p>

<p>"It seems that Israel believes that killing our leaders means the end of our movement and the struggle of the Palestinian people," Naim said.</p>

<p>"Hamas each time became stronger and more popular, and these leaders became an icon for future generations to continue the journey towards a free Palestine."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnlapn8o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["Hamas is a liberation movement led by people looking for freedom," said the official (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarming-rise-in-ai-produced-child-abuse-material-warns-regulatory-body-6817927]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Alarming Rise In AI-Produced Child Abuse Material, Warns Regulatory Body]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/alarming-rise-in-ai-produced-child-abuse-material-warns-regulatory-body-6817927]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 15:22:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[AI is being used to create highly realistic child sexual abuse content that is increasingly accessible online.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The negative impacts of artificial intelligence, which have already led to the proliferation of fake and deepfake videos of celebrities online, are now extending to children. AI-generated child sexual abuse content is increasingly being found on publicly accessible areas of the internet.</p>

<p>According to a <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iwf.org.uk/news-media/news/public-exposure-to-chilling-ai-child-sexual-abuse-images-and-videos-increases/">report by the Internet Watch Foundation</a> (IWF), AI-generated child sexual abuse content is exposing even more people to the harmful and horrific imagery.</p>

<p>Many of the images and videos of children being hurt and abused are so realistic that they can be very difficult to tell apart from imagery of real children and are regarded as criminal content in the eyes of UK law, much in the same way as 'traditional' child sexual abuse material would be, as per the IWF.</p>

<p>In the past six months alone, analysts at the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.iwf.org.uk/news-media/news/public-exposure-to-chilling-ai-child-sexual-abuse-images-and-videos-increases/">IWF </a>have seen a 6% increase in confirmed reports containing AI-generated child sexual abuse material, compared with the preceding 12 months.</p>

<p>The IWF is warning that almost all the content (99%) was found on publicly available areas of the internet and was not hidden on the dark web. Most of the reports have come from members of the public (78%) who have stumbled across the criminal imagery on sites such as forums or AI galleries. The remainder were actioned by IWF analysts through proactive searching.</p>

<p>Analysts say that viewing AI-generated content of children being sexually abused can be as distressing as seeing real children in abuse imagery if a person is not prepared or trained to cope with seeing such material.</p>

<p>Some AI child sexual abuse material is classified as non-photographic imagery, such as cartoons, and is also regarded as harmful to view and accordingly assessed by IWF analysts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/q5am60i_aiproduced-child-abuse-material_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This poses a significant threat to children's safety and well-being.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baby-dies-65-rescued-after-migrant-boat-sinks-off-france-6817653]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Baby Dies, 65 Rescued After Migrant Boat Sinks Off France]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/baby-dies-65-rescued-after-migrant-boat-sinks-off-france-6817653]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:45:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A baby died when an overloaded migrant boat headed for Britain sank in the Channel off the coast of France on Thursday night, French maritime authorities said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A baby died when an overloaded migrant boat headed for Britain sank in the Channel off the coast of France on Thursday night, French maritime authorities said Friday.</p>

<p>The accident occurred off the French town of Wissant, the maritime authority in charge of the Channel and the North Sea told AFP, adding that 65 people were rescued but a "baby was found unconscious and sadly declared dead".</p>

<p>The latest sinking brings the number of migrants who perished while trying to cross the Channel this year to at least 52 -- a record since 2018.</p>

<p>On September 3, six children and an equal number of adults died. A month later, a two-year-old boy and three adults died after overloaded boats got into trouble during the dangerous crossing.</p>

<p>The number of migrants arriving in boats to Britain averaged 53 this year as opposed to 13 in 2020, according to official British figures.</p>

<p>Over 26,000 migrants have landed on British shores since January 1, according to UK Home Office figures.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/jlr0uak_brazil-court-blocks-couples-chosen-baby-name_625x300_14_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/virtual-reality-could-hold-the-key-to-beating-cocaine-addiction-uk-study-finds-6817651]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Virtual Reality Could Hold Key To Beating Cocaine Addiction, UK Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/virtual-reality-could-hold-the-key-to-beating-cocaine-addiction-uk-study-finds-6817651]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:44:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A UK-based trial is using virtual reality technology to combat cocaine addiction by placing users in real-life scenarios to better manage cravings.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Across the world, millions of people are impacted by the cocaine addiction epidemic. It fuels serious health problems, criminal activity, and social unrest. Nonetheless, resolving this widespread issue calls for concerted global action as well as ongoing assistance for individuals impacted.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/oct/18/virtual-reality-cocaine-addiction-uk-drug-overdoses"><em>The Guardian report,</em></a> researchers are building a virtual reality world to help people overcome their cocaine addiction by repeatedly exposing them to tempting scenarios in a safe environment.</p>

<p>In order to treat cocaine users, Paolo Deluca of King's College London is leading a virtual reality initiative that immerses users in situations that are realistic and likely to stimulate cravings, such as being alone or at a party. By disentangling drug-use triggers from cocaine addiction, the "cue exposure treatment" approach, which has been shown to be beneficial in lowering alcohol cravings, enables users to rehearse refusal techniques in a safe setting.</p>

<p>"We are trying to better understand the scenarios-the cues and interactions-that trigger cravings in people who use cocaine," he told<em> The Guardian.</em></p>

<p>The work is one of 11 projects announced on Friday as part of a 12 million Pounds (Rs 122 crore) government investment to reduce drug overdoses through virtual reality, artificial intelligence, and wearable technology.</p>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/06/1151446">UN reports</a>, in the decade to 2022, the number of people using illicit drugs increased to 292 million, the UNODC report says.</p>

<p>It noted that most users worldwide consume cannabis-228 million people-while 60 million people worldwide consume opioids, 30 million people use amphetamines, 23 million use cocaine, and 20 million take ecstasy.</p>

<p>Further, UNODC found that there was an increase in overdose deaths following the emergence of nitazenes-a group of synthetic opioids potentially more dangerous than fentanyl-in several high-income countries.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/la948uo_cocaine_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The initiative aims to reduce drug overdoses through VR and AI.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-hamas-israel-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-was-released-by-israel-in-2011-prisoner-swap-deal-6817591]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[13 Years Ago, Hamas Chief Yahya Sinwar Was Released By Israel In Swap Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/yahya-sinwar-hamas-israel-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-was-released-by-israel-in-2011-prisoner-swap-deal-6817591]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:34:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar, the leader of Hamas in Gaza, was released by Israel in 2011 as part of a major prisoner swap deal that involved the release of 1,027 Palestinian and Israeli Arab prisoners in exchange for a single Israeli soldier, Gilad Shalit.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/topic/yahya-sinwar">Yahya Sinwar</a>, the leader of Hamas in Gaza, was released by Israel in 2011 as part of a major prisoner swap deal that involved the release of 1,027 Palestinian and Israeli Arab prisoners in exchange for a single Israeli soldier, Gilad Shalit. Shalit, a soldier in the Israel Defense Forces (IDF), had been held captive by Hamas for five years after being kidnapped in 2006 in a raid that involved Sinwar's brother, a senior Hamas military commander.</p>

<p>Sinwar had spent over 22 years in Israeli prisons from 1988 to 2011, a period that reportedly hardened his radical views. According to experts, his time in solitary confinement and his interactions with other prisoners further solidified his leadership within Hamas.</p>

<p>Israeli authorities described him as "cruel, authoritative, influential," with significant endurance, manipulative tendencies, and the ability to rally crowds. Sinwar's ability to maintain authority inside prison, including negotiating with prison authorities and enforcing discipline among inmates, helped solidify his position as a key Hamas leader.</p>

<p><strong>WATCH </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drone-footage-of-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwars-last-moments-released-by-israel-6815660#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">Drone Footage Of Hamas Chief Yahya Sinwar's Last Moments Released By Israel</a></p>

<p>Following his release, Sinwar called for more kidnappings of Israeli soldiers. His time in prison had not softened his stance; instead, it appeared to have intensified his commitment to Hamas's goals.</p>

<p>After returning to Gaza following the 2011 swap, Sinwar's prominence grew, largely due to his status as a founding member of Hamas and his long imprisonment, which elevated his prestige. His leadership was also bolstered by fear, as Sinwar had a reputation for violence, reportedly earning the nickname "The Butcher of Khan Younis." He was believed to be responsible for the detention, torture, and murder of a Hamas commander in 2015, accused of embezzlement and homosexuality.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>| <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/how-israeli-military-tracked-and-killed-hamas-chief-yahya-sinwar-in-gaza-6814828#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll">How Israeli Military Tracked And Killed Hamas Chief Yahya Sinwar In Gaza</a></p>

<p>In 2017, Sinwar became the head of Hamas's Political Bureau in the Gaza Strip. His younger brother, Mohammed Sinwar, also played a major role in Hamas's military activities and was believed to have survived multiple Israeli assassination attempts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/0as4rdso_yahya-sinwar_625x300_17_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Following his release, Sinwar called for more kidnappings of Israeli soldiers.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-siberia-to-the-sahara-huskies-conquer-mauritania-6817470]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Siberia To The Sahara: Huskies Conquer Mauritania]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-siberia-to-the-sahara-huskies-conquer-mauritania-6817470]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:18:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[While the sweltering heat is not ideal for the Arctic breed, huskies have a great capacity to adapt, said Hela Rokbani of France's Animal Protection Society (SPA).]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As dusk fell on the edge of Nouakchott, Kayo the husky left a trail of paw prints in the warm Sahara sand, an incongruous yet increasingly familiar sight in Mauritania.</p>

<p>Traditionally bred as sled dogs in the far north of Siberia, huskies have become a popular pet in the northwest African state -- where temperatures regularly soar to 40 degrees Celsius (104 degrees Fahrenheit).</p>

<p>"I thought he might have problems with the heat, but that's not the case," said Kayo's owner Ahmed Maham, admiring his majestic pet.</p>

<p>While the sweltering heat is not ideal for the Arctic breed, huskies have a great capacity to adapt, said Hela Rokbani of France's Animal Protection Society (SPA).</p>

<p>The dogs have two layers of fur which act as a thermal regulator, protecting them from the cold as well as the heat, she explained.</p>

<p>They renew their coats twice a year and automatically adapt their fur to the climate, she added.</p>

<p>"A husky in Siberia will therefore moult differently in Africa," she explained, while stressing Mauritania was not their natural habitat.</p>

<p>"You have to remain vigilant and take precautions: give them fresh water, take them out at certain times of the day, shelter them in the shade...", Rokbani said.</p>

<p><strong>Like wolves</strong></p>

<p>On his sun-drenched roof terrace in Nouakchott, husky owner Amadou Daff filled a bowl with water to cool his pet.</p>

<p>Like many other owners around the world, Daff's affection for the hardy dog breed began with the hit TV series Game of Thrones.</p>

<p>"That's what I loved about huskies, because they look like wolves," he said.</p>

<p>"I wanted an all-white one like Arya's" he added, referencing one of the main characters in the fantasy series.</p>

<p>"You have to take a lot of care and keep them in the right conditions" he said, explaining the importance of hydration and making kennel roofs out of wood rather than metal to keep out the heat.</p>

<p>"You really have to look after huskies. They're not just for anyone," he added.</p>

<p>Amadou Mbodj, a dog trainer specialised in selling and training huskies, proudly showed off his canine companion.</p>

<p>"Her name is Gloria -- she's the first husky I ever had. She's been here nearly seven years," he said.</p>

<p>"I got her from a Syrian friend, and I haven't been able to part with her since," he added.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/j8cb4tr_husky-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg?im=FaceCrop,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p><strong>Sign of wealth</strong></p>

<p>Mbodj imports the dogs from Morocco, which he explained required "a lot of paperwork", permits and a vaccination certificate.</p>

<p>"It's a long way and there are hassles at customs", he said, "but it can be done".</p>

<p>Mbodj warned that thefts of huskies were on the rise.</p>

<p>Mauritania has not traditionally been a dog-friendly country, but Mbodj said that trends were changing and adoptions were on the rise.</p>

<p>He sells his huskies for the equivalent of between $380 and $760.</p>

<p>"I used to go for walks on the beach and in upmarket areas, and people would ask me about these dogs," Mbodj said.</p>

<p>"Mauritanians love huskies because of their beauty, their sociability and their extraordinary coat," he added.</p>

<p>Mouhamadou Ba, a canine specialist and secretary general of Mauritania's veterinary association, said the number of huskies had increased over the last 10 years.</p>

<p>But there are no reliable official statistics.</p>

<p>Ba described having a pedigree dog as a social marker and a sign of wealth in the desert state.</p>

<p>Breeds such as German shepherds, poodles and Chihuahuas have also become more popular, he said, particularly among wealthier Mauritanians who travel abroad.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/b6re7sig_husky_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Huskies have two layers of fur which act as a thermal regulator.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-2nd-visit-to-russia-this-year-to-attend-brics-summit-next-week-6817358]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[PM Modi's  2nd Visit To Russia This Year, To Attend BRICS Summit Next Week]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-narendra-modis-2nd-visit-to-russia-this-year-to-attend-brics-summit-next-week-6817358]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 13:59:26 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Russia at the invitation of Russian President Vladimir Putin from October 22-23 to attend the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi will visit Russia at the invitation of Russian President Vladimir Putin from October 22-23 to attend the 16th BRICS Summit in Kazan.</p>

<p>The BRICS Summit in Kazan is being held under the chairmanship of Russia, according to the Ministry of External Affairs (MEA). During his visit, PM Modi is also expected to hold bilateral meetings with his counterparts from BRICS member countries and invited leaders in Kazan.</p>

<p>The MEA said, "The Summit, themed "Strengthening Multilateralism for Just Global Development and Security," will provide an important platform for leaders to discuss key global issues.:"</p>

<p>It further said, "The Summit will offer a valuable opportunity to assess the progress of initiatives launched by BRICS and to identify potential areas for future collaboration."</p>

<p>The leaders of BRIC (Brazil, Russia, India, and China) countries met for the first time in St Petersburg in Russia in 2006. After a series of high-level meetings, the first BRIC summit was held in Russia's Yekaterinburg in 2009.</p>

<p>BRIC group was renamed as BRICS (Brazil, Russia, India, China, South Africa) after South Africa was accepted as a full member at the BRIC Foreign Ministers' meeting in New York in September 2010.</p>

<p>BRICS is an important grouping bringing together the major emerging economies from the world, comprising 41 per cent of the world population, having 24 per cent of the world GDP and over 16 per cent share in the world trade.</p>

<p>Earlier in September, Russian President Vladimir Putin extended an invitation to PM Modi, proposing a bilateral meeting on October 22, on the sidelines of the BRICS Summit in Kazan. During the invitation, Putin also referred to PM Modi as a "good friend."</p>

<p>The remarks by Putin came while he met National Security Advisor Ajit Doval on the sidelines of the BRICS National Security Advisers' meeting. Putin had a meeting with Doval at the Constantine Palace in Russia's St. Petersberg.</p>

<p>Quoting President Putin, the Kremlin in a statement said, "We will be expecting Mr Modi in Kazan. I also suggest holding a bilateral meeting there on October 22 in order to close the books on our joint work in implementing the agreements reached during his visit to Moscow and outline some prospects for the near future."</p>

<p>"Please extend my warmest regards and best wishes to Mr Modi, my good friend," the statement added.</p>

<p>It will be PM Narendra Modi's second visit to Russia in 2024 as he travelled to Moscow in July to attend the 22nd India-Russia Annual Summit. During his visit to Russia, PM Modi held a bilateral meeting with Russian President Putin.</p>

<p>PM Modi was also conferred with Russia's highest civilian award, the Order of St. Andrew the Apostle at the Kremlin in Moscow. The two leaders visited the Rosatom Pavilion at the VDNKh Exhibition Centre in Moscow.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2ie9ca7g_pm-modi-putin_625x300_18_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[This will be PM Narendra Modi's second visit to Russia in 2024. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-studying-in-prison-to-heading-hamas-oct-7-attack-who-was-yahya-sinwar-6817331]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[From Studying In Prison To Heading Hamas Oct 7 Attack: Who Was Yahya Sinwar]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/from-studying-in-prison-to-heading-hamas-oct-7-attack-who-was-yahya-sinwar-6817331]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 13:53:31 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) and the Israel Security Agency have jointly confirmed that Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was killed in the Gaza Strip by Israeli soldiers on Wednesday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Israel Defense Forces (IDF) and the Israel Security Agency have jointly confirmed that Hamas leader Yahya Sinwar was killed in the Gaza Strip by Israeli soldiers on Wednesday. No official confirmation has been made by Hamas.</p>

<p>Sinwar was born in October 1962 in the Khan Younis refugee camp in the southern Gaza Strip. He studied in Khan Younis schools before being enrolled in the Islamic University of Gaza, where he graduated with a bachelor's degree in Arabic studies. In 2011, he married a woman from the Gaza Strip, and they have three children, Xinhua news agency reported.</p>

<p>He was first arrested in 1982 at the age of 20 due to his involvement in subversive activities and subsequently placed under administrative detention for four months. Following his release, he was re-arrested just one week later and spent six months in prison without trial. In 1985, he faced another arrest and was sentenced to eight months in prison.</p>

<p>In 1988, he was arrested again and tried on charges related to leading the kidnapping and murder of two Israeli soldiers, as well as the killing of four Palestinians suspected of collaborating with Israel. He was sentenced to four life sentences.</p>

<p>During his imprisonment, Sinwar led the Supreme Leadership Committee of Hamas prisoners in Israeli jails, helping to manage confrontations with prison authorities during a series of hunger strikes. He was transferred between several prisons.</p>

<p>He attempted to escape from prison twice, but both attempts were unsuccessful.</p>

<p>Sinwar used his time in prison for reading and writing, learning Hebrew and writing several books and translations in political, security, and literary fields.</p>

<p>He was released in 2011 as part of a prisoner exchange for an Israeli soldier.</p>

<p>After his release, Sinwar was elected to Hamas's political bureau during the movement's internal elections in 2012, where he took charge of security matters. In 2013, he assumed leadership of Hamas's military wing, the al-Qassam Brigades, coordinating efforts between the political bureau and the brigades' leadership.</p>

<p>He was elected in 2017 as the head of the movement's political bureau in Gaza, and in 2021, he was re-elected for a second four-year term during the movement's internal elections.</p>

<p>Sinwar's house has been bombed multiple times, and he is described as a cautious figure who rarely speaks publicly.</p>

<p>Sinwar was considered the chief architect of the Hamas attack against Israel on October 7, 2023.</p>

<p>In August, Hamas announced that Sinwar was appointed as its leader following the assassination of former leader Ismail Haniyeh in Tehran.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dnlapn8o_yahya-sinwar_625x300_07_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Yahya Sinwar was considered the chief architect of the Hamas attack against Israel on October 7, 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-house-of-mirrors-where-ex-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-jailed-her-dissidents-6816762]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Inside 'House of Mirrors': Sheikh Hasina's Secret Jail]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/inside-house-of-mirrors-where-ex-bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-jailed-her-dissidents-6816762]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 13:29:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Months after a student-led protest in Bangladesh snowballed into a full-blown anti-government movement and led to Sheikh Hasina's ouster, horrifying details have emerged about the secret prisons where the former Prime Minister's dissidents were held.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Months after a student-led protest in Bangladesh snowballed into a full-blown anti-government movement and led to Sheikh Hasina's ouster, horrifying details have emerged about the secret prisons where the former Prime Minister's dissidents were held. The victims of forced disappearances have since come forward and spoken about what went on inside these jails, called 'Aynaghor', literally translated as the "House of Mirrors."</p>

<p>As Bangladesh and its 170-million-strong population prepare for a new future under an interim government, among them are also those who once thought they would never be a part of the free world again.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-court-orders-arrest-warrant-for-ex-prime-minister-sheikh-hasina-6809213">Bangladesh Court Orders Arrest Warrant For Ex-Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina</a></p>

<p>During Hasina's regime, which began in 2009, hundreds of people were allegedly picked up by the security forces, sometimes for even the smallest of demonstrations against the state. While many were reportedly killed and their bodies discarded, some were put in secret military detention centre -- code-named the 'House of Mirrors', The New York Times reported.</p>

<h2><strong>What was 'Aynaghor'?</strong></h2>

<p>Ms Hasina is believed to have marshalled the state machinery to take on anyone challenging her hold on power. A part of this effort's "deepest recesses" was the enforced disappearances programme, the NYT reported.</p>

<p>Human rights organisations estimate over 700 people have been victims of forced disappearances since 2009. They say the actual figure is expected to be much higher.</p>

<p>In some cases, dissidents were even targeted for organising an rally or blocking roads to mark a protest, or even posting a message to express dissent on social media.</p>

<p><b>Read |&nbsp;</b><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sheikh-hasinas-partys-student-leader-beaten-to-death-on-campus-6604862">Sheikh Hasina's Party's Student Leader Beaten To Death On Campus</a></p>

<p>Under the House of Mirrors, there were several secret long-term detentions entrusted to the Bangladesh military's intelligence wing. Many of these detainees, who were taken to an underground prison, have claimed hearing morning military parades above them.</p>

<p>Maroof Zaman, a former Bangladesh ambassador to Qatar and Vietnam, spent a total of 467 days in prison before re-emerging in 2019. Zaman was able to pinpoint the military garrison in Dhaka on Google Maps, which has now been marked as Aynaghor - Bengali for House of Mirrors.</p>

<h2><strong>What happened Inside</strong></h2>

<p>Run by army intelligence, the 'House of Mirrors' was given this name because the detainees were never supposed to see any other person apart from themselves.</p>

<p>This tightly run centre offered a life barely worth living. Here, people faced direct physical torture during interrogations. Health checkups were regular and thorough. Every four to six months, inmates were given haircuts.</p>

<p>The goal behind this was to torture the mind, The New York Times stated.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-amends-law-scrapping-special-security-for-sheikh-hasina-family-6447607">Bangladesh Amends Law Scrapping Special Security For Sheikh Hasina, Family</a></p>

<p>Bangladeshi barrister Ahmad Bin Quasem, who was detained in 2016, was blindfolded, handcuffed, and bundled out of the secret prison after eight years. "That's the first time I got fresh air in eight years. I thought they were going to kill me," he told AFP earlier this year.</p>

<p>Inside the prison, Quasem was shackled around the clock in a windowless solitary confinement. Further, the jailers were strictly instructed not to relay news from the outside world. Also, he was made to wear metal handcuffs nearly all the time.</p>

<p>When asked to sketch the facility, some of the former detainees stated that it had long corridors with half a dozen rooms that were facing away from each other. The detention centre had toilets at each end, both standing and a squatting one. Each of the cells here had large exhaust fans meant to drown out the guards' chatter as well as send the prisoners into madness.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/rgalb7k_bangladesh-enforced-disappearances-getty_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-tells-north-korean-soldiers-south-korea-is-hostile-foreign-country-6816836]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Tells North Korean Soldiers South Korea Is 'Hostile, Foreign' Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kim-tells-north-korean-soldiers-south-korea-is-hostile-foreign-country-6816836]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 12:44:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un told North Korean soldiers that the South was a "foreign" country, state media reported Friday, saying Pyongyang had jettisoned any idea of reunification.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kim Jong Un told North Korean soldiers that the South was a "foreign" country, state media reported Friday, saying Pyongyang had jettisoned any idea of reunification.</p>

<p>Despite remaining officially at war, the two Koreas have long defined ties as a "special relationship", not state-to-state relations, with a view to eventual reunification.</p>

<p>But Kim in January defined Seoul as his country's "principal enemy", and on Friday described ties with the South as an "evil relationship" that had ended with the detonation of roads between the two.</p>

<p>After months of laying fresh mines and ramping up security on the border, Pyongyang this week blew up roads and railways linking it to the South, and said its constitution now defined the South as a "hostile" state.</p>

<p><strong>READ</strong> |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/north-koreas-constitution-changed-it-now-calls-south-korea-hostile-state-6807525">North Korea's Constitution Changed, It Now Calls South Korea 'Hostile State'</a></p>

<p>"Our army should keep in mind once again the stark fact that (South Korea) is a foreign country and an apparent hostile country," Kim told the 2nd Corps of the Korean People's Army, state media said.</p>

<p>Dynamiting roads and railways this week means "the end of the evil relationship with Seoul," Kim said, plus "the complete removal of the... unreasonable idea of reunification".</p>

<p>The North's army will strike back if needed "against the hostile country, not the fellow countrymen," he added, the official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) reported.</p>

<p>The North last week held a key meeting of its rubber-stamp parliament, where experts had widely expected the constitution to be revised.</p>

<p>On Thursday, Kim also examined "important documents" outlining the North's "military action plans for coping with different developments of the situation," KCNA said.</p>

<p>Pyongyang's official newspaper Rodong Sinmun published photographs of Kim issuing orders in front of a large, blurred map, while high-ranking officials diligently took notes.</p>

<p>The current armistice agreement, which ended active fighting in the 1950 to 1953 Korean War is akin to "a truce between the two systems that assert claims over the entire Korean Peninsula," said Hong Min, a senior analyst at the Korea Institute for National Unification.</p>

<p><strong>READ </strong>|&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/why-is-kim-jong-uns-north-korea-blowing-up-roads-railways-to-the-south-6802312">Why Is North Korea Blowing Up Roads, Railways To The South?</a></p>

<p>But "this system may lose its relevance" as North Korea might change the way it thinks about its borders, he told AFP.</p>

<p>"Such a shift would represent a transition from a temporary military demarcation line under ceasefire to a formal border system between nations," he added.</p>

<p><strong>Copyright dispute?</strong></p>

<p>South Korea's military released video footage on Tuesday of North Korean soldiers dynamiting the roads and railways, and Seoul later said Pyongyang appeared to have used the footage in state media.</p>

<p>Kim Yo Jong, the North Korean leader's powerful sister and a key regime spokesperson, said that the image in question was "a screenshot from one of the video clips released by NBC, Fox News, Reuters and other foreign media."</p>

<p>All Seoul-based foreign media received the footage from the South Korean military.</p>

<p>Citing an investigation, Kim Yo Jong then accused South Korean media outlets, including the official Yonhap News Agency, of using images from Pyongyang's state media without authorisation.</p>

<p>She said in a statement carried by KCNA that the North would investigate.</p>

<p>Seoul's unification ministry said Friday that all South Korean "media companies legally use materials from the Korean Central News Agency by paying royalties through Japanese intermediaries", deputy spokesperson Kim In-ae told a briefing.</p>

<p>"We make it clear that it is North Korea that is unlawfully using our materials," Kim said. "As a member of the Berne Convention, North Korea should demonstrate a responsible attitude," she added, referring to the agreement designed to protect copyrighted works from infringement among member countries.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/qnmnpi2o_kim-jong-un-afp-_625x300_16_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kim described ties with the South as an "evil relationship".]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-death-emergency-call-by-hotel-manager-reveals-he-was-high-on-drugs-and-alcohol-before-he-died-6816305]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Moments Before Liam Payne Died, A Frantic Call, Request For Help]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-death-emergency-call-by-hotel-manager-reveals-he-was-high-on-drugs-and-alcohol-before-he-died-6816305]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 12:26:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[British pop star Liam Payne fell to death yesterday from the third-floor hotel balcony, sending shockwaves across the entertainment world.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British pop star <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/one-direction-singer-liam-payne-dead-after-fall-from-balcony-in-argentina-6806821">Liam Payne</a> fell to death yesterday from the third-floor hotel balcony, sending shockwaves across the entertainment world. Moments earlier, a manager at the hotel made a frantic call to the emergency helpline and informed them about an unruly guest.</p>

<p>The call detailed the frightening moments before the former member of the famous boy band One Direction fell from the balcony of Hotel CasaSur Palermo in Argentina's Buenos Aires.</p>

<p>During the call, the manager claimed the singer was out of control and "putting his life at risk", and sought "urgent" assistance.</p>

<p>In the audio obtained by The Sun UK, the manager named Esteban is heard claiming that the singer was destroying his hotel room under the influence of "drugs and alcohol". "We have a guest drunk with drugs and alcohol. When he is conscious, he is breaking everything in the room," the manager said.</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/liam-payne-death-news-details-surrounding-death-of-one-direction-star-liam-payne-6813718">Details Surrounding Death Of One Direction Star Liam Payne</a></p>

<p>According to the report, the head of reception made two phone calls to the authorities. When he made the second call, he repeated his request and stated, "We need you to send someone urgently because I don't know if the guest's life is in danger."</p>

<p>The manager noted the guests were in a room with a balcony. "And well, we're a little bit worried he'll do something, that he'll put his life at risk," he added.</p>

<p>Asked how long the guest had been staying at the hotel and whether it was a long-stay hotel, the person stated, "He's been there for two or three days".</p>

<p><strong>Read |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/smashed-hotel-room-drugs-found-as-liam-payne-death-probe-unfolds-6814720">Smashed Hotel Room, Drugs Found As Liam Payne Death Probe Unfolds</a></p>

<p>According to the New York Post, "resources" were sent to the hotel at 5:04 PM (local time), while emergency medical services were requested only after the police were notified of the fall at around 5:07 PM. Payne was "behaving erratically" and even was carried back to his room before his death, eyewitnesses said.</p>

<p>Liam Payne died on the spot and the authorities stated that "there was no possibility of resuscitating him." Soon after, his body was put into the ambulance and driven away with a police escort.</p>

<p>Prosecutors had earlier said an initial inquiry suggested the fall came after substance abuse. His autopsy revealed 25 injuries including fatal head injuries, prosecutors said, adding that there was no sign of a third party being involved.</p>

<p>Payne is survived by his parents, son Bear Grey Payne with his former girlfriend Cheryl, and two older sisters.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/ggnu5k6_liam-payne-and-hotel-where-he-died_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Liam Payne fell to death from the third-floor balcony of a hotel in Buenos Aires.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/iran-is-under-fire-but-its-still-winning-the-ideological-war-6816583]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Iran Is Embattled. But It's Still Winning The Ideological War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/iran-is-under-fire-but-its-still-winning-the-ideological-war-6816583]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 12:07:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[What Iran cannot do militarily to Israel, it's doing with its soft power. It has encircled the Jewish state with a web of entities deeply influenced by its ideology.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8s66n2ug_iran_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>Cafes in bustling Central London are always full of tourists, of which many moneyed ones come from the Arab world. Once, I found myself deep in conversation with a young Saudi architect, who, in a moment of rare candour, shared his thoughts on what he termed the "slaughtering of Gazans" over the past year.</p>

<p>"We are in distress," he sighed. "We young Saudis can see Gaza being flattened, but my country stays silent." These are brave words from a Saudi, no doubt on foreign land. But then, it's a country where the closest thing to freedom of speech is the freedom to agree with the monarch.</p>

<p>But what really made the conversation interesting was his view on Iran's missile strike against Israel on October 1. "Iran is the only country standing up to Israel and America," he said in admiration and relief. A Sunni Saudi praising a Shiite Iran is like an Iranian praising Israel. It should give Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman a sleepless night.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago, an avalanche of missiles rained down over Israeli skies, causing limited damage but sending shockwaves through the Muslim world. From Jakarta to Jenin, the celebrations were will -&nbsp; people cheering as though it was Israel's final defeat. Screams, slogans, sheer disbelief. Never mind that Israel's inevitable retaliation, which is yet to come, could be even more spectacularly deadly. For them, the mere fact that someone - anyone - had dared to defy Israel was enough. Forget logic. This was emotional catharsis at its peak.</p>

<p>It is not surprising then that Tehran's defiance against Israel and the US is making the Islamic Republic more popular across both the wider Shiite and Sunni communities. It is important to recall the 2006 Lebanese war, when Iran's active support to Hezbollah against Israel generated a surge in support for Iran across the Muslim world.</p>

<h2><strong>Iran's Soft Power</strong></h2>

<p>"The Iranian people's revolution is just the beginning of the revolution for the entire Islamic world." Those were the words of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini, the man who kickstarted the 1979 Iranian Revolution and essentially declared his intention to export Iran's brand of Islamic revival far and wide.</p>

<p>While policymakers and analysts in the West tend to fixate on the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and its well-trained armed militias, they are really just scratching the surface. Sure, the IRGC's militia network packs a punch, but that's only one part of Iran's influence. The real thing happens behind the scenes, where Iran has built a whole soft-power empire across West Asia - and beyond -thanks to its soft-power agencies. Under Iran's current supreme leader, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, Iran has continued with its policy of exporting its revolution. In fact, the export of its ideology is enshrined in its Constitution implemented after the 1979 revolution.</p>

<p>What Iran cannot do militarily to Israel, it's doing with its soft power. It has encircled the Jewish state with a web of entities deeply influenced by its ideology. It has cloned its ideology in Hezbollah in Lebanon and the Houthis in Yemen. Its ideological fingerprints are all over Syria and Iraq too. Additionally, Tehran's influence is creeping into parts of the Gulf, with Bahrain, a Shia-majority country, being a notable example. It's also trying to make inroads into Afghanistan and even in places like the Palestinian territories. &nbsp;</p>

<p>And if you are looking for where else Iran's revolution is spreading much beyond its boundaries, just visit the Shia majority Kargil in Kashmir. The life-size cutout of Khamenei outside a Shia mosque in the main town says it all.</p>

<p>By 2009, right in the middle of US and UN sanctions, Iran had completed around several hundred development projects in southern Lebanon - schools, religious centres, sports complexes, hospitals -you name it. And all of them conveniently spread Tehran's Islamic ideology.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The question is, why does Iran support Hamas and, more generally, all Palestinians, even though they are Sunni who have not accepted its Shia revolution? The answer is simple. The clerical regime asserts it is its Islamic duty to be the defender of what it believes is the oppressed people. To support the oppressed and oppose the oppressor is at the core of the Shia doctrine.</p>

<h2><strong>Shiite Doctrine Of Sacrifice</strong></h2>

<p>From the early years of Islam, the followers were divided into Sunni and Shia sects. The former enjoys the majority and the latter's population is restricted to West Asia, Pakistan and India. Persia had a vibrant ancient culture. After embracing Shia Islam, the Persian pride in culture remains strong in Iran.</p>

<p>Urdu poet Allama Iqbal has summed up the spirit of Shiite martyrdom in this couplet: "<em>Islam zinda hota hai har karbala ke baad</em>" (Islam is revived after every Karbala-like tragedy). The Shiite spirit of martyrdom is deeply rooted in the tragedy of Karbala, where Imam Hussain, the grandson of Prophet Muhammad, and his followers, were brutally killed in their stand against tyranny. This sacrifice is seen not just as a historical event but as a timeless symbol of resistance, justice, and self-sacrifice for a higher cause. In Shiite belief, martyrdom is the ultimate act of devotion and defiance against oppression, which has been encapsulated in the Islamic Republic of Iran's ideology.</p>

<p>Therefore, US sanctions or Israeli attacks on its infrastructure only hardens a Shiite's resolve to resist and defy. Take, for example, how over the last four years, the Israeli campaign against Iran, which has seen sabotage and attacks on nuclear and military facilities within Iran, assassinations of nuclear scientists and decorated military officers on Iranian soil and even elsewhere in Syria, Lebanon, Yemen and other locations, have failed to deter Iran or Hezbollah from harming the Israeli cause.</p>

<p>Israel may launch an attack on Iran and destroy its oil fields or other infrastructure in retaliation to the October 1 attack, but it is quite possible it will only firm up the Shiite resolve to launch further attacks on Israel. It might become a never-ending cycle of violence&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Competition To Win Over Muslims</strong></h2>

<p>Much before the Islamic Republic of Iran began exporting its ideology, it was Saudi Arabia that was engaged in winning the hearts and minds of the Muslim world. The export of Wahhabism gained momentum during King Faisal's reign (1964-1975) and continued under subsequent monarchs. Its primary objective was to promote Wahhabism, support Muslim communities worldwide and counter Shia and Iranian influence. "The Wahhabi Mission and Saudi Arabia" by David Commins encapsulates the rise of Wahhabi ideology quite well. Wahhabism took an extreme form in some societies, which gave birth to entities such as the Taliban and Al Qaeda. There was no surprise in the fact that out of the 19 hijackers of planes in the 9/11 terror attack, 15 were Saudi nationals.</p>

<p>It is ironic then that the US would continue to nurture monarchs in Saudi Arabia. Of course, there is no denying that in recent years, Saudi Arabia has attempted to rebrand itself as a force against extremism, introducing reforms under Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman's 'Vision 2030'. However, critics argue that these reforms are superficial and the underlying Wahhabi ideology remains intact.</p>

<h2><strong>Saudi Influence Wanes</strong></h2>

<p>Saudi Arabia was on the brink of signing the Abraham Accord with Israel before the deadly attack by Hamas on October 7 last year. Many in Muslim societies complain that Saudis appear to be doing nothing for the Palestinians in Gaza and the West Bank. On the contrary, it is being accused of cold-shouldering the Palestinian issue. Clearly, with Iran positioned to take on powerful forces like Israel and America, Saudi Arabia is losing the battle of winning the hearts and minds of Muslims.</p>

<p>But West Asia is a complex region. Arabs, Turks and Persians are the largest ethnic or linguistic groups there. Together, they make up 90% of the region's population. The Arab population is divided into over 20 countries. Turks and Iranians largely live in Turkey and Iran, respectively. Much of the current Arab countries and the land where Israel stands today were until the First World War part of the Ottoman Empire. So, Turkish influence in the region cannot be ignored. Turkey Muslims practise Sunni Islam but they are more moderate compared to the Saudi brand of Islam. Modern Turkey, under President Erdogan, is engaged in spreading its cultural and political influences across the Muslim world.</p>

<h2><strong>Iran Is Far From Isolated&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p>It is widely believed that due to sanctions imposed by the US since 1979, the Islamic Republic of Iran stands isolated. The sanctions have no doubt hugely impacted its economy, but the country has still managed to create a huge missile production industry and manufacture the most modern drones. Iran has not only built its axis of resistance in Hezbollah and the Houthis, but it has also nurtured good diplomatic ties with key regional players, such as Turkey, Iraq, Syria, Qatar and, more recently, even with Saudi Arabia. In the last two years, it has become part of geopolitically important multilateral fora, such as BRICS and the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO). A strong anti-US sentiment has also brought Iran and Russia much closer together, which is indeed a big deal for the former.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The US once had an excellent relationship with Iran after it helped depose an elected Prime Minister and install a monarch in 1953. It continued to support the oppressive regime of the Pahlavi monarchy until the 1979 Islamic revolution replaced the tyrant administration. In a way, the US is indirectly responsible for the Islamic revolution and for oppressed Iranians under the monarchy finding refuge in the Shiite faith. True to its habit, the US has often supported dictators and anti-democracy leaders in West Asia. Military dictatorships in Egypt and the monarchies in Saudi Arabia and Jordan continue to depend on the US security umbrella. Maybe there is a need for a West Asia policy reset. But then there are hawks in the US Congress and inside Israel for whom any rapprochement with Iran will be tantamount to blasphemy.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/8s66n2ug_iran_625x300_11_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-turns-60-a-birthday-amid-age-controversy-in-us-polls-2024-6816316]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kamala Harris Turns 60: A Birthday Amid Age Controversy In US Polls 2024]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-turns-60-a-birthday-amid-age-controversy-in-us-polls-2024-6816316]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 11:26:42 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Kamala Harris celebrates her 60th birthday on Sunday, but it's US election rival Donald Trump whose age is under scrutiny after a series of rambling speeches and a bizarre dance party.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kamala Harris celebrates her 60th birthday on Sunday, but it's US election rival Donald Trump whose age is under scrutiny after a series of rambling speeches and a bizarre dance party.</p>

<p>Seeking to shift the polls in a desperately tight White House race, Harris has ramped up attacks on the mental fitness of the 78-year-old, who is the oldest presidential candidate in US history.</p>

<p>"Donald Trump is increasingly unstable," Democratic Vice President Harris said on Wednesday after Trump spent nearly 40 minutes on stage swaying to music at a town hall event.</p>

<p>Harris is unlikely to take time off the campaign trail for her birthday as she and Republican former president Trump hammer crucial battleground states that could decide the November 5 vote.</p>

<p>US presidential elections are a major test of stamina for any candidate -- but the 2024 race has been unusually focused on age.</p>

<p>Harris's remarkable ascent to the top of the Democratic ticket came after 81-year-old President Joe Biden was forced to throw in the towel after a disastrous debate performance against Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Biden's replacement as nominee by a vice president two decades his junior provided a shot in the arm for the party's election hopes, as Harris chased down Trump in the polls.</p>

<p>Trump said as much shortly after Biden pulled out.</p>

<p>"She is younger," Trump told Fox News at the time. "I mean, she's 60 years old... I didn't realize she was 60. I thought she was a little younger. But she is 60."</p>

<p>But with the polls stagnant for weeks, Harris has played the age card more and more.</p>

<p>The Democrat released her own medical report on October 12, describing her as in "excellent health" and fit for the presidency, with the only minor health issue of note being seasonal allergies and hives.</p>

<p>She then repeatedly pushed Trump over his own refusal to do the same.&nbsp;</p>

<h3><strong>'Sexism against older women'&nbsp;</strong></h3>

<p>The billionaire has instead referred to a note issued by his former White House doctor last year and his campaign insists on his stamina.</p>

<p>Harris's campaign has increasingly insinuated that Trump is not up to a second term, citing the withholding of his medical history plus a series of cancelled television interviews and political events.</p>

<p>"What is Donald Trump trying to hide?" Harris said on X.</p>

<p>Her campaign has also highlighted Trump's increasingly dark and erratic stump speeches and interviews, including when he recently raised the possibility of using the US military against the "enemy from within."</p>

<p>Polls suggest it's a strong issue for Harris.</p>

<p>Pew Research Center polling showed the percentage of people who call Trump "mentally sharp" dropping from 58 per cent in July to 52 per cent in September.</p>

<p>And while 49 per cent of voters said Trump's age would hurt his candidacy, 46 per cent of voters said Harris's age would help hers.</p>

<p>But the balancing act is also a tough one in an election where the age of voters is also a key issue.</p>

<p>Harris commands solid support among younger voters but older voters who may find her attacks on Trump's age lean towards him -- in a recent CBS poll, voters aged 45-64 side with Trump over Harris 53 per cent to 46, while among voters aged 65 and over it grows to 57 per cent to 42 per cent.</p>

<p>Yet Harris too faces underlying prejudices about age, said Nancy Hirschmann, a professor of American social thought at the University of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p>"Her age does have an effect in one sense, in that, the sexism of America really is for sure on older women," Hirschmann told AFP.</p>

<p>Trump's running mate JD Vance found himself under scrutiny for comments from a few years back in which he called top Democrats "childless cat ladies" and appeared to agree with dismissive remarks about post-menopausal women.</p>

<p>Harris has two stepchildren from her marriage to "Second Gentleman" Doug Emhoff.</p>

<p>"There's an added layer of sexism against older women over 50," added Hirschmann.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/mtruabig_kamala-harris-afp-_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Kamala Harris is unlikely to take time off the campaign trail for her birthday.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-near-miss-and-a-famous-kiss-king-charles-in-australia-6816264]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[A Near Miss And A Famous Kiss: King Charles In Australia]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/a-near-miss-and-a-famous-kiss-king-charles-in-australia-6816264]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 11:18:21 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[King Charles on Friday begins a six-day tour of Australia, the realm where he was briefly schooled, shared a famous seaside kiss, and had a close shave with a would-be assassin.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>King Charles on Friday begins a six-day tour of Australia, the realm where he was briefly schooled, shared a famous seaside kiss, and had a close shave with a would-be assassin.</p>

<p>It will be his 17th visit since he first arrived as a shy teenager in 1966 -- and his first tour Down Under as king.</p>

<p>Here are five things you may not know about Charles' time in Australia.</p>

<p><strong>'Pommy' bashing</strong></p>

<p>Then-Prince Charles first visited Australia as a gawky 17-year-old, who was shipped away to the secluded alpine Timbertop school in regional Victoria.</p>

<p>A stark departure from his rigid education in Scotland, he would spend two terms chopping logs to make firewood and on gruelling hikes in the nearby woods.</p>

<p>"While I was here I had the Pommy bits bashed off me," he would later remark, also describing it as "by far the best part" of his education.</p>

<p>Media baron Rupert Murdoch is among the many well-heeled alumni to also study at Timbertop, while former British Prime Minister Boris Johnson worked there as an assistant.</p>

<p><strong>King of the surf</strong></p>

<p>Bachelor Charles stripped off and plunged into the surf during a royal tour that took him to Western Australia in 1979.</p>

<p>As the shirtless prince strode towards the shore, he was ambushed by a bikini-clad model who planted a kiss on his cheek.</p>

<p>The instantly iconic photo would help Charles shed his pretentious reputation, prompting some to speculate that it was staged by Buckingham Palace all along.</p>

<p>On an earlier tour, Charles would shun a wetsuit to surf at the world-famous Bondi Beach in Sydney.</p>

<p>"By gee, it's bloody cold," he said. "Reminds me of home."</p>

<p><strong>Mummy dearest</strong></p>

<p>During that same 1977 visit, Charles would grant a rare interview to music television show Countdown.</p>

<p>"I saw your mum in London," star interviewer Molly Meldrum would remark in a faux pas since immortalised in Australia's national film archive.</p>

<p>"Are you referring to Her Majesty the Queen?" came Charles's frosty reply.</p>

<p><strong>Doting on Diana</strong></p>

<p>Charles returned to Australia with wife Diana in 1983, drawing mobs of adoring fans eager to see the "people's princess" at landmarks like the Sydney Opera House.</p>

<p>On the couple's first royal tour together, Diana broke royal protocol by bringing baby William along.</p>

<p>Their dancefloor whirl at Sydney's Wentworth Hotel would inspire a touching scene in the hit show The Crown.</p>

<p><strong>Close shave</strong></p>

<p>Two bangs rang out as Charles rose to give a harbourside speech to a packed Sydney crowd in 1994.</p>

<p>As security wrestled the gunman to the ground, Charles was filmed somewhat nonchalantly fiddling with his cufflinks.</p>

<p>It would later emerge that the 23-year-old assailant was a human rights protester who had fired blank rounds in a mock assassination attempt staged to raise awareness for asylum seekers.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-10/orfejm5_king-charles_625x300_18_October_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[King Charles is on a six-day tour of Australia.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[NDTV Explains: US Charge Over Plot To Kill Terrorist, India's Reaction]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ndtv-explains-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-for-hire-case-ex-spy-vikash-yadav-drug-smuggler-nikhil-gupta-plot-to-kill-khalistani-terrorist-6816220]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 11:10:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The US this week named n ex-Indian intelligence officer - once associated with the Research and Analysis Wing - as the shadowy central figure in a failed plot to kill Gurpatwant Pannun, a Khalistani terrorist.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States this week named <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/vikash-yadav" target="_blank">Vikash Yadav</a>, also known as Vikas Yadav, a former Indian intelligence officer once associated with the Research and Analysis Wing, or R&amp;AW - as the shadowy central figure in a failed plot to kill <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/gurpatwant-singh-pannun" target="_blank">Gurpatwant Pannun</a>, a Khalistani terrorist and founder of the banned Sikhs For Justice.</p>

<p>Pannun is a resident of New York and holds dual American and Canadian citizenship.</p>

<p>Vikash Yadav, 39, - known so far only as 'CC-1' in the indictment filed in a New York court - is in India at this time, but US officials are expected to pursue his extradition in connection with an alleged murder-for-hire conspiracy involving a second Indian citizen - <a class="sp_lnk2" href="http://www.ndtv.com/topic/nikhil-gupta" target="_blank">Nikhil Gupta</a>.</p>

<p>Gupta, 53, was extradited from Czechia to the US in June.</p>

<p>Yadav and Gupta face charges of murder-for-hire, conspiracy to commit murder-for-hire, and conspiracy to commit money laundering, and could be jailed for 40 years if convicted.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ex-indian-spy-charged-in-us-over-alleged-khalistani-terrorist-murder-plot-report-6815072#pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll_Imagetopscroll" target="_blank">Ex Indian Spy Charged In US Over Plot To Kill Khalistani Terroristt</a></p>

<p><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/cc1-man-named-in-us-indictment-in-khalistani-terrorist-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-case-no-longer-government-employee-india-6810995" target="_blank">India has confirmed Yadav is an ex-employee</a> of its premier spy agency.</p>

<p>The third member of this alleged conspiracy was the 'hitman' - allegedly contacted by Gupta on instructions from Yadav - who turned out to be an undercover American federal agent.</p>

<h3><strong>Gurpatwant Pannun Murder Plot Latest</strong></h3>

<p>Yadav's identity was made public Thursday after the US Justice Department unsealed a second indictment - the first named Gupta - in the Pannun murder-for-hire plot.</p>

<p>Vikas Yadav remains "at large", the Justice Department said, accusing the two men of "conspiring to assassinate an American citizen of Indian origin on US soil".</p>

<p>India has said Yadav - who also claims to have served in the Central Reserve Police Force - is no longer a government employee, after which State Department Spokesperson Matthew Miller told reporters the prosecutors are "satisfied" with New Delhi's cooperation.</p>

<h3><strong>Vikash Yadav, Gurpatwant Pannun Murder-For-Hire Conspirator</strong></h3>

<p>US prosecutors believe Yadav recruited Gupta in May last year.</p>

<p>According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-charges-against-indian-government-employee-connection-foiled" target="_blank">unsealed indictment</a> Vikas Yadav - "during times relevant (to these charges)" - was, in fact, was "employed by the Government of India's Cabinet Secretariat, which houses Indian's foreign intelligence service (i.e., RAW)".</p>

<p>The indictment has Yadav describing his position as a "senior field officer" responsible for "security management" and "intelligence". Apart from claiming to have served in the CRPF - which Delhi has not confirmed - Yadav also claimed to have been trained in "battle craft".</p>

<p>The document also includes a photograph of Mr Yadav in military attire.</p>

<p>It also includes a photo two people exchanging money - American dollars - in a car. The photo was reportedly taken in New York and shows, prosecutors claim, money being paid to the 'hitman' by an as yet unknown man acting on behalf of Nikhil Gupta and Vikash Yadav.</p>

<h3><strong>Gurpatwant Pannun Murder Conspiracy Details</strong></h3>

<p>The prosecution claims possession of communications between Vikas Yadav and Nikhil Gupta, in which the former demands the latter plan and execute the killing of Gurpatwant Pannun. In return, Gupta was told criminal charges against him, filed in a Gujarat court, would be dropped.</p>

<p>As part of this murder-for-hire conspiracy the prosecution also claims Yadav and Gupta contacted the 'hitman' - the undercover federal agent - to carry out the hit for $100,000.</p>

<p>An advance of $15,000 was paid in June last year, days before Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to the United States and shortly before another Khalistani terrorist, Hardeep Singh Nijjar, 45, was shot dead outside a gurdwara in Canada's Vancouver.</p>

<p>Nijjar's killing is the subject of a Canadian federal investigation and became the source of a bitter diplomatic row between Ottawa and New Delhi after Canada Prime Minister Justin Trudeau's comment about "agents of the Indian government" being involved in the murder.</p>

<p>India denounced the claim - coming as Mr Trudeau's popularity tanks before a general election - as "absurd", "preposterous", and "malicious", and claimed vindication this week after the Canadian leader admitted he had no hard evidence to back his claim.</p>

<h3><strong>Gurpatwant Pannun Murder-For-Hire Plot</strong></h3>

<p>The attempted killing was to take place in June.</p>

<p>US officials believe Yadav provided Gupta with details about Pannun, including his New York address and daily schedule. This was passed on to the 'hitman'.</p>

<p>However, Gupta told the 'hitman' to not act during or immediately after Mr Modi's visit.</p>

<p>According to the indictment, the plan changed after Nijjar was shot dead on June 18 - two days before Prime Minister Modi's visit. The following day Gupta allegedly told the 'hitman' not to wait; US officials claim he said "Nijjar was also a target... we have so many...:</p>

<p>On June 20 he reportedly told the 'hitman' "it is a priority now".</p>

<h3><strong>The Nikhil Gupta Case</strong></h3>

<p>The storm broke in November last year after the US charged Gupta and Yadav; the latter was then referred to only as CC-1 amid uncertainty over links to the Indian government.</p>

<p>Gupta - in US custody now - claimed involvement with an international drug syndicate and weapons trafficking in his communications with Yadav, according to the indictment.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/who-is-nikhil-gupta-man-charged-in-failed-plot-to-kill-khalistan-terrorist-4623848" target="_blank">Who Is Nikhil Gupta, Man Charged In Failed Plot To Kill Khalistan Terrorist</a></p>

<p>He was in Czechia at the time and was detained by authorities there till his extradition this year. While in Czech custody Gupta moved the Supreme Court in India - via a family member identified only as Mr X.</p>

<p>He claimed multiple violations of fundamental rights, including threats to himself and his family, and requested the Indian government to intervene.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/gurpatwant-singh-pannun-nikhil-gupta-indian-accused-of-khalistani-terrorists-murder-plot-moves-supreme-court-4677720" target="_blank">"Approach Czech Court": Supreme Court On Indian Arrested In US Murder Plot</a></p>

<p>The Supreme Court said the matter did not lie in its jurisdiction and directed Gupta to seek relief from courts in Prague, but also told the External Affairs Ministry to do what it could.</p>

<p>The court noted it could only intervene to ensure consular access and that this had already been supplied, according to the petitioner's own statement.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/nikhil-gupta-gurpatwant-singh-pannun-murder-plot-illegally-detained-in-black-suv-what-indian-us-murder-plot-accused-claimed-4678370" target="_blank">"Made To Eat Beef," Claims Family Of Indian Arrested In US Murder Plot</a></p>

<p>At present Gupta is being held at a detention centre in Brooklyn in New York.</p>

<p>Gupta's lawyers have argued he was caught in 'crossfire' between the two governments.</p>

<h3><strong>Indian Government On Pannun Murder Plot</strong></h3>

<p>As soon as charges were filed India responded, firmly distancing itself from any murder-for-hire bid to kill an American citizen on foreign soil. The External Affairs Ministry said Delhi "takes such inputs seriously... and relevant departments are already examining the issue".</p>

<p>In December Mr Modi made his first public statement, asserting that though the allegations were serious "a few incidents" could not derail ties between the two countries.</p>

<p><strong>READ |&nbsp;</strong><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/pm-modi-financial-times-interview-few-incidents-cannot-derail-our-relations-pm-modi-on-india-us-ties-4707958" target="_blank">PM Modi Breaks Silence On US' Sikh Murder Plot Claim</a></p>

<p>"If someone gives us any information, we will definitely look into it," the Prime Minister told the Financial Times, "If a citizen of ours has done anything, good or bad, we are ready to look into it. Our commitment is to the rule of law."</p>

<h3><strong>Pannun Civil Suit Summons</strong></h3>

<p>The Indian government has, however, reacted strongly to a 'summons' by a US court in connection with a civil suit filed by Pannun, in which he claims a plot to kill him.</p>

<p>Apart from Yadav, Gupta, and the Government of India, the US District Court for the Southern District of New York also named National Security Advisor Ajit Doval and former RAW chief Samant Goel. This was in September. A reply was sought within 21 days.</p>

<p>India slammed the 'summons' as "<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/completely-unwarranted-india-on-us-court-summons-over-khalistani-terrorist-6600977" target="_blank">completely unwarranted</a>".</p>

<p><em><strong>With input from agencies</strong></em></p>

<p><em>NDTV is now available on WhatsApp channels. <a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/channel/0029Va4lixw7z4kcvZI9JM12">Click on the link</a> to get all the latest updates from NDTV on your chat. </em></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/d10hkbbo_pannun3_625x300_18_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Gurpatwant Pannun has been branded a terrorist by the Indian government (File).]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-aerobraking-that-a-secretive-us-spacecraft-will-perform-in-earths-orbit-6816189]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[What Is Aerobraking That A Secretive US Spacecraft Will Perform In Earth's Orbit]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/what-is-aerobraking-that-a-secretive-us-spacecraft-will-perform-in-earths-orbit-6816189]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Oct 2024 11:09:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The spacecraft, X-37B Orbital Test Vehicle, is an experimental space plane operated by the United States Space Force]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A highly secretive US spacecraft is set to embark on a series of innovative flight manoeuvres in Earth's orbit. The spacecraft, the X-37B Orbital Test Vehicle (OTV-7), is an experimental space plane operated by the United States <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.spaceforce.mil/News/Article-Display/Article/3932137/x-37b-begins-novel-space-maneuver/" rel="nofollow, noindex">Space Force </a>(USSF). While the full scope of its mission remains classified, the X-37B has garnered significant attention for its cutting-edge capabilities.</p>

<p>In a release, the US Space Force said that the X-37B Orbital Test Vehicle (OTV-7) is set to carry aerobraking, which will allow it to adjust its orbit around Earth and safely discard its service module in line with international guidelines for managing space debris. Since December 28, 2023, the US Space Force, with the support of the Air Force Rapid Capabilities Office, has been conducting radiation impact studies and trialling Space Domain Awareness technologies while in a highly elliptical orbit.</p>

<p>Aerobraking involves the spacecraft making multiple passes through Earth's atmosphere, using the atmospheric drag to alter its orbit while conserving fuel. Once this manoeuvre is successfully completed, the X-37B will continue its testing and experimental missions. After fulfilling its objectives, the vehicle will de-orbit and return to Earth safely.</p>

<p>Frank Kendall, Secretary of the Air Force, said, This novel and efficient series of manoeuvres demonstrates the Space Force's commitment to achieving groundbreaking innovation as it conducts national security missions in space.</p>

<p>This marks the first time the US Space Force and the X-37B will attempt the dynamic aerobraking manoeuvre, building on the success of six previous missions where the space plane has operated safely, according to the release.</p>

<p>An official illustration of the spacecraft unveiled last year hinted at its potential, depicting the futuristic vehicle intercepting a hostile satellite attempting to disable a friendly satellite, suggesting its role in space defence operations, stated a report in the&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/15/science/secretive-us-spaceship-to-attempt-unprecedented-maneuvers-above-earth/" rel="nofollow, noindex">New York Post</a>.<br />
<br />
Another report in <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.livescience.com/technology/engineering/top-secret-x-37b-space-plane-will-execute-never-before-seen-maneuvers-on-its-descent-to-earth" rel="nofollow, noindex">Live Science</a> stated that X-37B, a covert, remotely operated spacecraft developed by Boeing, is designed for undisclosed missions under the direction of the US Department of Defense (DOD). While its specific operations remain classified, Live Science said that the spacecraft has previously been used to study the impact of solar radiation on seeds.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/kcee55jg_spacecraft_625x300_15_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[(Representational Image)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>