<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 15:21:38 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-becomes-worlds-2nd-largest-5g-mobile-market-surges-past-us-apple-tops-report-6503573]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[India Now World's 2nd Largest 5G Mobile Market, Surges Past US: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/india-becomes-worlds-2nd-largest-5g-mobile-market-surges-past-us-apple-tops-report-6503573]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:58:35 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market for the first time, behind China, a report has mentioned.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market for the first time, behind China, a report has mentioned.</p>

<p>Global 5G handset shipments grew 20 per cent (year-on-year) in the first half of 2024, according to the Counterpoint Research. Apple led the 5G handset shipments, accounting for more than 25 per cent share.</p>

<p>Apple led the 5G handset shipments globally, accounting for more than 25 per cent share, driven by strong shipments of the iPhone 15 series and 14 series, reported news agency IANS.</p>

<p>5G handset shipments have been growing steadily and with the increased availability of 5G handsets in the budget segment, the emerging markets have witnessed high growth in this segment.</p>

<p>"India became the second-biggest 5G handset market during the first half, overtaking the US. The strong shipments from Xiaomi, Vivo, Samsung and other brands in the budget segment were the main reason for this trend," said senior analyst Prachir Singh.</p>

<p>Samsung followed in the second position, capturing more than 21 per cent share, driven by the Galaxy A series and S24 series. Apple and Samsung took five spots each in the top-10 list for 5G models in the first half of 2024, with Apple taking the top four spots.</p>

<p>Other emerging markets also witnessed high growth in 5G handsets. Consumers in emerging markets are looking at 5G handsets as an upgrade to their devices, even in the lower price segments.</p>

<p>Asia-Pacific accounted for 63 per cent of the overall global net adds and commanded a 58 per cent 5G shipment share. In Europe and the Middle East and Africa (MEA) regions also, 5G handset shipments witnessed double-digit growth.</p>

<p>Research Director Tarun Pathak said that as the democratisation of 5G handsets increases with increasing 5G penetration in lower price segments as well as increasing expansion of 5G networks, this trend will further grow.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/clegqgm8_5g-network-generic_625x300_06_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[India has overtaken the US to become the world's second-biggest 5G handset market. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-firm-launches-ai-life-assistant-that-can-order-food-hail-taxis-6504002]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[China Firm Launches AI "Life Assistant" That Can Order Food, Hail Taxis]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/china-firm-launches-ai-life-assistant-that-can-order-food-hail-taxis-6504002]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 14:39:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The fintech firm backed by Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba has made a foray into products powered by artificial intelligence after announcing a "life assistant" mobile app.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The fintech firm backed by Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba has made a foray into products powered by artificial intelligence after announcing a "life assistant" mobile app.</p>

<p>Ant Group said its Zhixiaobao app can help users "order meals, hail taxis, book tickets, and discover local dining and entertainment options" as well as access services in the digital payment app Alipay.</p>

<p>Unveiled in Shanghai on Thursday, comes as tech giants such as Google, Meta and Microsoft ramp up investment in the AI market, with many firms touting tighter integration of chatbots.</p>

<p>"Alipay is committed to harnessing AI's potential to improve the user experience, ensuring that AI assistants like Zhixiaobao become valuable tools in everyday life for all," Ant Group president Cyril Han said in a news release.</p>

<p>Since Ant's initial public offering was scrapped by Chinese authorities in 2020, the firm has been forced to overhaul its business model to satisfy financial regulators.</p>

<p>Last year, it was fined 7.1 billion yuan (US$984 million) for "illegal" acts months after its billionaire founder Jack Ma relinquished control.</p>

<p>The Hangzhou-based company saw its profits fall 10 percent in the January-March quarter, Bloomberg News reported, adding that Ant's valuation has fallen more than 70 percent since the aborted IPO.</p>

<p>Ant on Thursday described its new product as an "AI-native application powered by Ant Group's BaiLing foundation model", referring to the company's large language model.</p>

<p>The Chinese government gave the green light last year for Ant to offer products that used BaiLing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At the Shanghai event, the firm also announced AI-powered products for merchants, healthcare service users and insurance</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-12/5oia0dg8_artificial-intelligence-generic-ai-generic-_625x300_20_December_23.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-surgeon-accused-removing-patients-liver-instead-of-spleen-causing-death-report-6503655]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Died Helpless": Wife Of US Man Whose Liver Was Mistakenly Removed]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/florida-surgeon-accused-removing-patients-liver-instead-of-spleen-causing-death-report-6503655]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:45:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The family of 70-year-old William Bryan accused Dr Thomas Shaknovsky of removing the wrong organ from his body.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Florida doctor has been accused of removing the wrong organ from a man's body, resulting in his death. The family of William "Bill" Bryan, 70, claimed that surgeon Dr Thomas Shaknovsky mistakenly removed Bryan's liver instead of the spleen,&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/sep/04/alabama-man-death-wrong-organ-surgery" rel="nofollow,noindex">reported The Guardian</a>. As of Wednesday, Shaknovsky has not been charged but the law firm appointed by Bryan's family stated that they planned to move the court.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the law firm, Bryan visited the Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital on August 18 after experiencing pain in his flank area. The patient and his wife Beverly were given a rundown of the "risks, benefits, and alternatives" of the surgery before he underwent a splenectomy under surgeon Thomas Shaknovsky on August 21. However, instead of removing Bryan's spleen as intended, the doctor removed his liver, resulting in his untimely death.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
"Dr Shaknovsky removed Mr Bryan's liver and, in so doing, transected the major vasculature supplying the liver, causing immediate and catastrophic blood loss resulting in death,” read the statement. "The surgeon proceeded with labeling the removed liver specimen as a 'spleen,' and it wasn't until following the death that it was identified that the organ removed was Mr Bryan's liver, as opposed to the spleen."</p>

<p>The lawyers also claimed that Shaknovsky had a history of "wrong-site surgery". In 2023, the surgeon mistakenly removed a portion of a patient's pancreas instead of performing the intended adrenal gland resection. The law firm claimed the matter was settled and the terms were not made public. Beverly Bryan stated she hired the legal team to pursue "justice" for her husband.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
In a statement, she said, “My husband died while helpless on the operating room table by Dr Shaknovsky. I don't want anyone else to die due to his incompetence at a hospital that should have known or knew he had previously made drastic, life-altering surgical mistakes.” She is pursuing both civil and criminal actions in the case.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
The Ascension Sacred Heart Emerald Coast Hospital has also released a statement, saying it “take[s] allegations like this very seriously, and our leadership team is performing a thorough investigation into this event”.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-03/8r3kgal_surgery-generic_625x300_21_March_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ic-814-row-and-my-chance-encounter-with-a-global-terrorist-6503645]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: IC 814 Row, And My 1994 Encounter With Terrorist Omar Sheikh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/ic-814-row-and-my-chance-encounter-with-a-global-terrorist-6503645]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:43:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The Netflix web series IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack has sparked a controversy over names of a few of the hijackers. But it has taken me back to my chance encounter with Omar Sheikh, one of the three terrorists released after the hijack.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202004/omar_shiekh_reuters_0.jpeg" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>It was around 8:30 or 9 in the evening on the last day of 1999. I was in Copenhagen, the capital of Denmark, and was visiting a fellow Bihari friend, Tabish Khair - now an established novelist and poet - to celebrate the New Year festivities. While waiting for others to get ready, I switched on the TV to get an update on IC 814, an Indian Airlines plane hijacked eight days earlier with 155 passengers on board. The news was that the terrible saga had ended, and all passengers had been freed. But, of course, their freedom was secured in exchange for the release of three terrorists.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Two of them released from jail were known in India - Maulana Masood Azhar (founder of terror outfit Jaish-e-Mohammed) and Mushtaq Ahmed Zargar (Al Umar Mujahideen). But except the police and intelligence agencies, only a few had heard of the third person: Omar Saeed Sheikh. Just two years later, Sheikh would become infamous worldwide for kidnapping and beheading a US journalist. He also nearly caused a diplomatic crisis between India and Pakistan following the November 26 terror attacks in Mumbai in 2008.</p>

<h2><strong>The Kidnapping Of 3 Westerners</strong></h2>

<p>The Netflix web series <em>IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack</em> has sparked a controversy over names and the portrayal of a few of the hijackers. But it has taken me back to my chance encounter with Sheikh.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The year was 1994. My cameraman and I were out to cover a story for a Delhi-based TV channel; it was going through dry runs before the launch. We had barely reached Ghaziabad when we witnessed elaborate security arrangements outside a private hospital. The road was cordoned off. We were told that a terrorist was admitted to the hospital after being wounded in a police encounter in Saharanpur the previous night, during which a police inspector had been shot dead.</p>

<p>Security was tighter inside the hospital. But some smooth-talking with an amiable Uttar Pradesh '<em>daroga ji</em>' did the trick. He allowed us in on the condition that we would brief him on our conversation with the man inside, Omar Sheikh, whose English accent, he admitted, he did not understand. We rolled the camera as we entered the room, not knowing who Sheikh was and how big a catch he was for the police. The only piece of information we had was that the injured man had kidnapped three Britons and an American in Delhi and hid them in a house in Saharanpur on their way to Kashmir. He had told his captives that his name was Rohit Sharma, and that he was taking them to his quaint ancestral village in Kashmir. But when a Saharanpur police patrol party stumbled upon the captives, a shootout ensued. A police inspector was killed, and Sheikh got injured. All the captives though were freed.</p>

<h2><strong>Omar Sheikh, The London-Born, LSE-Educated Terrorist</strong></h2>

<p>The hospital was posh, Sheikh's room big and clean. He lay in bed with a bandage around his right shoulder. The camera was rolling as we came face to face with a tall and bearded young man, propped up against hospital pillows, looking puzzled and befuddled. His first reaction was to shout a barrage of questions at us, "Who are you, why are you here, who has sent you?".&nbsp;</p>

<p>We asked for an interview, but he refused to speak to us in protest because he said he had no prior notice we were going to do an interview with him. He relented after I produced my press ID card. Before the interview began, he told us his name and that he was 20 years old. He was a student at the prestigious London School of Economics (LSE). He also said he was born in London and was raised both there and in Lahore. His Pakistani immigrant parents lived in London, where they ran a clothes business.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the half-hour interview, Sheikh Omar looked extremely worried. He told me he would give anything to return to life in Britain. He also kept pleading with me, "Brother, take me out of here, please." During the interview, he revealed how at the age of 18, he had already done 'jihad' in Bosnia, fighting alongside and on behalf of Bosnian Muslims, who, he said, were being butchered by the Serbs. He was strikingly young and his accent was distinctly British. I thought he had the gift of the gab. I am not surprised he managed to lure foreign tourists and later, in 2002, used the same trick to lure American journalist Daniel Pearl into captivity.</p>

<h2><strong>Fooled by Extremists</strong></h2>

<p>He also recounted how he had been indoctrinated on the campus by an Islamist organisation that wanted to establish an Islamic society in Britain. He said he had been fooled by the hard-luck stories he had heard about the plight of Muslims and Kashmiris in India.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh admitted that he was charged with kidnapping some foreign tourists to barter for Maulana Masood Azhar, who was then held in prison in India. He also admitted that he had been in Delhi for more than a month before the kidnapping and was struck by the religious freedom he saw. "I had been told that Muslims in India had no religious rights and Kashmiri Muslims were being subjected to torture and rape by the Hindu army," he said.</p>

<p>I asked him, if released, would he go back and tell people in Britain that Indian Muslims were free to build mosques, say prayers, and work in government offices? He said he would. He appeared repentant, but clearly not enough.</p>

<h2><b>Meeting Masood Azhar</b></h2>

<p>Why Omar Sheikh chose the path of destruction was hard to say. He was exposed to Islamist extremism at a tender age. But that doesn't fully explain the path he chose early in his life. He was privileged. He went to the private Forest School in London - the same school former cricketer Nasser Hussain studied in. But while Sheikh became a terrorist, Hussain went on to become the captain of the England cricket team.&nbsp;</p>

<p>At LSE, Sheikh was known for his academic brilliance, especially in maths and economics. But he dropped out before completing his degree to join the 'jihad' in Bosnia. It is reported that he met a couple of Pakistani "fighters" there, who introduced him to Maulana Masood Azhar upon his return to Pakistan. He trained in both Pakistan and Afghanistan.</p>

<p>After his release, it's unclear where Sheikh went in Pakistan. According to some Pakistani papers, he lived in Lahore, where he married a local woman and had a child.</p>

<p>Until this time, Omar Sheikh was known mostly to Indian investigators and intelligence communities. His name cropped up at the time of his release in December 1999 from Tihar, but outside of India, he remained unknown.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>The Kidnapping Of Daniel Pearl</strong></h2>

<p>That changed after the kidnapping of American journalist Daniel Pearl. Suddenly, everyone wanted to know who Sheikh was. A foreign media outlet published my encounter with him, and I was inundated with requests for interviews by the Western media.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Sheikh was found guilty of kidnapping and murdering Pearl. He was given a death sentence, which was later turned into life imprisonment. According to a respected Pakistani journalist, who met a prison officer where Sheikh was lodged, Omar was shuttled regularly between Karachi and Hyderabad jails, spending a fortnight in each. The officer told the journalist that it was necessitated by the fact that he used his gift of the gab and often cast his spell on prison officials, who would then do him favours, like smuggling cellphones.&nbsp;</p>

<h2><strong>When Sheikh Posed As Pranab Mukherjee</strong></h2>

<p>It is precisely this gift that once landed the authorities into hot water and led to a near diplomatic crisis between India and Pakistan. A year after the 2008 Mumbai terror attacks, Karachi's Dawn newspaper ran an investigative story claiming that Sheikh had called the Pakistani President at the time, Asif Zardari, claiming to be India's then-foreign minister Pranab Mukherjee. It was reported that he used unparliamentary language on the call and threatened Zardari with dire consequences for the Mumbai attacks. The English daily claimed, "Omar Saeed Sheikh, a detained Pakistani militant, had made hoax calls to President Asif Ali Zardari and the Chief of Army Staff, Gen Ashfaq Parvez Kayani, in a bid to heighten Pakistan-India tensions after last year's terrorist attacks on Mumbai, investigators have told Dawn."</p>

<p>A diplomatic crisis was averted after the call was traced to his cell in Hyderabad jail. The cell was raided, and it was found that Sheikh used a British SIM card to make the threatening calls.</p>

<p>Despite Daniel Pearl's wife, Mariane Pearl, writing a book, titled A Mighty Heart, and despite the book being made into a Hollywood film with the same title, the story of Omar Sheikh remains shrouded in mystery. In dozens of court appearances, he often appeared affable and charming, but not a lot of his terror connections have been confirmed.</p>

<h2><strong>Omar Sheikh Is Still A Mystery</strong></h2>

<p>Former dictator Pervez Musharraf called him a British spy in his autobiography. Omar himself boasted of his deep links to Pakistan's Inter-Services Intelligence (ISI) in his off-the-cuff remarks to journalists during court hearings. He was known to have good relations with Jaish-e-Mohammed's Maulana Masood Azhar and Lashkar-e-Toiba's Zaki-ur-Rehman Lakhvi. Some journalists, who investigated the roles terror outfits played in the &nbsp;9/11 attacks, claimed he was an operative of Al-Qaeda.</p>

<p>Omar is being held in jail despite his release order by the Supreme Court in Pakistan. It is believed the country has kept him in prison after re-arresting him because of international pressure. But some also claim that he is better off in jail, lest he reveal too much.</p>

<p><em>(Syed Zubair Ahmed is a London-based senior Indian journalist with three decades of experience with the Western media)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202004/omar_shiekh_reuters_0.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/treated-like-garbage-french-woman-on-husband-who-let-50-men-rape-her-6503587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Treated Like Garbage": French Woman On Husband Who Let 50 Men Rape Her]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/treated-like-garbage-french-woman-on-husband-who-let-50-men-rape-her-6503587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:36:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[During investigation, police found a file, labelled as "abuses" on the USB drive that was connected to the accused husband's computer. While searching the drive, officials found nearly 20,000 images and films of the woman getting raped almost 100 tim]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 72-year-old French woman, whose husband admitted to drugging her and inviting dozens of men to rape her over a decade, told a court that she was treated "like a rag doll" and was "sacrificed on the altar of vice".<br />
<br />
In a calm and clear voice, Gisele Pelicot, in the southern French city of Avignon, detailed the horror of how her husband Dominique Pelicot, 71, allegedly lined up scores of men to rape her while she was unconscious.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
This happened close to 100 times in their home for nearly a decade, while her husband systematically filmed the suspected rapes and stored thousands of images as well as videos later found by the investigators.<br />
<br />
“I was sacrificed on the altar of vice... They regarded me like a rag doll, like a garbage bag... I no longer have an identity. I don't know if I will ever rebuild myself," she testified, as per a report in <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/france-wife-rape-trial-gisele-dominique-pelicot-b2607529.html">The Independent</a>.<br />
<br />
She added, “For me, everything collapses. These are scenes of barbarity, of rape.”<br />
<br />
She said she was abused at least six times by someone, who was known to have HIV.<br />
<br />
“My life was in danger but not one second did anyone stop... I was tested for HIV as one man who came (to rape me) six times was seropositive,” Gisele told the court, testifying about the abuse inflicted on her between 2011 and 2020, <a href="http://https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/world-news/french-husband-accused-of-drugging-wife-allegedly-let-hiv-positive-attacker-rape-her-six-times/">New York Post</a> reported.<br />
<br />
<strong>Police 'saved my life'</strong><br />
<br />
The woman said the “police saved my life” after they investigated her husband's computer back in November 2020 after he was caught by a security guard filming up the skirts of women at a supermarket near their home in a village in southern France, <a href="http://https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/sep/05/french-woman-world-fell-apart-alleged-rapes-men-invited-by-husband-gisele-pelicot">The Guardian</a> reported.<br />
<br />
Describing the moment the investigators first showed her the videos of images of sexual abuse orchestrated and filmed by her husband, Gisele Pelicot termed it as “an explosion, a tsunami”.<br />
<br />
“My world is falling apart. For me, everything is falling apart. Everything I have built up over 50 years... Frankly, these are scenes of horror for me,” she said while Dominique Pelicot kept listening to her in court with his head bowed.<br />
<br />
The report stated that while investigating the case, police saw a file, labelled "abuses" on the USB drive that was connected to Dominique Pelicot's computer. While searching the drive, officials found nearly 20,000 images and films of the woman getting raped almost 100 times.<br />
<br />
<strong>The crime</strong><br />
<br />
According to police, the accused husband used to crush sleeping pills and anti-anxiety medication and mix them into his wife's meal or wine. He then used to invite men to rape her after contacting them through an online chatroom.<br />
<br />
Dominique Pelicot as well as 50 other men, aged between 26 and 74, are on trial, reports said.<br />
<br />
According to <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/world-news/2024/09/05/french-rape-trial-latest-updates/">The Telegraph</a>, the woman's husband and 14 other co-accused have admitted to rape, while 35 men, belonging to all walks of life, have denied the charges, claiming the woman was in some way consented to libertine sex.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/95tt9k4k_gisele-pelicot_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-children-die-after-fire-rips-through-primary-school-hostel-in-kenya-6503406]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[17 Children Die After Fire Rips Through Primary School Hostel In Kenya]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/17-children-die-after-fire-rips-through-primary-school-hostel-in-kenya-6503406]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 13:08:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least 17 children died after a fire ripped through their primary school dormitory overnight in central Kenya, police said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least 17 children died after a fire ripped through their primary school dormitory overnight in central Kenya, police said Friday.</p>

<p>The blaze in Nyeri county's Hillside Endarasha Academy broke out at around midnight, police said, engulfing rooms where the children were sleeping.</p>

<p>The primary school caters to some 800 pupils, aged between roughly five and 12.</p>

<p>"There are 17 fatalities from this incident and there are also others who were taken to hospital with serious injuries," national police spokesperson Resila Onyango told AFP.</p>

<p>"The bodies recovered at the scene were burnt beyond recognition," she said.</p>

<p>Police said the average age of the victims was around nine years old.</p>

<p>Several others were injured, Onyango said, 16 of them seriously, and had been rushed to a nearby hospital.</p>

<p>"More bodies are likely to be recovered once (the) scene is fully processed," she said.</p>

<p>The cause of the fire remains unknown, she said, but an investigation had been launched.</p>

<p>President William Ruto expressed his condolences for those killed.</p>

<p>"Our thoughts are with the families of the children who have lost their lives in the fire tragedy," he said in a post on X.</p>

<p>"This is devastating news."</p>

<p>He said he had instructed officials to "thoroughly investigate this horrific incident", and promised that those responsible will be "held to account".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The school is located around 170 kilometres (100 miles) north of the capital Nairobi, in Nyeri county.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Kenyan Red Cross said it was on the ground assisting a multi-agency response team.</p>

<p>In a post on X, it said it was "providing psychosocial support services to the pupils, teachers and affected families".</p>

<h2>Deadly blazes</h2>

<p>There have been numerous school fires in Kenya and across East Africa.</p>

<p>In 2016, nine students were killed by a fire at a girls' high school in the Kibera neighbourhood of Nairobi.</p>

<p>In 2001, 67 pupils were killed by an arson attack on their dormitory at the Kyanguli Mixed Secondary School David Mutiso in Kenya's southern Machakos district.</p>

<p>Two pupils were charged with the murder, and the headmaster and deputy of the school were convicted of negligence.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In 1994, 40 school children were burned alive and 47 injured in a fire that ravaged the Shauritanga Secondary School for Girls in the northern region of Kilimanjaro in Tanzania.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/a8a2gqf_house-fire-generic_625x300_11_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police said the average age of the victims was around nine years old. (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-easyjet-flight-forced-to-make-emergency-landing-after-drunk-passenger-causes-chaos-mid-air-6503079]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Video: Drunk EasyJet Passenger Forces Emergency Landing In Munich]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/video-easyjet-flight-forced-to-make-emergency-landing-after-drunk-passenger-causes-chaos-mid-air-6503079]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:16:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An EasyJet flight, bound for Kos International Airport in Greece, was forced to make an emergency landing at Munich International Airport after an allegedly drunk passenger caused midair chaos and terrorised others onboard.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An EasyJet flight, bound for Kos International Airport in Greece, was forced to make an emergency landing at Munich International Airport after an allegedly drunk passenger caused midair chaos and terrorised others onboard. According to the <em>New York Post,</em> the incident took place on Tuesday. The trouble began about two hours after flight U28235 took off from London Gatwick Airport. As the Airbus A320 flew through some turbulence during the scheduled four-hour flight, the passenger, who was clearly intoxicated, stood up to disrupt the flight and also berated the Captain.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A video shared on X by @FlightModeblog captured the dramatic aftermath. In the clip, passengers were seen erupting into cheers, with some even shouting, "Get off, you loser", as German police escorted the rowdy traveller off the plane. Another passenger also received applause for reportedly holding the man down until the Captain landed the plane safely.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Take a look at the video below:&nbsp;</strong></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">On September 3, <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/easyJet?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#easyJet</a> Airbus A320 (G-EZUR) flight <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/U28235?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#U28235</a> from <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/London?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#London</a> Gatwick to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Kos?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Kos</a>, Greece, was forced to divert to <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Munich?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Munich</a> after a drunk passenger allegedly attempted to open an emergency exit door during the flight.<br />
<br />
? ©Charlotte_keen1/TikTok<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/aviation?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#aviation</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AvGeek?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#AvGeek</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/avgeeks?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#avgeeks</a> <a href="https://t.co/ZakIQO8FEv">pic.twitter.com/ZakIQO8FEv</a></p>
— FlightMode (@FlightModeblog) <a href="https://twitter.com/FlightModeblog/status/1831568908018454798?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/world-news/easyjet-flight-makes-emer/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>The Post</em></a>, EasyJet said that the emergency landing stemmed from a "passenger behaving disruptively on board".&nbsp;</p>

<p>The outlet reported that the passenger, whose identity hasn't been revealed, got into a war of words with other passengers. He even broke the onboard intercom and fought with the flight crew, which led to a brawl and the traveller being detained.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"Safety is easyJet's highest priority and our cabin crew are trained to assess and act quickly and appropriately in all situations to ensure that the safety of the flight and other passengers is not compromised at any time," the airline told <em>The Post</em>. "While such incidents are rare, we take them very seriously and do not tolerate abusive or threatening behaviour onboard," it added.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The remaining passengers, on the other hand, disembarked the plane and received hotel and meal accommodations overnight before the flight departed for Greece on Wednesday. "While this was outside of our control, we are sorry for the inconvenience caused," the airline said.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/kamala-harris-or-donald-trump-nostradamus-of-us-elections-makes-final-prediction-for-2024-6501674">Harris Or Trump? 'Nostradamus' Of US Presidential Elections Makes Final Prediction For 2024</a></strong></p>

<p>Meanwhile, in another incident, a US man was arrested in August for his alleged disruptive and life-threatening behaviour on an American Airlines flight. Twenty-six-year-old Eric Nicholas Gapco, travelling on flight 2101 from Seattle to Dallas on July 18, exhibited what authorities described as "unruly" behaviour.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Apart from propositioning a female crew member for sex, Gapco also reportedly attempted to open the plane's door mid-flight multiple times, forcing the emergency landing. According to the outlet, he removed his shirt mid-flight and began inhaling on a vape pen while cursing and hitting on a crew member, proposing to her for sex. The passenger also allegedly assaulted a flight attendant.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/a06114s_easyjet-passenger-_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The incident took place on Tuesday. (Representative pic)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-find-connection-between-alzheimers-and-night-time-light-pollution-6502947]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Researchers Find Connection Between Alzheimer's, Night Time Light Pollution]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/researchers-find-connection-between-alzheimers-and-night-time-light-pollution-6502947]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:57:54 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A team of US researchers on Friday said that they have found a connection between Alzheimer's disease (AD) and night time light pollution from the outdoors.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A team of US researchers on Friday said that they have found a connection between Alzheimer's disease (AD) and night time light pollution from the outdoors.</p>

<p>Researchers at Rush University Medical Center, US have found that night time light pollution is more strongly correlated with the prevalence of Alzheimer's disease (AD) in people aged under 65, than other risk factors like alcohol abuse, chronic kidney disease, depression, and obesity.</p>

<p>“We show that there is a positive association between AD prevalence and exposure to light at night, particularly in those under the age of 65. Nightly light pollution – a modifiable environmental factor, may be an important risk factor for AD,” said Dr Robin Voigt-Zuwala, Associate Professor at Rush University Medical Center.</p>

<p>Other risk factors, such as diabetes, high blood pressure, and stroke, were more strongly associated with AD than light pollution.</p>

<p>However, for people under 65, higher night time light intensity was associated with a greater AD prevalence than any other risk factor.</p>

<p>This could be due to individual differences in light sensitivity and lifestyles in urban areas.</p>

<p>“Awareness of the association should empower people – particularly those with risk factors for AD – to make easy lifestyle changes. Easy to implement changes include using blackout curtains or sleeping with eye masks. This is useful, especially for those living in areas with high light pollution,” noted Dr Voigt-Zuwala.</p>

<p>The researchers hope that their findings can help educate people about the potential risks of light at night and encourage lifestyle changes to prevent the onset of diseases like Alzheimer's and other debilitating conditions.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-09/i248cja_alzheimers-glance_625x300_07_September_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Other risk factors, such as diabetes, stroke, were more strongly associated with AD.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-is-new-zealands-maori-queen-know-her-key-responsibilities-6502835]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Responsibilities Of New Zealand's Second-Ever Maori Queen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-is-new-zealands-maori-queen-know-her-key-responsibilities-6502835]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:39:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono I Te Po was anointed as the new Maori Queen in New Zealand on Thursday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nga Wai Hono I Te Po was anointed as the new Maori Queen in New Zealand on Thursday. The decision was taken by a council of the Indigenous Maori chief after the death of King Kiingi Tuheitia Potatau Te Wherowhero VII. Although the monarch is primarily a ceremonial role and has little official authority, it is still regarded by many tribes as the supreme chief.<br />
<br />
<strong>Role and responsibilities</strong><br />
<br />
<a href="http://https://monarchy.org.nz/home/kingitanga/">As per the official Monarchy New Zealand website</a>, the role of the Maori monarch is different from that of the King of New Zealand. However, the role of monarchy remains important.<br />
<br />
"When Kingitanga, the Maori King movement, was established in 1858, it was hoped that by creating a King, Maori tribes could deal with the settlers on a more equal political footing," reads the website.<br />
<br />
The current <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-new-zealand-s-new-maori-queen-5-points-on-nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki-6495087">Maori Queen</a>, Nga Wai Hono I Te Po, has a major symbolic function but no constitutional role. The Maori King or Queen is the paramount chief of several tribes, or iwi, but is not affiliated with all of them, according to Reuters.<br />
<br />
The Queen -- like her predecessor -- has no judicial or legal authority in New Zealand.<br />
<br />
The <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/new-zealands-maori-crowned-new-queen-after-fathers-death-6494926">Maori monarchy </a>might be old, but it is not an outdated institution and is still relevant. It persists as a lasting manifestation of unity. It is fundamental to Maori communities' cultural and social identities as well as the larger New Zealand identity.<br />
<br />
The Kingitanga movement in New Zealand serves as an example of why monarchies are popular. A monarch is a mana person who dedicates their life to serving others. He or she is the centre of culture and a live representation of a group of people or a country.<br />
<br />
While the Maori Queen functions solely at the cultural level, New Zealand's current monarch Charles III acts on both constitutional and cultural levels. As of now, there seems to be no tension between the two positions. The monarchs enhance each other and share mutual respect, allowing both to better represent New Zealand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/i97ql18g_nga-wai-hono-i-te-po-paki_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Nga Wai Hono I Te Po is 27 years old]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-vote-for-donald-trump-6502692]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Meet Malik Obama, Barack Obama's Half-Brother Who Will Vote For Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-vote-for-donald-trump-6502692]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:16:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In 1992, Malik Obama was the best man during his half-brother Barack Obama’s wedding to Michelle.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Abon'go Malik Obama, half-brother of former US president Barack Obama, is in the spotlight after declaring he will vote for Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump in the November 5 elections.<br />
<br />
"I am Malik Obama. I'm a registered Republican and I'm voting for President Donald Trump," Malik wrote on the social media site X.<br />
<br />
However, this was not the first time he extended support to Trump. He backed the former US president in 2016 as well, saying he supported Trump's policies, especially his focus on security.<br />
<br />
Who is Abon'go Malik Obama?<br />
<br />
Born in Kenya, Malik is the son of economist Barack Obama Sr and his first wife Kezia Obama. The Kenyan-American businessman and philanthropist is a US citizen.<br />
<br />
He serves as the Lead Ambassador at Puppet, a software configuration management tool,<a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/who-is-malik-obama-barack-obamas-half-brother-now-backs-donald-trump-following-tim-walz-family-controversy/articleshow/113087800.cms"> The Times of India</a> reported.<br />
<br />
In the US, he has majorly worked as an accountant for organisations in and around Washington DC. Some of these include Lockheed Martin, the American Red Cross and Fannie Mae.&nbsp;<br />
<br />
Earlier, Malik tried to run for governor in Kenya's Siaya district, where his father hailed from. However, he only managed to get 1% of the vote.<br />
<br />
As per public records, he still maintains a residence in Maryland and is a registered voter there.<br />
<br />
Personal life<br />
<br />
Malik has often been in the limelight due to his controversies and political endorsements. His relationship with his half-brother Barack Obama has witnessed several ups and downs.<br />
<br />
In 1992, Malik was the best man during Barack's wedding to Michelle. He even visited the White House during his half-brother's time in office, <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/05/us-news/barack-obamas-half-brother-malik-says-hes-voting-for-trump/">New York Post</a> reported.<br />
<br />
Earlier, several media reports even suggested that Malik was married to between three and 12 women, but he refuted these claims later.<br />
<br />
Malik had a fallout with the former US president after he launched a charity, named Barack H. Obama Foundation. However, he failed to register it and even lied about it being a tax-exempt organisation.<br />
<br />
"My brother didn't help me at all. He wanted me to shut it down when I set it up. He hasn't supported me at all," Malik said in an earlier interview.<br />
<br />
Malik even added fuel to the conspiracy theory, which was earlier spread majorly by Donald Trump, claiming that Barack Obama was not born in the US and was rather a citizen of Kenya.<br />
<br />
To prove his claims, Malik reportedly even shared a fake image of a birth certificate, dated from before the 1964 establishment of the Republic of Kenya. It purportedly showed Barack Obama was born outside the US.<br />
<br />
Calling his younger half-sibling a “deep disappointment,” Malik earlier also slammed Hillary Clinton, the 2016 Democratic nominee, for his exit from the party.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/lkoh694g_barack-obama-half-brother_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-says-issues-over-teesta-water-treaty-with-india-must-be-resolved-6502627]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Muhammad Yunus Says Issues Over Water Treaty With India Must Be Resolved]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/muhammad-yunus-says-issues-over-teesta-water-treaty-with-india-must-be-resolved-6502627]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:01:13 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladesh's Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus has said the interim government would pursue with India ways to resolve the differences over the long-pending Teesta water sharing treaty, as delaying it for years serves no purpose for either nation.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladesh's Chief Adviser Muhammad Yunus has said the interim government would pursue with India ways to resolve the differences over the long-pending Teesta water sharing treaty, as delaying it for years serves no purpose for either nation.</p>

<p>In an interview with PTI at his official residence in Dhaka, Muhammad Yunus stated that the water-sharing issue between the two countries must be resolved according to international norms, emphasising that lower riparian countries like Bangladesh have specific rights that they seek to uphold.</p>

<p>"By sitting over this issue (water sharing), it is not serving any purpose. If I know how much water I will get, even if I am not happy and sign it, it would be better. This issue has to be resolved," he said.</p>

<p>Replying to a query on whether the interim government would push for resolving the issues over the Teesta water-sharing treaty at the earliest, he said the new regime will pursue it.</p>

<p>"Push is a big word; I am not saying it. We will pursue it. But we have to sit together and resolve it," he told PTI.</p>

<p>India and Bangladesh were set to sign a deal on Teesta water sharing during then-Prime Minister Manmohan Singh's visit to Dhaka in 2011, but West Bengal Chief Minister Mamata Banerjee declined to endorse it, citing a scarcity of water in her state.</p>

<p>"This is not a new issue but a very old issue. We have spoken on this issue on several occasions. The discussions began during the period of Pakistan's rule. While we all wanted this treaty to be finalised, even the Indian government was ready for it. However, the state government of West Bengal was not ready for it. We need to resolve it," he said.</p>

<p>Muhammad Yunus reiterated that lower riparian countries like Bangladesh have specific rights that they seek to uphold.</p>

<p>"We have to resolve this issue according to international norms. The lower riparian countries have certain rights, and we want those rights," he said.</p>

<p>His remarks come days after the interim government's Adviser on Water Resources, Syeda Rizwana Hasan, told PTI that Dhaka would push for restarting the dialogue regarding the Teesta water-sharing treaty with New Delhi and asserted that both countries should adhere to international principles regarding water-sharing between upper riparian and lower riparian countries.</p>

<p>Speaking about the flood situation in Bangladesh and reports from Dhaka blaming India for the floods, Muhammad Yunus said that until the treaty is signed, a humanitarian approach can be adopted to deal with such crises.</p>

<p>"When the High Commissioner (of India) came to meet me, I said that we can work on better management to see how the situation can be controlled during the floods. For such coordination between two countries, we don't need any treaty." "We can work on this together on humanitarian grounds and resolve this, as this will ease the suffering of the masses. Such humanitarian steps would really help," he said.</p>

<p>Monsoon rainfall-triggered floods in deltaic Bangladesh and upstream Indian regions have killed several people and marooned or affected nearly three million others in Bangladesh, posing a huge administrative challenge to the newly installed interim government amid a political transition.</p>

<p>India has described as factually incorrect the reports from Bangladesh that the current flood situation in certain parts of the country has been caused by the opening of a dam on the Gumti River in Tripura.</p>

<p>The Ministry of External Affairs (MEA) in New Delhi stated that floods in the shared rivers between the two countries are a "shared" problem affecting people on both sides and require close mutual cooperation to resolve.</p>

<p>Speaking about the contentious issue of border killings, Muhammad Yunus condemned it and said killing is not a solution to dealing with it.</p>

<p>The Border Security Force (BSF) of India has accused Bangladeshi smugglers and infiltrators of crossing over the border and attacking Indian forces when challenged.</p>

<p>They have raised the issue with the Bangladesh counterpart BGB on several occasions. West Bengal shares a total of 2,217 kilometres of its border with Bangladesh, along with Tripura (856 km), Meghalaya (443 km), Assam (262 km), and Mizoram (318 km).</p>

<p>Deaths at times occur along the Bangladesh-India border due to alleged infiltrators trying to cross into India illegally, cross-border firing, and cattle smuggling.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/j4vjvr9g_muhammad-yunus-afp_625x300_19_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA["We have to resolve this issue according to international norms," he said (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-kamala-harris-will-win-nostradamus-of-us-presidential-polls-allan-lichtman-to-ndtv-6502573]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Who Will Win White House Race? "Nostradamus" Of US Polls Tells NDTV...]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-presidential-election-2024-kamala-harris-will-win-nostradamus-of-us-presidential-polls-allan-lichtman-to-ndtv-6502573]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 10:54:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Allan Lichtman, often referred as the "Nostradamus of US presidential elections", has predicted that Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris will win the race to the White House this year.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Polls&nbsp;prophet Allan Lichtman, often&nbsp;called&nbsp;the "Nostradamus of US presidential elections", has predicted that Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris will win the race to the White House this year. In an exclusive interview with NDTV, Mr Litchman, who has&nbsp;correctly predicted&nbsp;nine out of&nbsp;10&nbsp;election&nbsp;results, said that Vice President Kamala Harris will beat Republican Presidential nominee Donald Trump.</p>

<p>To accurately predict who will occupy the Oval Office, Mr Lichtman has <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-presidential-polls-makes-his-prediction-for-2024-5569902">designed what he calls "13 keys to the White House</a>," a groundbreaking method that revolutionized election forecasting. The keys, comprising a series of true or false questions, assess various factors such as party mandate, contest, incumbency, third party, short-term economy, long-term economy, foreign success, social unrest, incumbent charisma and challenger charisma.</p>

<p>Mr Lichtman explained that if six or more keys go against the White House party, they are predicted losers, or else they are predicted winners. While Kamala Harris has secured eight of Mr Litchman's keys to the White House, Trump only has three of his keys.</p>

<p>"They lost the mandate key, which is based on losses in US house election. They have obviously lost the incumbency key with Biden not running. But with the party uniting around Harris, the avoided the loss of the contest key. Finally, the third key that they lost was incumbent charisma key," he explained, adding that Democrats will hold on the White House.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nostradamus-of-us-presidential-polls-makes-his-prediction-for-2024-5569902">'Nostradamus' Of US Presidential Polls Makes His Prediction For 2024</a></strong></p>

<h3><strong>Foreign Policy Success, Failures Undecided</strong></h3>

<p>Mr Litchman, who has successfully predicted election outcomes since 1984, said foreign policy failure and success remain undecided.</p>

<p>"The only other two keys that are shaky are the two foreign policy keys, he explains, because the wars in the Middle East and Ukraine are so fluid. I think those keys will split and Harris will be down 4 keys. But even if they both flip negative, this means Harris is down only 5 keys, still one key short of defeat. All other keys are locked in her favour," he added.</p>

<p>Asked about areas of uncertainty, the US historian said "Two areas of uncertainty are two foreign policy keys- foreign military success and failure. We don't know exactly what could happen in Ukraine or Middle East. But they won't affect my prediction that Kamala Harris is going to be the next President of the United States. These two keys are not enough to predict that Donald Trump could regain the White House."</p>

<h3><strong>On Short-Term, Long-Term Economy</strong></h3>

<p>"My two economic keys are statistical and they are very specifically defined. The short-term economy key says there is no recession in the election year. You can't just have recession in a couple of months, it takes much longer than that.</p>

<p>"The long term economy key asks whether the per capita growth on the current term is equal to the average of previous two terms. &nbsp;And per capita growth under Biden is double or more that that of the average of previous two terms," he explained.</p>

<p>Asked if Republicans could do anything to fare better, the election forecaster said, "There is actually nothing they can do. That's the whole point of the keys. It is fundamentally different that all of the conventional wisdoms."</p>

<p>Mr Lichtman's predictive prowess faced its most significant test in the tumultuous 2000 election between Al Gore and George W Bush. While he forecasted a victory for Gore, the controversial outcome cast a shadow over his prediction.</p>

<p><strong>ALSO READ |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/factbox-what-new-proposals-did-trump-make-during-his-economic-speech-6501352">Factbox: What New Proposals Did Trump Make During His Economic Speech?</a></strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/shmlric_kamala-harris-and-allan-licthman_625x300_06_September_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/june-august-2024-were-hottest-summer-months-ever-recorded-6502519]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[June-August 2024 Were Hottest Summer Months Ever Recorded]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/june-august-2024-were-hottest-summer-months-ever-recorded-6502519]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 10:44:05 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The 2024 northern summer saw the highest global temperatures ever recorded, beating last year's record and making this year likely Earth's hottest ever, the EU's climate monitor said Friday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 2024 northern summer saw the highest global temperatures ever recorded, beating last year's record and making this year likely Earth's hottest ever, the EU's climate monitor said Friday. The data from the Copernicus Climate Change Service followed a season of heatwaves around the world that scientists said were intensified by human-driven climate change.</p>

<p>"During the past three months of 2024, the globe has experienced the hottest June and August, the hottest day on record, and the hottest boreal summer on record," Samantha Burgess, deputy director of Copernicus, said in a report.</p>

<p>"This string of record temperatures is increasing the likelihood of 2024 being the hottest year on record."</p>

<p>The average global temperature at the Earth's surface was 16.82C in August, according to Copernicus, which draws on billions of measurements from satellites, ships, aircraft and weather stations.</p>

<p>The June and August global temperature broke through the level of 1.5C above the pre-industrial average -- a key threshold for limiting the worst effects of climate change.</p>

<p>Human-caused greenhouse gas emissions are warming the planet, raising the likelihood and intensity of climate disasters such as droughts, fires and floods.</p>

<p>Heat was exacerbated in 2023 and early 2024 by the cyclical weather phenomenon El Nino, though Copernicus scientist Julien Nicolas told AFP its effects were not as strong as they sometimes are.</p>

<p>Meanwhile the contrary cyclical cooling phenomenon, known as La Nina, has not yet started, he said.</p>

<h2>Emissions reductions</h2>

<p>Against the global trend, regions such as Alaska, the eastern United States, parts of South America, Pakistan and the Sahel desert zone in northern Africa had lower than average temperatures in August, the report said.</p>

<p>But others such as Australia -- where it was winter -- parts of China, Japan and Spain experienced record warmth in August.</p>

<p>Globally, August 2024 matched that month's previous global temperature record from one year earlier, while this June was hotter than last, Copernicus data in the report showed.</p>

<p>July was slightly hotter in 2023 than this year, but on average the three-month period broke the record in 2024.</p>

<p>Governments have targets to reduce their countries' planet-heating emissions to try to keep the rise below 1.5C under the 2015 Paris Agreement.</p>

<p>Scientists will not consider that threshold to be definitively passed until it has been observed being breached over several decades. The average level of warming is currently about 1.2C, according to the World Meteorological Organisation.</p>

<p>Copernicus said the 1.5C level has been passed in 13 of the past 14 months.</p>

<h2>Wildfires, hurricanes</h2>

<p>The oceans are also heating to record levels, raising the risk of more intense storms.</p>

<p>Copernicus said that outside of the poles, the average sea surface temperature in August was just under 21C, the second-highest level on record for that month.</p>

<p>It said August "was drier than average over most of continental Europe" -- noting the wildfires that struck countries such as Greece.</p>

<p>But places such as western Russia and Turkey were wetter than normal, with floods in some places.</p>

<p>The eastern United States had more rain than usual, including areas lashed by Hurricane Debby.</p>

<p>"The temperature-related extreme events witnessed this summer will only become more intense, with more devastating consequences for people and the planet unless we take urgent action to reduce greenhouse gas emissions," Copernicus's deputy director Burgess said.</p>

<p>Some researchers say that emissions in some of the biggest countries may have peaked or will soon do so, partly as a result of the drive towards low-carbon energy.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/fn9jgh8_heat-generic_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The oceans are also heating to record levels, raising the risk of more intense storms.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xs-global-affairs-head-nick-pickles-resigns-after-10-years-6502516]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[X's Global Affairs Head Nick Pickles Resigns After 10 Years]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/xs-global-affairs-head-nick-pickles-resigns-after-10-years-6502516]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 10:42:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[X's global affairs head Nick Pickles said on Thursday he is quitting after a decade with the social media company formerly called Twitter. Pickles, who joined the company in 2014, said he]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>X's global affairs head Nick Pickles said on Thursday he is quitting after a decade with the social media company formerly called Twitter.</p>

<p>Pickles, who joined the company in 2014, said he had decided to leave X several months ago and was working with the Chief Executive Linda Yaccarino through the transition.</p>

<p>"After more than ten years, tomorrow will be my last day at X. It's been an incredible journey," he said.</p>

<p>It was not immediately clear what his next plans were, or why he made the decision to quit.</p>

<p>Elon Musk-owned X and Nick Pickles did not immediately respond to Reuters requests for comment outside of regular business hours.</p>

<p>In June, X's head of business operations, Joe Benarroch left the company, the Wall Street Journal reported, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>

<p>Pickles had started at X as a senior manager in their London office and was appointed the Vice President of Global Affairs for X in 2023 after serving in multiple roles, his LinkedIn profile showed.</p>

<p>The Financial Times reported that he was the company's spokesperson in battles with multiple governments, including in Brazil, which said last week it was suspending access to the social network in the country.</p>

<p>The popular social media platform missed a court-imposed deadline to name a legal representative in Brazil, triggering the suspension.</p>

<p>Musk has argued that Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes was trying to enforce unjustified censorship, while the judge has insisted that X needs hate speech regulations.</p>

<p></p>

<p>(Reporting by Harshita Meenaktshi in Bengaluru; Editing by Nivedita Bhattacharjee)</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/ivkpfd04_nick-pickles_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-charges-5-russian-military-officers-over-ukraine-cyberattacks-6502368]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Charges 5 Russian Military Officers Over Ukraine Cyberattacks]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-charges-5-russian-military-officers-over-ukraine-cyberattacks-6502368]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 10:16:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The United States charged five Russian military officers on Thursday for allegedly conducting cyberattacks on civilian infrastructure in Ukraine ahead of the Russian invasion.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States charged five Russian military officers on Thursday for allegedly conducting cyberattacks on civilian infrastructure in Ukraine ahead of the Russian invasion.</p>

<p>Assistant Attorney General Matthew Olsen said the members of Russia's GRU military intelligence agency indicted in Maryland waged a cyber campaign against Ukraine known as "WhisperGate."</p>

<p>"The WhisperGate campaign included the targeting of civilian infrastructure and Ukrainian computer systems wholly unrelated to the military or national defense," Olsen said at a press conference in Baltimore.</p>

<p>FBI special agent William DelBagno said the WhisperGate malware attack in January 2022 "could be considered the first shot of the war."</p>

<p>It was intended to cripple Ukraine's government and critical infrastructure by targeting financial systems, agriculture, emergency services, healthcare and schools, DelBagno said.</p>

<p>Olsen said the cyber campaign was not restricted to Ukraine but also included attacks on computer systems in the United States and other NATO countries backing Ukraine.</p>

<p>A Russian civilian, Amin Timovich Stigal, 22, was indicted in Maryland in June on charges of conspiracy to hack into and destroy computer systems for his alleged involvement in WhisperGate.</p>

<p>Stigal and the five Russian GRU members remain at large and the State Department offered a combined $60 million reward for information leading to their arrest.</p>

<p>Stigal's indictment accused him and members of the GRU of distributing WhisperGate malware to dozens of Ukrainian government agency computer systems ahead of the Russian invasion.</p>

<p>- 'Deadly dirty tricks' -</p>

<p>The Justice Department said WhisperGate was designed to look like ransomware but was really a "cyberweapon designed to completely destroy the target computer and related data."</p>

<p>It said patient health records were exfiltrated from computer systems and websites were defaced to read: "Ukrainians! All information about you has become public, be afraid and expect the worst."</p>

<p>The hacked data was also offered for sale on the internet.</p>

<p>US Attorney Erek Barron said the indicted GRU officers were members of a subset of unit 29155 of the Russian Main Intelligence Directorate, which he described as "a military intelligence agency responsible for attempted deadly dirty tricks around the world."</p>

<p>They were named in the indictment as Colonel Yuriy Denisov, commanding officer of cyber operations for Unit 29155, and four lieutenants: Vladislav Borovkov, Denis Denisenko, Dmitriy Goloshubov and Nikolay Korchagin.</p>

<p>The unsealing of the indictment comes a day after the United States accused Russia's state-funded news outlet RT of seeking to influence the 2024 US presidential election.</p>

<p>Attorney General Merrick Garland also announced the seizure of 32 internet domains that were part of an alleged campaign "to secure Russia's preferred outcome," which US officials have said would be Donald Trump winning the November vote.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-05/43at22o8_hacker-generic-cybercrime-generic-cyber-scam-generic_625x300_12_May_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-may-not-return-for-another-term-wants-to-spend-time-with-children-6502160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Blinken May Not Return For Another Term, Wants To Spend Time With Children]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/blinken-may-not-return-for-another-term-wants-to-spend-time-with-children-6502160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 09:32:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Thursday he hoped to spend more time with his children next year, hinting he would not pursue another term as the top US diplomat.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Secretary of State Antony Blinken said Thursday he hoped to spend more time with his children next year, hinting he would not pursue another term as the top US diplomat.</p>

<p>Blinken, who has two young kids, has pressed on with a punishing travel schedule that has only increased over the past year, with nine tours of the Middle East since the October 7 Hamas attack on Israel.</p>

<p>"As to my own future, all I'm looking at right now is the balance of this administration in January," Blinken told reporters in Haiti, where he was the first secretary of state to visit in nearly a decade.</p>

<p>"I can tell you from having spent some time over the last week on a bit of a break with my kids, I will relish having a lot more time with them," he said.</p>

<p>It is highly unusual for a secretary of state to stay on past an election. The last to do so was George Shulz, who joined in 1982, halfway through Ronald Reagan's first term, and remained after the Republican's reelection.</p>

<p>Blinken is known as a highly trusted aide to Joe Biden, advising him as a senator, vice president and president.</p>

<p>But speculation that Blinken, 62, might consider staying dissipated when Biden in July decided to give up his campaign for a second term after a disastrous debate performance against Donald Trump revived questions about the 81-year-old president's age.</p>

<p>Blinken, a lifelong Democrat, has praised the record of Vice President Kamala Harris, who is running against Trump, but he is not known to be as close with her as he is with Biden.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/1c37bhlo_antony-blinken-afp-_625x300_20_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/frozen-in-terror-extremely-well-preserved-ancient-mummies-found-in-iran-6502013]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Frozen In Terror: Extremely Well-Preserved Ancient Mummies Found In Iran]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/science/frozen-in-terror-extremely-well-preserved-ancient-mummies-found-in-iran-6502013]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 09:02:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[An ancient salt mine in Iran naturally preserved dead miners for thousands of years in a grisly state - some of them frozen with their arms still raised before being buried alive.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An ancient salt mine in Iran naturally preserved dead miners for thousands of years in a grisly state - some of them frozen with their arms still raised before being buried alive. According to the <em>New York Post</em>, these corpses - known as the "Saltmen" - were naturally mummified and preserved in the Chehrabad salt mine, near the village of Manzelou in northwest Iran. The bodies came from various time periods, with the oldest dating back to 9550 BCE - more than 10,000 years ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The first Saltman - complete with a long white beard and a single gold earring, as well as a set of iron knives - was accidentally unearthed by miners in 1993. This mummy was still wearing one of his leather boots and had some traces of woollen trousers on his leg. According to the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://nypost.com/2024/09/03/world-news/eerie-photos-show-the-freakishly-well-preserved-ancient-saltmen/" rel="noindex, nofollow"><em>Post</em></a>, the man is believed to have died in the mine around 300 CE. His remains were buried in the middle of a 148-foot tunnel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The second corpse was discovered in 2004, just 50 feet from where Saltman 1's remains were uncovered. In 2005, two more mummies - including the remains of a 16-year-old boy - were found in another tunnel. By 2010, a total of six corpses had been found in the salt mine.&nbsp;</p>

<p>All of the corpses were remarkably well-preserved by the salt that surrounded them. The lack of oxygen also meant that the bodies could not decompose.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A study of the first Saltman head revealed that the corpse had fractures around his eye and damage to the head - leading scientists to conclude that they were all likely killed in mining collapse. The 16-year-old mummy was even found with his hands still raised above his face as if he was surprised by a sudden fall or other threat.</p>

<p><strong>Also Read |&nbsp;<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/new-york-man-says-he-pays-over-rs-1-5-lakh-a-month-in-rent-to-live-with-23-roommates-6495585">New York Man Says He Pays Over ₹ 1.5 Lakh A Month In Rent To Live With 23 Roommates</a></strong></p>

<p>The fifth Saltman was more well-preserved than the others, which allowed scientists to examine his organs up close. They discovered that he had tapeworm eggs which indicated that the men consumed raw or undercooked meat before they met their untimely death in the salt caves.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The discovery marked the earliest evidence of ancient intestinal parasites in Iran, according to a 2012 research paper published in the Journal of Parasitology.</p>

<p>While six whole bodies have been accounted for, detached body parts have also been found, the <em>Post </em>reported. The number of potential "Saltmen" bodies is now believed to be eight or more. It is highly probable that all of them were miners who died in collapses or accidents. The official cause of death as well as how many more of them there could be inside the mine remains a mystery.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/g3vl6bu8_saltmen-mummies_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The bodies came from various time periods.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abandon-blind-bias-hamas-urges-us-pressure-on-netanyahu-for-gaza-deal-6501860]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Abandon Blind Bias": Hamas Urges US Pressure On Netanyahu For Gaza Deal]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/abandon-blind-bias-hamas-urges-us-pressure-on-netanyahu-for-gaza-deal-6501860]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:25:50 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hamas called on the United States Thursday to "exert real pressure" on Israel to reach a Gaza ceasefire agreement as Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said there was no deal in the making.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hamas called on the United States Thursday to "exert real pressure" on Israel to reach a Gaza ceasefire agreement as Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said there was no deal in the making. The two sides have traded blame over stalling talks for a ceasefire and hostage exchange as Netanyahu faces pressure to seal a deal following the deaths of six Gaza captives.</p>

<p>Hamas's Qatar-based lead negotiator Khalil al-Hayya called on the US to "exert real pressure on Netanyahu and his government" and "abandon their blind bias" towards Israel.</p>

<p>But Netanyahu said there is "not a deal in the making".</p>

<p>"Unfortunately, it's not close but we will do everything we can to get them to the point where they do make a deal," he told US media.</p>

<p>Netanyahu insists that Israel must retain control over the Philadelphi Corridor along the Egypt-Gaza border to prevent weapons smuggling to Hamas, whose October 7 attack on Israel started the war.</p>

<p>Hamas is demanding complete Israeli withdrawal from the area and on Thursday said Netanyahu's position "aims to thwart reaching an agreement".</p>

<p>The Palestinian militant group says a new deal is unnecessary because they agreed months ago to a truce outlined by Biden.</p>

<p>"We warn against falling into the trap of Netanyahu... who uses negotiations to prolong the aggression against our people," Hamas said in a statement.</p>

<p>Washington has been pushing a proposal it says could bridge gaps between the warring sides, with Secretary of State Antony Blinken saying "90 percent is agreed".</p>

<p>"It's really incumbent on both parties to get to yes on these remaining issues," Blinken said during a visit to Haiti.</p>

<h2>'Make them' sign deal</h2>

<p>At Israeli protests in several cities this week, Netanyahu's critics have blamed him for hostages' deaths, saying he has refused to make necessary concessions for striking a ceasefire deal.</p>

<p>"We'll do everything so that all hostages will be with us. And if the leaders don't want to sign a deal, we'll make them," said Gil Dickmann, cousin of Carmel Gat, one of the six hostages whose bodies were found in a Gaza tunnel last week.</p>

<p>Dickmann took part in a rally at Tel Aviv on Thursday evening, where crowds of demonstrators carried symbolic coffins in a procession, an AFP journalist reported.</p>

<p>Key mediator Qatar has said that Israel's approach was "based on an attempt to falsify facts and mislead world public opinion by repeating lies".</p>

<p>Such moves "will ultimately lead to the demise of peace efforts", Qatar's foreign ministry warned.</p>

<p>The October 7 attack by Hamas resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians including some hostages killed in captivity, according to official Israeli figures.</p>

<p>Of 251 hostages seized by Palestinian militants during the attack, 97 remain in Gaza including 33 the Israeli military says are dead. Scores were released during a one-week truce in November.</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory offensive in Gaza has so far killed at least 40,878 people, according to the health ministry in the Hamas-run territory.</p>

<p>Most of the dead are women and children, according to the UN rights office.</p>

<p>Israel kept up its bombardment overnight into Friday, with an AFP correspondent reporting a huge explosion in the east of Gaza City.</p>

<p>Six people were killed and others wounded in an Israeli airstrike on a house southeast of the city, Gaza's civil defence agency said Friday.</p>

<h2>West Bank deadly assault</h2>

<p>While Israel presses its Gaza offensive, Defence Minister Yoav Gallant said the military should use its "full strength" against Palestinian militants in the occupied West Bank.</p>

<p>"These terrorist organisations that have various names, whether in Nur al-Shams, Tulkarem, Faraa or Jenin, must be wiped out," he said, referring to cities and refugee camps where an Israeli military operation is underway.</p>

<p>The Israeli military said Thursday its aircraft "conducted three targeted strikes on armed terrorists" in the Tubas area, which includes Faraa refugee camp.</p>

<p>A strike on a car killed five men aged 21 to 30 and wounded two others, the territory's health ministry.</p>

<p>The Palestinian Red Crescent said the Israeli military handed over the dead body of a 17-year-old, after medics were prevented from reaching him when he was wounded.</p>

<p>Israel has killed at least 36 Palestinians across the northern West Bank since its assault there started on August 28, according to figures released by the health ministry, including children and militants.</p>

<p>One Israeli soldier was killed in Jenin, where the majority of the Palestinian fatalities have been.</p>

<h2>Polio vaccination drive</h2>

<p>Israel's bombardment of Gaza has left the territory in ruins, with the destruction of water and sanitation infrastructure blamed for the spread of disease.</p>

<p>The humanitarian crisis has led to Gaza's first polio case in 25 years, prompting a massive vaccination effort launched Sunday with localised "humanitarian pauses" in fighting.</p>

<p>Nearly 200,000 children in central Gaza have received a first dose, the World Health Organization said, and a second stage got underway Thursday in the south, before medics move north.</p>

<p>Louise Wateridge, spokeswoman for the UN agency for Palestinian refugees (UNRWA), warned however that the vaccination drive in the south may not reach all children, as some do not reside in the designated zones where Israel has agreed not to strike.</p>

<p>The campaign aims to fully vaccinate more than 640,000 children, with second doses due in about four weeks.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/435p3ito_benjamin-netanyahu_625x300_21_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-school-shooting-colin-gray-colt-gray-us-school-shooting-suspects-father-arrested-he-bought-him-gun-as-gift-6501786]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US School Shooting Suspect's Father Arrested. He Bought Him Gun As Gift]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/georgia-school-shooting-colin-gray-colt-gray-us-school-shooting-suspects-father-arrested-he-bought-him-gun-as-gift-6501786]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:07:15 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The shooting at Apalachee High School in Georgia's Winder saw two teachers and two 14-year-old students being killed.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The father of the 14-year-old suspected in a Georgia school shooting that killed four people on Wednesday has been arrested with the officials saying he "knowingly allowed his son to have the murder weapon. Colin Gray, 54, was charged with four counts of involuntary manslaughter, two counts of second-degree murder, and eight counts of cruelty to children, officials said on Thursday.</p>

<p>"These charges stem from Gray knowingly allowing his son Colt to possess a weapon," Chris Hosey, the director of the Georgia Bureau of Investigation, told a press conference.</p>

<p>His son, Colt Gray, has been charged with four counts of felony murder and would be tried as an adult, Hosey said.</p>

<p>The shooting at <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/gunfire-reported-at-high-school-in-us-georgia-currently-under-hard-lockdown-news-agency-afp-6491595" target="_blank">Apalachee High School in Winder</a> saw two teachers - Richard Aspinwall, 39, and Christina Irimie, 53 - and two 14-year-old students - Mason Schermerhorn and Christian Angulo - being killed. Two teachers and seven students were also injured in the attack.</p>

<p>Investigators say that Gray used an "AR platform style weapon," or semiautomatic rifle, to carry out the shooting.</p>

<p>CNN reported that Colin purchased the gun as a holiday present for his son in December 2023. The rifle was purchased at a local gun store as a Christmas present, a CNN report said.</p>

<p>The suspect was interviewed by law enforcement last year over online threats about committing a school shooting.</p>

<p>The US has witnessed hundreds of shootings inside schools and colleges in the past two decades, which has intensified the debate over gun laws in the country.</p>

<h3><strong>"We've Gotta Stop It"</strong></h3>

<p>US Vice President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/time-to-end-this-epidemic-of-us-gun-violence-says-kamala-harris-6492567" target="_blank">Kamala Harris</a>, the Democratic Party nominee for president, called the Georgia shooting a "senseless tragedy."</p>

<p>"We've gotta stop it. We have to end this epidemic of gun violence," she said at a campaign event.</p>

<p>The White House said in a statement that US President Joe Biden had been briefed on the shooting "and his administration will continue coordinating with federal, state, and local officials as we receive more information."</p>

<p>"Jill and I are mourning the deaths of those whose lives were cut short due to more senseless gun violence and thinking of all of the survivors whose lives are forever changed," Biden said in a statement, calling on Republicans to work with Democrats to pass "common-sense gun safety legislation."</p>

<p>Former US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-calls-georgia-school-shooter-sick-and-deranged-monster-6492697" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a>, the Republican nominee for president, called it a "tragic" event.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"These cherished children were taken from us far too soon by a sick and deranged monster," he wrote on social media.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/n4b4nv38_colin-gray-colt-gray_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Colin Gray purchased the gun as a holiday present for his son in December 2023.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-to-play-roller-skating-gaza-girl-10-killed-in-israeli-strike-6501676]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Wanted To Play": Roller-Skating Gaza Girl, 10, Killed In Israeli Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/wanted-to-play-roller-skating-gaza-girl-10-killed-in-israeli-strike-6501676]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 Sep 2024 07:36:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Now that Tala is gone, her parents and brothers are left to marvel at their bad luck, with the strike landing during one of the rare occasions Hussam let one of his children go outside.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At first Hussam Salah Abu Ajwa resisted letting his daughter out to play, but finally he relented so she could zip around on her pink skates near their Gaza City home.</p>

<p>Within two minutes he heard the boom of a strike that made the girl, 10-year-old Tala Abu Ajwa, the latest child fatality in the ongoing war in Gaza that has killed tens of thousands.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She begged me and said, 'Please, Daddy, let me go out'. I felt sad because she wanted to play with the girls" in the neighbourhood, Hussam told AFP after the strike on Tuesday.</p>

<p>Upon hearing the blast he raced outside, but "when I reached the flat that had been bombed, I found her among the rubble", he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"I recognised her by her roller skates, the only thing that was visible."&nbsp;</p>

<p>Details of the strike were unclear.</p>

<p>A photograph of Tala has since circulated widely on social media, the skates with white velcro straps and pink wheels sticking out from underneath a white cloth covering her dead body.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Mass wartime displacement and destruction of schools have deprived children across the Gaza Strip of chances for recreation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>More than 70 percent of schools operated by the United Nations agency for Palestinian refugees, known as UNRWA, have been destroyed or damaged, agency chief Philippe Lazzarini said on X this week.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"The longer children stay out of school, the higher the risk of a lost generation, fuelling resentment &amp; extremism," Lazzarini said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"With no ceasefire, children are likely to fall prey to exploitation including child labour and recruitment into armed groups."&nbsp;</p>

<h2>'We don't want wars, Mum'</h2>

<p>For Tala, the problem was more basic: she simply did not like being cooped up indoors all the time, Hussam said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She was cheerful and always liked to laugh, and loved to get out of the house," he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She had lots of dreams. She was always asking me for lots of things and I responded to her requests. She told me. 'I want a pair of skates', so I brought them for her."&nbsp;</p>

<p>The war in Gaza was triggered by Hamas's attack on southern Israel on October 7 which resulted in the deaths of 1,205 people, mostly civilians and including hostages killed in captivity, according to an AFP tally based on Israeli official figures.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Of 251 hostages seized by Palestinian militants during the attack, 97 remain in Gaza including 33 the Israeli military says are dead.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Israel's retaliatory campaign against Hamas has killed at least 40,878 people in Gaza, according to the Hamas-run territory's health ministry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The UN rights office says most of the dead are women and children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Now that Tala is gone, her parents and brothers are left to marvel at their bad luck, with the strike landing during one of the rare occasions Hussam let one of his children go outside.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She used to say to me, 'Why don't we live like all the other children in the world? I wish we could live a peaceful life. We don't want wars, Mum. I've had enough of wars'," her mother, Umm Tala, recalled.&nbsp;</p>

<p>"She was one of the best pupils and she excelled, she was very intelligent. She used to say to me: 'I'd like to be able to go to the park and play.' She's dead and so are her wishes."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-09/mal67kpk_palestinian-roller-skating-girl_625x300_06_September_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>