<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 15:50:50 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/love-life-and-woman-math-of-a-31-year-old-unmarried-bengaluru-woman-6214384]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Opinion: Love, Life And Woman-Math Of A 31-Year-Old, Unmarried, Bengaluru Woman]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/opinion/love-life-and-woman-math-of-a-31-year-old-unmarried-bengaluru-woman-6214384]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 15:41:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[I've met lawyers and designers and writers and artists and technology brothers, and couples and divorcees and singles and weirdos and non-weirdos and what I'm learning is this: there is no right way to live.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Add image caption here" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nuf865_woman_625x300_29_July_24.jpg" title="Add image caption here" /></div>
</div>

<p>There comes a point in the life of every 30-something Indian woman where many interactions take the form of an explanation. The pressing issue to be addressed is this: "What's a brilliant girl like you doing single?"</p>

<h2><strong>30s, A Graveyard</strong></h2>

<p>You'd think the legalisation of homosexuality, new flourishing pockets of polyamory and open relationships, the fluidities in gender and sexuality and self-expression, would've dulled the kind of thinking that prompts people to ask such questions. But even the young and supposedly open-minded let slip their belief now and then that 30 is some kind of a graveyard, after which life either ends or is not as meaningful as it once was. A young man was recently telling our common friend about "a really old woman" he was lucky to have sex with. "She was, like, 31 or something, dude," he bragged, before realising his faux pas.</p>

<p>Another Gen-Z woman told me "I'll never be Gen-Z, no matter how hard I try". I wondered if the implication was that I was too old to be so online, or that I was not as good at it as she was, or that instead of being so up-to-date with memes and popular discourse, I should do something more age-appropriate. The internet is, after all, riddled with girl-math and boy-math-never woman-math.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But when you are content with your life and its discontents, you don't want to engage with anyone who doesn't get it. Especially when you can just write a column about it.</p>

<h2><strong>Young, Sweet Love</strong></h2>

<p>So, let me tell you (almost) everything: At the age of 29, I was in perhaps the best relationship of my life with a cool, caring and emotionally stable man I'd known for years, who had a family that I'd have been honoured to enter. Just a few weeks into our relationship, I knew that I should marry him, but by our two-year anniversary, when we were at a crossroads about what to do next, I felt I'd changed too much. "Settling down" suddenly seemed too distant from who I felt I was becoming, even though I'd been anxious to get married throughout my late twenties. Maybe it was distaste at having chased something so externally imposed that made me want to upend it, or maybe it was something deeper (it was definitely something deeper. My parents are divorced and my family is dysfunctional, and I have been subject to my own creative, destructive self-sabotage for a long time now).</p>

<p>Either way, I was trying to discard the imposed and honour the internal. My twenties had been driven by the need to succeed at every task thrown my way, despite familial troubles, all some form of survival disguised as decorum. But I now intended to live my many unlived lives: I moved out of our shared apartment into a one-bedroom flat-a veritable 'Room with a View'-in which I started writing more, painting for the first time, thinking and working fully without disruption. I loved my solitude, which also I'd never allowed myself, because even outside of your gender, living and doing things alone, and enjoying them no less, is considered 'weird' at best. I wanted to date freely and widely, to understand what really suited me, to devote more time to my many friendships, without romance or marriage becoming the fulcrum for the rest of my life. I'd seen much harm ensue from people doing things just because other people were doing them too.&nbsp;</p>

<p>I wanted to be a sovereign individual, in short.</p>

<h2><strong>I Now Understand Carrie Bradshaw</strong></h2>

<p>Favourable or not, this was the honest thing to do. From Virginia Woolf to Carrie Bradshaw - whose room with a view was in expensive New York City ( even in Bengaluru, I work multiple non-writing jobs to sustain my mostly modest lifestyle) &nbsp;- writers especially want this kind of solitary freedom. The first time I watched Sex and the City last year, however, just after I turned 30, my reaction to Carrie's life was not a kindred "I'm just like her fr". I was way more judgmental. Her initially crazy behaviour with Big notwithstanding, I thought her dresses were too floozy and her columns simplistic and her attitude too carefree-not dark and brooding and real, like mine-and her pursuits too meaningless. Going out every night, meeting new people, buying more shoes than she could afford... What kind of 30-year-old woman does that? She was being such a... girl... I realised, in horror.</p>

<p>She was being what I could never be at home, as the eldest daughter to perfectionistic Tamil Brahmin parents: unbothered, free, promiscuous, cute, silly, often stupid, at least financially, if not romantically too. She was being what I found it hard to be even now, due to both internal and external deterrents. Unlike in New York City, a Bangalorean landlady might still tell you things like "don't allow boys to enter for your own safety". When I told this woman that I had male friends, she asked me whether I was "really Brahmin". Another landlady flat out refused to rent to a single woman because "if something happened to me", she'd be responsible.</p>

<h2><strong>There Is No Right Way To Live</strong></h2>

<p>So, when you walk away from such well-trodden paths, the pressure to display satisfaction and success intensifies. Carrie was one of TV's first female protagonists to portray women as desiring beings, rather than just desired objects. She doesn't just take what she gets - not always; she tries to be a discerning customer, at least. And like her, despite choosing authenticity over safety, I too experience doubt. I might catch myself thinking like the 'society uncle and aunty', who'd wonder about how much money I'm making or how big my house is or how many followers I have or how likely I am to get married in the next few years. After all, what do I have to show for my deviance? &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>

<p>But if there's one thing I've learnt from my Robert Frost era, it discourages this kind of habitual comparative evaluation, normalised by the hypercompetitive Indian coming-of-age experience. I have to keep reminding myself of it, but the only lesson is this: There is No Right Way to Live.</p>

<h2><b>On Love And Lovers</b></h2>

<p>In just the past few weeks, as I was travelling through Goa and Kerala, I wondered sometimes what "settling down" might look for someone like me. I met people from, as ChatGPT might say, "all walks of life". It started with an old friend ringing to tell me he was back in the city, on a sort of a sabbatical, an unimaginable luxury for '90s Indian kids who were repeatedly asked to excel.&nbsp;</p>

<p>We spent the day yapping - if I may be so bold, my Gen-Z readers - and then met a few of his friends. The single ones chatted about how romance is irrevocably different in our 30s than in our 20s. It's less about giving into chemistry and more about overcoming the attachment styles and subconscious patterns that lead to exciting but otherwise unsuitable partners. Another was in an open relationship with her primary partner for nearly a decade, with girlfriends and boyfriends in other countries too. Another bemoaned his inability to fall in love after his most serious relationship ended badly. Another old friend texted me about the end of their marriage after years of being together.&nbsp;</p>

<p>From this colorful scene, my friend and I departed to meet two other friends, a married couple, who might be the poster child of the 'New-Indian-Happily-Married-Hindu' Family. Like the other couples I've hung out with of late, they too briefly made me long for the traditional monogamous setup. We talked until 3 am, and I woke up the next day to meet a friend I'd made in Goa. He'd moved there to "be more queer", after realising that the more metropolitan cities wouldn't offer him the life he wanted. We flirted with the idea of dating, but my now familiar commitment-phobia reared its head again. I was hardly out of a situationship with an ex who had once been a favourite, but was now completely wrong for me, thanks to chemistry coupled with traumatic highs and lows.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Talk about being romantically stupid, well past the age for it.</p>

<h2><strong>Who Doesn't Have 'Problems'?</strong></h2>

<p>Fortunately, it didn't take me long to forget about him, because I matched with interesting, desirable people on the multiple apps you can now be on-from Bumble and Hinge and Feeld to, yes, even... Shaadi.com. Many people find these platforms hellish, and I might too eventually, but if you're an anthropologist as I sometimes get to be, it's easier to trade outcomes for observations and stories. I'm still not sure what I want, but I've met a wildlife researcher whose first conversation with me included an image of a bear standing on one of his weighing scales. I've also met lawyers and designers and writers and artists and technology brothers, and couples and divorcees and singles and weirdos and non-weirdos - some chronically online and others not - and what I'm learning is something no relationship coach or matchmaker will ever tell me, but what feels most important to know: there is no right way to live.</p>

<p>No one seems objectively happier than the other. No one seems to not have any problems. Some of these problems are despite following the well-trodden path. Some of them are from walking away from it, understandably. A lot of problems come from wondering if the problems are even legitimate, and whether others could or would or should have them.</p>

<p>For now, I am here to confirm: they do have problems, and they're quite like yours, and you're okay.&nbsp;</p>

<p>And I'm okay too, I think.</p>

<p><em>(<a href="https://twitter.com/ramachandranesk">Sanjana Ramachandran</a>&nbsp;is a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ramachandranesk?utm_source=share&amp;utm_campaign=share_via&amp;utm_content=profile&amp;utm_medium=ios_app">writer and the founder</a>&nbsp;of storyfied.in, a marketing agency)</em></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer: These are the personal opinions of the author</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/1n9vmmng_woman_625x300_29_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-rail-network-telecoms-installations-attacked-in-france-amid-olympics-6214032]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[After Rail Network, Telecoms Installations Attacked In France Amid Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/after-rail-network-telecoms-installations-attacked-in-france-amid-olympics-6214032]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:57:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Telecom installations belonging to French companies SFR and Bouygues Telecom have been vandalised, reported Le Parisien newspaper and BFM TV on Monday, citing unnamed sources.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telecom installations belonging to French companies SFR and Bouygues Telecom have been vandalised, reported Le Parisien newspaper and BFM TV on Monday, citing unnamed sources.</p>

<p>SFR and Bouygues did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>

<p>The reports said cables in electrical cabinets had been cut in southern France, and that installations in the Meuse region near Luxembourg and the Oise area near Paris had been vandalised, affecting mainly fixed-line services.</p>

<p>Saboteurs targeted France's high-speed rail network on Friday with pre-dawn attacks on signal substations and cables, causing travel chaos hours before the opening ceremony of the Paris Olympics.</p>

<p>Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said that one far-left extremist had been arrested on Sunday in relation to the case.</p>

<p>Traffic only returned to normal Monday morning but only after some 800,000 people faced disruptions, including 100,000 people whose trains had to be cancelled outright.</p>

<p>The reports by Le Parisien and BFM TV did not state if there were any links between the vandalism on the telecom installations, and that earlier sabotage on the rail network.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2412vl2o_france-telecom-generic_625x300_29_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Reports said cables in electrical cabinets had been cut in southern France.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daughter-of-n-koreas-kim-jong-un-trained-as-future-leader-local-media-6213938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Kim Jong Un's Daughter Being Trained As Next North Korean Leader: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/daughter-of-n-koreas-kim-jong-un-trained-as-future-leader-local-media-6213938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:42:46 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The daughter of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un was being trained to become the next leader, Yonhap news agency reported on Monday, citing South Korea's spy agency.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The daughter of North Korean leader Kim Jong Un was being trained to become the next leader, Yonhap news agency reported on Monday, citing South Korea's spy agency.</p>

<p>North Korea's state media has reported on the public activities of Kim's daughter, Ju Ae, but not on her political future.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/uplbm0ho_kim-jong-un-with-daughter-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[North Korean leader Kim Jong Un and his daughter Kim Ju Ae (File photo)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/activist-arrested-in-french-rail-sabotage-case-before-paris-olympic-games-opening-6213877]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Activist Arrested In French Rail Sabotage Case Before Olympic Games Opening]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/activist-arrested-in-french-rail-sabotage-case-before-paris-olympic-games-opening-6213877]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:37:47 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A far-left activist has been arrested in connection with the sabotage attack on France's high-speed rail network last Friday, Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A far-left activist has been arrested in connection with the sabotage attack on France's high-speed rail network last Friday, Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said on Monday.</p>

<p>It is the first publicly announced arrest made since the sabotage attack, which took place on Friday hours before the Olympic Games opening ceremony got underway.</p>

<p>Earlier Monday, Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said that France suspects members of far-left groups were behind the sabotage of the country's high-speed rail network.</p>

<p>"We have identified the profiles of several people," Darmanin told France 2 TV, adding that the sabotage bore the hallmarks of far-left groups.</p>

<p>In recent years, France has been targeted in attacks by Islamist militants, but security services have been increasingly concerned about far-left or anarchist militants, who typically oppose the state and capitalism.</p>

<p>The then-head of France's domestic intelligence agency, Nicolas Lerner, told Le Monde newspaper last year French President Emmanuel Macron's divisive 2023 pension shake-up had helped lure recruits to far-left groups, which have increasingly incorporated ecological issues into their ideologies.</p>

<p>"In recent years, the far-left movements have been known for particularly violent clandestine actions, including arson campaigns ... ransacking and destruction of property," Lerner, who now leads the foreign spy agency DGSE, said in the interview.</p>

<p>In a 2023 report on terrorism trends, the European police agency Europol said left-wing and anarchist groups typically attacked "critical infrastructure, such as repeaters and antennas, government institutions and private companies" with their "most common modus operandi" being arson and improvised explosive devices.</p>

<p>Train services in France were back up and running by early Monday after teams worked around the clock over the weekend to fix the damage, Transport Minister Patrice Vergriete told RTL radio.</p>

<p>Vergriete said 800,000 people had faced travel disruptions and said the cost to the state-owned rail operator SNCF would be considerable.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/6qd1d4hg_french-rail-network_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-week-vegan-diet-linked-to-lower-biological-age-study-finds-6213680]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[8-Week Vegan Diet Linked To Lower Biological Age, Study Finds]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/8-week-vegan-diet-linked-to-lower-biological-age-study-finds-6213680]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:34:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Going vegan for eight weeks was found to be linked to lowering of biological age, according to a study published in the journal BioMed Central (BMC) Medicine.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going vegan for eight weeks was found to be linked to lowering of biological age, according to a study published in the journal BioMed Central (BMC) Medicine.</p>

<p>Researchers looked at the molecular effects of the plant-based diet that abstains from consuming animal food products, such as dairy. The diet largely includes eating fruits and vegetables, along with grains, beans and nuts.</p>

<p>The researchers, including those at Stanford University, US, found that consuming the plant-based diet was related with changes in how a gene expressed itself, or gene behaviour, without changing the DNA itself. Specifically, they looked at DNA methylation, known to be able to "turn off" or "silence" a gene, thereby not allowing it to express itself.</p>

<p>Higher levels of DNA methylation is associated with a higher biological age. It is one of the epigenetic processes, which affect the behaviour of a gene by altering its environment.</p>

<p>For eight weeks, the team followed 21 pairs of adult identical twins -- one half of each pair consumed an omnivorous diet, including meat, eggs and dairy, while the other consumed a vegan one. Identical twins share a significant amount of their genetic makeup.</p>

<p>On average, the participants were aged 40 years and had a body mass index (BMI) in the overweight category. About 77 per cent of the group were women.</p>

<p>After eight weeks, the researchers observed a 'younger' heart, liver, inflammatory and metabolic system among the participants consuming the vegan diet. These changes were not seen in those eating the omnivorous diet.</p>

<p>However, the authors cautioned that the extent to which these changes could be attributed to their diets was unclear.</p>

<p>They noted that on average, the individuals on the vegan diet lost two kilograms more compared to those on the omnivorous diet.</p>

<p>The results suggest that the weight loss could have contributed to lowering of the biological age in the vegan group, the researchers said.</p>

<p>Reacting to the study, Tom Sanders, a professor emeritus of Nutrition and Dietetics at King's College London, and not involved in the study, said that the findings might be favourable for vegans in terms of ageing.</p>

<p>However, the diet can come with micronutrient deficiencies, which often take years to exert harmful effects, Sanders said.</p>

<p>"For example, unless a vegan diet is supplemented with vitamin B12 they develop vitamin B12 deficiency that causes chronic and often insidious damage to the nervous system," Sanders said.</p>

<p>Long-term studies of vegans also find adverse effects on bone density, probably caused by very low calcium and barely adequate protein intakes, Sanders said.<br />
&nbsp;</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-06/im045hq8_vegan-diet_625x300_01_June_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Going vegan for eight weeks was found to be linked to lowering of biological age.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/steven-van-de-velde-dutch-volleyball-player-convicted-of-raping-a-minor-booed-at-paris-olympics-6213423]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Dutch Volleyball Player, Convicted Of Raping A Minor, Booed At Olympics]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/steven-van-de-velde-dutch-volleyball-player-convicted-of-raping-a-minor-booed-at-paris-olympics-6213423]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:38:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[In 2016, Steven Van de Velde was sentenced to four years in prison after admitting to three counts of rape involving a 12-year-old British girl.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dutch beach volleyball player Steven van de Velde, a convicted child rapist, was met with boos during his Olympic debut in Paris.</p>

<p>He was sentenced to four years in prison in 2016 after admitting to three counts of rape involving a 12-year-old British girl.</p>

<p>He met his victim on Facebook, travelled from Amsterdam to the UK in 2014, and raped her in Milton Keynes. Despite his sentence, he served only 12 months, sparking strong reactions from the public.</p>

<p>During the volleyball competition near the Eiffel Tower, Van de Velde and his teammate Matthew Immers played against the Italian pair Alex Ranghieri and Adrian Carambula.</p>

<p>When Van de Velde was introduced, he was greeted exclusively with boos.</p>

<p>The Dutch Olympic Committee maintains that Van de Velde has been successfully rehabilitated and deserves his place in the squad. However, Rape Crisis England &amp; Wales has called his inclusion at the Games "shocking."</p>

<p>The International Olympic Committee (IOC) has faced calls for an investigation into how a convicted child rapist has been allowed to compete at Paris 2024. Despite this, the IOC insists it has no plans to prevent the Dutchman from competing.</p>

<p>Dutch team spokesperson John van Vliet said the decision to shelter van de Velde was made by the National Olympic Committee and shared with the IOC. When asked if they were protecting a convicted child rapist, he responded, "We are protecting a convicted child rapist to do his sport as best as possible and for a tournament which he qualified for."</p>

<p>He recognised the gravity of sex-related crimes, saying they were a more significant concern than sport. Van de Velde has fulfilled all conditions to compete again after serving his sentence, he added.</p>

<p>Van de Velde is understood to be staying outside the Olympic Village at his request and will not participate in the usual post-match mixed zone interviews.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/lsvb4pmg_steven-van-de-velde_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Steven van de Velde with his Netherlands' teammate Matthew Immers during the Paris 2024 Olympic Games]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-train-services-resumed-3-days-after-arson-attacks-ahead-of-olympics-6213337]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[France Train Services Resume 3 Days After Arson Attacks Disrupted Travel]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/france-train-services-resumed-3-days-after-arson-attacks-ahead-of-olympics-6213337]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:28:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The attacks affected 800,000 travellers, but "in the end, 700,000 were able to make their trips" while 100,000 were hit by train cancellations.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>France's high-speed train network was back to normal on Monday, three days after coordinated acts of sabotage heavily disrupted travel before the Olympics opening ceremony, Transport Minister Patrice Vergriete said.</p>

<p>It remains unclear who carried out the three arson attacks on strategic points of the rail infrastructure early Friday, or if they were deliberately timed to disrupt the Games' opening spectacle later that day.</p>

<p>The network gradually returned to normal over the weekend following repairs.</p>

<p>"This morning, all trains are running," Vergriete told RTL radio.</p>

<p>The attacks affected 800,000 travellers, but "in the end, 700,000 were able to make their trips" while 100,000 were hit by train cancellations, he said.</p>

<p>Since the attacks, 50 drones, 250 rail security agents and 1,000 maintenance workers were deployed to tighten security along the 28,000-kilometre (17,400-mile) high-speed train network, the minister added.</p>

<p>The incident will likely cost millions of euros, Vergriete said.</p>

<p>Interior Minister Gerald Darmanin said authorities had "identified a certain number of profiles that could have committed" the acts of sabotage.</p>

<p>Far-left French anarchists have a history of targeting the train network with arson attacks.</p>

<p>The attacks were "deliberate, very precise, extremely well-targeted," Darmanin told France 2 television.</p>

<p>"This is the traditional type of action of the ultra-left," he said.</p>

<p>But asked whether the profiles that were identified were close to the far left, Darmanin said: "We must be cautious."</p>

<p>He said "The question is to know whether they were manipulated" or acted "for their own benefit".</p>

<p>"These are people who may be close to this movement," the interior minister added.</p>

<p>A statement signed by "an unexpected delegation" was sent to several news media outlets expressing support for the sabotage and criticising the Olympic Games as being a "celebration of nationalism" and the oppression of peoples by nation-states.</p>

<p>Darmanin said the statement was "something that resembles a claim", but "we must be careful because it could be an opportunistic claim".</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/nqd756tg_france-train-network-reuters_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[It remains unclear who carried out the three arson attacks on strategic points of the rail infrastructure]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keep-your-ring-us-woman-rejected-man-she-met-on-dating-app-he-killed-her-the-next-day-6213256]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Woman Rejected Man She Met On Dating App. He Killed Her The Next Day]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/keep-your-ring-us-woman-rejected-man-she-met-on-dating-app-he-killed-her-the-next-day-6213256]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:13:44 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Fabiola Thomas, 39, was discovered in a bathtub by her roommate in June 2019 in her Roswell, Ga., apartment.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Georgia man has been sentenced to life in prison for the 2019 murder of a woman he briefly met on a dating app, <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://people.com/woman-unfriended-man-then-he-murdered-her-8683696"><em>The People</em></a> reported.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Fabiola Thomas, 39, was discovered in a bathtub by her roommate in June 2019 in her Roswell, Ga., apartment, according to reports from <em>WSB-TV, 11 Alive, </em>and <em>FOX 5 Atlanta</em>.</p>

<p>Antonio Wilson, then 38, was arrested and charged with her murder months later, as reported by the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ajc.com/news/crime--law/man-charged-with-murder-death-roswell-woman-found-bathtub/nPIoQybamtbHNCtalSjIBM/"><em>Atlanta Journal-Constitution</em></a> and 11 Alive, citing Roswell Police.</p>

<p>The investigation began on June 8, 2019, when police received a frantic phone call from Ms Thomas' roommate, who reported finding her in the bathtub and feared "something bad had happened to her," according to FOX 5 Atlanta and 11 Alive.</p>

<p>Police found Ms Thomas unresponsive at the scene, and she was later pronounced dead at the hospital, as per FOX 5 Atlanta.</p>

<p>A medical examiner ruled her death a homicide several months later, according to FOX 5 Atlanta.</p>

<p>During the investigation, authorities discovered that Ms Thomas and Wilson had met on a dating app shortly before the murder, as reported by WSB-TV.</p>

<p>"Ms. Thomas did everything that you would think you should do," Assistant District Attorney Abigail Potter told WSB-TV. "She told her friends where she was going. She would only meet him in public places."</p>

<p>Prosecutors stated that when Ms Thomas expressed her desire to end the relationship, Wilson could not handle the rejection, according to WSB-TV.</p>

<p>In a text message sent before her death, Thomas asked Wilson to "stop claiming" her, authorities said.</p>

<p>"Keep your ring, I'm not your woman, never was, stop claiming me because I never claimed u," Ms Thomas wrote in a text, according to WSB-TV, citing prosecutors.</p>

<p>Senior Assistant District Attorney Nalda Charles told the outlet, that on the day she died, she 'unfriended'&nbsp;Wilson. It remains unclear which dating app they were using to communicate.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Wilson was arrested on October 25, 2019, after Ms Thomas' death was ruled a homicide. Five years later, following his trial, a jury took only 30 minutes to find him guilty, according to WSB-TV.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, July 23, a judge sentenced Wilson to life in prison without the possibility of parole for malice murder, as reported by WSB-TV from a Fulton County court.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3dt0udb_fabiola-thomas_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A medical examiner ruled her death a homicide several months later]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-loud-message-to-china-quad-says-no-country-should-dominate-others-6213172]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In Loud Message To China, Quad Says No Country Should "Dominate" Others]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-loud-message-to-china-quad-says-no-country-should-dominate-others-6213172]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 13:00:27 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The foreign ministers of the Quad countries -- S Jaishankar, US' Antony Blinken, Japan's Yoko Kamikawa, and Australia's Penny Wong -- met in Tokyo.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a loud and clear message to China, the Quad on Monday reaffirmed its steadfast commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific, vowing to work towards a region where no country dominates others and each state is free from coercion in all its forms.</p>

<p>At a meeting here, the foreign ministers of the Quad countries called for upholding the free and open rules-based international order and respecting the principle of freedom, human rights, democratic values, sovereignty and territorial integrity of nations.</p>

<p>Without directly naming China, the four foreign ministers expressed serious concern over the situation in the East and South China Seas and reiterated the Quad's strong opposition to any "unilateral actions that seek to change the status quo by force or coercion." The meeting was attended by External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar, US Secretary of State Antony Blinken, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoko Kamikawa and Australia's Penny Wong.</p>

<p>"All countries have a role in contributing to regional peace, stability, and prosperity while seeking a region in which no country dominates and no country is dominated, competition is managed responsibly, and each country is free from coercion in all its forms and can exercise its agency to determine its own future," the ministers said in the statement.</p>

<p>The Quad also vowed to work towards a free, open and prosperous Indo-Pacific, a region that has seen increasing Chinese military muscle-flexing in the last few years.</p>

<p>"We reaffirm the Quad's steadfast commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific, which is inclusive and resilient, and are united in our commitment to upholding the free and open rules-based international order, with its strong support for the principle of freedom, human rights, the rule of law, democratic values, sovereignty and territorial integrity, and peaceful settlement of disputes," the ministers said.</p>

<p>The ministers also referred to increasing Chinese manoeuvres in the South China Sea, especially the "dangerous use" of coast guard and maritime militia vessels.</p>

<p>"We continue to express our serious concern about the militarisation of disputed features, and coercive and intimidating manoeuvres in the South China Sea, " the joint statement said.</p>

<p>"We also express our serious concern about the dangerous use of coast guard and maritime militia vessels, the increasing use of various kinds of dangerous manoeuvres, and efforts to disrupt other countries' offshore resource exploitation activities," it said.</p>

<p>The ministers emphasised the importance of adherence to international law, particularly as reflected in the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), to address challenges to the global maritime rules-based order, including in the South and East China Seas.</p>

<p>The ministers also "unequivocally" condemned terrorism and violent extremism in all its forms including cross-border terrorism.</p>

<p>"We deplore the use of unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), drones, tunnels and information and communication technologies by terrorists and terrorist entities," they said.</p>

<p>"We strongly reiterate our condemnation of terrorist attacks, including the 26/11 Mumbai and Pathankot attacks and call for bringing the perpetrators of these attacks to justice without delay," they added.</p>

<p>The Quad urged all countries to take immediate, sustained and irreversible action to prevent territory under their control from being used for terrorist purposes.</p>

<p>"We are committed to working together to promote accountability for the perpetrators of terrorist attacks and support implementation including through domestic designations of UN Security Council resolutions as they pertain to sanctions," the ministers said.</p>

<p>"We reiterate the call for concerted action against all UN-listed terrorist groups including Al-Qa'ida, ISIS/Daesh, Lashkar e-Tayyiba (LeT), Jaish-e-Mohammad (JeM), and their proxy groups," they said.</p>

<p>The ministers said the Quad is committed to international cooperation and working together with our international and regional partners in a comprehensive and sustained manner to strengthen their capacity to prevent, detect and respond to threats posed by terrorism and violent extremism. PTI MPB NSA AKJ NSA NSA</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/2917iot_quad-_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The foreign ministers of the Quad countries met in Tokyo]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-airlines-flight-diverted-over-biohazard-scare-crew-is-vomiting-6212890]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Crew Is Vomiting": United Airlines Flight Diverted Over "Biohazard" Scare]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/united-airlines-flight-diverted-over-biohazard-scare-crew-is-vomiting-6212890]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 12:31:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A United Airlines flight bound for Boston from Houston was forced to divert to Washington DC over a "biohazard" situation connected to a passenger that left crew members vomiting and other fliers onboard in distress.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A United Airlines flight bound for Boston from Houston was forced to divert to Washington DC over a "biohazard" situation connected to a passenger that left crew members vomiting and other fliers onboard in distress.</p>

<p>The United Airlines flight UA2477 (Boeing 737-800) operating from Houston George Bush Intercontinental Airport to Boston was diverted to the Dulles International Airport in Washington DC on July 28, the New York Post reported citing the airline.</p>

<p>The flight was cut short and forced to land at Dulles Airport, Washington DC to undergo a "deep clean", according to the airline.</p>

<p>The conversation between the captain and the air traffic control indicated a distressing situation in mid-air.</p>

<p>"I talked to the crew and it sounds like it's quite bad back there. The crew is vomiting, and passengers all around are asking for masks," a crew member was heard saying in audio from the flight as cited in the New York Post report.</p>

<p>The plane landed safely at Washington Dulles Airport, where none of the plane's 155 passengers or its six crew members required medical help, the US publication said.</p>

<p>"The aircraft is currently undergoing a deep clean and we are working to get customers on their way to Boston soon," the airline said.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-01/88lc6k88_united-airlines-plane_625x300_11_January_24.png' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The conversation between captain and air traffic control indicated a distressing situation in mid-air.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drew-kohn-florida-man-who-woke-up-from-244-day-coma-killed-by-pickup-truck-6212587]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Florida Man, Who Woke Up From 244-Day Coma, Killed By Pickup Truck]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/drew-kohn-florida-man-who-woke-up-from-244-day-coma-killed-by-pickup-truck-6212587]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 12:10:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A 30-year-old Florida man, who miraculously survived a 244-day coma after a motorcycle crash years ago, was killed in another accident last week, reported WLTV News.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 30-year-old Florida man, who miraculously survived a 244-day coma after a motorcycle crash years ago, was killed in another accident last week, reported <a href="https://www.firstcoastnews.com/article/news/local/drew-kohn-hit-and-killed-by-a-truck/77-c5f5a411-f7a0-4664-824a-e8b35f58eb33 ">WLTV News</a>.</p>

<p>Drew Kohn was 22 years old when he was involved in the crash in 2017, which left him with a traumatic brain injury and in a deep coma. At one point, his condition was so severe that doctors considered harvesting his organs, but his mother, Yolanda Osborne-Kohn, refused to give up hope.</p>

<p>Mr Kohn's mother recalled the miraculous moment her son first spoke to her after his long coma. "Yeah Mom, I'm OK," he said. "I love you, mom." After years of gruelling rehab, Mr Kohn managed to walk again, earning him the title of "modern-day miracle".</p>

<p>Mr Kohn eventually woke up after eight months and began the long recovery process. However, his life was cut short when he was struck and killed by a pickup truck on July 26.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the Jacksonville Sheriff's Office, Mr Kohn was walking on Collins Road in Jacksonville around 5:30 am on Friday when the accident occurred. The driver, who claimed not to have seen the victim, pulled over and called 911, but Mr Kohn was pronounced dead at the scene.</p>

<p>His mother said she was grateful for the seven extra years she had with her son. "I'm grateful for the borrowed time I had with him," she said. "God honoured my request, and I'm not mad. I'm not angry. I'm at peace," she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Ms Osborne-Kohn reflected on the moment she surrendered her son's fate to God, recalling a moment when she sat on his hospital bed and prayed, "Thy will be done."</p>

<p>She believes her son is now in a better place, free from suffering and pain. "Drew is healed, walking, not struggling to keep his balance," she said. "His arm is probably lifted so high saying 'Thank you, Jesus!' Drew probably has a football in one hand and a Bible in the other."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/7v6hv3ag_drew-kohn-florida-man-gofundme_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Drew Kohn was 22 years old when he was involved in the crash in 2017.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-still-driving-high-mortality-rate-in-this-country-6212442]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Covid-19 Still Driving High Mortality Rate In This Country]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/covid-19-still-driving-high-mortality-rate-in-this-country-6212442]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 11:12:59 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Experts measured the number of people who had died as a direct or indirect result of Covid and found the excess mortality rate was still higher than pre-pandemic levels.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Covid-19 is still driving Australia's above-average mortality rate, research showed on Monday, with experts predicting the disease's impact will continue to be felt for years to come.</p>

<p>The Australian Actuaries Institute found that five per cent more people died than would be expected in 2023, amounting to 8,400 excess deaths.</p>

<p>Experts measured the number of people who had died as a direct or indirect result of Covid and found the excess mortality rate was still higher than pre-pandemic levels.</p>

<p>About 4,600 deaths were directly attributed to Covid-19, the ninth leading cause of death last year.</p>

<p>Non-Covid-19 excess deaths, meanwhile, were "particularly apparent" in Australians over 75 years old -- with previous infections and interruptions in healthcare related to Covid increasing risks related to heart disease, stroke, diabetes and dementia.</p>

<p>Delays in routine or emergency care and undiagnosed Covid-19 were cited as possible reasons for the higher-than-usual death rate.</p>

<p>Still, the excess mortality rate was lower in 2023 than it was in 2022, according to experts.</p>

<p>"It's encouraging that each successive Covid-19 wave has, so far, resulted in fewer deaths than the previous one," Actuary Institute spokeswoman Karen Cutter said.</p>

<p>"However, we think that Covid-19 is likely to cause some excess mortality for several years to come, either as a direct cause of death or a contributing factor to other causes such as heart disease."</p>

<p>She added the "new normal" level of mortality was likely higher than it would be had the pandemic not occurred.</p>

<p>The report also found Australia's excess mortality was lower than the global average -- with Ecuador, Mexico and Russia showing the highest rates of unexplained deaths.</p>

<p>New Zealand had the lowest excess mortality rate of the 40 countries for which data was available.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/s3j9rvj_hospital-generic-_625x300_29_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nicolas-maduro-venezuela-elections-venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-wins-reelection-with-51-2-of-vote-6212225]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Venezuela President Nicolas Maduro Wins Reelection, Gets 51.2% Of Votes]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/nicolas-maduro-venezuela-elections-venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-wins-reelection-with-51-2-of-vote-6212225]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 10:38:19 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro won reelection with 51.2 per cent of votes cast Sunday, the electoral council announced, after a campaign tainted by claims of opposition intimidation and fears of fraud.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venezuela's President Nicolas Maduro won reelection with 51.2 per cent of votes cast Sunday, the electoral council announced, after a campaign tainted by claims of opposition intimidation and fears of fraud.</p>

<p>Elvis Amoroso, president of the CNE electoral body, in its majority loyal to the government, told reporters that 44.2 per cent of votes had gone to opposition candidate Edmundo Gonzalez Urrutia who had been leading in polls.</p>

<p>Maduro, 61, won a third six-year term at the helm of the once wealthy petro-state where GDP dropped by 80 per cent in a decade, pushing more than seven million of its 30 million citizens to emigrate.</p>

<p>In office since 2013, he is accused of locking up critics and harassing the opposition in a climate of rising authoritarianism.</p>

<p>Independent polls had suggested Sunday's vote could bring an end to 25 years of "Chavismo," the populist movement founded by Maduro's socialist predecessor and mentor, the late Hugo Chavez.</p>

<p>Gonzalez Urrutia replaced popular opposition leader Maria Corina Machado on the ticket after authorities loyal to Maduro excluded her from the race.</p>

<p>Machado, who campaigned far and wide for her proxy, urged voters late Sunday to keep "vigil" at their polling stations in the "decisive hours" of counting amid widespread fears of fraud.</p>

<p>Maduro counts on a loyal electoral apparatus, military leadership and state institutions in a system of well-established political patronage.</p>

<p>Sunday's election was the product of a mediated deal reached last year between the government and the opposition.</p>

<p>The agreement led the United States to temporarily ease sanctions imposed after Maduro's 2018 reelection, which was rejected as a sham by dozens of Western and Latin American countries.</p>

<p>But the sanctions were snapped back after Maduro reneged on the agreed condition</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/3pufr8eg_venezuela-president-nicolas-maduro-reuters-_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Venzuela's Nicolas Maduro won a third six-year term this time.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/megyn-kelly-journalist-slams-jennifer-aniston-amid-jd-vances-childless-cat-ladies-row-6212215]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Journalist Slams Jennifer Aniston Amid JD Vance's "Childless Cat Ladies" Row]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/megyn-kelly-journalist-slams-jennifer-aniston-amid-jd-vances-childless-cat-ladies-row-6212215]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 10:33:57 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Megyn Kelly accused the actress of being hypocritical for not speaking out against gender ideology and transgender issues.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>US journalist Megyn Kelly has defended JD Vance, the Republican nominee for Vice President, and slammed actor Jennifer Aniston after she criticised his comments on childless women.</p>

<p>The controversy stems from a 2021 Fox News interview in which Vance stated that “childless cat ladies,” including politicians like Kamala Harris, the Democrat running for the White House, have no “direct stake” in the country.</p>

<p>The comment recently resurfaced, drawing a sharp rebuke from Aniston.</p>

<p>Aniston, who has been vocal about her struggles with infertility, <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/jennifer-aniston-slams-donald-trumps-running-mate-jd-vance-over-childless-cat-ladies-remark-6191543">responded to Vance's remarks</a> by sharing a screenshot of the interview on Instagram. In her post, she mentioned Vance's 2-year-old daughter, saying she hopes the child will be able to have children of her own one day and won't need to rely on IVF, a service Vance has opposed in legislation. “I hope she will not need to turn to IVF as a second option because you are trying to take that away from her, too,” the <em>Friends </em>star wrote.</p>

<p>Megyn Kelly, a former Fox News host, has now slammed the actress for her response.</p>

<p>“Well, now, all this s*** has run, has rained down on him like he hates women and he hates people who have no children, and that's not true,” Kelly said.</p>

<p>However, Vance's record suggests otherwise. In June, he voted against the Right to IVF Act, which would have protected the accessibility and affordability of IVF services across the US.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C926AQhOF-V/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C926AQhOF-V/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C926AQhOF-V/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C926AQhOF-V/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by The Megyn Kelly Show (@megynkellyshow)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Kelly also accused the actress of being hypocritical for not speaking out against gender ideology and transgender issues.</p>

<p>She asked where Aniston was when it came to standing up for little girls who were "getting their breasts chopped off" for political purposes by people who were "shoving this gender ideology down their throats without figuring out that they might just be temporarily depressed" or being forced to compete against boys in high school sports, which left them "partially paralysed and permanent nerve damage."</p>

<p>Kelly further criticised Aniston for her selective activism, saying she was happy to see Aniston on board with women's rights but didn't see her actively engaged on these specific issues before.<br />
<br />
<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/disgusting-jd-vance-slams-jennifer-anistons-remarks-on-his-daughter-6206824">JD Vance also responded to Aniston's criticism</a>, calling her comments "disgusting". He pointed out his daughter was only two years old, and if she were to face fertility issues in the future, he “would try everything I could to try to help her because I believe families and babies are a good thing.”<br />
<br />
Vance also clarified his previous “childless cat ladies” remark, explaining it was meant to be sarcastic and not taken literally. He said people were focusing on the tone rather than the substance of his argument and reiterated that his criticism was aimed at the Democratic Party for becoming anti-family and anti-child, not “about criticising people who, for various reasons, don't have kids."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://i.ndtvimg.com/i/2016-03/megyn-kelly_650x400_71458369714.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Megyn Kelly accused the actress of being hypocritical (File photo)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-supports-kamala-harris-im-right-in-1-000-in-for-her-6212050]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Right In 1,000% In For Her" :Salman Rushdie Supports Kamala Harris]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/salman-rushdie-supports-kamala-harris-im-right-in-1-000-in-for-her-6212050]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 10:05:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Mumbai-born author Salman Rushdie has endorsed Kamala Harris's candidacy for the US presidency and said he believes she is the person who can prevent former president Donald Trump from dragging the country towards authoritarianism.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mumbai-born author Salman Rushdie has endorsed Kamala Harris's candidacy for the US presidency and said he believes she is the person who can prevent former president Donald Trump from dragging the country towards authoritarianism.</p>

<p>Rushdie on Sunday extended his support and endorsement of US Vice President Harris during a virtual 'South Asian Men for Harris' event attended by scores of leading names from the Indian-American community, including prominent lawmakers, authors, policy experts, entrepreneurs and diaspora organisations.</p>

<p>"It's a critical moment. I'm a boy from Bombay and it's great to see an Indian woman running for the White House. And my wife is African-American, so we like the fact that a Black and Indian woman is running for the White House," Rushdie said.</p>

<p>Harris, 59, is the presumptive presidential nominee of the Democratic Party. She officially declared her candidacy after incumbent President Joe Biden withdrew from the race for a second term on July 20. She is expected to be officially declared as the presidential candidate by the Democrats next month.</p>

<p>The 77-year-old British-American novelist also noted that ethnicity itself is not enough. "We would not be gathering in this way let's say for Usha Vance or Nikki Haley," he said, referring to the Indian-American wife of Republican Vice Presidential nominee J D Vance and the Indian-American former South Carolina governor.</p>

<p>Rushdie emphasised that the momentum is because something "very extraordinary, transformative has happened in American politics" in just under one week.</p>

<p>"The conversation has entirely changed with the arrival of Kamala Harris's candidacy and it's changed most joyfully, a way of optimism and positive, forward-thinking," he said.</p>

<p>Rushdie underscored that the community has to make that work because "we can't allow the alternative to happen".</p>

<p>"This hollow man without a single noble quality, trying to drag this country towards authoritarianism. That cannot happen," he said, referring to 78-year-old Trump, a Republican.</p>

<p>Rushdie voiced his confidence that Harris "is the person who can prevent it. And so I'm right in 1,000 per cent in for her." He added that star power matters in America and one could argue that Trump's celebrity status from being on TV for many years helped him get elected to the White House in 2016.</p>

<p>"Well, right now, he doesn't look like the star. He looks like the old, fat guy. Kamala looks like the superstar. And I think the charisma she brings to the campaign could be critical in the weeks ahead," he said.</p>

<p>In response to a question that there are sceptics in the country who believe that America would not elect a woman with Black and Indian heritage as President, Rushdie said this may well have been an argument even as recently as maybe a decade but the times have changed.</p>

<p>"I think the way in which women's leadership is viewed now is different. The way in which the race issue can be made a positive is a new thing. And so I think there's absolutely no reason why Kamala Harris should not win and actually win it quite handily," Rushdie said.</p>

<p>Underlining that the tide is turning, Rushdie cited recent media polls that put Harris neck and neck with Trump, "which is a pretty big bounce from the last Biden poll".</p>

<p>"And it's not even a week. We can do this. We just have to believe it." Rushdie called on people across the country, including the writer community, to "use every power we have, whether it's speaking out, writing, arguing, we've got to win this argument. And writers are pretty good at arguing. So I think we're going to do our best." Noting that the November 5 presidential election is just 100 days away, Rushdie said: "There's not a minute to lose," as he urged "aunties" and extended families to mobilise and come out and vote in large numbers for Harris.</p>

<p>With communities ranging from South Asian to Indo-Carribean coming together and galvanising for Harris, Rushdie described their support as very moving.</p>

<p>"It's moving in the way that in recent days these great assemblies of people have been moving. The gathering of Black women, the gathering of White women, the gathering of Asian women, and now this event. It just shows that there is enormous power in our coming together," he said.</p>

<p>Rushdie underscored that "we cannot be complacent. We have to fight this down to the wire because it's probably going to go down to the wire, but that doesn't mean we can't be the first pass the post. I believe we can".</p>

<p>The event called on all South Asian men and women to rally, fundraise and get out to vote for "our first female president, Kamala Harris!" The event, co-hosted by CEO and Co-founder of full-service digital agency Digimentors Sree Sreenivasan, featured prominent names including Congressman Raja Krishnamoorthi from Illinois, co-founder of South Asians for Harris Harini Krishnan and Montgomery County Commissioner Neil Makhija.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/l7uh8lfo_kamala-harris-salman-rushdie-_625x300_29_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Salman Rushdie extended his support for Kamala Harris during a virtual 'South Asian Men for Harris' event]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-alleges-google-interfering-with-us-presidential-election-6211949]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk Claims Google Placed Search Ban On Donald Trump]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musk-alleges-google-interfering-with-us-presidential-election-6211949]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 09:54:56 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk on Monday attacked Sundar Pichai-run Google, saying if the search giant is interfering with the US Presidential election, they are going to face "a lot of trouble".]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk on Monday attacked Sundar Pichai-run Google, saying if the search giant is interfering with the US Presidential election, they are going to face "a lot of trouble".</p>

<p>Sharing a screenshot where a Google search on “president Donald” resulted in “president Donald Duck” and “president Donald Regan,” the tech billionaire asked if the tech giant has placed a search ban on the former US president and Republican presidential nominee.</p>

<p>“Wow, Google has a search ban on President Donald Trump! Election interference?” asked the X owner.</p>

<p>Musk further said Google is “getting themselves into a lot of trouble if they interfere with the election”.</p>

<p>An X user posted that “Google is owned by Democrats”.</p>

<p>Another Musk follower commented: “Elon, I'm sure they'll claim you're suppressing the Democrats, but my algorithm shows me both parties posting their thoughts and opinions. Under the previous management, anyone who didn't share the same views as the left was limited or banned”.</p>

<p>However, some X users also slammed Musk, saying “You have a search ban on so many accounts you don't like. What's the difference?”</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the presidential race between Kamala Harris and Trump is incredibly close, according to a new media poll, revealing a surge in support for Harris among non-white voters and a significant rise in enthusiasm among Democrats for her campaign.</p>

<p>Trump maintains a slight lead, garnering 49 per cent of the vote compared to 47 per cent for Harris, according to the Wall Street Journal poll.</p><p><i>(This story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is auto-generated from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-02/frr9q5p_elon-musk-reuters_625x300_02_February_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Elon Musk said Google has a search ban on President Donald Trump.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-praises-us-secret-service-agent-amid-criticism-so-brave-6212001]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["She Got Crushed": Trump Defends Secret Service Agent Amid Criticism]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-praises-us-secret-service-agent-amid-criticism-so-brave-6212001]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 09:54:40 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Former US President Donald Trump has praised the woman Secret Service agent for protecting him during an assassination attempt on him at a Pennsylvania rally.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Former US President <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/trump-calls-kamala-harris-crazy-liberal-she-calls-out-his-wild-lies-6206955" target="_blank">Donald Trump</a> has praised the woman Secret Service agent for protecting him during an assassination attempt on him at a Pennsylvania rally.</p>

<p>His remarks came days after female US Secret Service agents, who were on stage with Trump during the shooting at his rally on July 13, were criticized for not "properly" protecting someone bigger and taller than themselves, and for not acting in a "professional manner".</p>

<p>"Beautiful person - she was shielding me, everything she could. And she got crushed. And she got criticized by the fake news because she wasn't tall enough," Trump told his supporters at a Minnesota rally on Sunday, Fox News reported.</p>

<p>"Well, you know, she wasn't tall enough. Because I'm tall, and she wasn't tall enough. And she was criticized - she was so brave, she was shielding me with everything, and she wanted to take a bullet because the bullets were flying. Incredible," the Republican presidential candidate was quoted as saying by Fox News.</p>

<p>He called her "so brave" and said she "wanted to take a bullet" for him.</p>

<p>The <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-says-he-refused-to-be-put-on-stretcher-after-shooting-reveals-why-6169675" target="_blank">Secret Service</a>, which is responsible for the protection of current and former US presidents, was under fire after a gunman, identified as 20-year-old nursing home aide Thomas Crooks, opened first at Trump from a roof overlooking the outdoor rally in Butler.</p>

<p>He was shot dead by Secret Service snipers shortly after his bullet injured Trump's right ear.</p>

<p>Secret Service Director <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-secret-service-director-quits-days-after-shooting-at-trumps-rally-6172169" target="_blank">Kimberly Cheatle</a> last week resigned after the agency failed to stop the would-be assassin from wounding Trump.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/5vb5dgi8_donald-trump-_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-on-brink-of-all-out-war-after-12-children-die-in-rocket-strike-6211901]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israel, Hezbollah On Brink Of All-Out War After 12 Die In Rocket Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hezbollah-on-brink-of-all-out-war-after-12-children-die-in-rocket-strike-6211901]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 09:33:51 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israel attacked Hezbollah targets and threatened further retaliation for a rocket strike that resulted in the death of 12. But Israel has also signaled openness to a proposed Gaza truce that could also calm the combustible front with Lebanon.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ol>
	<li>In the worst single-incident of civilian losses for Israel since Hamas stormed into its southern villages and army bases on October 7, a rocket exploded in Golan Heights on Saturday, killing 12.</li>
	<li>The rocket strike hit a football pitch and killed children who local authorities said were aged 10 to 16.</li>
	<li>While Israel claims Hezbollah fired a Falaq-1 Iranian rocket at them, the Iran-backed group said it had "no connection" to the incident. The rocket strike has raised fears of a wider conflict between Israel and Hezbollah.</li>
	<li>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has vowed to exact a "heavy price" from Hezbollah. He has held several meeting with his security cabinet and military chiefs to decide on the next course of action. &nbsp;</li>
	<li>The US has condemned the rocket attack and called for restraint from all parties.</li>
	<li>But Iran issued a warning saying that any new military "adventures" by Israel in Lebanon could lead to "unforeseen consequences".</li>
	<li>Israel says it can't compromise with enemies sworn to its destruction and blacklisted as terrorists in the West. But domestic pressure for a hostage recovery is growing, and the IDF, which leans on conscripts and reservists, is fatigued.</li>
	<li>Reports state that some senior officials within Israel are in favour of a ceasefire within Gaza, after which Hezbollah has assured to not attack Israel.</li>
	<li>Israel launched its war against Hamas after the October 7 attacks in which 1,200 people in southern Israel were killed and 250 taken hostage to Gaza. The Hamas-run health ministry in Gaza says the death toll in Gaza has exceeded 39,000.</li>
	<li>Hezbollah is far stronger than Hamas was before October 7, with more fighters, missiles and drones. A war would probably be devastating for both Lebanon and Israel, officials from both countries have said.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8g6eak2s_israel-hezbollah-getty_625x300_29_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-6-injured-in-mass-shooting-at-park-in-new-york-report-6211377]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[1 Killed, 6 Injured In Mass Shooting At Park In New York: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/1-killed-6-injured-in-mass-shooting-at-park-in-new-york-report-6211377]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 07:19:41 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[At least one person has been killed and six have been injured following a mass shooting at a park in New York's Rochester city today, according to local media.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At least one person has been killed and six have been injured following a mass shooting at a park in New York's Rochester city today, according to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.rochesterfirst.com/news/large-police-presence-in-maplewood-park/">local media</a>.</p>

<p>According to the Rochester police, they went to the Maplewood Park around 6:20 pm, responding to the report of a large gathering with shots fired, and found several people suffering from gunshot wounds and a large group of people fleeing from the scene.</p>

<p>According to the police, a 20-year-old died, and another is in a life-threatening condition. Five people have been hospitalised with "relatively minor injuries".</p>

<p>Police said some people were transported to the hospital by private vehicles through the night and others by ambulance.</p>

<p>The identity of the victim who was shot dead has not yet been released.</p>

<p>Several police agencies responded to the incident including the Irondequoit Police, Monroe County Sheriffs, Rochester Police and New York State Police.&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2023-07/6835sp0g_us-police-generic_625x300_27_July_23.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-he-offered-joe-biden-1-million-to-play-golf-he-rejected-6211375]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Donald Trump Claims Joe Biden Rejected $1 Million Offer To Play Golf]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/donald-trump-claims-he-offered-joe-biden-1-million-to-play-golf-he-rejected-6211375]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 29 Jul 2024 07:17:16 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA["They talk a good game, but it's all talk," Mr Trump said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald Trump recently revealed that he once offered United States President Joe Biden $1 million if he could "he could break 100 in a game of golf." The former President was speaking at a rally in St Cloud, Minnesota. "I said I will take you to any course you want...I would give you $1 million if you could break 100 in a game of golf," Mr Trump told the audience. He continued, "He turned me down."</p>

<p>The real estate tycoon added that he changed his offer. "Then I said, I'll give you ten strokes a side...I'll give you one million dollars if you could beat me. He had no chance," he stated. "They talk a good game, but it's all talk," Mr Trump added.</p>

<p>Watch the video below:</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Donald Trump talks about his video playing golf with <a href="https://twitter.com/b_dechambeau?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@b_dechambeau</a> Trending #1 on YouTube and then brings up how Joe Biden challenged him to a round of golf but then chickened out. <a href="https://t.co/ualDgiNa1O">pic.twitter.com/ualDgiNa1O</a></p>
— ALX ?? (@alx) <a href="https://twitter.com/alx/status/1817371468730159526?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 28, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Notably, the discussion around golf began early in June, during Mr Biden and Mr Trump's first presidential debate. Mr Trump said that he had won two club championships and two regular club crowns, despite doubts about his age and level of physical fitness. He claimed that to do so, one must be "very smart" and capable of long-range hitting. "I just won two club championships - not even senior. Two regular club championships. To do that, you have to be quite smart, and you have to be able to hit the ball a long way. He doesn't do it. He can't hit a ball 50 yards. He challenged me to a golf match; he can't hit a ball 50 yards," he said.</p>

<p>Responding to the same, Mr Biden said, "I'd be happy to have a driving contest. I got my handicap when I was vice president down to a six. By the way, I told you before, I'm happy to play golf with you if you carry your own bag. Think you can do it?"</p>

<p>The 45th President of the US then went on to mock Mr Biden and said that it was a "lie." "That's the biggest lie - that he was a six handicap - of all," he said.</p>

<p>When confronted, Mr Biden withdrew his statement and admitted that he was actually eight handicap. However, Mr Trump did not take his remarks at their value and said, "I've seen your swing. I know your swing. Let's not act like children."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/8bbas48_donald-trump-joe-biden_625x300_11_July_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[US President Joe Biden ended his re-election campaign on July 21.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>