<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:media='http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/'>
<channel>
   <title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
   <link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
   <lastBuildDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 16:32:13 +0530]]></lastBuildDate>
<language>en</language>	<image>
	<title>NDTV News-World-news</title>
	<url>https://www.ndtv.com/common/header/images/ndtv_logo_black.gif</url>
	<link>https://www.ndtv.com</link>
	</image>
<description>NDTV.com provides the latest information from and in-depth coverage of India and the world. Find breaking news, India news, top stories, elections, politics, business, cricket, movies, lifestyle, health, live TV, videos, photos and more.</description>   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-minister-arrested-for-taking-bribe-worth-half-a-million-dollars-6319905]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Ukrainian Minister Arrested For Taking Bribe Worth Half A Million Dollars]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/ukrainian-minister-arrested-for-taking-bribe-worth-half-a-million-dollars-6319905]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:37:22 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Ukrainian deputy energy minister accused of taking a bribe worth half a million dollars has been arrested along with three alleged accomplices, Ukraine's SBU Security Service said on Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Ukrainian deputy energy minister accused of taking a bribe worth half a million dollars has been arrested along with three alleged accomplices, Ukraine's SBU Security Service said on Monday.</p>

<p>The minister, whom the SBU did not name, allegedly demanded mining industry officials pay him to transfer equipment from mines in the frontline eastern Donetsk region to a coal basin in western Ukraine.</p>

<p>"The equipment in question is unique and scarce, belonging to one of the state-owned coal companies located in the most active area of the eastern frontline -- Pokrovsk," the SBU said in a statement.</p>

<p>"In the spring of 2024, industry representatives approached the deputy energy minister to obtain permission to evacuate the equipment from the war zone and use it at mines in a western region," it added.</p>

<p>"However, the official, whose duties included the preservation of mining equipment, demanded money for its removal," it said.</p>

<p>The minister took the payment with the help of three alleged accomplices, all of whom were caught "red handed" after the minister had received part of the bribe, according to the statement.</p>

<p>The SBU did not disclose the identity of the four accused, posting photos of its officers arresting the suspects with their faces blurred.</p>

<p>But Ukrainian opposition MP Yaroslav Zheleznyak named the minister as Oleksandr Kheilo, a deputy energy minister.</p>

<p>Ukraine's Cabinet of Ministers later issued an order to dismiss Kheilo from his post, according to a government Telegram channel.</p>

<p>Ukraine, which had severe corruption problems even before Russia's 2022 invasion, has pledged to bolster efforts to combat graft as it seeks EU membership and to reassure its Western military backers.</p>

<p>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky rose to power on a platform of ending corruption, and has fired a number of officials including his defence minister last year over graft scandals in the army.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/dq44jp2o_russiaukraine-war_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The minister took the payment with the help of three alleged accomplices (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/javad-zarif-iran-presidents-deputy-quits-days-after-assuming-charge-6319847]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["I'm Ashamed...": Iran President's Deputy Quits Days After Assuming Charge]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/javad-zarif-iran-presidents-deputy-quits-days-after-assuming-charge-6319847]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:30:14 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Iran's former foreign minister Javad Zarif, who negotiated a landmark 2015 nuclear deal with major world powers, on Monday announced he had resigned from his new post as vice president.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran's former foreign minister Javad Zarif, who negotiated a landmark 2015 nuclear deal with major world powers, on Monday announced he had resigned from his new post as vice president.</p>

<p>"I resigned from the position of vice president for strategic affairs last week," Zarif said in a post on X, less than two weeks after the newly-elected reformist President Masoud Pezeshkian chose him as his deputy.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="rtl" lang="fa">سلام بر مردم بزرگوار ایران<br />
پیام دیشب بنده به‌معنای پشیمانی و یا ناامیدی از دکتر پزشکیان عزیز و یا مخالفت با واقع‌گرایی نیست؛ بلکه به معنای تردید در مفید بودن خودم در معاونت راهبردی است.<br />
البته برخی مردودین از جانب مردم، با تفسیر عجیبی از قانون مصوب 1401، اشتغال بنده در مشاغل حساس… <a href="https://t.co/OtLynZe4DH">pic.twitter.com/OtLynZe4DH</a></p>
— Javad Zarif (@JZarif) <a href="https://twitter.com/JZarif/status/1822886072612696187?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Zarif cited several reasons for his resignation, most notably his disappointment with the line-up in the newly proposed 19-member cabinet.</p>

<p>"I am ashamed that I could not implement, in a decent way, the expert opinion of the committees (responsible for selecting candidates) and achieve the inclusion of women, youth and ethnic groups, as I had promised," he said.</p>

<p>Pezeshkian on Sunday presented his cabinet, which included one woman, to parliament for approval.</p>

<p>The proposed list drew criticism from some among Iran's reformist camp, including over the inclusion of conservatives from the government of late President Ebrahim Raisi.</p>

<p>Zarif pointed out that he also faced pressure after his appointment as vice president because his children hold US citizenship.</p>

<p>"My message... is not a sign of regret or disappointment with dear Dr Pezeshkian or opposition to realism; rather it means doubting my usefulness as a vice-president for strategic affairs," he said, noting he would return to academia and focus less on Iran's domestic politics.</p>

<p>Zarif, who was Iran's top diplomat between 2013 and 2021 in the government of moderate president Hassan Rouhani, became known on the international stage during the lengthy negotiations for the 2015 accord formally known as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action.</p>

<p>The deal was effectively torpedoed three years later when then-president Donald Trump pulled the United States out of the deal and reimposed crippling sanctions on the Islamic Republic.</p>

<p>But it made Zarif a figurehead for a more open, outward-looking Iran that Pezeshkian pledged to strive for during his campaign, during which he was frequently joined by the former top diplomat.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2019-08/10l115to_iranian-foreign-minister-mohammad-javad-zarif-afp_625x300_05_August_19.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Javad Zarif also faced pressure after his appointment because his children hold US citizenship. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-minister-yoav-gallant-tells-us-that-large-scale-iranian-attack-expected-report-6319723]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Israeli Minister Tells US That "Large-Scale" Iranian Attack Expected: Report]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-israeli-minister-yoav-gallant-tells-us-that-large-scale-iranian-attack-expected-report-6319723]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:08:04 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told U.S. Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Sunday that Iran was making preparations for a large-scale military attack on Israel, Axios reporter Barak Ravid said in a post on X.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yoav Gallant told US Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin on Sunday that Iran was making preparations for a "large-scale" military attack on Israel, Axios reporter Barak Ravid said in a post on X, citing a source with knowledge of the call.</p>

<p>In a statement on Monday, Gallant's ministry confirmed the call took place overnight. It said Gallant and Austin discussed operational and strategic coordination and the Israeli military's readiness in the face of Iranian threats.</p>

<p>Austin has meanwhile ordered the deployment of a guided missile submarine to the Middle East. The US military had already said it would deploy additional fighter jets and Navy warships to the region to bolster Israeli defences.</p>

<p>On Friday, an Iranian Revolutionary Guards deputy commander was quoted as saying by local news agencies that Iran was set to carry out an order by Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei to "harshly punish" Israel over the assassination on July 31 of the leader of Palestinian operative group Hamas in Tehran.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/478j1lh_lloyd-austin-yoav-gallant-_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The US Defense Secretary (left) and Israeli Defense Minister discussed operational coordination (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-youtuber-makes-late-term-abortion-video-faces-police-probe-6319606]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[South Korean YouTuber Makes Late-Term Abortion Video, Faces Police Probe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/south-korean-youtuber-makes-late-term-abortion-video-faces-police-probe-6319606]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:47:48 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The woman claimed to have undergone an abortion in her thirty-sixth week of pregnancy, saying she had only discovered she was pregnant very late in the process.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean police said Monday they were investigating a YouTuber who vlogged about undergoing a late-term abortion, sparking online outrage and calls from the country's health ministry for a murder probe.</p>

<p>The woman, whose identity police withheld, claimed in a video posted on Google-owned YouTube in June to have undergone an abortion in her thirty-sixth week of pregnancy, saying she had only discovered she was pregnant very late in the process.</p>

<p>The footage, which was later deleted, quickly went viral in South Korea, with screenshots from it still circulating widely online and the country's health ministry calling for a murder investigation.</p>

<p>"We have booked the woman and the head of a medical clinic who performed the procedure as suspects," a representative of the Seoul Police Agency told AFP.</p>

<p>The police confirmed the footage was genuine, saying they had identified the clinic where the procedure was performed through an analysis of the video.</p>

<p>Police are investigating exactly what happened, a police official said according to the Yonhap news agency, adding that the probe could implicate more people.</p>

<p>Until 2019, South Korea was one of just a handful of industrialised nations that broadly criminalised abortion, except in instances of rape, incest, and when the mother's health was in jeopardy.</p>

<p>But five years ago, the Constitutional Court ordered the decades-old ban lifted, ruling that the 1953 statute "goes against the constitution".</p>

<p>It ordered the law to be revised by the end of 2020 but it has yet to be.</p>

<p>As a result of the legal vacuum, there is technically no limit on late-term abortions, but police are claiming authority to investigate.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/atkj5em8_pregnant-woman_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The police have withheld the identity of the woman (Representational)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-killed-her-husband-and-hid-his-body-for-18-years-she-was-never-caught-6319605]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[UK Woman Killed Her Husband, Hid Body For 18 Years. She Was Never Caught]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/uk-woman-killed-her-husband-and-hid-his-body-for-18-years-she-was-never-caught-6319605]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:47:25 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Investigations revealed that Leigh Ann murdered her husband and cleverly concealed his body within her own home for 18 years while abandoning her five children.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In November 2015, a chilling murder case made headlines around the world. Shockwaves rippled through the quiet town of Beddau, Wales after the skeletal remains of John Sabine were unearthed in a garden, wrapped in plastic. Police believe he was murdered by his wife Leigh Ann Sabine, who died in October 2015, <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-wales-south-east-wales-35097310">BBC</a></em> reported. Investigations revealed that Leigh Ann, known locally as ''Mad Lee'',&nbsp;murdered her husband and cleverly concealed his body within her own home for 18 years while abandoning her five children.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The woman's story is told in <em>'The Body Next Door'</em>, a three-part documentary series that explores one of the most bizarre and shocking true crime stories of the past decade.</p>

<p><strong>The Murder Case</strong></p>

<p>In 1997, 67-year-old accountant John Sabine vanished from his home in Beddau. His wife cunningly concealed his disappearance, claiming he had abandoned her of his own accord. However, in reality, she had brutally murdered John with a stone frog ornament, then meticulously wrapped his body in layers of plastic and shopping bags, effectively mummifying him, and hid him in a series of locations - under a bed, in a garden shed, and finally, in her attic.</p>

<p>For 18 years, Sabine collected John's pension. Her dark secret remained hidden until her death from brain cancer on October 30, 2015. A few weeks later, her friend&nbsp;stumbled upon a gruesome discovery in the attic while sorting through her belongings. She found a large package that had the mummified corpse of John Sabine.</p>

<p>Soon, detectives from South Wales Police arrived at her home to scour her photos for any trace of the murder weapon.&nbsp;A postmortem carried out by forensic pathologist Dr Richard Jones found the cause of death was blunt force trauma to the head. Dr Jones said the way the body had been wrapped meant it was well preserved through ''chemical mummification.''</p>

<p>The autopsy also revealed that the unique pattern of wounds on the victim's head matched the protrusions on a frog-shaped ornament.&nbsp;Investigators later discovered the frog figurine in a box of trinkets that she had gifted to her friend Michelle.</p>

<p>A few months before she died, Sabine told a hairdresser, ''People are going to talk about me after I have gone. I could be famous.'' When the hairdresser asked why, she replied: "Because of the body in the bag.''</p>

<p>Photographer Juliet Eden who met&nbsp;Sabine a year before her death told <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/11/a-woman-hid-husbands-dead-body-inside-home-18-years-21352144/#:~:text=In%20reality%20Sabine%20had%20savagely,shed%20then%2C%20to%20her%20attic.">Metro</a></em>, ''Lee was highly intelligent, very confident and quite mad. She called everyone “darling” and hid her secrets behind a crazy, flamboyant demeanour. I always found that puzzling; if people have something they want to hide, usually they stay quiet and tuck themselves away in a corner. But Lee was the opposite,&nbsp;she hid in plain sight.''</p>

<p>Ms Eden has also written a book,&nbsp;<a href="https://julieteden.co.uk/"><em>Frog Murderer</em></a>, which revisits her experience with Sabine.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/a1pekslg_leigh-ann-sabine-_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[For 18 years, Sabine collected John's pension.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-greece-as-superhuman-efforts-fail-to-control-wildfire-6319440]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Residents Flee As Greece Wildfires Spread Despite "Superhuman" Efforts]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/residents-flee-greece-as-superhuman-efforts-fail-to-control-wildfire-6319440]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:24:28 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Greece ordered the evacuation of hospitals and homes near Athens Monday as wildfires spread despite "superhuman" efforts to combat the flames, the fire brigade said.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greece ordered the evacuation of hospitals and homes near Athens Monday as <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/raging-wildfire-forces-dozens-to-evacuate-in-greece-6317306" target="_blank">wildfires spread</a> despite "superhuman" efforts to combat the flames, the fire brigade said.</p>

<p>At least five more communities were told to flee by civil protection authorities, after hundreds of people evacuated Sunday from at least eight villages.</p>

<p>"Civil protection forces battled hard throughout the night, but despite superhuman efforts, the fire evolved rapidly," fire brigade spokesman Vassilis Vathrakogiannis said.</p>

<p>"At this moment it has reached Mount Pentelicus and is headed in the direction of Penteli," he added.</p>

<p>Two hospitals in Penteli -- one for children and a military facility -- were evacuated at dawn according to Vathrakogiannis.</p>

<p>The brigade has deployed 510 firefighters and 152 vehicles, while 29 aircraft were due to set out at first light, he added.</p>

<p>"Forest fire near you. Follow the instructions of the authorities," said SMS messages sent to people in the Attica region, indicating in which direction to flee.</p>

<p>Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis cut short his holiday and returned to Athens Sunday evening to deal with the crisis.</p>

<p>By Sunday afternoon, firefighters had quickly dealt with 33 out of the 40 blazes that had broken out in the past 24 hours.</p>

<p>But the force was battling seven more in the high Mediterranean summer heat, the fire brigade spokesman said Sunday.</p>

<p>Residents of the historic town of Marathon, 40 kilometres (25 miles) east of Athens, were among those ordered to evacuate Sunday.</p>

<p>"Everything is burning," said Giorgos Tsevas, a resident of Polydendri village.</p>

<p>"I have 200 olive trees there but now they are gone," the 48-year-old said Sunday.</p>

<p>Already Saturday, Civil Protection Minister Vassilis Kikilias had warned that half the country was under a high-risk warning for fires due to high temperatures, wind gusts and drought conditions.</p>

<p>"Throughout the night, winds remained strong, creating dangerous situations. Unfortunately their intensity is expected to increase in the coming hours," Vathrakogiannis warned.</p>

<p>The Mediterranean country is exceptionally vulnerable to summer blazes, with this season seeing fires burn daily.</p>

<p>After the warmest winter on record, Greece also experienced its hottest June and July since reliable data collection began in 1960.</p>

<p>Scientists warn that human-induced fossil fuel emissions are worsening the length, frequency and intensity of heatwaves across the world.</p>

<p>The rising temperatures are leading to longer wildfire seasons and increasing the area burnt in the flames, according to the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/17e4ueeo_greece-wildfire_625x300_12_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The brigade has deployed 510 firefighters and 152 vehicles to battle the wildfire.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-grabbed-by-woman-kissed-at-paris-olympics-closing-ceremony-6319012]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tom Cruise Grabbed By Woman, Kissed At Paris Olympics Closing Ceremony]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tom-cruise-grabbed-by-woman-kissed-at-paris-olympics-closing-ceremony-6319012]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 13:24:23 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Hollywood superstar Tom Cruise was left stunned after a woman grabbed and kissed him forcefully at the closing ceremony of the Paris Olympics 2024.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hollywood superstar Tom Cruise was left stunned after a woman grabbed and kissed him forcefully at the closing ceremony of the Paris Olympics 2024. The incident occurred when the actor, rappelling down from the roof of the Stade de France, was mobbed by fans seeking selfies.&nbsp;</p>

<p>A video of the incident, widely shared on social media, shows the woman grabbing Cruise and planting a kiss on his cheek while recording it on her phone. The <em>Top Gun Maverick</em> star appeared taken aback by the sudden move.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">How'd that lady almost make out with Tom Cruise on international TV ????<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ClosingCeremony?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ClosingCeremony</a> <a href="https://t.co/IxtmIUPdcA">pic.twitter.com/IxtmIUPdcA</a></p>
— Georgia Rose ???????? ???? (@Rasheeda_S) <a href="https://twitter.com/Rasheeda_S/status/1822750936324055272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Social media users have criticised the woman's behaviour, with many arguing the incident would be unacceptable if the roles were reversed.</p>

<p>"Imagine if the roles were reversed..." a user wrote on X.&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Imagine if the roles were reversed…</p>
— ham (@meme_cycle) <a href="https://twitter.com/meme_cycle/status/1822781203197665547?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Another user wrote, "Cringe. If a man did that to a female celebrity there would be questions."&nbsp;</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Cringe. ????<br />
If a man did that to a female celebrity there would be questions...</p>
— ???? Dewy ♀️ (@BlueSkiesG1) <a href="https://twitter.com/BlueSkiesG1/status/1822763579008778593?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>"Did she ask for consent?" a comment read.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Did she ask for consent? ????</p>
— Mr Ribs (@Oloomzy) <a href="https://twitter.com/Oloomzy/status/1822762616852554118?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Someone else stated that these were the "worst kind of people in audiences." "Absolute zero respect for personal space. If it had been a man with a woman people would already be looking for all his information to burn him alive."</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The worst kind of people in audiences. Absolute zero respect for personal space. If it had been a man with a woman people would already be looking for all his information to burn him alive.</p>
— Siul Oczoro ???????????????????? (@SiulOczoro989) <a href="https://twitter.com/SiulOczoro989/status/1822760116275306940?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2024</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>The <a href="https://sports.ndtv.com/olympics-2024/from-tom-cruise-to-snoop-dogg-performers-that-set-the-stage-on-fire-in-olympics-closing-ceremony-6316972">Paris Olympics 2024</a> ended on Sunday with a dazzling closing ceremony featuring superstar athletes and artists. The ceremony began with a musical performance and the France swimmer Leon Marchand bringing the Olympic flame to the Stade de France. The Parade of Nations started inside the stadium, with the flag-bearers of the IOC Refugee and Olympic Team and France leading the way. Indian shooter Manu Bhaker and hockey goalkeeper PR Sreejesh carried the Indian flag as flag-bearers.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The Olympic Flag Handover Ceremony marked the transition from the Paris Olympics 2024 to Los Angeles 2028. The Olympic flag was passed from the Mayor of Paris to IOC President Thomas Bach, then to the Mayor of Los Angeles Karen Bass. Tom Cruise made a stunning entry, sliding down the roof of the stadium. Bass and Biles gave the flag to the 'Mission Impossible' actor, who took off on a bike, showing the transition from Paris to Los Angeles.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ijrtbok_tom-cruise-kissed-forcibly_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A video of the incident has been widely shared on social media.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktoks-viral-underconsumption-core-trend-explained-buy-less-buy-better-6319210]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["Buy Less, Buy Better": Viral "Underconsumption Core" Trend Explained]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tiktoks-viral-underconsumption-core-trend-explained-buy-less-buy-better-6319210]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:50:37 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Social media has long had room only for picture-perfect homes, lavish closets and an abundance of beauty products. But a new trend is sweeping the other way -- urging repurposing, more frugal lifestyles and prioritizing quality over quantity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exhausted from the rising cost of living in the United States and non-stop ads, some young adults on TikTok are pushing back.</p>

<p>"When every moment of your life feels like you're being sold something and the price of said item keeps going up, people will burn out on spending money," Kara Perez, an influencer and financial educator, told AFP.</p>

<p>Social media has long had room only for picture-perfect homes, lavish closets and an abundance of beauty products. But a new trend is sweeping the other way -- urging repurposing, more frugal lifestyles and prioritizing quality over quantity.</p>

<p>Known as "underconsumption core," it spotlights living sustainably and using what you have, a reversal of the excess and wealth that dominates ad-heavy Instagram and TikTok.</p>

<p>"When you get 300 videos on TikTok about people who have 30 Stanley cups, you want to have as many as you can afford. People want to fit in," said Perez, who repurposes jars as cups.</p>

<h3><strong>Consumer fatigue</strong></h3>

<p>A video with over 100,000 views from TikTok user loveofearthco critiqued the tendency toward overconsumption often amplified and encouraged on social media: "I spent money I didn't have on things I didn't need."</p>

<p>Another account, nevadahuvenaars, shared what "normal" consumption looks like: used furniture, a modest closet, decor upcycled from glass bottles, meal prep and a downsized skincare collection.</p>

<p>Despite financial hardships felt particularly by Gen Z and millennials, the US economy is thriving, with record corporate profits and high prices on shelves.</p>

<p>In a way, "that feels almost 'gaslighty' to consumers" amid a period of economic and geopolitical uncertainty, culture and consumer marketing analyst Tariro Makoni told AFP.</p>

<p>She argued that Buy Now, Pay Later (BNPL) plans commonly adopted by many young adults' budgets exacerbate consumption and represent a distortion in access to wealth.</p>

<p>But years of inflation have forced many to the conclusion that they cannot keep up with the spending habits of those on their social media feeds.</p>

<p>A Google Trends analysis shows US searches for "underconsumption" hit a high point this summer, surfacing alongside queries about "overproduction" and the "Great Depression."</p>

<p>Many young adults have developed a "compulsive behavior to spend down to their last pound on a fashion item," said UK-based influencer Andrea Cheong who recently shared an "underconsumption core" style video of her mending old clothes.</p>

<p>It is an addiction tied to a pressure "to articulate who we are through possessions," Cheong noted.</p>

<p>In contrast, "underconsumption core" breaks from traditional core trends promoted by influencers, who often sell an ever changing purchasing blueprint embodying the latest trend and aesthetic, according to Cheong. She and Makoni agreed that the shift also reflects increased calls for authenticity from content creators.</p>

<p>Now, "conserving is cool" said Makoni -- "we saw very similar patterns after 2008" during the financial crisis.</p>

<p>Over half of Gen Z adults -- age 18 to 27 -- polled in a 2024 survey by Bank of America stated the high cost of living as a top barrier to their financial success, adding that many do not make enough money to live the life they want.</p>

<h3><strong>Sustainability concerns</strong></h3>

<p>"The social media trend of 'underconsumption' is another way for Gen Z to make the most of their money and be environmentally friendly at the same time," said Ashley Ross, head of consumer client experience and governance at Bank of America.</p>

<p>While younger generations worry about making sustainable choices, a lack of financial autonomy drives their decisions.</p>

<p>"Let's be honest, no one's gonna change their GDP for sustainability. We don't live in that world ... The motivation for people to do these things has always been to save money," said Cheong.</p>

<p>But she told AFP "underconsumption" trends ultimately provide the most accessible approach to sustainability for those who seek it. The message is simple: "Buy less, buy better."</p>

<p>Low consumption brick-and-mortar initiatives cast a wider net of profiles and generations.</p>

<p>Anjali Zielinski, 42, joined a "Mending 101" workshop in Georgetown, DC in the hopes of acquiring new skills. She brought her daughter, Mina, seven, along with her.</p>

<p>In addition to providing an outlet to her daughter's creativity, she hopes the craft will teach her the "value of our possessions and the work that goes into them."</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/44jcikoo_mending-101_625x300_12_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Anjali Zielinski joined a "Mending 101" workshop in Georgetown, DC in the hopes of acquiring new skills]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-high-hopes-in-israel-for-super-hero-cocoa-that-has-survived-war-6319160]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[High Hopes In Israel For "Super Hero" Cocoa That Has Survived War]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-hamas-war-high-hopes-in-israel-for-super-hero-cocoa-that-has-survived-war-6319160]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:46:18 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Farming can develop in mysterious ways. Israeli researchers learned about that when the war in Gaza seemed to have all but wrecked their work on a more resilient strain of the cocoa plant that could help alleviate a global shortage of the beans.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Farming can develop in mysterious ways. Israeli researchers learned about that when the war in Gaza seemed to have all but wrecked their work on a more resilient strain of the cocoa plant that could help alleviate a global shortage of the beans.</p>

<p>Just days after Israel's agriculture research centre, the Volcani Institute, sent 140 seedlings to a facility in southern Israel to study how this tropical plant could be grown in dry conditions, the area came under attack by the Palestinian Islamist group Hamas.</p>

<p>The October 7 assault that sparked the war in Gaza, paralysed southern Israel and left the facility shut down for months without electricity or irrigation.</p>

<p>"When we came back in January we saw everything around us, all the experiments that died," said Talli Ilani, a researcher at the R&amp;D Darom site.</p>

<p>Everything except for 18 cocoa seedlings.</p>

<p>While the team had not planned on testing the selected cocoa strains specifically for drought resistance, they may have found just that.</p>

<p>"It's a very unusual result, to find a strain that can withstand 3-1/2 months of drought as new fresh seedlings and also severe cold front," said Ellen Graber, a senior principal scientist at the Volcani Institute. "It means that we may be able to develop strains that can expand the growing regions for cocoa."</p>

<p>Bad weather and disease have hurt cocoa production and sent global cocoa prices soaring.</p>

<p>Graber now plans to clone the surviving plants - which she refers to as "super heroes" - and test them for other qualities such as resistance to pests, and identify the genes responsible for their resilience.</p>

<p>The Volcani Institute has developed resilient plant strains in the past, including drought-resistant wheat that ripens earlier and with a higher nutrient content, as well as a chill-resistant basil that yields all year round.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/4ld34icg_plant_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-faces-privacy-complaints-over-data-use-in-europe-6318953]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk's X Faces Privacy Complaints Over Data Use In Europe]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/elon-musks-x-faces-privacy-complaints-over-data-use-in-europe-6318953]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:16:01 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A Vienna-based privacy campaign group lodged complaints in eight European countries against Elon Musk's X on Monday over "unlawfully" feeding the personal data of users into its artificial intelligence technology without their consent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Vienna-based privacy campaign group lodged complaints in eight European countries against Elon Musk's X on Monday over "unlawfully" feeding the personal data of users into its artificial intelligence technology without their consent.</p>

<p>The complaints filed by the European Center for Digital Rights -- also known as Noyb ("None of Your Business") -- come after Ireland's Data Protection Commission (DPC) earlier this month took court action against X over its data collection practices to train its AI.</p>

<p>X had recently started "irreversibly feeding" the personal data of more than 60 million European users into its Grok AI technology, "without ever informing them or asking for their consent", according to Noyb.</p>

<p>Noyb slammed X for "never proactively informing" its users that their data is being used for AI training, saying many people appeared to have "found out about the new default setting through a viral post on 26 July".</p>

<p>Last week the DPC -- which acts on behalf of the European Union -- said that X had agreed to suspend its much-criticised processing of users' personal data for its AI technology.</p>

<p>But Noyb founder Max Schrems said in a statement that the DPC failed to "question the legality" of the actual processing, seemingly taking action "around the edges, not at the core of the problem".</p>

<p>Noyb also warned that it remained unclear what happened with already ingested EU data.</p>

<p>Calling for a "full investigation", Noyb has filed complaints in Austria, Belgium, France, Greece, Ireland, Italy, the Netherlands and Spain.</p>

<p>The group has requested an "urgency procedure" against X that allows data protection authorities in the eight European countries to act.</p>

<p>"We want to ensure that Twitter (now X) fully complies with EU law, which -- at a bare minimum -- requires to ask users for consent," Schrems said, referring to the bloc's landmark General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</p>

<p>The GDPR aims to make it easier for people to control how companies use their personal information.</p>

<p>The group recently launched similar legal action against social media giant Meta, causing it to halt its AI plans.</p>

<p>Noyb has taken several court proceedings against technology giants, often prompting action from regulatory authorities.</p>

<p>The group began working in 2018 with the advent of the GDPR.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-04/do8o3bco_elon-musk-reuters-_625x300_26_April_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The complaint was filed by the European Center for Digital Rights also known as Noyb (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tropical-storm-maria-hits-japan-disrupts-travel-forces-evacuations-6318938]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Tropical Storm Maria Hits Japan, Disrupts Travel, Forces Evacuations]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/tropical-storm-maria-hits-japan-disrupts-travel-forces-evacuations-6318938]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 12:11:29 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Tropical Storm Maria made landfall on Monday in Japan's northern region of Iwate, bringing torrential rain that disrupted flights and rail services while forcing people in some areas to evacuate homes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tropical Storm Maria made landfall on Monday in Japan's northern region of Iwate, bringing torrential rain that disrupted flights and rail services while forcing people in some areas to evacuate homes, but there were no immediate reports of casualties.</p>

<p>The storm, packing maximum wind speeds of 72 kph (45 mph), is expected to move towards the Sea of Japan.</p>

<p>The Japan Meteorological Agency warned of risks from mudslides and floods after record-breaking rainfall over the last two days in some cities of the region.</p>

<p>The government will do its best to tackle the situation, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida told reporters. "We'll continue to provide information to residents and support those evacuating," he said.</p>

<p>Although Japan is observing a holiday, some high-speed bullet trains and regular services have been suspended in Iwate and other northern areas, while Japan Airlines and All Nippon Airways also cancelled flights in the affected regions.</p>

<p>Public broadcaster NHK said municipal authorities urged people in Iwate to take shelter. Media said no casualties had been reported.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ephe5t4o_tropical-storm-maria-japan-afp_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The Japan Meteorological Agency warned of risks from mudslides and floods after record-breaking rainfall.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-police-return-to-capital-dhaka-streets-after-weeklong-strike-6318829]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Police Return To Dhaka Streets After Weeklong Strike]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-police-return-to-capital-dhaka-streets-after-weeklong-strike-6318829]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:58:36 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Bangladeshi police resumed patrols of the capital Dhaka on Monday, ending a weeklong strike that left a law and order vacuum following the abrupt ouster of autocratic ex-premier Sheikh Hasina.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangladeshi police resumed patrols of the capital Dhaka on Monday, ending a weeklong strike that left a law and order vacuum following the abrupt ouster of autocratic ex-premier Sheikh Hasina.</p>

<p>Officers vanished from the streets of the sprawling megacity of 20 million people last week after Hasina's resignation and flight abroad ended her 15-year rule.</p>

<p>Police were loathed for spearheading a lethal crackdown on the weeks of protests that forced her departure, with 42 officers among the more than 450 people killed.</p>

<p>Police had vowed not to resume work until their safety on duty was guaranteed, but they agreed to return after late-night talks with the new interim government, helmed by Nobel laureate Muhammad Yunus.</p>

<p>"The police association ended its strike last night," the force's national spokesperson Enamul Haque Sagor told AFP.</p>

<p>"Police officers have returned to work today," he added. "You can see them managing traffic in Dhaka's streets."</p>

<h3><strong>'Heinous attacks'</strong></h3>

<p>Student-led protests against Hasina's government had been largely peaceful until police attempted to violently disperse them.</p>

<p>Around 450 of the country's 600 police stations were targeted in arson and vandalism attacks over the past month, according to the national police union.</p>

<p>Some began reopening late last week under guard by the army, an institution held in higher esteem for largely refusing to participate in the crackdown.</p>

<p>In the police's absence, the students who led the protests that toppled Hasina volunteered to restore law and order after looting and reprisal attacks in the hours after her departure.</p>

<p>They acted as traffic wardens, formed overnight neighbourhood watch patrols and guarded Hindu temples and other places of worship, quickly settling the unrest.</p>

<p>Yunus's "council of advisors", the de facto cabinet now administering the country, said it had noted with "grave concern" some attacks on Hindus and other minorities.</p>

<p>In its first official statement on Sunday night, the cabinet said it would work to "find ways to resolve such heinous attacks".</p>

<p>Bangladeshi Hindus account for around eight percent of the country's 170 million people and have regularly been the targets of violence during periods of upheaval.</p>

<p>Hundreds have arrived on India's border since last week, asking to cross.</p>

<p>Hasina, 76, fled by helicopter to neighbouring India a week ago as protesters flooded Dhaka's streets in a dramatic end to her iron-fisted tenure.</p>

<p>Her government was accused of widespread human rights abuses, including the extrajudicial killing of thousands of her political opponents.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/ivpbh1rg_bangladesh-police-afp_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Police were loathed for spearheading a lethal crackdown, with more than 450 people killed. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-dead-as-lightning-strike-causes-park-pavilion-to-collapse-in-china-6318747]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[6 Dead As Lightning Strike Causes Park Pavilion To Collapse In China]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/6-dead-as-lightning-strike-causes-park-pavilion-to-collapse-in-china-6318747]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:44:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Six people were killed and 10 were injured when a lightning strike caused a park pavilion to collapse in eastern China, state media said Monday.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Six people were killed and 10 were injured when a lightning strike caused a park pavilion to collapse in eastern China, state media said Monday.</p>

<p>The accident took place in the city of Changzhou in Jiangsu province on Sunday, state news agency Xinhua said.</p>

<p>The 10 injured people were in stable condition and an investigation into the accident was being carried out, state broadcaster CCTV said.</p>

<p>China is enduring a summer of <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/july-becomes-chinas-hottest-month-on-record-since-1961-6240041" target="_blank">extreme weather</a>, with heavy rains across the east and south, and much of the north sweltering in successive heat waves.</p>

<p>Last month, heavy rain in the northern province of Shaanxi caused a highway bridge to collapse, killing at least 38 people.</p>

<p>Climate change, which scientists say is exacerbated by greenhouse gas emissions, is making these types of extreme weather phenomena more frequent and more intense.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-07/q2i5jml_lightning_625x300_23_July_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Last month, heavy rain in the northern province of Shaanxi killed at least 38 people (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-stabs-mother-to-death-after-being-denied-overnight-stay-at-family-home-6318691]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[US Man Stabs Mother To Death After Being Denied Overnight Stay At Home]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/us-man-stabs-mother-to-death-after-being-denied-overnight-stay-at-family-home-6318691]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:35:10 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The accused got into an argument with his 74-year-old mother, Barbara Mortimer when she told him he could not stay the night at their family home.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 40-year-old Ohio man was arrested and charged with murder, attempted murder, and felonious assault after stabbing his mother&nbsp;to death and critically wounding his father. The incident occurred when Kenneth Mortimer's mother told him that&nbsp;he couldn't stay overnight at their home, leading to an argument that turned physical.</p>

<p>Green Township police said the attack happened about 4 p.m. Friday at a home in the 3300 block of Palmhill Lane, as per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/crime/stabbing-parents-mom-ohio-home-b2594815.html">Independent</a></em>.</p>

<p>Notably, the accused&nbsp;got into an argument with his 74-year-old mother, Barbara Mortimer when she told him he could not stay the night at their family home. The argument escalated, and Barbara urged her husband, Thomas, to dial 911. In a chilling turn of events, Kenneth retrieved a knife from the kitchen and approached his parents, who were seated on the couch.</p>

<p>He began stabbing both his parents leaving them critically injured. Despite her wounds, Barbara attempted to flee, but Kenneth overpowered her, dragging her back into the house. In the aftermath, Kenneth fled the scene but was apprehended by responding police officers. While his mother died, his father remains in serious condition at the hospital&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to authorities, Kenneth Mortimer told officers he stabbed both of his parents.&nbsp;A Hamilton County judge has set the 40-year-old's bail at $2 million.</p>

<p>Last month, a 20-year-old<a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/20-year-old-us-man-strangles-mother-to-death-after-she-asked-him-to-clean-his-room-6025056"> Indiana man was charged with strangling his mother to death</a> after she asked him to clean his room and find a full-time job. Connor Kobold, a student at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, called 911 five times on February 5, reporting a dead person in his home in Valparaiso, as per court documents, according to <em>Fox News.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p>When police arrived, Kobold surrendered himself, asking to be handcuffed and placed in the squad car. He allegedly confessed to the crime, stating, "There is a dead person inside of the house on the corner" and "I killed somebody in that house," reported WGNTV.</p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/upb7rvlg_kenneth-mortimer-_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[A Hamilton County judge has set the 40-year-old's bail at $2 million.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-evacuates-more-border-areas-amid-rising-threat-from-ukraine-forces-6318687]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Russia Evacuates More Border Areas Amid Rising Threat From Ukraine Forces]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/russia-evacuates-more-border-areas-amid-rising-threat-from-ukraine-forces-6318687]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:33:24 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Russia on Monday evacuated parts of another region next to Ukraine after Kyiv sharply increased military activity near the border just days after its biggest incursion into sovereign Russian territory since the start of the 2022 war.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia on Monday evacuated parts of another region next to Ukraine after Kyiv sharply increased military activity near the border just days after its biggest incursion into sovereign Russian territory since the start of the 2022 war.</p>

<p>Ukrainian forces rammed through the Russian border early on Tuesday and swept across some Western parts of Russia's Kursk region, a surprise attack that may be aimed at gaining leverage in possible ceasefire talks after the US election.</p>

<p>Apparently caught by surprise, Russia by Sunday has stabilised the front in the Kursk region, though Ukraine had carved out a sliver of Russian territory where battles were continuing on Monday, according to Russian war bloggers.</p>

<p>In the neighbouring Belgorod region to the south, the regional governor, Vyacheslav Gladkov, said that evacuations had begun from the Krasnaya Yaruga District due to "enemy activity on the border" that was a "threat".</p>

<p>"I am sure that our servicemen will do everything to cope with the threat that has arisen," Gladkov said. "We are starting to move people who live in the Krasnaya Yaruga district to safer places."</p>

<p>Russia has imposed a sweeping security regime in the Kursk, Bryansk and Belgorod regions while Russian ally Belarus said it was bolstering its troop numbers at its border after Minsk said Ukraine had violated its airspace with drones.</p>

<p>The audacious Ukrainian attacks on Russian sovereign territory are aimed at showing its Western supporters that Kyiv can still muster major military operations while trying to gain a bargaining chip ahead of possible ceasefire talks.</p>

<p>Russian forces, which have a vast numerical supremacy and control 18% of Ukrainian territory, have been advancing this year along the 1,000-km (620-mile) front after the failure of Ukraine's 2023 counteroffensive to make any major gains.</p>

<p>Ukraine broke its silence on the attacks on Saturday when President Volodymyr Zelenskiy said that Ukraine had launched an incursion into Russian territory to "restore justice" and pressure Moscow's forces.</p><p><i>(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)</i></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/q2msta7g_ukraine-incursion-into-russia_625x300_09_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Russia has imposed a sweeping security regime in the Kursk, Bryansk and Belgorod regions. (File)]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-features-of-uaes-golden-visa-thats-attracting-indias-richest-6318460]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Key Features Of UAE's Golden Visa That's Attracting India's Richest]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/key-features-of-uaes-golden-visa-thats-attracting-indias-richest-6318460]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 11:00:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The UAE government launched the Golden Visa programme in 2019 with the goal of attracting and keeping international investors and talent.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About 4,300 Indian millionaires were likely to leave the country in 2024, and a majority of them have set their eyes on the United Arab Emirates (UAE) as their preferred destination, according to a June&nbsp;<a href="https://www.henleyglobal.com/publications/henley-private-wealth-migration-report-2024">report</a> by international investment migration consultancy firm Henley &amp; Partners.</p>

<p>UAE's <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/indians-can-apply-for-multiple-entry-schengen-visa-with-longer-validity-says-eu-5498315">visa regulations</a> are a major factor why the ultra-rich see it as their best option when leaving their home countries.</p>

<p>Anyone with a Golden Visa can reside, work, and make investments in any of the seven emirates -- Abu Dhabi, Ajman, Dubai, Fujairah, Ras Al Khaimah, Sharjah, and Umm Al Quwain -- &nbsp;in the UAE.</p>

<h3><strong>Key Features&nbsp;UAE Golden Visa</strong></h3>

<p>Here are the key features of the<a href="https://www.ndtv.com/feature/indian-ceo-explains-why-dubai-is-the-best-place-to-settle-down-no-crime-best-infra-5980260"> UAE Golden Visa</a>, according to the official portal of the UAE Government:&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
	<li>Extended residency: The visa grants a long-term residence permit without a local sponsor.&nbsp;</li>
	<li>Travel ease: Visa holders can enter and exit the UAE with ease.</li>
	<li>Professional freedom: The visa promotes an atmosphere favourable to both professional and entrepreneurial growth by allowing complete business ownership and the ability to select employers.</li>
	<li>Sponsorship of family members and domestic workers: Visa holders can sponsor one or more family members as well as domestic workers.</li>
</ul>

<h3><strong>Eligibility Of&nbsp;UAE Golden Visa</strong></h3>

<ul>
	<li>Physicians and scientists: You need to get permission from the appropriate scientific committees or the Ministry of Health.</li>
	<li>Creative professionals: Department of Culture and Arts clearance is required.</li>
	<li>Executive directors: A degree, a minimum of five years of experience, and an AED 50,000 salary are required.</li>
	<li>Executive directors: A degree, a minimum of five years of experience, and an AED 50,000 (about Rs 11,42,808) salary are required.</li>
	<li>Investors: Must have a business, deposit AED 2 million, and pay AED 250,000 in taxes.</li>
	<li>Entrepreneurs: Must have a project with a minimum estimated value of AED 500,000 and the necessary approvals.</li>
	<li>Entrepreneurs: Must have a project with a minimum estimated value of AED 500,000 and the necessary approvals.</li>
</ul>

<p>The UAE government launched the Golden Visa programme in 2019 with the goal of attracting and keeping international investors and talent.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/g9k7kji8_dubai_625x300_12_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Representational Image]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-bearcat-that-died-in-uk-zoo-to-be-cryogenically-frozen-6318427]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Rare 'Bearcat' That Died In UK Zoo To Be Cryogenically Frozen]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/rare-bearcat-that-died-in-uk-zoo-to-be-cryogenically-frozen-6318427]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 10:49:34 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[The decision to freeze the bearcat was to preserve its body and genetic material for potential research and educational purposes.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A rare bearcat that died in a UK zoo is set to be frozen for future study and preservation. According to <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://metro.co.uk/2024/08/11/rare-bearcat-died-uk-zoo-frozen-21402669/#:~:text=An%20extremely%20rare%20'bearcat'%20who,of%2018%20on%20July%2031."><em>Metro</em></a>, Penh, the Cambodian binturong who lived at Drusillas Park in East Sussex, died at the age of 18 on July 31.&nbsp;He was one of only three of this type of species in European zoos and had spent 14 years in England. The decision to freeze the bearcat was to preserve its body and genetic material for potential research and educational purposes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p>As binturongs face the looming threat of extinction in their native Southeast Asian habitats due to rampant deforestation, conservation efforts rely on the help of wildlife sanctuaries. By freezing Penh's body, scientists can tap into its genetic legacy, fueling the fight to protect this extraordinary animal and its dwindling population.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the zookeepers at Drusillas Park are left saddened by the loss of their beloved Penh, a cherished member of their animal family. ''A true gentleman, lover of tomatoes, and a sweet and gentle soul, he will be missed by his keepers and our visitors. But Penh's legacy will live on,'' Drusillas Park said in a statement on Instagram.&nbsp;</p>

<p><strong>See the pictures here:</strong></p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-IAhYCITGb/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-IAhYCITGb/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-IAhYCITGb/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-IAhYCITGb/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Drusillas Park (@drusillaspark)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p></p>

<p>The park added, ''The loss of Penh is of great sadness, but through this collaboration, his genetic legacy will live on, contributing to the conservation of binturongs for years to come. Together, we are ensuring that future generations will continue to witness the wonderful diversity of the natural world.''</p>

<p>Animal charity Nature's SAFE has been given the task of&nbsp;cryogenically preserving Penh's body, freezing his genetic material, including his sperm and skin cells. By preserving his genetic material, conservationists hope to one day use it to breed more bearcats, helping to ensure the long-term survival of the unique species.</p>

<p>Headkeeper Gemma, who was charged with delivering Penh's cell tissue to Nature's SAFE said, ''It felt very bittersweet, I've worked with Penh for over a decade so although I felt sad, it was also a positive feeling knowing it was not necessarily the end for him. The team at Nature's SAFE lab immediately tested Penh's sperm sample and we had confirmation that it was viable.''</p>

<h2><strong>What is a bearcat?</strong></h2>

<p>A bearcat, also known as a binturong (Arctictis binturong), is a unique and fascinating animal native to Southeast Asia. Despite its name, it's neither a bear nor a cat, but a member of the Viverrid family, related to civets and genets. Bearcats are relatively large, with adults reaching up to 6 feet (1.8 meters) in length and weighing around 20-40 pounds (9-18 kilograms). They have a distinctive coat with a mix of grey, white, and black fur, and a long, bushy tail.</p>

<p>Bearcats inhabit forests and grasslands in countries like Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Myanmar, the Philippines, Thailand, and Vietnam. They're solitary, nocturnal, and excellent climbers, often resting in trees during the day.&nbsp;They're omnivores, feeding on fruits, leaves, insects, and small animals.</p>

<p>They are listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List due to habitat loss, hunting, and human-wildlife conflict.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/t26ptnh8_bearcat_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Binturongs face the looming threat of extinction in their native Southeast Asian habitats d]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-28-year-old-deaf-woman-crowned-miss-south-africa-amid-controversy-6318380]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[In A First, 28-Year-Old Deaf Woman Crowned Miss South Africa Amid Controversy]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/in-a-first-28-year-old-deaf-woman-crowned-miss-south-africa-amid-controversy-6318380]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 10:40:20 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[She was declared the winner after finalist Chidimma Adetshina withdrew due to criticism regarding her Nigerian origin and allegations regarding her mother's identity.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A 28-year-old woman has become the first deaf woman to be crowned Miss South Africa after a divisive competition, as per a report in the <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1l5nrge372o.amp"><em>BBC</em></a>. Mia Le Roux, who was diagnosed with profound hearing loss when she was aged one, expressed her hope in her victory speech that her success will inspire those who feel excluded to pursue their "wildest dreams, just like I am." She also said that she wished to help those who were "financially excluded or differently abled".</p>

<p>Ms Le Roux was declared the pageant winner after finalist Chidimma Adetshina, aged 23, withdrew due to criticism regarding her Nigerian origin and allegations regarding her mother's identity. Notably, Ms Adetshina was born in South Africa to a Nigerian father and a South African mother, but the family came from Mozambique.</p>

<p>South Africa's Culture Minister Gayton McKenzie, the leader of the Patriotic Alliance party also questioned Ms Adetshina's identity to represent in the contest. "We truly cannot have Nigerians compete in our Miss SA competition. I wanna get all facts before I comment but it gives funny vibes already," he said on X.</p>

<p>Ms Adetshina said that the entire event felt like "black-on-black hate," bringing attention to the specific form of xenophobia known as "Afrophobia" that exists in South Africa and targets other Africans. She said that although there were other contestants with South Asian and European names among the 16 women, she was the only one getting most of the criticism.</p>

<p>The country's Home Affairs Minister Leon Schreiber said on August 6 that the department was <a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://x.com/Leon_Schreib/status/1820781492642910542">investigating her citizenship </a>at the request of the Miss South Africa organisation. Following the investigation, the ministry revealed: "Prima facie reasons exist to believe that fraud and identity theft may have been committed by the person recorded in home affairs records as Chidimma Adetshina's mother." As per <em><a class="sp_lnk2" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/08/miss-south-africa-contestant-withdraws-after-mother-is-accused-of-identity-theft">the Guardian,</a></em> the statement added, "An innocent South African mother, whose identity may have been stolen as part of the alleged fraud committed by Adetshina's mother, suffered as a result because she could not register her child."</p>

<p>On August 8, the 23-year-old took to Instagram to announce her decision to withdraw from the competition. "After much careful consideration, I have made the difficult decision to withdraw myself from the competition for the safety and well-being of my family and I. With the full support of the Miss South Africa Organisation, I leave with a heart full of gratitude for this amazing experience," she wrote.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aE4F4NdoA/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);">
<div style="padding:16px;">
<div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;">
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div>

<div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aE4F4NdoA/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"><svg height="50px" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 60 60" width="50px" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd" stroke="none" stroke-width="1"><g fill="#000000" transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></a></div>

<div style="padding-top: 8px;">
<div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aE4F4NdoA/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank">View this post on Instagram</a></div>
</div>

<div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;">
<div>
<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div>

<div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: 8px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div>
</div>

<div style="margin-left: auto;">
<div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div>

<div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div>
</div>
</div>

<div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;">
<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;"></div>

<div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;"></div>
</div>

<p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-aE4F4NdoA/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A post shared by Chidimma Adetshina (@chichi_vanessa)</a></p>
</div>
</blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>

<p>Meanwhile, Ms Le Roux uses a cochlear implant to help her hear. She claimed that before she could pronounce her first words, she had to have speech treatment for two years. The model, who is also a marketing manager said, "I am a proudly South African deaf woman and I know what it feels like to be excluded. I know now that I was put on this planet to break boundaries and I did it tonight."</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/krfhecig_miss-south-africa_625x300_12_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Ms Le Roux uses a cochlear implant to help her hear.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-shashi-tharoor-if-we-had-not-helped-her-shashi-tharoor-on-sheikh-hasina-in-india-6318147]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA["If We Had Not Helped Her...": Shashi Tharoor On Sheikh Hasina In India]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/sheikh-hasina-bangladesh-shashi-tharoor-if-we-had-not-helped-her-shashi-tharoor-on-sheikh-hasina-in-india-6318147]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:57:09 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[Praising the Centre for giving refuge to Sheikh Hasina after she was forced to resign as Bangladesh Prime Minister amid violent protests, Congress leader and MP Shashi Tharoor told NDTV power shift in the neighbouring country is no cause for worry]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Praising the Centre for giving refuge to Sheikh Hasina after she was forced to resign as Bangladesh Prime Minister amid violent protests, Congress leader and MP Shashi Tharoor told NDTV that the power shift in the neighbouring country is not a cause for worry for India.</p>

<p>Asked about his views on how the developments in Bangladesh would impact its ties with India, Mr Tharoor said, "Our fundamental interest lies in close and friendly relations with Bangladesh, our basic commitment is to the well-being of Bangladesh people, the State comes second and any individual leader comes third."</p>

<p>"We are with the people of Bangladesh, we were with them in 1971, we have been with them through thick and thin, even when they had governments who were less than friendly to us, we have managed to keep our relationship on an even keel and certainly there should be no deterioration in that relationship in time to come," he added.</p>

<div class="ins_instory_dv">
<div class="ins_instory_dv_cont"><img alt="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" id="story_image_main" src="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/nn1b5018_shashi-tharoor_625x300_12_August_24.jpg?im=FitAndFill,algorithm=dnn,width=1200,height=738" title="Latest and Breaking News on NDTV" /></div>
</div>

<p>On the interim government headed by Nobel peace prize winner and Grameen Bank founder Muhammad Yunus, he said it's no cause for anxiety for New Delhi. "I know Muhammad Yunus personally, he is a highly respected figure. I suppose he is somewhat close to Washington rather than being seen as close to Jamaat e Islami or Pakistani ISI. If you look at the overall composition of the interim government, there doesn't seem to be any particular reason for India to feel any anxiety about countries hostile to us having put their stamp on this interim government," he said.</p>

<p>The big concern for India, he said, has always been whether Pakistan and China will fish in troubled waters. "In this kind of context, there is always a possibility that the Pakistani ISI could have had a hand in some outrageous incidents of violence during the agitation, that the Chinese who have a strong presence in Bangladesh might have seen this as an opportunity to expand their influence, those are things people watching relations in the subcontinent are most concerned about. But certainly there is no implication of anything in the composition of the interim government or the initial statements of Mr Yunus that would give us any cause for worry," he said, underlining the interim leader's call for peace and protection of minorities.</p>

<p>On India giving refuge to Sheikh Hasina following her ouster, Mr Tharoor had words of praise for the Narendra Modi government. "If we had not helped her, it would have been a disgrace for India. Nobody would have wanted to be our friend if we had treated our friend badly. Sheikh Hasina is a friend of India and India is a friend of her. And when a friend is in trouble, you don't look twice before you help them, keep them safe. That's exactly what India has done. I applaud the government for doing it. I would have wanted nothing less. As an Indian, we have certain standards we stand for in the world. The government has done right thing to bring her here and ensure her safety," he said.</p>

<p>"How long she wishes to remain is not for us. You don't call someone to your house and ask them when are you leaving. My view is we wait and see, how long she feels she can stay before she moves on. There are practical considerations before moving to any other country, there ae visa considerations, other issues. For now, She is with us and we should be proud of the fact that we have stood by a friend when her personal safety was in danger," Mr Tharoor said.</p>

<p>In his response to a question on whether the Indian government should raise concerns regarding attacks on minorities more forcefully, he conflicting reports are coming out of Bangladesh. "There certainly have been some attacks, no one can deny it, no one should deny it. It's a fact. At the same time, there is no doubt that there are also stories coming out that Bangladeshi Muslims are guarding Hindu homes and temples, So there is a bit of good news also during all the bad news," he said.</p>

<p>The Congress leader saw hope in Muhammad Yunus's address after taking charge of the interim government. "Prof Yunus's statement that the government stands by the minorities and urges people to be calm and stop acts of violence, that's a very good sign. Any continuing violence will be definitely instigated by those elements in Bangladesh's society who have traditionally been anti-Indian, anti-Hindu and will do whatever it takes to create the conditions of disorder that may give them the opportunity to fish in troubled waters. But for now, I don't believe there is any one authority who wants to see that situation continue," he said.</p>

<p>Sheikh Hasina, who had to step down after protests against reservation in Bangladesh snowballed into a movement demanding her ouster, has been in India for nearly a week now. Following her arrival, External Affairs Minister S Jaishankar chaired an all-party meeting and briefed leaders from Opposition parties on the situation and the government's plan. The Opposition has assured full support to the Centre on tackling this crisis.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/6etffbkg_sheikh-hasina-afp_625x300_06_August_24.jpeg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[Shashi Tharoor spoke to NDTV on implications of Bangladesh developments leading to Sheikh Hasina's ouster]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
   <item>
       <guid isPermaLink='true'><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protest-anti-hindu-attacks-iconic-statue-of-pakistan-army-1971-surrender-vandalised-in-bangladesh-6318144]]></guid>
       <title><![CDATA[Iconic Statue Of Pakistan Army's 1971 Surrender Vandalised In Bangladesh]]></title>
       <link><![CDATA[https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/bangladesh-protest-anti-hindu-attacks-iconic-statue-of-pakistan-army-1971-surrender-vandalised-in-bangladesh-6318144]]></link>
       <pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Aug 2024 09:57:02 +0530]]></pubDate>
       <description><![CDATA[A statue meant to commemorate the liberation of Bangladesh has been destroyed by "anti-India vandals", Congress leader Shashi Tharoor said today.]]></description>
       <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A statue meant to commemorate the liberation of Bangladesh has been destroyed by "anti-India vandals", Congress leader Shashi Tharoor said today. Mr Tharoor shared an image of the broken statue which depicted the moment Pakistan surrendered after the 1971 war.</p>

<p>"Sad to see images like this of statues at the 1971 Shaheed Memorial Complex, Mujibnagar, destroyed by anti-India vandals," the Thiruvananthapuram MP said in a post on X (formerly Twitter). &nbsp;</p>

<p>"This follows disgraceful attacks on the Indian cultural centre, temples, and Hindu homes in several places, even as reports came in of Muslim civilians protecting other minority homes and places of worship," he added.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Sad to see images like this of statues at the 1971 Shaheed Memorial Complex, Mujibnagar, destroyed by anti-India vandals. This follows disgraceful attacks on the Indian cultural centre, temples and Hindu homes in several places, even as reports came in of Muslim civilians… <a href="https://t.co/FFrftoA81T">pic.twitter.com/FFrftoA81T</a></p>
— Shashi Tharoor (@ShashiTharoor) <a href="https://twitter.com/ShashiTharoor/status/1822830968702750934?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 12, 2024</a></blockquote>

<p>The 1971 war not only liberated Bangladesh but also dealt Pakistan a crushing blow. The statue depicted the signing of the 'Instrument Of Surrender' by Pakistan Army Major-General Amir Abdullah Khan Niazi to the Indian Army and Bangladesh's Mukti Bahini. Major-General Niazi surrendered with his 93,000 troops before Lt General Jagjit Singh Aurora, then General Officer Commanding-in-Chief of India's Eastern Command. This was the largest military surrender since World War II.</p>

<p>A student-led uprising in Bangladesh has led to the resignation of former Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and several other top officials. At least 450 people were killed in more than a month of deadly protests that led to Hasina's exit on August 5.</p>

<p>Hasina faces allegations of murder, forced disappearance, money laundering, and corruption, and must face the law, Amir Khosru Mahmud Chowdhury, a senior member of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party said.</p>

<p>The protests have also been severely harsh on Hindus residing in the country who have been subjected to several attacks against Hindu households, temples, and businesses. Hindus are the largest minority faith in mostly Muslim Bangladesh and are considered a steadfast support base for Hasina's party, the Awami League.</p>

<p>Members of minority communities in the violence-hit nation have faced more than 205 incidents of attacks across 52 districts since the fall of the government.</p>

<p>Shashi Tharoor urged the new caretaker government, led by Nobel laureate Muhammed Yunus, to take urgent steps to restore law and order.</p>

<p>"The agenda of some of the agitators is quite clear. It is essential that Muhammed Yunus and his interim government take urgent steps to restore law &amp; order in the interests of all Bangladeshis, of every faith. India stands with the people of Bangladesh at this turbulent time, but such anarchic excess can never be condoned," he said.</p>]]></content:encoded>
<media:content url='https://c.ndtvimg.com/2024-08/bvrfkol_bangladesh-war-memorial-vandalised_625x300_12_August_24.jpg' type='image/jpeg' expression='full' width='538' height='190'>
<media:description type='plain'><![CDATA[The 1971 war not only liberated Bangladesh but also dealt Pakistan a crushing blow.]]></media:description>
</media:content>   </item>
</channel>
</rss>