<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-09T10:03:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T10:03:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T10:03:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Searching for color at Pantone’s all-brown party</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5wkSBffShh1lJWS_NCMuOfSasvU=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775972/247409_Pantone_color_of_the_year_AKrales_0073.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Are we here to celebrate the color of the year or the luxury goods produced in its hue?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24316196/pantone-2025-color-of-the-year-mocha-mousse-party"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24316196/pantone-2025-color-of-the-year-mocha-mousse-party"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24316196/pantone-2025-color-of-the-year-mocha-mousse-party</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kristen Radtke</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Lego Fortnite is getting a big expansion with a GTA-style roleplaying city</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Promotional art for Lego Brick Life, a social game inside of Fortnite." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/AhzddTurtAkvVAGkOlJ4uy-nR50=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775930/LEGO_Fortnite_Brick_Life_KeyArt.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="JF62ri"&gt;Lego is building something new in &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. A year after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/7/23990660/lego-fortnite-release-epic"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lego Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; launched a new era inside of the game&lt;/a&gt; — one based on the idea that &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is a collection of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/9/23992574/fortnite-festival-harmonix-guitar-hero-rock-band"&gt;many game experiences&lt;/a&gt;, rather than just a battle royale — Lego is expanding its presence with a new title that sounds reminiscent of &lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto V&lt;/em&gt; roleplaying as well as a rebrand of its core survival game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PUxdvD"&gt;First up is a game called &lt;em&gt;Brick Life&lt;/em&gt;, which is billed as “an all-new social roleplay experience.” Players explore a Lego-ified city location with 31 other people and can take on specific jobs like courier, security guard, or sushi chef. Players can design their own homes and explore locations like a magical school and rooftop club, and there are missions to take on as well. From the sounds of it, &lt;em&gt;Brick Life&lt;/em&gt; is a more family-friendly take on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/8/11/23828431/rockstar-cfx-re-mod-tools-roleplay-server"&gt;the enduring popularity of roleplaying servers in &lt;em&gt;GTA V&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Epic isn’t being all that subtle about the connection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="mQW4WB"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Ah bricks here we go again... &lt;a href="https://t.co/1HiNMIbUKX"&gt;pic.twitter.com/1HiNMIbUKX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— LEGO Fortnite (@LEGOFortnite) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/LEGOFortnite/status/1865803561210204202?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 8, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="rGTSp2"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brick Life&lt;/em&gt; is launching inside of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on December 12th, though it won’t be available for players in South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h1e7E5"&gt;As part of the announcement, &lt;em&gt;Lego Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; — the &lt;em&gt;Minecraft&lt;/em&gt;-style survival experience that launched last December — is being renamed &lt;em&gt;Lego Fortnite Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;. From now on, “Lego Fortnite” will be the name of the hub inside of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; that houses all of the Lego experiences. Epic and Lego have been steadily expanding their partnership over the last year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/27/24084644/fortnite-new-lego-games-raft-survival-obby-fun"&gt;launching new games&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/20/24106477/lego-fortnite-user-created-games-epic"&gt;letting &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players build their own Lego games&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QaXblH"&gt;The ongoing collaboration between Lego and &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; could provide a hint at what to expect from the upcoming “persistent universe” that Epic and Disney are making together, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/7/24065281/disney-epic-games-investment-fortnite-metaverse"&gt;following a $1.5 billion investment from Disney in February&lt;/a&gt;. Since then, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/4/24261555/epic-disney-fortnite-unreal-fest"&gt;we’ve heard very little specifics&lt;/a&gt; about what the virtual world might look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLSF7g"&gt;Meanwhile, Epic has also announced that &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; is getting support for a revamped version of text chat, which will be available as an option across all of its experiences starting on December 10th. There will be three kinds of text chat available: party channel for talking with your squad; game channel for a public conversation with people on the same island; and DMs with people on your friends list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="o00PVY"&gt;Epic says there will be two kinds of chat filters — one that removes personal information, and another that filters out “various kinds of mature language and toxicity” — which will be on by default for any players under the age of 13. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/16/23962354/epic-games-fortnite-report-voice-conversations"&gt;The feature will also include a reporting system similar to the voice reporting tool Epic launched last year&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s an example of what text chats look like in the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of Fortnite featuring an in-game text chat." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/3ubHynyP_fizIJkpa20ygm1uT1M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25781166/Fortnite_Text_Chat.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="VEGMdP"&gt;All of these announcements come at a particularly busy time for &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;. The battle royale game is currently in the midst of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/26/24306403/fortnite-minus-one"&gt;a brand-new chapter&lt;/a&gt; that kicked off &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/4/24288014/fortnite-chapter-2-remix-snoop-dogg-times-square-music"&gt;following an ambitious music-themed season&lt;/a&gt;, and Epic also recently &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/12/24294616/fortnite-og-permanent-december-release-date"&gt;brought back the nostalgia-filled &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; OG as a permanent mode&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24315134/fortnite-ballistic-counter-strike-first-person-shooter-fps"&gt;Epic just announced “Ballistic,”&lt;/a&gt; a multiplayer first-person shooter mode that launches inside of &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; on December 11th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316954/lego-fortnite-brick-life-social-roleplay-game"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316954/lego-fortnite-brick-life-social-roleplay-game</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Webster</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft AI CEO Mustafa Suleyman says conversational AI is the next web browser</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo illustration of Microsoft AI CEO Mustafa Suleyman." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p2APKjGCjcYQwCiSocIE9V9rgNU=/1x0:2760x1839/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775946/DCD_Mustafa_Suleyman_Microsoft.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo illustration by The Verge / Photo: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;The company’s new AI chief on working for Microsoft, the OpenAI relationship, and when superintelligence might actually arrive.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24314821/microsoft-ai-ceo-mustafa-suleyman-google-deepmind-openai-inflection-agi-decoder-podcast"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24314821/microsoft-ai-ceo-mustafa-suleyman-google-deepmind-openai-inflection-agi-decoder-podcast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24314821/microsoft-ai-ceo-mustafa-suleyman-google-deepmind-openai-inflection-agi-decoder-podcast</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T09:59:24-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T09:59:24-05:00</updated>
    <title>Raspberry Pi’s new keyboard computer can power an optional $100 display</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Raspberry Pi 500 computer keyboard on a desk connected to the Raspberry Pi Monitor." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gAErz__ovF5snzd-csyG0LW3hgU=/0x1:1220x814/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775927/raspberry_pi_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Raspberry Pi 500 computer keyboard starts at $90, but you’ll need to add your own mouse, power supply, and screen for that price.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Raspberry Pi&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Id14Bq"&gt;Raspberry Pi has announced an &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/news/raspberry-pi-500-and-raspberry-pi-monitor-on-sale-now/"&gt;upgraded version of its compact computer-in-a-keyboard&lt;/a&gt;, adding the new features and performance improvements of the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/28/23889238/raspberry-pi-5-specs-availability-pricing"&gt;Raspberry Pi 5&lt;/a&gt; microcomputer it introduced last September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G6EgNp"&gt;The Raspberry Pi 500, which is &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-500/"&gt;available now&lt;/a&gt; starting for $90, is $20 more expensive than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/11/2/21542278/raspberry-pi-400-keyboard-computer-arm-release-date-news-features"&gt;Raspberry Pi 400 that debuted in late 2020&lt;/a&gt;. That extra cost gets you a 2.4GHz 64-bit quad-core Arm Cortex-A76 processor and 8GB of RAM. If you want more than just the computer keyboard, a $120 Desktop Kit includes it plus a matching mouse, a 27W USB-C power supply, a single micro HDMI cable, and a printed copy of the &lt;em&gt;Raspberry Pi Beginner’s Guide&lt;/em&gt; book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Raspberry Pi Monitor against a gray background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6d0SkysoV042v3Woyk-R4uafcLw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25781160/raspberry_pi_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Raspbery Pi&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Raspberry Pi Monitor features a 15.6-inch full HD IPS panel and built-in speakers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="90jrP0"&gt;The company is also introducing a display for those looking to buy a $220 all-in-one desktop solution. The $100 Raspberry Pi Monitor features a 15.6-inch full HD IPS panel with a built-in pair of 1.2W speakers and a folding stand. The display can be powered directly from a Raspberry Pi microcomputer with a USB port that outputs 1.5A at 5V, which includes the new Raspberry Pi 500 computer and its predecessor. But brightness will be limited to 60 percent while volume maxes out at 50 percent. With its own power supply —which you’ll need to buy separately — you’ll get full volume and brightness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Raspberry Pi 500 computer keyboard against a gray background." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yg3_hQv_AYxhkujdDvQsDo_aQS4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25781174/raspberry_pi_3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Raspberry Pi&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Raspberry Pi 500’s keyboard features a compact tenkeyless design with its various ports accessible on the back.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="RcjSzv"&gt;Other features of the Raspberry Pi 500 computer keyboard include an 800MHz VideoCore VII GPU, a 40-pin Raspberry Pi GPIO connector for attaching peripherals, support for 802.11ac Wi-Fi and Bluetooth 5.0, two USB 3.0 ports, one USB 2.0 port, a gigabit ethernet port, and a single USB-C port that’s only used for power. There are also a pair of micro HDMI ports that can drive two 4K displays at 60Hz each, and a microSD card slot that comes with a 32GB card preloaded with the Debian-based Raspberry Pi operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JjaMrN"&gt;The new Raspberry Pi 500 won’t entirely replace the older Raspberry Pi 400, which is being kept around with a price drop from $70 to $60. The Raspberry Pi 400 Personal Computer Kit, which includes additional accessories like a mouse and power supply, is also getting a price cut from $100 to $80.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316955/raspberry-pi-500-keyboard-computer-monitor"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316955/raspberry-pi-500-keyboard-computer-monitor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Liszewski</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T09:09:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T09:09:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Reddit’s new AI search tool helps you find Reddit answers without Google</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image showing the Reddit logo on a red and white background" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lLYKIbCvk9SbeF-SSYa1hLYpTHI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775861/STK115_Reddit_04.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="LgLcfs"&gt;Reddit is launching a new AI-powered search tool called Reddit Answers to help you more easily find information on the platform. The tool, similar to other AI search products, responds to queries by generating well-formatted responses and showing links to its sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5F6f0A"&gt;But the distinction with Reddit Answers is that it sources things directly from Reddit, which means it could be a way to skip Google and get information directly from the source. Reddit has already been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205244/reddit-blocking-search-engine-crawlers-ai-bot-google"&gt;cracking down&lt;/a&gt; on where you can search for things from Reddit, and Google is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/24/24205244/reddit-blocking-search-engine-crawlers-ai-bot-google"&gt;only major search engine&lt;/a&gt; that shows recent Reddit results. But Reddit probably would prefer if you did searches right on its platform, and Reddit Answers might prove to be a good way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ilmLf"&gt;Reddit Answers will initially roll out to “a limited number of users” in the US and in English, and it will be available on the web (not on Old Reddit) and iOS. (“We’re working on Android as we speak,” Serkan Piantino, Reddit’s VP of product, said in an interview.) Reddit plans to bring the tool to more languages and locations “in the future,” &lt;a href="https://redditinc.com/blog/introducing-reddit-answers"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0gG3oN"&gt;Reddit gave me access to a test version of Reddit Answers, and while I haven’t been able to mess around with it very much, I’ve liked what I’ve seen. There’s a big box to ask a query, but the initial Reddit Answers page also floats a bunch of suggested searches you can click on, like “favorite Nintendo character of all time,” “best mystery novels of 2025,” and “tips for flying with a baby for the first time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7tL7LT"&gt;I clicked that last one, and the tool quickly pulled together a list and some bulleted suggestions with hyperlinks on the text &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; an arrow to click to see the source of the information. When you click either, a sidebar pops up showing the exact post where the information comes from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An example results page for Reddit Answers." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SoTpotPdO_U-cAqLDSb1Q59fJ40=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25777694/Screenshot_2024_12_06_at_2.34.47_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Jay Peters / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is from a test version of Reddit Answers, so things might look a tad different when you try it. But you can get the gist.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="0yCFZ2"&gt;A Reddit site search for the same query on Google, on the other hand, just gave me a standard long list of links to evaluate and click through. On its face, Google’s version, which doesn’t have the summaries or bullet points, isn’t as immediately informative as Reddit Answers. But personally, I’m pretty skeptical of AI summaries anyway — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24313222/chatgpt-pardon-biden-bush-esquire"&gt;they can make some pretty bad errors!&lt;/a&gt; — so for me, the Google results are still perfectly fine as a way to explore some potentially useful posts on Reddit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A screenshot of a Google search for “site:reddit.com + tips for flying with a baby for the first time”" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mbYYa3fEGWI5MF93eDruffiFbrg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25777858/Screenshot_2024_12_06_at_4.29.29_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot by Jay Peters / The Verge&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Reddit site search on Google.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="B9rDh8"&gt;Reddit Answers can also pick up on things happening on Reddit within minutes, according to spokesperson Tim Rathschmidt, so there’s also a chance responses to your queries will have timely results. I haven’t had much luck with that; on Friday, for example, I asked “who won yesterday’s NFL game,” and instead of pulling up answers about Thursday’s Packers-Lions game, it included details on the Eagles-Ravens game that happened on December 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3PV7kd"&gt;That might have just been a quirk of the product not being fully ready yet. In my testing, though, Reddit Answers has been much more useful as a jumping off point to dig into a more general topic on Reddit rather than an up-to-the-minute search tool. And while Reddit Answers is useful, I’m not sure yet if it’s good enough for me to change my habits around using Google to search for things on Reddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Q8OCy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24314445/reddit-answers-ai-powered-search-tool"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24314445/reddit-answers-ai-powered-search-tool</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-09T05:15:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-09T05:15:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>Itch.io went offline due to a ‘trash AI-powered’ phishing report</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Itch indie store" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EyIiBX2jETfau7K9ueh1nJRZZDs=/200x0:2360x1440/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73775550/itch.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UERCht"&gt;Indie game storefront &lt;a href="http://Itch.io"&gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; went offline early Monday morning after what it described as a bogus phishing report. While the game store’s servers were still online during the outage, the domain for the website pointed towards IP addresses that itch.io doesn’t own — making it inaccessible for most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hN5hr7"&gt;After going offline at around 2AM ET, the site seemed to come back at around 7AM ET. Itch.io blames pop culture collectibles company Funko for the issues in a &lt;a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829"&gt;post on X&lt;/a&gt;, “because they use some trash ‘AI-powered’ Brand Protection Software called Brand Shield that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="KBL1rw"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I kid you not, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/itchio?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@itchio&lt;/a&gt; has been taken down by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OriginalFunko?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@OriginalFunko&lt;/a&gt; because they use some trash "AI Powered" Brand Protection Software called &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BrandShieldltd?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BrandShieldltd&lt;/a&gt; that created some bogus Phishing report to our registrar, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/iwantmyname?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@iwantmyname&lt;/a&gt;, who ignored our response and just disabled the domain&lt;/p&gt;— itch.io (@itchio) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1866017758040993829?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 9, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aB6YLH"&gt;While the disputed page was taken down, itch.io’s domain registrar, &lt;a href="https://iwantmyname.com/"&gt;iwantmyname&lt;/a&gt;, still disabled the domain likely due to automated systems. According to a &lt;a href="https://x.com/itchio/status/1866022784222245305"&gt;post on X&lt;/a&gt;, the indie game marketplace had to wait for the domain registrar to respond and re-enable its domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0ehpT6"&gt;The domain issues come just days after itch.io &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295998/you-can-now-use-your-itch-io-url-as-your-username-on-bluesky"&gt;started allowing its users&lt;/a&gt; to use its domain name for Bluesky accounts. If you have spent $10 on the platform then you have the option to use your itch.io profile URL on Bluesky, but the domain issues meant anyone who switched to the custom itch.io URLs had an “invalid handle” error on Bluesky until the main itch.io domain came back online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BHwv2S"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, December 9th: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Noted that Itch is back online.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316882/itch-io-offline-domain-registration-funko-report"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24316882/itch-io-offline-domain-registration-funko-report</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-08T18:48:11-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-08T18:48:11-05:00</updated>
    <title>Trailers of the week: Star Trek, Severance, and Gundam</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Stylized picture of Michelle Yeoh’s Emperor Philippa Georgiou sitting in a chair." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/CLq4tjFTS9rALVHscbYk6s1FX08=/426x0:2000x1049/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73774999/Section_31_Michelle_Yeoh.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Michelle Yeoh in Star Trek: Section 31.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Paramount Plus&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="cswHyX"&gt;It’s the first week of December, and the end of the year is coming in fast and with a lot to look forward to at theaters this month. That very cool-looking &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24226288/the-lord-of-the-rings-war-of-the-rohirrim-anime-trailer"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; anime&lt;/a&gt; hits US theaters on the 13th; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24228966/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-trailer-keanu-reeves"&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog 3&lt;/a&gt; follows on the 20th; and I’m deeply excited to see &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311195/thank-goodness-robert-eggers-saw-nosferatu-1922-on-a-bootlegged-vhs"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nosferatu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on December 25th. (If you’re not with me on that last one, give Matt Zoller Seitz’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295480/y2slay"&gt;RogerEbert.com review&lt;/a&gt; of it a read and get back to me.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iopXfc"&gt;While I’m waiting to go be unnerved by Robert Eggers’ new spooky vampire movie, let’s take a look at some good trailers from the last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="crZLiJ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24315722/star-trek-section-31-official-movie-trailer-michelle-yeoh-paramount-plus-streaming"&gt;Star Trek: Section 31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="QCPjxq"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/63k1Otp9qtM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="lDd5YR"&gt;I’ll admit that the biggest appeal for me about this straight-to-streaming spy movie spinoff of &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Discovery&lt;/em&gt; is Michelle Yeoh as Emperor Philippa Georgiou. She’s just having so much &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; in this trailer. The trailers haven’t revealed yet what threat she’ll be facing, other than being forced to do teamwork, but it seems like it’ll be pretty heavy on the rag-tag team of antiheroes action thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4N6mx8"&gt;The Olatunde Osunsanmi-directed movie also stars Omari Hardwick, Kacey Rohl, Sven Ruygrok, Humberly Gonzalez, Rob Kazinsky, and Sam Richardson. It premieres on Paramount Plus starting January 24th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vBMz5J"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24314837/severance-season-2-trailer-goats-apple-tv-plus"&gt;Severance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="DPw7N5"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_UXKlYvLGJY?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QCkxq9"&gt;I was late to the &lt;em&gt;Severance &lt;/em&gt;party, having finally finished it a few months ago, so I can only imagine how eager people who saw its cliffhanger ending have been to see the story continue. Well, the second season of creator Dan Erickson’s bizarro sci-fi drama is almost here, and it looks like it’s probably going to bring answers, with even more mystery heaped on top of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9BLP7z"&gt;All of the first season’s main characters, including Mark (Adam Scott), Dylan (Zach Cherry), Helly (Britt Lower), and Irving (John Turturro) are returning, and they’ll be joined by characters played by the likes of Alia Shawkat, Gwendoline Christie, and Bob Balaban. Season two of &lt;em&gt;Severance&lt;/em&gt; premieres January 17th on Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="dkyCkN"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316383/invincible-season-3-trailer-amazon-prime-video"&gt;Invincible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="z9gD82"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rbHUhCcSXEM?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5iv07T"&gt;The third season of &lt;em&gt;Invincible&lt;/em&gt; will see a stronger, older Mark Grayson (Steven Yeun) tell off GDA director Cecil Stedman (Walton Goggins) and episodes that show creator Robert Kirkman hopes will each feel like a finale. And there’s no season break this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s8a1Iu"&gt;The show debuts with three episodes February 6th on Amazon Prime, with new episodes releasing every Thursday after until March 13th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IBLEie"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316339/wheel-of-time-season-3-streaming-premiere-amazon-prime-trailer-release-date"&gt;The Wheel of Time&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="vvcKHt"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/erxeLAg85fg?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="LOmNiw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wheel of Time&lt;/em&gt; continues its retelling of the Robert Jordan fantasy epic on March 13th next year. In its third season, the show follows Joshua Stradowski’s Rand al’Thor — the “Dragon Reborn” — and Moiraine Damodred (Rosamund Pike) as they go into the Aiel Waste. It’s been more than two decades since I read the book series, so I couldn’t spoil what happens there for you if I wanted to, but I seem to recall this was a fairly dark time in the series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sAhqs7"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/7/24315769/whats-in-the-gorge-stays-in-the-gorge"&gt;The Gorge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="L97o1w"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rUSdnuOLebE?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="NoVTgP"&gt;Who knows what evil is in &lt;em&gt;The Gorge&lt;/em&gt;’s, uh, gorge, but it’s apparently contained well enough that humanity only needs two snipers — who aren’t allowed to interact with each other — stationed on either side of it to make sure it stays there. The snipers, Levi (Miles Teller) and Drasa (Anya Taylor-Joy), &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;interact and fall for eachother, then end up in the gorge. Oops! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MSiErv"&gt;Scott Derrickson directs the movie, which also stars Sigourney Weaver, Sope Dirisu, and William Houston. It premieres February 14th on Apple TV Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="IK1mSD"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313105/gundam-gquuuuuux-trailer-hideaki-anno-yoji-enokido"&gt;Mobile Suit Gundam GQuuuuuuX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id="NHiGtS"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VZaqtgVtL1M?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Tazqnv"&gt;Giant robot anime fans rejoice: there’s a new &lt;em&gt;Mobile Suit Gundam&lt;/em&gt; coming next year. It’s called &lt;a href="https://en.gundam.info/about-gundam/series-pages/gquuuuuux/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mobile Suit Gundam GQuuuuuuX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;and it’s produced by Khara, the studio behind the &lt;em&gt;Rebuild of Evangelion&lt;/em&gt; films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZQOax"&gt;The weird name references a Gundam called the gMS-Ω GQuuuuuuX. The show will follow a highschooler — named Yuzuriha “Machu” Amate (Tomoyo Kurosawa) — who learns to co-pilot the building-sized, sword-wielding robot with pilot Shuji Ito (Shimba Tsuchiya). Some of its episodes will head to Japanese theaters on January 17th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="qfKJBm"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="RqVG4N"&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p id="BSyL6G"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMVPiI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CxF9Qb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316520/trailers-of-the-week-star-trek-severance-gundam-the-gorge-wheel-of-time-invincible-gundam"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316520/trailers-of-the-week-star-trek-severance-gundam-the-gorge-wheel-of-time-invincible-gundam</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-08T14:49:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-08T14:49:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>The latest Invincible season 3 trailer shows off Mark’s new duds</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2sCGXCDiBQsuctpHkmoJ_EngwGk=/285x0:2717x1621/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73774568/Screenshot_2024_12_08_at_1.41.40_PM.0.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S1lPIO"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invincible &lt;/em&gt;season three is on its way, and Amazon has &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rbHUhCcSXEM?si=uYVYLDo_w0xcVbHH"&gt;released a new trailer&lt;/a&gt; in which hero Mark Grayson takes on robots, rams a rocket in space, and chastises Oliver. He also gets a new blue suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l6gNYT"&gt;“Mark’s speed has increased 65 percent; his endurance, 70 percent; and his strength, 138 percent,” says GDA agent Donald Ferguson (Chris Diamantopoulos), setting up the action-filled trailer. What follows are a &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat-&lt;/em&gt;style beheading, nuclear explosions, and the promise of drama as Mark (Steven Yeun) tells GDA director Cecil Stedman (Walton Goggins) that he’s quitting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HtJx8s"&gt;The action will apparently persist all season long, as &lt;em&gt;Invincible&lt;/em&gt; creator Robert Kirkman &lt;a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/invincible-season-3-tease-robert-kirkman/"&gt;said earlier this year&lt;/a&gt; that he wanted every episode of it to “feel like it’s a finale.” And unlike the last season, this one &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/15/24270890/invincible-season-3-premiere-date-no-break-amazon"&gt;won’t have a midseason break&lt;/a&gt;. Three episodes will start streaming on February 6th, 2025, with a new one following every Thursday through March 13th.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316383/invincible-season-3-trailer-amazon-prime-video"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316383/invincible-season-3-trailer-amazon-prime-video</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-08T14:00:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-08T14:00:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Wheel of Time spins up its third season in March</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Screenshot showing Rand and Moiraine standing in a tent." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4Zua7U0LBVgD-KUKL6WCF68mzXI=/91x0:1989x1265/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73774495/Screenshot_2024_12_08_at_12.41.42_PM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rand (Joshua Stradowski) and Moiraine (Rosamund Pike).&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rSC70k"&gt;Amazon announced at CCXP in Brazil yesterday that season three of Prime Video fantasy series &lt;em&gt;The Wheel of Time&lt;/em&gt; will start streaming on March 13th, 2025, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2024/12/the-wheel-of-time-season-3-premiere-date-trailer-prime-video-1236195835/"&gt;writes &lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The company also &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=erxeLAg85fg"&gt;released a new teaser trailer&lt;/a&gt;, setting stakes that include the life of at least one main character. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NjvZrs"&gt;The trailer opens with Rand al’Thor (Joshua Stradowski) and others standing on a hill overlooking a fog-shrouded city. Rand and Moiraine Damodred (Rosamund Pike) are headed to the Aiel Waste “to uncover the true fate of the Dragon Reborn” in this season, according to the trailer’s description. If you haven’t watched the show or read Robert Jordan’s book series by the same name, Rand is the Dragon Reborn, a prophecied being who could save the world — or destroy it if he succumbs to the Dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="X3AIaX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’ve seen a thousand, thousand futures, and in every one of them, The Wheel of Time returns March 13. Behold the official Season 3 teaser trailer. &lt;a href="https://t.co/ULZiKjWEHy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ULZiKjWEHy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— THE WHEEL OF TIME (@TheWheelOfTime) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheWheelOfTime/status/1865536345696874913?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 7, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VprHRe"&gt;“I have seen a thousand thousand futures. In every future where I lived, Rand dies,” says Moiraine Damodred (Rosamund Pike). “And the only way he lives is if I don’t,” she adds before she’s seen being carried, unconscious, by Rand at the end of the trailer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fRjo4B"&gt;Besides Stradowski and Pike, season 3 will see the return of several characters, including Perrin Aybara (Marcus Rutherford), Nynaeve al’Meara (Zoë Robbins), Mat Cauthon (Dónal Finn), and al-Lan Mandragoran (Daniel Henney). &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316339/wheel-of-time-season-3-streaming-premiere-amazon-prime-trailer-release-date"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24316339/wheel-of-time-season-3-streaming-premiere-amazon-prime-trailer-release-date</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-08T13:04:14-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-08T13:04:14-05:00</updated>
    <title>Sony is still slashing prices on consoles, controllers, and more for the holidays</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Sony DualSense controller" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/47YpuIzRCvUqlUviZ71Yfws6_10=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73774376/cfaulkner_141231_4974_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sony’s “cosmic red” DualSense Wireless Controller is down to $54.99 ($20 off) for a limited time.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Cameron Faulkner / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="At5kr3"&gt;Black Friday and Cyber Monday may be over, but &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fdeals&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sony’s ongoing holiday sale&lt;/a&gt; lives on, giving you a chance to save on various PlayStation 5 consoles, games, and accessories through January 2nd. Now until December 25th, for example, you can save up to $75 on the newer &lt;strong&gt;PS5 “slim”&lt;/strong&gt; (now $424 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0DJHF6Q9Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/xjkpy6p8gucga"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fplaystation-5-console-slim%2F-%2FA-90188801&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;) and the &lt;strong&gt;PS5 Digital Edition &lt;/strong&gt;(now $374 at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation%C2%AE5-Digital-slim-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CL5KNB9M/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/8ju5ctjya02r0"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSony-PlayStation-5-PS5-Digital-Console-Slim%2F5113183757%2F&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="VQcjKS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Sony brings back original PlayStation boot screen with PS5 anniversary update","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/2/24311112/playstation-30th-anniversary-psx-boot-sequence-ps5-update"},{"title":"Sony’s making a handheld console to compete with Nintendo and Microsoft","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/25/24305337/sony-handheld-gaming-console-playstation-nintendo-microsoft"},{"title":"SteelSeries is launching $160 gaming earbuds for your Xbox, PlayStation, or PC","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/26/24253924/steelseries-arctis-gamebuds-earbuds-pc-xbox-playstation-nintendo-switch-release-date-pricing"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nuVvQu"&gt;If you already have a PS5 and are looking for new ways to play, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23601368/sony-playstation-ps-vr2-review-virtual-reality"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PlayStation VR 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is currently on sale at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-VR2-PSVR2-5/dp/B0C1Q9X8VH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.me/cmLNtTk4a88"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fplaystation-vr2-horizon-call-of-the-mountain-bundle%2F-%2FA-88995903&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23600772/horizon-call-of-the-mountain-sony-psvr2-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizon Call of the Mountain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $349 ($250 off), which may be tempting. The virtual reality headset is easy to set up and offers excellent PC-grade immersion, though its lineup still remains somewhat limited nearly two years after its release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="qfreSG"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12113209"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="NMNAzB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12103973"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="fzIFVD"&gt;Not into VR? It’s also a great time to pick up extra controllers, gaming headsets, and other PS5 accessories. Now until December 13th, Sony’s standard &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21562206/ps5-dualsense-controller-review-games-features-vibrations"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DualSense Wireless Controller&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on sale for as low as $54 ($21 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PlayStation-DualSenseTM-Wireless-Controller-Gaming-Console/dp/B0CQKLS4RP?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/pqqy8du894kfs"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fdualsense-wireless-controller-for-playstation-5-midnight-black%2F-%2FA-83374958&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;, while the reflective “Chroma” variants can be had for $59. There aren’t many PS5 controllers we’d recommend over the DualSense, namely because most third-party options lack the adaptive triggers and haptic engine, which add real tension to mirror your in-game actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dfK7iP"&gt;You can also pick up Pulse-branded headsets throughout the same period, including the &lt;strong&gt;Pulse Elite&lt;/strong&gt;, which is down to an all-time low of $129.99 ($20 off) at &lt;a href="https://howl.me/ckX7ZN0AZg2"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-PULSE-Elite-Wireless-Headset%2F5113175920&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fgaming-accessories%2Fgaming-headsets%2Fplaystation-5%2Fproducts%2Fsony-pulse-elite-wireless-gaming-headset-for-playstation-5%2F402800.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;Pulse Explore&lt;/strong&gt; earbuds are also on sale starting at $169 ($30 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds-PlayStation-5/dp/B0CMDFSB89/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.me/ckX7YVHI2Te"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FPlayStation-PULSE-Explore-Wireless-Earbuds%2F5113283042&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. Both use planar magnetic drivers, which noticeably impact the 3D audio listening experience, along with a proprietary low-latency codec that works natively on PS5 consoles and Windows PCs with the included dongle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4hTa9i"&gt;If you’re looking to change up the look of your PS5, you can also pick up one of several &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fdeals%2Fholiday-accessories&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Console Covers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; starting at $44.99 ($10 off). A number of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fdeals%2Fholiday-games&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;games are on sale&lt;/a&gt;, too, including the collector’s editions of &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fbuy-games%2Fmarvels-spider-man-2-collectors-edition-ps5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marvel’s Spider-Man 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $149.99 ($80 off) and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fbuy-games%2Fmlb-the-show-24-collectors-edition-ps5-ps4&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MLB The Show 24&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;for $49.99 ($10 off), along with &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdirect.playstation.com%2Fen-us%2Fbuy-games%2Fastro-bot-ps5&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Astro Bot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for $49.99 ($10 off).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="xxs5OB"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12001102"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="X1rRi9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12051479"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="r8rQDi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12027643"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="vDbMUM"&gt;More deals to shop this weekend&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="c65Ljh"&gt;Now through January 2nd, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mintmobile.com%2Fphone-plans%2F12-month-plans%2F%3Fselected%3DMINT-UNLIMITED-12&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;new &lt;strong&gt;Mint Mobile&lt;/strong&gt; customers can get a year of cellular service&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;unlimited talk, text, and data&lt;/strong&gt; for $180 (50 percent off), which breaks down to $15 a month. You have to pay for all 12 months upfront, but that’s a great value for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/1/24146547/t-mobile-mint-mobile-acquisition-complete"&gt;T-Mobile-owned MVNO carrier&lt;/a&gt;. Just bring your phone, drop in the SIM card (or activate via eSIM), and you can connect to the same 4G LTE and 5G towers that T-Mobile customers do. Just be mindful that you’ll be slowed after using 40GB of data each month, and your video streaming will be limited to 480p.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gPqGP8"&gt;It’s a little nippy out in many parts of the US, but the birds are still cutting through the chilly winds to get their food. Fortunately, you can keep watch on them from the warmth of your home with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/4/23528786/bird-buddy-hummingbird-feeder-ai-camera"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bird Buddy’s smart bird feeder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is currently available for $199 ($20 off) &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fmybirdbuddy.com%2Fproduct%2Fsmart-bird-feeder%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F8%2F24315169%2Fsony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;directly from Bird Buddy&lt;/a&gt;. The feeder will alert you when new visitors arrive, take a photo of them, and even detect their species so you can learn more about them. It also uses a detachable solar roof, allowing it to stay powered indefinitely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="0aGGYZ"&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Marshall Emberton II&lt;/strong&gt;, a Bluetooth speaker that resembles a mini guitar amp, is on sale for $99.99 ($50 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Marshall-Emberton-Portable-Bluetooth-Speaker/dp/B09XXW54QG?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/byrstky28sfap"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.marshall.com/us/en/product/1006788" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Marshall’s online storefront&lt;/a&gt;. While we haven’t reviewed the second-gen model yet, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21308398/marshall-emberton-review-bluetooth-speaker-waterproof-specs-price"&gt;the original&lt;/a&gt; offered a warm, bassy sound signature with well-balanced mids and highs. The sequel builds on it with IP67 water resistance while retaining up to 30 hours of battery life and the ability to sync with multiple units for an even bigger sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="67wvO2"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24315169/sony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24315169/sony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal</id>
    <author>
      <name>Quentyn Kennemer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
