<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-10T11:32:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T11:32:58-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T11:32:58-05:00</updated>
    <title>Over $6 billion in CHIPS Act funding finalized for Micron plants in the US</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="CPUs surrounded by shadowy ones, kinda spooky and the background is red" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f0HuIka5Ewhd3q_cpFWfeIiDlEw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778309/acastro_210430_1777_semiCon_0003.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="fulvTR"&gt;The US Commerce Department &lt;a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2024/12/department-commerce-awards-chips-incentives-micron-idaho-and-new-york"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; it has awarded memory chip maker Micron Technology with “up to $6.165 billion in direct funding” derived from the CHIPS Act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G1uDWU"&gt;The new funding will go towards multiple semiconductor manufacturing projects in the US, including an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/9/1/23332930/micron-idaho-manufacturing-chips-act-biden-white-house"&gt;Idaho plant&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/4/23386906/micron-new-york-chip-factory-investment-syracuse-chips-act"&gt;Syracuse, New York “mega-fab” facility&lt;/a&gt;, both announced in 2022. Between them, the Commerce Department says they’ll create about 20,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="28wG32"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Where the CHIPS Act money has gone","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24166234/chips-act-funding-semiconductor-companies"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="AT3L39"&gt;The grant, which was announced in April, approaches the size of other multibillion-dollar CHIPS Act subsidies given to Intel, TSMC, and Samsung. Micron “is committing to spend approximately $50 billion before the end of the decade,” according to the release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kOp43P"&gt;The Commerce Department says it also “signed a non-binding Preliminary Memorandum of Terms” to give Micron $275 million in proposed funding for the expansion of its Manassas, Virginia facility. The funding goes to Micron with just over a month left before Donald Trump, who has criticized the CHIPS Act, will be inaugurated on January 20th. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1xonW0"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l90MRZ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317897/micron-chips-act-6-1-billion-subsidy-grant-new-plants-idaho-new-york-virginia"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317897/micron-chips-act-6-1-billion-subsidy-grant-new-plants-idaho-new-york-virginia</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T11:28:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T11:28:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Character.AI sued again over ‘harmful’ messages sent to teens</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vector illustration of the Character.ai logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J9XSE7xmrRwf5WNJbZ8VY9zeivM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778297/STK278_character_ai_D.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="OMLsaz"&gt;Chatbot service Character.AI is &lt;a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25450619-filed-complaint/?mode=document&amp;amp;q=founder#document/p10"&gt;facing another lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; for allegedly hurting teens’ mental health, this time after a teenager said it led him to self-harm. The suit, filed in Texas on behalf of the 17-year-old and his family, targets Character.AI and its cofounders’ former workplace, Google, with claims including negligence and defective product design. It alleges that Character.AI allowed underage users to be “ targeted with sexually explicit, violent, and otherwise harmful material, abused, groomed, and even encouraged to commit acts of violence on themselves and others.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gNaPmM"&gt;The suit appears to be the second Character.AI suit brought by the Social Media Victims Law Center and the Tech Justice Law Project, which have previously filed suits against numerous social media platforms. It uses many of the same arguments as an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/23/24277962/character-ai-google-wrongful-death-lawsuit"&gt;October wrongful death lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Character.AI for allegedly provoking a teen’s death by suicide. While both cases involve individual minors, they focus on making a more sweeping case: that Character.AI knowingly designed the site to encourage compulsive engagement, failed to include guardrails that could flag suicidal or otherwise at-risk users, and trained...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317839/character-ai-lawsuit-teen-harmful-messages-mental-health"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317839/character-ai-lawsuit-teen-harmful-messages-mental-health"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317839/character-ai-lawsuit-teen-harmful-messages-mental-health</id>
    <author>
      <name>Adi Robertson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T11:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram will let creators test experimental reels on random people </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Instagram icon is featured in the middle of a background filled with pink, orange, and purple shapes." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/uPl7-kFvoimHpU5buaHsqvjr64o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778209/VRG_Illo_K_Radtke_STK070_Instagram_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Kristen Radtke / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="g8fRCN"&gt;Instagram is allowing creators to test their reel ideas on new audiences before sharing them with followers. Trial reels will be shown to non-followers first, providing engagement data including views, likes, comments, and shares approximately 24 hours after publishing to help creators determine whether it’s worth sharing with people following their account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VYOXbE"&gt;The feature aims to help users try out new ideas and expand their audiences without negatively impacting their established following on the platform, which may be useful for creators who feel chained to a particular style of content. Instagram will provide insights that monitor how trials are performing compared to previous trials that the user has shared. Creators can then choose to share the trial reel with their followers if it’s performing well or set Instagram to automatically share it based on the views it receives within the first 72 hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbQC3j"&gt;“We often hear from creators that they feel nervous about posting too much to their audience or trying out new content that’s outside of their niche on Instagram, for fear of it not resonating with their followers,” Instagram said in its announcement. “Now, if you want to try out a new genre, storytelling format or topic, you can easily get a gut check on how your content might perform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WU8X0N"&gt;Trial reels are rolling out starting today and will be globally available to “all eligible creators in the coming weeks,” according to Instagram. The feature is enabled via a “Trial” toggle before publishing a regular reel, and will appear alongside a user's drafts once live. Only the creator can see that the reel is a trial, and it won’t appear on their main grid or reels tab, or in the feeds or reels tabs of their followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RsdTCo"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LKxgV2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317762/instagram-trial-reels-test-feature-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317762/instagram-trial-reels-test-feature-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jess Weatherbed</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T10:40:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T10:40:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>California could become the first state to require social media warning labels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A smartphone sits on top of a surface with red tape reading “DANGER.” Where one strip intersects the phone, it continues inside the phone’s screen." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B5CMbiYTZq0_MB3BoiuXnIzdi5M=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778178/akrales_220309_4977_0324.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="n2cqic"&gt;A new California bill &lt;a href="https://oag.ca.gov/news/press-releases/attorney-general-bonta-assemblymember-bauer-kahan-introduce-legislation-require"&gt;could require social media platforms&lt;/a&gt; to display warning labels about the potential risk to kids and teens. The &lt;a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB56"&gt;bill (AB 56)&lt;/a&gt;, introduced by Assembly member Rebecca Bauer-Kahan and California Attorney General Rob Bonta, is meant to help address “the growing mental health crisis” among young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hX38Rr"&gt;If passed, social networks would have to show a “black box warning” to all users, regardless of age, during their first time using the platform. The warning, which platforms must display for 90 seconds or more, would then show up at least once a week following its initial appearance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2HBKL4"&gt;After &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/23/23734047/social-media-mental-health-warning-us-surgeon-vivek-murthy"&gt;issuing a public advisory&lt;/a&gt; about social media platforms last year, US Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/17/24180005/surgeon-general-warning-labels-social-media-mental-health"&gt;proposed putting tobacco-like warning labels&lt;/a&gt; on social networks &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/29/23000460/social-media-mental-health-window-puberty"&gt;in response to studies&lt;/a&gt; that link social platforms to mental health issues in young people. Nearly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240920/state-ags-back-surgeon-general-social-media-warning-labels"&gt;40 US states announced their support&lt;/a&gt; of the proposal in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="iqKKUD"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Dozens of states ask Congress to un-doom the Kids Online Safety Act","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/18/24299941/state-ag-letter-congress-pass-child-safety-kosa-deadline"},{"title":"TikTok hit by over a dozen state lawsuits for allegedly harming teens","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/8/24265169/tiktok-lawsuit-state-attorneys-general-kids-mental-health"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="kjCcja"&gt;“Social media companies have demonstrated an unwillingness to tackle the mental health crisis, instead digging in deeper into harnessing addictive features and harmful content for the sake of profits,” Attorney General Bonta said in the press release. “Warning labels alone are not a panacea, they are another tool in the toolbox to address the growing mental health crisis and protect future generations of children.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UhdEhD"&gt;In October, Bonta and several other state attorneys general &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/8/24265169/tiktok-lawsuit-state-attorneys-general-kids-mental-health"&gt;filed a lawsuit against TikTok over claims&lt;/a&gt; it hurts the mental health of children by designing addicting features and promoting things like beauty filters. Meta is also&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/24/23930408/meta-instagram-facebook-child-safety-lawsuit-states-kosa"&gt; facing a lawsuit from dozens of states&lt;/a&gt;, alleging the company misled users about the safety of its products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OUg7uZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/25/24087979/florida-desantis-social-media-age-verification-parental-consent-law"&gt;While some states&lt;/a&gt; have moved forward with their own laws regulating the use of social media, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/18/24299941/state-ag-letter-congress-pass-child-safety-kosa-deadline"&gt;state attorneys general are urging Congress&lt;/a&gt; to pass the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24205718/senate-passes-kids-online-safety-act-kosa-content-moderation"&gt;Kids Online Safety Act (KOSA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317835/california-social-media-warning-labels-bill"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317835/california-social-media-warning-labels-bill</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T10:20:26-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T10:20:26-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon’s online car dealership with Hyundai is now live</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/382WpWBiJ92mPI3b2Y9iOSDmiNs=/155x0:1846x1127/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778133/hero001_aboutamazon_hyundai_autos_amazon_autos_pr_blog_hero_2000x1125a_2000x1127.0.jpeg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mpAlBg"&gt;Today, for the first time, you can buy a car — yes, a whole car — on Amazon. Same-day delivery not guaranteed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dxPREU"&gt;The e-commerce giant’s first foray into car shopping is called &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/b?node=10677469011&amp;amp;linkCode=sl2&amp;amp;tag=aboutamazonin-20&amp;amp;linkId=d58a386ca62282da2a0326b67bec46f4&amp;amp;language=en_US&amp;amp;ref_=as_li_ss_tl" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Auto&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/16/23964233/amazon-car-online-sale-hyundai-dealer-alexa"&gt;The company is partnering with Hyundai dealers in 48 cities&lt;/a&gt; in the US to list vehicles on the site. Customers can browse, order, find financing, and arrange delivery — all within the familiar confines of Amazon’s online ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SA6Diy"&gt;Of course, if you’re looking for anything other than a Hyundai, you’re out of luck. At least for now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AMbz4U"&gt;“With Amazon Autos, we’re bringing the simplicity and ease customers expect from Amazon to car shopping, one of their largest purchases, while offering dealers a new channel to connect with a broad audience,” Fran Jin, global head of Amazon Autos, &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.com/news/retail/amazon-autos-buy-car-online"&gt;said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. “We’re excited to have Hyundai as our exclusive launch partner and look forward to welcoming more brands and expanding our selection to customers as the program grows.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="G75XSZ"&gt;&lt;q&gt;“We’re bringing the simplicity and ease customers expect from Amazon to car shopping.”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="ZzOOTm"&gt;Amazon first announced its plans to get into car buying last year, Previously, customers could browse car showrooms and compare prices on Amazon — but not actually buy a car. With the partnership with Hyundai, Amazon has finally added a key piece of the puzzle. And importantly, the end seller of the vehicle is still the dealer; Amazon’s platform will be the middleman between the customer and the dealership. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LzynR0"&gt;As such, Amazon needs to appeal to dealers almost as much as it does to car shoppers. The company is making its pitch by arguing that it can offer “a new sales channel that connects them with millions of Amazon customers.” And with over 310 million active users, Amazon certainly has the numbers to back it up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZUEesE"&gt;Trade-ins will also be accepted through Amazon’s new car vertical. Customers will have to answer a series of questions about the conditions of the vehicle, after which the request will be processed by an “independent valuation service” to determine the value of the trade-in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/K1U9F89wMVXPyFBWWjizIHkOufU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25783460/Screenshot_2024_12_10_at_10.12.23_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Screenshot: Amazon Autos&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A list of the 48 US cities where Amazon can sell you a car. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="VdzFue"&gt;And for a limited time, Amazon is sweetening the deal by offering a gift card for $2,300 for anyone who buys a car through the site. The card can be applied to the vehicle purchase, but the offer ends on January 10th, 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3eDWjh"&gt;People typically hate car shopping, with &lt;a href="https://www.coxautoinc.com/news/2022-car-buyer-journey-study/"&gt;most surveys&lt;/a&gt; showing that the dealership experience tops people’s lists of frustrations. Tesla has helped spearhead a movement toward a direct-to-consumer (DTC) model in which people buy their vehicles directly from the company, eschewing a dealership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bzOnKb"&gt;Forty-eight states have laws that limit or ban manufacturers from selling vehicles directly to consumers — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/3/18/8251821/tesla-new-jersey-direct-sales-dealerships-christie"&gt;though that has started to shift recently&lt;/a&gt; thanks to Tesla’s popularity. Tesla has no independent dealerships, but dealership associations in multiple states have filed &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/government/tesla-gets-us-assist-lawsuit-challenging-louisiana-direct-sales-ban-2023-10-20/"&gt;numerous lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; against Tesla to prevent the company from selling cars. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NCzcRH"&gt;Amazon’s deal with Hyundai neatly sidesteps this issue by ensuring that dealers remain a crucial part of the process. Most dealers allow customers to browse and buy a car through their own websites, but having Amazon as an additional platform with millions of daily customers is sure to help make the process even easier.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317821/amazon-autos-hyundai-online-car-shopping"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317821/amazon-autos-hyundai-online-car-shopping</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T10:04:33-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T10:04:33-05:00</updated>
    <title>I want to push the big red AC buttons on Genki’s USB-C packed power strip</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Genki Moonbase 240W Desktop Supercharger sitting on a desk next to a keyboard." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XQeW_HSqLe2VeX_y3ShfYRs0guE=/1x0:2250x1499/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778097/genki_moonbase1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Genki’s Moonbase charger can delivery up to 140W of power through one of its USB-C ports.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Genki&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UIKEF3"&gt;Genki has announced its first power strip, capable of charging up to seven devices simultaneously using three AC outlets and four USB-C ports. The Moonbase can deliver up to 240W of power through its USB-C ports — maxing out at 140W to a single device — and will be available with custom USB-C cables featuring built-in lighting, making it easier to plug devices in when it’s dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9bkSI"&gt;The Moonbase is available for preorder now through an &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.indiegogo.com%2Fprojects%2Fgenki-moonbase-240w-desktop-supercharger--2%23%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F10%2F24317792%2Fgenki-moonbase-moonlink-usb-c-power-charger-cables" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Indiegogo crowdfunding campaign&lt;/a&gt; with delivery expected in April 2025. Full retail pricing for the power strip alone is expected to be $120, but it’s discounted to $88 for those who preorder early, or $129 if you also want a set of four of Genki’s Moonlink USB-C cables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ravcGM"&gt;Genki might not be a household name, but since 2019 the company has successfully &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/27/23475551/genki-covert-dock-mini-nintendo-switch"&gt;crowdfunded several products&lt;/a&gt; including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2019/8/8/20791378/genki-covert-dock-portable-nintendo-switch-tv-hdmi-kickstarter"&gt;portable Nintendo Switch docks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/29/24231208/genki-turbocharger-100w-gan-charger-thin-foldable-price"&gt;smaller USB-C chargers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="hCK8pv"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Go4GmAyhR1A?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5cESIF"&gt;Measuring about 7.7 inches in length, the Moonbase features three AC outlets on top that are generously spaced to accommodate chunkier AC adapters and multi-port chargers. The AC outlets feature a transparent design with LEDs that change color at the push of a button. Below the outlets, the power strip incorporates an energy efficient GaN (Gallium Nitride) charger delivering a total of 240W of power through its four side USB-C ports. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PSFPHO"&gt;The maximum power output of an individual USB-C port is limited to 140W, and that’s when just two of them are in use. With devices plugged into all four of the Moonbase’s USB-C ports, two can deliver a maximum of 100W, while the other two top out at just 20W.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Genki Moonlink USB-C cables plugged into the Moonbase power strip." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dHqJ_hie9G2chj1OwR3MhSD-6y8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25783359/genki_moonbase2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Genki&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of the four Moonlink cables includes a built-in display and the ability to handle 240W of power.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="bkunRn"&gt;Not every USB-C cable can handle over 100W of power, so Genki created an optional set of upgraded USB-C Moonlink cables to go along with the Moonbase. Three of the cables support 100W charging and come in small (1-foot), medium (3.3-feet), and large (6-foot) lengths, while the Moonlink+ can handle 240W and includes a built-in LED display showing the current power draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yX4YQ6"&gt;With one end plugged in, all of the Moonlink cables glow on their other end to help illuminate the USB-C port on the device you want to power — the lighting turns off once both ends are plugged in. Although the Moonlink cables are available as part of a bundle with the Moonbase power strip, you only get one of each of the four versions —  unfortunately, you can’t pick and choose which of the cables will work best for your setup.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317792/genki-moonbase-moonlink-usb-c-power-charger-cables"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317792/genki-moonbase-moonlink-usb-c-power-charger-cables</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Liszewski</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T09:32:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T09:32:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Solos challenges Meta’s Ray-Bans with $299 ChatGPT smart glasses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Solos AirGo Vision smart glasses in the krypton 1 frame style." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/U3zCm7bc-loXzewOTl25ad4e0Yw=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73778005/Solo_AirGo_Vision_grey.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Solos&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lTT8tD"&gt;Solos’ camera-equipped smart glasses have arrived to provide some much-needed competition against Meta’s Ray-Bans. The AirGo Vision is &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=1025X1701640&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fsolosglasses.com%2Fpages%2Fairgo%25E2%2584%25A2-v-pre-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;available now starting at $299&lt;/a&gt; — the same price as the Ray-Ban Meta eyewear tech — and features integration with OpenAI’s GPT-4o AI model to identify and answer questions about the people, objects, and text seen by the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dsIsQZ"&gt;That allows the AirGo Vision to do things like translate text into different languages, provide directions to nearby locations or landmarks, and give the wearer more information about what they’re looking at. Solos says the glasses can also be integrated with other AI models like Google Gemini and Anthropic’s Claude, something the company previously teased &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/28/24188457/solos-airgo-vision-glasses-chatgpt-ray-ban-meta-competitor"&gt;when it announced the AirGo Vision in June&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cL48gY"&gt;Like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23922425/ray-ban-meta-smart-glasses-review"&gt;Ray-Ban Meta Smart Glasses&lt;/a&gt;, the AirGo Vision camera can capture photos on demand. A swappable frame system means that you can wear the glasses with or without the camera — the battery and touch sensors used to control the device are housed in the frame’s USB-C chargeable hinges, providing an audio-only option when paired with the standard, no-camera-included AirGo frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mUosO8"&gt;“One thing we promised to deliver on was allowing consumers to have control of their experience with AI and smart technology, particularly with privacy options in mind,” Solos co-founder Kenneth Fan said in the announcement. “That’s why we developed frames that can easily be changed to decide when and where a camera may be appropriate without sacrificing any of the fun features.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7O9L5LvN7FKL8XYA4FDgAiDELy4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25783293/1_R1.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Solos&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a frontal view of the Krypton 1 frame style...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HUIrkt-RXd_WsJYjghOIbPmHyLQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25783298/1_R1__1_.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Solos&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;...compared to the slimmer Krypton 2 design.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="7nvDtQ"&gt;Solos says the Vision comes “with the option to purchase the frame only for $149 or bundle a camera frame with a regular frame for enhanced privacy, priced at $349.” It’s available in seven colors and two frame styles: Krypton 1, which sports a large square design with prominent nose pads, and the slimmer Krypton 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6xbHqW"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LQYOm2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317805/solos-airgo-vision-chatgpt-ai-smart-glasses-price-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317805/solos-airgo-vision-chatgpt-ai-smart-glasses-price-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jess Weatherbed</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T09:22:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T09:22:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Fortnite FTC refunds are starting to show up</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image from Fortnite" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BOevAsvAqsx32lzKAn-CUr88xlM=/150x0:1770x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73777983/fortnite_chapter_6_image.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Epic Games&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mw0o0d"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; players have finally &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/12/ftc-sends-refund-payments-consumers-impacted-epic-games-unlawful-billing-practices"&gt;started receiving refunds&lt;/a&gt; as part of a settlement Epic Games reached with the Federal Trade Commission, which claimed the developer tricked players into making in-game purchases. So far, &lt;a href="https://consumer.ftc.gov/consumer-alerts/2024/12/refunds-way-fortnite-gamers-charged-unwanted-items?utm_campaign=new_consumer_alert:_refun&amp;amp;utm_content=1733768289&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=facebook"&gt;the FTC says&lt;/a&gt; it sent out more than 600,000 payments totaling $72 million, and &lt;a href="https://x.com/aiddennson/status/1866219417652330587"&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://x.com/thoubean/status/1866314100818772374"&gt;players&lt;/a&gt;, including some of us here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, have already reported receiving payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sQHK3W"&gt;In 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/19/23516464/epic-games-ftc-settlement-fortnite-privacy-violations-purchases"&gt;Epic Games agreed to pay $245 million&lt;/a&gt; to compensate players affected by &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt;’s alleged “counterintuitive, inconsistent, and confusing button configuration” that the FTC said led to unwanted purchases. The FTC is currently sending payments to players who submitted valid claims before October 8th, 2024, but it’s reviewing the claims it received after that date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NR59gg"&gt;There’s still time to file a claim for a &lt;em&gt;Fortnite&lt;/em&gt; refund if you haven’t yet, as the FTC is giving players until January 10th, 2025 to submit a claim. You can find more information about the refunds &lt;a href="https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/refunds/fortnite-refunds"&gt;on the FTC’s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317779/fortnite-players-receiving-ftc-refunds"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317779/fortnite-players-receiving-ftc-refunds</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T09:13:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T09:13:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Vergecast Vergecast, part two</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A Vergecast logo, on a Vergecast illustration background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/sKxnj-PmLOSBZNO9Z8lZJehbEos=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73777970/VST_1210_Site.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alex Parkin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="tuLnEq"&gt;Every once in a while, we turn &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; inward. Not only are we constantly covering and discussing what’s happening in the tech and media worlds, we’re also living it ourselves. We’re trying to navigate changes in platforms and economies, and figure out the best ways to do our work and share it with you. And it’s complicated! So, once a year or so, we get into the weeds of how it all works for us here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qqVZKL"&gt;On &lt;a href="https://link.chtbl.com/vergecast"&gt;this episode of &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it’s all inside baseball, all the time. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/helen-havlak"&gt;Helen Havlak&lt;/a&gt;, our publisher (and everybody’s boss), joins the show to talk about our new subscription: why we’re doing it now, how we decided on a price, why we’re not getting rid of &lt;em&gt;all &lt;/em&gt;the ads, and what we’re thinking about going forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="3D9lDy"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.megaphone.fm/VMP8870588891" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 200px;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="RkAqbO"&gt;After that, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/nilay-patel"&gt;Nilay Patel&lt;/a&gt;, our editor-in-chief and your &lt;em&gt;Vergecast&lt;/em&gt; co-host and friend, joins to talk about everything else you’ve been wondering. We talk about host-read ads, what we do during ad breaks, how &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is like a Montessori, what he thinks about our redesign two years later, and more. We got so many good questions — thanks to everyone who called and emailed! — and we couldn’t get to them all, but we tried to answer as many as we could. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6h6OhV"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="The Vergecast Vergecast, part two | The Vergecast|118696" data-volume-uuid="f592f8ef0" data-volume-id="118696" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-198" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3IHdf2"&gt;If you want to know more about what &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; is up to, and where we think (gestures widely) &lt;em&gt;all this &lt;/em&gt;is headed, here are a few links to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5d1TK5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/3/24306571/verge-subscription-launch-fewer-ads-unlimited-access-full-text-rss"&gt;Here we go: &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; now has a subscription&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="CumeMs"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/subscribe"&gt;Subscribe to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7tbusD"&gt;From &lt;em&gt;Status&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.status.news/p/nilay-patel-donald-trump-big-tech-interview"&gt;The Verge Editor-In-Chief Nilay Patel breathes fire on Elon Musk and Donald Trump’s Big Tech enablers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="w53tAX"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24167865/google-zero-search-crash-housefresh-ai-overviews-traffic-data-audience"&gt;Google Zero is here — now what?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="djYyKO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24087834/hank-green-decoder-podcast-google-youtube-web-media-platforms-distribution-future"&gt;Guest host Hank Green makes Nilay Patel explain why websites have a future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="ujgAdu"&gt;Keep sending us questions, too! Call the Vergecast Hotline at 866-VERGE11, or email vergecast@theverge.com, and ask us anything. Our goal is always to be as transparent and accountable as we can — disclosure is our brand, after all — and we’d love to know everything else that’s on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317808/future-of-media-verge-subscription-podcasts-vergecast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317808/future-of-media-verge-subscription-podcasts-vergecast</id>
    <author>
      <name>David Pierce</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-10T09:09:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-10T09:09:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>The dead are still raging in 28 Years Later’s first trailer</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A wide shot of a massive tree growing out of a hill. On either side of the tree stand small groups of naked, emaciated zombies." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oJfZxMrroBbw1LFv9hkZwrEd7dQ=/356x0:1895x1026/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73777967/Screenshot_2024_12_10_at_8.27.03_AM.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bsQkjd"&gt;It feels like we only just heard that Danny Boyle and Alex Garland’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24034340/28-years-later-movie-danny-boyle-alex-garland"&gt;&lt;em&gt;28 Years Later  &lt;/em&gt;was in development&lt;/a&gt;, but the long-awaited sequel already has a full-length trailer and a solid release date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cOF53F"&gt;Set almost 30 years after the initial outbreak of the rage virus, &lt;em&gt;28 Years Later &lt;/em&gt;focuses on the lives of a new group of survivors who have managed to find a modicum of safety living on an isolated, tied island. Because the island is only connected to the mainland by a long, thin, heavily-guarded path that seems like it might disappear when the tide comes in, people like Jamie (Aaron Taylor-Johnson) are able to build semi-stable lives for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ojiiWt"&gt;But things are very different and dangerous on the mainland where time has given rise to all sorts of new mutations in the infected. Though the trailer doesn’t really give you a sense of why Jamie wants to journey into infected territory, it makes it clear that he’ll encounter other people who have somehow managed to survive living among the rabid pseudo-undead. Between the &lt;em&gt;Purge&lt;/em&gt;-like masks and towers of skulls on display in the trailer, the mainland human survivors almost seem more ghoulish than the infected they live in fear of. But as disturbing as the trailer is, what makes it pretty delightful is the news that &lt;em&gt;28 Years Later &lt;/em&gt;is set to hit theaters on June 20th, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317796/28-years-later-trailer"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317796/28-years-later-trailer</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
