<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-13T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Kraven the Hunter is the flimsiest strand in Sony’s spider-free web</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A muscular man in a leather vest leaning down to punch someone in a forest." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f_4kU5Z6LOkW5CPigSzK0FpVbIo=/0x0:1284x856/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784596/DF_05660_rv2_2000x1125_thumbnail.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Sony has made bad Spider-Man spinoff movies before, but Kraven the Hunter is another level of terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24318825/kraven-the-hunter-review"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24318825/kraven-the-hunter-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24318825/kraven-the-hunter-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s NotebookLM AI podcast hosts can now talk to you, too  </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of Google’s multicolor “G” logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/A7MocGwsGzQ7kBVrAabktih_ChM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784598/STK093_Google_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3DBpRp"&gt;Google’s NotebookLM and its podcast-like Audio Overviews have been a surprise hit this year, and today Google company is starting to roll out a big new feature: the ability to actually talk with the AI “hosts” of the overviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WzzqFW"&gt;When the feature is available to you, you can try it out with new Audio Overviews. (It won’t work with old ones.) Here’s how, &lt;a href="https://blog.google/technology/google-labs/notebooklm-new-features-december-2024/"&gt;according to a blog post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Xo3rtx"&gt;Create a new Audio Overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KVWkxE"&gt;Tap the new Interactive mode (BETA) button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ipusmC"&gt;While listening, tap “Join.” A host will call on you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IC7isI"&gt;Ask your question. The hosts will respond with a personalized answer based on your sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VGbWlq"&gt;After answering, they’ll resume the original Audio Overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="32XpIu"&gt;The ability to actually talk with NotebookLM seems like a potentially useful way to learn more about what you’ve collected in the app. But Google cautions that it’s an “experimental feature” and that “hosts may also pause awkwardly before responding or occasionally introduce inaccuracies,” so it may not be a totally polished experience to start. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rcczNm"&gt;In addition to the interactive Audio Overviews, Google is introducing a new interface for NotebookLM that organizes things into three areas: a “sources” panel for your information, a “chat” panel to talk with an AI chatbot about the sources, and a “studio” panel that lets you make things like Audio Overviews and Study Guides. I think it looks nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A GIF showing NotebookLM’s new interface." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9eoQUazpa-jo9hJCpMqHJcTZNg8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25787564/NotebookLM.gif"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;GIF: Google&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="TirK79"&gt;Google is announcing a NotebookLM subscription, too: NotebookLM Plus. The subscription will give you “five times more Audio Overviews, notebooks, and sources per notebook,” let you “customize the style and tone of your notebook responses,” let you make shared team notebooks, and will offer “additional privacy and security,” Google says. The subscription is available today for businesses, schools and universities, and organizations and enterprise customers. It will be added to Google One AI Premium in “early 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6e0n6F"&gt;Google is also launching “Agentspace,” a platform for custom AI agents for enterprises. “Agentspace can provide conversational assistance, answer complex questions, make proactive suggestions and take actions based on your company’s unique information,” Google says. It also has connectors for apps like Microsoft SharePoint, Jira, and ServiceNow.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24318099/google-notebooklm-audio-overviews-talk-plus"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24318099/google-notebooklm-audio-overviews-talk-plus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Platforms need the news — but they’re killing it</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A graphic of a smartphone featuring the faces of tech billionaires. " src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/g_pISBn9Zy3zee6pCfAhP9rK9DE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784482/DCD_1213.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge / Photos: Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Media critic Matt Pearce on ‘Lessons on media policy at the slaughter-bench of history’&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24320380/platforms-tiktok-influencers-news-media-journalism-google-matt-pearce-decoder-podcast-interview"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24320380/platforms-tiktok-influencers-news-media-journalism-google-matt-pearce-decoder-podcast-interview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24320380/platforms-tiktok-influencers-news-media-journalism-google-matt-pearce-decoder-podcast-interview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nilay Patel</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Waymo’s robotaxis pass the first responder test</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Waymo’s robotaxis in San Francisco" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Fowi5ZZ4rz3bd2sNpKWOXbOZji4=/204x0:3512x2205/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784480/1497020128.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YImrW1"&gt;Waymo’s driverless vehicles can detect emergency vehicles, know how to respond to hand signals for traffic cops, and can be disabled manually when something goes wrong, according to an independent review of the company’s first responder protocols. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IVDbwW"&gt;As such, the Alphabet company’s first responder protocols passed an independent review conducted by Tüv Süd, a German tech inspection company. The firm’s assessment found that Waymo’s First Responder Program “meets industry standards” for responding to emergency situations, which is in line with the &lt;a href="https://www.sae.org/standards/content/avsc-i-01-2024/"&gt;best practices&lt;/a&gt; set out in the Society of Automotive Engineers (SAE). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5TkwBx"&gt;Waymo — and indeed the entire autonomous vehicle industry — has been under intense scrutiny, especially around how its driverless cars behave around police, fire, and other emergency responders. But Waymo is staking out the position that it goes beyond what’s required to prove that its vehicles are trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="5kqgQD"&gt;&lt;q&gt;The firm’s assessment found that Waymo’s First Responder Program “meets industry standards”&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="IEBPrX"&gt;Case in point: having its first responder protocols scrutinized by an independent group like Tüv Süd. The company has also publicly released its own guide for first responders who are responding to incidents involving autonomous vehicles. &lt;a href="https://storage.googleapis.com/waymo-uploads/files/documents/first-responders/Emergency%20response%20guide%20and%20law%20enforcement%20interaction%20protocol%20.pdf"&gt;The 32-page document&lt;/a&gt; includes a toll free number for getting in touch with remote operators, a visual guide for disabling the vehicle’s autonomous mode, and instructions for how to disconnect the high-voltage battery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3QKYka"&gt;Waymo also hosts training sessions for police and fire officials in the cities in which it operates. The company says it has trained 15,000 first responders from over 75 agencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8UTfQ"&gt;Waymo isn’t the only company to seek Tüv Süd’s stamp of approval. The German firm also &lt;a href="https://ir.aurora.tech/news-events/press-releases/detail/100/first-of-its-kind-independent-audit-recognizes-auroras"&gt;audited Aurora’s safety guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for its self-driving trucks, as well as protocols for &lt;a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241008155613/en/Gatik-Paves-the-Way-for-Safe-Driverless-Operations-%E2%80%98Freight-Only%E2%80%99-at-Scale-with-Industry-First-Third-Party-Safety-Assessment-Framework"&gt;autonomous freight company Gatik&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4FL3Bv"&gt;Given some of the history, it’s understandable why Waymo feels it needs to go to such lengths to assure first responders that it's a good actor. In San Francisco last year, city &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/10/23789905/waymo-cruise-sf-cpuc-vote-orange-cone"&gt;officials pleaded with regulators&lt;/a&gt; to reconsider a measure to allow robotaxis to operate 24/7, citing a spate of incidents in which autonomous vehicles have stopped traffic, blocked buses, or obstructed emergency vehicles. And despite Waymo’s efforts to promote itself as a safe operator, these incidents keep happening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LChlfD"&gt;Last July, Phoenix police pulled over a driverless Waymo vehicle that was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/6/24193094/phoenix-waymo-car-pulled-over-traffic-stop-oncoming-lane-police"&gt;driving in the oncoming lane of traffic&lt;/a&gt;. (The company blamed “inconsistent” construction signs.) And in October, a Waymo car ignored police in Austin trying to direct traffic outside a football game. Meanwhile, another Waymo partially blocked an intersection nearby and prevented an escorted bus from passing through, &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/local/austin/2024/12/12/cruise-autonomous-vehicle-reports-austin"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Axios&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. (The company said these were minor occurrences and that its vehicles provide thousands of rides each week in Austin without incident.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MDaBwf"&gt;As Waymo continues to slowly march ahead, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24313346/waymo-miami-robotaxi-moove-2026"&gt;launching in new cities&lt;/a&gt; and taking on new partners, the company is mindful that one bad incident is all it takes for everything to collapse. It happened &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/12/7/22158745/uber-selling-autonomous-vehicle-business-aurora-innovation"&gt;to Uber&lt;/a&gt; and, more recently, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318651/cruise-robotaxi-gm-funding-autonomous-vehicles-risk"&gt;to Cruise&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why it needs to take all precautions it can to prove that its vehicles are as safe, if not safer, than human drivers. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24319860/waymo-robotaxi-first-responder-tuv-sud-analysis"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24319860/waymo-robotaxi-first-responder-tuv-sud-analysis</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew J. Hawkins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T09:41:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T09:41:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>NASA thinks it’s figured out why the Mars helicopter crashed</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="NASA’s Ingenuity helicopter on the surface of Mars." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XlLZB9qFMv8yzZ_QhxwDFEVKNyc=/52x0:949x598/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784452/mars_helicopter.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A color image taken by Perseverance’s Mastcam-Z instrument of NASA’s Ingenuity Mars helicopter in April 2023.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: NASA/JPL-Caltech/ASU/MSSS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="MXZo2P"&gt;Ahead of a full technical report that’s expected to be released in the next few weeks, engineers from NASA’s Jet Propulsion Laboratory and AeroVironment have &lt;a href="https://www.nasa.gov/missions/mars-2020-perseverance/ingenuity-helicopter/nasa-performs-first-aircraft-accident-investigation-on-another-world/"&gt;revealed what’s believed to be the cause of the Ingenuity Mars Helicopter’s crash&lt;/a&gt; on January 18th, 2024. The craft’s vision navigation system, which was designed to track textured features on the surface of Mars, was confused by a featureless stretch of rippled sandy terrain, resulting in incorrect velocity estimates that led to a hard landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="77IQof"&gt;Relying on remote data, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/4/29/23044697/mars-nasa-ingenuity-helicopter-perseverance-space"&gt;including photographs taken after the flight&lt;/a&gt;, the investigators believe that “navigation errors created high horizontal velocities at touchdown,” which most likely resulted in Ingenuity experiencing a “hard impact on the sand ripple’s slope,” causing it to pitch and roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="An illustration that details what NASA believes happened to Ingenuity after its final flight." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/0kNRsg8cYpuQMkUWMuZM6sQyN6k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25788347/nasa_landing.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Illustration: NASA/JPL-Caltech&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;A graphic shared by NASA depicts what’s thought to be the most likely scenario for Ingenuity Mars Helicopter’s final flight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DMIQ9x"&gt;NASA’s engineers originally assumed that Ingenuity’s spinning rotor blades were damaged after making contact with the surface of Mars during the crash. They now believe they snapped off because “the rapid attitude change resulted in loads on the fast-rotating rotor blades beyond their design limits.” A part of one of the rotor blades was located about 49 feet away from the craft’s final resting place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="F0QfGd"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"NASA’s Mars helicopter had a midair brain fart","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2021/5/28/22457316/nasa-ingenuity-mars-helicopter-navigation-glitch-sixth-flight"},{"title":"NASA’s Mars Helicopter has made its final flight.","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24051192/nasas-mars-helicopter-has-made-its-final-flight"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2Gxx0Q"&gt;Communications were lost during the crash as a result of excessive vibration in the damaged and unbalanced rotor system that resulted in an excessive power demand. However, despite being permanently grounded, communications were reestablished the next day, and Ingenuity “still beams weather and avionics test data to the Perseverance rover about once a week,” which NASA says “is already proving useful to engineers working on future designs of aircraft and other vehicles for the Red Planet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xpYjqx"&gt;Initially designed to perform only up to five experimental flights over the course of a month on Mars, Ingenuity &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/19/22391496/nasa-ingenuity-helicopter-mars-flight-success"&gt;operated for almost three years&lt;/a&gt; and accumulated over two hours of flight time across 72 flights.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320329/nasa-mars-perseverance-ingenuity-helicopter-crash"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320329/nasa-mars-perseverance-ingenuity-helicopter-crash</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Liszewski</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T09:39:05-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T09:39:05-05:00</updated>
    <title>Airbnb’s anti-party tech is cracking down on ‘unauthorized’ get togethers</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration of Airbnb logo in The Verge’s iconic style." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/RMcdA28tQx-546iG9i1FN3TI7Ww=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784448/acastro_STK090_04.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Airbnb would prefer if you have your rowdy New Year’s Eve bash elsewhere.&lt;/em&gt; | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="YM2LxJ"&gt;If you were thinking of booking an Airbnb to host a rowdy New Year’s Eve shindig, the company is already one step ahead of you. Airbnb says it’s &lt;a href="https://news.airbnb.com/anti-party-crackdown-over-new-years-eve/"&gt;rolling out anti-party technology&lt;/a&gt; worldwide to help prevent “unauthorized and disruptive” get togethers over the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oRbD4B"&gt;Airbnb describes its anti-party technology as machine learning tools to identify and block risky bookings. The tech will be rolled out globally, but Airbnb specifically called out the US, UK, Australia, Canada, France, Puerto Rico, Spain, and New Zealand. It assesses things like trip length, when the reservation is being made, and how far the booking is from your current location. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LKPQdo"&gt;If a booking is deemed a high risk, guests will either be blocked or redirected to different accommodations. For folks hoping to book an entire home for a short holiday getaway, reservations of one to three nights will also be blocked. Guests booking entire homes will also have to agree to a “mandatory anti-party attestation.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qUpGlR"&gt;Airbnb says it blocked 74,000 such bookings last New Year’s Eve, with roughly 33,000 of those coming from the US. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VVsGV2"&gt;The company’s stance against disruptive parties isn’t new. It started &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/12/20/22846414/airbnb-party-night-rentals-new-years-eve-restrictions"&gt;banning “party houses” in 2019&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/20/21377408/airbnb-global-ban-house-parties-coronavirus"&gt;added tighter restrictions&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 during the covid-19 pandemic as a public health measure. Airbnb then decided to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/28/23186141/airbnb-party-ban-policy-16-person-occupancy-limit-lifted"&gt;permanently ban&lt;/a&gt; rowdy parties worldwide in 2022. The decision came after &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Business/airbnb-issues-permanent-global-party-ban-wake-string/story?id=85917930#:~:text=In%20April%2C%20two%20teenagers%20were,by%20jumping%20out%20of%20windows."&gt;several shootings occurred at parties&lt;/a&gt; hosted at Airbnbs, including an incident where &lt;a href="https://www.publicsource.org/mass-shooting-at-airbnb-party-leaves-two-teens-dead-upends-small-north-side-neighborhood/"&gt;two teenagers were killed&lt;/a&gt; and eight people wounded at a Pittsburgh rental. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320345/airbnb-anti-party-tech-new-years-eve"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320345/airbnb-anti-party-tech-new-years-eve</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T09:32:51-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T09:32:51-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Backbone One with USB-C is just $50 for today only</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Backbone One" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-NmZjn0zKXl0Y31pRwF-OrHdz_Q=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784442/cfaulkner_220630_5324_0006.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The USB-C Backbone One (second-gen) offers the same experience as the Lightning version pictured.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GtTk9z"&gt;As good as the Backbone One is (&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/11/24175498/backbone-one-smartphone-iphone-android-game-controller-deal-sale"&gt;read our review of the original version&lt;/a&gt;), it can be hard to justify earmarking $100 for a mobile gaming controller. Even at its common $70 sale price, you’re entering pro controller territory. That said, a 50 percent discount for the second-gen &lt;strong&gt;Backbone One (USB-C)&lt;/strong&gt; seems worth jumping over the fence for. Today only, you can get it for $49.99 at &lt;a href="https://howl.link/m2izynfmle3vn"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, which is a record low price and just in time for the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/7/24264510/the-resident-evil-2-remake-is-coming-to-apple-devices-on-new-years-eve"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resident Evil 2&lt;/em&gt; remake that’s soon launching on the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="euhKcb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Final Fantasy XIV Mobile will bring Eorzea to your phone ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24301435/final-fantasy-14-mobile-square-enix"},{"title":"Destiny: Rising is a new mobile RPG shooter set in Bungie’s Destiny universe ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/14/24269790/destiny-rising-mobile-rpg-shooter"},{"title":"Monster Hunter is getting an open-world RPG spinoff for mobile ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/12/24294524/monster-hunter-outlanders-mobile-game"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5VsoMv"&gt;The Backbone One’s USB-C connector means it works both with Android smartphones and iPhones 15 or newer. It’s sleek with a bubbly grip sized &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; right to comfortably reach any of its face buttons, triggers, bumpers, or analog sticks. Ergonomically, it’ll lose to bulkier controllers, but should feel pretty good in most hands and is infinitely better than pecking away at the screen. The controller also has USB-C passthrough charging and 3.5mm for headphones and headsets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gloqgP"&gt;The Best Buy-exclusive &lt;em&gt;Warzone Mobile&lt;/em&gt; edition on sale here is mostly a spiritual tie-in: it’s visually and functionally identical to the standard Backbone One, but comes with free in-game rewards. You can use it with any games or apps with controller support, including cloud streaming services like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/14/24269925/xbox-cloud-gaming-call-of-duty-black-ops-6-warzone-support"&gt;Xbox Cloud Gaming&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23561989/nvidia-geforce-now-rtx-4080-price-reflex-hands-on-cloud-gaming"&gt;GeForce Now&lt;/a&gt;. The purchase includes a free one-month trial of Backbone Plus ($40 a year afterward), which unlocks more app features like gameplay recording, live streaming, and Play on Any Screen (the latter enabling wired gaming on PC and tablets). You’ll also get three months of Apple Arcade ($7 a month value).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="IJbrjv"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12290474"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2KS73A"&gt;More deals and discounts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Y6zII0"&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Logitech G203 Lightsync &lt;/strong&gt;is on sale starting at $18.99 ($21 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07YN82X3B/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/3xhkiek28ebwj"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://imp.i125364.net/c/482924/795933/11355?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.logitechg.com%2Fen-us%2Fproducts%2Fgaming-mice%2Fg203-lightsync-rgb-gaming-mouse.910-005790.html&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Logitech&lt;/a&gt;. The wired gaming mouse doesn’t boast the same button count or overall features from the brand’s flagship models. That said, it still has six programmable buttons total, plus an accurate sensor 8,000 DPI optical sensor and a scroll wheel with lock. It even has a touch of RGB lighting that you can customize with your favorite colors or sync to the action in your game using the G Hub app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kBg9UZ"&gt;You can get the &lt;strong&gt;Anker Power Bank (30W, Fusion, Built-In USB-C Cable) &lt;/strong&gt;in black for $19.99 (50 percent off) from &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CFKSJMVJ/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when clipping the on-page coupon.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The versatile travel-friendly charger has a built-in folding wall plug on one end to charge the 5,000mAh battery inside, but you can use the USB-C cable on the opposite end to do the same. There’s versatility in charging modes, too — you can use it in battery mode with the USB-C cable to charge smartphones or other devices at 22.5W speeds, or plug it into an AC outlet and use it as a 30W USB-C adapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="TQhe88"&gt;Besides its name potentially stoking cravings for a sweet roll, the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/9/24239682/ultimate-ears-miniroll-bluetooth-speaker-price-availability"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimate Ears Miniroll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;may pique your interest for other reasons, one being the record low $49.99 price &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ultimate-Ears-Ultra-Portable-Waterproof-Bluetooth/dp/B0DCJ9N5XR/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.sweetwater.com%2Fstore%2Fdetail%2FMiniRollMRG--ultimate-ears-miniroll-compact-bluetooth-speaker-majestic-revive-gray%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F13%2F24319689%2Fbackbone-one-usb-c-mobile-gaming-controller-logitech-g203-mouse-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sweetwater&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://ultimate-ears.dubn.net/c/482924/500013/8590?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ultimateears.com%2Fen-us%2Fshop%2Fp%2Fminiroll.984-002015&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Ultimate Ears&lt;/a&gt; have it for right now. The portable Bluetooth speaker is circular, roundish, and small enough to stow in a bag or pocket, and the integrated clip lets you attach it to belt loops, straps, pole, and any other object thin enough to clamp. The IP67 speaker has oversized buttons and floats in water, too, and lasts up to 12 hours per charge. You can buy a second one and sync it for stereo sound, but you may find it surprisingly loud on its own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="F5OXTR"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24319689/backbone-one-usb-c-mobile-gaming-controller-logitech-g203-mouse-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24319689/backbone-one-usb-c-mobile-gaming-controller-logitech-g203-mouse-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Quentyn Kennemer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T09:29:20-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T09:29:20-05:00</updated>
    <title>Tumblr adds Reddit-like ‘communities’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration featuring the Tumblr wordmark logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/29xBlz53ep2xWs1-tq09vc4gEAc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784434/STK137_Tumblr_K_Radtke_02.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="HWqsN0"&gt;Tumblr is &lt;a href="https://staff.tumblr.com/post/769680688183164928/tumblr-theyre-here-communities-are-finally"&gt;introducing&lt;/a&gt; a new Community feature — in-app groups organized by topic or interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RInO8J"&gt;Communities are similar to subreddits or Facebook groups and had previously been in beta.  Topics include things like film photography, marine biology, LGBTQ, and video games, and each topic has its own landing page where posts shared with the community populate. Many of the features mirror Reddit, like a count of how many members are online, moderators,  and community guidelines. Posts shared to communities also get a new comments section that’s only visible within the group. Communities have the option to be public or private.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Tumblr’s landing page for the video games community, with related tags, member information, and a feed of posts." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/akU5G7mRUDYVbardEm6FVmM2x7A=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25788338/Screenshot_2024_12_13_at_8.27.34_AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Tumblr&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tumblr’s video games community&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="vBP3bz"&gt;Tumblr pulling a page from Reddit’s playbook shouldn’t be surprising. As other communities and forums on the web have died off or been eaten by Google, Reddit has been on the up-and-up, growing its user base and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/29/24283056/reddit-earnings-user-growth-revenue-up"&gt;turning a profit for the first time&lt;/a&gt;. But Subreddits managed by users are both Reddit’s crown jewels and a thorn in the side of corporate interests, as demonstrated by the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/6/12/23755974/reddit-subreddits-going-dark-private-protest-api-changes"&gt;coordinated action taken&lt;/a&gt; last year in protest of changes to the platform’s API pricing structure. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/c/23998379/google-search-seo-algorithm-webpage-optimization"&gt;As Google Search degrades in usefulness&lt;/a&gt; — or is replaced by AI summaries — platforms like Reddit have become a central part of finding helpful information online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SLWvfn"&gt;Reddit is also adding search engine-like features, including &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24314445/reddit-answers-ai-powered-search-tool"&gt;an AI-powered summary tool called Answers&lt;/a&gt; announced earlier this week. Though Tumblr’s communities feature — and Tumblr in general — isn’t the search destination Reddit is, the new grouping feature does streamline how users can find and engage with topic-based content and peers with similar interests. Communities is available on the web, iOS, and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320336/tumblr-communities-reddit-topics-groups"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320336/tumblr-communities-reddit-topics-groups</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T09:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple MacBook Pro (M4 Pro and Max) review: still on top</title>
    <content type="html">
  &lt;p&gt;The 14- and 16-inch MacBook Pros are still the best laptops for creative professionals. This year they’re a little faster, with better webcams, new anti-glare screen options, and that’s mostly it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24319419/apple-macbook-pro-m4-max-pro-review-price-specs"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24319419/apple-macbook-pro-m4-max-pro-review-price-specs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24319419/apple-macbook-pro-m4-max-pro-review-price-specs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Antonio G. Di Benedetto</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-13T08:44:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-13T08:44:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>Searching for the first great AI app</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Photos of Google’s Project Astra, on a Vergecast background." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/L5ha3aQC583pqkeZ5INarnmTKwQ=/1x0:2040x1359/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73784331/VRG_VST_1213_Site.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alex Parkin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="jWy7dk"&gt;ChatGPT launched roughly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24318650/chatgpt-openai-history-two-year-anniversary"&gt;two years and two weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. Now, as we near the end of 2024, the AI race is... well, where is it, exactly? It’s more competitive than ever, there’s more money being poured into new models and products than ever, and it’s not at all clear when or even whether we’re going to get products that make it all worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RIC2Zz"&gt;On &lt;a href="https://link.chtbl.com/vergecast"&gt;this episode of &lt;em&gt;The Vergecast&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we talk about a lot of different AI news, all along a single trend line: the tech industry trying desperately to build a killer app for AI. (Ideally, for them, also one that makes money.) &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/richard-lawler"&gt;Richard Lawler&lt;/a&gt; joins us as we discuss Google &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318444/google-gemini-2-0-flash-ai-model"&gt;Gemini 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent"&gt;Project Astra and Project Mariner&lt;/a&gt;, and everything else Google is doing to put AI in the products you already use every day. We also talk through the new Android XR announcement, and Google’s renewed commitment to making headsets and smart glasses that work. It’s all an AI story, no matter how you look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="0xRTph"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.megaphone.fm/VMP2346089447" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 200px;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="XyKSkY"&gt;After that... more AI! We talk about the launch and near-immediate disappearance of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317092/openai-sora-text-to-video-ai-launch"&gt;OpenAI’s Sora&lt;/a&gt;, what’s new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317119/ios-18-2-apple-intelligence-chatgpt-genmoji"&gt;in iOS 18.2&lt;/a&gt;, Reddit’s clever-but-primitive &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24314445/reddit-answers-ai-powered-search-tool"&gt;new Answers feature&lt;/a&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EgNnwE"&gt;Finally, in the lightning round, it’s a smorgasbord of tech news. YouTube is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318434/youtube-living-room-tv-growth-2024"&gt;big on TVs&lt;/a&gt;; Instagram is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317762/instagram-trial-reels-test-feature-availability"&gt;testing a way&lt;/a&gt; for you to test your posts; the TikTok ban is coming, but a sale &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317094/donald-trump-tiktok-ban-sale-meet-the-press-interview"&gt;sounds like the answer&lt;/a&gt;; Sonos once again &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24315195/sonos-arc-ultra-soundbar-review-dolby-atmos-more-bass"&gt;made a great soundbar&lt;/a&gt;; and what the heck &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24318259/gm-cruise-shutdown-robotaxi-super-cruise"&gt;happened to Cruise&lt;/a&gt;? The year’s almost over, but the news keeps coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="gBRlzp"&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Searching for the first great AI app | The Vergecast|118733" data-volume-uuid="813f48b75" data-volume-id="118733" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" data-volume-autoplay="false" id="volume-placement-530" class="volume-video" data-volume-player-choice="youtube"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="6gJPVR"&gt;If you want to know more about everything we discuss in this episode, here are some links to get you started, beginning with Google:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="4zLp2u"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent"&gt;Google’s AI enters its ‘agentic era’ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="v72FHZ"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318444/google-gemini-2-0-flash-ai-model"&gt;Gemini 2.0: what’s new in Google’s new flagship AI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mhyMZe"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318672/google-smart-glasses-ai-gemini"&gt;Google’s AI-powered smart glasses are a little closer to being real &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="gb2b9R"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318628/jules-google-ai-coding-agent-gemini-2-0-announcement"&gt;Google’s new Jules AI agent will help developers fix buggy code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="EcOmwK"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318530/google-gemini-2-0-understand-rules-video-games-genie"&gt;Google is testing Gemini AI agents that help you in video games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kFHuxT"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318217/google-gemini-advanced-deep-research-launch"&gt;Google built an AI tool that can do research for you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="f4KnKG"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/12/24319528/google-android-xr-samsung-project-moohan-smart-glasses"&gt;I saw Google’s plan to put Android on your face&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="bGuhBD"&gt;And in other AI news:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="otvb0F"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317092/openai-sora-text-to-video-ai-launch"&gt;OpenAI has finally released Sora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="7ewyka"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317119/ios-18-2-apple-intelligence-chatgpt-genmoji"&gt;iOS 18.2 is out now, adding ChatGPT integration and more Apple Intelligence tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="lPekSt"&gt;From &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/personal-tech/apple-iphone-ios-18-update-review-ai-fc304bec"&gt;iOS 18.2 Review: The AI Apple Promised Us&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6kOhRB"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24318122/chatgpts-side-by-side-canvas-view-is-now-available-to-everyone"&gt;ChatGPT’s side-by-side ‘Canvas’ view is now available to everyone. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GNZWWO"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24314445/reddit-answers-ai-powered-search-tool"&gt;Reddit’s new AI search tool helps you find Reddit answers without Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="XTmcRw"&gt;And in the lightning round:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="7nbAQy"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318434/youtube-living-room-tv-growth-2024"&gt;YouTube is still growing fast on TVs in the living room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="8TZy3Z"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317762/instagram-trial-reels-test-feature-availability"&gt;Instagram will let creators test experimental reels on random people&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="FMHHT3"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DDZ15g9vs0v/"&gt;Adam Mosseri’s post on trial reels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="g7GJed"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317094/donald-trump-tiktok-ban-sale-meet-the-press-interview"&gt;It sure sounds like Trump would be okay with a TikTok sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="57SBLo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24315195/sonos-arc-ultra-soundbar-review-dolby-atmos-more-bass"&gt;Sonos Arc Ultra review: don’t call it a comeback (yet)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="6Cf6ZA"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24318259/gm-cruise-shutdown-robotaxi-super-cruise"&gt;Cruise’s robotaxi service will likely shut down as GM pulls its funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="GpRObF"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/10/24317821/amazon-autos-hyundai-online-car-shopping"&gt;Amazon’s online car ‘dealership’ with Hyundai is now live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320342/ai-killer-app-gemini-chatgpt-vergecast"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/13/24320342/ai-killer-app-gemini-chatgpt-vergecast</id>
    <author>
      <name>David Pierce</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
