<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-04T11:23:07-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T11:23:07-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T11:23:07-05:00</updated>
    <title>Misinformation researcher admits ChatGPT added fake details to his court filing</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration of a robot brain." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_q7tvwzXjd0IuLmbWNUFx-4cF0o=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73766113/STK_414_AI_A.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ttLQG8"&gt;A misinformation expert &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/21/24301955/minnesota-deepfake-bill-lawsuit-affidavit-ai"&gt;accused of using AI to generate a legal document&lt;/a&gt; admitted he used ChatGPT to help him organize his citations, leading to “hallucinations” that critics said called the entire filing into question. Jeff Hancock, the founder of the Stanford Social Media Lab who wrote the document, says the errors don’t change the “substantive points in the declaration.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="P1IovQ"&gt;Hancock submitted the affidavit in support of Minnesota’s “Use of Deep Fake Technology to Influence an Election” law, which is being challenged in federal court by Christopher Khols — a conservative YouTuber who posts under the name Mr Reagan — and Minnesota state Rep. Mary Franson. After discovering that Hancock’s filing seemed to contain citations that didn’t exist, attorneys for Khols and Franson said it was “unreliable” and asked that it be excluded from consideration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fxXQK6"&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mnd.220348/gov.uscourts.mnd.220348.39.0.pdf"&gt;subsequent declaration&lt;/a&gt; filed late last week, Hancock acknowledged that he used ChatGPT to draft the declaration but denies he used it to &lt;em&gt;write &lt;/em&gt;anything. “I wrote and reviewed the substance of the declaration, and I stand firmly behind each of the claims made in it, all of which are supported by the most recent scholarly research in the field and reflect my opinion as an expert regarding the impact of AI technology on misinformation and its societal effects,” Hancock wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h7e4hC"&gt;As for the citation errors, Hancock explained that he used Google Scholar and GPT-4o “to identify articles that were likely to be relevant to the declaration so that I could merge that which I knew already with new scholarship.” Hancock says he used GPT-4o to create a citation list, not to write the document, and didn’t realize the tool generated “two citation errors, popularly referred to as ‘hallucinations’” and added incorrect authors to another citation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HqIRcL"&gt;“I did not intend to mislead the Court or counsel,” Hancock wrote in his most recent filing. “I express my sincere regret for any confusion this may have caused. That said, I stand firmly behind all the substantive points in the declaration.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313132/jeff-hancock-minnesota-deepfake-law-ai-hallucinations-citation"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313132/jeff-hancock-minnesota-deepfake-law-ai-hallucinations-citation</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gaby Del Valle</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T11:20:10-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T11:20:10-05:00</updated>
    <title>2024 in review: AI</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Wireframe brain to illustrate AI." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DaUlHuHTGe9G3kijTalLESp6KlU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73766099/STK_414__AI_EOY.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge, Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="lhlAuw"&gt;In 2024, you couldn’t escape hearing about AI. From &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24145141/ai-gadgets-smartphones-meta-rabbit"&gt;smartphones&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/3/24148513/meta-rayban-smart-glasses-ai-wearable-race"&gt;wearables&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24043060/smart-home-interface-map-view-samsung-lg-amazon-ces-2024"&gt;smart home&lt;/a&gt;, it seemed every tech company wanted to pitch their &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24278413/ai-manifesto-anthropic-dario-amodei-agi-digital-god-openai-sam-altman-decoder-podcast"&gt;next great AI innovation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5tfJvS"&gt;The year was filled with impressive technological leaps and useful new tools, endless hype and frequent misfires, and implications for the future that range from truly exciting to unpredictable. This is the year we got a sense of what AI might actually do — and just how unprepared we still are to grapple with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0LyiC"&gt;Here at &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, we thought a lot about AI’s impacts on the industries and people we cover. From strikes across industries like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/5/24213808/video-game-voice-actor-strike-sag-aftra"&gt;gaming&lt;/a&gt; to its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24211177/ai-climate-crisis-energy-use-microsoft-openai-chatgpt-google-gemini-decoder-podcast"&gt;impact on our climate&lt;/a&gt; to the desire for &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/24/24253439/california-sb-1047-newsom-hollywood-sag-aftra-ai-safety"&gt;policy protections for Hollywood&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/12/24197058/eu-ai-act-regulations-bans-deadline"&gt;AI Act&lt;/a&gt;, AI is already reshaping nearly every area of our lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cIZgup"&gt;So let’s take a look back at some of the biggest, boldest, weirdest AI stories from the last year — and look ahead to what could be in store for 2025. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24305880/artificial-intelligence-ai-chatgpt-openai-google-generative-year-in-review"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24305880/artificial-intelligence-ai-chatgpt-openai-google-generative-year-in-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24305880/artificial-intelligence-ai-chatgpt-openai-google-generative-year-in-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:52:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:52:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>GM and EVgo now have over 2,000 EV charging stalls and counting </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Picture of an EV truck in a parking lot, plugged into an EVgo / GM Energy fast charger." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VWrnyXVCq3uUnacPOKi4Np62mFo=/6x0:1275x846/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765988/GM_EVgo_fast_charging.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of the co-branded GM Energy / EVgo fast chargers.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: General Motors&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="FeE7Mk"&gt;General Motors and EV charging company EVgo &lt;a href="https://news.gm.com/home.detail.html/Pages/topic/us/en/2024/dec/1204-evgo.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that they’ve installed their 2,000th public EV charging stall, in Murrieta, California. With that, GM has met a deadline it &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/12/24242068/gm-energy-evgo-ev-dc-fast-charging-network-flagship-locations"&gt;set in September&lt;/a&gt; to have the bulk of its planned 2,850 DC fast-charging stalls set up by the end of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LVCUuR"&gt;GM says the new station, which is near Interstate 215 in Riverside County, serves five 350kW fast chargers for as many as 10 EVs simultaneously. It doesn’t mention whether these are strictly CCS chargers or if they include Tesla’s NACS ports, which have emerged as the de facto standard over the last year and a half. We’ve asked GM for more information and will update if it responds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="poCLfb"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"GM offers free nighttime charging to Chevy EV owners in Texas ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/13/24295809/gm-chevy-ev-reliant-free-nighttime-charging"},{"title":"An analysis of 20,000 EV stations concludes that charging is still a massive bummer","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/6/24214581/electric-vehicle-charging-reliability-study-chargehelp"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="9kkmcB"&gt;EVgo president Dennis Kish said that its relationship with GM has helped his company “bring public charging to communities in more than 30 states across the US,” and that the company is working toward deploying its “first flagship destinations next year.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTKQqc"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/12/24242068/gm-energy-evgo-ev-dc-fast-charging-network-flagship-locations"&gt;GM said back in September&lt;/a&gt; that this network, which is distinct from another planned 2,000-strong network of DC fast chargers at &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/5/23988171/gm-ev-charging-station-progress-pilot-evgo"&gt;Flying J and Pilot truck stops&lt;/a&gt;, will include 400 “flagship” gas station-style charging locations. Those will be built out in major metropolitan areas of states like Florida, California, Texas, and Michigan, the company said today. That’s all in addition to &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; EV charging network consortium &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24176160/ionna-ev-charging-dc-fast-headquarters-network"&gt;called Ionna&lt;/a&gt; that GM is participating in along with car companies like Hyundai, Kia, BMW, and Stellantis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KN0itG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DUAMAj"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313038/gm-and-evgo-now-have-over-2000-ev-charging-stalls-and-counting"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313038/gm-and-evgo-now-have-over-2000-ev-charging-stalls-and-counting</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:31:50-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:31:50-05:00</updated>
    <title>Xreal’s new glasses are a surprisingly good TV for your face</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A person wearing Xreal One glasses." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a84L7k6ogJa_tkBD9UhNaGiRh24=/689x0:8132x4962/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765932/XREAL_One_Series_lifestyle_2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Xreal One.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Xreal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="8Kh36l"&gt;During a recent flight from Los Angeles to New York City, I put a headset on my face to watch a movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TN68Iv"&gt;I wasn’t wearing the Vision Pro or a Meta Quest. I was trying the latest pair of AR glasses from Xreal, a Chinese startup taking an unusually focused approach to face computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lCym6F"&gt;To call the Xreal One, which is available for preorder starting on Wednesday for $499, a pair of AR glasses feels like a stretch. While they do technically overlay graphics onto your field of vision, they really just function as a display mirror for your phone, laptop, or gaming console. But given the display advancements in the One over Xreal’s last Air 2 glasses, that may be enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="D0JvHF"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="gallery:12498062"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="HhFzbJ"&gt;The Xreal One uses a custom birdbath lens system to achieve what the company says is equivalent to a 1080p display with a 50-degree field of view. Practically, based on my experience watching Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Rebel Ridge&lt;/em&gt; from my plane seat (a very good movie), that translates to a fairly immersive viewing experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MtPSRp"&gt;It’s not like watching something in the Vision Pro. But the fact that I was wearing an 84-gram pair of glasses that didn’t fully occlude my vision more than made up for the difference. The only time I felt the...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312269/xreal-one-ar-glasses-release-news"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312269/xreal-one-ar-glasses-release-news"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312269/xreal-one-ar-glasses-release-news</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:15:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:15:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>Govee’s smart Christmas tree lights are cheaper than ever</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Govee’s Christmas Lights 2 wrapped around a Christmas tree in the middle of a living room near a fireplace." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BoS47Y8rwkYErhgQ3OjvCCk6FZg=/0x0:1785x1190/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765862/goveechristmas.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Govee’s Christmas Lights 2 adds some holiday cheer to your home with color-changing smart lights that sync to music. &lt;/em&gt; | Image: Govee&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="rjzANC"&gt;Ornaments are nice and all, but few Christmas tree decorations are as magical as &lt;strong&gt;Govee’s Christmas Lights 2&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want your tree to truly dazzle this year, then you might want to check out Govee’s 66-foot smart string lights while they’re still&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;available at their all-time low price of $63.99 ($36 off) from &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=1025X1701640&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fus.govee.com%2Fproducts%2Fchristmas-string-lights-2%3Fvariant%3D44468723384505" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Govee&lt;/a&gt; and at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Govee-Christmas-300LEDs-Mapping-Function/dp/B0D45BS8XH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you clip the on-page coupon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="AHDMAp"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"The Verge’s 2024 holiday gift guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24224043/holiday-gift-guide-2024-best-ideas-unique-tech-gadgets"},{"title":"The Verge’s 2024 home tech holiday gift guide","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24224049/best-smart-home-gift-ideas-2024-deals-tech-gadgets"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="0dF8Pg"&gt;Govee’s string lights add a touch of color to your Christmas tree while making it come alive with 200 lamp beads that can dance to the beat of holiday tunes, and over 130 preset lighting effects to set the mood. What really make the lights shine, though, is their level of customizability. Govee lets you exercise your creative muscles, adding shape matching and AI features to design your own custom light displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0LOR6S"&gt;Aside from cool effects, Govee also added other features that make the lights a good investment. They’re IP65 waterproof-rated, which means you can install them indoors or hang them up outside if you prefer. They’re also compatible with Matter, allowing you control them via Amazon Alexa, Google Assistant, and any other major smart home platform. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="9Fa95X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12497371"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="EWELv9"&gt;A few more deals worth checking out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="6A26GD"&gt;You can buy the &lt;strong&gt;Divoom Ditoo Plus Bluetooth speaker &lt;/strong&gt;directly from &lt;a href="https://go.skimresources.com?id=1025X1701640&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fdivoom.com%2Fproducts%2Fdivoom-pro" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Divoom&lt;/a&gt; starting at an all-time low of $65 (about $70 off) when you apply the code &lt;strong&gt;BF40&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout, with &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Divoom-Bluetooth-Speaker-Controlled-Screen/dp/B08SK36MF6?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; matching that price. Divoom’s retro-inspired speaker features 3.55-inch display you can customize with pixel art and even control with a joystick or mechanical keys. The speaker also combines a clock and calendar into one, making it a cute and handy desktop companion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="amhG5l"&gt;The&lt;strong&gt; iFixit Pro Tech&lt;/strong&gt; is still available at its record low price of $59.99 ($15 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01GF0KV6G/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/f6bf9o0qv4tuk"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and directly from &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ifixit.com%2Fproducts%2Fpro-tech-toolkit&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F4%2F24312195%2Fgovees-smart-christmas-tree-lights-are-cheaper-than-ever" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;iFixit&lt;/a&gt;. The toolkit comes with everything you need to make repairs to small electronics like smartphones, tablets, laptops, and consoles, including tweezers, spudgers, a 64-piece driver kit,  a SIM removal tool, and a magnetic case that doubles as a sorting tray. It also comes with with basic Phillips and flatheads, so you can use it to repair other objects like bikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="KWiGE4"&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sennheiser’s Momentum 4 Wireless&lt;/strong&gt; headphones are on sale for $229.95 ($150 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sennheiser-Momentum-Wireless-Headphones-Crystal-Clear/dp/B0B6GHW1SX/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, which is their second-best price to date. You can also buy them for $20 more at &lt;a href="https://howl.link/tnogzg1i7oouj"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FSennheiser-Momentum-4-Wireless-Headphones-Bluetooth-Headset-Crystal-Clear-Calls-Adaptive-Noise-Cancellation-60h-Battery-Life-Customizable-Sound-Black%2F5262188350&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;. The noise-canceling headphones deliver impressive battery life and can last a whopping 60 hours on just a single charge, which is why they’re &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/21345733/best-noise-canceling-headphones"&gt;among our favorites&lt;/a&gt;. The over-ears also offer other impressive capabilities, including excellent noise cancellation, comfort, and sound. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23297129/sennheiser-momentum-4-wireless-headphones-review"&gt;Read our review.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="4msgPn"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312195/govees-smart-christmas-tree-lights-are-cheaper-than-ever"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312195/govees-smart-christmas-tree-lights-are-cheaper-than-ever</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sheena Vasani</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:08:42-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:08:42-05:00</updated>
    <title>OpenAI’s 12 days of ‘shipmas’ include Sora and new reasoning model</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An OpenAI logo over an illustration of its o1 model." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DTrpVzKGoU6tAK2X9A9sHl3L4-s=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765840/VST_0924_Site.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Alex Parkin / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="Keahis"&gt;Happy holidays from OpenAI. The AI startup plans to kick off a “shipmas” period of new features, products, and demos for 12 days, starting on December 5th. The announcements will include OpenAI’s long-awaited text-to-video AI tool Sora and a new reasoning model, sources familiar with OpenAI’s plans tell &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1hn7Re"&gt;OpenAI CEO Sam Altman confirmed the 12 days of announcements onstage at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;’ DealBook conference on Wednesday morning, though he didn’t say exactly what was coming. OpenAI plans to launch or demo something every day for 12 days straight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="47nMkC"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;12 days.&lt;br&gt;12 livestreams.&lt;br&gt;A bunch of new things, big and small.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;12 Days of OpenAI starts tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;— OpenAI (@OpenAI) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OpenAI/status/1864328928267259941?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 4, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="id__gptv7sq6qf"&gt;Just ahead of the launch, a few OpenAI employees began teasing the coming releases on social media: “What’s on your Christmas list?” a member of the technical staff &lt;a href="https://x.com/zedlander/status/1864043139167932570"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt;. “Got back just in time to put up the shipmas tree,” another staffer &lt;a href="https://x.com/stevenheidel/status/1863682511999733782?s=46"&gt;wrote&lt;/a&gt;. Sora lead Bill Peebles &lt;a href="https://x.com/billpeeb/status/1863886057194049949"&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; to a staffer who &lt;a href="https://x.com/tszzl/status/1863882905422106851"&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; that OpenAI is “unbelievably back” with one word: “Correct.” The startup’s senior vice president also &lt;a href="https://x.com/markchen90/status/1863903206994334127"&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt; with IYKYK (if you know, you know).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VEOSPz"&gt;The imminent launch of Sora comes just...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312352/openai-sora-o1-reasoning-12-days-shipmas"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312352/openai-sora-o1-reasoning-12-days-shipmas"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312352/openai-sora-o1-reasoning-12-days-shipmas</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
      <name>Kylie Robison</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Instagram creators can now turn on replies in broadcast channels</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BQ169ZNG305Hzqi75AYTidlnNmY=/38x0:1163x750/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765779/IGBC_Replies_1.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broadcast channel replies allow participants to respond to messages as they can on Instagram posts.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Meta&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="1RFgcn"&gt;Instagram is adding some new features to broadcast channels that give platform creators more ways to directly interact with their followers. &lt;a href="https://creators.instagram.com/blog/instagram-broadcast-channels-replies-prompts-insights"&gt;Meta announced that creators can enable “Replies”&lt;/a&gt; in their broadcast channel limited group chats, allowing participants to respond to messages and each other’s comments — just like they already can on Instagram posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nUqhRS"&gt;Creators can also publish time-sensitive “Prompts” to their channels, presented as questions like “what are you having for dinner today?” to encourage audience engagement. Channel participants have 24 hours to respond with text or photos, and can like their favorite comments left by other users. Instagram is also rolling out new metrics for creators to track, including total number of interactions, story shares, and poll votes, alongside “personalized, actionable guidance” that can help them grow and manage their audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/b4oInOfsUW9rnX2oQnl0yxwvick=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25773029/IGBC_Prompts.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Meta&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prompts work like open-response polls or sub-threads, allowing channel members to engage in a contained conversation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="KY3FVX"&gt;These features are rolling out globally starting today. &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/mosseri/?hl=en"&gt;Instagram head Adam Mosseri&lt;/a&gt; initially teased the update by enabling it on his own “IG Updates” channel earlier this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vSBSzl"&gt;While Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/18/23922888/facebook-broadcast-channels-instagram-whatsapp"&gt;also support broadcast channels&lt;/a&gt;, these new features have only been announced for Instagram. Meta hasn’t mentioned if they’ll eventually be rolled out to its other platforms, but given Instagram was the first to launch broadcast channels it may be being used as a testing ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tSaMLL"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, December 4th:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Added confirmation of global availability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312956/instagram-broadcast-channels-replies-prompts-availability"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312956/instagram-broadcast-channels-replies-prompts-availability</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jess Weatherbed</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>ESPN is coming to the Disney Plus app starting today</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A screenshot of the new ESPN tile in the Disney Plus app." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R0jgzt-RgfPVprvhcLZC0VefGdU=/0x122:2911x2063/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765781/disneyespn.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="mpOOco"&gt;After bringing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/27/24112747/disney-plus-hulu-tile-app-streaming"&gt;Hulu content to the Disney Plus app&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, Disney is now doing the same for ESPN Plus programming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G185IW"&gt;A new ESPN tile is being added to the app’s homescreen. The tile just says “ESPN,” because for right now, it’ll only include the live games and shows that are normally part of ESPN Plus. But next year will mark the long-awaited debut of a &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; ESPN streaming service — you know, the actual cable channel with shows that sports fans can’t live without — and that’ll eventually be accessible through this Disney Plus portal, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kYPLUd"&gt;Disney’s reasoning for putting all this content under one umbrella is simple: it wants to get more people signed up for the Disney Plus / Hulu / ESPN Plus triple-package bundle. And the less friction there is, the more appealing that bundle becomes for customers who might only be paying for the core service right now. To help push the bundle even harder, Disney Plus subscribers can now access “a curated selection of live sports events and shows from ESPN Plus and movies and series from Hulu.” The tiles for both services will now appear in the main navigation even if you’re not paying for Hulu or ESPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A list of content available through ESPN on Disney Plus." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EzPBO4E-8z-uDm2KJO2H6vb1BYQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25773303/ESPN_on_Disney__16x9_FINAL.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Disney&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a bundle subscriber, you get all the stuff! If you’re not, you get a small sampling of stuff... to help tempt you into the bundle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="bJjcpW"&gt;“This gives our bundle subscribers one place to consume everything they love from all our brands.” Alisa Bowen, president of Disney Plus, said in a press release. ESPN Plus offers access to “over 30,000 live sports events each year” along with plenty of original content. But this is really just a half-step towards the end goal of bringing real, linear ESPN to the service. Disney says what we’re seeing today is “the groundwork for an expanded sports offering on Disney Plus in the US upon the launch of ESPN’s flagship direct-to-consumer product, expected in fall of 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5wileb"&gt;That ESPN streaming service is expected to launch as early as August and has been &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/5355283/2024/03/20/espn-tv-rights-nfl-nba/"&gt;rumored to cost upwards of $30&lt;/a&gt; per month. Yes, just for ESPN. You’ll be able to view it through Disney Plus, but &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/2/7/24065449/the-real-standalone-espn-streaming-channel-will-launch-in-the-fall-of-2025"&gt;CEO Bob Iger has said&lt;/a&gt; the ESPN app will offer a more feature-packed sports experience with integrated betting and fantasy leagues. The Disney option is there for people who want the convenience of everything being crammed into a single app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L6J6Cd"&gt;Disney is determined to make its streaming business a reliable profit maker, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/14/24296307/disney-plus-streaming-business-profit-q4-2024-earnings"&gt;the real money is in bundles and ad-supported plans&lt;/a&gt;. On the ad front, advertisers will have the ability to purchase inventory “by sport, league, team, within live events, and across all marketplaces” now that ESPN content is streaming within Disney Plus. The company has also &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/25/24254189/disney-plus-password-sharing-pricing-extra-member"&gt;taken steps to tackle password sharing&lt;/a&gt; and now charges customers between $6.99 and $9.99 for letting others sign into their Disney Plus account from a different location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDCyhq"&gt;The cost of subscribing to Disney Plus is inevitably going to keep climbing higher. And Disney will no doubt cite the app’s value as an all-encompassing entertainment hub — now with sports — as the rationale for those hikes. For the end user, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24152330/netflix-hulu-disney-plus-hbo-streaming-cable-video-verge"&gt;it can all feel reminiscent of cable&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s the streaming era we find ourselves in. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312617/espn-disney-plus-now-available-bundle-free-preview"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24312617/espn-disney-plus-now-available-bundle-free-preview</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Welch</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Skeleton Crew is a kid-friendly reminder of who Star Wars is for</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An anthropomorphic elephantine alien wearing a cream-colored jacket and sitting at a desk. The alien is resting its head on its cheek and looking to its right with an exasperated expression." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YiNhXE8i5yLLyQuKGUR38sth23Y=/0x18:3551x2385/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765790/GR_022754_R.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Disney Plus / Lucasfilm Ltd.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Disney Plus’ latest Star Wars series is trying to speak directly to a new generation of young fans.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24312202/star-wars-skeleton-crew-review"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24312202/star-wars-skeleton-crew-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24312202/star-wars-skeleton-crew-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Verge picks out the most memorable tech of 2024</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HEOUflBmssRulDyK1wYeet-y_FE=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73765782/Lookback_Site_image.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EToDbI"&gt;As far as tech goes, 2024 was a strong year for some innovative, interesting, and unforgettable moments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mG3c44"&gt;We kicked off the year with the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hdwaWxY11jQ"&gt;Apple Vision Pro&lt;/a&gt; — Apple’s long-awaited entry into the world of “spatial computing.” It was impressive, with &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief, Nilay Patel, describing the device as “magic, until it’s not.” But it still remains to be seen if Apple’s first MR device can kick off this new age of computing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rQjGME"&gt;Meta also showed us what it developed after &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/10/25/22745381/facebook-reality-labs-10-billion-metaverse"&gt;investing billions&lt;/a&gt; into its metaverse division. Deputy editor Alex Heath got a demo of &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24253908/meta-orion-ar-glasses-demo-mark-zuckerberg-interview"&gt;Project Orion&lt;/a&gt; — a pair of AR glasses that won’t make you look like a super dork (okay, maybe a little). More importantly, though, we got a sense of where AR is heading, which arguably puts Meta in pole position in this space. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Spuizb"&gt;This was also the year of &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_w1vv7_dU2Y?si=y07kXU0O4eJALWVM"&gt;wearable AI assistants&lt;/a&gt;. At CES 2024, we were introduced to the cute Rabbit R1 that stole our hearts. And we got to see Humane’s highly anticipated AI Pin. Even though the devices were big &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/DVJL6LXgOE4?si=AdHMpCrjis0H9kGO"&gt;disappointments&lt;/a&gt; when they finally released, they do represent a turning point in the future of AI interactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wln1yu"&gt;We can never go a year without the biggest smartphone upgrades. Samsung,...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24305935/verge-staff-favorites-video-2024"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/24305935/verge-staff-favorites-video-2024"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/24305935/verge-staff-favorites-video-2024</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
