<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-06T13:17:17-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T13:17:17-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T13:17:17-05:00</updated>
    <title>This Game Boy Advance clone could satisfy your purple taco nostalgia </title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A person is playing a Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles game on the Anbernic RG34XX retro handheld." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R5QG2jy0BuZiC4dpFd85_1pYyMQ=/1x0:1186x790/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770953/anbernic1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Anbernic RG34XX looks inspired by Nintendo’s GBA but with a larger screen and more buttons.&lt;/em&gt; | Screenshot: YouTube&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="bGDos7"&gt;Anbernic announced its next retro handheld today and it’s easy to see where the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=64M_BHXsiiE&amp;amp;t=1s"&gt;design of the RG34XX draws its inspiration&lt;/a&gt;. It appears to be a faithful clone of Nintendo’s original Game Boy Advance, although updated with &lt;a href="https://x.com/KeepRetro/status/1865057457157877766"&gt;additional action and shoulder buttons&lt;/a&gt; allowing games from more recent systems to be played. Pricing and availability hasn’t been revealed yet, but the RG34XX will come in transparent red and green colors, as well as the GBA’s purple and black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HPg8X8"&gt;One feature Anbernic didn’t carry forward is the Game Boy Advance’s LCD screen which lacked a backlight and was notoriously difficult to see unless you were playing outside on a sunny day or cozied up next to a bright lamp. The RG34XX will instead feature a larger 3.4-inch display with a 720x480 resolution. The display will also use the same 3:2 aspect ratio as the Game Boy Advance, so GBA titles should look great, and older games developed for 4:3 TV screens will fit without extensive stretching or pillarboxing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="The Anbernic RG34XX pictured in its four color options." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/yvv2YsuXyHeyuog5iDnKOglF7O0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25777028/anbernic3.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Keep Retro&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RG34XX will be available in purple or black colors, and transparent red or green.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="IcgRa8"&gt;As with previous Anbernic handhelds, the RG34XX doesn’t have a cartridge slot like the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24236829/analogue-pocket-handheld-gaming-game-boy-color"&gt;Analogue Pocket&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/3/24170572/modretro-chromatic-game-boy-color-palmer-luckey-price-release-date"&gt;ModRetro Chromatic&lt;/a&gt;. It’s instead designed to play games through software emulation. Details on the RG34XX’s processor aren’t known yet, but &lt;a href="https://retrohandhelds.gg/anbernic-rg34xx-announced/"&gt;Retro Handhelds speculates&lt;/a&gt; it will be based on the Allwinner H700 chipset the company has &lt;a href="https://anbernic.com/products/rg28xx"&gt;used in its other XX series handhelds&lt;/a&gt;. If that’s the case, you can expect it to play games from older consoles up to the original Sony PlayStation, and even some N64 and Sega Dreamcast titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A close-up look at the top of the Anbernic RG34XX including its ports, card slots, and shoulder buttons." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/k-gvlVhhVOX5u3ID5emVECDHJ0Q=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25777023/anbernic2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Keep Retro&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The RG34XX will include two sets of shoulder buttons, a mini HDMI port, USB-C for charging, and dual microSD slots.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="qNUY7l"&gt;The RG34XX will include Wi-Fi connectivity facilitating online play as well as streaming PC titles through &lt;a href="https://moonlight-stream.org/"&gt;Moonlight&lt;/a&gt;, and Bluetooth for connecting multiple wireless controllers for shared screen multiplayer. If that 3.4-inch screen still seems too small, the RG34XX also includes a mini HDMI port for connecting it to a TV, alongside a USB-C port for charging, and a pair of microSD card slots for storing ROMs and its operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="o8TUE5"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/64M_BHXsiiE?rel=0&amp;amp;start=1" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1oBKFL"&gt;This isn’t the first time that Anbernic has copied Nintendo’s homework. Earlier this year the company released its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/8/24152105/can-you-resist-anbernics-game-boy-advance-sp-that-plays-ps1-and-n64-games"&gt;RG35XXSP with a design inspired by the clamshell Game Boy Advance SP&lt;/a&gt; but with an improved screen, a more capable processor, and a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/13/24177983/this-amazing-knockoff-gba-sp-comes-stuffed-with-software-piracy"&gt;concerning number of pre-installed pirated ROMs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314884/anbernic-rg34xx-handheld-emulator-retro-nintendo-game-boy-advance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314884/anbernic-rg34xx-handheld-emulator-retro-nintendo-game-boy-advance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Liszewski</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T13:12:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T13:12:22-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple’s in-house 5G modem plans are just getting started with next year’s iPhone SE</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An image showing the iPhone SE" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o3deRsledj3JUKmowX8TwhwiJB0=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770951/ajohnson_221103_5070_0002.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new modem is rumored to appear in next year’s iPhone SE.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Allison Johnson / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ZhW66J"&gt;Apple’s betting that its upcoming in-house 5G modem could help it beat Qualcomm's performance eventually, according to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-06/apple-s-three-year-modem-road-map-company-plans-to-beat-qualcomm-by-2027"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;’s Mark Gurman&lt;/a&gt;. Apple has worked on developing its own modem for years, but the initiative reportedly experienced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/9/21/23883565/apple-5g-modem-failure-inside-story"&gt;technical issues and other setbacks&lt;/a&gt; despite &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/7/25/8909671/apple-intel-5g-smartphone-modems-acquisition"&gt;purchasing Intel’s modem unit&lt;/a&gt; in 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d93I7k"&gt;The first Apple modem is rumored to come to the iPhone SE before appearing in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/25/24305670/iphone-17-slim-rumors-sim-card-battery-problems"&gt;the rumored iPhone “Slim”&lt;/a&gt; and entry-level iPads. Down the line, Apple is reportedly planning to roll out a second-generation modem with mmWave in 2026, putting it in the iPhone 18 line and higher-end iPads. In 2027, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg &lt;/em&gt;reports that Apple “hopes to top Qualcomm” with its “Prometheus” modem, which could support AI features and “next-generation satellite networks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gEuZgx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Apple’s next iPhone SE might get an OLED upgrade","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/3/24234749/apple-iphone-se-4th-generation-oled-display-rumor-leak"},{"title":"The new Mac Mini is great — now do the&amp;amp;nbsp;iPhone&amp;amp;nbsp;SE","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/15/24296505/apple-iphone-se-rumors-mac-mini"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="PzAfpL"&gt;However, its first chip may fall short of Qualcomm’s in terms of the absolute highest possible speed for a couple of reasons: lacking support for the mmWave technology available in some cities from carriers like Verizon and supporting four-carrier aggregation instead of six. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDtW4H"&gt;Those features boost the maximum bandwidth available to multiple gigabits per second, but speeds are typically much slower in the real world, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22968066/apple-iphone-se-5g-mmwave-verizon-uw"&gt;the current iPhone SE also lacks mmWave support&lt;/a&gt;. The new modem will, however, support dual SIM standby, allowing people to have two active SIM cards at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bPOrKb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XQ8kLF"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314898/apple-5g-modem-debut-iphone-se-2025"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314898/apple-5g-modem-debut-iphone-se-2025</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T13:10:43-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T13:10:43-05:00</updated>
    <title>You can now try Microsoft’s Recall AI feature on Intel and AMD Copilot Plus PCs</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A timeline with buttons for yesterday, today, and now, with apps like Teams and Excel at the bottom." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2hmYXe1FmoByFlUS6e3LDnKqnZw=/144x0:1698x1036/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770949/Gen_AI_feature3_VP5_1842x1036.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3zPjMX"&gt;Microsoft is expanding the testing of its new Recall AI feature to Intel- and AMD-powered Copilot Plus PCs. The software giant first &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/22/24302947/microsoft-recall-windows-insider-testing-dev-channel-click-to-do"&gt;released a preview of Recall&lt;/a&gt; on Qualcomm-powered laptops last month, allowing Windows Insiders in the Dev Channel to test the new AI-powered feature. Now Intel and AMD Copilot Plus PCs &lt;a href="https://blogs.windows.com/windows-insider/2024/12/06/previewing-more-copilot-experiences-with-windows-insiders-in-the-dev-channel/"&gt;are getting access&lt;/a&gt; in a new build today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QL974Z"&gt;Recall takes screenshots of almost everything you do on a Copilot Plus PC to make it searchable and easy to recall a memory or retrace your steps. Microsoft has made the AI experience entirely optional, so you can enable snapshots to find what you were working on previously through natural language search or a scrollable timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XfzmcyXUD84A0yvmrnIYQ79JkGk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25749006/2_recall_timeline.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Recall timeline feature.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="e5hjkx"&gt;Much like the experience on Qualcomm Copilot Plus PCs, Windows 11 will download the models for Recall and Click to Do in the background once you install the Dev Channel build. You’ll then need to enable snapshots yourself. You can control what snapshots are saved and delete them based on apps or much like you’d delete browsing history by date. Microsoft also provides a way to exclude apps and websites from Recall, and the feature also automatically detects sensitive information like credit card details, passwords, and personal ID numbers to ensure snapshots are not saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3xAwzO"&gt;Microsoft has made a variety of security upgrades to Recall after researchers raised the alarm over the controversial feature. You now need to use Windows Hello to confirm your presence and access snapshots, and it also requires BitLocker and Secure Boot — both of which should be enabled already on a Copilot Plus PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vni8CC"&gt;Click to Do is also part of this Recall testing. Click to Do can recognize text and images in Recall snapshots so you can use AI-powered actions on them like copying text or saving images out of old snapshots. Microsoft is also expanding Click to Do outside of Recall so you can use it to take actions on images and text by summoning it through Windows key + mouse click. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JDCT2v"&gt;Lastly, Microsoft is also introducing its Image Creator and Restyle Image features to the Photos app for Intel- and AMD-powered Copilot Plus PCs. These devices will also get access to Cocreator in Paint today to let you create AI-powered images directly in Paint.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314795/microsoft-recall-testing-amd-intel-copilot-plus-pcs"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314795/microsoft-recall-testing-amd-intel-copilot-plus-pcs</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T12:12:55-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T12:12:55-05:00</updated>
    <title>X’s Grok AI chatbot is now available to all users</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vector illustration of the Grok logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vLbhdlMz3xdYHmdVmVbhaWWr5xA=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770853/STK262_GROK_D.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="eVergz"&gt;Elon Musk’s AI chatbot Grok is now available to free users on X. &lt;a href="https://x.com/blankspeaker/status/1864826210951307330"&gt;Several users&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://x.com/nima_owji/status/1865058483529290086"&gt;noticed the change&lt;/a&gt; on Friday, which gives non-Premium subscribers the ability to send up to 10 messages to Grok every two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swGogS"&gt;xAI launched Grok last year as a “humorous AI assistant,” but it was only available to Premium subscribers. In August, xAI added a text-to-image generation feature to Grok, which turned out to be capable of producing &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/14/24220173/xai-grok-image-generator-misinformation-offensive-imges"&gt;some questionable images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="avXToi"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"X’s new AI image generator will make anything from Taylor Swift in lingerie to Kamala Harris with a gun","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/14/24220173/xai-grok-image-generator-misinformation-offensive-imges"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="REg2hY"&gt;&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/11/10/x-is-testing-a-free-version-of-ai-chatbot-grok/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;TechCrunch &lt;/em&gt;reported last month&lt;/a&gt; that Musk’s xAI started testing a free version of Grok in certain regions. Making Grok more widely available might help it compete with the already-free chatbots like OpenAI’s ChatGPT, Google Gemini, Microsoft Copilot, and Anthropic’s Claude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lpff3M"&gt;xAI, &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-05/musk-s-xai-wraps-up-6-billion-in-funding-in-latest-round"&gt;which raised $6 billion in its latest funding round&lt;/a&gt;, is &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/27/24307571/xai-consumer-app-planned-report"&gt;also considering launching&lt;/a&gt; a standalone app for Grok — something ChatGPT, Gemini, and Claude already have, according to a report from &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314860/x-grok-ai-chatbot-available-all-users"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314860/x-grok-ai-chatbot-available-all-users</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T12:11:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T12:11:40-05:00</updated>
    <title>AirPods 4 with Active Noise Cancellation hit new all-time low with $40 off</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A hands-on photo of Apple’s AirPods 4 wireless earbuds." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1BvlauaUYN3KC1t_3onLxqT4JyI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770847/DSCF0028.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;You should definitely skip the base AirPods 4, which are only $9 cheaper right now.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Chris Welch / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="K01ihQ"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23365910/apple-airpods-pro-second-generation-review"&gt;AirPods Pro&lt;/a&gt; stole the spotlight recently with an incredible discount that made them even cheaper than the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24245570/apple-airpods-4-review"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AirPods 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; with Active Noise Cancellation&lt;/strong&gt;. But now the script is flipped and the AirPods 4 are currently discounted to $139 ($40 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0DGJ7HYG1?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. That’s a new record low for Apple’s newest pair of wireless earbuds and just $9 more than the version without ANC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="dRj2tj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are the best AirPods deals you can get right now","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21302051/best-apple-airpods-deals"},{"title":"Why is Apple sleeping on the AirPods Max?","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/17/24242378/airpods-max-usb-c-unchanged-missing-features"},{"title":"The best wireless earbuds to buy right now ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/21309820/best-wireless-earbuds"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="dDZG3r"&gt;The AirPods 4 are a substantial upgrade over the previous generation, with better overall sound quality and a stronger bass profile. They also borrow a couple more features from the AirPods Pro, like the Voice Isolation feature that analyzes your voice to separate it and cancel out the environment, resulting in clearer voice calls. Other features include a wireless charging case with a speaker that lets you trigger a sound from Apple’s Find My app, spatial audio with head-tracking, and adaptive audio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G9XfO4"&gt;Active noise cancellation is solid in the upgraded pair, but since there are no canal-sealing ear tips, they won’t offer the same dampening. That’s where you’d opt instead for the AirPods Pro, which ultimately sound better and offer a few extra capabilities, like more intuitive volume controls and the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24275178/apple-airpods-pro-hearing-aid-test-protection-preview"&gt;use them as hearing aids&lt;/a&gt;. But if you don’t mind making some tradeoffs, the entry-level AirPods 4 offer a lot for the money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="ERE9bp"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24245570/apple-airpods-4-review"&gt;Read our Apple AirPods 4 review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id="BeVd4K"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12434303"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="e2p9Xl"&gt;A few more deals to kick the weekend off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="TREAkg"&gt;If you need a solid pair of earbuds but you can’t justify spending close to $100 or more, the &lt;strong&gt;JLab Go Air Pop&lt;/strong&gt; should have your attention right now. They’re just $9.88 ($15 off) at &lt;a href="https://goto.walmart.com/c/482924/565706/9383?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.walmart.com%2Fip%2FJLab-Go-Air-Pop-Bluetooth-Earbuds-True-Wireless-with-Charging-Case-Slate%2F799981023&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Walmart&lt;/a&gt;, which is their lowest price to date. They don’t do much but play music, but they sound decent, they’re reasonably comfortable, and you can get them in a variety of fun colors. You’ll get eight hours of runtime per charge, with an extra 24 hours available in the charging case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="nxaF3q"&gt;Today only, you can get a two-pack of black&lt;strong&gt; Xbox Core Wireless Controllers&lt;/strong&gt; with a USB-C cable from &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Felectronics.woot.com%2Foffers%2F2-pack-xbox-core-wireless-controller-usb-c-cable&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F6%2F24314768%2Fapple-airpods-4-with-active-noise-cancellation-wireless-earbuds-xbox-core-controller-deal-sale" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Woot&lt;/a&gt; for $73.59 (about $46 off) with code &lt;strong&gt;20PERCENT&lt;/strong&gt;. The controllers are often on sale for $40 on their own, so you’re getting a better deal compared to buying them separately. Although Microsoft created the controllers specifically for the Xbox Series X/S launch, you can use them with older Xbox One consoles and on Windows PCs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="Xd4JJx"&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Ring Battery Doorbell Plus&lt;/strong&gt;, which we think is the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22954554/best-video-doorbell-camera"&gt;best battery-powered video doorbell&lt;/a&gt;, is matching its all-time low of $99.99 ($50 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Ring-Battery-Doorbell-detection/dp/B09WZBPX7K?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/2b4pzb9n9vuf6"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://goto.target.com/c/482924/81938/2092?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.target.com%2Fp%2Fring-battery-doorbell-plus-8211-smart-wi-fi-video-doorbell-with-head-to-toe-hd-video-satin-nickel%2F-%2FA-88293229&amp;amp;sharedid=theverge.com" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Target&lt;/a&gt;. The doorbell boasts an impressive 1536p video resolution as well as a head-to-toe view that offers better visibility for packages and visitors. While there are cheaper wireless options from Ring and competitors, they’re not quite as responsive as the Doorbell Plus. Other handy features include color night vision, live view, and two-way audio, though you’ll need to pay $4.99 a month for others like recorded video and package alerts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="wh7LvZ"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314768/apple-airpods-4-with-active-noise-cancellation-wireless-earbuds-xbox-core-controller-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314768/apple-airpods-4-with-active-noise-cancellation-wireless-earbuds-xbox-core-controller-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Quentyn Kennemer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T12:01:36-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T12:01:36-05:00</updated>
    <title>Anthem BCBS is reversing its anesthesia policy after online outrage</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Cigna Corp. And Anthem Inc. Offices As Insurers Face Off Against U.S. To Save $48 Billion Deal" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/giT7X3mY1qiQS54-Uro5uV3jn-s=/0x0:5616x3744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770821/626407904.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="C3nhi8"&gt;Beginning in February, health insurer Anthem Blue Cross Blue Shield was planning to set a time limit for anesthesia coverage during surgeries and procedures. Now, following days of widespread outrage at the health insurance industry generally, Anthem is walking that policy back, the insurer &lt;a href="https://providernews.anthem.com/connecticut/articles/update-to-anesthesia-billed-time-units-policy-23311"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nvJ5E5"&gt;In mid-November, the American Society of Anesthesiologists &lt;a href="https://www.asahq.org/about-asa/newsroom/news-releases/2024/11/anthem-blue-cross-blue-shield-will-not-pay-complete-duration-of-anesthesia-for-surgical-procedures"&gt;issued a press release&lt;/a&gt; about the policy, which was set to take effect in February in states like Connecticut, New York, and Missouri. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8veL0d"&gt;“If an anesthesiologist submits a bill where the actual time of care is longer than Anthem’s limit, Anthem will deny payment for the anesthesiologist’s care,” they group writes. “With this new policy, Anthem will not pay anesthesiologists for delivering safe and effective anesthesia care to patients who may need extra attention because their surgery is difficult, unusual or because a complication arises.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nsxL5v"&gt;The letter appears to have garnered little public attention until this week when &lt;a href="https://x.com/MorePerfectUS/status/1864363128584130774"&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://x.com/GovKathyHochul/status/1864495315362926753"&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; on social media about the policy change began circulating. The posts gained traction after the CEO of UnitedHealthcare, Brian Thompson, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/05/us/unitedhealthcare-ceo-killed-what-we-know-hnk/index.html"&gt;was shot and killed in New York&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday in what police say was a targeted attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GzJmHI"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Outrageous. I’m going to make sure New Yorkers are protected. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Mqtjeu0ZD7"&gt;https://t.co/Mqtjeu0ZD7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Governor Kathy Hochul (@GovKathyHochul) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovKathyHochul/status/1864495315362926753?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 5, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="QJ99KQ"&gt;A spokesperson for Anthem’s parent company, Elevance Health, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/05/health/blue-cross-blue-shield-anesthesia-anthem.html"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that “misinformation” about the plan contributed to Anthem’s reversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xg4pIM"&gt;“We realized, based on all the feedback we’ve been receiving the last 24 hours, that our communication about the policy was unclear, which is why we’re pulling back,” Janey Kiryluik, staff vice president for corporate communications, is quoted as saying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gG3Kn2"&gt;Thompson’s shooting shocked the public, but it also ignited discussions about the havoc wreaked by the US healthcare system and insurers like UnitedHealthcare. United specifically has been &lt;a href="https://www.statnews.com/2023/11/14/unitedhealth-algorithm-medicare-advantage-investigation/"&gt;the subject of investigations by outlets like &lt;em&gt;Stat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;which found the company uses algorithms to cut off payments and deny rehabilitation care for patients. The rate at which insurers deny patient claims &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/how-often-do-health-insurers-deny-patients-claims"&gt;is a closely guarded secret&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;ProPublica &lt;/em&gt;last year &lt;a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/unitedhealth-healthcare-insurance-denial-ulcerative-colitis"&gt;followed one chronically ill patient’s fight&lt;/a&gt; to get coverage from United. In some online forums, there was little sympathy for the company and Thompson’s death: Americans carry &lt;a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/issue-brief/the-burden-of-medical-debt-in-the-united-states/"&gt;at least $220 billion in medical debt&lt;/a&gt;, which &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2022/06/16/1104969627/medical-debt-upended-their-lives-heres-what-it-took-from-them"&gt;upends lives&lt;/a&gt; as insurance companies profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fVHBH9"&gt;The shooter’s motives are not yet clear, but shell casings &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/05/us/unitedhealthcare-ceo-killed-what-we-know-hnk/index.html"&gt;discovered at the scene&lt;/a&gt; were found to have &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/12/05/nyregion/brian-thompson-unitedhealthcare-news?smid=url-share#b394ac8b-4b7c-5962-8c6e-04d61f0166c7"&gt;the words “delay” and “deny”&lt;/a&gt; written on them. Following the murder, healthcare companies like &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/healthcare-industry-rethinks-risk-after-murder-unitedhealth-exec-2024-12-05/"&gt;CVS Health&lt;/a&gt; began &lt;a href="https://www.404media.co/multiple-major-health-insurance-companies-take-down-leadership-pages-following-murder-of-united-healthcare-ceo/"&gt;taking down webpages about corporate leadership&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WYc2M2"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DdP8tI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314770/anthem-blue-cross-blue-shield-anesthesia-limit-policy-health-insurance"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314770/anthem-blue-cross-blue-shield-anesthesia-limit-policy-health-insurance</id>
    <author>
      <name>Mia Sato</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T11:02:56-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T11:02:56-05:00</updated>
    <title>Researchers put bird legs on a drone so it can take off by jumping</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="EPFL’s RAVEN drone shown posed in flight with its bird-inspired legs dangling." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-7-Fz_AGk3YeZ9kyziPi2AKpMYY=/0x0:2500x1667/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770675/EPFL_raven_drone1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;EPFL’s RAVEN drone trades traditional landing gear for a pair of legs that function similar to a bird’s.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Alain Herzog&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="VMc99V"&gt;Researchers from the École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL) in Switzerland and UC Irvine have developed a drone capable of landing and taking off in areas that would otherwise leave a fixed-wing aircraft stranded. Their &lt;a href="https://actu.epfl.ch/news/bird-inspired-drone-can-jump-for-take-off-2/"&gt;Robotic Avian-inspired Vehicle for multiple ENvironments&lt;/a&gt; (RAVEN) trades traditional landing gear for a pair of bird-inspired articulated legs that allow the drone to walk around, hop over obstacles, and even &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/bird-drone"&gt;leap into the air to take flight&lt;/a&gt; without the need for a runway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Kzfvd5"&gt;Quadcopter drones may offer more flexibility when it comes to where they can take off and land, but most rely on four motors which are less energy-efficient than fixed-wing drones that use a single motor paired with gliding for flight. To expand the capabilities of fixed-wing drones, the researchers took inspiration from birds like crows and ravens which can easily maneuver on the ground using a scrawny pair of legs, as detailed in a &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-024-08228-9"&gt;paper published in &lt;em&gt;Nature&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A close-up look at the EPFL’s RAVEN drone’s legs and feet." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rZrRsjWduS-81mAzzF1C2dA_IdE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25776421/EPFL_raven_drone2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Alain Herzog&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;RAVEN’s legs and feet use a simplified design but still offer enough articulation for the drone to maneuver on the ground.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="M1fw6p"&gt;Recreating the strength and capabilities of a bird’s legs mechanically without adding significant weight to a drone and reducing its operating range required a mix of “mathematical models, computer simulations, and experimental iterations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="khbZQP"&gt;The final design for the legs uses a combination of springs and motors to mimic “powerful avian tendons and muscles” while its simplified feet use “two articulated structures” plus toes with a passive elastic joint. The toes not only prevent RAVEN from constantly face planting, they’re also critical for walking and positioning the drone at the right angle of attack for an effective takeoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TiPIAN"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-8DJ1a3sLIc?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mGaJ2M"&gt;Fixed-wing drones that take advantage of legs for short takeoffs and landings aren’t an entirely new idea. In 2019, a South African startup called Passerine &lt;a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/delivery-drones-use-birdinspired-legs-to-jump-into-the-air"&gt;demonstrated a drone called Sparrow&lt;/a&gt; that used a pair of spring-loaded legs to leap into the air and take flight from a standstill. What sets RAVEN apart is the complexity of its legs that allow the drone to walk across rough terrain, jump over gaps, and hop onto obstacles as high as 10 inches — in addition to being able to leap into flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X1FYag"&gt;RAVEN’s operations aren’t limited to airports or areas with smooth surfaces, which traditional wheeled landing gear requires. It also doesn’t require human intervention to get airborne again. It’s capable of landing and exploring areas that may be dangerous or restricted to humans, and then repositioning itself to an area that’s safe for takeoff. And it does it all using less power than a quadcopter drone would, giving it a larger operational range.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314771/epfl-uc-irvine-drone-raven-aircraft-research-science"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314771/epfl-uc-irvine-drone-raven-aircraft-research-science</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Liszewski</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T10:51:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T10:51:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Amazon just completed its first delivery by drone in Italy</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="drone in sky with amazon building in background" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NhDDgNCVjjRhFjQSvwX19qdzEuY=/102x0:1218x744/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770625/90_1.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Amazon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CZGZJ3"&gt;Amazon &lt;a href="https://www.aboutamazon.it/notizie/company-news/amazon-completa-con-successo-il-primo-volo-di-prova-per-le-consegne-con-i-droni-a-san-salvo-in-abruzzo"&gt;completed&lt;/a&gt; its first drone flight test in Italy on Wednesday. The test used its &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/11/10/23451851/amazon-mk30-drone-prime-air-delivery"&gt;MK30 drone&lt;/a&gt;, which can carry up to five pounds (or 2.27 kilograms) of packages through light rain and, in the US, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24288735/amazon-arizona-tolleson-phoenix-drone-prime-air-launch"&gt;is licensed&lt;/a&gt; to operate Beyond Visual Line of Sight (BVLOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z4LriP"&gt;Italian regulators ENAC and ENAV, which are like the US Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), authorized Amazon to carry out the test in San Salvo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="38xSE3"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FTHXHvFBmVw?rel=0&amp;amp;start=2" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="gRiEZ9"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Amazon is shutting down its drone delivery service in California as it looks to other markets","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/22/24137383/amazon-prime-air-drone-delivery-closing-lockeford-california-phoenix-arizona"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="52p4Tk"&gt;Last year, the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/18/23922910/amazon-prime-air-delivery-drone-italy-united-kingdom"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; its intention to expand to Italy and the UK in 2024. Amazon says it plans to launch its Prime Air delivery service commercially in Italy in 2025, pending regulatory approval. According to &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/amazon-successfully-tests-using-delivery-drones-italy-2024-12-05/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Britain has selected six drone testing projects, including Amazon, however, there’s no word on when testing will take place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BTvbZC"&gt;In the US, Amazon’s drone deliveries are up and running in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/12/28/23529705/amazon-drone-delivery-prime-air-california-texas"&gt;College Station, Texas&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/5/24288735/amazon-arizona-tolleson-phoenix-drone-prime-air-launch"&gt;Phoenix, Arizona&lt;/a&gt;, with plans to operate in more areas next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V1nFQx"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wh5Jpp"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FDClgA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUGrXq"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SVUmKy"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314789/amazon-drone-test-italy-prime-air-delivery"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24314789/amazon-drone-test-italy-prime-air-delivery</id>
    <author>
      <name>Umar Shakir</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T10:45:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T10:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Netflix’s Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld is a fresh remix of Buffy-style monster slaying</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A blonde girl wearing a black and yellow T-shirt, jeans, and a backpack. The girl is standing in a dark high school hallway and holding her hands, which are engulfed in flames, up in defense." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EMcVUfzX6dBNelpjTKzOUTmFXus=/0x0:3430x2287/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770611/Jentry_PromoImage.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld’s first season feels like a classic monster slaying story remixed for a new generation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p--has-dropcap" id="XJZuv4"&gt;Though it has been decades since &lt;em&gt;Buffy the Vampire Slayer&lt;/em&gt;’s final episode aired, the show’s lasting cultural impact can still be felt through &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24141747/i-saw-the-tv-glow-review-a24"&gt;the stories being told&lt;/a&gt; by people who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24159054/i-saw-the-tv-glow-jane-schoenbrun-interview"&gt;were impacted by it&lt;/a&gt;. Netflix’s &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld &lt;/em&gt;feels like the kind of show that might not exist if it weren’t for the way an entire generation of kids grew up watching a teenage girl fight monsters from week to week. The new Titmouse-produced animated show’s world of magic, and its focus on a young warrior who just wants to be a regular high schooler, makes it impossible not to see it as a tribute to Sunnydale’s finest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UgTtKV"&gt;But as often as it riffs some of &lt;em&gt;Buffy&lt;/em&gt;’s signature beats — teen angst, supernatural love triangles, a town full of normies who &lt;em&gt;kinda &lt;/em&gt;know something weird is going on around them — &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld &lt;/em&gt;uses them to tell a much more dynamic tale about who gets to be an “all-American girl.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hpGREA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld &lt;/em&gt;tells the story of how its titular Chinese American teen is yanked out of her boarding school in South Korea and dragged to a small Texas town to fulfill a destiny she doesn’t want any part of. Things are &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; for Jentry in Seoul, where her friends have basically become her family and people that she can trust with some of her dark secrets. They know about Jentry’s uncontrollable ability to start fires and that it is part of why her feisty elderly aunt Gugu (Lori Tan Chinn) sent her to study abroad. But as dangerous as Jentry might be, her friends don’t care because they, like Gugu, love her. And with Jentry’s powers having seemingly gone dormant since she left the US, she assumes her days of literal bridge-burning are all in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div id="8gZYaJ"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EHYcymIQ7xo?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1m8NNC"&gt;All Jentry wants for her 16th birthday is for things to stay as they are and to keep building a new life that feels like it’s really hers. But when she’s attacked by Ed (Bowen Yang), a &lt;em&gt;Twilight&lt;/em&gt;-obsessed shapeshifting vampire tasked with delivering her to his master Mogui (Kenton Chen), Jentry knows that her wish for a blissfully mundane childhood isn’t coming true anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BUiXj7"&gt;While younger viewers might not initially pick up on just how much &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau &lt;/em&gt;borrows from &lt;em&gt;Buffy&lt;/em&gt;, the ’90s monster-of-the-week show’s influence on showrunner Echo Wu shines through in Jentry’s journey back to Texas to enroll in a school run by a paranoid administrator. Jentry’s being new-ish in town is all it takes for vice principal Wheeler (Sean Allan Krill) to be suspicious of her sudden arrival, and she tries to keep quiet about her extracurricular monster hunting. But because Jentry’s reignited powers lure so many mythological ghouls out of the woodwork, there’s enough day-to-day chaos that it’s kind of easy for her to pretend she’s just another student who can’t believe how her high school seems to be situated on top of a hellmouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KZo7Ld"&gt;The show’s monsters — a cavalcade of demons and spirits plucked from Chinese mythology — are a huge part of what makes &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld &lt;/em&gt;feel like such an inspired spin on the monster-of-the-week genre. Almost every supernatural creature Jentry faces speaks to the series’ focus on exploring her cultural heritage, rather than using its aesthetics as superficial set dressing. Jentry’s powers make her formidable, but it’s because of Gugu’s years of teaching her about Chinese folklore that she’s able to outsmart the ghosts she encounters when she journeys into the underworld.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kvStsJ-d7CCdCOzgg0A03RquVt4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25776361/en_US_JCVU_Teaser_Girl_On_Fire_Still005.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Netflix&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Hif1WY"&gt;One of the series’ funnier episodes follows Jentry and her classmates on a field trip to the Alamo, where a tour guide summons a bunch of dead American soldiers to scold the kids about how “rude” it is for them to want to know more about &lt;a href="https://stateline.org/2021/09/14/forget-the-alamo-depicts-a-racist-heritage-sparking-backlash/"&gt;the monument’s actual history&lt;/a&gt;. It’s one of the instances where &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau &lt;/em&gt;more explicitly reminds you that, in addition to centering Jentry’s Chinese heritage, it’s telling a story about an American girl who has been encouraged to think about her country’s past and how that shapes some people’s perceptions of her. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="co7OFH"&gt;Jentry has far more interesting things to deal with than racism, like her complicated love triangle situation with her childhood friend Michael (A.J. Beckles) and Kit (Woosung Kim), another mysterious transfer student. But it’s clear the show wants you to appreciate that there’s more to telling relatable yet culturally specific stories than simply putting a few characters of color onscreen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i0bAKq"&gt;Even though the &lt;em&gt;Buffy &lt;/em&gt;vibes only grow stronger with each episode — Jentry ends up with a Scooby Gang of her own who all have their own supernatural stuff going on — the show remixes them just enough to make this first season feel like a refreshing addition to the Chosen Girl™ canon. You can see that Wu and the rest of &lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld&lt;/em&gt;’s creative team have poured their hearts into this first chapter, and it would be great to see what else they might want to conjure up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="WL1Zvd"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jentry Chau vs. The Underworld&lt;/em&gt;’s first season is now streaming on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24307486/jentry-chau-vs-the-underworld-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24307486/jentry-chau-vs-the-underworld-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-06T10:43:59-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-06T10:43:59-05:00</updated>
    <title>TikTok divest-or-ban law upheld by federal court</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Photo illustration of the Capitol building next to the TikTok logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QEQzPwIFKbOCKPdjztmzEGprIWI=/20x0:2021x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73770607/STK051_TIKTOKBAN_CVirginia_A.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Cath Virginia / The Verge | Photos from Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="EgkSqI"&gt;A bill that could ban TikTok from the US unless its Chinese parent company divests it is constitutional, a panel of judges for the DC Circuit Court of Appeals &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861.1208687457.0_5.pdf"&gt;unanimously ruled&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BZCac3"&gt;The decision comes soon before ByteDance’s January 19th deadline to sell the popular video app, or face its expulsion from the US. That deadline now falls one day before President-elect Donald Trump will be inaugurated for the second time — thanks in part to donations from &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-06-24/jeff-yass-how-tiktok-billionaire-became-a-top-influence-in-2024-election"&gt;ByteDance investor Jeff Yass&lt;/a&gt;. Though Trump sought to ban TikTok during his first term, he changed his tune on the campaign trail this year, saying a ban would just &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/8/24094587/republicans-ignore-trump-criticism-and-plan-to-vote-next-week-on-a-bill-that-could-ban-tiktok"&gt;help a different target of his ire&lt;/a&gt;: Meta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VdQ14r"&gt;While Trump allies &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/11/12/trump-tiktok-ban-sale/"&gt;reportedly expected him to try to halt the ban&lt;/a&gt;, the options for recourse are somewhat limited. The law allows for a 90 day extension at the president’s discretion, but only if progress is being made toward a spin-out. Trump could direct the Department of Justice not to enforce the bill, but that still leaves app store companies like Google and Apple — tasked with being the gatekeepers to the app — in a precarious spot, should Trump change his mind or a future administration decide to enforce the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="4Ezix1"&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="200" scrolling="no" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm?e=VMP1241317430" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="thK3tp"&gt;The court decided that the law could survive even strict scrutiny under the First Amendment, and did not find TikTok’s arguments that it violates equal protections under the Fifth Amendment compelling. “We emphasize from the outset that our conclusion here is fact-bound,” Judge Douglas Ginsburg writes in &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861/gov.uscourts.cadc.40861.1208687460.0_3.pdf"&gt;the opinion for the court&lt;/a&gt;. “The multi-year efforts of both political branches to investigate the national security risks posed by the TikTok platform, and to consider potential remedies proposed by TikTok, weigh heavily in favor of the Act. The Government has offered persuasive evidence demonstrating that the Act is narrowly tailored to protect national security.” These risks included both fears that China could use TikTok for data collection and that it could covertly manipulate the recommendation algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DWmGzV"&gt;The court relies only on evidence in the public record to reach its decision, even though many of the justifications for the bill that led lawmakers to vote for it were presented in classified briefings. The judges add that TikTok’s argument that divestiture from ByteDance would be impractical is really the result of the Chinese government’s potential resistance — not a function of the law itself. “TikTok would have us turn the Takings Clause into a means by which a foreign adversary nation may render unconstitutional legislation designed to counter the national security threats presented by that very nation,” they conclude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=":78b"&gt;“The Supreme Court has an established historical record of protecting Americans’ right to free speech, and we expect they will do just that on this important constitutional issue,” TikTok spokesperson Michael Hughes writes in a statement. “Unfortunately, the TikTok ban was conceived and pushed through based upon inaccurate, flawed and hypothetical information, resulting in outright censorship of the American people. The TikTok ban, unless stopped, will silence the voices of over 170 million Americans here in the US and around the world on January 19th, 2025.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HX6zV7"&gt;Despite Trump’s opposition, many Republicans in Congress voted to pass the bill earlier this year. It received overwhelming bipartisan support in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/20/24135163/tiktok-ban-divest-bytedance-house-foreign-aid-package"&gt;both&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/23/24137638/senate-passes-tiktok-ban-bill-divest-bytedance-foreign-aid"&gt;chambers&lt;/a&gt;, before &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/24/24139036/biden-signs-tiktok-ban-bill-divest-foreign-aid-package"&gt;President Joe Biden signed it into law&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/3/15/24102472/house-tiktok-ban-bill-staffers-calls-congress"&gt;Proponents of the law&lt;/a&gt; say that it’s necessary protect the privacy of Americans and protect them from foreign influence campaigns. That’s because Chinese law lets the government compel companies headquartered there to hand over internal information for national security reasons. And while TikTok has repeatedly asserted its independent operations from ByteDance and says US data is not stored in China, many lawmakers still feared Chinese officials could have a say in what information Americans do and don’t see. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oxlhk4"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/14/24243794/tiktok-ban-bytedance-court-oral-arguments-lawsuit-explainer"&gt;During oral arguments&lt;/a&gt; in September, TikTok and a group of creators also suing to block the law argued that it would stifle Americans’ speech, and unfairly limit the information they’re able to access. The DOJ defended the law as appropriately tailored to address a national security risk. The three-judge panel that heard the case &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/16/24246568/tiktok-v-garland-oral-arguments-dc-circuit"&gt;appeared skeptical of the company’s arguments&lt;/a&gt;, prodding at the practicality of a more restrained approach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BQz9MC"&gt;The ruling could still appealed &lt;em&gt;en banc&lt;/em&gt; to the full panel of judges on the DC Circuit, and ultimately to the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24297454/tiktok-divest-or-ban-dc-circuit-court-appeals"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/6/24297454/tiktok-divest-or-ban-dc-circuit-court-appeals</id>
    <author>
      <name>Lauren Feiner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
