<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-11T12:45:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T12:45:47-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T12:45:47-05:00</updated>
    <title>Nvidia must face lawsuit alleging it downplayed crypto’s impact on its success</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vector collage of the Ndivia logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/InG0tLEXBKKQruT0YdkEttVI1kQ=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780803/STK083_NVIDIA_A.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Cath Virginia / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="CXHTYE"&gt;Nvidia must face an investor lawsuit claiming it misled shareholders about the impact of the cryptocurrency market on its sales after the Supreme Court dismissed the company’s appeal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Bgb7oI"&gt;The court said it had “improvidently granted” Nvidia’s petition, meaning it decided it shouldn’t have taken it up in the first place. That means the case will have to continue on in the lower courts. During oral arguments last month, some justices seemed skeptical about whether it was appropriate for them to weigh in on the case, wondering if it was more of a dispute over facts than a legal question, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/us-supreme-court-hear-nvidia-bid-avoid-securities-fraud-suit-2024-11-13/"&gt;according to &lt;em&gt;Reuters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uYEWXr"&gt;The case stems from a pair of &lt;a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/8490233/1/in-re-nvidia-corporation-securities-litigation/"&gt;2018 investor lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; claiming Nvidia recklessly misled investors about how closely tied its revenue growth was to cryptocurrency performance. Investors alleged that Nvidia and its top executives made materially false claims downplaying the impact of the volatile cryptocurrency market on its revenue growth, and exaggerating its ability to adapt its changes. An appeals court &lt;a href="https://cdn.ca9.uscourts.gov/datastore/opinions/2023/08/25/21-15604.pdf"&gt;had allowed&lt;/a&gt; at least a portion of the consolidated case to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W9HqDb"&gt;In a separate case in 2022, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/5/6/23059930/nvidia-sec-charges-fine-settlement-gaming-gpu-crypto-mining"&gt;Nvidia settled charges with the Securities and Exchange Commission&lt;/a&gt; for $5.5 million over claims it obscured how its success was linked to the volatile cryptocurrency market. The company did not admit to any wrongdoing in the settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iqeViT"&gt;Nvidia is facing increased legal scrutiny alongside its business success. The company is reportedly facing antitrust investigations from both &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/9/24317016/nvidia-mellanox-antitrust-china-ai-chips"&gt;Chinese authorities&lt;/a&gt; and the US &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/3/24235233/nvidia-doj-ai-antitrust-investigation"&gt;Department of Justice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ju5EWS"&gt;“We would have preferred a decision on the merits affirming the trial court’s dismissal of the case, but we are fully prepared to continue our defense,” Nvidia spokesperson John Rizzo says in a statement. “Consistent and predictable standards in securities litigation are essential to protecting shareholders and ensuring a strong economy, and we remain committed to supporting them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JdPtos"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318794/nvidia-supreme-court-investor-lawsuit-cryptocurrency"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318794/nvidia-supreme-court-investor-lawsuit-cryptocurrency</id>
    <author>
      <name>Lauren Feiner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T12:44:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T12:44:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Microsoft wants to make the Xbox app the home of PC gaming</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vector illustration of the Xbox logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6kF_f5-n8oNtRLu6UR2mhsP6Hd4=/20x0:2021x1334/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780799/STK048_XBOX_C.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6bmHua"&gt;Microsoft is updating the Xbox app on Windows today with hundreds of PC games that weren’t previously available and a new home experience. It’s part of a broader effort to make the Xbox app &lt;em&gt;the &lt;/em&gt;place to find PC games, regardless of whether they’re part of PC Game Pass or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RfKY8R"&gt;“Earlier this summer, we began working with partners to bring all PC games with Xbox features into the Xbox app,” &lt;a href="https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/games/articles/2024/12/updates-to-the-xbox-app/"&gt;explains Chris Charla&lt;/a&gt;, general manager of content curation and programs at Xbox. “We’re super excited to see what Xbox games come to Windows PC from game creators in the future and to welcome nearly 400 titles that previously weren’t discoverable or purchasable in the Xbox app.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xX2Lkuy6CI4vzYKHphz3DcQz2Qs=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25785345/XboxAppInsiderHERO.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Microsoft&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The new Xbox app homescreen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="Tk69Oa"&gt;The 400 new games include titles from Japanese studios like Kemco and Kairosoft, alongside games like &lt;em&gt;The Invincible&lt;/em&gt; by Double 11. More than 100 of these new titles are also Xbox Play Anywhere, so if you buy the Xbox console version then you can play the Xbox PC version too. “Universal Xbox ownership, as well as universal cloud saves on Xbox, and cross-play between Xbox versions on console and PC (and other platforms, at the developer’s discretion) are awesome features players love,” says Charla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0KakJi"&gt;What’s not immediately clear from Microsoft’s blog post is exactly what “bring all PC games with Xbox features into the Xbox app,” means. Microsoft has been trying to tempt game developers over to its Windows-based store in recent years, even &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/29/22409285/microsoft-store-cut-windows-pc-games-12-percent"&gt;lowing its cut from 30 percent to just 12 percent&lt;/a&gt; to try and shake up PC gaming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HSWMC3"&gt;Despite these efforts, there are plenty of PC games that have cross-play between the Xbox and PC version of the game but aren’t part of the Microsoft Store currently or the Xbox app. Microsoft now appears to be working to bring even more of these games into the Xbox app, and it will be interesting to see whether the company makes the bold move of listing Steam, Epic Games Store, or &lt;a href="http://itch.io"&gt;itch.io&lt;/a&gt; games in the Xbox app soon, too. Microsoft says it will have more to share about its Xbox app plans at the game developers conference in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2DiOvs"&gt;Microsoft is also rolling out a new home UI for the Xbox app on Windows today. The home UI now includes featured content from PC Game Pass and the Microsoft Store, alongside collections of deals and discounts. Microsoft has also added a “jump back in” section that lets you quickly get back into recent games just like you can on an Xbox console.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318799/microsoft-xbox-app-new-games-homescreen"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318799/microsoft-xbox-app-new-games-homescreen</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tom Warren</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T12:30:45-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T12:30:45-05:00</updated>
    <title>The PS5 disc drive is back in stock, but only for GameStop Pro members</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Photo of PS5 disc drive" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Wv9CrOaJPwda01wnxK7KV5jeTdA=/0x0:1005x670/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780783/Sony_Disc_Drive_For_PlayStation_5_Digital_Edition_Consoles_Slim.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;We never thought such a simple attachment would be so difficult to come by.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Sony&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="xAxtoK"&gt;Sony’s detachable disc drive for the PlayStation 5 has been &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/11/24242334/the-people-want-disc-drives"&gt;hard to come by&lt;/a&gt; as of late, and it’s disappointing that the $700 &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/reviews/24289319/ps5-pro-review"&gt;PS5 Pro&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t include one. However, &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fconsoles-hardware%2Fplaystation-5%2Fconsoles%2Fproducts%2Fsony-disc-drive-for-playstation-5-digital-edition-consoles-slim%2F402415.html" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;GameStop&lt;/a&gt; is now offering a rare window for GameStop Pro members to pick one up for its original MSRP of $79.99. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="zs9d6G"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here are all the games enhanced by PS5 Pro","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24240027/sony-ps5-pro-enhanced-games-list-game-boost"},{"title":"Sony’s new PS5 heralds the end of disc drives","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/10/24241265/sony-ps5-pro-game-console-disc-drive-end"},{"title":"Sony is still slashing prices on consoles, controllers, and more for the holidays","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/8/24315169/sony-ps5-slim-psvr-2-dualsense-controller-holiday-sale-deal"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="GtLQu0"&gt;GameStop’s loyalty program &lt;a href="https://click.linksynergy.com/deeplink?id=nOD%2FrLJHOac&amp;amp;mid=24348&amp;amp;u1=verge&amp;amp;murl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gamestop.com%2Fpro%2F" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;costs $25 a year&lt;/a&gt;, so you can consider that an added premium if you’re not interested in its other benefits. Those include a $5 welcome reward, two percent cash back rewards, free shipping, exclusive deals and discounts, and an extra $5 monthly reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="nMJ2gS"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12450405"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="zCBvTx"&gt;Whether you already own or anticipate purchasing a digital-only PS5, such as the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/10/23955005/sony-playstation-5-ps5-slim-size-comparison-photo-gallery-hands-on-impressions"&gt;newest Digital Edition&lt;/a&gt; or recently released PS5 Pro, it’s a good idea to pick one up while you have the chance. Neither console requires the disc drive, but with no future guarantee that your favorite games will be available for download after the console generation runs its course, it offers nice peace of mind. The add-on also ensures that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/entertainment/24054458/physical-media-preservation-discs-cartridges-digital"&gt;physical media preservationists&lt;/a&gt; can continue using physical game copies, although you may still have to download extra data to play many of them. It also allows you to play your entire Blu-Ray and DVD collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HZxwcb"&gt;What’s neat about the PS5’s Disc Drive is that it hides away under a cover that makes it look like a seamless piece of the overall hardware. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/e/23723205"&gt;Setup is easy&lt;/a&gt;, too, and only requires connecting a cable before pairing it to your console. You’ll need an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/10/25/23931637/ps5-slim-removable-disc-drive-internet-required"&gt;internet connection for the initial setup&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s a small inconvenience to gain the long-term benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="wNqOdy"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318790/playstation-5-ps5-disc-drive-restock-gamestop-pro-members"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318790/playstation-5-ps5-disc-drive-restock-gamestop-pro-members</id>
    <author>
      <name>Quentyn Kennemer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T12:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T12:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Watching sports: a special series from The Verge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VEs66v2ZHv5-ZmGQO2yiSfdnxgg=/0x65:3000x2065/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780769/headere__1_.5.png" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="UsTobe"&gt;It should be simple to stream live TV at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HQb4Fd"&gt;But depending on the sport, you might be signing up (and paying handsomely) for a lot of different services just to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6mwf9"&gt;There are the rare leagues, like Major League Soccer, that can be watched on a single channel. (In the US, every match can be viewed live on Apple TV Plus.) But keeping up with most sports resembles, say, tennis, where the rights for its four major tournaments are scattered across several different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rXBjKX"&gt;And in general, as the large streaming platforms go toe-to-toe with the legacy broadcast companies transitioning to digital, the much-sought-after rights have positioned leagues to make a lot of money. The adverse effect for viewers is that many professional sports are now available “exclusively” in many different places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PxAu5G"&gt;Basically, watching sports has never been easier. And it’s also never been harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2Ad0qL"&gt;The high cost of NFL streaming options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="L83VF1"&gt;In the US, you can stream the majority of live NFL games through Sunday Ticket, a full season of which costs $349, plus you’ll need to be subscribed to YouTube TV at $72.99 a month. For six months of football ($437.94), from week one to Super Bowl Sunday, that brings...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/c/24312149/sports-gymnastics-tennis-surveillance-ai"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/c/24312149/sports-gymnastics-tennis-surveillance-ai"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/c/24312149/sports-gymnastics-tennis-surveillance-ai</id>
    <author>
      <name>Verge Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Lord of the Rings: The War of the Rohirrim is a soulless return to Middle-earth</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A red-haired woman wearing a wedding dress and a circlet as she charges into battle on the back of a horse." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/olWt0LdPihZvbBKVMZ9ZKp9LlmM=/390x0:1658x845/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780687/rev_1_LOTR_WOTR_T1_018_High_Res_JPEG.0.jpeg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Warner Bros. Animation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Director Kenji Kamiyama’s new Lord of the Rings anime film feels like what happens when you try to turn a footnote into a feature-length story.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318164/lord-of-the-rings-war-of-the-rohirrim-review"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318164/lord-of-the-rings-war-of-the-rohirrim-review"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318164/lord-of-the-rings-war-of-the-rohirrim-review</id>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Pulliam-Moore</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T11:34:31-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T11:34:31-05:00</updated>
    <title>The Onion’s acquisition of Infowars was blocked by a judge</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo showing Alex Jones" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/zxJbrqOJpxB5PmAyRqsDzRLS604=/0x0:8660x5773/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780632/1425979532.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Joe Buglewicz/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="KE3MDA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Onion&lt;/em&gt;’s acquisition of InfoWars isn’t happening — at least for now. In a ruling on Tuesday, a Texas bankruptcy judge rejected &lt;em&gt;The Onion&lt;/em&gt;’s purchase of the conspiracy-ridden website founded by Alex Jones, according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/10/business/media/the-onion-infowars-alex-jones.html"&gt;a report from &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OjChu9"&gt;Last month, &lt;em&gt;The Onion&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/14/24296375/the-onion-infowars-acquisition-alex-jones"&gt;announced that it had purchased InfoWars&lt;/a&gt; during a bankruptcy auction of Jones’ assets. It had the support of the families of the Sandy Hook Elementary School shooting victims, who successfully sued Jones &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/06/06/nx-s1-4995796/conspiracy-theorist-alex-jones-agrees-to-liquidate-assets-to-pay-sandy-hook-families"&gt;for more than $1 billion&lt;/a&gt; for spreading false claims. However, Judge Christopher Lopez &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/judge-onion-infowars-hearing-review-auction-1236211183/"&gt;halted the sale shortly after the auction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hZawJf"&gt;As reported by &lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;, Lopez disagreed with the sealed bidding process used to sell Jones’ assets, saying that the auction didn’t “maximize” the amount of money Jones’ creditors could’ve gotten from the sale of InfoWars. “It seemed doomed almost from the moment they decided to go to a sealed bid,” Judge Lopez said when handing down his decision, according to &lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt;. “Nobody knows what anybody else is bidding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TPT6tX"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="bluesky-embed" data-bluesky-uri="at://did:plc:x4qyokjtdzgl7gmqhsw4ajqj/app.bsky.feed.post/3lcyypar33k2o" data-bluesky-cid="bafyreih6f25oyy3p5qw7hm2ycmce4bu6oo5gugncvvnaf2st5cdovaox2u"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en"&gt;A statement from The Onion about InfoWars.&lt;/p&gt;— &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:x4qyokjtdzgl7gmqhsw4ajqj?ref_src=embed"&gt;Tim Onion (@bencollins.bsky.social)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:x4qyokjtdzgl7gmqhsw4ajqj/post/3lcyypar33k2o?ref_src=embed"&gt;2024-12-11T05:14:01.469Z&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://embed.bsky.app/static/embed.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2XerIi"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Onion &lt;/em&gt;bid $7 million to acquire InfoWars, which included $1.75 million &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24225592/the-onion-new-owners-print-newspaper-digital-media-gawker-ben-collins-decoder-interview"&gt;from its parent company Global Tetrahedron&lt;/a&gt;, while the remainder would come from money Sandy Hook families won from their lawsuit against Jones, &lt;em&gt;The Times&lt;/em&gt; reports. Despite this roadblock, Global Tetrahedron still intends to pursue an acquisition of InfoWars, with the goal of replacing the site with “a relentless barrage of humor for good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mDFxI3"&gt;“We are deeply disappointed in today’s decision but The Onion will continue to seek a resolution that helps the Sandy Hook families receive a positive outcome for the horror they endured,” &lt;em&gt;The Onion&lt;/em&gt; CEO Ben Collins &lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:x4qyokjtdzgl7gmqhsw4ajqj/post/3lcyypar33k2o?ref_src=embed"&gt;said in a post on Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;. “We will also continue to seek a path toward purchasing InfoWars in the coming weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318745/the-onion-infowars-acqusition-blocked-judge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318745/the-onion-infowars-acqusition-blocked-judge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T11:00:15-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T11:00:15-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple Watch Series 10’s record low price from Black Friday is back</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="person looking at Tides app in watchOS 11" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/R4abju0SGmU2A51gXHp0NVJo2_w=/0x0:2700x1800/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780493/247270_Apple_watch_series_10_AKrales_0613.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Series 10 has the biggest display of any non-Ultra Apple Watch.&lt;/em&gt; | Photo by Amelia Holowaty Krales / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="ttLOs3"&gt;If you happened to miss out on the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24246464/apple-watch-series-10-review-smartwatch-wearables"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Watch Series 10’&lt;/strong&gt;s&lt;/a&gt; all-time low Black Friday price, now is a good chance for redemption. The &lt;strong&gt;42mm GPS model&lt;/strong&gt; of Apple’s latest smartwatch has dropped to $329.99 (about $70 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DGJ5KQL7/?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; when you click a coupon. The &lt;strong&gt;46mm GPS Series 10&lt;/strong&gt; is also on sale for $359.99 ($70 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0DGJ4QLYH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; with a coupon and matching its lowest price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="qjOQx3"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Here’s how the new Apple Watch Series 10 stacks up to other models ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24240412/apple-watch-series-10-vs-ultra-2-se-comparison-specs-price"},{"title":"How to choose which Apple Watch to buy ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/23037217/best-apple-watch-series-se-ultra"},{"title":"The Apple Watch is now a better TV remote ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/19/24249074/apple-watch-watchos-11-tv-remote"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="Ez8Elh"&gt;The Apple Watch Series 10 would be a great jump from older models if your last upgrade happened more than a few cycles ago, and certainly a viable alternative to the Watch Ultra 2 if you’re not interested in spending $800. Compared to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23878981/apple-watch-series-9-ultra-2-review-double-tap-precision-finding-siri"&gt;Series 9&lt;/a&gt;, it offers a slightly bigger wide-angle OLED display while being about 10 percent thinner and a touch lighter. It also has faster wireless charging than any Apple Watch before it (up to 80 percent in 30 minutes or eight hours of use from 15 minutes of charging). New to the Apple Watch lineup as of the Series 10 are underwater depth and water temperature sensors for tracking your aquatic activities. You can also play music over its speaker and enjoy clearer calls thanks to a voice isolation feature. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZiYjAr"&gt;Everything else will mostly feel familiar if you’re coming from a Series 9, including the new &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/16/24246150/apple-watch-sleep-apnea-detection-fda-approval"&gt;FDA-approved sleep apnea feature&lt;/a&gt; that debuted late into its launch. We haven’t had enough time to judge its effectiveness, but note that it uses the accelerometer instead of the blood oxygen sensors &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24009254/apple-watch-itc-ban-patent-dispute"&gt;Apple was forced to remove from its watches in the US&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Z0YhTj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12429524"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="1Qxys4"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="productcard:12462708"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="5uM4Vb"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="j2ADX8"&gt;A few more mid-week deals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5zAqYt"&gt;Looking for a different aesthetic to drive the point home in a PC gaming setup? The &lt;strong&gt;8BitDo Retro Mechanical Keyboard&lt;/strong&gt; can certainly do the trick. You can get the NES-inspired design with a matching joystick and dual oversized super buttons for $84.99 ($15 off) at &lt;a href="https://howl.link/nvpbb3ktwu6yz"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;. The tenkeyless wireless board works over Bluetooth or 2.4GHz Wi-Fi, or via USB-C. It’s nice to look at and type on with its Kailh White switches and PBT-capped keys, but the package offers nice versatility for playing retro games. You can even reconfigure every button on the keyboard and customize the super buttons with any macro you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="uQCZaQ"&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sonos Ace&lt;/strong&gt; are very good noise-cancelling headphones on their own merit, but they’re especially intriguing for an all-time low $349 ($100), a deal &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sonos-Ace-Wireless-Headphones-Cancellation/dp/B0CYHGTMNH?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://howl.link/0gg85rx7yyouq"&gt;Best Buy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.sonos.com/en-us/shop/sonos-ace-black" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Sonos&lt;/a&gt; are repeating from Black Friday. They look and sound the part for a premium pair of headphones, with great comfort, good audio quality, and solid ANC performance. Unfortunately, the Ace doesn’t fully blend into the wider Sonos ecosystem right now. The unique TV Audio Swap feature is iOS-only and not fully compatible across its full range of soundbars or &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; other Sonos speaker, for example. That said, they’re worthy of consideration at this price if you’re into the brand. &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24169086/sonos-ace-headphones-review"&gt;Read our review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="mOe5Bn"&gt;You can get the &lt;strong&gt;Anker PowerCore 548 Power Bank &lt;/strong&gt;for $79.99 ($70 off) at &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CQ5BMM9Z?tag=theverge02-20" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; with a coupon, which is an all-time low price. It offers two USB-C ports and two USB-A ports with up to 87W charging speeds available between them. The 192Wh (60,000mAh) capacity is enough to charge laptops, tablets, and smartphones several times over. It has an integrated retractable LED lamp with adjustable brightness and an SOS mode, which turns the light on automatically during a blackout while plugged in. It also has a carrying handle and solar inputs, making it ideal for both in-home and outdoor needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;aside id="WLxbhL"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"deals"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318667/apple-watch-series-10-smartwatch-sonos-ace-headphones-deal-sale"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318667/apple-watch-series-10-smartwatch-sonos-ace-headphones-deal-sale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Quentyn Kennemer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T10:33:02-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T10:33:02-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s AI enters its ‘agentic era’</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo of a person holding a phone up to a bus." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/slHPE0UxRvPK3vr21WUSDgtuB80=/300x0:1920x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780393/videoframe_151522.10.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Project Astra is supposed to be more useful than ever — and it knows where you are. | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yh0QVL"&gt;I stepped into a room lined with bookshelves, stacked with ordinary programming and architecture texts. One shelf stood slightly askew, and behind it was a hidden room that had three TVs displaying famous artworks: Edvard Munch’s &lt;a href="https://www.edvardmunch.org/the-scream.jsp"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Scream&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Georges Seurat’s &lt;a href="https://www.artic.edu/artworks/27992/a-sunday-on-la-grande-jatte-1884"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sunday Afternoon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and Hokusai’s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Great_Wave_off_Kanagawa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Wave off Kanagawa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “There’s some interesting pieces of art here,” said Bibo Xu, Google DeepMind’s lead product manager for Project Astra. “Is there one in particular that you would want to talk about?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JtPKZx"&gt;Project Astra, Google’s prototype AI “universal agent,” responded smoothly. “The &lt;em&gt;Sunday Afternoon &lt;/em&gt;artwork was discussed previously,” it replied. “Was there a particular detail about it you wish to discuss, or were you interested in discussing &lt;em&gt;The Scream&lt;/em&gt;?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mkgXk5"&gt;I was at Google’s sprawling Mountain View campus, seeing the latest projects from its AI lab DeepMind. One was Project Astra, a virtual assistant &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/14/24156296/google-ai-gemini-astra-assistant-live-io"&gt;first demoed at Google I/O&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. Currently contained in an app, it can process text, images, video, and audio in real time and respond to questions about them. It’s like a Siri or Alexa that’s slightly more natural to talk to, can see the world around you, and can “remember”...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24317436/google-deepmind-project-astra-mariner-ai-agent</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kylie Robison</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>It sure sounds like Google is planning to actually launch some smart glasses</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A man in a bike helmet, wearing glasses." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QZUN81v654TmFeyekOgmYrAdLMc=/70x0:1690x1080/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780383/Google_Glasses.0.png" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what Google’s latest smart glasses prototype looks like.&lt;/em&gt; | Image: Google&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="9peXhl"&gt;Google is working on a lot of AI stuff — like, a &lt;em&gt;lot &lt;/em&gt;of AI stuff — but if you want to really understand the company’s vision for virtual assistants, take a look at Project Astra. Google first showed a demo of its all-encompassing, multimodal virtual assistant at Google I/O this spring and clearly imagines Astra as an always-on helper in your life. In reality, the tech is somewhere between “neat concept video” and “early prototype,” but it represents the most ambitious version of Google’s AI work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gFgV3p"&gt;And there’s one thing that keeps popping up in Astra demos: glasses. Google has been working on smart facewear of one kind or another for years, from Glass to Cardboard to the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/7/19/23270219/google-ar-prototypes-test-public"&gt;Project Iris&lt;/a&gt; translator glasses it showed off two years ago. Earlier this year, all Google spokesperson Jane Park would tell us was that the glasses were “&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/14/24156518/google-glass-prototype-ar-glasses-io-2024"&gt;a functional research prototype&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nbPDvv"&gt;Now, they appear to be something at least a little more than that. During a press briefing ahead of the launch of Gemini 2.0, Bibo Xu, a product manager on the Google DeepMind team, said that “a small group will be testing Project Astra on prototype glasses, which we believe is one of the most powerful and intuitive form factors to experience this kind of AI.” That group will be part of Google’s Trusted Tester program, which often gets access to these early prototypes, many of which don’t ever ship publicly. Some testers will use Astra on an Android phone; others through the glasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="TGH9Ac"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hIIlJt8JERI?rel=0" style="top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute; border: 0;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="TmdjhB"&gt;Later in the briefing, in response to a question about the glasses, Xu said that “for the glasses product itself, we’ll have more news coming shortly.” Is that definitive proof that Google Smart Glasses are coming to a store near you sometime soon? Of course not! But it certainly indicates that Google has some hardware plans for Project Astra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N9VhLr"&gt;Smart glasses make perfect sense for what Google is trying to do with Astra. There’s simply no better way to combine audio, video, and a display than on a device on your face — especially if you’re hoping for something like an always-on experience. In a new video showing Astra’s capabilities with Gemini 2.0, a tester uses Astra to remember security codes at an apartment building, check the weather, and much more. At one point, he sees a bus flying past and asks Astra if “that bus will take me anywhere near Chinatown.” It’s all the sort of thing you &lt;em&gt;can &lt;/em&gt;do with a phone, but nearly all of it feels far more natural through a wearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="14be84"&gt;Right now, smart glasses like these — and like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24253908/meta-orion-ar-glasses-demo-mark-zuckerberg-interview"&gt;Meta’s Orion&lt;/a&gt; — are mostly vaporware. When they’ll ship, &lt;em&gt;whether &lt;/em&gt;they’ll ship, and whether they’ll be any good all remains up in the air. But Google is dead serious about making smart glasses work. And seems to be just as serious about making the smart glasses itself.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318672/google-smart-glasses-ai-gemini"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318672/google-smart-glasses-ai-gemini</id>
    <author>
      <name>David Pierce</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-11T10:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-11T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <title>Google’s new Jules AI agent will help developers fix buggy code</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="An illustration of Google’s multicolor “G” logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wEhfAvC2MonJj2pXsrH-puCX3SU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73780369/STK093_Google_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="oGsece"&gt;Google has announced an experimental AI-powered code agent called “Jules” that can automatically fix coding errors for developers. &lt;a href="https://developers.googleblog.com/en/the-next-chapter-of-the-gemini-era-for-developers"&gt;Jules was introduced today&lt;/a&gt; alongside Gemini 2.0, and uses the updated Google AI model to create multi-step plans to address issues, modify multiple files, and prepare pull requests for Python and Javascript coding tasks in GitHub workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BI4rXb"&gt;Microsoft introduced &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/3/22/23651456/github-copilot-x-gpt-4-code-chat-voice-support"&gt;a similar experience for GitHub Copilot last year&lt;/a&gt; that can recognize and explain code, alongside recommending changes and fixing bugs. Jules will compete against Microsoft’s offering, and also against tools like &lt;a href="https://www.cursor.com/"&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; and even Claude and ChatGPT’s coding abilities. Google’s launch of a coding-focused AI assistant is no surprise — &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/29/24282757/google-new-code-generated-ai-q3-2024"&gt;CEO Sundar Pichai said in October&lt;/a&gt; that more than a quarter of all new code at the company is now generated by AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OPzYlw"&gt;“Jules handles bug fixes and other time-consuming tasks while you focus on what you actually want to build,” Google says in its blog post. “This effort is part of our long-term goal of building AI agents that are helpful in all domains, including coding.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SsLVQy"&gt;Developers have full control to review and adjust the plans created by Jules, before choosing to merge the code it generates into their projects. The announcement doesn’t say that Jules will &lt;em&gt;spot &lt;/em&gt;bugs for you, so presumably it needs to be directed to a list of issues that have already been identified to fix. Google also says that Jules is in early development and “may make mistakes,” but internal testing has shown it’s been beneficial for boosting developer productivity and providing real-time updates to help track and manage tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e4WGaG"&gt;Jules is launching today for a “select group of trusted testers” according to Google, and will be released to other developers in early 2025. Updates about availability and how development is progressing will be available via the &lt;a href="http://labs.google.com/jules"&gt;Google Labs website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318628/jules-google-ai-coding-agent-gemini-2-0-announcement"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/11/24318628/jules-google-ai-coding-agent-gemini-2-0-announcement</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jess Weatherbed</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
