<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Verge -  All Posts</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52801/VER_Logomark_32x32..png</icon>
  <updated>2024-12-05T05:51:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/full.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-05T05:51:44-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-05T05:51:44-05:00</updated>
    <title>Vodafone and Three clear to merge and form the UK’s biggest mobile operator</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Logos Of Companies And Stores In Stuttgart, Germany" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LYYUPgFP_TvrMNVIjqyuM5r117Y=/0x0:6000x4000/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767836/2156794866.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="vdmLgj"&gt;Vodafone and Three have been cleared to create the UK’s biggest mobile operator after committing to address concerns around network upgrades and price hikes. The proposed £16.5 billion merger (about $20.9 billion) was &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-clears-vodafone-three-merger-subject-to-legally-binding-commitments"&gt;approved by the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) on Thursday&lt;/a&gt; following months of regulatory scrutiny, and is expected to be completed in the first half of 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2yhJ1z"&gt;“Having carefully considered the evidence, as well as the extensive feedback we have received, we believe the merger is likely to boost competition in the UK mobile sector and should be allowed to proceed – but only if Vodafone and Three agree to implement our proposed measures,” Stuart McIntosh, chair of the inquiry group leading the antitrust investigation, said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdO3lW"&gt;The approval was subject to both companies signing binding commitments to invest billions into expanding their combined 5G network over the next eight years. The agreement also requires the new entity to cap some mobile tariffs and offer preset contractual terms to mobile virtual network operators for three years, &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/cma-provisionally-finds-vodafone-three-could-address-competition-concerns-through-network-investment-and-customer-protections#:~:text=The%20CMA%20investigation%20%E2%80%93%20led%20by,Lyca%2C%20Lebara%20and%20iD%20Mobile."&gt;addressing previous CMA concerns&lt;/a&gt; that the merger could harm competition and lead to higher prices for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TQr3bx"&gt;“Today’s approval releases the handbrake on the UK’s telecoms industry, and the increased investment will power the UK to the forefront of European telecommunications,” &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vodafone.co.uk%2Fnewscentre%2Fpress-release%2Fcma-approves-merger-vodafone-three-uk%2F&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F5%2F24313871%2Fvodafone-three-mobile-network-merger-uk-antitrust-approval" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Vodafone CEO Margherita Della Valle said in a statement&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dISiPt"&gt;The plan to combine two of the country’s top four mobile operators was &lt;a href="https://otp.tools.investis.com/clients/uk/vodafone4/rns/regulatory-story.aspx?cid=221&amp;amp;newsid=1695021"&gt;first announced in 2023&lt;/a&gt;, and will create a network with 27 million customers once complete. Vodafone will own 51 percent of the merged entity, and is expected to buy out the remaining 49 percent after three years. The deal follows similar large-scale mergers between companies like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2012/8/21/3257380/t-mobile-orange-rebrand-everything-everywhere-october-rumor"&gt;Orange and T-Mobile in 2010&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.virginmedia.com%2Fhelp%2Fmobile%2Fyour-move-to-o2&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F5%2F24313871%2Fvodafone-three-mobile-network-merger-uk-antitrust-approval" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Virgin Mobile and O2 in 2021&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24313871/vodafone-three-mobile-network-merger-uk-antitrust-approval"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/5/24313871/vodafone-three-mobile-network-merger-uk-antitrust-approval</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jess Weatherbed</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T23:20:19-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T23:20:19-05:00</updated>
    <title>Suspect in UnitedHealthcare CEO shooting reportedly didn’t use a Citi Bike to escape</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="UnitedHealth Executive Fatally Shot In NYC On Investor Day" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DBt-HQRUMTWKR8C_AtxSIBPyTMY=/0x1:4000x2668/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767132/2187636759.0.jpg" /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="TFM1vP"&gt;CNN &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/unitedhealthcare-brian-thompson-death-12-04-24#cm4agzsar00073b6n7bc0ndq5"&gt;is reporting&lt;/a&gt; that according to an unnamed source in law enforcement, the person who shot and killed UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson outside the Hilton hotel in midtown Manhattan fled on an e-bike, but not a Citi Bike, as NYPD Chief of Detectives Joe Kenney previously said &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/vEOgXttzKjM?si=RdNxxZAKBHhKZg13&amp;amp;t=252"&gt;during a press conference&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WYQws1"&gt;Thompson had been scheduled to appear at the company’s investor meeting, which was canceled a few hours later. Kenney said it looked like the killer “specifically targeted” Thompson and that “at this point, we do not know why.” The CEO’s wife, Paulette Thompson, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/man-fatally-shot-nyc-hotel-police-say-rcna182789"&gt;told &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that “there had been some threats.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wjHkIy"&gt;In an email to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;, Lyft spokesperson Eric Smith had said previously that the company was “ready to assist law enforcement.” Had the shooter used one of the bikes owned by Lyft, it might have left a digital trail and GPS data while the shooter was renting or using the vehicle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="yJk4Hi"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true" align="center" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;These are images of the individual sought in connection to this investigation. If anyone has information as to the identity or location of this individual please contact &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NYPDTips?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@NYPDTips&lt;/a&gt; at 1(800)577-TIPS. &lt;a href="https://t.co/sm2GuEOYk1"&gt;pic.twitter.com/sm2GuEOYk1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— NYPD NEWS (@NYPDnews) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NYPDnews/status/1864353214784557105?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 4, 2024&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BQThTR"&gt;Other updates from CNN’s sources say that investigators &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/unitedhealthcare-brian-thompson-death-12-04-24#cm4afohys00003b6np6rtkqww"&gt;have recovered a cell phone&lt;/a&gt; from the alley the attacker ran through after the shooting that may belong to them, as well as a bottle of water he was seen purchasing, along with two PowerBars, at a Starbucks just before the attack. Additionally, they said police &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/unitedhealthcare-brian-thompson-death-12-04-24#cm4ak7i0b000c3b6npzs044kx"&gt;have video of the suspect&lt;/a&gt; from earlier in the morning, “carrying what appears to be a battery for an electric bike.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="K4GdWu"&gt;Another element is what law enforcement called the attacker’s “distinctive” backpack, which &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/peakdesign/comments/1h6kmof/united_healthcare_shooter_wearing_peak_design_bag/"&gt;many people believe&lt;/a&gt; is Peak Design’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/10/11/13240828/peak-design-everyday-backpack-review-not-an-ad"&gt;Everyday Backpack V1&lt;/a&gt; in a charcoal or ash color, based on its shape, color, and the straps visible in the pictures from Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a0fQXd"&gt;Earlier this year, UnitedHealthcare suffered a massive ransomware attack, which leaked info on &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24279288/unitedhealth-change-breach-100-million-leak"&gt;over 100 million people&lt;/a&gt; and snarled healthcare for weeks despite &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/1/24146693/unitedhealth-22-million-ransom-ransomware-hack-blackcat"&gt;a $22 million payment&lt;/a&gt; to the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="noIHUb"&gt;NYPD shared images of the shooter, including one of them on the bike, and asked that anyone with “information as to the identity or location of this individual” contact police at 1-800-577-TIPS. Police officials had been spotted asking around for video footage of a Citi Bike kiosk on Madison Avenue and 82nd Street in Manhattan early Wednesday afternoon, according to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/12/04/nyregion/brian-thompson-uhc-ceo-shot/929beb87-2496-5629-b1d1-1b4736ecad3b?smid=url-share"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0p5TUt"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, December 4th&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;: Updated based on the report attacker did not use a Citi Bike, as police previously indicated, and added additional info from CNN.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313480/lyft-united-health-ceo-shooter-escaped-citi-bike-cooperating-authorities"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313480/lyft-united-health-ceo-shooter-escaped-citi-bike-cooperating-authorities</id>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Davis</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T22:41:08-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T22:41:08-05:00</updated>
    <title>Bitcoin just hit $100,000</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The orange Bitcoin logo appears on a background of blue arrows pointing up." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/eRzxcip4-RI433wYkZB2uXaCwbU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767583/STK087_VRG_Illo_N_Barclay_1_bitcoin.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Nick Barclay / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7A87EL"&gt;Bitcoin has passed $100,000, marking its highest price since the cryptocurrency launched more than a decade ago, and as of this writing, it has reached $103,359.00, according to Kraken. Despite its triumphs, Bitcoin’s value is still being measured in USD, emerging as an &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/22744728/money-fandom-cryptocurrency-retail-trades-stocks"&gt;alternate payment option or investment&lt;/a&gt; rather than a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166096/bitcoin-blockchain-code-currency-money-genesis-block-silk-road-mt-gox"&gt;replacement for fiat currency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f9zasU"&gt;The price of Bitcoin spiked following the news that Donald Trump won the 2024 US Presidential Election. Bitcoin sat around $69,000 on Election Day but later shot to $75,000 following the news that Trump won, &lt;a href="https://www.coindesk.com/price/bitcoin"&gt;according to data from &lt;em&gt;CoinDesk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Its price has been rising since, as investors expect a more crypto-friendly environment under the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="cMUCRN"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"How bitcoin grew up and became big money","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/3/18166096/bitcoin-blockchain-code-currency-money-genesis-block-silk-road-mt-gox"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1dbHqh"&gt;Trump, who &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/15/24271242/world-liberty-financial-token-sale-website-crash-trump"&gt;has launched his own cryptocurrency platform&lt;/a&gt;, has &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnbc.com%2F2024%2F11%2F06%2Ftrump-claims-presidential-win-here-is-what-he-promised-the-crypto-industry-ahead-of-the-election.html&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F4%2F24303204%2Fbitcoin-price-hit-100000" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;promised to hold onto&lt;/a&gt; the Bitcoin owned by the federal government while also &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-27/trump-pledges-to-fire-gensler-pick-regulators-who-love-crypto"&gt;vowing to fire Securities and Exchange Commission&lt;/a&gt; chair Gary Gensler, who has &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24280387/gary-gensler-sec-chair-presidential-election-2024"&gt;fought to regulate crypto firms&lt;/a&gt;. Gensler later announced that he would &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/21/24302518/gary-gensler-quits"&gt;step down&lt;/a&gt; from the position in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Chart showing Bitcoin price history in USD since January 2020" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7RmDh6rFQItvX-gxshCFqfJm4CY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25774425/btc_price.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Dune Analytics&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="XnlxRx"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"CNBC: Bitcoin tops $100,000 as monster 2024 rally reaches new heights","url":"https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/bitcoin-tops-100000-as-monster-2024-rally-reaches-new-heights.html"},{"title":"WSJ: Bitcoin Hits $100,000, Lifted by Hopes of a Crypto-Friendly Washington ","url":"https://www.wsj.com/finance/currencies/bitcoin-price-hits-100000-8ec230a2"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I0nSpx"&gt;The final push past the $100k mark occurred a few hours after Trump announced several nominations for his administration, which included &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313285/trump-sec-doj-antitrust-nominees-paul-atkins-gail-slater"&gt;adding former Republican Securities and Exchange Commissioner Paul Atkins as his pick&lt;/a&gt; to lead the agency. Atkins has served as co-chair of the Chamber of Digital Commerce’s Token Alliance, and Trump said he “recognizes that digital assets &amp;amp; other innovations are crucial to Making America Greater than Ever Before.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1EnLOf"&gt;Other factors contributed to the Bitcoin spike as well, including the start of options trading on Blackrock’s Bitcoin exchange-traded fund, which &lt;a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/blackrock-bitcoin-etf-options-unheard-of-day-one-volume"&gt;saw $1.9 billion traded during its first day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24303204/bitcoin-price-hit-100000"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24303204/bitcoin-price-hit-100000</id>
    <author>
      <name>Emma Roth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T19:09:09-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T19:09:09-05:00</updated>
    <title>Humane wants to put the AI Pin’s software inside your phone, car, and smart speaker</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A photo of a person wearing a Humane AI Pin in a car." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/XtRCNJ3HYw8qlMNkRogagjYgvAI=/0x160:3840x2720/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767329/8e3eec7bc75f88a1f31bc1578597a51249363207_10000x7500.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Humane&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="yzuNIw"&gt;Humane, which makes the &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/24126502/humane-ai-pin-review"&gt;not-great AI Pin&lt;/a&gt;, wants other companies to build AI devices and gadgets that use its CosmOS operating system, and it has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fsnysAHD2CU"&gt;released a video&lt;/a&gt; that appears to show that the company already has it working in a car, TV, smart speaker, and phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vwTaTj"&gt;But note that the video, according to Humane’s own fine print, is for “illustrative purposes only” — it shows “working prototypes” and some “simulated experiences,” and the print says that all “designs, features, and specifications” are subject to change. So don’t take it entirely at face value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hkp4lj"&gt;In one example, the video shows a person talking to CosmOS in their car (with a blurred out logo on the steering wheel) to turn the heat up at their house and figure out what time people are coming over. They ask their (blurred out) smart speaker about a guacamole recipe, and their TV about how many goals a soccer player onscreen has scored. The video also shows CosmOS reading an email on the person’s phone and responding to a question about whether the person can attend a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kprMkG"&gt;If you’ve been following recent AI hype, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/10/24266333/ai-agents-assistants-openai-google-deepmind-bots"&gt;especially around agents&lt;/a&gt;, none of these examples should feel particularly novel — Humane wants to demonstrate that CosmOS is capable of powerful agent-like capabilities, and for companies to consider it as a possible backbone for their devices. But the items in this video aren’t Humane’s own products, and Humane clearly isn’t promising to make them. It’s building an SDK for others to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="zEypy6"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Humane AI Pin review: not even close","url":"https://www.theverge.com/24126502/humane-ai-pin-review"},{"title":"Agents are the future AI companies promise — and desperately need","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/10/24266333/ai-agents-assistants-openai-google-deepmind-bots"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hGsvNY"&gt;That CosmOS SDK isn’t available publicly yet — the &lt;a href="https://humane.com/cosmos"&gt;company’s website&lt;/a&gt; only says that it’s “coming soon,” though you can click a button to “sign up to build with us,” which takes you to a form to fill out. Humane doesn’t mention any partners building devices that rely on CosmOS — the blurred-out logos on the car and smart speaker suggest the company may have not gotten that far yet. We’ve asked Humane if it can share any examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ib1mDJ"&gt;Humane may be looking for a new line of business after the AI Pin flopped; we reported in August that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/7/24211339/humane-ai-pin-more-daily-returns-than-sales"&gt;daily returns of the device were outpacing sales&lt;/a&gt;. The product initially launched in April, but the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/23/24277964/humane-slashes-ai-pin-price-weak-sales"&gt;dropped the price of the Pin&lt;/a&gt; just six months later. Earlier this year, Humane was reportedly &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/21/24162185/humane-seeking-acquisition-rumor-ai-pin"&gt;looking for a buyer&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/6/24172718/humane-ai-pin-selling-hp-rumor-1-billion"&gt;HP at one point being a contender&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313582/humane-ai-pin-cosmos-phone-car-smart-speaker"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313582/humane-ai-pin-cosmos-phone-car-smart-speaker</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T17:45:38-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T17:45:38-05:00</updated>
    <title>Jeff Bezos says he’s ‘very optimistic this time around’ about Trump</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Jeff Bezos stands in front of an Amazon logo" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YQ-85Rirf4kgFkMFQDB0FLMtH_E=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767160/VRG_Illo_STK173_L_Normand_JeffBezos_Positive2.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jeff Bezos.&lt;/em&gt; | Laura Normand / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="3WRwH2"&gt;Jeff Bezos and President-elect Donald Trump famously didn’t get along the last time Trump was in the White House. This time, Bezos says he’s “very optimistic” and even wants to help out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sr3Pvr"&gt;“I’m actually very optimistic this time around,” Bezos said of Trump during a rare public appearance at &lt;em&gt;The New York Times &lt;/em&gt;DealBook Summit on Wednesday. “He seems to have a lot of energy around reducing regulation. If I can help him do that, I’m going to help him.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1pkEc5"&gt;Trump &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/14/17233680/trump-amazon-bezos-postal-service-explained"&gt;railed against Bezos&lt;/a&gt; and his companies — Amazon, Blue Origin, and &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;— during his 2016 term. Bezos defended himself but it did little to help his reputation with Trump. Now, his companies have a lot at stake in the coming administration, from the FTC’s antitrust lawsuit against Amazon to Blue Origin’s efforts to compete with SpaceX for government contracts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nQ5EM5"&gt;Onstage at the DealBook Summit on Wednesday, Bezos called Trump “calmer this time” and “more settled.” He said he will try to “talk him out of” the idea that the press, which includes &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, is an enemy of the people. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9wv2TS"&gt;“You’ve probably grown in the last eight years,” he said to DealBook’s Andrew Ross Sorkin. “He has, too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cyf8Ds"&gt;Bezos also echoed Sam...&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313549/bezos-trump-optimistic-dealbook-summit-doge"&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313549/bezos-trump-optimistic-dealbook-summit-doge"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313549/bezos-trump-optimistic-dealbook-summit-doge</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Heath</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T17:24:28-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T17:24:28-05:00</updated>
    <title>US officials recommend encrypted messaging to evade hackers in telecom networks</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Photo collage of a phone with a deadbolt and key over the passcode number pad." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mc6uzwXvDdf9tF_1GZFZhoa5rRI=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767093/STK478_breaking_into_phone_A.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge; Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="7oSKVA"&gt;US officials are urging Americans to make calls and send text messages over encrypted apps to minimize the risk of private information falling into the hands of foreign adversaries who might still be lurking in America’s telecommunications networks,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/security/us-officials-urge-americans-use-encrypted-apps-cyberattack-rcna182694"&gt;&lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6QC6mQ"&gt;Two officials from the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) spoke with news outlets, including &lt;em&gt;NBC News,&lt;/em&gt; Tuesday on the lasting effects of a &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/u-s-wiretap-systems-targeted-in-china-linked-hack-327fc63b"&gt;recent attack on US telecommunications systems&lt;/a&gt;. The attack, which was tied to Chinese hacking group Salt Typhoon, impacted companies including AT&amp;amp;T, Verizon, T-Mobile and Lumen Technologies, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/u-s-wiretap-systems-targeted-in-china-linked-hack-327fc63b"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; first reported&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;in October. &lt;em&gt;The Journal &lt;/em&gt;later reported that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24279635/salt-typhoon-hackers-reportedly-targeted-phone-numbers-for-trump-vance"&gt;targets of the hack&lt;/a&gt; included phone numbers for people in the Donald Trump and Kamala Harris campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u5Lce7"&gt;Two months after the initial report of the hack, malicious actors &lt;a href="https://www.yahoo.com/tech/fbi-urges-americans-encryption-complaining-191150800.html"&gt;may still be able to gain access&lt;/a&gt; to sensitive information about Americans’ communications from the telecom networks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="OoZD0g"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"T-Mobile actually stopped some hackers from stealing customer data","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/20/24301570/t-mobile-network-breach-stopped-salt-typhoon"},{"title":"‘Salt Typhoon’ hackers reportedly targeted phone numbers for Trump and Harris campaigns.","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/25/24279635/salt-typhoon-hackers-reportedly-targeted-phone-numbers-for-trump-vance"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="mLTlle"&gt;An FBI official&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;on the call, who was not identified in press reports, reportedly said hackers accessed information including call records showing phone numbers called and the times of the call, and in some cases actual live phone calls of certain targets. &lt;em&gt;The Journal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/china-hack-enabled-vast-spying-on-u-s-officials-likely-ensnaring-thousands-of-contacts-1340ba4a"&gt;reported last month&lt;/a&gt; that hackers could have gained access to unencrypted texts as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0mj7G3"&gt;Jeff Greene, executive assistant director for cybersecurity at CISA, told reporters&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;on the call that the scale of the hack was so great that agencies could not possibly predict when there would be a “full eviction” of malicious material, &lt;em&gt;NBC News &lt;/em&gt;writes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EmZzok"&gt;“Encryption is your friend, whether it’s on text messaging or if you have the capacity to use encrypted voice communication,” Greene said, according to &lt;em&gt;NBC News&lt;/em&gt;. “Even if the adversary is able to intercept the data, if it is encrypted, it will make it impossible.” Services like &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/2/24/21150918/european-commission-signal-encrypted-messaging"&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; and WhatsApp offer end-to-end encrypted messaging that can obscure communications outside of the users involved in the call or text. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yj46vW"&gt;Law enforcement’s embrace of encrypted apps is particularly notable given that the FBI has previously railed against tech companies’ protectiveness over the technology. Though the FBI &lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/about/mission/lawful-access"&gt;publicly says&lt;/a&gt; it does not oppose encryption, it has strict parameters on its support. The agency’s website states that it “does not want encryption to be weakened or compromised so that it can be defeated by malicious actors,” but wants companies that “manage encrypted data to be able to decrypt that data and provide it to law enforcement only in response to U.S. legal process.” That’s something tech companies say could undermine the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rdNvID"&gt;The bureau engaged in &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2016/2/17/11036306/apple-fbi-iphone-encryption-backdoor-tim-cook"&gt;a long standoff with Apple&lt;/a&gt; following a shooting in San Bernadino, California in 2015, because the company refused to break the encryption on the shooter’s iPhone to give investigators access, warning that to do so would endanger users’ privacy across its products. The FBI eventually &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/14/22383957/fbi-san-bernadino-iphone-hack-shooting-investigation"&gt;found a way to get into the phone without Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313187/encrypted-apps-salt-typhoon-hack-telecom-fbi-cisa"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313187/encrypted-apps-salt-typhoon-hack-telecom-fbi-cisa</id>
    <author>
      <name>Lauren Feiner</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T16:47:13-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T16:47:13-05:00</updated>
    <title>OpenAI is partnering with defense tech company Anduril</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Illustration of the OpenAI logo on an orange background with purple lines" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kqlud2FxMFbOWJIW-Op48YUPb1A=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73767020/STK149_AI_01.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration: The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="GK7Bsd"&gt;OpenAI, the AI model maker that &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/02/17/844721/ai-openai-moonshot-elon-musk-sam-altman-greg-brockman-messy-secretive-reality/"&gt;used to describe its mission as saving the world&lt;/a&gt;, is partnering with Anduril, a military contractor, the two companies announced Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oDIPHe"&gt;As part of the partnership, OpenAI will integrate its software into Anduril’s counterdrone systems, which detect and take down drones. It’s OpenAI’s first partnership with a defense contractor — and a significant reversal of its earlier stance towards the military. OpenAI’s terms of service once banned “military and warfare” use of its technology, but it softened its position on military use earlier this year, &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/12/24036397/openai-is-softening-its-stance-on-military-use"&gt;changing its terms of service&lt;/a&gt; in January to remove the proscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cQLPRj"&gt;“OpenAI builds AI to benefit as many people as possible, and supports U.S.-led efforts to ensure the technology upholds democratic values,” OpenAI CEO Sam Altman said in a &lt;a href="https://www.anduril.com/article/anduril-partners-with-openai-to-advance-u-s-artificial-intelligence-leadership-and-protect-u-s/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;. “Our partnership with Anduril will help ensure OpenAI technology protects U.S. military personnel, and will help the national security community understand and responsibly use this technology to keep our citizens safe and free.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4O2e1B"&gt;As the &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; notes, Anduril — currently valued at $14 billion — has a $200 million counterdrone systems contract with the Marine Corps. But OpenAI won’t just benefit financially from its Anduril partnership; it also stands to gain political clout. Anduril co-founder Palmer Luckey was an early supporter of president-elect Donald Trump, and also has ties to Elon Musk, one of the heads of the still-nebulous (and still nonexistent) &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/11/22/24302735/elon-musk-doge-vivek-ramaswamy-rage-curtis-yarvin"&gt;Department of Government Efficiency&lt;/a&gt;. And the America First Policy Institute, a right-wing think-tank working closely with the Trump transition team, has proposed that &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/31/24282719/tech-leaders-trump-jeff-bezos-zuckerberg-pichai"&gt;Trump embrace AI&lt;/a&gt; to create a new “Manhattan Project” for defense.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313486/openai-anduril-partnership-counterdrone-systems"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313486/openai-anduril-partnership-counterdrone-systems</id>
    <author>
      <name>Gaby Del Valle</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T16:36:12-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T16:36:12-05:00</updated>
    <title>Verizon is once again raising its fees</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="Vector illustration of the Verizon logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J-FZKygOrVHwkO1iWhpi9e1uvi8=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73766998/STK066_VERIZON_A.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The fee creep is back. | Image: Cath Virginia / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="6hRiwy"&gt;Verizon customers will soon see yet another fee increase on their next bill, a game that wireless carriers love to play. As &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/verizons-hidden-fee-just-went-up-without-anyone-noticing/"&gt;spotted by &lt;em&gt;Android Police&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Verizon customers &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/verizon/comments/1h5evtu/verizon_fee_is_going_up_again/"&gt;on reddit&lt;/a&gt; noticed the small fee bump — just 20 cents extra per line. But it comes &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/5/16/23075448/verizon-phone-bill-increase-administrative-fee"&gt;only a couple of years after a bigger increase&lt;/a&gt; to the “Administrative and Telco Recovery Charge” the company tacks onto monthly bills, and Verizon’s claim that it’s just the cost of doing business seems dubious at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FqQ8tG"&gt;Verizon spokesperson George Koroneos confirmed the fee hike to &lt;em&gt;The Verge, &lt;/em&gt;saying that “Starting December 18, the monthly Verizon wireless Administrative and Telco Recovery Charge will increase by $0.20 per line for mobile voice (basic phones, Second Number, smartphones, etc.) and data-only (hotspots, tablets, etc.) products. Verizon Home Internet services are not affected.” That takes the fee from $3.30 to $3.50 for each voice line on a plan and $1.40 up to $1.60 per data line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="title-cardPromo-5930d7b37f"&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/support/surcharges/" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;a Verizon support page&lt;/a&gt;, the fee “helps defray and recover certain direct and indirect costs we or our agents incur,” including network operating and maintenance costs. AT&amp;amp;T and T-Mobile have slightly different names for the same fee, and all make basically the same claim about offsetting the costs of running a wireless network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gNdSbP"&gt;A more cynical perspective is that these wireless companies separate this fee from their monthly rate plan charges so they can raise rates without saying they’re raising rates. That was the basis for a class-action lawsuit against AT&amp;amp;T in 2022, which &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/5/12/23069156/att-vianu-lawsuit-class-action-administrative-fee"&gt;that company agreed to settle&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UBEN6I"&gt;It may just be 20 cents now, but that small increase adds up to a lot when you multiply it across millions of users. After all, Verizon &lt;a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/links/8532386/type/dlg/sid/verge/https://www.verizon.com/about/news/verizon-delivers-strong-third-quarter-results-customer-growth-mobility-extending-industry" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;only made $3.4 billion&lt;/a&gt; in net income the third quarter this year, down from $4.9 billion in the same quarter last year. And while the fee creep is nothing new, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/7/27/23810590/verizon-att-unlimited-elite-legacy-plan-rate-adjustment-5g-start"&gt;yet another&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/13/24243817/verizon-halved-my-10-autopay-discount-out-of-the-blue-just-because-it-can"&gt;reminder of of the levers&lt;/a&gt; these companies can pull in order to pad out their bottom line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n46tpA"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313251/verizon-admin-and-telco-recovery-charge-fee-increase"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313251/verizon-admin-and-telco-recovery-charge-fee-increase</id>
    <author>
      <name>Allison Johnson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T15:25:34-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T15:25:34-05:00</updated>
    <title>Peloton’s new audio-based app is like an invisible strength coach</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="A stock image featuring the Peloton logo." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/p9UCzeaLc1fQLIJ39-CXtuVSbOM=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73766856/acastro_STK119_Peleton_03.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;The Strength Plus app isn’t Peloton’s first attempt at capitalizing on strength training. | Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="pQdko9"&gt;Peloton &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1514734&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.onepeloton.com%2Fpress%2Farticles%2Fstrength-app-dedicated-to-strength-training-launches-out-of-beta&amp;amp;referrer=theverge.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theverge.com%2F2024%2F12%2F4%2F24313321%2Fpeloton-strength-plus-app-strength-training" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the launch of Strength Plus, a new standalone, audio-based strength training app. The app was introduced in a limited beta program earlier in September, but is now officially available.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b7D40D"&gt;The Strength Plus app allows users to generate custom workouts by choosing&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;workout length, equipment, experience level, and which muscle groups they want to focus on. It also includes multi-week&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;programs curated by Peloton’s strength coaches, though workouts can be done at a user’s own pace. Strength Plus includes audio cues and tips from instructors, as well as a library of instructional videos demonstrating exercises and equipment setup. It’s more like a strength training playlist than Peloton’s typical classes, which have you follow an instructor as they do the workout in real time.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It works with the Apple Watch and users can log weights and reps within the app. And, instead of being stuck with instructor-curated workout music, users can listen to their own music, audio books, or podcasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left c-float-hang"&gt;&lt;aside id="E2UbAg"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Peloton Guide review: a webcam that watches you squat ","url":"https://www.theverge.com/23009893/peloton-guide-review-fitness"},{"title":"Peloton’s&amp;amp;nbsp;bumpy ride","url":"https://www.theverge.com/c/24105625/peloton-bike-tread-plus-business-valuation-history"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="DMkqRh"&gt;This move isn’t surprising. Over the years, Peloton has repeatedly mentioned that strength training is its second most popular exercise type, though the company has had mixed success in capitalizing on it. In 2022, Peloton launched its own &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/23009893/peloton-guide-review-fitness"&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt; strength training hardware, but it hasn’t taken off like its treadmills or bikes. When it revamped the Peloton app, it also added &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/5/23/23734329/peloton-app-subscription-tiers-fitness"&gt;Peloton Gym workouts&lt;/a&gt; that catered to gym-goers with written workouts and video demos, though that wasn’t its own app, didn’t let you log reps, and didn’t include multi-week programming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Renders of Peloton Strength Plus app" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/iP8OODg0V4Wa6YwgNGbXGQhlhQ4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25773648/Strength__PR_Imagery_Screens.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Image: Peloton&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peloton really wants to make strength training work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="fZvPm9"&gt;On paper, Strength Plus looks similar to other apps, most notably &lt;a href="https://www.joinladder.com/"&gt;Ladder&lt;/a&gt;. (So much so, that Ladder has already clapped back with &lt;a href="https://www.joinladder.com/flattered"&gt;an entire Mac vs PC-style ad campaign&lt;/a&gt;.) The main difference is that Strength Plus leverages Peloton’s more widely known instructors. More broadly, this could be seen as an attempt to expand Peloton’s appeal outside the home — something the company &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/c/24105625/peloton-bike-tread-plus-business-valuation-history"&gt;has struggled to do&lt;/a&gt; after many people began returning to in-person gyms and classes once covid-19 lockdowns were lifted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7f1hOh"&gt;Existing Peloton All Access, Guide, and App Plus members can access the Strength Plus app for free. For everyone else, Peloton is offering a limited $1 monthly promotional subscription for the first six months, and then $9.99 monthly after. For now, the app will also be iOS only. &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt; asked Peloton whether it plans to expand further to Android, but didn’t immediately receive a response. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313321/peloton-strength-plus-app-strength-training"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313321/peloton-strength-plus-app-strength-training</id>
    <author>
      <name>Victoria Song</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2024-12-04T14:54:54-05:00</published>
    <updated>2024-12-04T14:54:54-05:00</updated>
    <title>Apple now lets you sync your passwords with Firefox, but not on Windows</title>
    <content type="html">  

    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img alt="The Firefox logo on a black background" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/INr9nQgetuCAxzgvGWbzvgRbzfU=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/73766786/acastro_200207_3900_firefox_0001.0.0.jpg" /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustration by Alex Castro / The Verge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p id="S7EoCn"&gt;If you keep your passwords stored on Apple’s iCloud, you can access those passwords on Firefox through an &lt;a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/icloud-passwords/"&gt;official iCloud Passwords extension&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2024/12/04/apple-icloud-passwords-firefox-add-on/"&gt;as spotted by &lt;em&gt;MacRumors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. However, the extension only supports macOS Sonoma or later, so you won’t be able to use it with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pn2Fj3"&gt;If you do need to access your iCloud passwords on Windows, you can access them by downloading iCloud for Windows and the iCloud Passwords extension for Chrome or Edge instead. We’ve asked Apple if it plans to add support for Windows to its Firefox extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Tq9qB"&gt;Another developer originally made the Firefox extension, but Apple has taken it over, according to &lt;a href="https://github.com/au2001/icloud-passwords-firefox?tab=readme-ov-file#update-2024-12-04"&gt;a notice on the extension’s GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;. Apple is “now the sole owners in charge of maintaining their own official iCloud Passwords extension,” the developer says. The extension’s repository and source code aren’t linked to it anymore except for “historical reasons.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kpuGUJ"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313300/apple-sync-passwords-firefox-not-windows"/>
    <id>https://www.theverge.com/2024/12/4/24313300/apple-sync-passwords-firefox-not-windows</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jay Peters</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
