<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-09-24T20:26:57Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Bill Carey</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing new benefits for Vox Members]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/press-room/373366/vox-membership-new-benefits-member-exclusive-stories" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373366</id>
			<updated>2024-09-24T20:01:07Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-24T20:01:07Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vox Press Room" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Vox launched our Membership program as a new way for you to directly support our journalism. Audience support is crucial to allowing our journalists to fulfill our mission of helping everyone understand our complicated world so that we can all help create a better one. During this unprecedented election season, the support [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Vox&lt;div class=&quot;duet--article--article-body-component&quot; style=&quot;box-sizing: border-box; border: 0px solid; backface-visibility: hidden;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: var(--_1eimjtq3); letter-spacing: var(--_1eimjtq4j); white-space-collapse: collapse;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/opt-1-2x.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Earlier this year, Vox <a href="https://www.vox.com/24160857/vox-membership-program">launched our Membership program</a> as a new way for you to directly support our journalism. Audience support is crucial to allowing our journalists to fulfill our mission of helping everyone understand our complicated world so that we can all help create a better one. During this unprecedented election season, the support of Vox Members has allowed us to break down policies, analyze rhetoric, and cut through the noise of misinformation so you can stay informed about the issues that really matter.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vox Members are part of a growing community and receive access to a number of benefits, including member-exclusive stories and newsletters, insider access to our newsroom, and a special monthly digital magazine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, we’re excited to tell you about several exciting updates to the membership program.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the coming weeks, we are launching <strong>three new monthly columns</strong> just for Vox Members.</p>

<ol>
<li>Senior correspondent<strong> Eric Levitz</strong>’s new column will focus on <strong>the ideas that animate the American political left</strong>, and the policy disputes, ideological disagreements, and strategic debates that could define the Democratic Party’s future. The first edition will publish next week.<br></li>



<li>Senior politics reporter <strong>Christian Paz </strong>will write each month on <strong>zoomers, boomers, and the changing politics of America</strong>. He’ll take a close look at the demographic shifts happening beneath our feet that are shaping the present — and explain how the tremors we’re feeling now could lead to the political earthquakes of the future. His first column will launch the week of October 7.&nbsp;<br></li>



<li>Each month, senior correspondents <strong>Rebecca Jennings and Alex Abad-Santos</strong> will bring you their group chat. It will provide a taste of <strong>the vital (and vitally frivolous) culture of the moment</strong> — the memes, TikToks, gossip, and internet ephemera that they can’t stop thinking about. Look out for the first edition <strong>this Friday</strong>.</li>
</ol>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to these columns, we’ll be publishing a number of other new stories each month just for members, <strong>including stories from our special election package being published this week</strong>. Plus, members will continue to have access to other exclusive newsletters, like Constance Grady’s monthly Ask a Book Critic and the Vox Explainer newsletter that takes you behind the scenes in our newsroom, as well as other opportunities to learn more about how we make our journalism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’ve also made it even easier for members to access their benefits by introducing member log-in to our site. If you’re already a member, thank you for your support — you’ll receive an email with instructions on <a href="https://voxmembership.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/33578921148947-How-Do-I-Create-My-Vox-com-Log-in">how to create your account</a> and access your new benefits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the months ahead, we plan to continue expanding the perks available to Vox Members as a reflection of their important role in making Vox’s vital journalism possible.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To support our work and read these exciting new columns,<strong> <a href="https://www.vox.com/support-now">become a member today</a>.&nbsp;</strong></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Has Harris pulled ahead of Trump? The state of the 2024 polls, explained.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373559/trump-harris-polls-electoral-college-pennsylvania-swing-states" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373559</id>
			<updated>2024-09-24T20:26:57Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-24T18:35:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that the dust has settled after the first and perhaps only presidential debate between Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump, the state of the polling looks clear: Harris has a slight edge in a race that remains extremely close. Harris leads national polls, on average, by 2 or 3 percentage points. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris, in a blue suit, and Walz, in a navy blazer and gray pants, both stand in front of a large banner reading “Pennsylvania for Harris Walz.”" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris speaks as her running mate Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz looks on during a stop on their campaign bus tour in Rochester, Pennsylvania, on August 18, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2166630983.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris speaks as her running mate Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz looks on during a stop on their campaign bus tour in Rochester, Pennsylvania, on August 18, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now that the dust has settled after the first and perhaps only <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/370958/harris-trump-debate-winners-losers">presidential debate</a> between Vice President Kamala Harris and former President Donald Trump, the state of the polling looks clear: Harris has a slight edge in a race that remains extremely close.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris leads national polls, on average, by 2 or 3 percentage points. More importantly, she leads in the key Electoral College states of Michigan, Wisconsin, and Pennsylvania by 1 to 2 points in recent polling averages. And if she wins all three, that would be just enough to give her the presidency (so long as she holds onto the other blue states, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/4/3/24119984/nebraska-electoral-college-vote-trump-biden-kirk">Nebraska’s Second District</a>).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s important to remember that a 1 or 2 point lead in polling averages is not a safe or reliable lead. A polling error underestimating Trump in these states — of the sort that occurred in <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/methods/2021/03/02/what-2020s-election-poll-errors-tell-us-about-the-accuracy-of-issue-polling/">2016 or 2020</a> — could send Harris to defeat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the other swing states: Nevada has had few high-quality polls since the debate, but the averages currently show a very close race, with Harris leading by a point or less. But Trump has a slight lead — 2 points or less — in the averages for North Carolina, Arizona, and Georgia.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The big picture, though, is that all seven of the swing states are close enough in polls that they could easily go to either candidate.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The New York Times/Siena polls have shown some unusual results</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the news for Harris in post-debate polling has generally been good, some results from the New York Times/Siena College polls tell a more complicated story.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This polling <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/19/upshot/harris-trump-poll-pennsylvania.html">found</a> Harris up by 4 points in Pennsylvania, the most important swing state, which is fantastic for her. But it also showed a tied race nationally — and larger than average <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/23/upshot/trump-harris-sun-belt-polls.html">Trump leads</a> in North Carolina (3 points), Georgia (4 points), and Arizona (5 points).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, the best practice for looking at campaign polling is to throw it all into an average, since any one pollster’s results could be an outlier. But the Times polls are highly respected in political circles, so it may be worth contemplating what it would mean for the race if their recent polls turned out to be accurate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One takeaway is that though those polls are generally worse for Harris, the Pennsylvania result is actually quite good — better than average. Overall, the Keystone State polling has not looked great for Harris since she entered the race, leading to <a href="https://www.natesilver.net/p/pennsylvania-may-be-a-problem-for">many</a> takes <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/how-does-the-harris-walz-campaign-solve-a-problem-like-pennsylvania-gov-josh-shapiro">about</a> her purported Pennsylvania “problem,” <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4869398-harris-shapiro-walz-trump-nate-silver/">second-guessing</a> about whether she should have picked the state’s governor, Josh Shapiro, as her running mate, and a belief that the Electoral College math gives Trump an advantage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Times polls, however, essentially point to a parallel world in which Electoral College bias doesn’t help Trump, and may even help Harris significantly. The Times has not polled Wisconsin or Michigan this month, but their polling of the states last month showed Harris up in those states — and in Pennsylvania — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/10/us/politics/harris-trump-battleground-polls.html">by 4</a> points.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Why would this be the case? Nate Cohn, the Times’ chief political analyst, has actually <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/11/upshot/electoral-college-trump-2024.html">written since last year</a> that Trump’s Electoral College edge might be fading. That could be because Republicans have gained ground in heavily blue states, like New York, but they’re still nowhere close to actually flipping those states — while Democrats have held on in the battleground states. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23451416/democrats-win-midterms-blue-red-new-york-elections">2022 midterm results</a> appear to be consistent with such a theory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Biden in 2020, the decisive Electoral College state was Wisconsin, but his margin was nearly 4 points worse there than his national margin, a serious gap. For Harris this time around, polling averages have tended to show a smaller disadvantage — but they have typically shown her performing a bit worse in the pivotal state, Pennsylvania, than she does nationally.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Times polling is unusual, though, in implying that the bias may go in the other direction this time around; that the Electoral College might actually <em>help</em> Harris. For now, this is an outlier result, but it’s certainly an interesting scenario.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A less encouraging takeaway for Harris if the Times polls are accurate is that Trump has the advantage in Georgia, Arizona, and North Carolina. Other pollsters have also typically shown Trump with a narrow edge in those states, but the Times polls may be ominous, showing him with a 3-5 point advantage in them all, just after Harris’s well-received debate performance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If those states prove out of reach for Harris, she’ll be stuck relying on Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, and Michigan as her only path to victory — the same “blue wall” Hillary Clinton hoped in vain would save her in 2016. Winning them, but not the other swing states, would put Harris at the narrowest possible 270 to 268 Electoral College victory. What could go wrong?</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why there are urgent calls to halt Marcellus Williams’s imminent execution]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/criminal-justice/373568/marcellus-williams-death-penalty-missouri" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373568</id>
			<updated>2024-09-24T18:19:22Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-24T18:20:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upcoming execution of a 55-year-old Missouri man — who maintains he is innocent — is the latest of several recent cases to renew scrutiny of the death penalty.  In 2001, Marcellus Williams was convicted of the 1998 killing of social worker and former St. Louis Post-Dispatch reporter Felicia “Lisha” Gayle, and sentenced to death. Since [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Joseph Amrine, who was exonerated two decades ago after spending years on death row, speaks at a rally to support Missouri death row inmate Marcellus Williams on August 21, 2024, in Clayton, Missouri. | Jim Salter/AP" data-portal-copyright="Jim Salter/AP" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/AP24267458872597.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Joseph Amrine, who was exonerated two decades ago after spending years on death row, speaks at a rally to support Missouri death row inmate Marcellus Williams on August 21, 2024, in Clayton, Missouri. | Jim Salter/AP</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The upcoming execution of a 55-year-old Missouri man — who maintains he is innocent — is the latest of several <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/25/24050932/alabama-nitrogen-gas-execution-death-penalty">recent cases</a> to renew scrutiny of the death penalty. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2001, Marcellus Williams was convicted of the 1998 killing of social worker and former St. Louis Post-Dispatch reporter Felicia “Lisha” Gayle, and sentenced to death. Since his sentencing, questions have been raised about how evidence in the case was handled and whether jury selection for his trial was fair. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given these concerns, and Williams’s continued claims that he did not kill Gayle, he and St. Louis prosecuting attorney Wesley Bell have called for the state to <a href="https://innocenceproject.org/court-denies-prosecutors-motion-to-vacate-marcellus-williams-conviction-and-death-sentence/" data-type="link" data-id="https://innocenceproject.org/court-denies-prosecutors-motion-to-vacate-marcellus-williams-conviction-and-death-sentence/">vacate his conviction</a>. While his execution was previously delayed twice before, the Missouri governor and state Supreme Court have declined to do so again this past week. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those decisions, and the outstanding uncertainty in Williams’s case, have put a new spotlight on capital punishment<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.aclu.org/documents/case-against-death-penalty">and many problems that have been cited with it</a>. Barring any action by the US Supreme Court, Williams is scheduled to be killed via lethal injection on Tuesday evening. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What are the new developments in Williams’s case?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Williams was convicted for Gayle’s murder based on the testimony of two witnesses, including his girlfriend at the time, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/missouri-execution-marcellus-williams-supreme-court-de47c99e00bb620db9db702f5f7e2ee8">who said she saw</a> the victim’s purse and laptop in his car. Williams was incarcerated at the time of his conviction in the Gayle case, and his then-cellmate Henry Cole also claimed that Williams had admitted to the killing. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Williams’s counsel argues that both witnesses had other motives for singling him out, including “reward money and a bargain for shorter sentences in their own criminal cases,” <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/09/24/marcellus-williams-execution-missouri-faq/">according to the Washington Post.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/09/23/missouri-execution-marcellus-williams-death-row/75194051007/">As USA Today notes</a>, there wasn’t forensic evidence linking Williams to the crime, and <a href="https://capitalbnews.org/missouri-marcellus-williams-death-row-dna-evidence/">his DNA was not found on the murder weapon</a> — a knife.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since his conviction, Williams’s counsel has called for greater investigation of the DNA that was on the knife, as well as a review of racial bias in the jury selection process. <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/missouri-set-to-execute-marcellus-williams-despite-pleas-from-victims-fam-and-prosecutors">Gayle’s family has also backed clemency</a> and the possibility of a life sentence without parole. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Previously, Williams’s counsel convinced former Missouri Gov. Eric Greitens that new testing of the DNA evidence, which included DNA from another man, had the potential to exonerate him. That led Greitens to grant a stay of execution in 2017 and to convene a panel to investigate this evidence. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Attorneys have since learned, though, that the knife had fingerprints and DNA from a prosecutor who had touched the murder weapon without wearing gloves, contaminating the evidence.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Williams’ allies have also argued he <a href="https://apnews.com/article/missouri-execution-marcellus-williams-supreme-court-de47c99e00bb620db9db702f5f7e2ee8">faced racial bias in his trial</a> after a former prosecutor said he removed a Black juror because of his resemblance to Williams.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Williams’ attorneys have called on the US Supreme Court to grant a stay of the execution due to this evidence of bias. But it’s not yet clear if the Court will. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Missouri Supreme Court had declined to do so, <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/lawyers-seek-supreme-court-intervention-hours-missouri-inmates-113961065#:~:text=%E2%80%9CDespite%20nearly%20a%20quarter%20century,Court%20Judge%20Zel%20Fischer%20wrote." data-type="link" data-id="https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/lawyers-seek-supreme-court-intervention-hours-missouri-inmates-113961065#:~:text=%E2%80%9CDespite%20nearly%20a%20quarter%20century,Court%20Judge%20Zel%20Fischer%20wrote.">with Judge Zel Fischer citing</a> “no credible evidence of actual innocence or any showing of a constitutional error undermining confidence in the original judgment.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What concerns does this raise about capital punishment?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The use of capital punishment has waned in recent years as concerns about how <a href="https://www.aclu.org/documents/death-penalty-questions-and-answers#:~:text=Q%3A%20Doesn%E2%80%99t%20the%20Death,than%20states%20without%20such%20laws.">well it works as a deterrent</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/1/25/24050932/alabama-nitrogen-gas-execution-death-penalty">how humane it is, and racial disparities in death sentences</a> have grown. <a href="https://www.nacdl.org/Content/Race-and-the-Death-Penalty">According to one 2016 study</a> in Washington State, Black defendants are four times more likely to be sentenced to death than non-Black defendants in similar circumstances.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although 27 states still allow the death penalty, 14 of those have not conducted any executions in the past 10 years, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/10/06/us/us-executions-death-penalty-dg/index.html">according to CNN</a>. Executions have also dwindled since 1999, which marked a recent high when nearly 100 people were killed. In 2023, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/10/06/us/us-executions-death-penalty-dg/index.html">24 people were executed across five states</a>; currently, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/09/23/missouri-execution-marcellus-williams-death-row/75194051007/">24 people are expected to be executed this year</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Among the concerns raised by executions is the fear that innocent people could face these sentences. Williams’s team is adamant that his case is an example of this issue. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Missouri is poised to execute an innocent man, an outcome that calls into question the legitimacy of the entire criminal justice system,” Tricia Bushnell, a Midwest Innocence Project attorney representing Williams, <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1bEqZFYntcV03ld6Lf_Rjf9v2q8tJzqLB/edit">said in a statement</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://deathpenaltyinfo.org/policy-issues/innocence">According to the Death Penalty Information Center,</a> at least 200 people who were wrongly convicted and sentenced to death have been exonerated since 1973. <a href="https://innocenceproject.org/innocence-and-the-death-penalty/">And per a 2014 study estimate</a>, roughly 4 percent of the people sentenced to death are innocent.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chappell Roan and the problem with fandom]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/373359/chappell-roan-speaks-out-against-toxic-fandom-stans-harassment" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373359</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T21:00:27Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-24T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having devoted fans can be a terrifying and fraught thing for a public figure to experience — and increasingly, the celebs are telling us about it. The latest round of toxic fandom discourse arguably started with Chappell Roan, who made headlines in August for speaking out against her own fans, elaborating in a pair of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Chappell Roan performing in London" data-caption="Chappell Roan performs during her “Midwest Princess Tour” at the Brixton Academy on September 21, 2024, in London, England. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Jim Dyson/Getty Images/&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Jim Dyson/Getty Images/&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2173676893.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Chappell Roan performs during her “Midwest Princess Tour” at the Brixton Academy on September 21, 2024, in London, England. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Jim Dyson/Getty Images/&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Having devoted fans can be a terrifying and fraught thing for a public figure to experience — and increasingly, the celebs are telling us about it. The latest round of toxic fandom discourse arguably started with Chappell Roan, who made headlines in August for <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/chappell-roan-blasts-invasive-fans-in-tiktok-rant">speaking out</a> against her own fans, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@chappellroan/video/7404955808980667690">elaborating</a> in a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@chappellroan/video/7404957266853645611">pair of TikToks</a> about fan harassment, stalking, inappropriate behavior, and bullying.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t care that abuse and harassment, stalking, whatever, is a normal thing to do to people who are famous or a little famous,” the “Good Luck Babe” singer said. “I don’t care that it’s normal; I don’t care that this crazy type of behavior comes along with the job, this career field that I’ve chosen. That does not make it okay. That does not make it normal. It doesn’t mean that I want it; it doesn’t mean that I like it.” She’s clearly not alone: The sheer number of celebrities who’ve either spoken out publicly or reached out privately in support of Roan after her TikTok rant is huge, <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/chappell-roan-lady-gaga-support-elton-john-mitski-1235099773/">a range of high-profile stars</a> from Katy Perry to Lady Gaga, from <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jewel/video/7409675347974720799?">Jewel</a> to Elton John.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What Roan is describing here is an increasing trend around the globe. Fandom has changed over the last decade to become more of a discourse, but while celebs have had to hear more and more of what fans have to say, now fans are getting a peek at what their actions mean to their favorite stars — and a lot of it is not so flattering. It’s unclear whether the celebrities’ pushback is making the situation better or if their protests will ever reach the most entitled fans and paparazzi — those for whom celebrities are less like people and more like collectible Pokémon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this suggests that Chappell Roan’s fans, and even her paparazzi, aren’t the problem: It’s the increasingly toxic nature of celebrity fandom itself.</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unfortunately, fans stalking and harassing celebrities is nothing new, and thanks to the rise of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23733213/fandom-purity-culture-what-is-proship-antiship-antifandom">anti-fandoms</a>, it’s possible to make hating a creator your full-time fannish hobby alongside legions of other haters, all without regard for how the person behind the persona might suffer as a result. What seems to be new, however, is that more and more frequently, the celebrities are defending themselves — openly calling out bad fan and paparazzi behavior in real time, and more publicly calling out the toxicity that leads to that behavior.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The onus is typically on celebrities to maintain their calm in the face of outlandish behavior from fans and paparazzi, no matter how out of hand things get. In August, when Justin Bieber lost his cool and rebuked a group of teens who’d been harassing him at a hotel, asking them, “Is this funny to you guys?” TMZ <a href="https://www.tmz.com/2024/08/09/justin-bieber-yell-teens-hotel/">framed the scene</a> as “Bieber freaks out on a bunch of young kids.” The tabloid <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-13729485/Justin-Bieber-yells-teenagers-viral-video.html">slant</a> was that Bieber was temperamental, even though the group of teens <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tuscanciones150/video/7401849318472240417">appeared to swarm him</a>, phones out, and even though Bieber never raised his voice. The singer <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@nojumper/video/6978301532500446469">previously</a> had to tell a group of fans, again very calmly, not to stalk him at his home — this after <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/lifestyle/every-time-justin-bieber-had-151000160.html">years</a> of scary stalking incidents, including fans breaking into his hotel rooms and getting arrested outside of his house.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes the celebrity’s reaction in the face of fan harassment seems to be similar to that of an abuse victim. <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/12/28/18156266/2018-tv-good-place-crazy-ex-girlfriend-queer-eye"><em>Queer Eye</em></a>’s Jonathan Van Ness <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/morgansloss1/jonathan-van-ness-27-questions-interview">told BuzzFeed</a> in 2022 that when a fan literally ran up behind him in order to tackle-hug him, his response was to apologize <em>to her</em>: “I&#8217;m sorry I tried to attack you. We’re friends, right? Do you wanna take a selfie?&#8221; With that level of ingrained passive conditioning to overcome, it’s no wonder many celebrities applauded Roan for speaking out.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might think a few extreme fans are causing most of the issues. The real problem, though, is messier. Modern fan culture has shifted away from worshiping aloof, unavailable Hollywood divas from afar and toward complex&nbsp; entanglements between fans and the people they stan.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This shift arguably began in the late aughts within <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/21258262/k-pop-essential-playlist-guide-for-beginners">K-pop fandom</a>, which is its own complicated ouroboros of pop stardom and standom, and within grassroots fandoms on YouTube and later Twitch. In those online spaces, amateur gamers and streamers who hit it big often had zero media training and zero preparation for how to deal with their new fame and the devotees that came with it. They typically interacted with their fans as though they were their friends — sometimes with <a href="https://ida.mtholyoke.edu/server/api/core/bitstreams/39def074-5d5a-4c4c-9b20-c09d6477a910/content">extremely complicated</a> and even <a href="https://www.courierpostonline.com/story/news/local/south-jersey/2016/12/18/forgotten-story-christina-grimmie-and-man-who-killed-her/95585040/">deeply tragic</a> results.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then came the advent of social media, which made celebrities even more accessible and gave fans with extreme tendencies even more ways to connect and mobilize en masse. These days, it’s no longer just about the mythical stalker fan, lurking in the dark, with clear, if poorly understood, intentions to do harm. Fans stalk celebrities openly, proactively, and proudly, often fully rejecting the idea that what they’re doing is wrong or causing their fave serious discomfort. In recent years, celebrities including <a href="https://www.ladbible.com/entertainment/celebrity/john-cena-filmed-fan-jake-paul-podcast-294876-20240125">John Cena</a> and <a href="https://www.nme.com/news/music/mitski-asks-fans-to-stop-filming-entire-songs-or-whole-sets-at-her-shows-3169422">Mitski</a> have asked fans to stop filming them, with Mitski claiming the experience of having to perform for a sea of phones makes them feel as though they’re being “consumed as content.” The fans <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/indieheads/comments/t16126/mitski_asks_fans_to_stop_filming_entire_songs_or/">may or may not comply</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In many cases, even the idea that an actor could be someone else outside of their professional persona<strong> </strong>is a cause of tension among fans, one that celebrities have to grapple with and learn how to reconcile. It’s by no means only “extreme” fans who fall prey to this level of entitled thinking. Think how many normal people on the internet were emotionally invested in <a href="https://www.vox.com/22663143/john-mulaney-olivia-munn-pregnant-parasocial-relationships-kylie-jenner">John Mulaney’s divorce</a> or the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23387679/cheating-scandals-adam-levine-nia-long-try-guys-ned-fulmer">Try Guys scandal</a>, or <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/351720/ben-affleck-jennifer-lopez-bennifer-timeline-divorce-rumors">the roller coaster that was (is? was?) Bennifer</a>. These media narratives play out the way they do precisely because so many normal people feel an intense amount of ownership over the lives of these people we’ve never met,and a <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-commentary/timothee-chalamet-kylie-jenner-club-chalamet-stan-culture-controversy-1234820673/">deep resistance</a> to anything that contradicts the narrative or the persona we’ve bought into. (<a href="https://www.vox.com/21337354/folklore-taylor-swift-kaylor-betty-gay-lesbian-subtext">Gaylors</a>, none of us are free from sin!)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be fair to the fans, they don’t always reach this stage on their own; they often experience tacit, perhaps unwitting, encouragement from the celebrities, or at least their PR teams. Sometimes celebrities will subtly lean into the ever-blurring lines of their parasocial relationships with their fanbases, usually in furtherance of marketing and promotion. Witness Jin, the oldest member of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/6/13/17426350/bts-history-members-explained">Korean mega-band BTS</a>, bizarrely having to give <a href="https://www.wvtm13.com/article/k-pop-star-hugs-fans-after-completing-mandatory-military-service/61092464">1,000 hugs to 1,000 fans</a> upon his exit from his mandatory military service earlier this year. Or see, for instance, the entire Swiftie <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23149181/taylor-swift-dance-party">ecosystem</a>, which arguably <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2017/11/9/16598106/taylor-swift-reputation-intimacy-control">depends upon</a> Taylor Swift being as obsessed with her fans, or at least with their opinions, as <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2023/4/10/23677713/taylor-swift-joe-alwyn-breakup-why">they are with her</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet this lean-in comes with blowback for the celebrity as well as the fan because they have to live not only with the socially constructed persona they helped create, but with the attitudes of the fans who’ve decided they adore that persona. Once that genie is out, there’s no putting it back in the bottle. “I just wanted to humbly welcome you to the shittiest exclusive club in the world,” an email from Mitski to Roan <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/chappell-roan-lady-gaga-support-elton-john-mitski-1235099773/">reportedly read</a>, “the club where strangers think you belong to them.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What Mitski is describing here is essentially the academic concept of the celebrity as a “<a href="https://litlab.stanford.edu/star-texts/">star text</a>” — when a celebrity persona occupies a socially constructed role that evolves independently from them, based on how they behave, how the public interprets that behavior, and the cultural narrative that might attach to that behavior. As I’ve <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/7/10/21315905/vox-book-club-rodham-week-1-political-fanfiction-rpf">previously argued</a>, every celebrity exists both as themselves and as the symbol, or the “star text,” that they represent, and very rarely is that text within any celebrity’s ability to control or corral.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The result of this sticky interdependence is an increase in fans feeling entitled to pieces of their celebrities’ lives, and sometimes physically entitled to the celebrities themselves, whether it be through stalking, harassment, refusal to stop filming them, or getting handsy and wildly inappropriate. It’s no secret, and certainly nothing new, that in many intense celebrity fandoms, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-68572668">fans seek to control and direct</a> their favorite stars’ private lives, even to the extent of shaming them and performing backlash against them when they try to have lives of their own outside of their public personas.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To some extent, we all form opinions and even judgments about high-profile people, and those people — at least the ones who’ve been properly media trained — know we do this and prepare for it. The evolving dynamics of fandom are constantly eroding current fandom etiquette and normative behavior, arguably faster than the celebs’ ability to adapt and adjust. What to do, for example, when fans <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/people-culture/china-personalities/article/3251212/crazed-china-fans-warned-famous-china-actor-stop-booking-flights-him-amid-rising-trend-devotees">change your flight information</a> or attempt to book a seat next to you on a plane? What to do when fans form <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23150487/zhang-zhehan-deepfake-fandom-conspiracy-theory">increasingly bizarre</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/4/18/11384118/larry-stylinson-one-direction-conspiracy-theory">conspiracy theories</a> that distort their sense of what’s real, all so they can maintain their collective narratives in the face of opposing information?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These mentalities don’t form in a vacuum, but rather within environments where fans cease to see idols as real people and begin to see them as commodities or as narratives in which they have invested — narratives that must be maintained at all cost. The economy of celebrity-stalking rewards fans and paparazzi for <a href="https://www.livemint.com/news/trends/mumbai-beggars-tip-paparazzi-on-celebrity-locations-reveals-varinder-chawla-during-ask-me-anything-on-reddit-11718967312667.html">being as invasive as possible</a>. They can also be <a href="https://exiledfan.substack.com/p/the-rise-of-the-stalker-fan">terrifyingly organized</a> in their methods, relying on one another for resources, intel, and access. For the celebrity, this kind of constant fan scrutiny and entitlement can prove too much to handle — at least not without an <a href="https://www.asiaone.com/entertainment/any-morals-chinese-idol-wang-junkai-rages-paparazzi-causing-chaos-airport-xiao-zhan">occasional outburst</a> or show of resistance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s tempting to wonder what, if anything, can be done to curb this kind of intense and pervasive level of fandom — especially when it seems to be creeping into all aspects of society, from <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24043045/politics-fandom-trump-fans-toxic-stan-culture-conspiracies">politics</a> to <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23733213/fandom-purity-culture-what-is-proship-antiship-antifandom">personal aesthetics</a>. For now, Roan may have found the answer, and it seems to be very similar to the recent tactics used by the left to emphasize how far outside the norm are the extreme political views of their opponents: <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365833/trump-harris-walz-weird-2024-election-voters-biden-poll-attack-messaging">Call them really weird</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t give a fuck if you think it’s selfish of me to say no for a photo or for your time or for a hug,” Roan <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@chappellroan/video/7404955808980667690">said</a> in her first TikTok post. “That’s not normal. That’s weird. It’s weird how people think that you know a person just because you see them online and you listen to the art they make. That’s fucking weird! I’m allowed to say no to creepy behavior, okay?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the public and celebrity support for Roan is any indication, there may be more to come where that came from, and celebrities finally saying “no” to their fans can arguably only be a net gain for everyone.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Hady Mawajdeh</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Noel King</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Can Georgia’s MAGA election board actually rig the vote for Trump?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/373334/georgia-election-board-rule-changes-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373334</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T21:12:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-24T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the next seven weeks until Election Day, the Today, Explained podcast will examine the major themes of the 2024 election by looking at each of the seven swing states. We’ll hear from voters in Georgia, Pennsylvania, Arizona, Nevada, Wisconsin, Michigan, and North Carolina, and dive deep into topics like abortion, the concerns of rural [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A “Wait Here To Vote” sign is seen in the foreground as voters, out of focus in the background, stand at a table." data-caption="A polling location in Atlanta, Georgia, on May 21, 2024. | Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2153450834.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A polling location in Atlanta, Georgia, on May 21, 2024. | Elijah Nouvelage/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the next seven weeks until Election Day, the <em>Today, Explained</em> podcast will examine the major themes of the 2024 election by looking at each of the seven swing states. We’ll hear from voters in Georgia, Pennsylvania, Arizona, Nevada, Wisconsin, Michigan, and North Carolina, and dive deep into topics like abortion, the concerns of rural voters, and economic stressors for retirees and Latino voters. We’re kicking it off with Georgia, where “election security” efforts are once again at the forefront for officials and voters alike. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For months, Georgia’s highest-ranking Republican leaders have been speaking out against an obscure, unelected board that has passed a series of controversial rule changes that could make it harder to know who won the state in the likely event of a close race, and facilitate attempts to dispute the election results.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to <a href="https://www.wabe.org/lawsuit-challenges-georgias-new-election-certification-rules/">WABE reporter Sam Gringlas</a>, one rule allows local election board members to prevent votes from being counted at precincts if board members identify discrepancies, pending an investigation. And if the board members believe the error cannot be corrected, the board “shall determine a method to compute the votes justly.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Georgia Secretary of State <a href="https://x.com/GaSecofState">Brad Raffensperger</a> has said <a href="https://www.wabe.org/georgia-election-board-approves-another-rule-that-could-disrupt-certification/">rule changes to the certification process</a> that have been advanced by the board are <a href="https://sos.ga.gov/news/raffensperger-defends-georgias-election-integrity-act-last-minute-changes-delaying-election">“misguided” and “will delay election results.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What they’re talking about is breaking open the ballot boxes,” Raffensperger <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/17/nx-s1-5103833/when-will-we-know-who-won-georgia-raffensperger-says-it-depends-on-how-close-it-is">told NPR’s Mary Louise Kelly</a> last week in an interview about new rules that allow local election board members to review massive amounts of documents before certifying election results. “Instead of [counting votes] in a secure warehouse and under the observation of the county election director … it would be happening at the precinct level.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Former President Donald Trump, who in 2020 <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/trump-raffensperger-call-georgia-vote/2021/01/03/d45acb92-4dc4-11eb-bda4-615aaefd0555_story.html">attempted to pressure</a> Georgia officials to flip the state in his favor after losing the state’s electoral college points to President Joe Biden, has celebrated the board’s changes. “They’re doing a great job,” <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/republican-backed-georgia-rules-risk-undermining-election-certification-critics-say/">Trump said</a> in August. “Three members are all pit bulls fighting for honesty, transparency, and victory.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Friday, the board voted on and passed <a href="https://www.wabe.org/georgias-republican-led-election-board-oks-controversial-rule-to-hand-count-ballots-2/">several more rule changes</a>. The <a href="https://www.11alive.com/article/news/politics/elections/georgia-state-election-board-meeting-live-stream-friday-september-20/85-75c5b5d4-c490-45a8-9ad9-6a7bb70e5a96">changes</a> require polling places to hand-count paper ballots, significantly slowing the reporting process; provide more access for poll watchers; post daily updates on the number of people in each county to cast a ballot; and post ballot reconciliation reports to a county website.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The latest round of changes is already facing scrutiny; <a href="https://x.com/chriscarr_ga?lang=en">Georgia Attorney General Chris Carr</a>, a Republican, wrote a <a href="https://www.11alive.com/article/news/politics/georgia-state-election-board-rules-georgia-ag-chris-carr-opinion-letter/85-fec8c5a5-ae76-49d4-ab09-40a5e4f40b8c">letter to the State Election Board</a> ahead of their meeting warning them that the proposed rules “are not tethered to any statute — and are, therefore, likely the precise type of impermissible legislation that agencies cannot do.”</p>

<iframe frameBorder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8499292549" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To better understand whether moves from election boards like Georgia’s will impact the upcoming election, <em>Today, Explained </em>co-host Noel King spoke with <a href="https://electioninnovation.org/team/david-becker/">David J. Becker</a>. He’s the founder of the Center for Election Innovation &amp; Research and has served as lead counsel on major voting rights litigation, including the Supreme Court case <a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/2002/02-182"><em>Georgia v. Ashcroft</em></a>, which dealt with redistricting in Georgia.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A partial transcript of their conversation, edited for length and clarity, follows. Listen to the full conversation on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3pXx5SXzXwJxnf4A5pWN2A">Spotify</a>, or wherever you find podcasts.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">David, we heard about these rule changes that the Georgia State Election Board has been trying to pass. They could, we understand, make disputing the election results easier. How much of a threat is that to the state’s election integrity?  </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">David J. Becker</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Georgia’s Election Board has some oversight responsibility for directing counties and the county boards on running elections, but they have no authority on actually certifying the vote. And it’s important that we understand what certification of the vote is in every single state. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Certification is just the non-discretionary ministerial act of giving an election legal effect. That’s not to say that there aren’t opportunities to bring legitimate legal challenges if candidates or campaigns think that there has been a problem. But there’s another path for that. And that path is through the courts where they have to bring evidence and they have to subject that evidence to scrutiny and cross-examination. And a court has to hear it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not the place for political appointees like the Georgia State Election Board to decide they don’t like the election. So the reality is that the State Election Board’s efforts are not going to change the fact that whoever wins Georgia’s electoral votes will get those electoral votes. However, it could be used to fuel disinformation and lies spread by a losing candidate that an election was stolen.  </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What about after the votes are cast? What kind of protections are in place to make sure all of those votes are counted?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">David J. Becker</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Georgia has all paper ballots. They have audits of those paper ballots to ensure that the machines counted them accurately. And Georgia has early certification dates. Counties are required to certify their votes — again, just reporting up to the state, “These are the votes. We legally say these are the votes.” And letting the state then certify. So if there are any counties or any county board members who decide that they have the power to overturn the will of the people of Georgia and want to delay that effort, the state will be able to act quickly on November 12 to compel them to certify. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There have been other attempts to do this in states like New Mexico, Arizona, Nevada, and Michigan. And they’ve been dealt with swiftly and decisively on a bipartisan basis. Georgia is prepared to do the same. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This will be resolved well in advance of the key deadline here, which in the presidential race is December 11. December 11 is the date that the new <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/21/23520649/electoral-count-reform-act-omnibus-trump">Electoral Count Reform Act</a>, passed by Congress in 2022, requires that electors be what’s called “ascertained,” which means that the governor has to sign a document saying the electors go to whoever won a given state. And I am 100 percent confident that Georgia, and in fact all of the states, will be able to work past efforts to destabilize an election and ensure that their voters in their states, including those who voted for the losing candidate, aren&#8217;t disenfranchised in the race for president and their electors are counted. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What should voters be watching out for on Election Day and the day after Election Day this year? Not just in Georgia, but around the country?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">David J. Becker</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, it shouldn&#8217;t be a surprise to us if any given candidate wins. Given how closely divided we are and especially how passions are running high, we&#8217;re going to see very high turnout. And that means we should expect on Election Day and night that election officials are going to be working incredibly hard to answer the one question on all of our minds, which is who won?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But we also should recognize that they are counting very complex ballots in every jurisdiction in this country. There are dozens of races on those ballots, not just the presidential race, not just Senate races in some states, not just congressional races, but state races, local races. County races. Ballot measures. There are places where there are as many as six pages on the ballot with dozens of races. And so we should expect that we&#8217;re not going to know who won the election on election night because it takes some time, especially when margins are very narrow, to count all the ballots.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one factor that election officials have no impact over — the margin of victory. And if the margin of victory is extremely narrow, it might take several days to get to the point where the media can call it. And that media call is unofficial. But it&#8217;s what we often think of as the decisive call. So we should be patient.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think we should also expect that there&#8217;s a very strong likelihood that a losing candidate might declare victory on election night and spread lies about the process. And we should ignore that. If you hear a candidate on election night claim victory before victory has been determined, you should know that that candidate thinks they lost because a candidate who thinks they won has every incentive to support the legitimacy of the process.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">David, although you sound very calm because there are protections in place to make sure the election is certified, the votes are counted, it sounds like you also do have some concerns that even though everything should go right, it could go wrong.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">David J. Becker</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What I&#8217;m concerned about is that we may have to prepare for an all-out assault on reality, on the reality that a candidate might lose. I mean, we saw that happen in 2020. Donald Trump lost the election. It wasn&#8217;t particularly close. And nevertheless, there are tens of millions of people who have believed the lies and that delusion has persisted for four years. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We should make no mistake that those who believe the lies, those who supported the former president are the target for this long-term grift. I have a deep amount of sympathy for people who voted for a candidate who lost and are sincerely disappointed. That&#8217;s who most of these people are.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unfortunately, the former president and many surrounding him have targeted them for a long-term grift, raising money off of their disappointment and lying to them about the outcome of an election that he lost. So I think we have to prepare for the very likely possibility that if former President Trump loses — and by the way, he could win legitimately. And if he does, I will be the first one to say so, as I did in 2016. But if he loses, I think we should expect that we will hear a significant amount of disinformation and lies about that election intended to keep his supporters angry and perhaps violent, and definitely donating.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Israeli attacks in Lebanon could lead to the wider war we’ve been fearing]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/israel/373428/lebanon-hezbollah-israel-hamas-gaza" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=373428</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T22:10:05Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-23T22:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 450 people were killed and 1,500 injured in Israeli airstrikes targeting southern and eastern Lebanon, as well as the country’s capital, Beirut, on Monday. The airstrikes mark a significant and threatening escalation of hostilities following an apparent Israeli attack that used explosive pagers (and other electronic devices) to kill members of the Shia [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A partially destroyed apartment building. In front is construction machinery and workers." data-caption="Officers use heavy construction equipment to remove debris from heavily damaged settlements following the Israeli army’s air strike on the Dahieh district of southern Beirut, Lebanon on September 21, 2024. | Housam Shbaro/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Housam Shbaro/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2172568505.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Officers use heavy construction equipment to remove debris from heavily damaged settlements following the Israeli army’s air strike on the Dahieh district of southern Beirut, Lebanon on September 21, 2024. | Housam Shbaro/Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">More than <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-military-says-it-is-striking-hezbollah-targets-lebanon-2024-09-23/">450 people were killed and 1,500 injured</a> in Israeli airstrikes targeting southern and eastern Lebanon, as well as the country’s capital, Beirut, on Monday. The airstrikes mark a significant and threatening escalation of hostilities following an <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/372399/pager-explosions-lebanon-syria-hezbollah-israel-gaza">apparent Israeli attack</a> that used explosive pagers (and other electronic devices) to kill members of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/10/28/23935157/hezbollah-lebanon-israel-hamas-palestine-gaza-iran-militia-group">Shia militant and political group Hezbollah</a>, which is based in Lebanon.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel and Hezbollah have regularly traded rocket fire over Lebanon’s southern border with Israel for years. However, since Israel launched its war in Gaza in retaliation for Hamas’s attacks in Israel on October 7, Hezbollah — a Hamas ally — has increased the tempo of rocket launches, and has hit targets deeper within Israel. Israel <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/menasource/gaza-hezbollah-israel-war-ghaziyeh-escalation/">has increased its attacks as well</a>, and as a result, more than <a href="https://dtm.iom.int/reports/lebanon-mobility-snapshot-round-47-19-09-2024">110,000 Lebanese</a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-evacuees-gaza-war-1841834d89af938a8445821567640aea">about 60,000 Israelis</a> are internally displaced.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, Israeli defense minister Yoav Gallant announced that Israel was entering a “new phase” of its ongoing war on Gaza and Hamas, one that would put greater focus on its conflict with Hezbollah. “The center of gravity is moving north. We are diverting forces, resources, and energy toward the north,” Gallant told members of Israel’s air force on September 18, referring to Israel’s northern border with Lebanon. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Concerns that the conflict in Gaza would <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364148/haniyeh-iran-israel-hamas-hezbollah">spark a full war</a> between Israel, Hezbollah, and their allies have existed for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/10/28/23935157/hezbollah-lebanon-israel-hamas-palestine-gaza-iran-militia-group">entirety of the nearly year-long conflict</a>. But the latest rounds of Israeli attacks are a provocative escalation that could threaten the fragile balance of more measured tit-for-tat missile strikes that had become fairly routine for Israel and Hezbollah.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the unknowns are many: whether Hezbollah can or will respond in an escalatory fashion; whether Israel is prepared to launch a ground invasion into Lebanon, as it has done before to disastrous effect; and whether the US will —&nbsp;or can —&nbsp;constrain Israel and force them to pull back.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Israel and Hezbollah’s conflict, briefly explained</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hezbollah has been in conflict with Israel <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/9/18/hezbollah-and-israel-a-timeline-of-conflict">for decades</a>. The group is both a militia and a political party that holds seats in Lebanon’s parliament and provides services for the country’s impoverished Shia community. Formed in the wake of Israel’s disastrous 1982 invasion of Lebanon, Hezbollah has fought against Israel multiple times, most recently in 2000 and 2006. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The latter war was particularly devastating, <a href="https://casebook.icrc.org/case-study/israellebanonhezbollah-conflict-2006#:~:text=Over%20789%20cluster%2Dbomb%20sites,casualties%20and%20deaths%20were%20children.">killing more than 1,000 people</a>, and leading to an estimated <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-lebanon-war-cost/factbox-costs-of-war-and-recovery-in-lebanon-and-israel-idUSL0822571220070709/">$2.8 billion in damage</a> across Lebanon. The country has never quite recovered from that war; a <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/5/15/23073845/lebanon-elections-political-corruption-economic-crisis-voter-apathy-beirut-port-hezbollah">government collapse</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9947038/">Covid-19</a>, and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/9/21/21445831/beirut-explosion-lebanon">Beirut port explosion of 2020</a> have pushed the country even further into crisis. The country can ill afford a full-scale war, and those in Lebanon not aligned with Hezbollah would <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/10/28/23935157/hezbollah-lebanon-israel-hamas-palestine-gaza-iran-militia-group">like to avoid a conflict like the one in 2006</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether that is possible remains to be seen. Israel has staged a number of attacks on Hezbollah, including the reported assassination of senior Hezbollah leader Fuad Shukr <a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/how-israel-killed-a-ghost-73e6db68?mod=hp_lead_pos7">in July</a>. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/372399/pager-explosions-lebanon-syria-hezbollah-israel-gaza">coordinated attack</a> that used pagers and walkie-talkies to decimate Hezbollah’s communications system believed to have been conducted by Israel injured more than 3,000 and killed at least 32, including children and the elderly, according to Lebanon’s <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/p0jr5y23">health minister Dr. Firass Abiad.</a> (Israel does not claim responsibility for assassinations or attacks like last week’s; Hezbollah has blamed Israel for the attack.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel began bombing targets in southern Lebanon Friday, including the suburbs and interior of Beirut, and a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/09/20/world/gaza-israel-hamas-hezbollah">Hezbollah commander</a> who had been part of the organization since the beginning was killed as he met with other Hezbollah fighters. Monday, September 23, has <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-news-lebanon-hezbollah-e3ca9c83642056f962fdf76319e3b8de">r</a>eportedly been <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-palestinians-hamas-war-news-lebanon-hezbollah-e3ca9c83642056f962fdf76319e3b8de">the deadliest Israeli attack on Lebanon</a> since the 2006 war.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s the distinct possibility that these continued attacks will spiral out of control; Israel has already shown willingness to cross the Biden administration’s “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/may/07/biden-israel-palestine-policy">red line</a>” in their war in Gaza by <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2024/5/6/24150729/israel-rafah-hamas-ceasefire-gaza-cairo-khan-younis-idf-gallant-netanyahu">invading the city of Rafah in Gaza</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hezbollah, meanwhile, must walk a fine line if it chooses to retaliate — which is not a given, despite leader <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/19/world/middleeast/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-strikes.html">Hassan Nasrallah’s promise</a> that Israel would “face just retribution and a bitter reckoning.” Hezbollah has reportedly fired 8,000 rockets into Israeli territory <a href="https://www.cnn.com/world/live-news/israel-lebanon-attacks-09-22-24#h_8d4276e578d16d8eb0f76fc030e52138">since October 7</a>, some <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-lebanon-hezbollah-news-09-22-2024-fb1aa8ae061885ba86855f7fe9ec5be7">targeting</a> the Israeli weapons manufacturer Rafael and the Ramat David air base, both near the city of Haifa. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hezbollah has emphasized its solidarity with Hamas since the start of the war in Gaza, and has <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-military-says-it-is-striking-hezbollah-targets-lebanon-2024-09-23/">promised to continue</a> attacks on Israel until there is a ceasefire. Both Hezbollah and Hamas benefit from Iranian financial and tactical assistance, but Hezbollah is much more closely aligned with Iran’s foreign policy objectives than Hamas is. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has led to concerns about Iran becoming <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2024/4/2/24119425/israel-attack-syria-damascus-strike-iran-officials-reza-zahedi-gaza-war-united-states">involved in a regional war</a> should Israel’s conflict with Hezbollah escalate. Even if Iran doesn’t enter the conflict, a Hezbollah-Israel war could be incredibly bloody: Hezbollah is larger and better armed than Hamas; if Israel does launch a ground invasion into southern Lebanon, there’s a large chance that they will face even fiercer resistance than in Gaza. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there are reasons to believe Hezbollah may choose to de-escalate the conflict, including the fact that any war would almost certainly be horrifically destructive to Lebanon, a country already struggling with a dysfunctional government and an economic crash.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Hezbollah has several concerns,” when it comes to deciding its next steps, Jon Alterman, director of the Middle East program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies, told Vox. “One is maintaining Iranian support, and [staying] aligned with Iran&#8217;s assessments and regional strategy. And the other is, 85 percent of Lebanese are now below the poverty line. The country&#8217;s been reeling economically, and if Hezbollah seems to invite a devastating Israeli assault on Lebanon, then some number of Lebanese would consider that reckless and damaging.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A diplomatic solution, perhaps one in which Hezbollah agrees to remove its positions close to Lebanon’s southern border, is certainly possible. That would allow Israelis to move back to their homes in the north. Whatever the outcome, however, Israel will likely not be able to eliminate Hezbollah, just as it has failed at eliminating Hamas. And continued aggression could lead to more extreme outcomes in the future. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump’s latest push to steal a Nebraska electoral vote appears to have flopped]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/4/3/24119984/nebraska-electoral-college-vote-trump-biden-kirk" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/4/3/24119984/nebraska-electoral-college-vote-trump-biden-kirk</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T20:47:35Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-23T20:47:33Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Donald Trump wanted Nebraska Republicans to change the state’s electoral vote rules — in a way that would likely flip one electoral vote from Kamala Harris to him. But he may not have the votes to get it done — a key state senator confirmed Monday that he was still opposed to the rules change. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Former President Donald Trump arrives for a rally at the I-80 Speedway in 2022 in Greenwood, Nebraska. | Scott Olson/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Scott Olson/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25369888/GettyImages_1394862861.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Former President Donald Trump arrives for a rally at the I-80 Speedway in 2022 in Greenwood, Nebraska. | Scott Olson/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Donald Trump wanted Nebraska Republicans to change the state’s electoral vote rules — in a way that would likely flip one electoral vote from Kamala Harris to him.</p>

<p>But he may not have the votes to get it done — a key state senator <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/2024/09/23/state-sen-mike-mcdonnell-deflates-gop-hopes-for-nebraska-winner-take-all-in-2024/">confirmed Monday</a> that he was still opposed to the rules change.</p>

<p>Nebraska currently has an unusual way of distributing its five electoral votes. Rather than giving them all to the statewide winner — as 48 other states do — it awards two votes to the statewide winner, and the rest go to the winner in each of Nebraska’s three congressional districts.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Nebraska is a deep red state that Trump won by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/11/03/us/elections/results-nebraska.html">a 19-point margin</a> in 2020. However, Joe Biden walked away with one of its electoral votes, because he won in Nebraska’s Second District, which includes the city of Omaha. <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4571799-trump-nebraska-governor-winner-take-all-electoral-system/">Trump</a> wants to switch this to a winner-take-all system, to lock down that vote.</p>

<p>The stakes are enormous: the single electoral vote from Nebraska’s Second District really could determine whether Trump or Harris wins in 2024.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Harris wins Pennsylvania, Wisconsin, and Michigan, while Trump wins Nevada, Georgia, Arizona, and North Carolina, and no other outcomes change from 2020, then Harris would need Nebraska’s Second District vote to win. If she doesn’t get it, the electoral vote would be a 269-269 tie. The new House of Representatives would break the tie with each state delegation getting one vote, and since Republicans will almost surely control more state delegations, that means a tie likely goes to Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An earlier Trump push to change Nebraska’s rules <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/04/03/nebraska-electoral-votes-trump-push/">failed to get the votes</a> back in April. And if it had succeeded, Democrats had an obvious option for a response: changing the rules in Maine. Maine is the only other state that splits its vote by congressional district, but there, the current rule benefits Trump — it delivered him one elector in a state Biden won. Democrats could, in theory, have changed Maine’s rules and cancel out any advantage gained by Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Trump’s allies suddenly revived the Nebraska rules change effort last week, and that timing may not have been a coincidence: It is now too late for Maine to change its rules, since bills take 90 days after they are passed to become law in the state. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats cried foul across the country, characterizing this as a dirty trick — an attempt to steal the 2024 election. But on Monday, state Sen. Mike McDonnell — who switched from the Democratic to the Republican party earlier this year — <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/2024/09/23/state-sen-mike-mcdonnell-deflates-gop-hopes-for-nebraska-winner-take-all-in-2024/">said</a> he was still opposed to the change. And if he holds firm, Republicans won’t have the votes.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why oddball Nebraska and Maine split their votes by congressional district</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond the angling for partisan advantage, it is true that Nebraska’s and Maine’s rules are kind of odd — quirky historical accidents that arguably should be brought in line with the way the other 48 states do it. The fair way to do it would be for both to change their rules in the same cycle, standardizing the winner-take-all rule without handing either candidate an advantage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The history of the Electoral College system <a href="https://www.vox.com/21539173/electoral-college-explained-2020-trump-biden">is a bizarre one</a>, but the modern norm of how it works is: each state holds a statewide vote, and the top candidate in that vote would get all of that state’s electors. That’s the winner-take-all system.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the nation’s earliest decades, there was more variety. Some states didn’t give voters a direct say at all, letting state legislators simply pick electors. Others did hold a statewide vote, but counted the results in separate districts of the state, awarding electors that way.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The district system could allow regional differences to be represented. But it watered down a state’s impact on the national outcome, as compared to the winner-take-all system where all a state’s votes went to one candidate. And as partisan competition intensified, states flocked to winner-take-all — the district system was gone <a href="https://www.thegreenpapers.com/Hx/ElectoralCollege.html">by the 1830s</a>, and stayed gone for more than a century.</p>

<p>Then, in the latter half of the 20th century, it came back. Two states decided to switch to a system where two electoral votes would go to the statewide winner, and one electoral vote to the winner in each congressional district.</p>

<p>The first was Maine, in 1969, which <a href="https://www.centralmaine.com/2016/10/09/paul-mills-the-history-of-maines-distinctive-electoral-college-voting-system/">adopted a proposal</a> from an idiosyncratic legislator, whose apparent motivation was to help voters with different views be reflected in the Electoral College results. (Maine had used the district system back in the 1820s.) The second was Nebraska, in 1991, where legislators <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-joe-biden-donald-trump-omaha-nebraska-52a600f3491ed479da827e466bd914c2">hoped to</a> get presidential candidates to pay more attention to the state rather than writing off all its electoral votes as safely Republican.</p>

<p>One might think that proposals like this would move the Electoral College closer to proportional representation — but often, these proposals are just partisan dirty tricks. Republicans in <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/pennsylvania-electoral-college-plan-could-backfire-on-g-o-p/">Pennsylvania</a> and <a href="https://wisconsinexaminer.com/2021/01/08/gop-eyes-bill-to-reallocate-wisconsins-electoral-votes-by-congressional-district/">Wisconsin</a> have batted around the idea, believing gerrymandered congressional maps would guarantee them more than half the electors in swing states that more often lean Democratic.</p>

<p>But Maine and Nebraska do not seem to have had partisan motivations — and at first, there was no partisan impact, or indeed, any impact, because the statewide winner kept also winning every congressional district in both states.</p>

<p>As urban-rural partisan polarization intensified, that started to change. In 2008, Barack Obama won Nebraska’s Second District. Republicans responded by making the district more conservative in redistricting, but the underlying polarization trends continued and by 2020 Biden won it again. In Maine, the rural Second District swung to Trump in both 2016 and 2020. (Neither district was all that close in 2020 — Biden won NE-2 by 6.5 percentage points, and Trump won ME-2 by 7.5.)</p>

<p>So we’ve ended up with a system where 48 states use winner-take-all, and then two states throw a stray electoral vote to someone every so often, which is pretty odd — just one of many ways the US’s method of picking a president <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/11/7/12315574/electoral-college-explained-presidential-elections-2016">is ridiculous</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s going on in Nebraska now</h2>

<p>As partisanship and polarization have risen, Nebraska Republicans have attempted to respond. Back in 2016, they tried to switch to a winner-take-all electoral vote system. But there was a problem — the filibuster.</p>

<p>Yes, the Cornhusker State is the rare state to have a legislative filibuster with a strong supermajority requirement. In fact, it’s stronger than the US Senate’s — a two-thirds vote, or 33 of 49 legislators, is necessary to overcome a filibuster in Nebraska. And though Republicans have regularly had big majorities, it’s proven maddeningly difficult for them to get over that hump. They fell <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/13/us/nebraska-legislature-rejects-winner-take-all-electoral-vote-system.html">just one vote short</a> in 2016.</p>

<p>This year’s initial push kicked off in April, when conservative activist Charlie Kirk <a href="https://twitter.com/charliekirk11/status/1775201223404331439">wrote on X</a> about a nightmare scenario for Trump supporters where Nebraska’s Second District could throw this year’s election to then-candidate<strong> </strong>Biden. He urged Nebraskans to “call their legislators and their governor to demand their state stop pointlessly giving strength to their political enemies.”</p>

<p>Just hours later, Gov. Jim Pillen made his announcement that, “in response to a call out for his support,” he supported such a change, and <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/112204756443508099">Trump praised him</a> in a Truth Social post. But many <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/04/02/2024/trump-and-nebraska-governor-push-to-deny-biden-a-crucial-electoral-vote">doubted</a> that they had the votes. Republicans had 32 seats — one vote short of the 33 seats necessary to beat a filibuster.</p>

<p>The plot thickened when a Democratic state senator, McDonnell, <a href="https://twitter.com/charliekirk11/status/1775572059479040275">announced</a> he was switching parties to the GOP — seemingly providing the necessary vote. Then the plot, er, thinned when <a href="https://twitter.com/ec_schneider/status/1775558726738477276">McDonnell told Politico’s Elena Schneider</a> that he would still support filibustering the electoral vote change. And when the proposal came to a vote, it wasn’t even close. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But last week, Republicans tried again. Gov. Pillen called in state senators and urged them to make the change, and Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-SC) traveled to the state with the same ask. Initially, some reports <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/2024/09/18/winner-take-all-push-gets-help-of-gov-jim-pillen-sen-lindsey-graham-trump/">indicated</a> McDonnell was wavering.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, though, McDonnell <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/2024/09/23/state-sen-mike-mcdonnell-deflates-gop-hopes-for-nebraska-winner-take-all-in-2024/">issued a statement</a> saying he was still against it: “After deep consideration, it is clear to me that right now, 43 days from Election Day, is not the moment to make this change,” he said.</p>

<p><em><strong>Update, September 23, 4:45 pm ET: </strong>This article was originally published on April 3 and has been updated to reflect the new GOP effort to change Nebraska’s rules.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Cameron Peters</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[America’s unique, enduring gun problem, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/23142734/apalachee-georgia-school-shooting-gun-violence" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/23142734/kansas-city-superbowl-mass-shooting</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T15:41:55Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-23T15:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Gun Violence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four people were killed and at least 17 were injured in Birmingham, Alabama, on Saturday when multiple shooters opened fire on a group of people in the southern part of the city. As of Monday morning, no suspects had been taken into custody, though the Birmingham police described the incident as an attack that involved [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A photo taken from the top of an outdoor staircase leading to the entrance of a building with an awning that reads “Hush Lounge.”" data-caption="A fatal shooting occurred outside Hush nightclub in Birmingham, Alabama, on September 21, 2024. | Vasha Hunt/AP" data-portal-copyright="Vasha Hunt/AP" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/AP24266559442935.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A fatal shooting occurred outside Hush nightclub in Birmingham, Alabama, on September 21, 2024. | Vasha Hunt/AP</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/birmingham-alabama-shooting-4-killed-dozens-injured-rcna172128" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/birmingham-alabama-shooting-4-killed-dozens-injured-rcna172128">Four people were killed and at least 17</a> were injured in Birmingham, Alabama, on Saturday when multiple shooters opened fire on a group of people in the southern part of the city. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As of Monday morning, no suspects had been taken into custody, though the Birmingham police described the incident as an attack that involved a specific target. “We believe there was a hit, if you will, on that particular person as far as someone willing to pay money to have that person killed,” <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/birmingham-alabama-shooting-4-killed-dozens-injured-rcna172128" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/birmingham-alabama-shooting-4-killed-dozens-injured-rcna172128">Birmingham police Chief Scott Thurmond said at a press briefing</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The four victims have been identified as Roderick Lynn Patterson Jr., 26; Anitra Holloman, 21; Tahj Booker, 27; and Carlos McCain, 27. Police noted that others were caught in the crossfire as the shooters aimed for their intended target, who was among the victims. According to authorities, the shooters got out of a car, fired multiple shots at people standing outside a nightclub, and fled. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/23/birmingham-alabama-mass-shooting" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/23/birmingham-alabama-mass-shooting">The incident marked the second mass shooting</a> to occur in Birmingham in roughly two months, and follows another <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/14/us/birmingham-nightclub-mass-shooting/index.html" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/14/us/birmingham-nightclub-mass-shooting/index.html">mass shooting that took place outside of a Birmingham nightclub this past July.</a> Authorities note that the perpetrators may have <a href="https://www.wvtm13.com/article/glock-switches-alabama-mass-shooting/62318295" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.wvtm13.com/article/glock-switches-alabama-mass-shooting/62318295">used conversion devices,</a> which can turn a semi-automatic weapon into an automatic one that fires off shots more quickly and causes more casualties as a result. </p>

<p>There have been <a href="https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/reports/mass-shooting">404 mass shootings in the United States in 2024</a>, including in Birmingham, following a <a href="https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/reports/mass-shooting?year=2023">near-record number</a> of mass shootings in 2023. No other high-income country has suffered such a high death toll from <a href="https://www.vox.com/22382180/supreme-court-uvalde-guns-violence-second-amendment-heller-scalia">gun violence</a>. Every day, more than <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/report/gun-violence-in-america/">120</a> Americans die at the end of a gun, including suicides and homicides, an average of 44,341 per year. According to the latest available analysis of data from 2015 to 2019,<strong> </strong>the US gun homicide rate was <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/report/gun-violence-in-america/">26 times</a> that of other high-income countries; its gun suicide rate was nearly <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/report/gun-violence-in-america/">12 times higher</a>. Mass shootings, defined as attacks in which at least four people are injured or killed excluding the shooter, have been on the rise since 2015, peaking at <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/mass-shootings-in-america/">686 incidents in 2021</a>.</p>

<p>Despite that sheer carnage, however, the political debate over how to ensure that guns don’t fall into the hands of people who may hurt themselves and others has long proved intractable. In 2022,<strong> </strong>Congress reached a <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/6/23/23180893/senate-gun-control-bipartisan-bill-2022-pass">deal on limited gun reforms</a> for the first time in nearly 30 years<strong> </strong>in the wake of a shooting at an elementary school in Uvalde, Texas — the deadliest school shooting since 2012.&nbsp;</p>

<p>But those narrow reforms clearly haven’t stopped America’s gun violence epidemic. The US’s expansive view of civilian gun ownership has been so ingrained in politics, in culture, and in the law since the nation’s founding that there’s no telling how many more people will die before federal lawmakers take further action. In that absence, many red states have loosened their gun laws over the last few years, rather than making it harder to obtain a gun.&nbsp;</p>

<p>“America is unique in that guns have always been present, there is wide civilian ownership, and the government hasn’t claimed more of a monopoly on them,” said David Yamane, a professor at Wake Forest University who studies American gun culture.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The US has a lot of guns, and more guns means more gun deaths&nbsp;</h2>

<p>It’s hard to estimate the number of privately owned guns in America since there is no countrywide database where people register whether they own guns, there is a<a href="https://www.everytown.org/issues/gun-trafficking/"> thriving black market</a> for them in the absence of strong federal gun trafficking laws, and people can manufacture their own guns with DIY kits or 3D printers. The gun lobby has also <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2013/02/atf-gun-laws-nra/">vehemently opposed</a> federal legislation to track gun sales and establish a national handgun registry.&nbsp;</p>

<p>One estimate from the Small Arms Survey, a Swiss-based research project, found that there were approximately <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-41488081">390 million guns</a> in circulation in the US in 2018, or about 120.5 firearms per 100 residents. That number has likely climbed in the years since, given that<a href="https://www.norc.org/NewsEventsPublications/PressReleases/Pages/one-in-five-american-households-purchased-a-gun-during-the-pandemic.aspx"> one in five households</a> purchased a gun during the pandemic, though the 2018 estimate remains the most recent available. There has also been a significant increase in the number of <a href="https://www.thetrace.org/2023/03/guns-america-data-atf-total/">guns manufactured and imported</a> in the years since. But even without accounting for that increase, US gun ownership is still well above any other country: Yemen, which has the world’s second-highest level of gun ownership, has only 52.8 guns per 100 residents; in Iceland, it’s 31.7.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24876824/1443590414.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.724909644683,100,78.550180710634" alt="At Least 5 Dead And 18 Injured In Colorado Springs Gay Nightclub Shooting" title="At Least 5 Dead And 18 Injured In Colorado Springs Gay Nightclub Shooting" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A makeshift memorial set up for the victims of the Club Q nightclub shooting in Colorado Springs that happened on November 19, 2022. | Scott Olson/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Scott Olson/Getty Images" />
<p>American guns are concentrated in a tiny minority of households: just 3 percent own about half the nation’s guns, according to a 2016 Harvard and Northeastern University<a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2016/09/study-70m-more-firearms-added-to-us-gun-stock-over-past-20-years/"> study</a>. They’re called “<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/sep/19/us-gun-ownership-survey">super owners</a>” who have an average of 17 guns each. Gallup, using a different methodology, found that <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/1645/guns.aspx">45 percent of Americans</a> lived in a household with guns in 2022.</p>

<p>Researchers have found a clear link between gun ownership in the US and gun violence, and some argue that it’s causal. One 2013 Boston University-led study, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3828709/">for instance</a>, found that for each percentage point increase in gun ownership at the household level, the state firearm homicide rate increased by 0.9 percent. And states with weaker gun laws have higher rates of gun-related homicides and suicides, according to a <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/rankings/">study</a> by the gun control advocacy group Everytown for Gun Safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The link between gun deaths and gun ownership is much stronger than the link that<strong> </strong>gun rights advocates often seek to draw<strong> </strong>between violence and mental health issues. If it were possible to cure all schizophrenia, bipolar, and depressive disorders, violent crime in the US would <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/myth-vs-fact-violence-and-mental-health">fall by only 4 percent</a>, according to a <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=v4oSb2Na4nQC&amp;lpg=PP1&amp;pg=PA101#v=onepage&amp;q=swanson&amp;f=false">study</a> from Duke University professor Jeffrey Swanson, who examines policies to reduce gun violence.</p>

<p>There’s still a pervasive idea, pushed by gun manufacturers and gun rights organizations like the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/5/25/23140519/uvalde-school-shooting-nra-texas-good-guy-gun">National Rifle Association</a>, that further arming America is the answer to preventing gun violence — <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/5/25/23140519/uvalde-school-shooting-nra-texas-good-guy-gun">the “good guy with a gun” theory</a>. But there have been relatively few instances in which police or armed bystanders have been able to successfully stop an active attack.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>According to a database maintained by Advanced Law Enforcement Rapid Response Training Center at Texas State University, there were 520 active attacks — <a href="https://www.activeattackdata.org/index.html">defined</a> as when one or more people are “actively killing or attempting to kill multiple unrelated people in a public space,” including but not limited to shootings — between 2000 and 2022. In many of those cases, police were <a href="https://www.activeattackdata.org/allattacks.html">unable to stop</a> the attacker, either because the attack had already ended by the time they arrived or because the attacker surrendered or committed suicide. Only in 160 cases were police able to successfully intervene by shooting or otherwise subduing the attacker.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24882439/Ndqdu_police_stopped_fewer_than_a_third_of_active_attacks_between_2000_and_2022__1_.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,20.109822298073,100,59.780355403855" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p>Another 2021 <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2776515">study</a> from Hamline University and Metropolitan State University found that the rate of deaths in 133 mass school shootings between 1980 and 2019 was 2.83 times greater in cases where there was an armed guard present. The researchers argue the results suggest the presence of an armed guard increased shooters’ aggression and that because many school shooters have been found to be suicidal, “an armed officer may be an incentive rather than a deterrent.”</p>

<p>“The idea that the solution to mass shootings is that we need more guns in the hands of more people in more places so that we’ll be able to protect ourselves — there’s no evidence that that’s true,” Swanson said.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The prevalence of the self-defense narrative is part of what sets apart the gun rights movement in the US from similar movements in places like Canada and Australia, according to Robert Spitzer, a professor at SUNY Cortland who studies the politics of gun control.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Self-defense has become by far the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/09/13/key-facts-about-americans-and-guns/">most prominent reason</a> for gun ownership in the US today, eclipsing hunting, recreation, or owning guns because they’re antiques, heirlooms, or work-related. That’s also reflected in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/17/us/politics/gun-manufacturing-atf.html">ballooning handgun sales</a>, since the primary purpose of those guns isn’t recreational, but self-defense.&nbsp;</p>

<p>American gun culture “brings together the hunting-sporting tradition with the militia-frontier tradition, but in modern times the hunting element has been eclipsed by a heavily politicized notion that gun carrying is an expression of freedom, individuality, hostility to government, and personal self-protection,” Spitzer said.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23589886/GettyImages_1240907270.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,7.1237996034465,100,85.752400793107" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="People gather at Sacred Heart Catholic Church to pray for the victims of the mass shooting at Robb Elementary School in Uvalde, Texas, on May 25, 2022. | Chandan Khanna/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chandan Khanna/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p>That <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/6/20/11975850/ar-15-owner-orlando">culture of gun ownership in the US</a> has made it all the more difficult to explore serious policy solutions to gun violence after mass shootings. In high-income countries lacking that culture, mass shootings have historically galvanized public support behind gun control measures that would seem extreme by US standards.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Canada <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2021/03/23/mass-shootings-response-other-countries-gun-laws/">banned military-style assault weapons</a> two weeks after a 2020 mass shooting in Nova Scotia. In 2019, less than a month after the Christchurch massacre, New Zealand lawmakers passed a gun buyback scheme, as well as restrictions on AR-15s and other semiautomatic weapons, and they later established a firearms registry. The 1996 Port Arthur massacre in Australia spurred the government to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/8/27/9212725/australia-buyback">buy back 650,000 firearms</a> within a year, and murders and suicides plummeted as a result.&nbsp;</p>

<p>By contrast, nearly a decade went by after the 2012 school shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary School in Newtown, Connecticut, before Congress passed a new gun control law. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/6/23/23180893/senate-gun-control-bipartisan-bill-2022-pass">Bipartisan Safer Communities Act</a>, the law passed in June 2022, was relatively limited:<strong> </strong>It incentivized states to pass red flag laws, enhanced background checks for gun buyers under 21, and closed the “boyfriend loophole,” which allowed some people with domestic violence convictions to purchase guns. But it did not ban any types of weapons, and certain studies suggest that even truly universal background checks may have <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/2/27/18224727/house-universal-background-checks-gun-violence-congress">limited effects on gun violence</a>.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p>At the same time, many states have sought to expand gun ownership in recent years. At least 27 states have now passed laws allowing residents to carry a <a href="https://www.handgunlaw.us/documents/Permitless_Carry_States.pdf">handgun without a permit</a> and allow school staff and teachers to <a href="https://www.rand.org/research/gun-policy/analysis/laws-allowing-armed-staff-in-K12-schools.html">carry guns on campus</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24882641/nwQcq_27_states_have_passed_laws_allowing_people_to_carry_a_handgun_without_a_permit.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,21.773275665832,100,56.453448668336" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p>“Other countries look at this problem and say, ‘People walking around in the community with handguns is just way too dangerous, so we’re going to broadly limit legal access to that and make exceptions on the margins for people who might have a good reason to have a gun,’” Swanson said. “Here we do just the opposite: We say that, because of the way that the Supreme Court interpreted the Second Amendment, everybody has the right to a gun for personal protection, and then we tried to make exceptions for really dangerous people, but we can’t figure out who they are.”</p>

<p><a href="https://iop.harvard.edu/get-involved/harvard-political-review/vast-majority-americans-support-universal-background-checks">While the majority of Americans</a> support more gun control restrictions, <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2021/09/13/key-facts-about-americans-and-guns/">including universal background checks</a>, a vocal Republican minority unequivocally opposes such laws — and is willing to put pressure on GOP lawmakers to do the same. Alongside the NRA, and a well-funded gun lobby, this contingent of voters sees gun control as a deciding issue, and one that could warrant a primary challenge for a lawmaker who votes for it.&nbsp;</p>

<p>The gun lobby has the advantage of enthusiasm. “​​Despite being outnumbered, Americans who oppose gun control are more likely to contact public officials about it and to base their votes on it,” Barnard College’s Matthew Lacombe <a href="https://barnard.edu/news/break-down-gun-politics-america">explained in 2020</a>. “As a result, many politicians believe that supporting gun regulation is more likely to lose them votes than to gain them votes.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24876847/1246706108.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.100531452033,100,73.798937095933" alt="Two older Asian women stand comforting each other." title="Two older Asian women stand comforting each other." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Mourners honor the victims of the January 27, 2023, Monterey Park, California, mass shooting. | Sarah Reingewirtz/MediaNews Group/Los Angeles Daily News via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Sarah Reingewirtz/MediaNews Group/Los Angeles Daily News via Getty Images" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Supreme Court has made it impossible to cure America’s gun violence epidemic</h2>

<p>In 2008, the Supreme Court effectively wrote NRA CEO Wayne LaPierre’s “good guy with a gun” theory into the Constitution. The Court’s 5-4 decision in <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/07-290.ZO.html"><em>District of Columbia v. Heller</em></a> (2008) was the first Supreme Court decision in American history to hold that the Second Amendment protects an individual right to possess a firearm. But it also went much further than that.</p>

<p><em>Heller</em> held that one of the primary purposes of the Second Amendment is to protect the right of individuals — good guys with a gun, in LaPierre’s framework — to use firearms to stop bad guys with guns. As Justice Antonin Scalia wrote in <em>Heller</em>, an “inherent right of self-defense has been central to the Second Amendment right.”</p>

<p>As a matter of textual interpretation, this holding makes no sense. The Second Amendment provides that “<a href="https://constitutioncenter.org/interactive-constitution/amendment/amendment-ii">a well regulated Militia, being necessary to the security of a free State</a>, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>We don’t need to guess why the Second Amendment protects a right to firearms because it is right there in the Constitution. The Second Amendment’s purpose is to preserve “a well-regulated Militia,” not to allow individuals to use their weapons for personal self-defense.</p>

<p>For many years, the Supreme Court took the first 13 words of the Second Amendment seriously. As the Court said in <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/307/174"><em>United States v. Miller</em></a><em> </em>(1939), the “obvious purpose” of the Second Amendment was to “render possible the effectiveness” of militias. And thus the amendment must be “interpreted and applied with that end in view.” <em>Heller</em> abandoned that approach.</p>

<p><em>Heller</em> also reached another important policy conclusion. Handguns, according to Scalia, are “overwhelmingly chosen” by gun owners who wish to carry a firearm for self-defense. For this reason, he wrote, handguns enjoy a kind of super-legal status. Lawmakers are not allowed to ban what Scalia described as “the most preferred firearm in the nation to ‘keep’ and use for protection of one’s home and family.”</p>

<p>This declaration regarding handguns matters because this easily concealed weapon is responsible for far more deaths than any other weapon in the United States — and it isn’t close. In 2021, for example, a <a href="https://cde.ucr.cjis.gov/LATEST/webapp/#/pages/explorer/crime/shr">total of 14,616 people were murdered in the US</a>, according to the FBI. Of these murder victims, at least 5,992 — just over 40 percent — were killed by handguns.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23589874/GettyImages_1240908247.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A woman holds a photo of Nevaeh Bravo, who was killed in the mass shooting at Robb Elementary School, during a vigil for the victims in Uvalde, Texas, on May 25, 2022. | Allison Dinner/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Allison Dinner/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p>In 2021, the Supreme Court made it even harder for federal and state lawmakers to combat gun violence. In its decision in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/20-843_7j80.pdf"><em>New York State Rifle &amp; Pistol Association v. Bruen</em></a><em>, </em>it massively expands the scope of the Second Amendment, abandons more than a decade of case law governing which gun laws are permitted by the Constitution, and replaces this case law with a new legal framework that, as Justice Stephen Breyer writes in dissent, “imposes a task on the lower courts that judges cannot easily accomplish.”</p>

<p><em>Bruen </em>has since allowed handguns — which are responsible for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/22382180/supreme-court-uvalde-guns-violence-second-amendment-heller-scalia">overwhelming majority of gun murders</a> in the United States — to proliferate on many American streets. That’s because <em>Bruen</em> strikes the types of laws that limit who can legally carry handguns in public, holding that “the Second and Fourteenth Amendments protect an individual’s right to carry a handgun for self-defense outside the home.” Amid a flurry of activity in the courts in recent years, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2023/07/28/bruen-supreme-court-rahimi-00108285">more than a dozen state and federal gun control laws</a> have been invalidated in whole or in part as a result.</p>

<p>Under this new legal regime, the future of firearm regulation looks grim for anyone who believes that the government should help protect us from gun violence.</p>

<p><em><strong>Update, September 23, 2024, 11:40 am ET: </strong>This story was originally published on May 26, 2022, and has been updated multiple times, most recently with the latest details from the September 21 shooting outside a night club in Birmingham, Alabama. </em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Marin Cogan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This book is changing how cities fight gun violence]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/373238/gun-violence-homicides-violent-crime-strategies" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/373238/this-book-is-changing-how-cities-fight-gun-violence</id>
			<updated>2024-09-23T15:02:55Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-23T15:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Gun Violence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Highlight" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unless something changes this fall, 2024 will go down as another year in which the United States made major progress in reducing homicides. Murder rose nearly 30 percent during the pandemic, but many cities have returned to pre-pandemic levels and are continuing to see the numbers decline. As summer ended, murder was down 17 percent [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="One person in the crowd holds a sign that says “advocating for a safer community.”" data-caption="People stand beside a memorial during a rally for an 11-year-old girl in the South Bronx who was caught in crossfire and killed on May 18, 2022 in New York City. | Bill Clark/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bill Clark/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Cgettyimages-1397959102.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>People stand beside a memorial during a rally for an 11-year-old girl in the South Bronx who was caught in crossfire and killed on May 18, 2022 in New York City. | Bill Clark/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Unless something changes this fall, 2024 will go down as another year in which the United States made major progress in reducing homicides. Murder rose nearly 30 percent during the pandemic, but many cities have returned <a href="https://counciloncj.org/homicide-most-other-violent-crimes-drop-to-pre-pandemic-levels-in-u-s-cities/#:~:text=WASHINGTON%20%E2%80%93%20Homicide%20and%20most%20other,the%20Council%20on%20Criminal%20Justice.">to pre-pandemic levels</a> and are continuing to see the numbers decline. As summer ended, murder was down <a href="https://jasher.substack.com/p/murder-is-likely-falling-at-the-fastest">17 percent</a> in American cities compared to the same time last year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plenty of cities still struggle with gun violence: This weekend, four people were killed and at least 17 were injured in a shooting <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/22/birmingham-alabama-shooting" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/22/birmingham-alabama-shooting">outside of a nightclub in Birmingham, Alabama</a>, part of an epidemic that explains why the United States has <a href="https://everytownresearch.org/graph/the-u-s-gun-homicide-rate-is-26-times-that-of-other-high-income-countries/" data-type="link" data-id="https://everytownresearch.org/graph/the-u-s-gun-homicide-rate-is-26-times-that-of-other-high-income-countries/">a gun homicide rate that is 26 times higher</a> than other comparable countries. Still, the decline in overall homicides is essential to saving lives and creating safer communities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What explains <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/366622/violent-crime-dropping-pandemic-wave-2024">such a dramatic rise and then fall</a> in homicides?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The US <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358831/us-violent-crime-murder-pandemic">did not experience a rise in crime more generally</a> during the pandemic. It was violent crime, particularly homicides, that drove the surge. The increase in homicides, in turn, <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/the-recent-rise-in-violent-crime-is-driven-by-gun-violence/">was driven largely by gun homicides</a> — which make up the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2023/04/26/what-the-data-says-about-gun-deaths-in-the-u-s/">vast majority of homicides in the United States</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The risk <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/353878/new-guns-us-violence">wasn’t shared equally across the population</a>, either: Nearly two-thirds of the victims of gun homicides in 2020 were Black, with the largest increases in gun deaths happening among <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2818887?utm_source=For_The_Media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_term=052224">men and boys between the ages of 10 and 44</a>, and most of these murders <a href="https://giffords.org/lawcenter/report/gun-violence-in-black-communities/">took place in cities</a>. For this reason, experts understand the rise in murder during the pandemic to have been primarily <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/07/01/us/homicides-shootings-spike-us-cities/index.html">a problem of urban gun violence</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts say there are a few possible explanations for why gun homicides have since abated: <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358831/us-violent-crime-murder-pandemic">The end of the pandemic</a> reestablished a sense of normalcy. The turmoil over the role of police following the murder of George Floyd — <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/353878/new-guns-us-violence">followed by protests and violence in some communities</a> and a <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-murder-spike-of-2020-when-police-pull-back-11626969547">reduction</a> in policing — has also eased.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But those explanations overlook an important truth. The drop is also partly the result of carefully coordinated efforts by local officials, community leaders, and law enforcement, backed in many cases by an infusion of cash <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/addressing-the-root-causes-of-gun-violence-with-american-rescue-plan-funds-lessons-from-state-and-local-governments/">from the federal government.</a> As leaders formulate violence reduction strategies, many are doing it with the help of a quietly influential book — a how-to guide in the fight against urban gun violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/thomas-abt/bleeding-out/9781541645714/?lens=basic-books"><em>Bleeding Out</em></a> by Thomas Abt, was published in 2019. It makes a compelling argument: that urban gun violence, rather than being an immovable facet of American life, can be effectively reduced using specific, evidence-based strategies. By following the principles in the book, Abt writes, cities can save lives right away, without completely overhauling their budgets or waiting for long-term investments that might take decades.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While it’s still early, the book’s lessons are having a real-world impact.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">A set of strategies to stop urban gun violence</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Bleeding Out</em> <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/7/12/20679091/thomas-abt-bleeding-out-urban-gun-violence-book-review">draws on existing research</a> about what works to reduce urban gun violence, as well as Abt’s <a href="https://ccjs.umd.edu/facultyprofile/abt/thomas#:~:text=Thomas%20Abt%20VRC's%20Founding%20Director%20%26%20Associate%20Research%20Professor&amp;text=Thomas%20Abt%20is%20the%20founding,of%20Criminology%20and%20Criminal%20Justice.">own experience from stints</a> in the Obama administration and under then-New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He points to evidence that most of this violence is highly concentrated among a small number of people, and in a small number of places. In 2015, he notes, more than a quarter of the nation’s gun homicides happened in only 1,200 neighborhoods, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2017/jan/09/special-report-fixing-gun-violence-in-america">containing just 1.5 percent of the population</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The challenge of reducing gun violence, then, is to reach the people and the places at the center of the crisis, and find ways to disrupt the patterns that perpetuate it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Abt lays out three guiding principles: focus, balance, and fairness. The ideas work, he argues, if you intensely focus on the most at-risk people and places, balance the work of law enforcement with prevention and community intervention, and enforce the law fairly. “Punishment by itself has not worked,” Abt writes. “Neither has prevention.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Abt <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/topics/community-violence-intervention">cites research</a> suggesting that direct outreach from “credible messengers” and other community workers can help prevent this violence. He narrows in on the promising results that cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) has shown in communities where gun violence is in part driven by retaliation between rival networks or gangs. Law enforcement, for their part, should inform the individuals most at risk of committing violence that they will be prosecuted if they shoot someone — but also offer them resources to help if they decide not to.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The primary value of <em>Bleeding Out</em> isn’t that it presents brand-new strategies, but that it helps disseminate valuable existing knowledge. “He gathered all of the evidence-based policy and research that was out there, in a way that was very balanced between law enforcement piece and the community piece, and put it into something that was digestible by not just researchers but policymakers and community members,” says <a href="https://aysps.gsu.edu/profile/volkan-topalli/">Volkan Topalli,</a> a criminology professor at Georgia State University. In other words, Abt took a big, complex issue and distilled it into a concise problem leaders weren’t helpless to solve.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The pandemic created a crisis — and an opportunity</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, the year after the book’s release, the pandemic lockdowns started, followed by a summer of protests over police brutality. In many cities, police clashed with the protesters, and violence erupted. By the end of the year, the US had recorded its highest increase in homicide rates in modern history, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2021/10/06/health/us-homicide-rate-increase-nchs-study/index.html">according to</a> the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That was a really difficult time,” Abt says. But it was also a moment where the ideas in the book could be put to the test.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In July 2021, the Council On Criminal Justice (CCJ), a nonpartisan think tank in Washington, DC, convened a Violent Crime Working Group to study the problem and try to offer solutions for cities facing the surge. The group, chaired by Abt and composed of experts, community leaders, law enforcement, and judges, met nearly a dozen times, issuing bulletins on their findings. In their final report, the group recommended ten “<a href="https://counciloncj.org/10-essential-actions/">essential actions</a>” communities could take to fight urban gun violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://counciloncj.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/VCWG-Final-Report.pdf">The broad scope</a> of the essential actions closely echoes the strategies and the three guiding principles — focus, balance, and fairness — that Abt recommends in <em>Bleeding Out</em>. Over the following year, communities like <a href="https://www.unionleader.com/news/crime/under-fire-manchester-tries-new-strategy-for-gun-crime/article_b4ad33ee-b052-52aa-8c45-d4c0e76bff20.html">Manchester, New Hampshire</a>, began adopting some of the recommendations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In December 2023, the Department of Justice announced its Violent Crime Reduction Roadmap, a “one-stop-shop to assist local jurisdictions” in fighting community gun violence. The recommendations were familiar: They were the exact same “essential actions” proposed by Abt and his colleagues in the CCJ’s working group. As <a href="https://counciloncj.org/ccj-directory/adam-gelb/">Adam Gelb, president of the CCJ</a>, put it, “The core ideas in <em>Bleeding Out</em> not only became the basis of violent crime working group report, but the foundation of federal violence reduction policy.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Helping establish the federal guidelines for gun violence reduction isn’t the only way the book has influenced policy. Leaders at every level are reading the book as they begin to form their own plans for violence reduction. <a href="https://people.miami.edu/profile/d506d27f83929e0a9839caa0309ae881">Alex Piquero</a>, former director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics and a criminologist at the University of Miami, was on the CCJ working group and read early drafts of <em>Bleeding Out.</em> He recalls seeing it on the desk of a Miami police official in a 2021 meeting and thinking: “That&#8217;s exactly the audience who Thomas wanted to read the book.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The police official wasn’t alone. US Attorney Dawn Ison, <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-edmi/meet-united-states-attorney">who oversees Michigan’s Eastern District</a>, told Vox that she turned to Abt while developing a summer violent crime reduction plan called “OneDetroit.” “I sent him our OneDetroit mission statement, and he gave it a thumbs up,” Ison says. The precincts OneDetroit targeted saw a 17 percent reduction in homicides and were part of a <a href="https://www.vox.com/24145161/detroit-crime-statistics-gun-violence-rate-violence-reduction">successful strategy of reducing murders in the city last year</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not just law enforcement and government officials who have found value in the book. “When Thomas&#8217;s book came out, we were like: See? We’re not crazy!” says Molly Baldwin, founder and CEO of Roca, a community program that does outreach to youth affected by urban gun violence in Massachusetts, Connecticut, and Maryland.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In November 2022, Abt founded the Violence Reduction Center at the University of Maryland, to assist cities wanting help. VRC is partnering with three cities: Knoxville, Tennessee; Boston, Massachusetts; and St. Louis, Missouri, and its surrounding counties.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As testing grounds for urban violence reduction, the cities couldn’t be more different. Boston, the largest of the three, has a strong history of this kind of work, but Abt “helps us redirect and organize,” says Isaac Yablo, Boston’s senior advisor for community safety.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Knoxville, the smallest, is newer to the effort. “We could have spent a lot of time flailing about, figuring out how to put this together,” without VRC’s help, says LaKenya Middlebrook, the city’s first director of community safety. St. Louis, which is approaching the effort on a regional level and is anchored by a city with one of the highest murder rates in the country — is still in the planning stages, but local officials say VRC’s expertise has been valuable as they coordinate a strategy across multiple county governments.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Abt provides access to experts and offers suggestions, but leaves it to policymakers to decide their priorities. While he has formal relationships with the three cities, informal discussions happen all the time. “Not everybody needs or is ready for some big intensive thing,” Abt says, of his relationships with leaders in other cities. “You could just email me.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He tries to be realistic about his role. “I have high hopes,” Abt says, but at the same time, “a little humility is in order here. The VRC is a help in all of the cities it works in, but ultimately it&#8217;s the good people in these cities — the mayors, the chiefs, and all of the people on the ground — who are doing this work.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not everyone agrees with his approach. Critics have described Abt’s focus on “stopping the bleeding” over addressing “root causes” of violence — economic disinvestment and racial segregation — as <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2019/09/can-thomas-abts-bleeding-out-curb-gun-violence/596164/">dismissive</a>. Others have called it an oversimplification.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Abt says he’s been criticized by the left for arguing against the idea of defunding the police, and by the right for emphasizing that for some crime reduction efforts, law enforcement is not the solution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People are dunking on me from all directions. There are people on the far left who think I’m placing the emphasis wrong, and worry that my message could be misinterpreted and misused to go back to tough-on-crime policies,” Abt says. “I try to be exquisitely careful about that. I’ve had many debates with tough-on-crime people, too.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, he is confident in his strategy, and in its position as a middle path, a data-driven approach that cuts across the long-held controversies over the role of policing and urban violence and prioritizes saving lives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of people, he says, want relief from the violence. “This is particularly true in these most marginalized communities,” Abt says. As he tells the mayors he works with: “They will reward you at election time if you can make them safer.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, September 23, 11:00 am: </strong>This story was originally published on September 5 and has been updated to include news of a shooting outside a nightclub in Birmingham, Alabama, on September 21. </em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Umair Irfan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Democrats have embraced a surprising “America First!” approach on climate]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/372665/harris-trump-debate-energy-nationalism-climate" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=372665</id>
			<updated>2024-09-19T21:09:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-23T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Fossil fuels" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Renewable Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Solar energy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the name suggests, global warming is a global issue that effectively requires every country to act to curb greenhouse gas emissions. Any ton of carbon dioxide produced anywhere adds to warming globally, while any ton reduced anywhere has the same effect in reverse. That’s why the most efficient way to reduce greenhouse gas emissions [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="An American flag hangs at the Venture Global Plaquemines LNG plant while under construction in Port Sulphur, Louisiana. The US is now producing more oil and gas than any country in history." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2165063430.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>An American flag hangs at the Venture Global Plaquemines LNG plant while under construction in Port Sulphur, Louisiana. The US is now producing more oil and gas than any country in history.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">As the name suggests, global warming is a global issue that effectively <a href="https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/climate-action/">requires every country to act</a> to curb greenhouse gas emissions. Any ton of carbon dioxide produced anywhere adds to warming globally, while any ton reduced anywhere has the same effect in reverse. That’s why the most efficient way to reduce greenhouse gas emissions broadly is through policies that encourage the cheapest clean technology, wherever it comes from.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the leading presidential candidates of both major American political parties are increasingly pushing for the US to develop <em>all</em> forms of energy — oil and natural gas included — and shield its own clean tech sector, even at the expense of its allies and its own climate goals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s little surprise that former President Donald Trump, a skeptic at best about climate change, has repeatedly <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/drill-baby-drill-donald-trump-oil-gas-rnc/story?id=112108980">boasted</a> about his track records in boosting domestic energy production, including fossil fuels, and has pledged to impose more tariffs on Chinese goods like solar panels if he becomes president again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Vice President Kamala Harris has also been hyping an America First energy policy. While the 2022 <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23281757/whats-in-climate-bill-inflation-reduction-act">Inflation Reduction Act</a> signed by President Joe Biden represents the single-largest US investment to address climate change, his vice president has been taking credit for how it expanded oil and gas development.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was the tie-breaking vote on the Inflation Reduction Act, which opened new leases for <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/9/12/20857196/kamala-fracking-ban-biden-climate-change">fracking</a>,” Harris said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s part of a stark bipartisan <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/on-tiktok-and-steel-u-s-retreats-further-from-free-trade-consensus-f60fe2d4">shift from the one-time consensus support for free trade</a> and open markets. But it’s a particularly notable change in tune from Democrats, who once made global, collaborative action on climate change a central issue.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris, during her first run for president in 2019, <a href="https://x.com/CNNPolitics/status/1169384141923606528">pledged to ban fracking</a>, a controversial technique for extracting oil and gas from shale rock, and one that is largely responsible for making the US an oil and gas power again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden <a href="https://grist.org/politics/biden-promised-no-new-drilling-on-public-lands-heres-why-he-broke-that-promise/">promised no new fossil fuel extraction</a> on federal lands and to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-environment/2020/11/07/biden-climate-change-monuments/">restore America’s climate standing</a> on the global stage. Biden did bring the US back into the <a href="https://www.vox.com/22241348/president-biden-climate-change-paris-agreement-executive-order-keystone-pipeline">Paris climate agreement</a> shortly after taking office, but since then has overseen a massive expansion in oil and gas production and <a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=61863">ramped up fossil fuel exports</a> to <a href="https://www.csis.org/analysis/geopolitical-significance-us-lng">other countries</a>. At the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368706/kamala-harris-dnc-climate-change-policy-poll">Democratic National Convention</a> last month, climate change scarcely came up at all. Now US <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/short-take-us-energy-production-exceeds-consumption-by-widest-recorded-margin-2024-06-26/">energy production is at an all-time high</a>, and the US is producing <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24098983/biden-oil-production-climate-fossil-fuel-renewables">more oil and gas than any country in history</a>. <br>Why the change? The simple reason is that voters right now <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/09/09/issues-and-the-2024-election/">care a lot more about the economy</a> and much less about the environment. “It’s not the climate politics of four years ago, or eight years ago,” said <a href="https://carnegieendowment.org/people/noah-gordon?lang=en">Noah Gordon</a>, who leads the climate program at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/PP_2024.9.9_harris-trump_2-01.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,25.783895611571,99.77421875,48.432208776857" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Though it remains a <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/09/18/1200068222/climate-change-young-voters-biden-trump-economy">priority for many young Democrats</a>, the spike in inflation and gasoline prices in the past several years pushed concerns about greenhouse gasses onto the back-burner. And when Democrats have acted on climate change, they haven’t received much credit from voters, many of whom are <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2023/8/16/23815837/inflation-reduction-act-joe-biden-impact-manufacturing-consumers">not even aware</a> of the climate provisions of the Inflation Reduction Act. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If voters think climate policy is a loser for jobs and the economy, it becomes a losing issue,” said <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/people/samantha-gross/">Samantha Gross</a>, who heads energy security and climate research at the Brookings Institution, in an email. “So if you care about the climate, solutions need to speak to voters’ economic concerns, like job creation and maintenance.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead of talking about climate change as its own issue, Democrats have increasingly broken it down into a subset of things that voters do demonstrably care about, like insurance rates, <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/climate-change-home-prices-housing-realtor-com/">housing</a>, energy prices, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23971356/thanksgiving-2023-food-steak-olive-oil-record-heat-climate-change">food security</a>. And when they do talk about climate change by name, it’s primarily to highlight how addressing warming can create new economic opportunities. The fact that the US’s largest climate investment in history is called the “Inflation Reduction Act” speaks to this strategy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“​​When we invest in climate, we create jobs, we lower costs, and we invest in families,” <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/04/05/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-historic-investments-in-climate-action/">Harris said</a> earlier this year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden-Harris administration has thus spent the past four years promoting job creation without being too picky about where they’re coming from, including the fossil fuel sector, and using protectionist trade policies to promote domestic energy production.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this shift in focus is leading to the US deliberately taking some of the cheapest clean energy options, like solar panels and cheap EVs made in China, off of the table, while extending a lifeline to some of the dirtiest sources of energy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This in turn has a cost for the planet: a slower path to decarbonization for the US, the <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/the-carbon-brief-profile-united-states/">world’s second-largest greenhouse gas emitter</a>. And that means locking in more warming and all its myriad harms for the world. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Putting jobs first has big political upsides, and some environmental downsides</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a long time, climate change was a direct function of economic output. As countries built more cars, roads, buildings, bridges, and farms, they burned more coal, oil, and natural gas, which produce greenhouse gasses that heat up the planet. That’s why early industrializing countries like the US are the <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-which-countries-are-historically-responsible-for-climate-change/">biggest historical emitters of carbon dioxide</a>, and why the unprecedented industrial giant that is China is now the world’s biggest current emitter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as energy efficiency has increased and clean power has taken root, economic output no longer has to be tied to greenhouse gas increases. More than 30 countries (including the US) <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23447414/degrowth-decoupling-carbon-emissions-economic-growth">have severed the connection</a> between emissions and economic growth, meaning they’re generating wealth and prosperity at a higher rate than they’re heating up the planet as they reduce their relative use of fossil fuels. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And increasingly, many countries see a business opportunity in limiting greenhouse gas emissions. Clean technology sectors like solar power, electric vehicles, and batteries have been a major focus in China, <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-clean-energy-was-top-driver-of-chinas-economic-growth-in-2023/">contributing $1.6 trillion to its economy</a> and driving 40 percent of its gross domestic product growth last year alone. China now has 80 percent of the world’s <a href="https://e360.yale.edu/features/china-renewable-energy">solar manufacturing capacity</a>, and its intense investment in the sector has helped drive a <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/data-insights/solar-panel-prices-have-fallen-by-around-20-every-time-global-capacity-doubled">precipitous decline in global solar panel prices</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as China gains momentum, and as its government <a href="https://www.citigroup.com/global/insights/china-economics-out-with-the-old-three-and-in-with-the-new-three">doubles down on export-driven growth</a>, its cheap products are undercutting efforts in the United States to build up its own clean tech sector. To compete, the US has struck back <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/14/fact-sheet-president-biden-takes-action-to-protect-american-workers-and-businesses-from-chinas-unfair-trade-practices/#:~:text=The%20tariff%20rate%20on%20solar,solar%20capacity%20outside%20of%20China.">with tariffs</a> of up to 100 percent on Chinese EVs, 25 percent on EV batteries, and 50 percent on solar cells. Legislation like the Inflation Reduction Act <a href="https://www.irs.gov/credits-deductions/domestic-content-bonus-credit">contains additional tax credits</a> for energy projects that require the use of US-made hardware and mandates that grantees buy American products. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These trade hurdles on other countries have helped shield US workers. Jobs in the US clean tech sector grew at <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-report-shows-clean-energy-jobs-grew-more-twice-rate-overall-us-employment">more than double the rate</a> of overall employment. However, they impose a cost on consumers and the overall economy, raising the prices for many of the tools required to curb emissions, including blocking some of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/4/24087919/biden-tariff-chinese-ev-byd-battery-detroit">cheapest, most popular EVs in the world</a>, which come from China, from US roads. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is all a clear demonstration that the US government is prioritizing domestic jobs and limiting China’s influence ahead of the most efficient ways to reduce carbon emissions. And these are efforts that have largely drawn support from both parties. Republicans in Congress have even introduced a <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/11/02/senate-gop-climate-bill-china-00124909">border-adjustment carbon tax</a> that would add a fee to goods imported from countries deemed to be major greenhouse gas emitters (i.e., China). </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But “Buy American” provisions have also created friction with US allies and trading partners like the <a href="https://www.europarl.europa.eu/thinktank/en/document/IPOL_IDA(2023)740087">European Union</a> that want to sell their clean technologies in US markets. These requirements also create more competition for limited supplies of US-made hardware, sometimes leading to delays and raising costs of projects as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/us-solar-factory-outlook-hit-by-supply-demand-headwinds-2024-07-18/">US factories struggle to compete</a>. And tariffs on China aren’t airtight: Chinese companies are <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/autos/chinese-ev-suppliers-invest-in-u-s-free-trade-partners-in-bid-to-tap-american-market-be7cefed">relocating factories for components like batteries</a> to South Korea and Morocco to dodge US regulations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such measures may be necessary to build a political coalition to support an energy transition, but they make the overall process slower and more expensive, and they’re difficult to undo. “It becomes hard to roll back tariffs once they’re implemented,” Gordon said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration has also shown that it’s concerned about the political consequences of switching to clean energy too quickly, especially if those actions are viewed as contributing to higher prices. They <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24106924/epa-vehicle-emissions-carbon-pollution-climate-ev-hybrid">weakened vehicle pollution rules</a> that were designed to accelerate the shift to EVs. They’ve also continued to push for more oil and gas drilling in the US, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/22/icymi-biden-to-release-1-million-barrels-of-gasoline-to-reduce-prices-at-the-pump-ahead-of-july-4/">even tapping reserves to lower gasoline prices</a>, while also renewing alarm about the US’s energy imports. “We have had the largest increase in domestic oil production in history because of an approach that recognizes that we cannot over rely on foreign oil,” Harris said at the debate.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the Biden administration did <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24055711/lng-export-pause-biden-liquefied-natural-gas-climate-change">pause approvals</a> of new export terminals for liquefied natural gas, US LNG exports are still poised to double by 2030 — and could rise higher depending on who takes the White House next year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Globally, greenhouse gas emissions are <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24139383/climate-change-peak-greenhouse-gas-emissions-action">on the cusp of leveling</a> off and could soon begin their decline. But the pace of that drop-off — and America’s influence on it — will shape whether or not the world will meet its climate change goals. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the US puts up trade barriers to get ahead, the world is falling behind schedule.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
