<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-10-16T23:50:07+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Anna North</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The new burnout generation]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/life/378065/teen-stress-burnout-teens-productivity-anxiety" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378065</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T18:44:01-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-17T07:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Education" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Family" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story originally appeared in&#160;Kids Today, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&#160;Sign up here for future editions. In high school, Jayden Dial worked on a podcast, planned school events, and made a film. That was on top of doing her homework and applying to college. But sometimes, she still felt like she wasn’t doing enough. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Students take an AP exam at West Potomac High School on May 10, 2011, in Alexandria, VA. | The Washington Post/Contributor via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="The Washington Post/Contributor via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-480886706.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Students take an AP exam at West Potomac High School on May 10, 2011, in Alexandria, VA. | The Washington Post/Contributor via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/family/369020/kids-children-generation-alpha-gen-school" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kids Today</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/kids-today-newsletter-policy-childhood-policy-culture" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In high school, Jayden Dial <a href="https://www.thisteenagelife.org/">worked on a podcast</a>, planned school events, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vh4nleXHqsU">made a film</a>. That was on top of doing her homework and applying to college. But sometimes, she still felt like she wasn’t doing enough.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jayden, now 18, would see kids her age on YouTube talking about their packed routines — “I worked out, I meditated, I read my Bible” — and she’d think, “Oh my God, I need to be so, so productive.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This kind of productivity anxiety is probably familiar to many adults. I, for example, have been known to stress myself out watching reels of parents somehow cleaning their houses while kids play happily in the background.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But according to <a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/research/unpacking-grind-culture-in-american-teens-pressure-burnout-and-the-role-of-social-media">a new report</a> by the nonprofit Common Sense Media and researchers at Harvard and Indiana University, the pressure to live a scheduled, optimized, perfected life has trickled down to teenagers, leading to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/23/well/mind/burnout-depression-symptoms-treatment.html">symptoms of stress and burnout</a> more closely associated with people decades older.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of the 1,545 teens the researchers surveyed, 56 percent felt pressure to have a “game plan” for their future lives, while 53 percent felt pressure to “be exceptional and impressive through their achievements.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The findings challenge the stereotype of young people today as <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/14/lifestyle/boomer-blames-his-generation-for-gen-zs-lazy-work-ethic-spoiled-by-my-generation/">lazy</a> and <a href="https://www.edweek.org/leadership/majority-of-parents-say-kids-are-dishonest-disrespectful-and-lazy/2023/01">entitled</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/369953/skibidi-tweens-gen-alpha-brainrot-ipad-kids">iPad kids</a> who just want to watch videos all day. In fact, researchers found that many teenagers have internalized a drive to succeed at the expense of their mental and physical health: Some reported that they didn’t prioritize self-care practices like getting enough sleep or talking with friends because they weren’t “productive.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And more than a quarter of teens say they’re burned out, a feeling one likened to being “an overused machine in a factory [&#8230;] You&#8217;re just doing the same thing over and over, and you don&#8217;t feel like you really have a purpose.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such statements are disturbing to hear from kids still in high school. The report’s authors believe that their findings could help explain <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/13/health/teen-girls-sadness-suicide-violence.html">high levels of depression</a>, anxiety, and sadness in young people. Rising rates of such mental health problems have often been blamed on <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/372690/instgram-teen-accounts-kid-safety-mental-health">smartphones and social media</a>, but the Common Sense report paints a more complicated picture: Teens exist within a culture obsessed with achievement and success, while the traditional markers of having “made it” (a home, a steady job, a savings account) feel more out of reach every day.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Social media may intensify these obsessions, allowing kids to compare themselves to more “successful” teens (a depressing concept in its own right). But it’s just one part of a larger problem, one with no easy solutions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s needed is “a shift in what’s important,” Jayden said. “There needs to be a bigger emphasis on time to explore.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Teens are already stressed about their future</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The report’s authors started out by studying the effects of technology on teen mental health, said lead author Emily Weinstein, executive director of Harvard’s <a href="https://digitalthriving.gse.harvard.edu/">Center for Digital Thriving</a>, which studies the role of tech in people’s lives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But teenagers told them they needed to widen their lens, to look at everything going on in young people’s lives. The researchers ended up asking a nationally representative sample of kids aged 13–17 about six potential sources of pressure in their lives: the idea of a “game plan,” grades and achievement, appearance, social life, friendship, and activism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The kids came from all over the country and from a range of socioeconomic backgrounds, and the researchers also specifically reached out to Black and LGBTQ+ teens to make sure their experiences were represented. Kids with higher family income tended to feel more pressure around achievement, but there were no consistent differences by race.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens, the researchers found, are more likely to be stressed out about their grades and their career plans than about having friends or looking good. And “this looming sense that you should have a plan for your future, and you should already be working toward it” has been a theme in the team’s research for some time, Weinstein said. She remembers a former teen adviser to the group who worried that she had “joined LinkedIn too late.” She was still in college.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Social media can feed into this pressure. “Before, you just saw things on talk shows about these really amazing, talented, gifted kids. Now, you go on TikTok, you could find 10 of them,” Dial said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But teens told the researchers that the top source of pressure around achievement and future planning was adults in their lives, said Sara Konrath, one of the report’s authors and a professor of philanthropic studies at Indiana University Indianapolis. Parents, teachers, and coaches may be “doing their best to try to help teens, but not really understanding that we&#8217;re kind of pushing the teens to internalize some very unhealthy attitudes and behaviors.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those behaviors include skipping sleep, exercise, or hobbies because they don’t fit into the larger plan. One 11th-grader told the researchers she loves books, but sometimes second-guesses herself because “I just feel unproductive sometimes when I&#8217;m reading.” In interviews, teens repeatedly expressed guilt over taking breaks, Weinstein said, feeling that “if you&#8217;re not performing, if you&#8217;re not striving, if you&#8217;re not doing something productive in some area, that somehow that is almost morally wrong.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such attitudes can lead to burnout, experienced by 27 percent of teens in the study —&nbsp; a state characterized by “emotional exhaustion, cynicism, and a lack of confidence that your effort will make a difference,” the report’s authors write.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Public conversations about burnout typically focus on adults — Anne Helen Petersen’s viral 2019 <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/annehelenpetersen/millennials-burnout-generation-debt-work">BuzzFeed essay</a> “How Millennials Became The Burnout Generation” was about people in their 20s and 30s. But according to the Common Sense report, a lot of teens feel like they’re part of the burnout generation, and they’re experiencing the same <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK279286/">ill effects</a> many adults do, including fatigue, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/23/well/mind/burnout-depression-symptoms-treatment.html">lack of interest</a> in formerly fun activities, and potentially an elevated risk of developing depression.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to providing a clue about what might be driving some of the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/04/23/health/mental-health-crisis-teens.html">troubling trends</a> in youth mental health, the research also offers a counter-narrative about why teens and young adults today aren’t reaching certain milestones — like <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/living-single/201710/teen-dating-and-sex-hit-record-lows-recent-decades">starting to date</a> or <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/parenting/2023/02/21/teens-not-driving/">getting a driver’s license</a> — at the same rate as their elders. “They’re kind of adulting in many other ways,” Konrath said. “Maybe the reason they’re not getting their license is because they’re in school all day and they come home and do five hours of homework.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to help burned-out teens</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though many adults wish kids would put their phones down and go play outside, we are the ones who created <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/2020/5/15/21252544/coronavirus-covid-19-hustle-work-productivity-ambition-loss">hustle culture</a> and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/22536756/covid-pandemic-quarantine-lockdown-productivity-hobbies-work">obsession with productivity</a>, as well as the economic conditions behind them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today’s young people are less optimistic about their economic futures than previous generations, Konrath said — they see what their parents are going through and worry about whether they’re going to be able to <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/375202/kids-politics-election-2024-economy-inflation-climate-change">afford a house one day</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They’re also constantly reminded of how much more unattainable the traditional markers of middle-class life are becoming, starting with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/01/opinion/college-admissions-applications.html">annual headlines</a> about record numbers of students applying to college (which could soon cost <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/05/your-money/paying-for-college/100k-college-cost-vanderbilt.html">$100,000 a year</a>).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s no wonder teenagers feel like they should already be on LinkedIn. “Certain aspects of childhood or teenagehood have been taken away from people my age,” Jayden said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Restoring what’s been taken from them won’t be easy. Self-care behaviors like exercise and spending time with friends do help — kids who engaged in them were less likely to be burned out, the report’s authors found. But “just giving kids another to-do list” is not going to fix the problem, Weinstein said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, kids need grownups to look at potential root causes of pressure and burnout, including a culture of “constant quantification” <a href="https://www.edweek.org/leadership/the-good-and-the-bad-of-using-apps-to-connect-with-parents/2024/04">enabled by apps</a> that allow schools to share every test score and assignment grade immediately with parents, Weinstein said. They also need to consider the world kids are growing up in, from climate change to school shootings. “When you&#8217;re a young person, a lot of times it can feel like the people in power do not have sympathy,” Jayden said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jayden, now a first-year student at Stanford, does have some advice for teens her age and younger who feel like they have to have their lives all figured out. “It’s much better to experience newness and try new things rather than trying to figure out everything,” she said. “You have the rest of your life to be an adult.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What I’m reading</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">USA Today columnist Marla Bautista wrote about <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/opinion/columnist/2024/10/09/hurricane-milton-evacuation-kids-mental-health/75559460007/">evacuating her family</a> ahead of Hurricane Milton, and the toll disasters like this can take on kids. “While the physical destruction receives significant attention,” she wrote, “there is much more damage that you don&#8217;t see, including the mental and academic destruction wreaking havoc in the lives of children.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A UK elementary school is <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/oct/11/children-mud-outdoor-play-nature">encouraging kids to play in mud</a>. Experts say it’s a great idea.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2024/10/10/to-make-children-better-fact-checkers-expose-them-to-more-misinformation-with-oversight/">UC Berkeley researchers studied</a> how kids react to misinformation. Their study is very fun and involves aliens with dark glasses and lies about zebras. They also have advice for exercising kids’ “skepticism muscles.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My little kid has discovered <em><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/truman-jean-reidy/16912104?ean=9781534416642" data-type="link" data-id="https://bookshop.org/p/books/truman-jean-reidy/16912104?ean=9781534416642">Truman</a></em>, a book about a brave tiny turtle (with an important guest appearance by a city bus). My big kid, as befitting the season, is into <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/723873/the-book-of-mysteries-magic-and-the-unexplained-by-tamara-macfarlane/"><em>The Book of Mysteries, Magic, and the Unexplained</em></a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From my inbox</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In lieu of reader emails, today I’m going to share a few perspectives from students that I didn’t get to include in my recent newsletter on <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/375202/kids-politics-election-2024-economy-inflation-climate-change">kids and politics</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I first got interested in politics in 7th grade through my <a href="https://nhd.org/en/">National History Day</a> year-long research projects, an enthusiasm that strengthened when I was in 8th grade during the 2020 election,” Hannah Cho, a high school senior and the national chair of the High School Democrats of America (HSDA), told me in an email. “I still remember watching the inauguration unfold on T.V. during breakfast and being eager to discuss President Biden&#8217;s inaugural address and Amanda Gorman&#8217;s inauguration poem among other events that occurred during the historical day with my history teacher, Mrs. Linck.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rishita Nossam, 16, the HSDA communications director, told me she started to get more interested in politics after seeing posts about Black Lives Matter on social media. Today, the biggest issues for her include gun violence, media safety, civics education, and reproductive rights: “Government should not have a right to interfere in the decisions that women make about their own bodies.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, I’d love to hear what you’re hearing from kids and teens in your life about the pressure to achieve or plan for the future. Are the teens you know experiencing these pressures? And what’s the role of parents and caregivers in helping them navigate all this? Let me know at anna.north@vox.com.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is everyone wearing the Oura Ring?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/378189/oura-ring-4-release-sale-health-sleep-tracker" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378189</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T18:43:52-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-17T07:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Fitness" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sleep tracking sounds like a dream. You get a gadget that tells you how you slept and then gives you tips on sleeping better and — boom — you’re better rested. As a parent of a young child, I know this is not how it would work for me, but I’ve been feeling desperate lately. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An Oura Ring on a peach starburst background." data-caption="The Oura Ring 4 costs $350 and you have to pay an additional $6 monthly membership fee to access all of its features. | Paige Vickers/Vox; Oura" data-portal-copyright="Paige Vickers/Vox; Oura" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Oura_Vox.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The Oura Ring 4 costs $350 and you have to pay an additional $6 monthly membership fee to access all of its features. | Paige Vickers/Vox; Oura</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Sleep tracking sounds like a dream. You get a gadget that tells you how you slept and then gives you tips on sleeping better and — boom — you’re better rested. As a parent of a young child, I know this is not how it would work for me, but I’ve been feeling desperate lately. If I’m sleeping less, then maybe with the help of a wearable, I could simply sleep smarter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s how I got drawn into the promise of the Oura Ring, a $350 device you wear on your finger to track a number of different health metrics, including sleep. You’ve probably <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/life-style/health-fitness/article/what-is-oura-ring-wellness-celebrity-3cnh6lm9j">seen a celebrity wearing one</a> in the tabloids. Mark Zuckerberg <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kerryadolan/2023/09/28/eight-hours-of-sleep-and-no-back-to-back-meetings-how-mark-zuckerberg-organizes-his-days/">wears one to optimize his sleep</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The big problem is that wearables don’t come with any guarantees. This fall, we’ve seen these gadgets gain new abilities like <a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/features/my-oura-ring-helped-me-discover-my-sleep-apnea-heres-what-i-learned">detecting sleep apnea</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/12/24242929/apple-airpods-pro-hearing-aids-fda-authorization">working as hearing aids</a>, making wearables seem more and more like medical marvels. However, research over the years has shown that doctors don’t currently find data from these devices very useful in a clinical setting, and left to their own devices, consumers might feel worse when using a wearable. The positive effects of sleep trackers, in particular, are difficult to nail down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if I just wanted a few data points to direct me toward better habits, surely a little ring couldn’t hurt. After spending a couple of days scouring medical journals in order to make a better decision about what a wearable could do for my sleep, however, I now feel more exhausted than ever. Buying a new gadget won’t fix that for a number of reasons. Nevertheless, if you’re thinking about using a wearable to improve your health, it’s helpful to know where the marketing stops and the proven benefits begin.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Despite what the marketing suggests, very few wearables are FDA approved</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Oura Ring 4, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24268024/oura-ring-4-review-smart-rings-wearables">out this week</a>, uses a variety of lights and sensors to measure your heart rate, respiration rate, blood oxygen, temperature, and movement. For an extra $6 monthly membership fee, you get access to things like detailed sleep analysis, advanced temperature monitoring, and reproductive health insights. The ring doesn’t have a screen; it connects to your phone via Bluetooth so you can see all your health data there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Oura Ring “is not a medical device.” This is the first thing the company’s PR team told me when I reached out to them for this article. In its marketing, however, Oura does bring up the potential health benefits often, and it <a href="https://ouraring.com/medical-advisory-board">promotes its medical advisory board</a> prominently on its website. Jason Russell, Oura’s vice president of consumer software, explained that the company is tapping into a real demand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People want to understand their bodies and live long and healthy lives, but they don’t want another tech device to manage,” Russell said, flagging the discreteness of the Oura Ring.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1052434132.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.276160134743,100,79.447679730513" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Even royalty wear Oura Rings: Prince Harry, Duke of Sussex, was spotted wearing the device on a trip to Melbourne, Australia, with Meghan, Duchess of Sussex, in 2019. | Scott Barbour/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Scott Barbour/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">You can also <a href="https://support.ouraring.com/hc/en-us/articles/19777137314579-Purchase-with-HSA-or-FSA-Funds?_gl=1%2A1s581vb%2A_gcl_aw%2AR0NMLjE3MjkwOTMxNzMuQ2owS0NRand5TDI0QmhDdEFSSXNBTG8wZlNDenAxaG4td1A5OWYtUENHSjMtMVJaWWdrZW9xcUxqeWdPcUFxS1Z1Q0J5TTJ4UlhacUMwd2FBcEkwRUFMd193Y0I.%2A_gcl_dc%2AR0NMLjE3MjkwOTMxNzMuQ2owS0NRand5TDI0QmhDdEFSSXNBTG8wZlNDenAxaG4td1A5OWYtUENHSjMtMVJaWWdrZW9xcUxqeWdPcUFxS1Z1Q0J5TTJ4UlhacUMwd2FBcEkwRUFMd193Y0I.%2A_gcl_au%2ANTc2NTY3MzI0LjE3MjkwMDQ5MDU.%2A_ga%2AMTUwOTM2Mzk1MS4xNzI5MDA0OTA1%2A_ga_QY3EB3Q3FY%2AMTcyOTA4NzgwNi4zLjEuMTcyOTA5MzIwOS4yMy4wLjA.">use your health savings account (HSA) and flexible spending account (FSA) funds</a> to buy an Oura Ring, which is confusing since you’re only supposed to use those <a href="https://www.irs.gov/taxtopics/tc502">for medical and dental expenses</a>. The Oura Ring does not have FDA clearance, although it <a href="https://help.naturalcycles.com/hc/en-us/articles/6778763871645-How-effective-is-using-the-Oura-Ring-with-Natural-Cycles#:~:text=Natural%20Cycles%20received%20FDA%20clearance,the%20Natural%20Cycles%20main%20algorithm.">can be used with the FDA-cleared Natural Cycles app</a> for menstrual cycle tracking. According to some reviewers, it is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/personal-tech/oura-smart-ring-review-12ece82c?mod=rss_Technology">especially useful for women</a> for this very reason. Natural Cycles <a href="https://www.naturalcycles.com/cyclematters/how-effective-is-the-pill#:~:text=Natural%20Cycles%3A%20The%20first%20FDA,98%25%20effective%20with%20perfect%20use">describes itself as</a> “a hormone-free alternative to the pill that is 93% effective with typical use.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This maze of regulations and clearances makes it hard to know if the Oura Ring, which is being marketed <a href="https://ouraring.com/why-oura">as a device that can improve your health</a>, comes with real medical benefits. The same is true for other wearables, like the Apple Watch, which recently <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/9/16/24246150/apple-watch-sleep-apnea-detection-fda-approval">got FDA clearance for detecting sleep apnea</a>. That’s on top of the device <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/9/13/17855006/apple-watch-series-4-ekg-fda-approved-vs-cleared-meaning-safe">being FDA-cleared</a> for detecting irregular heart rhythms and for recording electrocardiograms. (Smartwatches and fitness trackers from Google, Samsung, and Fitbit have similar clearances.) Even Apple AirPods Pro got clearance from the FDA this year for a new feature that turns them into “<a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-authorizes-first-over-counter-hearing-aid-software">the first over-the-counter (OTC) hearing aid software device</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of these devices are FDA approved. There’s a difference between FDA approval, which is a very involved process, and the less rigorous FDA clearance. There’s also a third designation called “de novo classification” reserved for low-risk devices that don’t already exist in the market. (The new hearing aid feature on the AirPods Pro got this designation recently.) The FDA acknowledges that its name gets tossed around in misleading ways, so much so that it has <a href="https://www.fda.gov/consumers/consumer-updates/it-really-fda-approved">a whole explainer on what FDA approval actually means</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So even though I can use this year’s leftover FSA dollars to buy an Oura Ring, the FDA has not put its stamp of approval on the device. Thanks to its partnership with Natural Cycles, the Oura Ring does enjoy a bit of that FDA-cleared glow, but that has nothing to do with the rest of its features. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any case, you’d be forgiven for thinking a device you can buy with <a href="https://www.healthcare.gov/have-job-based-coverage/flexible-spending-accounts/#:~:text=A%20Flexible%20Spending%20Account%20(FSA%2C%20also%20called%20a%20%E2%80%9Cflexible,the%20money%20you%20set%20aside.">funds set aside for health care costs</a> from a company that <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/54129998/en">name-checks the FDA</a> in its press release would lead to health benefits. When it comes to wearables, this isn’t always the case.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What wearables do for our health</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the day, you might not need a stamp of approval from a government agency to know whether a gadget is useful to you. I bought an Apple Watch not because I wanted something to alert me of an irregular heartbeat but because I liked getting notifications on my wrist. It’s easier to glance at a text message on my watch than it is to pull out my phone. The fitness tracking that comes with the watch is a bonus, and I can confidently say I move my body more because my watch <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/1/24/16926350/apple-watch-series-2-fitness-tracker-healthy-notification-behavior">tells me to</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Research suggests that smartwatches and other fitness trackers are best at this. A systematic review covering nearly 200,000 study participants <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/landig/article/PIIS2589-75002200111-X/fulltext">published in the <em>Lancet</em></a> in 2022 found that wearables indeed improved physical activity and helped people lose weight. People who wore fitness trackers walked an extra 1,800 steps a day, on average. But they had little effect on other health markers, including blood pressure and cholesterol. A smaller meta-analysis in the <em>BMJ</em>, a peer-reviewed journal from the British Medical Association, <a href="https://www.bmj.com/content/376/bmj-2021-068047">showed similar conclusions</a>: over 1,200 extra steps a day. Fitness tracking, it seems, leads to better fitness.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sleep tracking is not so clear-cut. Whether it&#8217;s on your wrist, <a href="https://www.withings.com/eu/en/sleep-analyzer?srsltid=AfmBOoomGbVC0bKm0ow--_Sk_OqL7matXVjJ0iBXHfxyTyuIkT-HqQZ5">under your mattress</a>, or wrapped around your finger, a sleep tracker will measure everything from your movement and body temperature to your heart rate and blood oxygen in order to determine how long you’ve slept and how well. The idea here is that by having more details about how you slept, you could link what you did before bed — say, rigorous exercise, drinking, or doomscrolling on your phone — with your quality of sleep. If bad habits lead to bad sleep, you can stop the bad habits.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Oura-SCREEN-copy.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.740101751179,100,78.519796497641" alt="The new Today tab (left) and Vitals tab (right) in the Oura App serve as dashboards to view various data collected by the Ring." title="The new Today tab (left) and Vitals tab (right) in the Oura App serve as dashboards to view various data collected by the Ring." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The new Today tab (left) and Vitals tab (right) in the Oura App serve as dashboards to view various data collected by the Ring. | Oura" data-portal-copyright="Oura" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Many sleep trackers will crunch all that data through an algorithm that spits out a score. (The Oura Ring’s app <a href="https://ouraring.com/blog/sleep-score/">gives you three scores</a>: one for sleep, one for activity during the day, and one for “readiness” which tells you on a scale of 1 to 100 how ready you are for the day.) Experts warn that these scores can be arbitrary, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/29/well/live/sleep-trackers.html#:~:text=Experts%20who%20study%20sleep%20trackers,insomnia%20or%20other%20sleep%20disorders.">if not downright useless</a>. Plus, most trackers can’t directly measure brain activity, which is the standard for diagnosing sleep disorders. Furthermore, obsessing over sleep data, scores, and metrics <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/evidence-based-living/202403/is-your-sleep-tracker-disrupting-your-sleep">can actually increase anxiety and lead to worse sleep</a>, according to a recent study from the American Academy of Sleep Medicine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s possible that some of this data could come in handy in a clinical setting. Newer Apple watches can perform an ECG that’s roughly as good as what you’d get in a doctor’s office, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10757793/">according to one study</a>. The problem is, for now, <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/05/17/wearables-data-clinical-use-ida-sim-andrea-coravos/">it’s not always easy</a> for doctors to get access to the data collected by wearables. This is not to say that doctors aren’t optimistic about a future in which they can access that data. Many doctors <a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/personal-tech/apple-watch-is-becoming-doctors-favorite-medical-device-af3719ec">tell their patients to buy wearables</a> and use them to help manage disease, especially heart-related issues that devices like the Apple Watch are designed to detect.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Medical device or not, all wearables come with benefits and drawbacks, largely depending on how you use them. The Oura Ring rabbit hole I fell into left me feeling more confident about how I was using the one wearable I own, my Apple Watch. It also talked me out of buying an Oura Ring.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, I haven’t tried the new Oura Ring, and for now, I’m holding off. Even though I do have some FSA funds to spend before the end of the year, I think the sleep-tracking function would make me anxious in the long run.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this phase of my life, sleeping smarter isn’t exactly an option. I simply need more hours in the day, and that gadget has not been invented yet.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here</a></em></strong><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The $1.3 trillion question: Who created bitcoin?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/378108/bitcoin-satoshi-nakamoto-peter-todd-money-electric" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378108</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T19:14:39-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-17T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Bitcoin" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Business &amp; Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Crypto" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite what a new HBO documentary suggests, the identity of one of the richest people in the world is still unknown. By now, the story is so famous that it’s taken on the aura of a creation myth: one day in early 2009, Satoshi Nakamoto, the pseudonym used by the inventor of bitcoin, released the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Close-up of a statue in Budapest, Hungary, honoring the anonymous founder of bitcoin, Satoshi Nakamoto" data-caption="In 2009, someone going by the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto created bitcoin — the world’s first cryptocurrency. | Getty Images/Janos Kummer" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/Janos Kummer" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1341873866.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>In 2009, someone going by the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto created bitcoin — the world’s first cryptocurrency. | Getty Images/Janos Kummer</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite what a new HBO documentary suggests, the identity of one of the richest people in the world is still unknown.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By now, the story is so famous that it’s taken on the aura of a creation myth: one day in early 2009, Satoshi Nakamoto, the pseudonym used by the inventor of bitcoin, released the world’s first cryptocurrency. Two years later, Nakamoto vanished seemingly forever. Since then, <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/7-people-who-could-be-bitcoin-creator-satoshi-nakamoto">countless</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/1b12azf/satoshi_nakamoto_was_john_nash_the_inventor_of/">theories</a> on who the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/craig-wright-perjury-bitcoin-trial">real Nakamoto</a> is have been advanced, with no single candidate coming out on top.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether Nakamoto’s anonymity is merely an entertaining mystery, a necessity for privacy, or a worrisome concern depends on who you ask. For filmmaker Cullen Hoback, whose documentary <em>Money Electric: The Bitcoin Mystery</em> premiered on HBO last week, finding the mysterious bitcoin founder is a matter of public interest — and Hoback believes he has unmasked him as a 39-year-old Canadian bitcoin developer named Peter Todd. Since the film’s release, Todd and other prominent voices in the community have dismissed Hoback’s arguments. According to them, Nakamoto remains an enigma. Many bitcoin enthusiasts prefer it that way.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s obvious why the search has endured over the past 15 years. Bitcoin is far and away the most popular digital currency in the world, with a market cap of about $1.3 trillion at the time of writing. (For comparison, the second biggest, ethereum, has a market cap of $312 million.) For those who believe a decentralized alternative to government-issued currencies — like the US dollar — is crucial to protect individual privacy and freedom, Nakamoto is akin to Prometheus bringing the gift of fire from the gods.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s this mind-boggling possibility: if <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/how-much-bitcoin-does-satoshi-nakamoto-own-number-will-blow-your-mind">reports</a> that Nakamoto might hold as much as 1.1 million bitcoins are true, they could be sitting on a fortune of over $70 billion, making them one of the 25 wealthiest individuals on Earth, according to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/real-time-billionaires/#495d947a3d78">Forbes’ real-time billionaires ranking</a>. But Nakamoto doesn’t seem to have spent any of it — at least, not anything in their confirmed bitcoin wallets. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What does it mean for the rest of us that such an enormous treasure chest remains in the hands of an unknown entity, whose true aims and intentions can’t be determined? Who benefits if Nakamoto remains in the shadows — and who benefits if they’re revealed?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What we know about the bitcoin creator</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The internet user Satoshi Nakamoto first appeared in 2008, when they published a paper to a cryptographic technology mailing list laying out a system that they had dubbed bitcoin. It would function as a form of digital cash that people could use to send money back and forth without involving any kind of bank. In other words, one could reliably make and receive payments completely anonymously.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There was a clear ideological aim: in Nakamoto’s view, the ability to keep your financial record out of the surveillance and reach of powerful authorities, whether it’s large private banks or the government, is an important personal freedom. Such institutions, after all, aren’t infallible. In one illuminating forum post in 2009, <a href="https://p2pfoundation.ning.com/forum/topics/bitcoin-open-source">Nakamoto wrote</a> that “the root problem with conventional currency” was “trust.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Banks must be trusted to hold our money and transfer it electronically, but they lend it out in waves of credit bubbles with barely a fraction in reserve,” they continued. “We have to trust them with our privacy, trust them not to let identity thieves drain our accounts.” When Nakamoto created the very first block that would become the bitcoin blockchain, they included a message <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/the-genesis-block:-the-first-bitcoin-block">referencing a headline</a> in the British newspaper The Times <a href="https://www.thetimes.com/article/chancellor-alistair-darling-on-brink-of-second-bailout-for-banks-n9l382mn62h">that day</a>: “Chancellor on brink of second bailout for banks.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The top suspects, and why Nakamoto’s identity is still up for debate</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nakamoto’s writings indicate that they’re most likely someone with a strong understanding of economics, computer science, and modern cryptography — which involves methods and technologies for keeping information secure, like <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22226618/what-is-signal-whatsapp-telegram-download-encrypted-messaging">encrypting a message</a> that can only be unlocked with a special key. Unsurprisingly, the commonly advanced candidates for who Nakamoto could be are self-identified “cypherpunks” — a community of mainly computer scientists who advocate for using cryptography to protect digital privacy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to Hoback, director of <em>Money Electric</em>, Peter Todd fits the bill. Todd is a libertarian pro-privacy advocate who, among other things, is a <a href="https://x.com/peterktodd/status/1646601411377999872">huge</a> <a href="https://x.com/peterktodd/status/1766100934503936511">proponent</a> <a href="https://x.com/peterktodd/status/1841832099923230804">of using cash</a> because it’s harder for governments and banks to track your spending. As a teenager, he was already communicating with older, respected cypherpunks and seemed unusually knowledgeable about bitcoin despite his youth. Todd would have been 23 years old when the bitcoin white paper was published.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoback builds his case primarily on the fact that Todd joined the message board Bitcointalk.org in 2010 right before Nakamoto stopped posting. But the crux of Hoback’s argument hinges on an interaction between Todd and Nakamoto on Bitcointalk. Nakamoto had <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=2181.msg28729#msg28729">posted something technical</a> about how bitcoin transactions work; about an hour and a half later, Todd <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=2181.msg28739#msg28739">replied</a> with a small disagreement. Hoback contends that the reply actually reads more like someone finishing their previous thought — that Todd had signed into the wrong account to make an addendum to the original Nakamoto post. In the film, he also points to a chat log in which Todd calls himself a foremost authority on sacrificing bitcoin, which Hoback connects to the fact that Nakamoto hasn’t done anything with their coins in all these years (at least, that we know of).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s an intriguing interpretation, but not exactly a smoking gun.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoback, both in interviews and within <em>Money Electric</em>, portrays Todd as someone who enjoys playing games over whether he could be the bitcoin founder, laughing on camera as the filmmaker explains why he believes Todd is Nakamoto — at one point saying with a smirking grin, “Well, yeah. I’m Satoshi Nakamoto.” On X, though, Todd has <a href="https://x.com/peterktodd/status/1843789750983110697">firmly denied</a> that he’s Nakamoto. In an email to Vox, Hoback wrote that Todd stopped speaking to him after filming this scene.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other main person of interest in <em>Money Electric</em> is Adam Back, a British cypherpunk in his 50s whose work toward a functional digital currency was cited in Nakamoto’s original bitcoin paper. One reason Hoback finds Back suspicious is that he became more active in the bitcoin world — specifically concerned with how to make transactions <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/27-year-old-codebreaker-busted-myth-bitcoins-anonymity/">completely anonymous</a> — right after <a href="https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=175996.msg1832533#msg1832533">speculation emerged</a> that Nakamoto controlled over 1 million bitcoins, more than previously thought. Unlike Todd, Back has stridently distanced himself from even joking suggestions that he could be Nakamoto.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other commonly floated contenders include prominent cypherpunk figures such as Hal Finney, who died in 2014 and was the recipient of the first test bitcoin transaction that Nakamoto sent, and <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/nick-szabo-bitcoin-hbo-satoshi-nakamoto">Nick Szabo</a>, who came up with the concept of “smart contracts,” a crucial function of many blockchains today. One wild suggestion claims that the Japanese etymology behind Satoshi Nakamoto can roughly translate to “<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/learn/who-is-satoshi-nakamoto/">central intelligence</a>,” a sign that bitcoin was in fact invented by the CIA as some sort of trap. Another conspiracy theory — practically a meme at this point — posits that Tesla and SpaceX billionaire Elon Musk is the real Nakamoto. (He <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2017/11/28/elon-musk-denies-he-is-bitcoin-creator-satoshi-nakamoto.html">denies</a> it.)</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1341873890.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.729780130345,100,78.540439739309" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A statue honoring the anonymous Satoshi Nakamoto, the creator of bitcoin, in Budapest, Hungary." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">It isn’t clear whether Nakamoto is still alive, or even whether they’re one person rather than a group of people working together. Early this year, an unknown person <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-community-bitcoin-transfer-satoshi-genesis-block">sent 26.9 bitcoins</a> (worth approximately $1.8 million today) to Nakamoto’s dormant wallet, firing up fresh excitement over where Nakamoto is and what they might be doing. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How do you track down a mystery like Nakamoto? Should you even try?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since 2011, Nakamoto hasn’t emailed or posted anywhere under their username. They also haven’t used the crypto wallets associated with that name.<strong> </strong>But even if someone is determined to remain in the shadows, and has left no obvious evidence giving them away, there are bound to be some breadcrumbs. Much of the theorizing around Nakamoto depends on analyzing their style of coding and writing. Hoback, at one point in the film, nods to the fact that <a href="https://mmalmi.github.io/satoshi/#email-24">Nakamoto</a> and <a href="https://x.com/peterktodd/status/1644557915703869442">Todd</a> both used slurs that could <a href="https://x.com/CullenHoback/status/1843893419443359867">indicate immaturity</a>. Another commonly noted marker is that Nakamoto often used British English spelling (such as “favour”), and Todd is Canadian.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But other <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/class/archive/cs/cs224n/cs224n.1184/reports/6858026.pdf">linguistic comparisons</a> of <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/stylometric-analysis-satoshi-nakamoto-294926cdf995">commonly used</a> <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2013/12/05/who-is-the-real-satoshi-nakamoto-one-researcher-may-have-found-the-answer/?guccounter=1">words and phrases</a> have been made that inconclusively point to other candidates. On the forum, Nakamoto often uses a double space at the start of a sentence, while Todd does not. Both Back and Todd pepper in dashes to break up clauses in a single sentence — Nakamoto doesn’t. Could the stylistic differences be a cunning, intentional misdirection? No one knows. Ultimately, none of these tics add up to definitive proof.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many in the bitcoin world conjecture that Nakamoto disappeared because WikiLeaks — the site where Julian Assange published many leaked documents — appeared poised to start accepting <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/rogerhuang/2019/04/26/how-bitcoin-and-wikileaks-saved-each-other/">donations in bitcoin</a>, which might lead to more attention on Nakamoto. In one of their <a href="http://gavinandresen.ninja/eleven-years-ago-today">last known communications</a>, Nakamoto wrote to bitcoin developer Gavin Andresen, “I wish you wouldn’t keep talking about me as a mysterious shadowy figure, the press just turns that into a pirate currency angle.” In the last known email, sent in April 2011, Nakamoto claimed they were no longer involved with bitcoin.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s clear that Nakamoto never intend to out themselves — and, indeed, they seem to argue that there’s no point. Bitcoin is now out of their hands. So how much does their identity matter?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoback argues that it matters a lot due to how important bitcoin has become. “Bitcoin is already being baked into our financial system,” he told Vox, referring to its acceptance as <a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/09/07/1034838909/bitcoin-el-salvador-legal-tender-official-currency-cryptocurrency">legal tender</a> in some countries and the fact that it could now be included in <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/daily-labor-report/bitcoin-funds-set-new-precedent-for-crypto-401k-ira-investing">401(k)s</a>. Nakamoto potentially controls a significant portion of the total limited supply of bitcoin; if they one day decided to come forward and start moving (and spending) the coins in their possession, such an enormous sell-off could be destabilizing for the cryptocurrency. If they spend their riches, there’s also arguably a public interest in knowing where so much money is going, and whether it has any political impact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Acknowledging the possibility that Nakamoto could be multiple people, Hoback continued, “This group is making themselves super rich while saying no one should look into Satoshi. Isn’t that a little suspicious?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you believe that holding the powerful to account is important, then Nakamoto’s insistence on anonymity stands against the transparency that such accountability requires. It’s no secret that many of the world’s richest people have historically cleaved to remaining as private as possible, using <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/2024/3/13/24086102/billionaires-wealthy-tax-avoidance-loopholes">elaborate financial structures</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2023/1/4/23413342/us-tax-havens-billionaires-wealthy">tax havens</a> to avoid scrutiny of <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23604105/philanthropy-mackenzie-scott-elon-musk-billionaires-charity">what their money is funding</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then again, there’s no proof that Nakamoto has spent any of their fortune. Their known bitcoin hoard is a rough value of net worth, not yet used for anything — and we know this because all bitcoin transactions are part of a public ledger. If they started cashing in their bitcoin stockpile, that could make it easier for people to <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/untraceable-bitcoin-is-a-myth-11623860828">find their real-life identity</a>, which is an incentive for Nakamoto to leave that stash untouched. (It is curious, though, that in late September about <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/satoshi-era-wallets-move-16m-075536741.html?guccounter=1">$13 million worth of bitcoin</a> mined in the very early days of the cryptocurrency suddenly moved.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps there’s a better question than whether it matters who Nakamoto is: How important is it that the inventor of bitcoin remains a mystery?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From the perspective of the cypherpunks, it’s crucial. There’s a financial motivation — the reveal of Nakamoto’s real identity could tank the price of bitcoin. But Nakamoto’s lasting anonymity is also an ideological resistance to government authority in an increasingly surveilled digital world. Many <a href="https://x.com/adam3us/status/1842503179130298492">key</a> <a href="https://x.com/lopp/status/1753475690174058979">figures</a> in the bitcoin community unequivocally express a desire for Nakamoto’s identity to stay a secret – according to Hoback, Todd seemed displeased that people had found Nakamoto’s million-plus bitcoin stash, and told him to leave Nakamoto alone. There’s also the potential danger someone could be in if others think they’re Nakamoto. In a comment to the <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/tech/annals-of-technology/has-bitcoins-elusive-creator-finally-been-unmasked">New Yorker</a>, Todd told the publication that Hoback had put his safety at risk by accusing him of being a multi-billionaire, and that he would soon be doing “some unplanned travel.” (He has not responded to an email from Vox.) Todd isn’t wrong that prior attempts to unmask Nakamoto have disturbed people’s personal lives — take the case of Dorian Satoshi Nakamoto, a former engineer and programmer in California who was the subject of a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/2014/03/14/face-behind-bitcoin-247957.html">Newsweek report</a> claiming he was the bitcoin God. Dorian Nakamoto has categorically denied even knowing what cryptocurrencies are, and has said the accusation and public scrutiny caused a “great deal of confusion and stress” for him and his family. In response, Hoback told Vox that other people long suspected of being Nakamoto — like Nick Szabo and Adam Back — are fine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Toward the end of the <em>Money Electric</em>, Todd says that the hunt for bitcoin’s Nakamoto is yet another example of “journalists really missing the point.” The point, he elaborates, is “to make bitcoin the global currency.” But if that came to fruition — and it <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-price-ultimate-700k-portfolio-allocation">isn’t close to becoming reality</a> yet — then ironically, Hoback’s argument for hunting down the bitcoin mastermind would only become more compelling to both the general public and almost certainly to governments around the world. The surest way to protect Nakamoto’s anonymity seems to be for bitcoin to not become a widespread alternative threatening government-issued currencies — to not become too important.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The strange case that the Supreme Court keeps refusing to decide]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/378058/supreme-court-hamm-smith-death-penalty-eighth-amendment" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378058</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T18:43:33-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-17T06:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For more than a year, Joseph Clifton Smith, a man who says he is intellectually disabled, has sat on death row, waiting to find out if the Supreme Court will greenlight his execution. Smith’s case, known as Hamm v. Smith, first arrived on the Court’s doorstep in August 2023. Since then, the justices have met [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A pair of tattooed brown-skinned hands are held out through the bars of a cell door, with a person in a white shirt visible down the hallway." data-caption="A prisoner’s hands inside a cell at Angola prison in Louisiana. | Giles Clarke/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Giles Clarke/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-894670834.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A prisoner’s hands inside a cell at Angola prison in Louisiana. | Giles Clarke/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For more than a year, Joseph Clifton Smith, a man who says he is intellectually disabled, has sat on death row, waiting to find out if the Supreme Court will greenlight his execution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Smith’s case, known as <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/hamm-v-smith-3/"><em>Hamm v. Smith</em></a>, first arrived on the Court’s doorstep in August 2023. Since then, the justices have met more than two dozen times to decide what to do about the case, and each time they’ve put the decision off until a future meeting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No one outside of the Court can know for sure why the justices keep delaying, but if you follow the Court’s Eighth Amendment cases closely, it’s easy to see how the <em>Hamm</em> case could open up all kinds of internal rifts among the justices.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Eighth Amendment, which has a vague ban on “<a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-8/">cruel and unusual punishments</a>,” is at the center of the <em>Hamm </em>case because, for decades, the Court has held this amendment forbids executions of<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/00-8452.ZO.html">intellectually disabled</a> offenders (and offenders who <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/543/551/">commit a crime while they are juveniles</a>). The idea is that both groups have diminished mental capacity, at least as compared to non-disabled adults, and thus bear less moral responsibility even for homicide crimes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That idea, however, has long been contested by the Court’s various ideological factions, and the <em>Hamm</em> case potentially reopens up all of the Court’s issues with the amendment at once. Indeed, in the worst-case scenario for criminal defendants, the justices could potentially overrule more than 60 years of precedents protecting against excessive punishments.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This Supreme Court’s ongoing battles over the Eighth Amendment, briefly explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In two 2000s decisions, <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/00-8452.ZO.html"><em>Atkins v. Virginia</em></a> (2002) and <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/543/551/"><em>Roper v. Simmons</em></a> (2005), a coalition of Democratic and moderate Republican justices handed down decisions that barred youths and people who are intellectually disabled from being executed. Those majority decisions came down over bitter dissents from the Court’s right flank — the same right flank that has since <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">gained a supermajority on the Supreme Court</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At least some of the current Court’s Republicans seem eager to use their newfound supermajority to blow up those two cases (and pretty much everything the Court has said about the Eighth Amendment in the last six or seven decades). So it’s possible that the Court is fighting over what to do with the <em>Hamm</em> case because many of the justices want a wholesale revolution in Eighth Amendment law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beginning in the mid-20th century, the Supreme Court maintained that the Eighth Amendment “must draw its meaning from the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/12/30/22187578/death-penalty-united-states-executions-decline-gregg-georgia-bucklew-precythe">evolving standards of decency that mark the progress of a maturing society</a>.” Thus, as a particular method of punishment grew less common, the Court was increasingly likely to declare it cruel and unusual in violation of the Constitution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At least some members of the Court’s Republican majority, however, have suggested that this “evolving standards of decency” framework should be abandoned. In <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/18pdf/17-8151_1qm2.pdf"><em>Bucklew v. Precythe</em></a> (2019), the Court considered whether states could use execution methods that risked causing the dying inmate a great deal of pain. Justice Neil Gorsuch’s majority opinion, which held that potentially painful methods of execution are allowed, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/12/30/22187578/death-penalty-united-states-executions-decline-gregg-georgia-bucklew-precythe">seems to exist in a completely different universe</a> than the Court’s Eighth Amendment cases that look to evolving standards.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the Court’s earlier opinions ask whether a particular form of punishment has fallen out of favor <em>today</em>, Gorsuch asked whether a method of punishment was out of favor <em>at the time of the founding</em>. Though his opinion does list some methods of execution, such as “disemboweling” and “burning alive” that violate the Eighth Amendment, Gorsuch wrote that these methods are unconstitutional because “by the time of the founding, these methods had long fallen out of use and so had become ‘unusual.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What makes <em>Bucklew</em> confusing, however, is that it didn’t explicitly overrule any of the previous decisions applying the evolving standards framework. So it’s unclear whether all five of the justices who joined that opinion share a desire to blow up more than a half-century of law, or if the justices who joined the <em>Bucklew </em>majority simply failed to rein in an overly ambitious opinion by Gorsuch, the Court’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/22431044/neil-gorsuch-nihilism-supreme-court-voting-rights-lgbt-housing-obamacare-constitution">most intellectually</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/27/23184848/supreme-court-kennedy-bremerton-school-football-coach-prayer-neil-gorsuch">sloppy justice</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any event, <em>Hamm</em> opens up at least two major potential divides within the Court. Smith says he is intellectually disabled; the state of Alabama wants to execute him anyway. So the case perfectly tees up a challenge to <em>Atkins</em> if a majority of the justices want to go there. Meanwhile, <em>Bucklew</em> looms like a vulture over any cruel and unusual punishment case heard by the Court, as it suggests that the Republican justices may hit the reset button on all of its Eighth Amendment precedents at any time.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So what is the specific legal issue in <em>Hamm</em>?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Court receives thousands of petitions every year asking it to hear a particular appeal, and it typically <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/supreme-court-procedure/#:~:text=In%20most%20circumstances%2C%20the%20Supreme,argument%20in%20only%20about%2080.">only grants several dozen of these petitions</a>. The vast majority of these cases are nominally discussed at one of the justices’ regular conferences, then promptly denied.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent years, the Court often discusses a case in two different conferences before agreeing to hear it — for this reason, I and other Supreme Court reporters often watch the <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/petitions-were-watching/">list of cases the Court “relisted”</a> for a second conference to identify cases the justices are more likely to hear. Occasionally, a case may be relisted for several conferences in a row. But this is rare, and typically is a sign either that the justices are negotiating over which issues they wish to decide in a particular case — or, more often, that a justice is dissenting from the Court’s decision not to hear a case and the “relists” are really just buying that justice time to draft an opinion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Hamm</em>, however, has now been relisted in every single conference since the justices first discussed it on October 27, 2023. That is, to say the least, highly unusual. And it suggests that some particularly bitter internal negotiations are ongoing. If someone were dissenting from the Court’s decision to turn the case away, they likely would have released that dissent last July, because the justices typically try to resolve loose ends before they go on their summer vacation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Hamm </em>involves a question that would inevitably arise once the Court decided <em>Atkins</em> — though it is unconstitutional to execute intellectually disabled offenders, there will always be some offenders who are on the borderline of what mental health professionals consider an intellectual disability. The specific question before the Court is what to do with these borderline cases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a general rule, someone must have an IQ of 70 or below to be considered intellectually disabled. But IQ tests aren’t particularly precise — as the Supreme Court acknowledged in <a href="https://casetext.com/case/moore-v-texas-12"><em>Moore v. Texas</em></a> (2017), the IQ of someone who scores 74 on a particular IQ test falls within “a range of 69 to 79.” So, if courts read IQ tests as if they can identify an offender’s IQ score exactly, an intellectually disabled person could be executed due to something as arbitrary as a measurement error.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Accordingly, the Court held in <a href="https://casetext.com/case/hall-v-florida-7#p723"><em>Hall v. Florida</em></a> (2014) that a capital offender with an IQ score slightly above 70 must be given “the opportunity to present evidence of his intellectual disability, including deficits in adaptive functioning over his lifetime.” That is, such an offender must be allowed to present additional evidence beyond their IQ score to show that they are, in fact, intellectually disabled.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Hamm</em> is such a case. Smith took five different IQ tests, four of which showed him with an IQ in the low to mid-70s. Accordingly, two lower courts looked at additional evidence of his disability, determined he is, in fact, intellectually disabled, and ruled that he must receive a sentence other than death.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In asking to execute Smith, in other words, Alabama is asking, among other things, that the Supreme Court overrule <em>Moore</em> and <em>Hall</em>, both cases that were handed down before former President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/9/20962980/trump-supreme-court-federal-judges">remade the Court in the Federalist Society’s image</a>. If the Court agrees, that alone would be a very significant legal development, both because it could allow intellectually disabled inmates to be executed due to a testing error, and because it would be a severe blow to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/5/18/22440256/brett-kavanaugh-supreme-court-edwards-vannoy-abortion-criminal-justice-constitution-stare-decisis">stare decisis</a> — the idea that judicial precedents shouldn’t be tossed out simply because the members of a court change.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, this Court’s Republican majority has shown little regard for stare decisis, at least in cases that divide along partisan lines. Since Justice Amy Coney Barrett’s confirmation gave the Republican Party a supermajority on the Supreme Court in late 2020, the Court has <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">behaved as if it was going down a checklist</a>, overruling liberal victories such as the cases establishing a constitutional right to abortion or the line of cases permitting affirmative action in limited circumstances, and replacing them with whatever outcome the GOP prefers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, while this process has been painful for Democrats and <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/supreme-court/">toxic for the Court’s approval rating</a>, it hasn’t been comprehensive — occasionally, one or more of the Republican justices signal that they will allow a previous liberal victory to remain in effect. Concurring in the Court’s decision to overrule <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, for example, Justice Brett Kavanaugh identified the Court’s past decisions <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/19-1392_6j37.pdf">protecting a right to contraception, as well as the right to marry a person of your own choosing</a>, as cases he did not intend to overrule.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of which is a long way of saying that there’s no good way to know if <em>Atkins</em> or <em>Roper</em> is on the Court’s checklist of past liberal decisions to be overruled. These justices’ approaches to specific cases are often idiosyncratic, unpredictable, and unbound by preexisting law — just look at the Republican justices’ recent decision holding that Trump was <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">allowed to commit many crimes while he was in office</a>. The question of whether <em>Atkins</em> survives or falls will turn on whether there are five justices who want intellectually disabled people to be executed, and nothing else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact <em>Hamm</em> has been relisted so many times suggests, at the very least, that there is a vocal faction within the Supreme Court that wants to use this case to aggressively reshape the law.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What can be made of <em>Bucklew</em>?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other uncertainty looming over <em>Hamm</em> is the <em>Bucklew</em> decision, which didn’t so much overrule the Court’s last six decades of Eighth Amendment precedents as pretend that they didn’t exist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Bucklew</em> involved a death row inmate who claimed that the Eighth Amendment would not allow him to be executed using Missouri’s lethal injection protocol — he said he had an unusual medical condition that would cause him to experience extraordinary pain before his death. So the question was whether the Constitution allows a state to execute an inmate in a manner that may amount to torture.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gorsuch’s opinion denying relief to this inmate reads like the Court’s “evolving standards of decency” framework never existed. This phrase appears nowhere in Gorsuch’s opinion, and the only citation to <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/356/86/"><em>Trop v. Dulles</em></a> (1958), the first Supreme Court case to use that phrase, appears in Justice Stephen Breyer’s dissent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rather than follow longstanding law, Gorsuch asked whether capital offenders could be subjected to similar pain “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/18pdf/17-8151_1qm2.pdf">at the time of the framing</a>.” This is the Eighth Amendment rule long favored by the Court’s rightmost flank, including in Justice Antonin Scalia’s dissenting opinion in <em>Atkins</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scalia’s <em>Atkins</em> dissent, moreover, doesn’t simply disagree with the Court’s past decisions. It lays out many examples of how the law would change — and how much easier it would be to subject even minor criminal offenders to outlandish punishments — under a framework that looks to how things worked in the 1790s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For starters, Scalia argues that <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/00-8452.ZD1.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">only “severely or profoundly” intellectually disabled people</a> enjoy some protection against execution (he argues these individuals were often “committed to civil confinement or made wards of the State” rather than being criminally punished). One of the sources Scalia cites suggests that only people with an IQ of 25 or below enjoy any constitutional protection.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More significantly, Scalia also argues that the Eighth Amendment only forbids “always-and-everywhere ‘cruel’ punishments, such as the rack and the thumbscrew,” and that it does not prohibit the government from imposing excessive punishments for minor crimes. Under Scalia’s framework, if the death penalty can constitutionally be applied to murderers (and he believes it can) then it can also be applied to shoplifters. If a rapist can be sentenced to life in prison, so too can a jaywalker.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gorsuch’s <em>Bucklew</em> opinion elaborates on the sort of punishments that, under this <a href="https://www.vox.com/21497317/originalism-amy-coney-barrett-constitution-supreme-court">originalist</a> framework, are prohibited by the Eighth Amendment. He lists “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/18pdf/17-8151_1qm2.pdf">dragging the prisoner to the place of execution, disemboweling, quartering, public dissection, and burning alive</a>” as examples.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So there is a faction within the Supreme Court that would drastically shrink Americans’ constitutional protections against cruel and unusual punishment. This faction would allow more people to be executed. They would apparently eliminate any concern that punishments must be proportionate to the crime. And the kinds of punishments they do offer up as examples of impermissible sanctions are the kinds of things normally depicted in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uFFvI0IQpt8">torture scenes from movies set in the Middle Ages</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Will five justices go there? It’s impossible to know. But that a total of five justices joined Gorsuch’s opinion in <em>Bucklew</em> suggests this faction could very well prevail — if and when the Court decides to take up <em>Hamm</em>.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Democrats’ pro-union strategy has been a bust]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378025/trump-harris-2024-election-polls-union-voters" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378025</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T18:42:51-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-17T06:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Labor" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Joe Biden took office, the Democratic Party had been bleeding support among working-class voters for decades.&#160; At mid-century, America’s two parties were cleaved by class, with educated professionals backing the GOP and blue-collar workers voting Democratic. But starting in the 1960s, this class divide began narrowing gradually, as white voters with college diplomas drifted [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris onstage flanked by American flags and in front of a large Local U.A.W. 900 sign." data-caption="Kamala Harris appears at a campaign rally at United Auto Workers Local 900 on August 8, 2024, in Wayne, Michigan. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2165926023.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Kamala Harris appears at a campaign rally at United Auto Workers Local 900 on August 8, 2024, in Wayne, Michigan. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When Joe Biden took office, the Democratic Party had been bleeding support among working-class voters for decades.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At mid-century, America’s two parties were <a href="http://piketty.pse.ens.fr/files/Piketty2018.pdf">cleaved by class</a>, with educated professionals backing the GOP and blue-collar workers voting Democratic. But starting in the 1960s, this class divide began narrowing gradually, as white voters with college diplomas drifted left while those without them shifted right, in a process political analysts have dubbed “<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2022/10/education-polarization-diploma-divide-democratic-party-working-class.html">education polarization</a>.” By 2004, college graduates were more Democratic than working-class voters. And Donald Trump’s conquest of the GOP accelerated this realignment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2016, for the first time since at least 1948 when the American National Election Studies (ANES) survey began collecting data, white voters in the top 5 percent of America’s income distribution voted for Democrats at a higher rate than those in the bottom two-thirds of the income distribution. This same pattern of support repeated in 2020, according to <a href="https://x.com/thomasjwood/status/1375231548237213699">an analysis</a> from Ohio State political scientist Tom Wood. In the latter election, Democrats also lost ground with nonwhite voters without college degrees, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/hzqbc0gambbp7fidn3wld/wh2020_public_release_crosstabs.xlsx?rlkey=8s3u9u0o64yczmt77kya2ckx1&amp;e=2&amp;dl=0">according to Catalist</a>, a Democratic data firm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rightward drift of America’s working class disconcerted progressives, who generated a variety of ideas for reversing it. But one of their <a href="https://jacobin.com/2016/06/white-working-class-new-deal-racism-reagan-democrats/">primary</a> <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/archive/right-to-work-laws-are-killing-democrats-at-the-ballot-box/">prescriptions</a> could be <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/01/democrats-paid-a-huge-price-for-letting-unions-die.html">summarized</a> in a single word: unions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, the erosion of Democrats’ working-class support had coincided with the collapse of organized labor in the United States. There were <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2022/10/education-polarization-diploma-divide-democratic-party-working-class.html">many reasons</a> to think the latter had caused the former.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, to prevent Democrats’ working-class support from diminishing further, the thinking went, the party needed to deliver for existing trade unions, whose demands Bill Clinton and Barack Obama had <a href="https://www.epi.org/blog/nafta-twenty-years-disaster/">sometimes</a> <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/obama-passes-teachers-testbarely/story?id=14003658">defied</a>. Meanwhile, to lay the seeds for a broader realignment of working-class voters, Democrats needed to make it easier for workers to organize by <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/22307891/democrats-unions-pro-act-policy-feedback">reforming federal labor laws</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration appears to have embraced this analysis. In his presidency’s first major piece of legislation, Biden <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2022/12/08/biden-teamster-federal-bailout-pension-fund/10855066002/">bailed out</a> the Teamsters’ pension funds, effectively transferring $36 billion to 350,000 of the union’s members. The president also appointed a <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/bidens-nlrb-restoring-rights/">staunchly pro-union federal labor board</a>, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/04/06/politics/biden-amazon-union-staten-island/index.html">encouraged union organizing</a> at Amazon, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/biden-makes-history-striking-auto-workers-picket-line-rcna117348">walked a picket line</a> with the United Auto Workers, and aligned Democratic <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/4/24087919/biden-tariff-chinese-ev-byd-battery-detroit">trade</a> and <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/the-strange-death-of-education-reform">education policy</a> with the AFL-CIO’s preferences. And although he failed to enact major changes to federal labor regulations, that was not for want of trying. In the estimation of labor <a href="https://www.govexec.com/management/2024/05/bidens-labor-report-card-historian-gives-union-joe-higher-grade-any-president-fdr/397002/">historian Erik Loomis,</a> Biden has been the most pro-union president since Franklin Delano Roosevelt.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the political return on Democrats’ investment in organized labor has been disappointing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last month, the Teamsters declined to make a presidential endorsement, after an internal survey found <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/18/teamsters-no-endorsement-2024-election-00179900">60 percent</a> of its membership backed Trump over Kamala Harris. In early October, the International Association of Fire Fighters <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4914399-firefighters-union-iaff-endorsement-trump-harris-race/">also announced</a> that they would not be making a presidential endorsement, despite backing Biden four years earlier.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These high-profile snubs — both driven by rank-and-file opposition to the Democratic nominee — may reflect a broader political trend. According to a <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/30/union-voters-decide-presidential-election-pro-worker-policies">report</a> from the Center for American Progress, between 2012 and 2016, the Democratic presidential nominee’s share of union voters fell from 66 to 53 percent. Four years ago, Biden erased roughly half of that gap, claiming 60 percent of the union vote. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But contemporary polling indicates that Democrats have lost ground with unionized voters since then. In fact, according to an <a href="https://www.mediaite.com/tv/cnns-harry-enten-says-kamala-harris-headed-for-worst-democratic-performance-in-a-generation-among-union-voters/">aggregation from CNN’s Harry Enten</a>, Kamala Harris is on track to perform even worse with union households than Hillary Clinton did in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some on the left have a simple explanation for why a historically pro-union presidency hasn’t bought the Democrats many union votes: Kamala Harris is not Joe Biden, and she <a href="https://x.com/matthewstoller/status/1841940145882194018">lacks his credibility on labor issues</a>. This theory is unsatisfying because Biden’s numbers with union voters early this year were roughly as bad as Harris’s are today. In February, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/union-households-favor-biden-closer-margin-2020-poll-finds-rcna140569">NBC News</a> found Biden winning only 50 percent of voters from union households.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this raises the possibility that organized labor’s capacity to prevent working-class voters from drifting out of the Democratic tent is more limited than progressives had hoped. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of this means that Democrats would derive no political benefit from a stronger labor movement. And it certainly does not undermine the substantive case for collective bargaining as a means of <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w24587">reducing inequality</a> and safeguarding workers’ interests. But the trends outlined above suggest that delivering for unions and helping them expand may be insufficient to dramatically<em> </em>improve the party’s performance with working-class voters in general and white ones in particular. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why unions don’t necessarily make their members more liberal&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Progressives have long believed that organized labor is a liberalizing force, and the notion that unions influence their members’ political views — to Democrats’ benefit — is far from baseless. The party <a href="https://www.americanprogressaction.org/article/unions-critical-democratic-partys-electoral-success/">consistently performs better</a> with unionized voters than nonunionized ones. Historically, this held true within demographic groups, with unionized white workers backing Democrats at higher rates than their nonunionized counterparts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many unions also actively engage in politically educating their members. Theoretically, unions that represent diverse memberships should discourage racial prejudice, as solidarity is indispensable to successful organizing and labor actions. A <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/ajps.12537">2021 paper</a> by the political scientists Paul Frymer and Jacob Grumbach found that white voters who gained union membership between 2010 and 2016 tended to display lower levels of racial resentment after getting their union cards.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there is reason to think that unions’ capacity to liberalize the views of non-college-educated voters has declined in the Trump era. According to the Democratic data scientist David Shor, his party’s “union premium” — the degree to which Democrats perform better with union voters, when controlling for all other demographic variables — dropped <a href="https://x.com/davidshor/status/1488621333101613059">nearly to zero in 2020</a>. Democrats still did better with unionized workers than nonunionized ones that year. Extrapolating from Shor’s math, this was almost entirely attributable to the demographic traits of America’s unionized population, which is <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/who-are-todays-union-workers/">more highly educated and less Southern</a> than the American electorate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More broadly, a <a href="https://elsevier-ssrn-document-store-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/24/03/06/ssrn_id4615336_code2539179.pdf?response-content-disposition=inline&amp;X-Amz-Security-Token=IQoJb3JpZ2luX2VjEAkaCXVzLWVhc3QtMSJGMEQCIG%2B0dBUmWs25uMfyi4JLjMM6qVhBWKWP%2BTR0sGzKpcNiAiAw6ENx%2BVIM%2Buih8r3ETxOWBZMoI5GK02Jd%2BCjxQOifKSq8BQhiEAQaDDMwODQ3NTMwMTI1NyIMZ9yOXQY2%2Furv48xNKpkF40uSQ2OdvfepqX%2BjmssT73rDIpCr7maauFyPQ3bTesikmCtE3PpLrd0crPH8UryzYZo87MvRehVC%2F4jhLbPSnih4A1u3OwpaC3V42Uc71fSXcrzFWkezGezhizm8GpJTMPf%2Bictfrf8nOqbKNv2qoLFz1DBy0%2Bf2Sqo%2F%2FP0EyHXHQ22KwPPWhsf6dkS6KRBQlmIs5Nhh73%2FnHLBgYpX8fwEGB8eNGo1mSteC%2BwWUZuJKPxzhb4JfPY7r0DnfRgag7Np%2BibhKrV2vlsV8Rtl6f8ESnNGhvpOLJcco0ucsx8ZTxxBqRhgN6dCybOMyrZ4B0KZki8W200vYExMIgO4lmm8r7QATX7qzg3Djw1dIm0OGT7rDdpT3QUZg%2BsPz1S9HLajxsu1ReEiexhmg%2Fv65NHELIgtXhxN9B5x%2BsgZUYICKwtVvJUjNySUGVOvcQtCmkvrkzk62x3zf4UXvirHWnCnTqRZDmC2AMEhUTnkQFn35b18hz5rAqqyNaOaU2J7xTj1hRjioIKP7QgMFU5heP%2BiRZ%2Bx9zpEpq280127xMytIcVd3CHWkP6hSSK0dsRD2%2BeT3iaFvaHDxWkuqSRdy5fmEMXCnCobQxGTshW1rlduZMVKgFDoDg9mhMF1SQmBnEU2n%2BfkC54uG4gWo2cW8QtEXwuIaqlER%2FtZHDoxbJz%2BdLSEiB5M4dlu963JFCEKgrdU1dr0ZHJB38mwmDuQrTDn47ZDHQ0S%2FZaXgIvsEuYxHWenU%2B5qPjkFGNzB44ZGDohssnjR5vhfQYNRl21dWG5scP%2FUtEUxCSfUS%2FCTu4QCEJ1E%2FxlJgd13%2Ftr7xwGpQVyWMWLSlwJ5SKSmVQ6cMIgTpjr076egL4XrOJoVr7C7mH57PErrkhEAw4u2auAY6sgEmpKxu%2FrldrzDB0w2UhU5attod7Hequ5Ri4prxzhUG36VZoph1iG%2BFqL86WLmMhcH%2BlsOxD0pOqc2elFtnvy4bQfhaPjmj%2Fh1OcpX9XMo8HGzwfhNi90Anmg7hOkLdejBn7xrmmAV2Xb3LavastZXAoR4Cuadgl1XIlrclzR%2BEINp8kVptjUn6PZ5wH6mSyezQLyMKzMJv%2B%2BcuSOQnt7TIX%2Fb2P%2BLaSDWi%2FGy3JvenmAtA&amp;X-Amz-Algorithm=AWS4-HMAC-SHA256&amp;X-Amz-Date=20241009T180816Z&amp;X-Amz-SignedHeaders=host&amp;X-Amz-Expires=300&amp;X-Amz-Credential=ASIAUPUUPRWEW3TWLQYO%2F20241009%2Fus-east-1%2Fs3%2Faws4_request&amp;X-Amz-Signature=90ab144a83ee403c540395b1698edd13b5b7525e0271c6349c665f3144eac2ef">recent study</a> from Alan Yan, a political science graduate student at UC Berkeley, suggests that unions’ historical tendency to liberalize their members’ views has been widely exaggerated.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To evaluate the impact of union membership on voters’ political views, Yan examines 13 panel surveys — in other words, polls of the same group of voters across multiple election cycles — conducted between 1956 and 2020. He looks at voters’ preferred party and issue positions in the election year before they gained union membership and in subsequent elections, when they were unionized. Controlling for other variables, he finds that the typical voter’s views barely change at all upon joining a union. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yan also offers some theoretical arguments for why this result makes sense. For one thing, political scientists generally believe that voters’ political identities tend to crystallize in early adulthood, much earlier than they usually gain union membership. By the time a given voter arrives in a unionized shop, therefore, their political views may be largely fixed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Furthermore, many unions make little effort to politicize their memberships. In the 2016 Cooperative Election Study — a large sample survey — only 20 percent of union members reported frequent political discussions with coworkers, according to Yan, while 39 percent could not remember ever being contacted by their union in the previous two years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Daniel Schlozman, a Johns Hopkins University political scientist whose work has focused on the relationship between organized labor and the Democratic Party, says that he finds Yan’s results unsurprising.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In many European countries in the early 20th century, unions often pervaded nearly every aspect of their members’ lives, not only mediating their workplace disputes, but providing gathering halls and clubs, <a href="https://www.oxfordreference.com/display/10.1093/oi/authority.20110803095850580">mutual aid programs</a>, and political parties. In that context, Schlozman would expect unions to shape the politics of their members more thoroughly. In the modern United States, by contrast — where unions have a light footprint outside the job site and myriad religious, ethnic, and ideological divisions inform voters’ politics — it makes sense that union leaders can’t dictate a party line to their members. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In a big pluralistic country where we are not polarized like Austria in the old days — where you join your union and then go to your social democratic stamp collecting club — union membership is just not going to be as powerful a force in determining political behavior” as other social attachments and identities, Schlozman said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there’s some reason to think that Yan’s paper understates unions’ political influence on their members. In an interview with Vox, Princeton political scientist Paul Frymer noted that during many of the years Yan studies — particularly in the 1950s and ’60s — many unions were still profoundly racist institutions, which one would scarcely expect to liberalize their memberships. “If a lot of unions are fighting integration, fighting immigrants, fighting the inclusion of Black Americans, of women,” Frymer said, “then yeah, that&#8217;s just going to create a push the other way.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yan and Frymer agree that some unions do successfully promote progressive political views among their members. But this requires both a leadership committed to evangelizing for liberal politics and a membership that’s open to such political messaging.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To the extent that education polarization and culture wars render many working-class union members skeptical of progressive messaging, their union leaders will have an incentive to back away from internal political advocacy. After all, such leaders ultimately need to win reelection in order to retain their positions. This could theoretically create a self-reinforcing dynamic in which the less Democratic a union’s members become, the less their leaders try to sell members on progressive politics, which then leads members to become even less Democratic.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Yan notes, even teachers unions, whose members tend to be better educated than union members, often focus on compensation rather than partisan politics because the latter divides their memberships. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further, in <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/ahertel/files/ilrr_hfkk.pdf">a 2020 survey experiment</a>, researchers from Columbia and MIT measure how workers’ interest in joining a hypothetical labor organization changed as different characteristics of that union were emphasized. When told that this union would campaign for pro-worker politicians in elections, the surveyed workers became less likely to want to join. If this result is representative, then many union leaders have a structural incentive to focus narrowly on bread-and-butter issues and keep quiet about their Democratic sympathies (to the extent that they possess them).</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Why unions are still good for Democrats</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this said, Democrats are still likely to benefit politically from delivering for labor unions and helping them grow. Even if such organizations can’t persuade their more culturally conservative members to vote for Democrats, they can help to mobilize the progressives within their ranks, since unions are <a href="https://ash.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/300871_hvd_ash_union_impact_v2.pdf">effective</a> at promoting higher voter turnout.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Separately, unions are major funders of Democratic campaigns, with almost <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/industries/indus?ind=P">90 percent</a> of organized labor’s political contributions going into Democrats’ coffers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it is possible that a larger and more self-confident labor movement would also be a more politically effective one. “As unions have retreated, even as they have put more efforts into politics and kept up their formal ties to the Democratic Party, their sociocultural imprint has declined,” Schlozman said. “It would not surprise me that union members feel less tied into the culture of unionism that would tie them into the Democrats.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Were Democrats to successfully promote a wave of unionization through labor law reform, unions could become more culturally relevant. Perhaps most importantly, a more powerful labor movement could nudge the Democratic Party’s issue positions into closer alignment with those of American workers. As unions have declined, power in the Democratic coalition has shifted away from organizations that represent mass working-class memberships and toward nonprofits that are accountable primarily to their wealthy, ideologically motivated donors. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Labor alone can’t build a more working-class Democratic Party&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, the Biden era should temper expectations of what organized labor can politically achieve, at least by itself. Perhaps, Biden’s historically pro-union policies would have paid more dividends if he had not also presided over inflation and the <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/11/23/biden-social-safety-net-2024-00128488">expiration of various social welfare benefits</a> established during the Covid crisis. The president’s advanced age surely did not help matters. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it remains the case that, under Biden, Democrats have seen their poll numbers with union voters decline at the presidential level, even as their support for organized labor’s interests increased. All the while, education polarization has continued apace. In the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/10/08/us/elections/times-siena-poll-likely-electorate-crosstabs.html">most recent New York Times/Siena poll</a>, Trump wins non-college-educated white voters by 30 points, while Harris wins college-educated ones by 23. And although the Democrat wins working-class nonwhite voters overwhelmingly, her margin among them is 8 points narrower than her margin among nonwhite Americans with college degrees.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats should not lessen their support for organized labor in light of these disappointing trends. But they should lower their expectations for what they’re likely to gain from delivering for individual unions with politically diverse memberships.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, education polarization does not look all that calamitous for the Democratic Party. The share of voters with college degrees is growing over time. In part because she is winning a historically large share of college graduates, Harris is currently competitive with Trump in enough states to win an Electoral College majority, <a href="https://www.natesilver.net/p/nate-silver-2024-president-election-polls-model">according to Nate Silver’s polling averages</a>. But in order to win comfortable Senate majorities and prevent figures like Donald Trump from remaining competitive in national elections, Democrats will need to improve their standing with working-class voters. Delivering for unions may be necessary for achieving that goal. But if the past four years are any guide, it will not be sufficient. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris and the problem with ceding the argument]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/378238/kamala-harris-fox-interview-bret-baier-2024-election-immigration" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378238</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T19:50:07-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T19:50:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fox News was never going to be a friendly venue for Vice President Kamala Harris. In an appearance on Special Report With Bret Baier, she was asked about some of the American right’s top fascinations and talking points: gender-affirming surgeries, Joe Biden’s mental acuity, the prospect of war with Iran. And — of course — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris visits the US-Mexico border with US Border Patrol Tucson Sector Chief John Modlin in Douglas, Arizona, on September 27, 2024. | Rebecca Noble / AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Rebecca Noble / AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2174047291.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris visits the US-Mexico border with US Border Patrol Tucson Sector Chief John Modlin in Douglas, Arizona, on September 27, 2024. | Rebecca Noble / AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Fox News was never going to be a friendly venue for Vice President Kamala Harris. In an appearance on <em>Special Report With Bret Baier</em>, she was asked about some of the American right’s top fascinations and talking points: gender-affirming surgeries, Joe Biden’s mental acuity, the prospect of war with Iran. And — of course — she got tough questions about immigration policy and the southern border.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was in answering those questions that Harris demonstrated how much the Democratic Party is moving right — toward the ideological center on immigration — under the banner of her candidacy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She chose not to defend the virtue of immigration, or of immigrants themselves, and continued to cede the playing field to the right. There were no references to the nation’s immigrant roots or the value of those immigrants (here legally or not) that Baier kept asking about. And there was no condemnation of Donald Trump’s stated plans for mass deportations of undocumented immigrants. She didn’t mention it, even as he pitches invoking archaic laws to round up and deport millions of people living in the United States.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, Harris used the interview to further distance herself from her past and her party’s left flank on immigration. Did she regret the immigrant-friendly positions she took in 2019 to allow undocumented immigrants to apply for driver’s licenses, qualify for free tuition at some universities, or <a href="https://kffhealthnews.org/news/article/fact-check-gop-trump-charge-kamala-harris-immigrant-health-care/">obtain</a> public health insurance under a universal plan?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not <em>no</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Listen, that was five years ago, and I’m very clear that I will follow the law. I have made that statement over and over again,” Harris responded.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>If so</em>, Baier followed up, <em>why did she select a running mate, Gov. Tim Walz, who signed some of those same proposals into state law in Minnesota?</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris paused before saying that her ticket is “very clear that we must support and enforce federal law and that is exactly what we will do.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And so the pattern repeated itself: Given opportunities to defend migrants in the face of classic right-wing fearmongering (as when she was asked about “single adult men who went on to commit heinous crimes”), Harris would cede the premise and pivot to the bipartisan border bill Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/5/24062710/senate-immigration-bill-border-security-ukraine-2024">proposed earlier this year that Trump helped tank</a>. She did the same when asked if she regretted the Biden administration’s repeal of Trump-era executive orders restricting immigration — citing a bill the White House proposed that she said would’ve “fixed our immigration system.” But she omitted that it also would have provided a <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/1177#:~:text=This%20bill%20establishes%20a%20path,status%20of%20lawful%20prospective%20immigrant.">pathway to citizenship</a> for certain undocumented immigrants already living in the US.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This all <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/10/kamala-harris-immigration-policy/680214/">continues a trend</a> for Harris. Just last week, at a town hall hosted by the Spanish-language media network Univision, Harris was twice presented with opportunities to invoke and condemn Trump’s mass deportation plans when speaking to attendees who had family who were deported or unable to get health care because they lacked legal status. She passed on that chance, instead referencing her past support for Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program recipients before pivoting to talk about reviving the bipartisan border bill. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And since becoming the nominee and headlining a national party convention that tended to reference immigration in the context of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/368138/dnc-immigration-border-security-latino-voters">needing more hardline border policies</a>, she’s continued to push for a bipartisan border bill that many progressive and liberal immigration advocacy groups and members of her own party <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/374661/kamala-harris-immigration-border-visit-arizona-activist-problem-election">don’t support</a>. Those critics are still biting their tongues — pointing out the need to unite to win the election and keep a roundly anti-immigrant Trump from controlling the executive branch — but that <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369177/democrats-kamala-harris-truce-immigration-progressive-border-security">truce</a> will only hold as far as November 5.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is every car dealer trying to rip me off?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me/374186/car-dealerships-sales-tactics-shady-practices" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=374186</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T16:42:49-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T07:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explain It to Me" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Vox reader writes: “Why are car dealers so shady? How do consumers avoid them? Is it frustrating for everyone?” Americans have long hated the car-buying experience. It’s not uncommon to spend hours (or even the whole day) at a dealership, finally reaching a deal and still walking away feeling vaguely hoodwinked. “It&#8217;s a process [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-869345488.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A Vox reader writes: “Why are car dealers so shady? How do consumers avoid them? Is it frustrating for everyone?”</em></p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Americans have long <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/when-it-comes-to-car-shopping-edmundscom-finds-that-americans-hate-the-haggle-so-much-theyd-give-up-sex-facebook-and-smartphones-to-avoid-it-261647461.html">hated</a> the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/study-americans-feel-taken-advantage-of-at-the-car-dealership-300301866.html">car-buying</a> <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/caredge-study-finds-auto-consumers-105800203.html">experience</a>. It’s not uncommon to spend hours (or even the whole day) at a dealership, finally reaching a deal and still walking away feeling vaguely hoodwinked.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s a process that generally stinks, and it&#8217;s designed that way,” says Tom McParland, founder of <a href="https://automatchconsulting.com/">Automatch Consulting</a>, a service that helps car buyers find the best price on the vehicle they want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of the distaste comes down to the uncertainty of what you’ll end up paying. In an age when you can buy almost anything online without interacting with another human being, where you can easily shop around for the best deal, cars remain one of the few purchases where your personal negotiation skills — as well as, sometimes, your race, gender, and income — can determine the price.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up">Explain It to Me newsletter</a></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The newsletter is part of Vox’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me">Explain It to Me</a>. Each week, we tackle a question from our audience and deliver a digestible explainer from one of our journalists. Have a question you want us to answer? Ask us <a href="http://www.vox.com/ask-vox">here</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes, the tactics car salespeople use go beyond just the hard sell to the downright deceptive. One common trap is <a href="https://www.theconsumerlawgroup.com/blog/consumers-beware-of-bait-and-switch-tactics-by-car-dealers.cfm">bait and switch</a> prices, where a car is initially advertised as one price (usually achieved by piling on discounts that you may not qualify for). When you run to the dealership to snag the deal, you’re told the vehicle has already been sold but there’s a similar one that’s more expensive. Or take <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/02/07/1155014842/how-car-buyers-can-become-entrapped-in-whats-known-as-a-yo-yo-sale">yo-yo sales</a>, in which you drive your new car home only to be told a few days later that the financing fell through so you’ll have to accept a higher interest rate or make a bigger down payment. A dealer might also try to sneak unneeded <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/blog/2024/08/car-dealers-included-add-ons-without-consumers-consent-discriminated-against-black-latino-buyers">add-ons</a> — like extended warranties or protective coatings — onto the total price of the car.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, the Federal Trade Commission received more than <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/federal.trade.commission/viz/TheBigViewAllSentinelReports/TopReports">184,000</a> auto-related consumer complaints, making it the third most common category after complaints about credit bureaus, as well as banks and lenders.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While there are some fair dealers, the car marketplace has “a lot of sharp and unethical business practices, and consumers are hurt by it,” says Chuck Bell, programs director of advocacy at Consumer Reports. “By the time that the consumer gets out the door, they feel like they’ve been doing battle.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why is shopping for cars done this way?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first hint that you’re on unequal footing with a car salesperson comes when they’re cagey about giving a price quote even over the phone, let alone in writing. McParland says that the dealers he calls around to for clients often tell him that he has to come to the dealership for a price. “They’re basically just telling us to go pound sand,” he says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dealers want you to come in because it’s much easier to upsell you that way. You’ve invested some effort into the process, and the salesperson can get a better read on how impatient you are to buy a car, how inexperienced you are with car shopping, and plenty of other factors to wield to their advantage. On the other hand, if they offer you an out-the-door price — which includes all extras and fees — before you ever meet in person, you could easily take the price to a competing dealer and ask if they can do better.&nbsp;While online used car dealers like CarMax and Carvana did make “no haggle” car prices more popular, they often come at a premium, according to McParland. Some traditional car dealers now offer fixed prices too, but it’s probably to your benefit to try to negotiate down.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How did the system get to be like this?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The general practice of negotiating car prices instead of paying a fixed price may actually stem from <a href="https://priceonomics.com/why-do-we-haggle-for-cars/">horse trading</a>, in which sellers and buyers also haggled and buyers would even trade in their old horse to offset the price of the new one, much as we do with cars today.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The model has endured for so long, though, in part thanks to state franchise laws that ensure these middlemen car dealerships can’t be easily cut out. Most states ban carmakers from selling directly to consumers. Tesla is the rare exception of a car company that sells directly, and it has <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2013/12/23/ohio-car-dealers-challenge-teslas-business-model.html">battled</a> with <a href="https://apnews.com/article/tesla-louisiana-car-dealers-federal-court-1dc44a5917731954de18f8455b9bad0b">car dealers</a> for the right to do so. Car dealer trade groups have considerable <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2023/05/rich-republicans-party-car-dealers-2024-desantis.html">political power</a>, and they’re organized enough and deep-pocketed enough to lobby against reforms that would threaten the status quo, such as changing franchise laws that give them exclusive rights to sell a certain car brand in a particular territory. The National Automobile Dealers Association (NADA), for its part, argues that <a href="https://www.nada.org/nada/issues/franchise-system">franchise laws</a> in fact increase competitiveness and benefit the consumer, all the while creating local jobs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They’re an enormously powerful lobby,” says Bell.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just look at how the industry pushed back against enforcement curtailing auto lending discrimination. Car dealers often arrange financing for customers, but they add a mark-up to the interest rate offered by banks because they can pocket that extra money for themselves. How much of a mark-up is applied is at the dealer’s discretion, and unlike mortgage lenders, they’re not required to collect data on the race of their customers, making it much harder to see if they’re complying with fair lending laws. Research shows that car dealers often charge <a href="https://www.nclc.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/report-time-to-stop-racing-cars-april2019.pdf">higher interest rates</a> to <a href="https://www.chicagofed.org/publications/profitwise-news-and-views/2023/discrimination-auto-loan-market">people of color</a>. When the Consumer Finance Protection Bureau started cracking down on this practice in 2013, the industry <a href="https://theintercept.com/2015/11/23/car-dealers-have-their-way-with-congress/">fought back</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/17/17248340/congressional-review-act-auto-loan-discrimination-cfpb">won</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Is there any hope for making the car-buying process better?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there’s reason to be optimistic about the future of shopping for cars. Late last year, the FTC announced <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/resources/ftc-cars-rule-combating-auto-retail-scams-dealers-guide">new regulation</a> that takes aim at the most rampant deceptive practices used by car dealers. It would, for one, require dealers to disclose the full, out-the-door price of a car, including all add-ons, before a customer visits the dealership. The price and other terms related to purchase of the car also have to be expressed in simple language. Dealers also wouldn’t be allowed to charge customers for useless add-ons. The FTC estimates the rule will <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/12/ftc-announces-cars-rule-fight-scams-vehicle-shopping">save customers $3.4 billion</a> and cut down the time spent shopping for cars by 72 million hours.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule was supposed to go into effect this summer but was delayed after two car dealer trade groups, including NADA, <a href="https://www.nada.org/nada/nada-headlines/nada-files-federal-court-challenge-stop-ftcs-vehicle-shopping-rule">filed a challenge</a>.<strong> </strong>The association told Vox that the rule would make the car-buying experience worse. “Consumers will have to spend an additional 60-80 minutes at the dealership, complete up to five new, untested forms, and will lose at least $1.3 billion a year in time as a result of this rule,” a spokesperson wrote in an email.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Bell is confident that the rule will ultimately go into effect, and if you’re looking for a car, you should behave as though these protections already apply. McParland advises asking dealers to provide, over email, an “itemized out-the-door price” on the vehicle you’re interested in. If they refuse, “that’s usually a red flag, so move on to somebody else,” he says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was featured in the Explain It to Me newsletter. Sign up&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em>&nbsp;<em>For more from Explain It to Me,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site"><em>check out the podcast</em></a><em>. New episodes drop every Wednesday.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jonquilyn Hill</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m Gen Z. ​​How can I save for retirement and still enjoy my life?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me/377960/saving-retirement-gen-z-401k-advice" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377960</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T16:20:01-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explain It to Me" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personal finance is hard no matter what stage of life you&#8217;re in. But for Zoomers just entering the workforce, the challenges are also coupled with a lot of uncertainty. And that combination is what brought Carolina to us with her question on this week’s episode of Explain It to Me, Vox’s go-to hotline for all [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A hand is shown dropping coins into another hand, against a pink and purple background." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1359132050.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Personal finance is hard no matter what stage of life you&#8217;re in. But for Zoomers just entering the workforce, the challenges are also coupled with a lot of uncertainty. And that combination is what brought Carolina to us with her question on this week’s episode of <em>Explain It to Me</em>, Vox’s go-to hotline for all your questions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Carolina is fresh out of college and already stressing about retirement. The older people in her life give her the same advice that generations before her have gotten: start saving immediately, contribute to your 401(k), and don’t touch it for decades until you’re ready to stop working.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s sound advice, but Carolina wonders if it applies to her and the rest of her cohort. She knows the havoc the Great Recession wreaked on everyday people and the economy at large. “I think people assume the stock market is always safe,” she says. “But then it keeps crashing.” It&#8217;s understandable why someone might be hesitant to put their trust in a financial system that had <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed">a scare as recently as this summer</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To answer this question, we enlisted <a href="https://www.yourrichbff.com/about-me">Vivian Tu, a.k.a. Your Rich BFF.</a> Vivian is a former Wall Street day trader and currently hosts <em>Networth and Chill</em> (<em>Explain It to Me </em>and <em>Networth and Chill</em> are both part of the Vox Media Podcast Network).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Can you enjoy today while preparing for the future? “You&#8217;ve got the folks who say ‘I&#8217;m going to blow all my cash today. I&#8217;m going to go on a shopping spree, because who knows if I get to retire in however many years.’” Tu says. “Then there are folks on the opposite side of the spectrum that say, ‘I need to prepare. I need to only think about retirement…I will have the worst life today so I can have a better future.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We sat down with Tu to discuss how to plan for the future while enjoying the now, how to protect yourself from financial uncertainty, and how younger generations can adjust to a changing financial landscape.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is an excerpt of our conversation, edited for length and clarity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can listen to <em>Explain It to Me</em> on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/explain-it-to-me/id1042433083">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1vSUO6Bg4abtjRF7fnGpT1">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site">wherever you get podcasts</a>. If you’d like to submit a question, send an email to askvox@vox.com or call 1-800-618-8545.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP2602588043" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How should we think about balancing living in the now and preparing for the future?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I ask folks to find the middle of that barbell. You are allowed to enjoy your life today. I promise you, you are not put on this big green earth to work a 9 to 5 to hate your life. That is not your ultimate purpose. You are allowed to have the little treat. You are allowed to take that trip. You are allowed to go and grab a manicure with a friend because it is fun.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You do not want to have so much fun today at the expense of future you. You want to be able to have fun today and tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Practically, what tips do you have for young people who are thinking about retirement?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I always tell everyone, there is a special Your Rich BFF method: you need to STRIP. Everyone says, “Oh, did I pick the wrong career?” No, STRIP is an acronym.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">S stands for savings. First and foremost you want to set aside an emergency fund. In particular, I recommend putting your emergency fund into a <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/high-yield-online-savings-accounts">high-yield savings account</a> so that your money waiting for that rainy day earns interest in the meantime. If you are a singleton, three to six months of living expenses is a good bet. If you are head of household, you have dependents, I would say closer to 6 to 12. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">T is total debt. A lot of us have debt — that is not a bad word. It is just a tool. What I say is rank it from highest to lowest interest rate. Make the minimum payment across everything to keep your credit score high. But then any additional funds you have for debt paydown goes towards the interest rate that is the highest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Up next R: retirement. Take advantage of tax-advantaged accounts through your job. You can also open up an IRA or a Roth IRA.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then I. This is important; it&#8217;s not enough to just open those accounts, you actually have to invest. Take the cash that you&#8217;re putting into those accounts and make investments that make sense based on your risk profile. <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/us/individual/education/retirement/what-is-a-target-date-fund">Target date retirement funds</a> or <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/i/indexfund.asp">index funds</a> often make sense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the last step is so critically important: P — plan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don&#8217;t get to have happily ever after, you don&#8217;t get to ride off into the sunset if you do not have a plan. Write down what your goals are, what those milestones are, what you’d like to accomplish, the amount of money it&#8217;s going to take to get you there, and then back into what you need to do to get there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How do you protect yourself and those investments from another financial crisis?</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s really important that your portfolio makes sense for how far you are away from retirement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So when you&#8217;re 20, yeah, you can be 100 percent or 90 percent in the stock market and have 0 percent or 10 percent in bonds. When you&#8217;re 50, it should look almost flipped. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it really depends on how much you&#8217;re making and how much you already have. Every single person is a little different.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What about people who are just getting by? How should they prioritize retirement savings?</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If they are just getting by, first and foremost we want to try and maximize that income. People always balk when I say this: You need to be asking for a raise somewhere between 10 percent to 15 percent every single year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ooof.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re getting it&nbsp; But if you ask for 10 to 15 and you get eight, that&#8217;s good, because eight is still going to help keep you above the inflation rate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Retirement and savings in general are often presented as this sacrifice. You&#8217;re going without your fancy groceries now so that future you can go on cruises and golf and do whatever it is that people do when they&#8217;re retired.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">JQ&#8217;s moving to Naples in her retirement!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But how do you find that balance? How do you prioritize those things?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think it&#8217;s about providing yourself with a life that you are happy with today while also thinking, “Hey, it&#8217;s not like saving for retirement means this money goes into a black hole.” You still get to spend it just later.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re not just setting this money aside and then getting that same number back in retirement. When you start investing your money, when it has a little bit of room and time to grow, that money gets to work really hard for you. And so you might put in $100,000. That $100,000 could be a couple million dollars in retirement.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Critiquing Trump’s economics — from the right]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/377972/friedrich-hayek-donald-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377972</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T10:11:57-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are few more influential right-wing scholars than the economist Friedrich Hayek — and few whose work is less compatible with the right’s ascendant Trumpian strain. Born in Austria in 1899, Hayek spent his career developing a wide-ranging libertarian social theory. Societies, for Hayek, emerge from the interplay of countless different systems and logics — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A black-and-white photo of an older white man wearing frameless glasses and a suit jacket and tie, seated in front of a bookshelf. " data-caption="University of Chicago professor Friedrich Hayek. | Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-515257540.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>University of Chicago professor Friedrich Hayek. | Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There are few more influential right-wing scholars than the economist Friedrich Hayek — and few whose work is <em>less</em> compatible with the right’s ascendant Trumpian strain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Born in Austria in 1899, Hayek spent his career developing a wide-ranging libertarian social theory. Societies, for Hayek, emerge from the interplay of countless different systems and logics — creating an order so complex that no single entity, not even a government, can fully understand how it all operates. He believed that any attempt to transform such a thing by policy would invariably break part of this system, leading to unintended and often disastrous consequences.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t a good argument against <em>all</em> government interference in the marketplace (as a shallow read of Hayek might suggest). But it is a powerful insight into how societies work, one that provides an especially clear explanation for why planned economies failed so badly during Hayek’s lifetime.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It also helps us understand why there’s an authentic strain of right-wing resistance to Trump’s “tariffs and deportations” economic agenda —&nbsp;one that attentive liberals could learn from.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hayek’s “spontaneous order” and the case against regulation</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Hayek, there were basically two different types of system or order. The first is an organization, meaning a top-down planned effort where one person or entity lays out the rules for everyone to follow. The second is a “spontaneous order,” a bottom-up system in which the rules are determined over time by enormous numbers of micro-interactions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take, for example, the ecosystem of the American West. No one person set the rules by which bison, wolves, moose, prairie dogs, and the like breed and interact; in fact, no one dictated that this particular place needed to have those particular species at all. Instead, a system emerged out of thousands of years of interactions between flora and fauna, prey and predator. It has predictable rules and outcomes, but no hand at the tiller.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hayek believed that humanity operated in a similar, but even more complex, fashion.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Our own social order, according to Hayek, reflects centuries of interactions between hundreds of millions of different people and an impossibly diverse set of institutions, ranging from organized religion to different economic sectors to artist collectives. What we call “society” is the spontaneous order that emerges from individuals and organizations interacting and developing oft-unwritten rules that govern those interactions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The structure of human activities constantly adapts itself, and functions through adapting itself, to millions of facts which in their entirety are not known to anybody,” he wrote in <em>Law, Legislation, and Liberty, Volume 1</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Government, Hayek argued, plays a special role in spontaneous order: It “becomes indispensable in order to assure that [social] rules are obeyed.” The state both protects people’s rights to participate in their corner of the spontaneous order and, at times, can even guide the order toward adopting a different (and perhaps better) set of rules.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What the state cannot do well, in Hayek’s eyes, is interfere with discrete and specific interactions inside the spontaneous order.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the government issues “commands” telling people where and for how much they can sell their goods, for example, it is engaging in an enterprise that bureaucrats and politicians cannot and never will have sufficient knowledge to do adequately. Most economic regulation, for Hayek, is akin to the mass slaughter of wolves in the American West —&nbsp;a shortsighted move with <a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/74/7/430/7687410?login=false" data-type="link" data-id="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/74/7/430/7687410?login=false">destabilizing long-term consequences.</a> (Recent efforts to reintroduce wolves have been <a href="https://www.yellowstonepark.com/things-to-do/wildlife/wolf-reintroduction-changes-ecosystem/">an extraordinary success</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The spontaneous order arises from each element balancing all the various factors operating on it and by adjusting all its various actions to each other, a balance which will be destroyed if some of the actions are determined by another agency on the basis of different knowledge and in the service of different ends,” Hayek wrote.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hayek versus Trump</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is very easy to take this pro-market line of thinking too far.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We know that certain elements of the economy, like the money supply, can in fact be effectively managed by governments. Hayek’s skepticism of government could bleed over into paranoia, as with his argument in <em>The Road to Serfdom</em> asserting that social democracy would invariably bleed into authoritarianism. In fact, he even went so far as to endorse Augusto Pinochet’s dictatorship in Chile on grounds that <a href="https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/friedrich-hayek-dictatorship/">its free-market policies</a> were worth the loss of political liberty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Hayek’s argument is essential to understanding why some government projects, like Soviet-style command economies, tend to fail so spectacularly. When an economic policy aims at fundamental transformation, one in which humans are put in charge of managing a vast swath of ordinary economic activity, the potential for the state to exceed the bounds of its knowledge is obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hayek did not believe that this was only a problem for socialists. In <em>The Constitution of Liberty</em>, Hayek argued that conservatives’ emphasis on preserving tradition and the nation inclined them toward dangerous forms of state control over society.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It is this nationalistic bias which frequently provides the bridge from conservatism to collectivism: to think in terms of ‘our’ industry or resource is only a short step away from demanding that these national assets be directed in the national interest,” he wrote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So despite unquestionably being a man of the right, Hayek rejected the label “conservative” for his politics (he preferred “liberal” on grounds that “libertarian” was too clunky). Conservatives, he argued, were dogmatic and nationalistic — useful allies against the left, but&nbsp;skeptical enough of liberty that they posed their own set of collectivist dangers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Were Hayek still alive, he would see the vindication of his concerns in the person of Donald Trump. The former president’s two most consistent policy proposals — deporting millions of migrants and imposing a 10-percent tariff on all foreign-made goods — are far more aggressive efforts at reshaping America’s spontaneous order than any tax-and-spend proposals offered by the Harris campaign. Each, in its own way, amounts to a fundamental revision of how the American state and economy operate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, there’s a reason that some of the most effective critics of Trump’s <a href="https://www.cato.org/people/scott-lincicome">trade</a> and <a href="https://www.cato.org/people/alex-nowrasteh">immigration</a> policies work for the libertarian Cato Institute. Hayek’s heirs, at least those who take his ideas seriously, understand that Trump represents something anathema to their tradition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was adapted from the On the Right newsletter.</em>&nbsp;<em>New editions drop every Wednesday. Sign up&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/on-the-right-newsletter-whats-driving-conservative-ideas" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The nightmare facing Democrats, even if Harris wins]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/377729/kamala-harris-supreme-court-electoral-college-senate-constitution" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377729</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T18:00:49-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="US Federal Courts" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the course of its last few terms, the Supreme Court has effectively placed itself in charge of the executive branch.&#160; It’s given itself an extra-constitutional veto power over virtually any policy decision made by a federal agency. Even when it ultimately rules in favor of President Joe Biden’s policies, it often sits on those [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Democratic presidential nominee Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to the media before boarding Air Force Two after assessing the Hurricane Helene recovery response in North Carolina on October 5, 2024, in Charlotte, North Carolina. | Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2177013366.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Democratic presidential nominee Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to the media before boarding Air Force Two after assessing the Hurricane Helene recovery response in North Carolina on October 5, 2024, in Charlotte, North Carolina. | Mario Tama/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the course of its last few terms, the Supreme Court has effectively placed itself in charge of the executive branch.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s given itself an <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">extra-constitutional veto power</a> over virtually any policy decision made by a federal agency. Even when it ultimately rules in favor of President Joe Biden’s policies, it often <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/29/23530842/supreme-court-arizona-mayorkas-title-42-mexican-border-immigration">sits on those cases for months</a>, allowing a lower court order to suspend Biden’s programs for as much as a year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, the Court has done extraordinary favors for America’s only recent Republican president. Just look at the Republican justices’ decision to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">immunize former President Donald Trump from prosecution</a> for criminal actions he committed while in office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The president, in other words, is increasingly subordinate to the courts. Yet, as the judiciary seizes more and more power, the battle over who gets to shape it grows increasingly lopsided.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/cook-pvi/2022-partisan-voter-index/republican-electoral-college-advantage">enjoy an advantage in the Electoral College</a>. Just how <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/25/upshot/trump-electoral-college-harris.html?unlocked_article_code=1.PU4.nFhX.g0QJHoVkVyWg&amp;smid=url-share">much is up for debate</a>, but that advantage does mean that even if the American people hand Vice President Kamala Harris a modest victory in the popular vote this November, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">Donald Trump could still become president</a>. He’d then get to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/373084/supreme-court-trump-judges-federalist-society">nominate loyal Republican judges</a> eager to implement his party’s agenda from the bench, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/9/20962980/trump-supreme-court-federal-judges">much as he did during his first term</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Harris wins by a large enough margin to overcome the Electoral College’s Republican bias, she still may not get to have much of an impact on the judiciary. Her presidency — and specifically her ability to name judges — is likely to be restricted by a Republican Senate. For Democrats to control even a tied 50-50 Senate, one in which Vice President Tim Walz would hold the deciding vote if Harris prevails, they must not just win in every single blue and swing state Senate race this year, but also Senate races in at least two of the red states of Ohio, Florida, Montana, and Texas. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That <em>could</em> happen, but it would require the kind of unusually triumphant Democratic election year that the party hasn’t seen <a href="https://www.270towin.com/2008_Election/">since at least 2008</a> and possibly not since President Bill Clinton’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1996_United_States_presidential_election">landslide reelection victory in 1996</a>. And that seems <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">quite unlikely</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Harris victory could halt America’s slide into a MAGA-dominated future but it is unlikely to give her the power to reshape the judiciary in the way <a href="https://www.vox.com/22233051/biden-courts-republican-trump-supreme-court-judicial-nominations-senate-dick-durbin">Trump was able to during his first term</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Electoral College and Senate malapportionment has completely warped the judiciary&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During the Biden administration, the Republican Supreme Court wielded its power aggressively. It <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/24/23181720/supreme-court-dobbs-jackson-womens-health-samuel-alito-roe-wade-abortion-marriage-contraception">greenlit abortion bans</a> in numerous red states. It <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23616868/supreme-court-affirmative-action-harvard-unc-students-fair-admissions-john-roberts">abolished affirmative action</a> at nearly all universities. It has turned itself into a printing press for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/27/23184848/supreme-court-kennedy-bremerton-school-football-coach-prayer-neil-gorsuch">court orders benefiting the Christian right</a>. It’s given itself <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/357900/supreme-court-loper-bright-raimondo-chevron-power-grab">sweeping veto power over literally anything done by a federal agency</a> that should be controlled by the president. And then there was that whole affair where the Republican justices said that <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/366855/supreme-court-trump-immunity-betrayal-worst-decisions-anticanon">Donald Trump was allowed to commit crimes while he was in office</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Along the way, the Court has pulled <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">new legal rules</a> out of thin air, then used these newly invented rules to nullify many of Biden’s most ambitious programs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the American people had voted for this agenda then it would be difficult to criticize the Republican Party for pushing it. But the electorate did nothing of the sort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After 2016, Trump was in a position to nominate three Supreme Court justices not because most Americans wanted him to be president but because enough Americans in the right places did. The Electoral College system means each American’s vote is not equal: Hillary Clinton, after all, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/elections/2016/results/president">won nearly 3 million more votes than Trump in 2016</a>, but still lost the presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump had a Republican Senate willing to put his choices on the bench because Republicans have an enduring advantage in the upper chamber, one that makes it more difficult for Democrats to control the Senate. Each state, regardless of population, gets two senators.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">antidemocratic features of the US Constitution</a> have been with the United States almost from the beginning, but they have an increasingly pronounced effect today, largely because <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/22/21293168/dc-statehood-vote-filibuster-supreme-court-joe-biden">the parties have sorted based on population density</a>. People in cities and other densely populated areas tend to vote for Democrats, while outlying areas become more and more Republican as they become less dense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That means that a system that effectively gives extra representation to the most sparsely populated states will unfairly favor the Republican Party. In 2021, for example, when the Senate split evenly between Democrats and Republicans, the Democratic “half” <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/11/6/21550979/senate-malapportionment-20-million-democrats-republicans-supreme-court">represented nearly 42 million more people</a> than the Republican “half.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the trend appears to be accelerating, this antidemocratic skew long predates the Trump presidency. Senate malapportionment has been one of the most consequential factors shaping US politics for decades. By some counts, if senators were distributed equally according to how the majority of Americans voted, Democrats would have <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/14/22925457/supreme-court-senate-confirmation-ketanji-brown-jackson-leondra-kruger-michelle-childs">controlled the Senate in every single year since the late 1990s</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/image_392068.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.602842183994,100,74.794315632012" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Wolf/Daily Kos Elections" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In that world, Democrats not only may have enacted more significant legislation, they would also almost certainly control the courts. Obama would have confirmed a justice to fill the vacancy created when Justice Antonin Scalia died in Obama’s last year in office, and none of Trump’s nominees would have likely been confirmed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, while Republicans probably would have still filled some Supreme Court seats during the 1990s and 2000s, it’s unlikely that they would have successfully confirmed an <a href="https://archive.thinkprogress.org/clarence-thomas-most-important-legal-thinker-in-america-c12af3d08c98/">ideologue like Justice Clarence Thomas</a> or an <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/350339/samuel-alito-republican-party-scotus">unapologetic GOP partisan like Justice Samuel Alito</a> if Senate seats were distributed fairly by population. In a fair Senate, Republican presidents would have to negotiate with Democrats to choose moderate nominees in the vein of, say, Justices Lewis Powell and Sandra Day O’Connor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is to say, the impact of recent population sorting is felt acutely in the courts. In all of US history, only three justices were nominated by a president who lost the popular vote and confirmed by a bloc of senators who represent less than half of the nation’s populace. <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/10/26/21534358/supreme-court-amy-coney-barrett-constitution-anti-democratic-electoral-college-senate">All three of them currently sit on the Supreme Court</a>; they are Gorsuch, Brett Kavanaugh, and Amy Coney Barrett, Trump’s three appointees to the Court.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What a broken Senate means for a potential Harris administration&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the event that Harris wins the presidency but Republicans capture the Senate, we only need to turn the clock back less than a decade to predict what is likely to happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obama’s final two years in office were the only two when Republicans controlled the Senate. And shortly after Scalia’s death in February 2016, Senate Republicans announced that they would confirm no one Obama nominated to fill that seat. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“<a href="https://www.vox.com/21448904/senate-republicans-supreme-court-vacancy-election-ruth-bader-ginsburg">This vacancy should not be filled until we have a new president</a>,” then-Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell announced at the time. (Four years later, when Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg’s death allowed Trump to fill a vacancy in the final months of his presidency, Republicans abandoned the position they adopted in 2016 and swiftly confirmed Trump’s nominee.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The GOP’s blockade on Supreme Court confirmations should have surprised no one who watched the Senate closely because Senate Republicans had already imposed a near-total halt on all confirmations to federal appellate courts, powerful bodies that hand down precedential decisions that determine what the law is in multiple states at a time. In Obama’s last two years in office, he <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/9/20962980/trump-supreme-court-federal-judges">successfully appointed only two judges to the appellate bench</a>, and one of these judges was confirmed to a highly specialized, relatively nonpolitical court that primarily deals with patent law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By contrast, President George W. Bush confirmed 10 appellate judges during his last two terms in office, during a period when Democrats controlled the Senate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, during Obama’s last two years in office, he appointed only 18 judges to federal district courts, the lowest rank of federal judge who enjoys a lifetime appointment. That compares to 58 judges during Bush’s final two years in office, according to <a href="https://www.fjc.gov/history/judges/search/advanced-search">data from the Federal Judicial Center</a>. In Trump’s final two years in office, when Republicans controlled both the White House and the Senate, an astonishing 121 district judges were confirmed, including some infamously partisan judges like <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/6/13/23757893/aileen-cannon-donald-trump-jack-smith-indictment-mar-a-lago-maga">Aileen Cannon</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/17/23512766/supreme-court-matthew-kacsmaryk-judge-trump-abortion-immigration-birth-control">Matthew Kacsmaryk</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">President Biden, for what it’s worth, has confirmed more than 200 judges thanks to Democrats&#8217; narrow majority in the Senate, including a total of 116 since the current Congress took office. Over his entire presidency, he’s filled 44 appellate seats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without the power to confirm judges, Harris will have no way to dilute the influence of judges like Cannon or Kacsmaryk, and Republicans could easily refuse to confirm anyone to any judicial vacancy that comes open until the GOP regains the White House. Alternatively, Harris may be able to strike deals with Republicans to confirm a few of her preferred judges, but the GOP has a history of demanding a very high price to confirm even a single Democratic judge. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2014, for example, thanks in part to a now-weakened Senate process that allowed senators to veto anyone nominated to a federal judgeship in their state, Georgia’s Republican senators convinced Obama to <a href="https://archive.findlaw.com/blog/rumored-bipartisan-deal-for-11th-cir-seats-just-went-through/">nominate four Republican judicial choices</a> — including a Republican appellate judge — in return for confirming only two Democrats. One of the Republican nominees was eventually dropped because his <a href="https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/228303-obama-drops-controversial-nominee-opposed-by-black-caucus/">views on abortion, marriage equality, and the Confederate Flag offended Democrats</a>, but Republicans still walked away with more confirmed judges than Obama did. Harris could very well find herself in a similar situation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problems for Harris likely wouldn’t stop there. Because Republicans continue to dominate the judiciary, Harris would likely spend her presidency watching her policies get <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">struck down on dubious legal theories</a> invented by GOP judges, much as the Supreme Court struck down President Biden’s student loan forgiveness policy despite the fact that it was <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">unambiguously authorized by an act of Congress</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Democrats are starting to awaken to the threat of a Republican judiciary, but they haven’t yet found a solution to their constitutional problem</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Absent constitutional reform, Democrats have good reason to fear a Republican judiciary for decades to come. A malapportioned Senate means that Democrats are increasingly defenseless against the GOP’s efforts to control the bench. In recent years, however, Democrats have become more aware of a GOP judiciary’s power to thwart their agenda and have started to try to explore ways around it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, elected Republicans have viewed the courts as a favorable issue that rallies their base, while Democrats have behaved much more cautiously. Many Republicans credit Trump’s decision to delegate judicial selection to the Federalist Society, a bar association for right-wing lawyers, and to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/373084/supreme-court-trump-judges-federalist-society">release a list of potential Supreme Court nominees during his 2016 candidacy</a>, for giving him enough support to prevail in that year’s election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden, by contrast, began his presidency very reluctant to take on the courts. After many Democrats called for Supreme Court reform in the wake of the Senate’s disparate treatment of the Scalia and Ginsburg vacancies, Biden tried to take the wind out of the sails of reform by promising to appoint a commission to study the issue — and then filling the commission with Republicans and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/4/10/22375792/supreme-court-biden-commission-reform-court-packing-federalist-society">scholars who historically have not supported reform</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, as <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/supreme-court/">the Supreme Court’s polling numbers collapsed</a> and as the Court <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">outraged elected Democrats with opinions like its <em>Trump</em> immunity decision</a>, Democrats have grown more aggressive. Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/363557/supreme-court-biden-kamala-harris-reform-term-limits-ethics">proposed term-limiting the justices and imposing a binding ethics code on the Court</a>, proposals also supported by Harris. Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) has a bill that would <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/364438/supreme-court-chuck-schumer-trump-immunity">strip the Court of jurisdiction to enforce its immunity decision</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the most <a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/judicial_modernization_and_transparency_act_one-pager.pdf">ambitious recent Supreme Court reform proposals</a>, from Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR), includes a number of very aggressive reforms. Wyden’s proposal would make every justice submit to a tax audit each year, require a two-thirds supermajority for the Court to overrule an act of Congress, and gradually expand the size of the Court to 15 seats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, while these proposals show that Democrats are moving in a more court-skeptical direction than they were four years ago, they would not solve the structural problems with US democracy that gave us the courts we have today. And they have virtually no chance of passing, especially in a world where it is increasingly difficult for Democrats to win the Senate even when they convincingly win the national popular vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, turning the United States into a nation where every vote counts equally — and where each voter is actually able to shape the judiciary —&nbsp;would require rewriting its Constitution. Until that happens, Democrats like Harris will struggle to win elections even when most Americans support them. And Democratic presidents will increasingly be at the mercy of Republicans in both the Senate and the courts.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
