<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-07-25T22:32:18Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Dieker</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Money Talks: The mother-daughter duo who won’t let their franchise fail]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/362770/cartridge-world-small-business-owners-franchise" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362770</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T18:03:05Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-26T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vox Guide to Entrepreneurship" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to&#160;Money Talks, a series in which we interview people about their relationship with money, their relationship with each other, and how those relationships inform one another. Jamie Parker is 45 and has owned a Cartridge World franchise in Christiansburg, Virginia, for 10 years. Ieshia Ahmed, her daughter, is 25 and describes herself as her [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of two women on either side of an imagined dollar bill. A storefront is in the middle with music notes floating around it." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/MoneyTalks_PaigeVickers_Vox_01.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Welcome to&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/personal-finance/2019/8/20/20813748/money-debt-personal-finance"><em>Money Talks</em></a><em>, a series in which we interview people about their relationship with money, their relationship with each other, and how those relationships inform one another.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Jamie Parker is 45 and has owned a Cartridge World franchise in Christiansburg, Virginia, for 10 years. Ieshia Ahmed, her daughter, is 25 and describes herself as her “mother’s sidekick.” Together, the two of them have turned a franchise into a family business and are actively working to maintain in-person customer relationships in an increasingly online world. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><a href="https://cartridgeworldusa.com/">Cartridge World</a>, which provides office printing systems to small businesses and individuals, has approximately 100 franchises and makes over $20 million in sales.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The following conversation has been lightly condensed and edited.<br></em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Jamie: </strong>When I was about 25, maybe 27, my ex-husband and I were working at a chain restaurant called Country Cookin’. That’s when we started researching franchises. We thought about Chick-fil-A for a while, but we didn’t like restaurant work. We wanted something that we could do on our own, with minimal employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We opened our first Cartridge World in 2005. No one was doing cartridges or anything like that — no one had even heard of a refill cartridge at that time. I built that store from zero to 100 percent in the first year. Got it off the ground. We started with inkjets and lasers, got the bigger businesses — Roanoke County public schools and that type of thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We really chose Cartridge World because of the minimum staff. We liked the idea that we could run it by ourselves. With a restaurant, you need a minimum of 15 employees. We wanted something that we could do on our own, that we could grow and that would be successful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> It became the family business. All of the teachers at my school who had toners or cartridges that needed to be recycled would put them into a recycle box, and I would carry the box onto the school bus and take it home to Mom and Dad.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve been in the business since I was 5 years old. Did I understand the mechanics behind it? Definitely not — but I remember carrying toners and cartridges that teachers wanted to recycle.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right now I’m in school for law, and that’s my passion. That said, I took a hiatus during the pandemic. Covid ruined a lot of things, and going to college and trying to learn online — and paying for it! — didn’t make sense to me, so I stopped. My brother is autistic and nonverbal, and my mom needed to be home to help my brother throughout the summer. It was time for me to step in. Mom could help Bubby, and Sissy could work at Cartridge World.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If something ever happened and my mom needed to be at home full-time with my brother, she could be — because I know the material, and I know what I’m doing. I would never allow our family business to fail.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Jamie:</strong> You can tell which one of us is more extroverted and which one of us is more introverted. I’m more behind-the-scenes, I take orders, drop-ship, pay the bills, that type of thing. Ieshia is more up-front, with the customers. She’s really the face of the business. She has a beautiful face!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> I’ve done pageants, and I’ve learned so much from them. I had no idea that I was going to win Miss Commonwealth Outstanding Teen — my family was so surprised that they dropped the camera, and you don’t actually see me getting crowned — but it made me who I am today. I was thrown into a chaotic environment, and my option was to thrive. I was doing appearances every single day, and I had to go out there and socialize. I had to wear my crown. I had to wear it up high and never let it tilt, and it’s been that way for my entire life.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“I know the material, and I know what I’m doing. I would never allow our family business to fail.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When our customers come in through the door, they see us. They connect with us. We listen to them. If they’re having a bad day, and they just need a 63XL HP cartridge, they’re going to get it — but they’re also going to tell me what’s going on in their lives. They’re going to get human connection. That’s what you can’t get anywhere else. We’re not just selling cartridges, we’re selling a service. We’re part of the community.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><strong>Jamie</strong>: </strong>We were in Roanoke when I opened my first store with my ex-husband. Note the <em>ex</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> They got divorced!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Jamie:</strong> I left Cartridge World for about 10 years [during which she worked for Country Cookin’ and started a catering business]<em> </em>and then I dusted myself off and opened my own Cartridge World in Christiansburg.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia: </strong>The definition of <em>girlboss</em>. Literally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><strong>Jamie</strong>: </strong>The Roanoke location closed in November, but I’m thriving. It’s difficult to get people from Roanoke in the Christiansburg store because they think, “Oh, I have to drive 45 minutes,” but I can drop-ship them cartridges online.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> We don’t want to be an online-only business because our customers wouldn’t see us anymore. That’s also why we came up with things like Wiggle Wednesdays. Halfway through the week, we’re playing music at the store and it’s another way to connect. I have footage of customers, people with dogs, couples, everyone dancing to the music we put on, so they can get 10 percent off their order!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We always have business cards on us. I don’t care if I’m in Roanoke and I’m out to dinner — if I hear someone say they’re a business owner, I’m going to give them my business card. You never know where it’s going to go.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><strong>Jamie</strong>: </strong>I have my territory, but I can sell to anyone. I have a lot of customers in North Carolina, and I just picked up a customer in Washington state.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cartridge World has told us multiple times that we should just go online, but that’s not how I choose to do things. I’d rather open my store and come here every day. I do it for my customers. My customers are my everything. I provide a service that’s more than ink and toner, if that makes sense at all.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> Until you get here, you don’t understand how small our town is. For us to go online, we’d go out-of-sight, out-of-mind. We would drown.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Jamie:</strong> I’ve thought about starting my own business, and we have the kind of following now so that I probably could, but I truly believe in the Cartridge World name. I really do. I could very well go out and do my own thing, but I feel like Cartridge World is going to be much bigger than it is today, very soon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ieshia:</strong> We’re making a profit — if we weren’t, we wouldn’t be doing this, and I wouldn’t be on payroll — but I still need to save money for college. So I got a second job. I’m in management in the hospitality business, but I’m also working here, too. In today’s society, it’s not realistic to have just one job.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve promised my mom that if she gets to the point that she can’t run it anymore — it’s a family business, and it’s been in my life since I was 5 years old — I’m not going to just let it go away. If something happens, and she can’t do it any more, I will put my law career goals on hold. I have my legal assistant, and I have my paralegal, and even if I’ve gotten my esquire, I will put it on pause and build up the business until I can step away and have other people work here. That’s always been my plan. My brother is going to need a source of income, so keeping the family business going is very important to me.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Celia Ford</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists are trying to unravel the mystery behind modern AI]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362759/ai-interpretability-openai-claude-gemini-neuroscience" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362759</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T16:41:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-26T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 23, AI researcher Jide Alaga asked Claude, an AI assistant created by tech startup Anthropic, how to kindly break up with his girlfriend. “Start by acknowledging the beauty and history of your relationship,” Claude replied. “Remind her how much the Golden Gate Bridge means to you both. Then say something like ‘Unfortunately, the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/growtika-nGoCBxiaRO0-unsplash.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,96.55625,96.636111111111" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">On May 23, AI researcher <a href="https://www.governance.ai/team/jide-alaga">Jide Alaga</a><a href="https://x.com/jide_alaga/status/1794011249828614353"> asked Claude</a>, an AI assistant created by tech startup <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23794855/anthropic-ai-openai-claude-2">Anthropic</a>, how to kindly break up with his girlfriend.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Start by acknowledging the beauty and history of your relationship,” Claude replied. “Remind her how much the Golden Gate Bridge means to you both. Then say something like ‘Unfortunately, the fog has rolled in and our paths must diverge.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alaga was hardly alone in encountering a very Golden Gate-centric Claude. No matter what users asked the chatbot, its response <a href="https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpreview.redd.it%2Fhas-anyone-tried-golden-gate-claude-yet-v0-53kouqhtu92d1.png%3Fwidth%3D1080%26format%3Dpng%26auto%3Dwebp%26s%3D978e249a58cc9229ecc1c4467b6f5742bbf20c36">somehow circled back</a> to the link between San Francisco and Marin County. Pancake recipes called for eggs, flour, and a walk across the bridge. Curing diarrhea required getting assistance from Golden Gate Bridge patrol officers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But several weeks later, when I asked Claude whether it remembered being weird about bridges that day, it denied everything.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/goldengatedenial.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=14.267688454198,0,71.442748091603,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Golden Gate Claude was a <a href="https://x.com/AnthropicAI/status/1793741051867615494">limited-time-only AI assistant</a> Anthropic created as part of a <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/mapping-mind-language-model">larger project</a> studying what Claude knows, and how that knowledge is represented inside the model — the first time researchers were able to do so for a model this massive. (Claude 3.0 Sonnet, the AI used in the study, has an <a href="https://lifearchitect.substack.com/p/the-memo-special-edition-claude-3">estimated 70 billion parameters</a>) By figuring out how concepts like “the Golden Gate Bridge” are stored inside the model, developers can modify how the model interprets those concepts to guide its behavior.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Doing this can make the model get silly — cranking up “Golden Gate Bridge”-ness isn’t particularly helpful for users, beyond producing <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Anthropic/comments/1cztu2q/chatting_to_golden_gate_claude_is_a_lot_of_fun/">great content for Reddit</a>. But the team at Anthropic found things like “deception” and “sycophancy,” or insincere flattery, represented too. Understanding how the model represents features that make it biased, misleading, or dangerous will, hopefully, help developers guide AI toward better behavior. Two weeks after Anthropic’s experiment, <a href="https://openai.com/index/extracting-concepts-from-gpt-4/">OpenAI published similar results</a> from its own analysis of GPT-4. (Disclosure: Vox Media is one of several publishers that have signed partnership agreements with OpenAI. Our reporting remains editorially independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The field of computer science, particularly on the software side, has historically involved more “engineering” than “science.” Until about a decade ago, humans created software by writing lines of code. If a human-built program behaves weirdly, one can theoretically go into the code, line by line, and find out what’s wrong.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“But in machine learning, you have these systems that have many billions of connections — the equivalent of many millions of lines of code — created by a training process, instead of being created by people,” said Northeastern University computer science professor <a href="https://baulab.info/">David Bau</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AI assistants like OpenAI’s ChatGPT 3.5 and Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 are powered by<a href="https://www.ibm.com/topics/large-language-models"> large language models</a> (LLMs), which developers train to understand and generate speech from <a href="https://gizmodo.com/chatbot-gpt4-open-ai-ai-bing-microsoft-1850229989">an undisclosed, but certainly vast amount of</a><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23674696/chatgpt-ai-creativity-originality-homogenization"> text scraped from the internet</a>. These models are more like plants or <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/2/14/24069722/political-ban-cell-cultivated-lab-grown-meat-plant-based-labeling-laws">lab-grown tissue</a> than software. Humans build scaffolding, add data, and kick off the training process. After that, the model grows and evolves on its own. After millions of iterations of training the model to predict words to complete sentences and answer questions, it begins to respond with complex, often very human-sounding answers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This bizarre and arcane process somehow works incredibly well,” said <a href="https://www.neelnanda.io/about">Neel Nanda</a>, a research engineer at Google Deepmind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">LLMs and other AI systems weren’t designed so humans could easily understand their inner mechanisms — they were designed to work. But almost no one anticipated <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/4/28/23702644/artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-technology">how quickly they would advance</a>. Suddenly, Bau said, “we’re confronted with this new type of software that works better than we expected, without any programmers who can explain to us how it works.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In response, some computer scientists established a whole new field of research: AI interpretability, or the study of the algorithms that power AI. And because<a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/CzZ6Fch4JSpwCpu6C/interpretability"> the field </a>is still in its infancy, “people are throwing all kinds of things at the wall right now,” said <a href="https://cs.brown.edu/people/epavlick/">Ellie Pavlick</a>, a computer science and linguistics professor at Brown University and research scientist at Google Deepmind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Luckily, AI researchers <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1389041723000906">don’t need to totally reinvent the wheel</a> to start experimenting. They can look to their colleagues in biology and neuroscience who have long been trying to understand the mystery of the human brain.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back in the 1940s, the earliest machine learning algorithms were <a href="https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~./epxing/Class/10715/reading/McCulloch.and.Pitts.pdf">inspired by connections between neurons in the brain</a> — today, many AI models are still called “artificial neural networks.” And if we can figure out the brain, we should be able to understand AI. The <a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/neuro.09.031.2009">human brain</a> likely has over 100 times as many <a href="https://bionumbers.hms.harvard.edu/bionumber.aspx?s=n&amp;v=3&amp;id=112055">synaptic connections</a> as <a href="https://the-decoder.com/gpt-4-architecture-datasets-costs-and-more-leaked/">GPT-4 has parameters</a>, or adjustable variables (like knobs) that calibrate the model’s behavior. With those kinds of numbers at play, <a href="https://x.com/thebasepoint?lang=en">Josh Batson</a>, one of the Anthropic researchers behind Golden Gate Claude, said, “If you think neuroscience is worth attempting at all, you should be very optimistic about model interpretability.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Decoding the inner workings of AI models is a dizzying challenge, but it’s one worth tackling. As we increasingly hand the reins over to large, obfuscated AI systems in <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23827785/artifical-intelligence-ai-drug-discovery-medicine-pharmaceutical">medicine</a>,<a href="https://www.vox.com/videos/2023/12/12/23998858/ai-chatgpt-education-cheating"> education</a>, and the <a href="https://theconversation.com/a-black-box-ai-system-has-been-influencing-criminal-justice-decisions-for-over-two-decades-its-time-to-open-it-up-200594">legal system</a>, the need to figure out how they work — not just how to train them —&nbsp;becomes more urgent. If and when AI messes up, humans should, at minimum, be capable of asking why.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>We don’t </strong><strong><em>need </em></strong><strong>to understand AI — but we should&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We certainly don’t need to understand something to use it. I can drive a car while knowing shamefully little about how cars work. Mechanics know a lot about cars, and I’m willing to pay them for their knowledge if I need it. But a <a href="https://www.apa.org/monitor/2017/11/numbers">sizable chunk of the US population</a> takes antidepressants, even though neuroscientists and doctors still <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/08/well/mind/antidepressants-effects-alternatives.html">actively debate how they work</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">LLMs kind of fall into this category — an estimated <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/6/23948386/chatgpt-active-user-count-openai-developer-conference">100 million people use ChatGPT</a> every week, and neither they <a href="https://observer.com/2024/05/sam-altman-openai-gpt-ai-for-good-conference/">nor its developers</a> know precisely how it comes up with responses to people’s questions. The difference between LLMs and antidepressants is that doctors generally prescribe antidepressants for a specific purpose, where multiple studies have proven they help at least some people feel better. However, AI systems are generalizable. The same model can be used to come up with a recipe or tutor a trigonometry student. When it comes to AI systems, Bau said, “we’re encouraging people to use it off-label,” like prescribing an antidepressant to treat ADHD.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To stretch the analogy a step further: While Prozac works for some people, it certainly doesn’t work for everyone. It, like the AI assistants we have now, is a blunt tool that we barely understand. Why settle for something that’s just okay, when learning more about how the product actually works could empower us to build better?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many researchers worry that, as AI systems get smarter, it will get easier for them <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/YgAKhkBdgeTCn6P53/ai-deception-a-survey-of-examples-risks-and-potential">to deceive us</a>. “The more capable a system is, the more capable it is of just telling you what you want to hear,” Nanda said. Smarter AI could produce more human-like content and make fewer silly mistakes, <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2024/05/10/1092293/ai-systems-are-getting-better-at-tricking-us/">making misleading or deceptive responses tricker to flag</a>. Peeking inside the model and tracing the steps it took to transform a user’s input into an output would be a powerful way to know whether it’s lying. Mastering that could help protect us from misinformation, and from more existential AI risks as these models become more powerful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The relative ease with which<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/27/business/ai-chatgpt-safety-research.html"> researchers have broken through the safety controls</a> built into widely used AI systems is concerning. Researchers often describe AI models as “black boxes”: mysterious systems that you can’t see inside. When a black box model is hacked, figuring out what went wrong, and how to fix it, is tricky — imagine rushing to the hospital with a painful infection, only to learn that doctors had no idea how the human body worked beneath the surface. A major goal of interpretability research is to make AI<a href="https://www.interpretable.ai/interpretability/why/"> safer by making it easier to trace errors back to their root cause</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The exact definition of “interpretable” is a bit subjective, though. Most people using AI aren’t computer scientists — they’re doctors trying to decide <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10740686/">whether a tumor is abnormal</a>, parents trying to <a href="https://www.khanmigo.ai/">help their kids finish their homework</a>, or writers using ChatGPT as <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CasualConversation/comments/17ku7to/chatgpt_is_a_better_thesaurus_than_any_thesaurus/">an interactive thesaurus</a>. For the average person, the bar for “interpretable” is pretty basic: can the model tell me, in basic terms, what factors went into its decision-making? Can it walk me through its thought process?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, people like Anthropic co-founder <a href="https://colah.github.io/about.html">Chris Olah</a> are working to fully reverse-engineer the algorithms the model is running. Nanda, a former member of Olah’s research team, doesn’t think he’ll ever be totally satisfied with the depth of his understanding. “The dream,” he said, is being able to give the model an arbitrary input, look at its output, “and say <em>I know why that happened.”</em></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What are large language models made of?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today’s most advanced AI assistants are powered by transformer models (the “T” in “GPT”). Transformers turn typed prompts, like “Explain large language models for me,” into numbers. The prompt is processed by several pattern detectors working in parallel, each learning to recognize important elements of the text, like how words relate to each other, or what parts of the sentence are more relevant. All of these results merge into a single output and get passed along to another processing layer…and another, and another.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At first, the output is gibberish. To teach the model to give reasonable answers to text prompts, developers give it lots of example prompts and their correct responses. After each attempt, the model tweaks its processing layers to make its next answer a tiny bit less wrong. After practicing on most of the written internet (<a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/352849/openai-chatgpt-google-meta-artificial-intelligence-vox-media-chatbots">likely including many of the articles on this website</a>), a trained LLM can write code, answer tricky questions, and give advice.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">LLMs fall under the broad umbrella of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jGCvY4gNnA8">neural networks</a>: loosely brain-inspired structures made up of layers of simple processing blocks. These layers are really just giant matrices of numbers, where each number is called a “neuron” — a vestige of the field’s neuroscience roots. Like cells in our human brains, each neuron functions as a computational unit, firing in response to something specific. Inside the model, all inputs set off a constellation of neurons, which somehow translates into an output down the line.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As complex as LLMs are, “they’re not as complicated as the brain,” Pavlick said. To study individual neurons in the brain, scientists have to <a href="https://www.gsnetwork.com/neuroscience-techniques-to-study-neurons/">stick specialized electrodes</a> inside, on, or near a cell. Doing this <a href="https://www.cell.com/neuron/fulltext/S0896-6273(22)00806-6">in a petri dish</a> is challenging enough — recording neurons in a living being, while it’s doing stuff, is even harder. <a href="https://academic.oup.com/book/24425/chapter-abstract/187426587?redirectedFrom=fulltext">Brain recordings are noisy</a>, like trying to tape one person talking in a crowded bar, and experiments are limited by technological and <a href="https://www.fda.gov/regulatory-information/search-fda-guidance-documents/institutional-review-boards-frequently-asked-questions">ethical constraints</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Neuroscientists have developed many clever analysis hacks to get around some of these problems, but “a lot of the sophistication in computational neuroscience comes from the fact that you can’t make the observations you want,” Batson said. In other words, because neuroscientists are often stuck with crappy data, they’ve had to pour a lot of effort into fancy analyses. In the AI interpretability world, researchers like Batson are working with data that neuroscientists can only dream of: every single neuron, every single connection, no invasive surgery required. “We can open up an AI and look inside it,” Bau said. “The only problem is that we don’t know how to decode what’s going on in there.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How do you study a black box?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How researchers ought to tackle this massive scientific problem is as much a philosophical question as a technical one. One could start big, asking something like, “Is this model representing gender in a way that might<a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/23738987/racism-ai-automated-bias-discrimination-algorithm"> result in bias</a>”? Starting small, like, <em>“</em>What does <a href="https://openai.com/index/language-models-can-explain-neurons-in-language-models/">this specific neuron</a> care about?<em>”</em> is another option. There’s also the possibility of testing a specific hypothesis (like, <em>“</em>The model represents gender, and uses that to bias its decision-making”)<em>, </em>or <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tysaiahfranklin/video/7148626782084697390?lang=en">trying a bunch of things just to see what happens</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Different research groups are<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-01314-y"> drawn to different approaches</a>, and new methods are introduced at every conference. Like explorers mapping an unknown landscape, the truest interpretation of LLMs will emerge from a collection of incomplete answers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many AI researchers use a neuroscience-inspired technique called <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/veterinary-science-and-veterinary-medicine/neural-decoding">neural decoding</a> or <a href="https://direct.mit.edu/coli/article/48/1/207/107571/Probing-Classifiers-Promises-Shortcomings-and">probing</a> — training a simple algorithm to tell whether a model is representing something or not, given a snapshot of its currently active neurons. Two years ago, a group of researchers <a href="https://thegradient.pub/othello/">trained a GPT model</a> to play <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xDnYEOsjZnM">Othello</a>, a two-player board game that involves flipping black and white discs, by feeding it written game transcripts (lists of disc locations like “E3” or G7”). They then probed the model to see whether it figured out what the Othello board looked like — and it had.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Knowing whether or not a model has access to some piece of information, like an Othello board, is certainly helpful, but it’s still vague. For example, I can walk home from the train station, so my brain must represent some information about my neighborhood. To understand <em>how</em> my brain guides my body from place to place, I’d need to get deeper into the weeds.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&amp;oi=ao&amp;user=GLnX3MkAAAAJ">Interpretability researcher</a> Nanda lives in the weeds. “I’m a skeptical bastard,” he said. For researchers like him, zooming in to <a href="https://www.alignmentforum.org/posts/NfFST5Mio7BCAQHPA/an-extremely-opinionated-annotated-list-of-my-favourite-1">study the fundamental mechanics</a> of neural network models is “so much more intellectually satisfying” than asking bigger questions with hazier answers. By <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.14082">reverse-engineering the algorithms AI models learn</a> during their training, people hope to figure out what every neuron, every tiny part, of a model is doing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This approach would be perfect if each neuron in a model had a clear, unique role. Scientists <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6822296/">used to think</a> that the brain had neurons like this, firing in response to super-specific things like <a href="https://www.nature.com/news/2005/050620/full/news050620-7.html">pictures of Halle Berry</a>. But in both neuroscience and AI, this has proved not to be the case. Real and digital neurons fire in response to a confusing combination of inputs. A <a href="https://distill.pub/2017/feature-visualization/">2017 study</a> visualized what neurons in an AI image classifier were most responsive to, and mostly found <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:%22Mona_Lisa%22_with_DeepDream_effect_using_VGG16_network_trained_on_ImageNet.jpg#/media/File:%22Mona_Lisa%22_with_DeepDream_effect_using_VGG16_network_trained_on_ImageNet.jpg">psychedelic nightmare fuel</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can’t study AI one neuron at a time — the activity of a single neuron doesn’t tell you much about how the model works, as a whole. When it comes to brains, biological or digital, the activity of a bunch of neurons is greater than the sum of its parts. “In both neuroscience and interpretability, it has become clear that you need to be looking at the population as a whole to find something you can make sense of,” said<a href="https://gracewlindsay.com/"> Grace Lindsay</a>, a computational neuroscientist at New York University.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In its <a href="https://transformer-circuits.pub/2024/scaling-monosemanticity/index.html">latest study</a>, Anthropic <a href="https://transformer-circuits.pub/2024/scaling-monosemanticity/umap.html?targetId=34m_31164353">identified millions of features</a> — concepts like “the Golden Gate Bridge,” “immunology,” and “inner conflict” — by studying patterns of activation across neurons. And, by cranking the Golden Gate Bridge feature up to 10 times its normal value, it made the model get super weird about bridges. These findings demonstrate that we can identify at least some things a model knows about, and tweak those representations to intentionally guide its behavior in a commercially available model that people actually use.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How interpretable is interpretable enough?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If LLMs are a black box, so far, we’ve managed to poke a couple of tiny holes in its walls that are barely wide enough to see through. But it’s a start. While some researchers are committed to finding the fullest explanation of AI behavior possible, Batson doesn’t think that we necessarily need to completely unpack a model to interpret its output. “Like, we don’t need to know where every white blood cell is in your body to find a vaccine,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ideally, the algorithms that researchers uncover will make sense to us. But biologists accepted years ago that nature did not evolve to be understood by humans — and while humans invented AI, it’s possible it wasn’t made to be understood by humans either. “The answer might just be really complicated,” Batson said. “We all want simple explanations for things, but sometimes that’s just not how it is.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some researchers are considering another possibility — what if artificial and human intelligence co-evolved to solve problems in similar ways? Pavlick believes that, given how human-like LLMs can be, an obvious first step for researchers is to at least ask whether LLMs reason like we do. “We definitely can’t say that they’re not.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether they do it like us, or in their own way, LLMs are thinking. Some people <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/04/24/artificial-intelligence-consciousness-thinking/">caution against using the word “thinking”</a> to describe what an LLM does to convert input to output, but this caution might stem from “a superstitious reverence for the activity of human cognition,” said Bau. He suspects that, once we understand LLMs more deeply, “we’ll realize that <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/351893/consciousness-ai-machines-neuroscience-mind">human cognition is just another computational process</a> in a family of computational processes.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if we could “explain” a model’s output by tracing every single mathematical operation and transformation happening under the hood, it won’t matter much unless we understand <em>why</em> it’s taking those steps — or at least, how we can intervene if something goes awry.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One approach to understanding the potential dangers of AI is “red teaming,” or trying to trick a model into doing something bad, like <a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/articles/2024/red-teaming-the-risks-of-using-ai-in-biological-attacks.html">plan a bioterrorist attack</a> or <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2023/04/26/is_your_ai_hallucinating/">confidently make stuff up</a>. While red teaming <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/red-team-ai-llms">can help find weaknesses</a> and problematic tendencies in a model, AI researchers haven’t really standardized the practice of red teaming yet. Without established rules, or a deeper understanding of how AI really works, <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/challenges-in-red-teaming-ai-systems">it’s hard to say exactly how “safe” a given model is</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To get there, we’ll need a lot more money, or a lot more scientists — or both. AI interpretability is a new, relatively small field, but it’s an important one. It’s also hard to break into. The largest LLMs are proprietary and opaque, and require huge computers to run. Bau, who is leading a team to <a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2024/05/02/nsf-funds-democratizing-ai-research/">create computational infrastructure</a> for scientists, said that trying to study AI models without the resources of a giant tech company is a bit like being a microbiologist without access to microscopes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Batson, the Anthropic researcher, said, “I don’t think it’s the kind of thing you solve all at once. It’s the kind of thing you make progress on.”&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Kamala Harris could win (or lose) the Electoral College]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/363256/kamala-harris-electoral-college-swing-state-polls" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363256</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T22:32:18Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-26T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris is the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee. But can she win the presidency? Due to the wonders of the Electoral College system, the answer depends on how she will do in a limited number of swing states. In 2020, seven states had their presidential winner determined by less than 3 percentage points: [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris holds a color-coded map of state abortion laws on October 17, 2022. | Gina Ferazzi/Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Gina Ferazzi/Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1244047283.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris holds a color-coded map of state abortion laws on October 17, 2022. | Gina Ferazzi/Los Angeles Times via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris is the presumptive Democratic presidential nominee. But can she win the presidency?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to the wonders of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/21539173/electoral-college-explained-2020-trump-biden">Electoral College system</a>, the answer depends on how she will do in a limited number of swing states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, seven states had their presidential winner determined by less than 3 percentage points: Michigan, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania, Nevada, Arizona, Georgia, and North Carolina. Joe Biden won the first six out of those seven, so he won the White House.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When President Biden was still in the race, polling was looking grim for him <a href="https://www.natesilver.net/p/nate-silver-2024-president-election-polls-model">in all these states</a>. Commentators speculated that North Carolina, Arizona, Georgia, and perhaps even Nevada were out of reach for him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s best path to victory, it was believed, was to hold strong in the Rust Belt trio of Michigan, Wisconsin, and Pennsylvania. Those three swing states, plus the traditionally Democratic states and a single electoral vote from <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/4/3/24119984/nebraska-electoral-college-vote-trump-biden-kirk">Nebraska’s Second Congressional District</a>, would have given Biden 270 electoral votes — the bare minimum he needed to win.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Biden’s best path may not be Harris’s. There’s an optimist’s case that that’s good news for her — and a pessimist’s possibility that it’s a real problem.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The pessimistic case is that some suspect Harris may do worse among Rust Belt working-class whites than “Joe from Scranton” did — making states like Wisconsin and Pennsylvania a tougher reach for her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The optimistic case is that perhaps Harris will do better than Biden among nonwhite voters — putting states with particularly large Black populations (Georgia and North Carolina) or Hispanic populations (Arizona and Nevada) back into contention. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some initial poll results on how Harris does in swing states have trickled in since Biden dropped out, though given the recent upheaval in the contest, it’s not clear how much to make of them. But here’s how the swing state math stacks up.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The seven swing states</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, Biden won the national popular vote by 4.5 percentage points, but the contest for an Electoral College majority was much closer. Biden stacked up 19 safe Democratic states, the District of Columbia, and Nebraska’s Second District. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he got over the top by triumphing narrowly in six of the seven swing states listed above. Here is his margin of victory in each:</p>

<ul>
<li>Michigan: 2.8%</li>



<li>Nevada: 2.4%</li>



<li>Pennsylvania: 1.2%</li>



<li>Wisconsin: 0.6% (this was the “tipping point state” that put him over the 270 electoral votes he needed to win)</li>



<li>Arizona: 0.3%</li>



<li>Georgia: 0.2%</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, meanwhile, won just one of the closest swing states:&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li>North Carolina: 1.4%&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump also won by 3.4 percent in Florida, which most analysts now believe should be considered a red-leaning state rather than a swing state.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden-Trump rematch was set to focus on the same lineup of swing states, in about the same order of competitiveness as last time. However, one change is that <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2023/11/nevada-biden-trump-2024-polling/675997/">many polls suggested</a> that Nevada (a state Trump lost in 2016 and 2020) has since moved more to the right.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Does Harris have room to grow in Georgia, North Carolina, Nevada, and Arizona?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Harris’s selection could scramble the map more. “Kamala Harris is doing SIGNIFICANTLY better than Joe Biden is among Black and Hispanic voters,” CNN polling analyst Harry Enten <a href="https://x.com/ForecasterEnten/status/1816463956707344444">wrote on X</a>, adding: “while Biden had really one path to win the electoral college, Harris has multiple. Specifically, she can win in the Sun Belt (AZ, GA, NC, &amp; NV).”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Currently, the evidence that might happen is strongest in Georgia, where <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/12/us/georgia-white-population.html">33 percent</a> of the population is Black and where there is <a href="https://x.com/Nate_Cohn/status/1816462041927839868">polling </a>showing Harris-Trump is a much closer race than Biden-Trump was. A Landmark Communications poll <a href="https://www.onlineathens.com/story/news/politics/elections/state/2024/07/24/new-poll-shows-trump-and-harris-are-nearly-tied-in-georgia/74526278007/">showed Harris down 1 point</a>, and an Emerson College poll <a href="https://emersoncollegepolling.com/july-2024-swing-state-polls-harris-trails-trump-in-arizona-georgia-michigan-pennsylvania-tied-in-wisconsin/">showed her down 2 points</a>. (Biden was trailing by about 4 points on average when he dropped out of the race.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">North Carolina is more of a reach, considering Trump won it twice, but it was close in 2020 and the state is <a href="https://myfox8.com/news/north-carolina/what-is-the-racial-breakdown-of-north-carolinas-100-counties/">21 percent Black</a>. So perhaps Harris could make the state competitive — though it’s worth remembering that she hasn’t led a nationwide ticket yet, so we don’t yet truly know just how well she’ll do among Black voters when she’s the nominee rather than Biden’s running mate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Nevada and Arizona, the question is more about Hispanic voters, who make up more than 20 percent of the electorate <a href="https://naleo.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/1_23_24_-_NEF_Release_NV_Primary_Profile_-_FINAL.pdf">in</a> <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/phoenix/2024/03/08/latino-voter-share-arizona">each</a> state. Democrats have won Nevada in the past four presidential cycles, but it’s drifted right a bit in recent years. Arizona, meanwhile, is a traditionally Republican state that Democrats have had surprising success in in the past few cycles.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">If Harris struggles in the Rust Belt, she’ll need to make up ground elsewhere</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Rust Belt power trio of Michigan, Wisconsin, and Pennsylvania famously determined the outcomes of both the 2016 and 2020 elections, by first swinging toward Trump and then to Biden.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Harris wins all three again (as well as that Nebraska Second District vote), she wins the presidency. But what if she doesn’t win all three? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another way to think about this is: If she loses one or more of the Rust Belt trio, what would she have to do to make up for that in the other four swing states (Georgia, North Carolina, Nevada, and Arizona)?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can break down the scenarios in a few different ways, but here are a few:</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>1) If Harris loses all three of Wisconsin, Michigan, and Pennsylvania:</strong> She has a chance of still winning, but there’s no more room for error, and it relies on a big swing of both Black and Hispanic voters to her side. She would have to win all four of Georgia, North Carolina, Nevada, and Arizona — that would give her 275 electoral votes. This is easier said than done — Trump won North Carolina twice and he only lost Georgia and Arizona in 2020 by the slimmest of margins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>2) If Harris wins Michigan, but loses Wisconsin and Pennsylvania: </strong>The trio won’t necessarily move together. Biden did slightly better in Michigan than in the other two Rust Belt states in 2020, it has a larger Black population, and perhaps Harris could win back voters alienated by the Gaza war.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If she secures Michigan’s 15 electoral votes, Harris would have two paths. Winning both Georgia and North Carolina would be enough to put her over the top. Alternatively, winning one of those two plus both Nevada and Arizona would do it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>3) If Harris wins Michigan and Pennsylvania, but loses Wisconsin:</strong> Adding Pennsylvania would put her close — at 260 electoral votes. She would only need to win one of Georgia, North Carolina, or Arizona to put her over the top. (Nevada’s electoral vote haul is too small to get her there.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This helps make it clear why Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro has emerged as a leading vice presidential contender — his state’s 19 electoral votes are extremely important to the electoral math, more so than, say, Arizona’s 11.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, all of this is speculative, since national voters have barely gotten a chance to make up their minds what they think of Harris since she became the presumptive nominee. She will have months to campaign in swing states to try to make her case — and the Trump campaign will also have months to try and make the case against her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the electoral math is already enough to show that, while her chances of victory may not utterly hinge on the Rust Belt states, her options are slim if she loses them.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rebecca Jennings</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[J.D. Vance didn’t have sex with a couch. But he’s still extremely weird.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/363230/jd-vance-couch-sex-hillbilly-elegy-rumor-false" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363230</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T21:27:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T21:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2024 election is already historic for a number of reasons, from an assassination attempt to a last-minute dropout, with the country’s first Black woman candidate slated to secure the Democratic nomination. It is also perhaps the first time in American history that a vice presidential nominee has been rumored to have had sex with [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="J.D. Vance." data-caption="J.D. Vance, who probably definitely did not have sex with a couch." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1253803949.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>J.D. Vance, who probably definitely did not have sex with a couch.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The 2024 election is already historic for a number of reasons, from an assassination attempt to a last-minute dropout, with the country’s first Black woman candidate slated to secure the Democratic nomination. It is also perhaps the first time in American history that a vice presidential nominee has been rumored to have had sex with a couch. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s get this out of the way: J.D. Vance did not say he had sex with a couch. The rumor began as a joke on X, when user @rickrudescalves tweeted on July 15: “can’t say for sure but he might be the first vp pick to have admitted in a ny times bestseller to fucking an Inside-out latex glove shoved between two couch cushions (vance, hillbilly elegy, pp. 179-181).” That the tweet appeared to be directly sourced from <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/360909/jd-vance-how-true-is-hillbilly-elegy-classism">Vance’s memoir, <em>Hillbilly Elegy</em></a>, convinced many people that it was in fact true, but if they were to read pages 179 to 181, all they’d find is Vance talking about his time at Ohio State University. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So many people embraced the shitpost, however, that it took on a life of its own, with countless memes popping up on TikTok and X. “[W]e cannot let JD Vance near the oval office,” <a href="https://x.com/lolennui/status/1816253691407851623">one person tweeted</a> with a picture of the many sofas inside the room. <a href="https://x.com/RichardHanania/status/1815596967516422476">Another juxtaposes</a> Vance staring longingly with zoom-ins of leather couches while Barry White’s “Never, Never Gonna Give Ya Up” plays. When the rumor had spread widely enough for the Associated Press to publish a lengthy explainer headlined “No, JD Vance did not have sex with a couch,” someone else <a href="https://x.com/djtweets/status/1816296893028180064">quoted it and referenced the infamous Bill Clinton denial, writing</a>, “I did not have sectional relations.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">we cannot let JD Vance near the oval office <a href="https://t.co/aKEAnaoLBB">pic.twitter.com/aKEAnaoLBB</a></p>&mdash; Amy A (@lolennui) <a href="https://twitter.com/lolennui/status/1816253691407851623?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 24, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s common for rumors about famous people that are objectively untrue but are funny or entertaining to go viral (a famous example suggests <em>Glee</em> actress <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/mychalthompson/lea-michele-responded-to-cant-read-comments">Lea Michele secretly can’t read</a>), whether started by intentional trolls, as was the case with Vance and the couch, or via games of digital telephone, where all context and factuality get left untranslated. Most of the time, the reason the rumors spread is because people genuinely want to believe them. In Vance’s case, the fact that he’d written a coming-of-age book meant that a common trope (teen boy tries to have sex with inanimate object) made some degree of sense, coupled with the fact that he’s espoused some <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/07/24/jd-vance-gender-views-00170673">extremely bizarre views</a> on sex and gender. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Curiously, the AP article debunking the rumor has been removed from its website — an unusual decision typically reserved for serious factual or editorial errors. As a spokesperson for the AP told Vox via email, “The story, which did not go out on the wire to our customers, didn’t go through our standard editing process. We are looking into how that happened.” Some still speculated that perhaps the AP’s commitment to fact-checking is such that, despite the fact that Vance didn’t write about it in <em>Hillbilly Elegy,</em> there’s <a href="https://x.com/knowyourmeme/status/1816498547753464034">no definitive proof</a> he didn’t try to have sex with a couch.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s more bizarre is that the couch joke was only one of the three most off-putting things Vance has been known for during his first 10 days as a VP nominee, and the only one that wasn’t verified as true. After Trump announced his pick on July 15, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7gPGxB2FqEc">a clip</a> from his 2021 appearance on Tucker Carlson went viral in which he complained that the US was “effectively run” by “a bunch of childless cat ladies who are miserable at their own lives,” naming Kamala Harris, Pete Buttigieg, and Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez. “The entire future of the Democrats is controlled by people without children, and how does it make any sense that we’ve turned our country over to people who don’t really have a direct stake in it,” he said, discounting Harris’s two step-children whom she co-parents with husband Doug Emhoff. Then, Vance tried and failed to get laughs at a Trump rally by <a href="https://people.com/internet-slams-jd-vance-for-cringe-diet-mountain-dew-joke-8682255">making an awkward joke</a> about drinking diet Mountain Dew and how “[Democrats] are going to call that racist.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance already <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/07/24/jd-vance-gender-views-00170673">held extreme views</a> on sex and gender; he opposes abortion even in cases of rape and incest and has <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/qjk8bd/ohio-republican-jd-vance-abortion-slavery">compared it to slavery</a>. He <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/j-d-vances-sad-strange-politics-of-family">has voted against</a> a bill ensuring access to IVF and suggested a <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/jd-vance-senate-pornography_n_628d3ba1e4b05cfc2692705b">ban on porn</a>. He <a href="https://x.com/JDVance1/status/1387763955557445640">called</a> universal child care “a class war against normal people.” He <a href="https://ohiocapitaljournal.com/2022/07/28/vance-would-vote-against-codifying-right-to-marriage-for-same-sex-couples/">opposes legislating codifying the right to gay marriage</a> and suggested that <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/93abve/jd-vance-suggests-people-in-violent-marriages-shouldnt-get-divorced">people in “violent” marriages</a> shouldn’t get divorced.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He is also among the nebulous group of young intellectual conservatives backed by Silicon Valley venture capitalist Peter Thiel loosely called the “<a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets">New Right</a>,” whose main project seems to be making techno-fascist and incel-adjacent ideas seem cool and edgy. On X, where Vance has spent a great deal of time, <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/jd-vance-twitter-x-following-fyp-trump-b2583022.html">he at one point followed</a> several white nationalist accounts, many of whom glorify bodybuilding and fascism while promoting the <a href="https://www.vox.com/23076952/replacement-theory-white-supremacist-violence">Great Replacement theory</a>. He is, in other words, exactly the type of guy you could imagine claiming that couch sex robots were the beginning of a glorious future without women.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pointing out Vance and Trump’s obvious weirdness now seems to be among Democrats’ main strategies in combating the Republican ticket. And it’s working: Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz <a href="https://x.com/BrianOliu/status/1815955081977549272">was praised</a> for <a href="https://x.com/JoshRaby/status/1815889888207892619">his appearances</a> on MSNBC in which he stressed how “weird” the Trump-Vance platform is, while the Harris campaign went viral for <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/184249/78-year-old-criminal-kamala-harris-roasts-trump-press-release">its statement</a> on Trump’s Fox News appearance, which read, “is Donald Trump ok?” and listed major takeaways like “Trump is old and quite weird?” That kind of blunt, call-it-like-you-see-it candor was once a boon to the Trump camp, which delighted in offending “blue-haired” “soy milk” liberals whom they saw as myopic and out of touch. But when we’ve got someone like Vance spouting deeply antisocial and bizarre ideas that are way outside the realm of normal political discourse, the most effective response is often a simple, “What the hell?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t really need to explain why everyone believing a joke about a vice presidential candidate having sex with a couch is funny, it just is. Much like the memes implying <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362300/kamala-harris-meme-brat-summer">Kamala Harris is a pop icon queening out to “Brat” summer</a>, “JD Vance fucked a couch” is just another absurdity of the wildest election summer in recent history, one where the truth is so much crazier than fiction that the fiction starts becoming believable. No, J.D. Vance didn’t fuck a couch. But he’ll always be remembered as the vice presidential nominee that was once rumored to have fucked a couch. And that’s pretty weird.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a fantastic cameo in Deadpool &#038; Wolverine’s post-credits scene]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362831/deadpool-wolverine-credits-scene-cameo-spoilers" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362831</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T19:51:10Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T21:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Comic Books" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Marvel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major spoiler alert: This post will absolutely ruin this movie for you. Please don’t read this unless you have seen the movie or want to get spoiled.&#160; While the hoopla of Deadpool &#38; Wolverine was all about the introduction of two iconic characters to the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), the movie is also about saying [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Ryan Reynolds as Deadpool and Hugh Jackman as Wolverine in Deadpool &amp; Wolverine. | Marvel Studios" data-portal-copyright="Marvel Studios" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/TDW-14349_R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Ryan Reynolds as Deadpool and Hugh Jackman as Wolverine in Deadpool &amp; Wolverine. | Marvel Studios</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Major spoiler alert: This post will absolutely ruin this movie for you. Please don’t read this unless you have seen the movie or want to get spoiled.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the hoopla of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/356083/deadpool-wolverine-gay-queerbaiting"><em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em></a> was all about the introduction of two iconic characters to the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), the movie is also about saying goodbye. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the film, Deadpool (Ryan Reynolds) faces the prospect of the collapse of his entire timeline, which has been destroyed by the death of Wolverine in 2017’s <em>Logan</em>. To save it, he seeks out a still-living, alternate-universe version of Wolverine (Hugh Jackman). But this new Wolvie has seen the rest of his X-Men die, and he can’t stop blaming himself. Together, they’re sent to the void (the same void that we see in Disney+’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22522332/loki-review-marvel-tom-hiddleston-owen-wilson"><em>Loki</em></a>) where they sync up with an island of misfit toys: Marvel superheroes (mainly from Fox’s filmography) that, for one reason or another, did not make it to Disney’s promised land of perpetual intellectual property. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Deadpool and Wolverine’s fictional conflict is a self-referential gag about <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/3/20/18273477/disney-fox-merger-deal-details-marvel-x-men">Disney’s real-life 2019 acquisition of Fox</a> and its plethora of film rights, which includes some significant Marvel comic book characters. Reynolds’s Deadpool is one of those superheroes, but he&#8217;s currently the only actor playing a Marvel mutant slated to continue on and make the transition to Marvel Studios and the MCU. Having disposable superheroes of yore sent to the MCU trash heap is a meta way for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/2/12/10979782/deadpool-explained">Deadpool to make an inside joke</a> about how Disney (and, to an extent, Marvel) now owns everything, including esoteric superhero nostalgia that you never knew existed and Deadpool himself.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They first meet the <em>Fantastic Four</em>’s Johnny Storm (played by Chris Evans, reprising his pre-MCU role from <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120667/">2005</a>) who Deadpool mistakes for Captain America. All three are captured by the psychic villain Cassandra Nova (Emma Corrin, playing an X-Men comic character we&#8217;ve never seen on film before). After Deadpool taunts her, as he taunts everyone, she telekinetically skins Storm alive before Deadpool and Wolverine make a miraculous, jetpack-fueled escape. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The duo eventually meet Storm’s compatriots, who have been living in this suspended state for years. There&#8217;s the half-human half-vampire Blade (Wesley Snipes, reprising his role from the <a href="https://www.empireonline.com/movies/features/blade-at-25-marvel-vampire-ahead-of-its-time/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Blade</em></a> trilogy), ninja <a href="https://screenrant.com/deadpool-3-elektra-return-jennifer-garner/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Elektra</a> (Jennifer Garner, last seen in the 2005 <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0287978/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_4_tt_8_nm_0_in_0_q_daredevl" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Daredevil</em></a> sequel of the <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0357277/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0_tt_4_nm_4_in_0_q_elektra" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">same name</a>), murder clone X-23 (Dafne Keen, who appeared with Jackman in 2017’s <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3315342/?ref_=nm_knf_c_1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><em>Logan</em></a>), and mutant energy wielder Gambit (Channing Tatum, finally playing the part Disney&#8217;s Fox acquisition supposedly <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/features/general/channing-tatum-marvel-gambit-movie-canceled-disney-fox-deal-1234800607" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">made impossible</a>). Faced with an eternity of storytelling purgatory, the forgotten heroes team up with their new friends to help the two get back to Deadpool’s main timeline. The misfits break into Cassandra’s lair, drawing the attention of her henchmen and allowing the bosom buddies to take on Cassandra. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the film, Deadpool and Wolverine dispatch Nova as well as Paradox (Matthew Macfadyen), the Time Variance Authority (TVA) middle manager who sent them to the void in the first place. They save Deadpool’s collapsing timeline and return home. Blade and the gang are rewarded by getting restored to their own timelines, mainly off-screen. Everything’s squared away and our <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/356083/deadpool-wolverine-gay-queerbaiting" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ambiguously coupled</a> duo get to be friends happily ever after.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And one post-credits scene can’t change that … or can it? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s one scene that happens at the end of <em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em>’s credits scroll. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In it, we find Deadpool at the TVA headquarters. As established in <em>Loki</em>, the TVA are essentially cops who watch every parallel timeline in the multiverse and make sure nothing goes sideways. Also established in <em>Loki</em> — and so many Marvel movies that deal with the splintering <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23024945/everything-everywhere-all-at-once-multiverse-explained-quantum-physicist">multiverse</a> — the TVA are susceptible to serious goofs. (Frankly, they aren’t very good at their job.) They’re also an authoritarian agency that imposes their will on these timelines and the countless people who live within them, so you don’t have to feel bad for them when they mess up. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Deadpool breaks the fourth wall; he wants to clear something up. Although he insulted Cassandra Nova and blamed it on Johnny Storm, he says he isn’t responsible for Storm’s death, even though it seemed like he was. He claims that he simply repeated what Storm told them when they were captured. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To prove his point, he rewinds TVA surveillance footage and shows us what really happened. Sure enough, Johnny Storm unleashes a cuss-filled, raunch-heavy monologue — delivered in Evans’s native Boston accent, no less — that includes references to fellatio, analingus, <a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Cain_Marko_(Earth-616)">Juggernaut</a> secretions, and derogatory comments about Cassandra’s baldness. He tells Deadpool that he can repeat it but would risk being skinned alive if he did because she is so beyond awful. The merc with a mouth is innocent!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps more importantly, he apparently has access to TVA HQ and ostensibly its timeline-jumping technology. By the logic and structure of this convoluted universe, that means Deadpool might be able to show up and snark in any MCU property (which, obviously, Marvel wants you to know). For now, though, he’s just content to show you Chris Evans saying absolutely filthy things.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What we know about the police killing of Sonya Massey]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/criminal-justice/363206/sonya-massey-police-killing-sean-grayson" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=363206</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T19:50:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T19:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Police Violence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Body camera footage released this week offered a harrowing look at the police killing of Sonya Massey, a 36-year-old Black woman in Springfield, Illinois, and renewed scrutiny of the disproportionate violence Black Americans face at the hands of law enforcement.&#160; On July 6, Massey was shot by a sheriff’s deputy in her own home, after [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Malachi Hill Massey, center, speaks at a news conference on July 23, 2024, at the NAACP headquarters in Springfield, Illinois, about his mother, Sonya Massey, who was shot to death by a Sangamon County Sheriff’s deputy. | John O’Connor/AP" data-portal-copyright="John O’Connor/AP" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/AP24205662506993.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Malachi Hill Massey, center, speaks at a news conference on July 23, 2024, at the NAACP headquarters in Springfield, Illinois, about his mother, Sonya Massey, who was shot to death by a Sangamon County Sheriff’s deputy. | John O’Connor/AP</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/video/bodycam-shows-moment-police-fatally-shot-illinois-woman-sonya-massey-215428165541">Body camera footage</a> released this week offered a harrowing look at the police killing of Sonya Massey, a 36-year-old Black woman in Springfield, Illinois, and renewed scrutiny of the <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/nbcblk/report-black-people-are-still-killed-police-higher-rate-groups-rcna17169">disproportionate violence Black Americans</a> face at the hands of law enforcement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On July 6, Massey was shot by a sheriff’s deputy in her own home, after officers responded to her call about a potential prowler. Following checks of her backyard and surrounding area, at least two officers entered her home as part of their visit. Inside, one of them asks her to turn off her stove. While doing so, she picks up a pot of boiling water and the officers back away, noting that they want to distance themselves from it. She makes a comment about rebuking them “in the name of Jesus,” at which point one of them, Sean Grayson, shoots at her three times, including once fatally in the head.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A grand jury has since indicted Grayson on three counts of first-degree murder, with some <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/22/us/sonya-massey-police-shooting/index.html">law enforcement experts</a> questioning why he’d shoot Massey rather than pursue other alternative responses like adding more distance between them or using a taser. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The shooting also adds to a long history of <a href="https://www.vox.com/police-violence">police violence</a> against Black Americans — and underscores how enduring the problem continues to be. In 2020, mass protests erupted across the US following the police murder of George Floyd in Minneapolis, Minnesota, after an officer knelt on his neck for over nine minutes. Those followed extensive demonstrations in 2014 after Michael Brown, an unarmed teenager, was shot and killed by police in Ferguson, Missouri. Massey is also among a number of Black Americans who’ve been shot by police in their own homes, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/24153974/roger-fortson-police-killing">Roger Fortson</a> in Fort Walton Beach, Florida, and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/12/05/us/aaron-dean-trial-atatiana-jefferson-killing/index.html">Atatiana Jefferson</a> in Fort Worth, Texas. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What we know about the incident</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Police arrived at Massey’s home after she called 911 around 12:50 am on July 6, and proceeded to do a sweep around the house. They eventually tell her that they didn’t find anyone in the area and appear prepared to leave, when video shows them entering her home. While speaking with Massey, they also ask her if she’s doing okay mentally and she responds by saying, “Yes, I took my medicine.” Ben Crump, a civil rights attorney for Massey’s family, <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/body-camera-footage-released-illinois-state-police-woman/story?id=112162337">has said she dealt with mental health struggles</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not immediately apparent why the officers then go into Massey’s house, but video shows her looking for her ID. While they’re inside, the officers realize the stove is on and urge Massey to turn it off. As she goes to do so, she moves the pot of boiling water that’s on it, prompting the officers to back away.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Where are you going?” says Massey.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Away from your hot, steaming water,” says Grayson.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Away from my hot, steaming water?,” Massey asks, while holding the pot. “I rebuke you in the name of Jesus.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You better f****** not or I swear to God I’ll f****** shoot you in your f****** face,” says Grayson as he draws his gun.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Massey then says “I’m sorry,” and ducks while raising the pot over her head, as Grayson shoots multiple times and fatally wounds her.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As his colleague moves to get a medical kit from their vehicle, Grayson comments, “Nah, she’s done. You can go get it but that’s a headshot.” <a href="https://cbs58.com/news/illinois-police-release-bodycam-video-of-fatal-shooting-of-black-woman-in-her-home">He also states later,</a> “Yeah I’m good, this f******* b**** is crazy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, a grand jury indicted Grayson on charges of first-degree murder, as well as aggravated battery with a firearm and misconduct, all of which he pleaded not guilty to. He’s also been fired from the Sangamon County Sheriff’s Department, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sangamoncountysheriff/posts/pfbid02VdbzM22GpUQPiEaC5AJWeLHZRT59aNNtM2bDo9LjNLCeiupXFjPtbf9uYdm8rKHKl">which noted that</a> “it is clear that the deputy did not act as trained or in accordance with our standards.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/24/us/sean-grayson-illinois-police-officer-shooting-sonya-massey/index.html">A state’s attorney review</a> of the incident similarly concluded that its analysis “does not support a finding that … Grayson was justified in his use of deadly force.” State prosecutors also cited an expert who described the act as comparable to “an officer intentionally and unnecessarily putting himself in front of a moving vehicle and then justifying use of force because of fear of being struck.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her family has said that Massey — a mother of two — was a “ball of energy,” and a “loving person” who was known for helping those around her. They also noted that they <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/24/us/sean-grayson-illinois-police-officer-shooting-sonya-massey/index.html">weren’t initially told</a> that the shooting had been committed by an officer and that there were early implications it was done by someone else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Massey’s family are now calling for an investigation into the Sheriff’s Department’s hiring of Grayson, who has worked in <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/former-sheriffs-deputy-fatally-shot-sonya-massey-held/story?id=112229695">six different law enforcement agencies</a> in the last four years, and been <a href="https://www.ksdk.com/article/news/crime/illinois-deputy-charged-murder-dui-charges-macoupin-county/63-b1167b53-ef81-4af1-8383-e341359d41b4">charged twice</a> with driving under the influence. According to <a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/07/25/sonya-massey-police-killing-sean-grayson-army/">an Intercept report</a>, Grayson had also been discharged from the military due to misconduct. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of the indictment, prosecutors will continue to pursue the charges against Grayson in a case that could head to trial. He has been denied pretrial release.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>It’s the latest incident to raise concerns about police violence</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Massey’s shooting highlights how pervasive police violence toward Black Americans still is, and the dearth of effective policies that have been passed to combat it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2023, police killed more than 1,300 people, which was a new record, according to the <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2024/01/17/police-killings-record-2023/72174081007/">organization Mapping Police Violence</a>. That same data set found that Black people were almost three times more likely to be killed by police than white people.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Attempts to advance police reforms have varied at the city, state, and federal levels, with places <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/research-reports/state-policing-reforms-george-floyds-murder">like San Francisco investing in crisis response teams</a> that serve as an alternative, and states like Minnesota <a href="https://www.minnpost.com/state-government/2021/04/the-minnesota-legislature-passed-new-deadly-force-standards-for-police-in-2020-why-lawmakers-are-already-looking-to-change-them/">approving new use of force standards</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But any federal compromise on police reform — including attempts after Floyd’s shooting in 2020 to end officers’ protections from legal liability — has thus far faltered.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What Kamala Harris really thinks about Israel and Gaza]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362782</id>
			<updated>2024-07-25T19:03:48Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T19:03:46Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Joe Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s war in Gaza created a rift between moderates and progressives in his party. Now that he has stepped aside in the 2024 presidential race, the question is whether Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic nominee, would chart a different path forward as president. One early signal that [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris speaking from behind a lectern." data-caption="Then-Sen. Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-878131632.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Then-Sen. Kamala Harris addressing the 2017 American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC) Policy Conference in Washington, DC. | Michael Brochstein/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s war in Gaza created a rift between moderates and progressives in his party. Now that he has stepped aside in the 2024 presidential race, the question is whether Vice President Kamala Harris, the presumptive Democratic nominee, would chart a different path forward as president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One early signal that she might: Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu<strong> </strong>addressed Congress on Wednesday, and Harris did not preside in her role as vice president due to a previously scheduled event she chose to attend in Indianapolis. A slew of congressional Democrats (not just progressives) decided not to attend in <a href="https://rollcall.com/2024/07/23/netanyahu-address-creates-a-dilemma-for-democrats/">protest of Netanyahu’s strategy in Gaza</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris will meet with Netanyahu one-on-one on Thursday in her ceremonial office in the Old Executive Office Building, and the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">Wall Street Journal reported</a> that she is expected to tell him “it is time for the war to end in a way where Israel is secure, all hostages are released, the suffering of Palestinian civilians in Gaza ends, and the Palestinian people can enjoy their right to dignity, freedom, and self-determination.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Only days into her campaign, Harris has yet to articulate her Gaza policy, but the fact that she is not attending Netanyahu’s speech and privately communicating the urgency of a ceasefire signals that she might not follow Biden’s lead in giving the Israeli leader a “<a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/world/biden-netanyahu-bear-hug-disaster/">bear hug</a>.” Biden literally embraced Netanyahu on the tarmac when the president landed in Tel Aviv in November as a symbolic gesture of unequivocal support for Israel, and has since kept the prime minister close metaphorically, offering military and financial support.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Harris does change course, even slightly, that could alter the US-Israel relationship, but could also have important electoral consequences as well.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Who could be Harris’s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What does Kamala Harris think about Israel and the war in Gaza?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has longstanding ties to the American Jewish community and Israeli interest groups.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her husband, second gentleman Doug Emhoff, is Jewish and has been at the forefront of the Biden administration’s <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/01/world-economic-forum-davos-antisemitism-herzog-greenblatt-emhoff-rosen/">initiative against antisemitism</a> since Hamas’s October 7 attack on Israel.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has a good working relationship with Israeli President Isaac Herzog, who <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/kamala-harris-has-long-embraced-jewish-ties-but-critics-take-issue-with-gaza-stance/">shares a passion for climate issues</a>. She has also been on every one of the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">more than 20 phone calls</a> that Biden has had with Netanyahu throughout the war.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her presidential bid, she has <a href="https://jewishinsider.com/2024/07/kamala-harris-jewish-democrats-vice-president-presidential-race/">won the backing</a> of major Jewish interest groups, including Democratic Majority for Israel, J Street, and the Jewish Democratic Council of America. She also has connections to the <a href="https://x.com/VP/status/1110301531306409986">American Israel Public Affairs Committee</a> (AIPAC) and gave a speech at the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=McK8bPR8pzU">organization’s annual conference in 2017</a> soon after she was elected to the US Senate, saying that one of her first acts in office was to introduce a resolution opposing a United Nations Security Council resolution condemning Israel. At the time, she said, “I believe the bonds between the United States and Israel are unbreakable.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After protesters outside Congress burned the American flag during Netanyahu’s visit, Harris issued a statement Thursday condemning that action and condemning “any individuals associating with the brutal terrorist organization Hamas, which has vowed to annihilate the State of Israel and kill Jews.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Concerning the war in Gaza, Harris has repeatedly upheld Israel’s “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">right to defend itself</a>” against Hamas and emphasized that the threat posed by Hamas to Israel must be “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">eliminated</a>.” This suggests she’s largely in agreement with Biden’s posture. Harris has, however, taken a sharper tone than Biden concerning Israel’s treatment of civilians in Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a high-profile <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">speech in March</a>, she became the first person in the Biden administration to call for an immediate ceasefire, albeit only a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/03/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-commemorating-the-59th-anniversary-of-bloody-sunday-selma-al/">temporary</a> one. She also said that the Israeli government must do more to increase the flow of aid to Gaza, “no excuses,” and called the situation in Gaza a “humanitarian catastrophe.” The version of the speech that was ultimately delivered had reportedly <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/kamala-harris-gaza-speech-watered-down-cease-fire-rcna141750">been softened</a> from its original draft, which more directly criticized Israel for its obstruction of aid trucks into Gaza.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She also has expressed empathy for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/4/24/24138333/columbia-student-protests-gaza-nyu-divest-faculty">student protesters on college campuses</a> who are horrified by the death and destruction in Gaza and have attempted to pressure their schools into cutting ties with Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They are showing exactly what the human emotion should be, as a response to Gaza,” Harris <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/kamala-harris-interview-profile-excerpt/">told the Nation</a>. “There are things some of the protesters are saying that I absolutely reject, so I don’t mean to wholesale endorse their points. But we have to navigate it. I understand the emotion behind it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If she becomes president, the Wall Street Journal reported that Harris is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/national-security/harriss-support-for-gaza-cease-fire-hints-at-foreign-policy-shift-bbe8dc2a">expected to replace</a> some of the chief architects of the Biden administration’s strategy in Gaza, including national security adviser Jake Sullivan, Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin. It’s to be expected that a new president would want their own team in place, but any changes would open up possibilities for taking a different tack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s national security adviser, Philip Gordon, has emphasized diplomatic rather than military solutions in foreign policy and written extensively about the difficulties of regime change in the Middle East. That background may prove relevant as Israel seeks to root out Hamas and install a new government in Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this suggests that Harris might be somewhat to Biden’s left on Gaza — but by how much is an open question and one that she will have to clarify.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She does have an opportunity. She’s using the right language in some instances. But we need a clearer explanation from her on where she stands,” said Abed Ayoub, national legal and policy director of the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And — as with Joe Biden’s campaign promises to make Saudi Arabia a pariah state — there’s always a chance that what Harris does eventually say while campaigning may change once she’s in office.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Biden’s Gaza policy has been divisive&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politically, Harris faces the quandary of determining if — and by how much — she should distance herself from Biden’s record on Gaza, which has fractured the Democratic base.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden at one point <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/05/08/congress/progressives-cheer-israel-weapon-pause-gop-fume-biden-00156857">paused shipments of large munitions</a> to Israel over concerns about how they would be potentially used against civilians in Gaza but has otherwise continued to offer material support for the war, even after Israeli operations in Gaza’s southernmost city of Rafah <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/07/middleeast/destruction-inside-rafa-gaza-israel-intl/index.html">wreaked widespread destruction</a>. Over <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/latest-israeli-strikes-southern-gaza-palestinian-death-toll-112159613">39,000 Palestinians</a> have already died in the course of the conflict, according to the Gaza Health Ministry.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In May, Biden called for a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/05/31/politics/biden-middle-east-remarks/index.html">deal to end the war</a> and return the remaining Israeli hostages in Gaza, while continuing to advocate for a two-state solution to the decades-long Israeli-Palestinian conflict. But the Israeli parliament has since voted to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/israels-knesset-votes-overwhelmingly-palestinian-statehood-netanyahu-p-rcna162466">reject a two-state solution</a> and ceasefire talks are still ongoing two months later.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, Biden promised he would <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/22/biden-gaza-war-end-hostages-return-pledge">deliver a ceasefire</a> deal before he leaves office. He did not elaborate on how he plans to overcome the roadblocks that have stalled negotiations thus far.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Progressives have for months been calling on Biden to halt weapons shipments to Gaza and put more pressure on Israel to end the war. Over 650,000 Democrats <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/05/biden-uncommitted-primary-vote-00161700">voted “uncommitted”</a> in the primary to protest Biden’s policies, and the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/video/opinion/100000009565908/biden-voters-dearborn-michigan.html">scale of the opposition to Biden in the Midwest</a> appeared as though it could have tipped the election in Trump’s favor in swing states including Michigan and Wisconsin. Depending on how Harris positions herself, she could win back some of those voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think there is excitement that [Biden] is not at the top of the ticket,” said Layla Elabed, a Palestinian American organizer in Michigan who helped lead the uncommitted movement, and the sister of Rep. Rashida Tlaib (D-MI). “But we are also right now watching and listening to what Harris is going to do next.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, however, Democrats and Republicans <a href="https://www.newsnationnow.com/world/war-in-israel/most-americans-support-israel-over-hamas-poll/">remain largely supportive</a> of Israel’s campaign. Since Israel’s establishment in 1948, the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/10/11/politics/presidents-israel-cnn/index.html">US has maintained a special relationship with the country</a>. It has been the largest cumulative recipient of American foreign aid since its founding, <a href="https://www.cfr.org/article/us-aid-israel-four-charts">totaling about $310 billion</a> (adjusted for inflation) in total economic and military assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For these reasons, it’s unlikely that Harris will deviate substantially from Biden on Israel — and if there is any change in her policy, it would be only slight. The question will be whether any changes can win back voters that the president has alienated without losing the voters who embraced his stance.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This leaves Harris with a difficult political tightrope to walk. But unlike Biden, she isn’t weighed down with the direct responsibility for all that has happened so far.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, July 25, 3 pm ET:</strong></em><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/362782/kamala-harris-gaza-israel-palestine-biden-netanyahu"> </a><em>This story, originally published July 24, has been updated with developments after Netanyahu’s speech to Congress.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Inspired by the Olympics? You can become an athlete at any age.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/362550/getting-into-sports-age-olympics-motivation-athlete-gymnastics-track-basketball-swimming" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362550</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T16:42:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a child, Brian Hankerson daydreamed not of watching television or getting into trouble with friends after school. He wanted to high jump. A grade school-aged Hankerson would rush home from class, set up a fishing pole supported by two chairs, lay out a blanket beneath it, and hurtle his body over the makeshift setup.  [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of eight people playing different sports, including tennis, soccer, volleyball, golf, badminton, football, and running." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1973203086.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">As a child, Brian Hankerson daydreamed not of watching television or getting into trouble with friends after school. He wanted to high jump. A grade school-aged Hankerson would rush home from class, set up a fishing pole supported by two chairs, lay out a blanket beneath it, and hurtle his body over the makeshift setup. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the decades following, Hankerson never formally trained or competed as a runner or high jumper. That is, until his mid-40s, when he noticed adults racing at a track-and-field meet his kids were also participating in. “They weren’t young adults, they were older adults,” Hankerson says. Hankerson, a Coral Springs, Florida-based accountant, signed up to compete in a division called masters — <a href="https://world-masters-athletics.org/world-masters-athletics/">for those aged 35 and up</a> — and wound up setting meet records for the high jump and long jump. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now 64, Hankerson still competes across the country and internationally — he’s headed to the World Masters Athletics Championships in Sweden this August — and continues to sing the praises of organized athletics for adults. “If I can get out and push the envelope beyond what I think I can do, or I feel like I can do, then so can you,” he says. “Do you believe you can get out there and accomplish something? You will absolutely not know until you try.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Hankerson can attest, there’s no time like the present to pursue athletics, no matter your age. But the older we get, the more we suspect our time has passed. While kids are offered the freedom to dabble and play when they first pick up a sport, adults <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23979535/permission-to-suck-terrible-hobbies">feel like they have to be good at it</a> or else the endeavor isn’t worth their time. “When adults come in for our gymnastics classes, they’re very apprehensive about doing new things with their body, or doing things they haven’t done in a very long time, and they get scared,” says Jackie Alexis, the recreational gymnastics coach at <a href="https://www.industrygymnastics.com/">Industry Gymnastics</a>, a Long Island-based gymnastics school for all ages and abilities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p> “Do you believe you can get out there and accomplish something? You will absolutely not know until you try.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358882/simone-biles-olympic-trials-paris-floor-vault">2024 Paris Olympics</a> upon us, you might be feeling particularly inspired to learn a sport, or wistful about ones you weren’t able to try in the past. But there’s so much to gain when picking up — or returning to — a sport, coaches say. Not only are you moving your body and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6908518/">learning new skills</a>, but you’re <a href="https://systematicreviewsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13643-023-02264-8">fostering social connections</a> in a niche community — all of which have positive <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9902068/">impacts on mental</a> and <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC11043276/">physical health</a>. If you don’t know where to start or are unsure of how to build athletics into your routine, coaches and athletes have some tips.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Let your interests motivate you</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From baseball to badminton, there are a myriad of athletic endeavors to choose from. Think about the sports currently capturing your attention, whether it’s Olympic gymnastics or <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24139393/challengers-sexy-tennis-zendaya-luca-guadagnino-investigation">tennis, thanks to <em>Challengers</em>,</a> and the ones that intrigued you as a kid. Use your interests — past and present — as a guide when selecting your sport.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If nothing comes to mind, let yourself be influenced. Patrick “Pat The Roc” Robinson began offering adult basketball classes at his <a href="https://pattherocacademy.com/">basketball skills academy</a> to keep parents of youth players engaged while their kids were practicing. Over time, parents began to take notice of the other lesson taking place during their child’s practice. “Each week, we get more and more parents that just happen to be in the gym,” Robinson says, “and they see the other adults participate. Now, they’re not ashamed or they’re not nervous about joining.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for classes, but don’t splurge on gear</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Enrolling in a class is often the best first step when diving into a new sport. Coaches will teach you proper form, safety, and the rules of the game, and have equipment for you to use. Knowing you have practice every Thursday night offers structure and consistency, which is helpful for building routine, Robinson says. You can also join a local club for free but less individualized instruction. Resist the urge to spend exorbitant amounts of money on new gear, Alexis and Robinson say.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a few options to find classes near you. See if your town’s parks and recreation department offers adult sport lessons or leagues — these may be cheaper than private gyms. Browse social media, like your city’s subreddit or local Facebook groups dedicated to specific sports to find recommended coaches or instructors.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Start with small, consistent efforts every day</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When people are super inspired, they tend to jump into their new sport headfirst, says <a href="https://www.teamsoho.org/coaches.html">Lucy Glanville</a>, the youth programming head coach at <a href="https://utaholympiclegacy.org/soldier-hollow-sports/">Soldier Hollow Nordic Center</a>, a facility that was used during the 2002 Olympic Winter Games in Salt Lake City. This excitement is motivating in the short-term, but a two-hour pickleball lesson might leave you so sore the next day that you never want to pick up a paddle again. Small, daily, consistent efforts will ensure you won’t get burned out, Glanville says. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For instance, Robinson tells his adult students to practice their shooting form sans basketball throughout the week between practices; Alexis breaks down every gymnastics move into incremental steps. “Some people come in, and they’re like, ‘I want to do a backflip,’” they say. “I’m like, ‘Let’s work our way up to that.’” </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“You can control getting your shoes on, stepping outside, and starting.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can also set incremental goals or milestones that support your consistency-building habits, Glanville says, making sure they are easily achievable and within your control. If your ultimate goal is to run a 10k, give yourself mini-goals that are more about the <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23344385/beginners-guide-running">process of running, rather than the outcome</a> of finishing a race. “You can’t control whether your body’s going to make 10k that first time,” Glanville says, “but you can control getting your shoes on, stepping outside, and starting. Focusing on that start process and what it is that you can do, as opposed to what the dream is.” These smaller wins boost your confidence and allow you to set bigger goals. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Bring a friend (and be open to making friends)</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re nervous about starting a new sport with a bunch of strangers, enlist a friend to come with you. Not only will you feel comfortable with a familiar face, but you can hold each other accountable. At Industry Gymnastics, friend groups often sign up for adult classes, Alexis says. “And if they come by themselves, they quickly make friends with the other people who come by themselves,” they say.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The social aspect of athletics is what brings players year after year to the adult basketball training center <a href="https://nevertoolate.com/">Never Too Late Basketball</a>, according to its founder, Steve Bzomowski. Ever since Never Too Late held their first clinic over 30 years ago, players have remarked on the organization’s ability to bring people together to collaborate. “People just really like the idea of getting together, meeting people you never knew before,” Bzomowski says, “and creating something that you had no idea that you could create.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Push yourself, but know your limits</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bzomowski wants to remind beginner adult athletes that they are capable of learning a new skill — it’s why he named his basketball clinic Never Too Late. At the end of weekend-long camps, each player is recognized for their particular strengths, whether it’s passing or effectively communicating, he says. Regardless of your skill level, there are areas where you will excel. While everyone’s bodies and abilities vary, Hankerson says you may be surprised at what your body can achieve. “I do something at 60 better than I did at 50,” he says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kelley Shaw, the program director at Industry Gymnastics, believes no one is too old to learn gymnastics, but “you don’t have to do every skill,” she says. “You can do the ones that you feel comfortable with and don’t hurt.” This approach can apply to all sports: Give a drill or exercise your best effort, but listen to your body and ask your instructor for modifications if needed.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Don’t compete with anyone but yourself</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Adult gymnasts at Industry Gymnastics are often concerned with doing a move or drill perfectly, Shaw and Alexis say. But both instructors say learning a new skill or brushing up on old ones requires some imperfection before you start to improve. As difficult as it may be, don’t compare your abilities to your classmates’ — or your younger self. “Just try to do better than yourself each day,” Hankerson says, “not someone else you see on TV or on YouTube or at the track meet. Don’t worry about that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Through these struggles, small accomplishments, and big wins, you learn about yourself, Bzomowski says. You learn what your body is capable of, how you work with other people, and what you’re able to overcome. “It’s not <em>just</em>, ‘I didn’t know whether I was capable of this physically,’” he says. “Feeling resistance within myself and overcoming that — I think that’s a big part of it.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s one perfect way to see Twisters]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362928/how-to-see-twisters-4dx-perfect-way-imax-rpx-explained" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362928</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T23:34:08Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had no business enjoying Twisters as much as I did.&#160; For one, I’m not a fan of disaster movies. Nor do I have a relationship to the original 1996 film Twister — although, it turns out you don’t need to know anything about the first movie to watch this stand-alone sequel. I didn’t walk [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Characters in the movie Twisters: one lying on the ground holding the other, who is being pulled into the air." data-caption="A still of actors Sasha Lane and Glen Powell from the new film Twisters. | Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-portal-copyright="Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/2571_D038_00298RV2_CROP_641680.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A still of actors Sasha Lane and Glen Powell from the new film Twisters. | Melinda Sue Gordon/Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I had no business enjoying <em>Twisters</em> as much as I did.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For one, I’m not a fan of disaster movies. Nor do I have a relationship to the original 1996 film <em>Twister</em> — although, it turns out you don’t need to know anything about the first movie to watch this stand-alone sequel. I didn’t walk out of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/359689/storm-chasing-twister-tornado-expert"><em>Twisters</em></a> thinking that it was particularly good. The performances by Daisy Edgar-Jones and (sorry) <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/361486/glen-powell-explained-twisters-hit-man-anyone-but-you">Glen Powell</a> were mediocre. The dialogue was silly. The music cues were laughable. Every aspect of the film felt like it was focus-grouped, including the omission of a climactic kiss between the two “romantic” leads. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how did I manage to leave<em> Twisters</em> elated, you might ask? I paid an extra $6 to see it in 4DX, an “immersive” theater experience that feels like the only way anyone should consume this ridiculous film. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the uninitiated, 4DX is sort of like if you watched an entire action movie inside one of those virtual-reality space shuttles at an amusement park — only a lot more visceral. The experience at Regal Cinemas includes motion-enabled seats that jolt and rotate. In the case of <em>Twisters</em>, there are bursts of wind, trickles of rain, and fog. You’re also guaranteed a heightened communal experience. At my screening, several set pieces were followed by loud applause, including after a tragic scene where innocent characters die. By the end of the film, I had no idea whether everyone was responding to the events in the film or to the chaotic bodily experience we had all endured together. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/2571_FP_00623B-3587x1500-d3275b2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=10.064120434904,0,79.871759130192,100" alt="A man and woman stand with their backs to the camera, facing a swirling cloud." title="A man and woman stand with their backs to the camera, facing a swirling cloud." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Glen Powell and Daisy Edgar-Jones in &lt;em&gt;Twisters&lt;/em&gt;. | Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" data-portal-copyright="Universal Pictures, Warner Bros. Pictures, and Amblin Entertainment" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Twisters</em> has already done a lot of <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tyvid5/video/7393766876129578283">good advertising</a> for the limited format. The film made $2.1 million in 4DX tickets during its opening weekend, and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@mnelson1610/video/7394233559055142175">moviegoers</a> can’t <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@thevelasquezfamilia/video/7393819455521901867">stop</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@tyvid5/video/7394553154374831403">raving</a> about the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@trulyoliviaa/video/7395063773020589342">experience</a> on social media. It’s certainly good advertising leading up to <em>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</em>, out this weekend, which can also be experienced for a limited time in 4DX.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX is just one of many movie formats that has made moviegoing more exciting but also a lot more confusing — and expensive. With streaming keeping more people at home, theater chains seem focused on selling premium experiences. However, are they enhancing the experience of moviegoing or complicating it with all these different options? The answer might be both. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Why are there so many movie theater formats?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’ve bought a movie ticket recently, you’ve probably noticed the increasing number of premium formats available. The list of options for <em>Twisters</em> in the New York City area is comically long and utterly perplexing. In addition to 4DX, you can also pay to see the film in IMAX, Laser at AMC, IMAX with Laser at AMC, Dolby Cinema at AMC, Prime at AMC, RPX, and Screen X. You could also see it in the standard digital 2D format, the cheapest of all these options. However, when listed alongside all these formats that sound innately fancy — even if you don’t have the vaguest idea what they mean — a standard screening might seem less ideal. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-660166846.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.669135487166,100,78.661729025667" alt="4DX seats in a theater." title="4DX seats in a theater." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The 4DX “Twist and Sway” chairs displayed during 2017 CinemaCon in Las Vegas, Nevada. | Bryan Steffy/Getty Images for 4DX" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Steffy/Getty Images for 4DX" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">So what do these formats entail exactly? For the most part, they magnify how you see and hear a movie. IMAX, which is shot on IMAX cameras using 70mm film, is probably the best-known. A more exclusive format like RPX is still a bit more foreign. <a href="https://www.regmovies.com/rpx">RPX</a> (Regal Premium Experience) is Regal Cinema’s in-house larger-screen format, which features an updated sound system. It’s not as high-quality as IMAX, nor is it as premium as <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/dolby-showcases-the-immersive-power-of-dolby-cinema-in-latest-love-more-global-brand-campaign-302073543.html">Dolby Digital Cinema</a>, which is located in AMC theaters. Dolby Cinema uses dual 4K laser projectors, which has four times more resolution than a standard theater projector. These theaters are also equipped with Dolby Atmos, an ultra-surround sound system that includes speakers in the ceilings and transducers in the seats.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Laser at AMC uses laser projectors in place of digital ones, while <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/imax-launches-next-generation-imax-with-laser-experience-to-enhance-blockbuster-moviegoing-at-amc-theatres-300635259.html">Laser with IMAX</a> simply combines their respective technologies. <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/amc-to-bring-cinionic-laser-to-all-prime-at-amc-locations-301814426.html">PRIME at AMC</a> boasts Cinionic laser projectors, better acoustics, and “sublime seating.” (On paper, it doesn’t seem that different from Laser.) Lastly, Screen X is a more immersive experience, using a 270-degree panoramic presentation system. Like 4DX, it’s an export from South Korea. It’s equally gimmicky, expanding images along the walls during key scenes to make audiences feel like they’re inside a room or on a battlefield. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As confusing and even unnecessary as they may be, the advent of these new, snazzy formats makes sense in a time when people need some extra motivation to leave their couches to go sit in a theater. With the popularity of streaming and with films going quickly from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/02/28/media/movies-streaming-box-office-theaters/index.html">theaters to VOD</a>, it seems as though theater chains have to promote themselves differently — not just with their film offerings but with a unique experience that can’t be emulated at home. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The strategy of selling a movie in a special format seemed to work for <a href="https://variety.com/2023/film/news/oppenheimer-imax-70mm-craze-projectors-1235697085/"><em>Oppenheimer</em></a>. While IMAX is hardly a new format, Christopher Nolan’s urging of the public to see <em>Oppenheimer</em> on the biggest screen possible, whether in IMAX 70mm or non-IMAX 70mm, seemed largely related to the overall success of the film. Not only did IMAX theaters sell out rapidly, particularly in New York City, but the level of demand prompted an <a href="https://variety.com/2023/film/news/oppenheimer-imax-70mm-extended-tickets-1235689899/">extended IMAX run</a>. It also reminded audiences how much the size of their screens and quality of a picture can highlight good filmmaking. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX, however, is an entirely different beast. Its goal is to entertain the audience, not elevate art. While it could grow into a huge cash cow for theater chains, it’s hard to know if it’s ultimately what’s best for cinema as a whole.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How does 4DX affect moviegoing?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Twisters</em> might do for 4DX what <em>Oppenheimer</em> did for IMAX. Critics and average moviegoers alike are spreading the gospel of the format online and selling out showings. This is certainly the most PR 4DX screenings have gotten since they arrived in America in 2014. But is this something we could see the film industry push back on? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">4DX is designed to heighten moviegoers’ senses and put them inside of the film. But there’s an argument to be made that all the movement and effects distract from the story being told onscreen. I spent most of my <em>Twisters </em>viewing waiting for action sequences so that I could be jolted in my seat and giggle with my friends. Additionally, it was hard to pay much attention to the direction of the film, the dialogue, or the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/359689/storm-chasing-twister-tornado-expert">science behind the storm-chasing</a> while being thrashed around. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the case of a silly movie about tornadoes, I didn’t feel like I was robbed. My friends and I agreed we would’ve been bored out of our minds if we had watched <em>Twisters</em> in any other format. Still, we walked away with a reaction that wasn’t truly genuine. Nor did we respond properly to the tone the film was trying to create in certain moments. For instance, a devastating opening sequence that sets up a post-traumatic arc for Edgar-Jones’s character, Kate, was met with excitement and laughter. Who knows whether being more locked into this moment would’ve made the stakes of the film feel more real. It’s hard to argue that you need to respect the gravitas of a film like <em>Twisters</em>, but for a higher-quality movie with good performances, one can imagine some seriousness being lost. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It has yet to be seen if 4DX will be an actual “threat” to cinema. Right now, there are only 50 4DX theaters in the United States. Plus, the higher ticket price, an <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/05/27/4dx-movie-experience.html">average of $8</a> more than a standard ticket, may not be worth it to certain moviegoers. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it’s not hard to see this becoming the next great film-viewing debate. Given the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2015/5/1/8528111/watching-movies-on-smartphones-spike-lee">panic</a> filmmakers have already displayed over young people watching movies on their iPhones, one can imagine the sort of uproar in Hollywood if 4DX became a bigger phenomenon. For now, though, it seems Americans haven’t been more excited about a new theater technology since before the pandemic. If film executives continue to feed us horrible IP, we might as well be allowed to rock out in our seats. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[J.D. Vance has made it impossible for Trump to run away from Project 2025]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362917/jd-vance-project-2025-book-kevin-roberts-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362917</id>
			<updated>2024-07-24T21:52:20Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-25T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former President Donald Trump has lately been trying to distance himself from Project 2025, claiming it was cooked up by the “severe right” and that he doesn’t know anything about it. But it turns out the severe right is coming from inside the house. Kevin Roberts, the self-proclaimed “head” of Project 2025, has a book [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="J.D. Vance, with a serious expression, points while speaking from a podium reading Trump Vance 2024, and standing in front of a US flag." data-caption="Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) speaks at a campaign rally at Radford University on July 22, 2024, in Radford, Virginia. | Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Alex Wong/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2163101562.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Sen. J.D. Vance (R-OH) speaks at a campaign rally at Radford University on July 22, 2024, in Radford, Virginia. | Alex Wong/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Former President Donald Trump has lately been trying to distance himself from <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a>, claiming it was cooked up by the “<a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/donald-trump-project-2025-rally-b2583142.html">severe right</a>” and that he doesn’t know anything about it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it turns out the severe right is coming from inside the house.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kevin Roberts, the self-proclaimed “head” of Project 2025, has a book coming out in September — and the book’s foreword is written by Trump’s vice presidential candidate, J.D. Vance, who lavishly praises its ideas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Never before has a figure with Roberts’s depth and stature within the American Right tried to articulate a genuinely new future for conservatism,” Vance writes, according to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dawns-Early-Light-Burning-Washington/dp/0063353504">the book’s Amazon page</a>. “We are now all realizing that it’s time to circle the wagons and load the muskets. In the fights that lay ahead, these ideas are an essential weapon.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What ideas? Like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361455/jd-vance-trump-vice-president-rnc-speech">Vance</a>, Roberts is obsessed with the idea that the left controls major American institutions — he lists Ivy League colleges, the FBI, the New York Times, the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, the Department of Education and even the <a href="https://www.netgalley.com/catalog/book/420673">Boy Scouts of America</a>. The book argues that “conservatives need to burn down” these institutions if “we’re to preserve the American way of life.” (Vox has requested a copy of the book, but has not yet received one at the time of this writing.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obviously, this poses a problem for Trump’s attempts to distance himself from the virally unpopular Project 2025 and its lengthy agenda for what he should do if he wins, which includes proposals to restrict abortion access and centralize executive power in the presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it’s one more indication that Trump’s pick of Vance <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/184106/trump-picking-jd-vance-mistake-biden-kamala-harris">might be politically problematic</a> for him. Vance <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug">has a fascination</a> with provocative and extreme far-right thinkers, and a history of praising their ideas. He is not a running mate tailored to win over swing voters who are concerned Trump might be too extreme — quite the opposite.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The book was written and announced before Vance was chosen as Trump’s running mate. But there’s some indication that people involved had some late second thoughts about it. It was <a href="https://x.com/Bon__Mots/status/1813587219351048196">originally announced</a> as “Dawn’s Early Light: Burning Down Washington to Save America,” with a cover image showing a match over the word “Washington.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More recently, though, the subtitle <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dawns-Early-Light-Burning-Washington-ebook/dp/B0CQHPFHWT/ref=sr_1_2?crid=3F2DU567XZRSM&amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.JJLB_KRiLLo1NMFtP-Gn4QnL_zVCR2ltpQaz8WLfQv5qVRf1xKTRhDIadUQ1KDANwziEvWMvIWXuq0d1vCJ5CgwkqFh0izVjpNc5Sz4-vudQnl90jezYmPx2BwZ3kcDtO4GIU83tYBEf9CkFqakSU0et4r0Kx8AvQD6v4zA1Qmht_1dWAzZdbSBzkt1ny8RF9ODuCzbcx9BpmrUQLWC2R4XjMqTQDEFsBIukdihaN1M.FMN8-LJ7hQn6C46DwhNNw32atyu_1it28xVsF8M3bnU&amp;dib_tag=se&amp;keywords=dawns+early+light&amp;qid=1721743470&amp;s=books&amp;sprefix=dawns+early+light%2Cstripbooks%2C123&amp;sr=1-2">has been changed</a> to “Taking Back Washington to Save America,” and the match has vanished from the cover.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Roberts headed Project 2025 — and contributed some of its most controversial proposals</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025, which I recently <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">wrote about at length</a>, is the conservative movement’s detailed and specific plan for what the next Republican president should do with his power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was crafted by people who have long worked closely with Trump and includes many policies Trump clearly supports — like centralizing power in the presidency over career civil service professionals, slashing regulations, and abandoning efforts to fight climate change. It also contains some proposals Trump currently finds politically problematic: aggressively using federal power to prevent abortions, restricting some contraceptive coverage, and banning pornography.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025 was put together by the conservative Heritage Foundation, which worked on it with more than 100 conservative groups. Though much of <a href="https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf">its 922-page policy document</a> is written in dry, wonkish language, Roberts wrote the fiery introduction. The porn ban is his idea specifically — he writes:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">Pornography should be outlawed. The people who produce and distribute it should be imprisoned. Educators and public librarians who purvey it should be classed as registered sex offenders. And telecommunications and technology firms that facilitate its spread should be shuttered.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On abortion, Roberts writes: “Conservatives in the states and in Washington, including in the next conservative Administration, should push as hard as possible to protect the unborn in every jurisdiction in America.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.heritage.org/staff/kevin-d-roberts-phd">Roberts</a>, who has led Heritage since late 2021, has a history of controversial statements. “We are in the process of the second American Revolution, which will remain bloodless if the left allows it to be,” he <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/kevin-roberts-man-behind-project-2025-just-said-the-quiet-part-out-loud">recently said</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Vance is a big fan. “I was thrilled to write the foreword for this incredible book, which contains a bold new vision for the future of conservatism in America,” he <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1803537040555876682">tweeted in June</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tucker Carlson, who was heavily featured at the recent Republican National Convention, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0063353504#:~:text=%E2%80%9CThere%20aren%E2%80%99t%20many%20public%20policy%20executives%20in%20Washington%20who%20actually%20understand%20where%20the%20world%20is%20going%20or%20why.%20In%20fact%2C%20I%E2%80%99ve%20met%20just%20one%3A%20Kevin%20Roberts%20of%20The%20Heritage%20Foundation.%20This%20is%20his%20plan%20to%20save%20America.%20It%E2%80%99s%20deep%20and%20wise.%E2%80%9D%20%E2%80%94%20Tucker%20Carlson">has also praised</a> the book and Roberts’s “plan to save America,” calling it “deep and wise.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vance agrees quite a bit with Project 2025’s most extreme ideas</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Project 2025 contains a multitude of proposals in its 922-page plan, not all of which J.D. Vance necessarily supports.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he’s on record backing ideas similar to those put forth in two of Project 2025’s most controversial issue areas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first is abortion. Project 2025 lays out <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce#:~:text=3)%20A%20hardline,fetal%20cell%20research">a sweeping agenda</a> by which the next president could use federal power to prevent abortions, including using an old law called the Comstock Act to prosecute people who mail abortion pills, and working to prevent women from abortion-banning states from traveling out of state to get abortions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance is on record supporting these ideas. Last year, he <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/07/17/jd-vance-abortion-comstock-vice-presidential-nominee/">signed</a> a letter demanding that the Justice Department prosecute physicians and pharmacists “who break the Federal mail-order abortion laws.” In 2022, he said he was “sympathetic” to the idea that the federal government <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">should stop</a> efforts to help women traveling out of their states to get abortions. That year, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">also said</a>: “I certainly would like abortion to be illegal nationally.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At other points, Vance has struck a different tone. ““We have to accept that people do not want blanket abortion bans,” he said <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/kfile-jd-vance-abortion-comments/index.html">last December</a>. And this month <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/2024/06/supreme-court-preserves-access-to-abortion-pill/">he said</a> he supported a Supreme Court decision that allowed the abortion bill mifepristone to remain available. Here, Vance is trying to align with Trump, who — fearing political blowback — argues he merely wants abortion to be a state issue, despite his long alliance with the religious right. But Vance’s record implies his true agenda might be otherwise.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second controversial area where Vance is sympatico with Project 2025 is centralizing presidential power over the executive branch. The project lays out various proposals to rein in what conservatives view as an out-of-control “deep state” bureaucracy — mainly, by firing far more career civil servants and installing far more political appointees throughout the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361455/jd-vance-trump-vice-president-rnc-speech">as I wrote last week,</a> has backed a maximalist version of this agenda. In 2021, Vance <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2022/04/inside-the-new-right-where-peter-thiel-is-placing-his-biggest-bets">said</a> that in Trump’s second term, Trump should “fire every single midlevel bureaucrat, every civil servant in the administrative state, replace them with our people.” The courts would try to stop this, Vance continued, and Trump should then “stand before the country like Andrew Jackson did, and say, ‘The chief justice has made his ruling. Now let him enforce it.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it’s no big surprise that Vance would write the foreword for a book by Project 2025’s architect. They fundamentally agree on how they see the world, and in much of what they want out of politics: a battle against the left for control of institutions, and expanded government power to stop abortions.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
