<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-23T06:05:32Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris just revealed her formula for taking down Trump]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/368489/kamala-harris-dnc-speech-takeaways-analysis" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368489</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T06:05:32Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-23T06:05:32Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris’s Democratic convention speech served two purposes: She introduced herself to the American people, and she revealed the case she intends to prosecute against Donald Trump. Harris picked familiar targets: Trump’s attack on democracy, his approach to taxes, and his anti-abortion rights record. But on each, she took a slightly new tack. Democrats (and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris, Democratic presidential nominee, speaks on the final night of the Democratic National Convention at the United Center in Chicago, Illinois, on  August 22, 2024. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2167983715.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris, Democratic presidential nominee, speaks on the final night of the Democratic National Convention at the United Center in Chicago, Illinois, on  August 22, 2024. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368462/kamala-harris-israel-palestine-gaza-dnc-speech">Democratic convention speech</a> served two purposes: She introduced herself to the American people, and she revealed the case she intends to prosecute against Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris picked familiar targets: Trump’s attack on democracy, his approach to taxes, and his anti-abortion rights record. But on each, she took a slightly new tack.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats (and pundits) have warned for years about the threat Trump poses to democracy, but Harris connected it to a critique of his character — that he is fundamentally out for “himself,” not for typical Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wonks have been raising the alarm about a Trump policy to impose 10 percent tariffs on all imports — but Harris rebranded this plan as the “Trump tax.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, Harris asked voters to believe that Trump would side with allies who are pushing sweeping anti-abortion policies — rather than believing what he’s saying about the issue as he campaigns.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1) Harris warned of a second-term Trump “with no guardrails”</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris tagged Trump as “an unserious man,” but argued that the consequences of putting him back in the White House “are extremely serious.” Part of that involved recapping his attempt to steal the 2020 election (“he tried to throw away your votes”) and his criminal conviction (“for an entirely different set of crimes, he was found guilty of fraud”).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Harris <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">argued</a> that next time could well be worse because of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">Supreme Court ruling</a> last month giving presidents broad immunity from prosecution for acts they commit as president. “Just imagine Donald Trump with no guardrails,” Harris said. “How he would use the immense powers of the presidency of the United States. Not to improve your life. Not to strengthen our national security. But to serve the only client he has ever had: himself.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is an important recognition that <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368024/kamala-harris-democratic-convention-speech-democracy-joe-biden">the democracy issue</a> is bigger than just repeating that Trump is a convicted felon or that January 6 was bad. Indeed, Harris treated Trump’s conviction as a small part of a larger argument that he is a fundamentally corrupt person, unfit for the presidency, and out for himself rather than everyday Americans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Later on, while discussing foreign policy, she was even more blunt. “Trump won’t hold autocrats accountable,” she said, “because he wants to be an autocrat.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2) Harris characterized Trump’s import tariff proposal as a “Trump tax”</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On economic policy, Harris went on to characterize Trump as fighting “for himself and his billionaire friends” rather than the middle class. “He will give them another round of tax breaks that will add $5 trillion to the national debt,” Harris said. But she also zeroed in on a Trump policy that <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/363146/trump-policy-war-mexico-trade-deportation-border">hasn’t gotten enough attention yet</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of Trump’s major campaign proposals this year is for <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-tariffs-proposal-10-percent-1700-cost-per-us-household/">a 10 percent tariff</a> on all foreign goods imported into the US — a policy that has been much criticized because it would lead to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/21/opinion/ezra-klein-matthew-yglesias.html">higher prices</a> for Americans buying such goods. Yet Democrats haven’t really effectively attacked Trump on this, perhaps in part because the word “tariff” is boring and makes people tune out.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So Harris chose a different word. “He intends to enact what, in effect, is a national sales tax — call it a Trump tax — that would raise prices on middle-class families by almost $4,000 a year,” she said. (In contrast, she said, she would support a middle-class tax cut “that will benefit more than 100 million Americans.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, it’s Republicans who claim their opponents are proposing scary-sounding tax hikes and Democrats who are struggling to defend themselves. But attacking a “Trump tax” seems like a savvy and potentially effective way to go after Trump’s tariff proposal. Expect to hear much more of this as the campaign continues.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3) Harris argued Trump would side with his “allies” on abortion</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On abortion rights, Harris first made it crystal-clear that it was Trump’s “hand-picked members of the United States Supreme Court” who overturned abortion rights. (A surprising number of voters in swing states <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/15/upshot/abortion-biden-trump-blame.html">hold the mistaken belief</a> that Biden did it.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris quoted Trump’s <a href="https://www.snopes.com/fact-check/trump-roe-alabama-ivf/">remark</a> at a Fox News town hall taking credit for overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em>: “I did it, and I’m proud to have done it.” She then pivoted to arguing that Trump’s second term would bring about awful developments for reproductive rights:</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“As a part of his agenda, he and his allies would limit access to birth control, ban medication abortion, and enact a nationwide abortion ban with or without Congress. And get this, he plans to create a national anti-abortion coordinator and force states to report on women’s miscarriages and abortions.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Simply put,” she continued, “they are out of their minds.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Trump has not actually said he would do any of those things. He’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/366495/trump-medication-abortion-mifepristone">been hazy</a> on what he’d do on abortion policy if elected again but has typically suggested he’d try to leave things to the states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Harris is suggesting he’s lying and that he would in fact end up siding with extreme proposals put forth by some of his key anti-abortion rights allies.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are proposals to limit access to certain birth control and roll back federal approval of medication abortion drugs in <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">Project 2025</a> – the policy plan for the next GOP president cooked up by conservative advocates (including many former Trump appointees) that Trump has tried to partially disavow now that it’s become a political liability for him. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s suggestion that Trump and his allies would ban abortion nationwide is unlikely to prove correct. Such a sweeping proposal isn’t even in Project 2025 and is viewed on the right as politically impossible (though anti-abortion rights groups would in a perfect world love to see it happen).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Trump will have a hard time pushing back against these critiques because he did appoint those Supreme Court justices who overturned <em>Roe</em>. The reality is that anti-abortion rights activists are one of Trump and the GOP’s most important and loyal constituencies, and they push to rein in abortion rights to the greatest extent they think is politically possible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s anti-abortion allies dictated his positions on the issue his first time in office. Harris wants to make the case that they’ll do that again if he wins a second term.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How a Beyoncé rumor engulfed the DNC]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/368466/dnc-beyonce-taylor-swift-rumors-reports" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368466</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T05:24:19Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-23T05:20:52Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[At the end of the day, the most pressing question surrounding the 2024 Democratic National Convention was: Where the hell is Beyoncé?&#160; The answer: Not at the DNC.&#160; To be clear, the idea of the greatest performer and arguably biggest pop star on the planet showing up to Chicago’s United Center and playing one song [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Beyonce in all black walking onto a stage." data-caption="Beyoncé not at the 2024 DNC. | Michael Buckner/Billboard via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Michael Buckner/Billboard via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2123634097.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Beyoncé not at the 2024 DNC. | Michael Buckner/Billboard via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the day, the most pressing question surrounding the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/367672/dnc-democratic-national-convention-harriz-walz-live-updates">2024 Democratic National Convention</a> was: Where the hell is Beyoncé?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The answer: Not at the DNC.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, the idea of the greatest performer and arguably biggest pop star on the planet showing up to Chicago’s United Center and playing one song to a sea of political dorks and lawmakers is, without a doubt, far-fetched. But it didn’t come out of nowhere. All the clues were there. Or, at least, so many people — including the media reporting on the event — thought so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rumor started Thursday afternoon, with an insidery post that promised something huge. “If you thought the Oprah surprise was big, just wait,” the since-deleted post from an anonymous X user said. Given Oprah’s gravitational pull on culture at large, the list of people who could outshine her is, at most, 10 or so names long. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyoncé Knowles is one of the very few people on Earth who is bigger than Oprah. While there was some necessary speculation about Taylor Swift as well, the fact that <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/367709/beyonce-freedom-kamala-harris-campaign-songs">Harris is using Bey’s song “Freedom”</a> on the campaign trail meant that election-watchers and fans alike began speculating that the singer was the secret VIP. There were also reports from people inside the arena that the convention’s house band <a href="https://x.com/nicholasrhutch/status/1826697269405778215">was using Beyoncé songs</a> to soundcheck. Later in the evening, <a href="https://x.com/weijia/status/1826802633820307829?s=61&amp;t=TQlk4x44ENcfSu3Y1ke6ew">reporters</a> noted that the podium was set up for someone special!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As whispers of the extremely famous and exciting guest who was definitely Beyoncé grew, White House political director Emmy Ruiz posted an emoji of a bee at around 4:30 pm. Bey calls her fans the Beyhive, and Ruiz’s bee post threw gasoline on the fire. It’s the equivalent of Gotham City lighting up the sky with the Bat Signal. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Surely Bey was coming! (Ruiz later <a href="https://x.com/emmyruiz/status/1826730658825392156">claimed</a> that her 6-year-old had posted the bee.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then the seemingly ultimate confirmation came: <a href="https://x.com/TMZ/status/1826769943502766414">TMZ reported</a> that Beyoncé was going to show. While your mileage may vary on how TMZ reports deaths and arrests (usually by talking to hospital workers and cops who shouldn’t be leaking that kind of private information), they’re hardly ever wrong.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sleuths then started piecing together more of the alleged puzzle. The Chicks, fellow Texans who Beyoncé has <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2016/11/4/13521928/beyonce-cma-awards-controversy-deleted-performance">collaborated</a> with, were on the schedule. As was Pink, the singer obsessed with aerial tricks and adult gymnastics who also <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W7jkygJ_QNo">once starred with Beyoncé</a> in a Pepsi commercial. Also on the docket was <a href="https://x.com/ArtCandee/status/1826782980209074287">Colin Allred</a>, a Democrat from Bey’s home state running for senate, speaking just a few slots before Harris, the main event. People from Texas, former collaborators, ah yes, it all makes sense if you squint hard enough and play Six Degrees of Separation: Beyoncé Edition.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the most believable connection is that supporting Kamala Harris feels like something Beyoncé would do. If Harris wins, she would be the first woman to become president and the second person of color in history to ever hold the nation’s highest office. That’s a political and historical milestone that aligns itself with Beyoncé’s art and her songs about the strength and vulnerability of being a Black woman. She has also endorsed multiple Democratic candidates in the recent past — starting with Barack Obama right through Hilary Clinton and Joe Biden — and played at President Obama’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HGrq1SzkHs0">Inaugural Ball</a> in 2009 and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qGDH18R7GfA">inauguration</a> in 2013.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyoncé’s cultural and political evolution over the past decade of her career has made her a legendary figure. Even more specifically, beginning with the release of <em>Renaissance</em> in 2022, the singer has been carefully crafting her work around a core idea: What is America? And further, what does it sound like? Who does it belong to?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By tapping into <a href="https://www.vox.com/23280445/beyonce-renaissance-house-disco-music">house music</a> in 2022 and then country in this year’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24114603/beyonces-cowboy-carter-cmas-2016-country-music-history"><em>Cowboy Carter</em></a>, Bey highlighted two distinctly American innovations and underscored how Black men and women are integral parts of those two genres. She’s challenging the ideas of America and reinventing it with each question and with each song. What could be more symbolic of Beyoncé’s Americana than the country’s first Black, biracial, woman president? What could be more on-brand than Beyoncé singing “Freedom,” the Harris-Walz <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/367709/beyonce-freedom-kamala-harris-campaign-songs">campaign song</a>, and introducing Kamala Harris?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout the evening, NBC and other outlets breathlessly speculated on the possibility that Beyoncé was just around the corner, with the Peacock talking to delegates in the audience who seemed to confirm. Just as the country was fully Bey-pilled, and as the clock approached 10:30 CT — right before Kamala Harris was scheduled to accept the nomination — the rumor was squashed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris got a video introduction, and <a href="https://x.com/PopBase/status/1826812366123925871/photo/2">Beyoncé’s publicist</a> posted on Instagram, “Do not report rumors.” <a href="https://x.com/THR/status/1826805194707104170">The Hollywood Reporter</a> also got a denial at around 10:15 pm ET. For Beyoncé fans and perhaps some independent voters, it would’ve been nice if the DNC or said publicist squashed the rumors hours earlier instead of dangling a Bey performance so close that we could taste it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It might be helpful, at this juncture, to remember that the point of the DNC is not, technically, to have a Beyoncé concert, but rather to introduce the country to the woman who wants to be president. And for a brief few hours, it looked like both would happen!&nbsp;Still, the X account that reportedly stated this whole mess says it <a href="https://x.com/Angry_Staffer/status/1826822504163205606">regrets the error</a>, as does <a href="https://x.com/TMZ/status/1826841403374403982">TMZ</a>.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The moment when Kamala Harris’s speech came alive]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368462/kamala-harris-israel-palestine-gaza-dnc-speech" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368462</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T05:45:23Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-23T05:05:21Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris’s acceptance speech started slow, getting bogged down in a familiar recitation of her biography. But it got stronger over time, really hitting its stride when she got around to a topic that’s often dry: foreign policy. There, she showed a facility with policy and an aptitude for navigating deeply divisive issues [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="US Vice President Kamala Harris speaks during the Democratic National Convention (DNC) at the United Center in Chicago, Illinois, US, on August 22, 2024. | Al Drago/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Al Drago/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2167179659.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>US Vice President Kamala Harris speaks during the Democratic National Convention (DNC) at the United Center in Chicago, Illinois, US, on August 22, 2024. | Al Drago/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris’s acceptance speech started slow, getting bogged down in a familiar recitation of her biography. But it got stronger over time, really hitting its stride when she got around to a topic that’s often dry: foreign policy. There, she showed a facility with policy and an aptitude for navigating deeply divisive issues like Israel-Palestine that did wonders for her commander-in-chief credibility.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of what worked was Harris’s palpably emotional delivery. But there was also a real crispness to the speech’s arguments. Here’s what she said, for example, in discussing Trump’s affinity for dictators:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">I will not cozy up to tyrants and dictators like Kim Jong Un who are rooting for Trump. Who are rooting for Trump because they know he is easy to manipulate with flattery and favors. They know Trump won’t hold autocrats accountable because he wants to be an autocrat himself.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In just three lines, she presented an entire cogent theory of what’s wrong with Trump — that he is a selfish, unserious man whose entire approach to politics is anathema to American democracy — and illustrated it with a compelling, easily graspable example. As a writer, it’s hard not to admire the craft here.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She also applied that in her discussion of Israel-Palestine, where she delivered one of the deftest handlings of the issue I’ve ever seen from a politician, one that displayed empathy for both sides while also implicitly distancing herself from Biden’s unbalanced pro-Israel approach:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">I will always stand up for Israel&#8217;s right to defend itself. And I will always ensure Israel has the ability to defend itself, because the people of Israel must never again face the horror that a terrorist organization called Hamas caused on October 7, including unspeakable sexual violence and the massacre of young people at a music festival.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, what has happened in Gaza over the past 10 months is devastating. So many innocent lives lost, desperate, hungry people fleeing for safety over and over again. The scale of suffering is heartbreaking. President Biden and I are working to end this war such that Israel is secure, the hostages are released, the suffering in Gaza ends, and the Palestinian people can realize their right to dignity, security, freedom, and self-determination.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s framing not only recognized the strongest points in both the Israeli and Palestinian narratives of the current conflict, it took them seriously.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She did not mince words or dance around the horror of October 7. She acknowledged why the attack was such an unforgivable assault on Israeli lives and reiterated her commitment to preventing it from ever happening again. At the same time, she went much further than even most Democrats are willing to in recognizing the immense and ongoing suffering of Palestinians. More than that, actually: She acknowledged that Palestinians have legitimate rights — rights that demand even more than an end to this war, but a future where Palestinians truly rule themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Too often, people discussing this topic feel the need to only recognize one of these narratives — and in American politics, that’s most often the Israeli one. Yet Harris placed them on truly equal footing, taking <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/22442052/israel-palestine-two-state-solution-gaza-hamas-one">the moral ideas implicit in a two-state solution</a> to the conflict and bringing them to the fore. The result was a discussion that anyone who cares about both Israeli and Palestinian lives could appreciate, and one that felt genuine in the delivery rather than just pro forma.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, to be clear: President Joe Biden has said similar-sounding things about Palestinian dignity, and his policy has still been overwhelmingly tilted in Israel’s direction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this speech felt meaningfully different in two respects.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, its rhetorical structure: Presenting Palestinian aspirations for self-determination as the moral climax of her discussion of the issue, the apex concern, felt like a meaningful shift away from a biased status quo. Second, and more importantly, it’s consistent: In public and reportedly in private, Harris has demonstrated far more concern with the suffering of Palestinian civilians.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris “would certainly show more pragmatism and flexibility than Biden has, and in her public commentary has also demonstrated a far more humanizing approach to the Palestinians in the past year,” Josh Paul, a former State Department official who resigned over Biden’s approach to Gaza <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/23/us/politics/harris-netanyahu-israel-gaza.html">told the New York Times in July</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t want to read too much into mere words; no one should be confident that Harris would govern perfectly on Israel-Palestine or any other foreign policy issue. But a speech that good at least earned her the benefit of the doubt.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why a Canadian labor dispute could make your life more difficult]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/368276/canada-rail-train-shipping-teamsters-trudeau-strike-lockout" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368276</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T00:41:03Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-23T00:41:01Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Transportation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Canada’s two main rail lines locked out rail workers early Thursday morning amid tense contract negotiations between the railways and the Canada Teamsters Rail Conference, which represents nearly 10,000 rail workers. Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said his government would resolve the dispute, and late Thursday, officials ordered the two sides to enter arbitration proceedings. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Aerial view of a rail yard." data-caption="Shipping containers on the rails outside the Canadian Pacific Railway Toronto Yard in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, on August 20, 2024. | Cole Burston/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Cole Burston/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166906944.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Shipping containers on the rails outside the Canadian Pacific Railway Toronto Yard in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, on August 20, 2024. | Cole Burston/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Canada’s two main rail lines locked out rail workers early Thursday morning amid tense contract negotiations between the railways and the Canada Teamsters Rail Conference, which represents nearly 10,000 rail workers. Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau <a href="https://nationalpost.com/news/canada/latest-lockout-railways-ongoing">said his government would resolve the dispute,</a> and late Thursday, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/22/world/canada/canada-freight-trains.html">officials ordered the two sides</a> to enter arbitration proceedings. Even if they are successful, however,<strong> </strong>the work stoppage could have a serious impact on the Canadian economy, as well as supply chains in both the US and Canada.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rail companies, Canadian National Railway (CN) and Canadian Pacific Kansas City (CPKC), and the union have been negotiating for months, but remain far apart. The stoppage is the result of the rail companies barring their workers from work, rather than a strike. The companies argued a lockout was necessary to ensure a safe and controlled drawdown of operations and that if they waited for operators to walk off the job, the companies wouldn’t have had time to secure hazardous materials or work out supply arrangements with key customers. The two rail lines facilitate the transit of people and about $740 million worth of goods across the country’s vast interior each day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, the impact of the work stoppage is mainly on the Canadian economy, but because about 75 percent of Canadian exports —&nbsp;including coal and agricultural products —&nbsp;are sold to the US, there could be an impact on the US supply chain if the dispute isn’t resolved soon.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What went wrong with Canadian railways&nbsp;and what it means for Canada’s supply chain</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The two railway systems had contracts with the Teamsters union that expired in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/cn-rail-cpkc-shut-canada-rail-network-labor-talks-deadlocked-2024-08-22/">December 2023</a>. Since then, each side has accused the other of refusing to accept reasonable terms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The union’s primary concerns, <a href="https://teamsters.ca/blog/2024/08/22/cn-and-cpkc-begin-work-stoppage/">according to its public communications</a>, have been over worker safety and rest periods, as well as predictable scheduling. They also claim that Canada National is issuing them unworkable relocation notices —&nbsp;forcing workers to move for months at a time in order to deal with staffing shortages.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rail workers voted to authorize a strike as early as May of this year, claiming that the rail companies weren’t bargaining in good faith and were attempting to undercut progress on working conditions, proposing a shift to an hourly wage rather than a salary for some positions, and removing <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/cpkc-says-possible-canada-rail-strike-unlikely-before-mid-july-2024-05-23/">scheduling provisions for adequate rest</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Across Canada, we have trains [that] are carrying goods, they are carrying energy, they are carrying chemicals,” François Laporte, national president of Teamsters Canada, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy76nnpyrnlo">told the BBC</a> Thursday. “And we want to make sure that those [trains] are operated by people who get the proper rest, who are safe, who are not fatigued.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Canadian railways carry goods like coal and potash —&nbsp;<a href="https://natural-resources.canada.ca/our-natural-resources/minerals-mining/mining-data-statistics-and-analysis/minerals-metals-facts/potash-facts/20521">an important ingredient in fertilizer</a> —&nbsp;as well as cooking oil, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/08/21/canada-rail-strike-lockout-teamsters/">propane, and frozen food</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many shipments both within Canada and between Canada and the US were already paused; by Tuesday, CPKC had already stopped shipments that started in the US and were bound for Canada. Under the work stoppage, around 2,500 US train cars bound for Canada will be halted each day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some organizations, like the US Chamber of Commerce, the American Farm Bureau Federation, and the National Cotton Council warned of devastating effects on the US supply chain and economy should the work stoppage persist.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The American Farm Bureau Federation and the National Cotton Council, among others, claimed in a Monday letter to President Joe Biden that the work stoppage could cause “harmful consequences for Canadian and American agricultural producers, the agricultural industry, and both domestic and global food security” if it persisted, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/08/21/canada-rail-strike-lockout-teamsters/">the Washington Post reported</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though it’s difficult to say exactly what the impact will be on the US economy, some prices on agricultural products could go up should the work stoppage stretch on, affecting consumers already struggling with high food costs. Sanitation could be affected, as the chlorine that many sanitation departments rely on to treat wastewater is shipped from Canada. The automotive industry could be impacted, too; <a href="https://rollcall.com/2024/08/22/us-industries-prepare-for-hit-from-canadian-rail-strike/">according to June numbers from the Bureau of Transportation Statistics</a>, automobiles and auto parts made up the bulk of rail shipments from the US to Canada in June. Some US auto plants could be forced to shut down before the week is out if there’s no agreement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Container ships unable to unload at Canadian ports will likely need to reroute to the US, potentially causing a backup at US ports,&nbsp;which could cause supply chain disruptions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Supply chain problems will become more pronounced the longer the lockout continues. The Canadian government had two options to try to solve the problem: either <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy76nnpyrnlo" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy76nnpyrnlo">pass return-to-work legislation</a> or force the companies and the union into private arbitration. The companies had signaled openness to arbitration, though the union — as well as Trudeau and his allies — seemed cool to it. Ultimately, however, arbitration was the route the government chose.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s possible the arbitration process will only paper over the real disputes without solving them, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/biden-signs-bill-block-us-railroad-strike-2022-12-02/">as the US return-to-work legislation in December 2022 did</a>. Without a resolution and a new contract, forcing the workers to return to their trains will only kick the problem down the track.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, August 22, 2024, 8:30 pm ET: </strong>This story, first published earlier on August 22, has been updated to reflect the Canadian government ordering the rail companies and union into arbitration. </em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Abdallah Fayyad</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The DNC was avoiding controversy — then it refused to give Palestinians airtime]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368411/dnc-palestinian-speaker-uncommitted-democratic-national-convention" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368411</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T23:31:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T23:31:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Democratic National Convention (DNC) was on track to closing out with little controversy until yesterday, when the Democratic National Committee decided to reject pro-Palestinian delegates’ efforts to get a Palestinian American speaker on the main stage. As a result, “uncommitted” delegates — representing a Democratic primary campaign that encouraged voters to choose “uncommitted” over [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A red-and-white flowered pin reads “Ceasefire Delegate,” on a red-and-white scarf." data-caption="A “Ceasefire Delegate” pin at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago on August 21, 2024. | Brandon Bell/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brandon Bell/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2167832370.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A “Ceasefire Delegate” pin at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago on August 21, 2024. | Brandon Bell/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Democratic National Convention (DNC) was on track to closing out with little controversy until yesterday, when the Democratic National Committee <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/21/palestinians-gaza-speaker-dnc/">decided to reject</a> pro-Palestinian delegates’ efforts to get a Palestinian American speaker on the main stage. As a result, “uncommitted” delegates — representing a Democratic primary campaign that encouraged voters to choose “uncommitted” over President Joe Biden to express their discontent over the president’s handling of Israel’s war in Gaza — staged a sit-in outside the convention hall. Now, “uncommitted” delegates and their allies have launched a <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/08/22/dnc-live-updates-coverage/will-there-be-a-palestinian-american-speaker-00175835">last-minute pressure campaign</a> to get a speaker on the last night.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the potential speakers that Uncommitted National Movement organizers put forward was Ruwa Romman, a Palestinian American and a Democratic member of the Georgia House of Representatives. She told me that she and the “uncommitted” delegates had felt optimistic about getting a speaking slot because up until yesterday, the Democratic National Committee had still been in discussions with the group and hadn’t said no to their request.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the surface, it might seem obvious that the Democrats wouldn’t want a speaker criticizing the Biden administration over its handling of the war. But Romman, who had prepared a speech just in case convention organizers tapped her to come on stage, had no such intention. Instead, she simply wanted to highlight the human story behind Palestinian suffering. <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2024/08/dnc-speech-uncommitted-movement-harris-walz-ruwan-romman/">Her draft speech</a> urges people to support the Harris-Walz ticket and criticizes former President Donald Trump for using the word Palestinian as a slur.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s why the Democrats’ refusal to elevate a Palestinian voice to the main stage, despite giving a <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/dnc-parents-israeli-american-hostage-make-emotional-plea/story?id=113039754">speaking slot to family members</a> of an Israeli American hostage, is rubbing many voters the wrong way — especially those who hoped that Harris would have a more sympathetic approach to Gaza compared to Biden. The group Muslim Women for Harris-Walz, for example, <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/22/muslim-women-harris-walz-disbands/74901820007/">promptly disbanded</a> after news broke that there would be no Palestinian speaker at the convention.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And for Romman, the fact that the party welcomed Republicans on the stage and not her felt like a slight, not just to her but to Palestinians more broadly. “When I saw [Republican former] lieutenant governor Geoff Duncan on that stage, knowing that the party rejected me — a member of the party and a Democratic elected official — frankly, it was just too much,” she said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This episode is yet another roadblock to softening the opposition Harris is facing from Arab and Muslim American voters, as well as others who view the Gaza war as a major concern. After Biden dropped out, Harris has had an opportunity to distance herself from the “genocide Joe” rallying cry that became common in pro-Palestinian protests. And by requesting a speaking slot, the uncommitted movement had offered her an olive branch — a small gesture to show that she’s listening. But by rejecting that offer, the Harris campaign is risking fracturing an already fragile coalition.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the fight over the speaking slot is really about </strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After Biden stepped aside, many anti-Biden Democrats concerned about the Gaza war saw an opportunity for a reset.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The “uncommitted” delegates initially <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/21/palestinians-gaza-speaker-dnc/">indicated</a> that the Harris campaign was much more open than the Biden campaign to discussing their concerns. And in the weeks since Harris became the nominee, the Democratic Party has made a handful of gestures to show that they’re listening to voters’ concerns about Gaza. The Harris-Walz campaign manager, for example, met with the Uncommitted National Movement. And the Democratic National Committee gave Palestinians a space to hold a panel in which doctors who worked in Gaza during the war <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/dnc-2024-palestine-israel">spoke about the horrors</a> they witnessed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But on their own, those gestures haven’t been enough to assuage voter concerns, especially because denying a Palestinian American speaking time at the convention sends a signal that the party isn’t interested in elevating the issue. And there have been moments when the campaign has been dismissive of pro-Palestinian voters altogether. At a rally in Detroit earlier this month, for example, Harris shut down protesters advocating for a ceasefire. “You know what? If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that. Otherwise, I’m speaking,” <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmzJaidv3iI">she said</a>, clearly irritated by the activists. If she wants to actually reassure pro-Palestinian voters, Harris has the difficult task of distancing herself from Biden while still serving as his number two. But that’s why small gestures like a speaking slot can go a long way.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This was supposed to be the symbolic bare minimum ask,” said Romman, the representative from Georgia. “We understand that we can’t change policy in a single election cycle, and this was supposed to be an easy way for the party to unite us on this issue. A lot of people care about this. Anybody who’s at the convention has seen the amount of people wearing pins and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/6/23990673/keffiyeh-symbolism-palestinian-history">keffiyehs</a> and flags. It is everywhere.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It also seems like giving a Palestinian American a speaking slot would not necessarily be as risky as the party appears to think, especially among the Democratic base. Some <a href="https://x.com/AyannaPressley/status/1826637258595741779">members of Congress</a> and other <a href="https://x.com/keithellison/status/1826648016281108638">Democratic officials</a> have been <a href="https://x.com/AOC/status/1826454738201661908">pushing the party</a> to <a href="https://x.com/RoKhanna/status/1826674536462647384">host a Palestinian speaker</a> at the convention, and groups like the United Auto Workers union <a href="https://x.com/uaw/status/1826626152049307934?s=46&amp;t=mPnbvyFgt7avJRNpnS1BDw">endorsed the idea as well</a>. And Israel’s actions in Gaza have been deeply unpopular among Democrats, with polls showing that a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/642695/majority-disapprove-israeli-action-gaza.aspx">majority of Americans disapprove</a> of Israel’s handling of its war. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When asked by Vox why the Democratic National Committee wouldn’t agree to having a Palestinian speaker at the convention, the Harris campaign declined to answer. But given that “uncommitted” delegates had been <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2024/08/uncommitted-delegates-push-for-speaker-slot-at-dnc-for-gaza-doctor-tanya-haj-hassan-palestine-israel-democratic-national-convention/">asking the party for a speaking slot for nearly two months</a> and the Democratic National Committee didn’t officially say no until yesterday, it seems like fitting in a speaker might have been on the table.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem for the Democratic Party is that while it pitches itself to be a big tent, it’s now falling short of actually walking the walk. It’s safe to assume that not every speaker up on that stage in Chicago represents Harris’s views or policy objectives, and even <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/12/12060358/political-science-of-platforms">official party platforms</a> don’t represent everything that a president will push for while they’re in the White House. So even if a Palestinian speaker were to say something that the Harris campaign disagrees with, that’s not the end of the world — after all, that’s what a big tent looks like.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For much of the convention, Democrats have focused their messaging on <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/20/g-s1-17884/democratic-national-convention-jasmine-crockett-kamala-harris-maxine-waters-aoc-deja-foxx">civil rights</a>, <a href="https://time.com/7013618/reproductive-rights-abortion-dnc/">human dignity</a>, and <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/philadelphia/2024/08/22/josh-shapiro-dnc-speech">projecting</a> an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vlZmG1i9wN4">image of decency</a> around the world. But if the party fully resists the push to have a Palestinian speak at the convention, the DNC is sending the message that what’s happening to Palestinians is an exception — not so much a grave injustice that ought to be addressed as much as it is an inconvenience that’s better left ignored. At least that’s what Palestinian American voters or their allies, who are all too <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/352663/anti-palestinian-racism-islamophobia-antisemitism">familiar with the many efforts</a> to keep their voices out of national conversations, might glean from this debacle.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The message I’m personally getting, frankly, is that nothing we do is ever going to be good enough,” Romman told me. “So how do I go back [to Georgia] and make the argument to people that I know that this is a party worth vouching for and trusting?”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Does RFK Jr. dropping out of the presidential race help Trump?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368394/rfk-drop-out-2024-presidential-campaign-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368394</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T22:04:04Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T22:05:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arguably the weirdest candidate of the 2024 election is expected to drop out soon.&#160; Following a controversy-filled campaign that included revelations that a worm had eaten part of his brain and that he was responsible for the bear carcass that mysteriously appeared in Central Park in 2014, Robert F. Kennedy Jr., and his running mate [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks during a campaign event on October 12, 2023 in Miami, Florida. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1720421711.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Robert F. Kennedy Jr. speaks during a campaign event on October 12, 2023 in Miami, Florida. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Arguably the weirdest candidate of the 2024 election is expected to drop out soon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following a controversy-filled campaign that included revelations that a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/08/us/rfk-jr-brain-health-memory-loss.html">worm had eaten part of his brain</a> and that he was <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365284/robert-f-kennedy-jr-bear-central-park">responsible for the bear carcass</a> that <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/newyork/news/bear-cub-found-dead-in-central-park-nypd-investigating-as-animal-cruelty/">mysteriously appeared</a> in Central Park in 2014, Robert F. Kennedy Jr., and his running mate Nicole Shanahan, are reportedly planning to suspend their presidential bid. He is <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/rfk-jr-plans-drop-presidential-race-end-week/story?id=113028999">considering endorsing</a> former President Donald Trump and reportedly hopeful that he might <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/rfk-jr-trump-health-secretary-anti-vaccine-rcna167588">secure the position of Trump’s health secretary</a> if he wins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy was an environmental lawyer <a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/rfk-jr-green-hero-turned-anti-vaccine-activist-takes-on-biden/">known for</a> his work cleaning up the Hudson River with a storied last name who in recent years has become known for spreading conspiracy theories about medicine, including <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-68447223">vaccines</a> and <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/robert-f-kennedy-jr-conspiracy-theory-twitter-elon-musk-1234747479/">anti-depressants</a>. He used the popularity he gained as an <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/07/13/1187272781/rfk-jr-kennedy-conspiracy-theories-social-media-presidential-campaign">anti-vaxxer during the pandemic</a> to briefly challenge President Joe Biden in the Democratic primary before announcing an independent bid for president in October 2023.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He had been seen as a potential spoiler for both candidates, given his connection to the Democratic Kennedy dynasty as well as his embrace of the anti-establishment and anti-vaccine views held by certain segments of the GOP. He was <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/22/rfk-jr-end-campaign-polls">polling around 10 percent</a> nationally for the better part of 2024, and even higher in some swing state polls.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/rfk-jr-map-on-the-ballot-states/">struggled to get on the ballot in many states</a>, though his campaign maintains that he has secured enough signatures to do so in all but Kentucky, Mississippi, Rhode Island, and Wyoming. And after Vice President Kamala Harris became the Democratic nominee, he seemed to hold less sway among voters who were turned off by Biden. His poll numbers <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/08/22/rfk-jr-end-campaign-polls">consequently cratered</a> to under 5 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite Kennedy’s flagging national numbers,&nbsp;polling suggests his exit from the race could still help Trump, with whom he’s become <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/7/17/is-rfk-jr-truly-independent">decidedly more cozy</a> in recent months. Trump wouldn’t have to win a lot of Kennedy’s potential voters to make a difference in key swing states; if the race is as close as it was in 2020, Trump gaining even a fraction of a percent from Kennedy could make the difference.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Kennedy’s exit may help Trump — possibly where it matters the most</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump probably has the most to gain from Kennedy dropping out. Kennedy has increasingly endeared himself to Republican voters while struggling to get the same support among Democrats and independents. And polls conducted in recent months, including since Biden dropped out of the race, suggest that Trump would pick up more of Kennedy’s supporters. Any margin would likely be small — but potentially significant.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans tend to see Kennedy more favorably than Democrats, and those with favorable views toward him tend to have more favorable opinions of Trump than of Harris, according to a <a href="https://apnorc.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/July-2024-W1-topline.pdf">July AP-NORC poll</a> conducted before Biden dropped out.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several national polls conducted since Harris became the presumptive nominee have also tested a race between Harris, Trump, and Kennedy, as well as a two-way race between Harris and Trump. Trump tends to get a bigger bump than Harris when Kennedy is excluded.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/ipsos-2024-us-national-election-survey-august-2024">August Reuters/Ipsos poll of registered voters</a>, for instance, Harris received 42 percent support, Trump 37 percent, and Kennedy 4 percent, while 15 percent supported another candidate, weren’t sure who they would support, or weren’t sure if they would vote at all. But when voters were pushed to select either Trump or Harris, 49 percent backed Harris and 47 percent Trump — a 10 percentage point boost for Trump.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump had a similar edge with Kennedy voters in a <a href="https://harvardharrispoll.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/HHP_July2024_KeyResults.pdf">July Harvard CAPS/Harris Poll</a>. In a three-way contest, Harris earned 44 percent support, Trump 47 percent, and Kennedy 10 percent. In a head-to-head poll, Harris earned 48 percent and Trump 52 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It may seem like the advantage Trump gains when Kennedy is out of the picture is relatively small. But Biden won in 2020 by exceedingly <a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/12/02/940689086/narrow-wins-in-these-key-states-powered-biden-to-the-presidency">narrow margins</a> in six key battleground states; in Arizona, it was by less than 11,000 votes. On the margin, Kennedy’s supporters could make a difference, depending on where they’re distributed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Arizona, for example, Kennedy is still polling at about 6 percent, according to <a href="https://elections2024.thehill.com/arizona/biden-trump-rfk-arizona/">The Hill’s polling average</a>. Of course, he might not actually win that large a vote share if he decides to stay in the race; third-party candidates tend to poll much better than they actually perform on Election Day, when their supporters are confronted with the reality that their preferred candidate won’t win. But that vote share would have been more than enough to have swung the 2020 results in the other direction.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The same is true in other swing states, where polling suggests a very tight race. An early <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/08/10/us/elections/times-siena-poll-registered-voter-crosstabs.html">August New York Times/Siena</a> survey of registered voters in Michigan, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin found Harris leading Trump 46 percent to 43 percent when respondents were given all third-party candidates to choose from. When asked to pick between just Harris and Trump, the gap tightened to 48 and 46 percent, respectively. Those <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/16/kamala-harris-polls-key-states">states are likely to be key</a>, given their high electoral college vote count — and in most scenarios, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/election/2024/electoral-college-map?game-id=2024-PG-CNN-ratings&amp;game-view=map">Harris would need all three to win</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris’s entry into the race likely limits the impact of Kennedy’s exit</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Kennedy’s supporters may still be able to make an important impact on the margins, their power to drag the Democratic nominee’s polling down seems to have diminished substantially.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before Harris became the nominee, there was a much larger than usual number of disaffected voters who didn’t like either Biden or Trump and just wanted someone — anyone — as an alternative. A theoretical no-name candidate as an alternative to Biden and Trump got about 10 percent in <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24112624/rfk-jr-kennedy-shanahan-running-mate-2024-election">Ipsos polling</a> conducted earlier this year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy provided an alternative for a while. But when Harris stepped up, that undermined his appeal — at least among Democrats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There were some wavering Democratic voters who just thought Biden was too old, or they didn&#8217;t like him, and Harris is just a more appealing candidate for those kinds of people,” said Kyle Kondik, managing editor of Sabato’s Crystal Ball at the University of Virginia Center for Politics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kondik said it’s possible that Biden may have ended up winning back those voters anyway if he had stayed in the race and had a <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/8/17/21371232/convention-polls-biden-trump-election">typical post-Democratic National Convention bump</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But at this point, Kondik said, he would not be surprised if the third-party vote share in the election ends up being about 2 percent of the electorate, as it was in 2012 and 2020. Before Harris became the nominee, political analysts were projecting that it would be closer to the nearly 6 percent share third parties got in 2016, which some analysts <a href="https://rollcall.com/2019/07/29/how-third-party-votes-sunk-clinton-what-they-mean-for-trump/">argued doomed</a> Democratic nominee Hillary Clinton’s candidacy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For all the talk about third parties in this election, a combination of the most prominent third-party candidate dropping out, in addition to the increased favorability of the two major party nominees, means that there’s just going to be less of a market for third-party candidates,” he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy could make more of an impact as a surrogate for Trump. He could help the former president with certain demographics, such as young men who listen to prominent personalities such as Joe Rogan, who has <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/joe-rogan-endorses-rfk-jr-president-1236101220/">praised Kennedy</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Trump campaign might also be wary of attaching itself to Kennedy’s brand: If the brain worm and the bear incident weren’t enough, he has been disavowed by <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/05/08/robert-kennedy-jr-measles-vaccines-226798/">members of his own famous family</a> and now peddles <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/07/06/us/politics/rfk-conspiracy-theories-fact-check.html">conspiracy theories</a> not just about the <a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19">Covid-19</a> vaccine, but <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/retropolis/wp/2018/05/26/who-killed-bobby-kennedy-his-son-rfk-jr-doesnt-believe-it-was-sirhan-sirhan/">his father’s killer</a>, <a href="https://time.com/6287001/rfk-jr-interview-2024-campaign/">5G cell phone transmission</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/06/25/fashion/25bobby.html">fraud in the 2004 election</a>, and more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Democratic refrain against Trump and [his running mate JD] Vance is that they’re ‘weird,’” Kondik said. “Kennedy doesn’t make them less weird.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This chart of ocean heat is terrifying]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/368324/hurricane-season-2024-gulf-mexico-ocean-warming" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368324</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T21:42:15Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T21:45:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The warm waters along the Gulf Coast are part of what draws people to the region and its many beaches. But there is such a thing as too warm —&#160;and the Gulf of Mexico has reached that point.&#160;&#160; Take a look at the chart below. It shows how much heat there is in the ocean [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A dark gray sky filled with looming clouds presses down on a white sand beach, with waves approaching the shore." data-caption="A view from the beach in Fort Myers, Florida, as Hurricane Idalia approached the state’s Gulf Coast in August 2023. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eva Marie Uzcategui/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1632090192.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A view from the beach in Fort Myers, Florida, as Hurricane Idalia approached the state’s Gulf Coast in August 2023. | Eva Marie Uzcategui/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The warm waters along the Gulf Coast are part of what draws people to the region and its many beaches. But there is such a thing as too warm —&nbsp;and the Gulf of Mexico has reached that point.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take a look at the chart below. It shows how much heat there is in the ocean over time for the Gulf. The red line is 2024 and the blue line is the average over the last decade.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/ohc_gulf.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.589156124409,100,74.821687751182" alt="A blue curved line tracks the average heat in the Gulf of Mexico over the last decade, rising in the summer months and falling in the winter. A red line shows ocean heat for 2024, which is high above the average for August. " title="A blue curved line tracks the average heat in the Gulf of Mexico over the last decade, rising in the summer months and falling in the winter. A red line shows ocean heat for 2024, which is high above the average for August. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A chart of ocean heat content in the Gulf of Mexico. | &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/tropics/ohc/&quot;&gt;Brian McNoldy/University of Miami&lt;/a&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/tropics/ohc/&quot;&gt;Brian McNoldy/University of Miami&lt;/a&gt;" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Gulf is now the hottest it’s been in the modern record, <a href="https://x.com/BMcNoldy/status/1825886302538965244">according</a> to <a href="https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/">Brian McNoldy</a>, a climatologist at the University of Miami, who produced the chart. Taking a dip would feel like a bath: The average temperature of the surface is close to 90 degrees, according to recent <a href="https://kouya.has.arizona.edu/tropics/SSTmonitoring.html#regional">measures of sea surface temperature</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is out of bounds from the kinds of variability that we’ve seen in [at least] the last 75 years or so,” <a href="https://people.miami.edu/profile/be7abbba52c947423b8133238c7e7b68">Ben Kirtman</a>, director of the Cooperative Institute for Marine and Atmospheric Studies, a joint initiative of the University of Miami and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), told Vox. “That can be scary stuff.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These record temperatures are just one signal of a more <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/2/28/24085691/atlantic-ocean-warming-climate-change-hurricanes-coral-reefs-bleaching">widespread bout of warming</a> across the North Atlantic that <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23762529/atlantic-ocean-record-heat-wave-el-nino-hurricane-climate-change">ramped up last year</a>. It’s still not entirely clear what’s causing it, though scientists suspect a combination of factors including climate change —&nbsp;which raises the baseline ocean temperature — as well as lingering effects of <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23738846/el-nino-2023-weather-heat-wave-climate-change-disaster-flood-rain">El Niño</a>, natural climate variability, and perhaps even a <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/tonga-volcano-eruption-raises-imminent-risk-of-temporary-1-5c-breach/">volcanic eruption</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The temperature in the Gulf is ultimately only a handful of degrees warmer than the historic average. Yet as scientists are increasingly warning, those degrees matter —&nbsp;a lot. It’s not just <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">sea life</a> that’s at risk, but cities full of people.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/sst_animation_30day_crb_930x580_6a72d4.gif?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,6.9765567727478,100,86.046886454504" alt="A changing animation darkens from yellow to red, depicting various degrees of ocean heat mapped across the Caribbean, getting much redder overall as it moves from July to August 2024." title="A changing animation darkens from yellow to red, depicting various degrees of ocean heat mapped across the Caribbean, getting much redder overall as it moves from July to August 2024." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A time lapse of sea surface temperatures in the Caribbean. | NOAA" data-portal-copyright="NOAA" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The double punch of extreme ocean heat</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are two major ways that a hot Gulf threatens coastal communities, and they both have to do with hurricanes. The first is straightforward: Hurricanes like heat. They need warm water, and the moist, rising air it produces. That air mingles with storm clouds and can eventually form a hurricane.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hotter water can lead to stronger hurricanes that accelerate faster, giving coastal regions less time to prepare.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now let’s return to that chart above. It’s not showing surface temperature, but the amount of heat energy measured across different layers of the ocean. It’s this energy that can fuel big storms, Kirtman said. Powerful winds stir up the ocean, bringing deeper, colder water to the surface. That can slow down a hurricane. But when the water is warm even below the surface, he said, then the hurricane can rapidly intensify —&nbsp;meaning, its wind speeds can increase by roughly 35 miles per hour or more in less than 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the other problem: Hot water kills corals, which defend coastal communities from hurricanes. These natural structures are large enough to <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/23046997/hurricane-ian-coral-reefs-climate-change-hurricanes">dampen waves that hit the shore</a>, minimizing the threat of storm surge. (Enduring ocean heat causes polyps — the little animals that make up a piece of coral — to lose a type of symbiotic algae that lives inside them. Without the algae, the coral turns white, or “<a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">bleaches</a>,” and can starve to death.)</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Another story you might like</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vox reporter Benji Jones recently visited the Caribbean’s healthiest coral reef. What he saw there offers hope — and a loud warning — for the future of these iconic ecosystems. Read the story <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a> and share feedback at <a href="mailto:benji.jones@vox.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">benji.jones@vox.com</a>. </p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, a hot Gulf could produce monstrous, rapidly intensifying hurricanes while also weakening our natural defenses against them. Good stuff.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year has seen five named storms so far, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358323/hurricane-beryl-rapid-intesification-caribbean-climate">Hurricane&nbsp;Beryl</a> —&nbsp;which rapidly intensified to become the earliest Category 5 storm on record. This is the kind of hurricane that scientists <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358323/hurricane-beryl-rapid-intesification-caribbean-climate">have been expecting</a> as oceans warm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’re continuing to see the climatological hallmarks of an active season,” Matthew Rosencrans, the lead hurricane season forecaster at NOAA’s Climate Prediction Center, <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/highly-active-hurricane-season-likely-to-continue-in-atlantic">said</a> in a statement earlier this month. “Sea surface temperatures remain abnormally high.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hurricane season in the Atlantic typically peaks around September 10, <a href="https://www.weather.gov/media/tbw/1921/Climatology.pdf">according to</a> NOAA, and the agency expects a total of 17 to 24 named storms —&nbsp;well above average, but perhaps also the new normal.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>A weird cold spot that’s puzzling scientists</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Gulf, and the North Atlantic ocean more broadly, are unusually hot. That much is clear. But there’s also a strange blob of colder water around the equator, which has spurred <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-atlantic-is-cooling-at-a-mysteriously-fast-rate-after-record-warmth-2000488967">conflicting, confusing headlines</a> that suggest the Atlantic is cooling.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The surface temperature in this stretch of ocean swung from exceptionally hot to unusually cool in a matter of months starting this spring, for reasons that scientists have yet to fully explain, according to <a href="https://www.aoml.noaa.gov/people/franz-tuchen/">Franz “Philip” Tuchen</a>, an oceanographer at the University of Miami. The rapid change is “very unusual,” he told Vox.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet this cooling is only in one area — somewhere between central Africa and Brazil —&nbsp;and it’s already fading. “It’s not the whole Atlantic, and it’s just a temporary cooling,” Tuchen said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not only is the effect fading, but the blob lies below the “main development region” for hurricanes — the band of ocean where storms usually form. So it likely won’t have a large effect on hurricane season.  <a href="https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/tropics/ohc/ohc_mdr_anom.png">That band</a>, like the Gulf and much of the North Atlantic, is now very, very warm. And in the long term, barring a dramatic drop in greenhouse gas emissions, it will likely only get warmer.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Supreme Court decides not to disenfranchise thousands of swing state voters]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/368310/supreme-court-rnc-mi-famila-vota" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368310</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T20:33:11Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T20:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Voting Rights" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Supreme Court handed the Republican Party a small victory on Thursday, making it marginally harder for new voters to register to vote in Arizona.&#160; The decision, however, could have been much worse for voting rights: Republicans asked the justices to strip thousands of already-registered voters of their ability to vote for president. Three justices [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A photo of Kamala Harris speaking at an event." data-caption="Thursday’s Supreme Court decision could have been much worse for this woman. | Grant Baldwin/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Grant Baldwin/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166317429.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Thursday’s Supreme Court decision could have been much worse for this woman. | Grant Baldwin/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Supreme Court <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/orders/courtorders/082224zr_n75p.pdf">handed the Republican Party a small victory</a> on Thursday, making it marginally harder for new voters to register to vote in Arizona.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The decision, however, could have been much worse for voting rights: Republicans asked the justices to strip thousands of already-registered voters <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">of their ability to vote for president</a>. Three justices voted to do just that, but six members of the Court rejected the request.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, five members of the Court — every member of the Court’s Republican majority except for Justice Amy Coney Barrett — voted to make it marginally more difficult to register to vote in Arizona.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So this is a victory for the GOP, but probably not a particularly significant one. If the three most MAGA-pilled justices, Justices Clarence Thomas, Samuel Alito, and Neil Gorsuch, had prevailed, a meaningful chunk of Arizona’s voters could have been locked out of voting in the 2024 presidential election. But that didn’t happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Court’s decision to hand Republicans even a small victory here is almost certainly wrong, under a 2006 Supreme Court decision warning judges <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/06-375">not to change</a> a state’s election procedures too close to an election. But the impact of Thursday’s GOP victory is likely to be fairly modest.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Arizona’s ridiculously complicated voter registration system, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The case, known as <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/orders/courtorders/082224zr_n75p.pdf"><em>Republican National Committee v. Mi Familia Vota</em></a>, involves a <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/367701/supreme-court-arizona-rnc-republicans-mi-familia-vota">ludicrously complicated system</a> that Arizona uses to register voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2004, Arizona enacted a law requiring voters to provide documentary proof of citizenship (such as a passport or a birth certificate) when registering to vote. This law, however, conflicts with a federal law, known as the National Voter Registration Act (NVRA), which permits voters in every state to register using a standardized federal form. The federal form requires Arizona voters to swear, under penalty of perjury, that they are citizens, but it does not require the same documentary proof that Arizona’s state law requires.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=8524729836774698956&amp;q=n+Arizona+v.+Inter+Tribal+Council+of+Arizona&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6,47&amp;as_vis=1"><em>Arizona v. Inter Tribal Council of Arizona</em></a> (2013), the Supreme Court ruled that Arizona must comply with the NVRA and allow voters who submit the federal form to register — but there was a twist. <em>Inter Tribal</em> also suggested that Congress’s power over voter registration is limited to “federal elections,” so Arizona responded to <em>Inter Tribal</em> by creating two tiers of voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters who submit the state’s form (including the document proving citizenship) are registered to vote in all elections in Arizona. But voters who submit the federal form are deemed “federal-only” voters and may only vote in congressional and presidential elections — and not for state and local offices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An expert witness who testified in the <em>RNC </em>case estimated that “approximately one-third of a [percent] of non-Hispanic White voters [in Arizona] are Federal-Only Voters, while a little more than <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A164/322042/20240808153230794_Application%20Appendix.pdf">two-thirds of a percent of minority voters are Federal-Only Voters</a>.” So the universe of voters who registered using the federal form isn’t that large, but it is disproportionately non-white, which likely explains the GOP’s interest in this case — among other things, Republicans wanted to prevent these federal-only voters from casting a vote for president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, President Joe Biden lost white Arizona voters, but very narrowly won the state due to his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/11/03/us/elections/exit-polls-arizona.html">strong performance among Latinos</a>. Biden’s margin of victory was only about three-tenths of a percent,&nbsp; so even a small shift in who was allowed to vote in Arizona might have changed the result.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So what was actually at stake in the <em>RNC v. Mi Familia Vota</em> case?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans asked the Court to impose three restrictions contained in a 2022 Arizona state law, which has never taken effect, and which was blocked by a federal court in 2023.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That law sought to ban Arizona’s federal-only voters from voting for president, and it also would have barred them from voting by mail. Although Thomas, Alito, and Gorsuch voted to allow these two restrictions to go into effect, a majority of the justices did not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Additionally, the 2022 law sought to override a 2018 court order that allowed voters who submit the state form without a document proving citizenship to still register as a federal-only voter. Five justices voted to let this provision of the 2022 law take effect. So new voters who submit the state form without the required documentation will not be registered at all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters who submit the federal form, however, will still be registered as federal-only voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This decision to allow even a small part of the 2022 law to take effect is almost certainly wrong. The 2022 law was blocked by a 2023 federal court decision, and the Supreme Court ruled in <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supremecourt/text/06-375"><em>Purcell v. Gonzalez</em></a> (2006) that “federal courts ordinarily should not alter state election rules in the period close to an election.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thursday’s order alters Arizona’s state election rules just over two months before a presidential election. Before the Supreme Court ruled, the lower court’s order blocking all three provisions of the 2022 law was in effect. Now the rules have changed, if only slightly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the past, the Court’s Republican majority has wielded <em>Purcell</em> very aggressively when lower court judges handed down voting rights decisions making changes that benefited Democrats. Justice Brett Kavanaugh has even suggested that the <em>Purcell</em> window opens up <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/8/22922774/supreme-court-merrill-milligan-alabama-brett-kavanaugh-racial-gerrymandering-voting-rights-act">more than nine months before a general election</a>. So the GOP’s request to change Arizona’s voting rules less than three months before an election should have been rejected if the justices were being consistent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, unless the 2024 election is historically close, the likelihood that Thursday’s decision will change the result of the upcoming election is small. Again, a majority of the justices voted to reject the GOP’s most aggressive attack on the franchise — the provision of the 2022 law barring federal-only voters from voting for president.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Matthews</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The case of the nearly 7,000 missing pancreases]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/367812/organ-donation-loophole-pancreas-opo" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367812</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T17:28:41Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T17:28:39Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some mysteries that I fear I’ll never see resolved. Who was DB Cooper and what happened to him? Who robbed the Gardner Museum of its Vermeer and Rembrandts in 1990? And, most pressingly: where are the thousands of pancreases taken out of Americans’ dead bodies in 2021, 2022, and 2023 that were never [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1244771286.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There are some mysteries that I fear I’ll never see resolved. Who was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D._B._Cooper">DB Cooper</a> and what happened to him? Who <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isabella_Stewart_Gardner_Museum_theft">robbed the Gardner Museum</a> of its Vermeer and Rembrandts in 1990? And, most pressingly: where are the <a href="https://www.amjtransplant.org/article/S1600-6135(23)00462-8/abstract">thousands of pancreases</a> taken out of Americans’ dead bodies in 2021, 2022, and 2023 that were never transplanted into anybody?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let me back up. Pancreata (the correct plural form of “pancreas”) are one of those organs that are difficult to live without. Without one, you don’t have insulin to regulate blood sugar or enzymes necessary to digest food. So all donated pancreata come from dead people who register as organ donors. In the US, we outsource the job of collecting organs from dead bodies to private groups called organ procurement organizations, or OPOs. Each OPO has a monopoly on organs in a particular geographic area; there are <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/about/search-membership/?memberType=Organ%20Procurement%20Organizations&amp;organType=%27AL%27&amp;state=0&amp;region=0">56 groups total</a>, some of which only cover part of a state and some of which cover multiple states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For some time now, independent analysts and investigative reporters have argued that OPOs are underusing deceased donor organs by the tens of thousands. One report from 2019 estimated that every year <a href="https://www.bridgespan.org/bridgespan/Images/articles/reforming-organ-donation-in-america/reforming-organ-donation-in-america-12-2018.pdf">28,000 usable organs</a> (mostly kidneys but also pancreata, hearts, livers, etc.) from deceased donors are never used; another put <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2018/national/organ-transplant-shortages/?utm_term=.806b23dd755d">the number at 75,000</a>. This, when the national waitlist for organs is <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/learn/organ-donation-statistics">more than 100,000 people long</a>.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, OPOs have faced perverse incentives. For instance, they were most often evaluated on the basis of how many organs are recovered per “eligible death,” but “eligible death” is a determination made by the OPOs themselves. That made it easy to juice the stats by, for instance, classifying some deaths as “ineligible” even when the organs were perfectly usable. That made “organs recovered per eligible deaths” go up without actually getting more people organs. OPO contracts with the federal government are <a href="https://archive.triblive.com/local/pittsburgh-allegheny/taxpayers-help-pay-for-organ-donor-groups-parties-rose-parade-expenses/">quite lucrative</a>, which means OPO executives have ample reason to <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/heartless-organ-donation-contractors-lobby-against-a-popular-health-care-initiative-while-pocketing-pandemic-relief-loans">fight hard</a> to retain them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2019, President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/7/10/20687507/triump-kidney-disease-transplant">issued a quite good executive order</a> instructing the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, which oversees OPOs, to change the way they’re evaluated. The order led to two new metrics that were meant to be harder to game. The rule was finalized in December 2020, and — after also being reviewed and approved by the <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/americas-transformative-new-organ-donation-rule-goes-into-effect-over-objections-from-monopolistic-contractors#:~:text=The%20Centers%20for%20Medicare%20and,effective%20on%20March%2030%2C%202021.">Biden administration</a> — <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/02/02/2021-02180/medicare-and-medicaid-programs-organ-procurement-organizations-conditions-for-coverage-revisions-to">took effect in March 2021</a>. It came with real teeth: OPOs that did particularly badly would face decertification, meaning another OPO with a better track record of serving patients would take over their territory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule had the potential to force OPOs to collect more organs and save thousands more lives every year. But the OPOs quickly figured out a new loophole.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The birth of the pancreas loophole</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule’s new metrics were meant to be based on objective criteria. It asked OPOs to tally the total number of deceased people 75 and younger with causes of death compatible with donation, and then estimate the number of deceased donors each year as a share of that total population, and the number of organs actually used as a share of that total population. The denominator was now something that OPOs couldn’t tamper with. That meant, hopefully, that they’d be judged solely on how many organs they recovered and transplanted into people — on how many thousands of lives they saved.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while OPOs couldn’t muck with the denominator anymore, they could still muck with the numerators. Being a donor generally means that your organs are used in a transplant, but there’s a carveout for one organ: the pancreas. A <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/details/PLAW-108publ362">narrow 2004 law</a> allows researchers running clinical trials to conduct transplants of islet cells (the parts of the pancreas that produce insulin) as a potential cure for diabetes. Because of that law, OPOs could “recover” pancreases for islet cell transplant research, and get credit for recovering more organs under the new rule. But the federal government never asked for any proof that these organs were part of any FDA-approved research.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sure enough, the total number of pancreata that OPOs labeled as for “research” grew from 513 in 2020 to a whopping 3,238 in 2023. The number of donors whose only recovered organ was a pancreas designated for research grew from 25 to 429, according to the <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/">Organ Procurement &amp; Transplantation Network</a>. That’s an over tenfold increase in three years.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-datawrapper wp-block-embed-datawrapper"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="OPOs reported many more pancreas recoveries right after the government started judging them on how many organs they recovered" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/QrbaT/1/" frameborder="0" height="412"></iframe>!function(){"use strict";window.addEventListener("message",(function(a){if(void 0!==a.data["datawrapper-height"]){var e=document.querySelectorAll("iframe");for(var t in a.data["datawrapper-height"])for(var r=0;r&lt;e.length;r++)if(e[r].contentWindow===a.source){var i=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][t]+&quot;px&quot;;e[r].style.height=i}}}))}();
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, Lenny Bernstein, a reporter at the Washington Post who’s been watching this scandal closely, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2023/03/20/organ-transplant-groups-pancreas-collection/">talked to pancreatic researchers</a> who all reported there was no sudden surge in need for pancreases in research projects. Indeed, if you look at the <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/about/search-membership/?memberType=Transplant+Centers&amp;state=-1&amp;region=0">small handful of medical centers</a> that use research pancreata for islet cell transplants, you find that there were only 24 transplants conducted in all of 2023: 22 at the University of Chicago Medical Center, and one each at City of Hope Medical Center outside Los Angeles, and at the Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s 3,238 pancreata recovered for islet cell transplant research in 2023, and only 24 actual transplants conducted that year. Where did the other 3,214 pancreata go? Where did the nearly 7,000 pancreata taken from dead Americans’ bodies over the past three years and not used for transplants go?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The waiting list for people needing just pancreata is <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/learn/organ-donation-statistics/detailed-description#fig1">barely 800 people</a>. That number could be zero if these organs were better allocated. Where are they?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I asked the Association of Organ Procurement Organizations (AOPO), a kind of trade group for the organ procurers, for an explanation. “CMS developed and implemented the current rule governing the use of pancreata for research in 2021. As is required, OPOs have been complying with the rule since that time,” AOPO’s president Dorrie Dils told Vox in a statement. “OPOs have always followed CMS guidance and will continue to do so.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one interpretation. Another is that we could be seeing an attempt by OPOs to get around regulations, and avoid being decertified because they don’t facilitate enough donations. That’s certainly how the <a href="https://www.finance.senate.gov/chairmans-news/wyden-grassley-cardin-young-raise-alarm-over-dramatic-increase-in-pancreata-procurement-">Senate Finance Committee</a>, where a bipartisan group of senators has been investigating the matter, sees it. In a letter to OPOs sent last year, the committee quoted from a listserv of OPO employees. In a thread discussing the new rules, an OPO employee wrote, “If you have a donor with only a pancreas for research, that is an organ donor for the Donor Rate. Otherwise, a donor is any donor with at least 1 organ transplanted. Savvy (or cynical?) OPOs ought to start a pancreas for research program immediately.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Savvy (or cynical?) indeed! In a <a href="https://aopo.org/wp-content/uploads/AOPO-SFC-Pancreas-Research-Statement-03-21-2023.pdf">reply to the committee</a>, AOPO protested that “OPOs have been operating according to the rule” and that the research donations mean “the organ does not go to waste.” Have they not gone to waste? The committee asked OPOs to report back which specific research studies they gave the pancreata to; I know of no OPO that has put out data formally tying each pancreas to a specific study.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This past January, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/qso-24-04-opo.pdf">CMS sent a letter to OPOs</a> reminding them that they could only count pancreases that were actually used for research. But it should go a step further and do what the <a href="https://www.finance.senate.gov/chairmans-news/wyden-grassley-cardin-and-young-call-on-cms-to-strengthen-protections-against-excessive-and-unnecessary-recoveries-of-pancreata-from-organ-donors">Senate committee is urging</a>: clarify that only pancreata donated to research approved by the FDA counts under the rule. That is, OPOs cannot make themselves look better and avoid decertification just by recovering pancreata and then sticking them in a freezer. They have to actually get the pancreata into the hands of scientists.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a very simple change, but it could mean the difference between rules that lead to thousands more organs going to people who need them, and rules that let the current system of unaccountable OPOs continue unabated.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Correction, August 22, 1:20 pm: </em></strong><em>A previous version of this story, originally published August 21, misstated whether a person can live without a pancreas. It’s possible, but difficult.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Miranda Kennedy</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Noel King</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Black women on Kamala Harris and their party’s future]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/368108/black-voters-kamala-harris-democrats" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368108</id>
			<updated>2024-08-22T21:16:14Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-22T17:10:01Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By now, you’ve probably heard the message loud and clear from Democrats: This election is all about unity.&#160; The Today, Explained podcast team has been at the Democratic National Convention in  Chicago this week, and inside and outside the perimeter of the United Center, Democrats are buzzing with exuberance and relief: They now believe they [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Rapper Lil Jon (right) joins the Georgia delegation during the Ceremonial Roll Call of States during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago this week. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2167642099.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Rapper Lil Jon (right) joins the Georgia delegation during the Ceremonial Roll Call of States during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago this week. | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">By now, you’ve probably heard the message loud and clear from Democrats: This election is all about unity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em><a href="http://VOX.COM/TODAy-explained-podcast" data-type="link" data-id="VOX.COM/TODAy-explained-podcast">Today, Explained</a></em> podcast team has been at the Democratic National Convention in  Chicago this week, and inside and outside the perimeter of the United Center, Democrats are buzzing with exuberance and relief: They now believe they have a real shot at winning the White House in 2024, and the party’s toughest issues are not a welcome topic of conversation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tonight, after accepting the party’s nomination earlier in the week from the campaign trail, Kamala Harris will appear in Chicago to close out the convention, carrying the mantle of the “renewed sense of hope” that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/367899/michelle-obama-dnc-convention-speech-2024-hope">Michelle Obama</a> — and the rest of the Democratic Party — have bestowed upon her.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, though, <em><a href="http://VOX.COM/TODAy-explained-podcast" data-type="link" data-id="VOX.COM/TODAy-explained-podcast">Today, Explained</a> </em>sat down with three Black women delegates for Harris to ask about the thorniest challenges, from Gaza policy to identity politics, that Democrats will face in these next 11 weeks before Election Day.  </p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6416947937" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The delegates are:&nbsp;</p>

<ul>
<li>Illinois Lt. Gov. <a href="https://ltgov.illinois.gov/">Juliana Stratton</a>, 58&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Hala_Ayala">Hala Ayala</a>, former Virginia State General Assembly member, 51&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://mojenkins.com/">Mo Jenkins</a>, precinct chair in Harris County, Texas, 25</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All three committed to cast their votes for Harris and consider it their role to support and defend Democratic Party policies. But we picked at the party’s scabs a little bit and found that even the most faithful Democrats were willing to acknowledge that Black voters and nonvoters are no longer the assured bloc of support they have been for decades and that the Israel-Palestine conflict has caused a worrisome fissure between the official party and young progressives. <br><br>Here&#8217;s what they had to say. You can hear more of the discussion <a href="https://link.chtbl.com/todayexplainedpod" data-type="link" data-id="https://link.chtbl.com/todayexplainedpod">here</a> on <em>Today, Explained.</em> </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2166931587.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.75214828329,100,78.49570343342" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A delegate turns their back in protest during a ceremonial roll call vote during the Democratic National Convention on Tuesday. Pro-Palestinian protesters have convened in Chicago to call for an end to US aid to Israel. | David Paul Morris/Bloomberg via Getty ImagesDavid Paul Morris/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="David Paul Morris/Bloomberg via Getty ImagesDavid Paul Morris/Bloomberg via Getty Images" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"> <strong>Gaza and the US policy on Israel remain an open sore for young progressives</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Americans’ disapproval of Israeli military actions in Gaza eased this summer, but 48 percent still disapprove, according to a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646955/disapproval-israeli-action-gaza-eases-slightly.aspx">Gallup poll</a> conducted in June. This week, thousands of protesters, mostly <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/6/23990673/keffiyeh-symbolism-palestinian-history">keffiyeh</a>-clad and young, were waiting for Joe Biden and Kamala Harris — or “Genocide Joe and Killer Kamala,” to them — in Chicago. On Monday, they gathered at Union Park and marched along a circuitous route outside the convention center to demand that the US end aid to Israel. They will march the same route Thursday ahead of Harris’s acceptance speech.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s a live issue for many voters, but especially people like Hala Ayala, who is of Lebanese descent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ayala points out that Harris called for an &#8220;immediate ceasefire&#8221; back in March, and told us she’d met Harris and felt seen on the issue of Gaza. “I took that authentically because that&#8217;s who she is, and I took that as there&#8217;s more work to be done,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The issue of Gaza is also fraught for Gen Z politician Mo Jenkins. Nearly 50 percent of Democrats or Democratic-leaning young adults under 30 say they <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/04/02/younger-americans-stand-out-in-their-views-of-the-israel-hamas-war/">sympathize more with Palestinians</a> than Israelis, according to Pew. That doesn’t always line up with the party’s loyalties: The Biden administration just approved the sale of <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/us-approves-20-billion-weapons-sales-israel-hamas-backs-out-cease-fire-talks/">$20 billion in arms to Israel</a> over the next five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When her Black constituents complain to her about pro-Palestinian activists refusing to back a Black woman candidate for president or not paying enough attention to ignored wars in Sudan or Congo, Jenkins said she tells them that she needs to join the system in order to bring about change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When they ask why she’s leaving them in the cold, her response is: “‘I&#8217;m not leaving you in the cold … We&#8217;re going to end up in the Arctic if I don&#8217;t do the work necessary to make sure that Donald Trump does not become president.’”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><strong>The Democratic Party no longer has the default support of Black Americans</strong></strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It won’t be clear until after the election whether Black voters will turn out for Harris as they have for Democratic candidates in the past, but much has been made in recent months about flagging party support among Black Americans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://goodauthority.org/news/are-black-voters-really-leaving-democratic-party-election-2024/">Data supports</a> the idea that the once-reliable Dem bloc has splintered considerably since 2008, with more Black would-be voters saying they plan instead to cast a vote for former President Donald Trump. This was certainly true when Joe Biden was at the top of the ticket, and now, even with Harris as the Democrats’ candidate for president, a significant share of Black voters are still leaning toward Trump. &nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Seventy percent of Black voters polled in July picked Harris over Trump on a hypothetical ballot, up from 59 percent who backed Biden in May and June polls, according to Reuters/Ipsos polling. But Trump&#8217;s share of the Black vote also rose slightly, to 12 percent in July from 9 percent in May and June.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2166910710.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.694600113617,100,78.610799772766" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Charlamagne tha God was an outspoken critic of President Joe Biden’s candidacy and told Vox this spring that Black people “shouldn’t be beholden to any political party in this country.” | Bryan Bedder/Variety via Getty ImagesBryan Bedder/Variety via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bryan Bedder/Variety via Getty ImagesBryan Bedder/Variety via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Ayala, the Woodbridge, Virginia-based delegate, says the party is well aware of this shuffling of allegiances: “Yeah, there&#8217;s been a separation [between Black men and women on politics]. We&#8217;ve seen it. Like, we can&#8217;t deny that.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jenkins said her Black male constituents in Houston often tell her they are voting for Trump “because he put a stimulus check in my hand.” She said she’ll remind them that their checks “<a href="https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/taxvox/did-adding-trumps-name-slow-down-mailing-stimulus-checks-course-it-did">got delayed</a> because he wanted his name on it. … I think it&#8217;s a confusion about the policy process.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her concern is whether she and other Democrats can effectively set the record straight and make a case to enough of these Trump-interested Black voters ahead of Election Day.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><strong><strong>Identity politics could be a stumbling block</strong></strong></strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This has been a very identity- and social justice-forward DNC. That is a realm Kamala Harris is comfortable in, but it also raises the question for Democrats: Will a focus on identity help them win the White House in November?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many analysts have urged the Harris campaign to avoid talking outright about her race and gender. We asked our roundtable about the theoretical 49-year-old white man in Michigan, a toss-up vote who has voted Democrat in the past. Will Harris talking about her identity as a Black and South Asian woman undermine her chance of getting his vote?<br><br>Stratton, the Illinois lieutenant governor, said emphatically that the Democratic Party also needs to talk about economic issues that impact the whole middle class, to draw voters like him in with discussions of “workers’ rights and making sure that we stand with organized labor. There are a number of things that we&#8217;re going to have to lay out when we talk about reducing gas prices and food prices and all of those other things.<br><br>&#8220;Those are things that everyday Americans are going to want to know.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally&nbsp;appeared&nbsp;in&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong><em>Today, Explained</em></strong></a><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
