<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-10-31T21:30:38+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 election violence is already happening]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381520/2024-election-violence-trump-loses-extremism-civil-war" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381520</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T16:01:17-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T16:01:17-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Political violence has reached alarming levels in the US over the last few years.&#160; The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband, and multiple assassination attempts against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment.  Now, the 2024 election could [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A protester flying a Trump flag and an upside down American flag on the lawn far in front of the Capitol Building." data-caption="Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1230734387.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Political violence has reached <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-politics-violence/">alarming levels </a>in the US over the last few years.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/david-depape-nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attacked-454cbde088fcae22a356f1f8dd0e9eba">attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club">multiple assassination attempts</a> against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the 2024 election could cause another flare-up, especially if Trump loses. Discussion of violence among right-wing extremists has already <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">spiked online</a>, and unlike Vice President Kamala Harris, Trump has refused to say that he would concede.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The polls show a <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">tight race</a> between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, suggesting that this time, as in 2020, the results may be decided by narrow margins in a few battleground states. Trump has been priming Republican voters to reject the results if he comes up short, making <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/29/politics/trump-voter-fraud-claims-pennsylvania/index.html">unsubstantiated claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-noncitizen-voter-fraud-fact-check/">noncitizens voting on a widespread basis</a>. Billionaire Trump supporter Elon Musk has also set up a platform on his social media site X, formerly known as Twitter, for users to &#8220;<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/31/nx-s1-5165523/voting-election-conspiracy-theories-social-media">share potential incidents of voter fraud or irregularities</a> you see while voting in the 2024 election.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those tactics seem to be working. If Trump loses, about a quarter of Republicans said they think he should do whatever it takes to ensure he becomes president anyway, according to a <a href="https://www.prri.org/research/one-leader-under-god-the-connection-between-authoritarianism-and-christian-nationalism-in-america/?preview=true">September PRRI poll</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That may include resorting to violence. Among Republicans who don’t believe Biden’s win in 2020 was legitimate, almost one-third said in an <a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2024/08/07/snf-agora-poll-july-2024/">August poll</a> by the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University that they expected “a lot” or “a great deal” of political violence after the November election. More <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/30/voters-fear-violence-trump-loss/">recent polls</a> have found similar results, including an October <a href="https://apnorc.org/projects/many-voters-are-worried-about-the-electoral-process-and-transition-of-power/">AP-NORC poll</a> that found 27 percent of Republicans, and 42 percent of voters overall, “extremely” or “very” worried about post-election violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this has put law enforcement and national security officials on high alert about political violence in the days before and after the election. Earlier this month, a joint Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and FBI intelligence <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/election-violence-domestic-extremists-fbi-dhs-bulletin/">bulletin</a> said that domestic extremists &#8220;pose a threat of violence to a range of targets directly and indirectly associated with elections through at least the presidential inauguration&#8221; on January 20.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What kind of political violence might break out?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some incidents of political violence have already been recorded in the runup to Election Day. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots in mailboxes and drop boxes in <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-marty-walsh-boston-elections-crime-3d9dd32292187df91d73cb153b9c0a73">Massachusetts,</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballots-damaged-usps-mailbox-fire-phoenix-rcna177067">Arizona</a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballot-boxes-set-fire-portland-vancouver-rcna177611">Washington, and Oregon</a> have been damaged in suspected arson. DHS warned this might happen, based on its monitoring of comments made online in domestic violent extremist circles. In a series of <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">security bulletins</a> in the last few months, the agency noted, “Some threat actors may perceive ballot drop boxes as ‘soft targets’ because they are more accessible” and that some of these actors had discussed a variety of methods for damaging them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A man was also <a href="https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe/2024/10/29/grand-jury-indicts-man-accused-of-shooting-at-democratic-party-office/75924391007/">indicted on terrorism and gun charges</a> for allegedly shooting at the Democratic National Committee’s offices in Phoenix on three occasions since September.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things might only get worse from here. Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco has <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/u-s-news-decision-points/articles/2024-09-24/deputy-ag-u-s-faces-unprecedented-level-of-political-threats">warned</a> that the US is “facing an unprecedented level of, and increase in, threats of violence against public officials.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">DHS bulletins</a>, there is a “heightened risk” that domestic violent extremists could “attempt to initiate civil war.” That kind of chatter has become increasingly common in online spaces <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">frequented by right-wing extremist groups</a>. That said, the DHS noted that the prosecutions of those involved in the January 6 insurrection and hesitation about potential false flag operations designed to entrap them could serve as deterrents.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Law enforcement officials across the country are bracing for the possibility of escalation, particularly in Democratic population centers. For instance, Detroit’s election headquarters have reportedly been reinforced with bulletproof glass and will be protected by armed guards after Trump supporters tried to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/legal/michigan-still-counting-votes-angry-poll-watchers-barred-in-detroit-trump-sues-idUSKBN27K2AL/">interrupt ballot counting</a> by chanting “Stop the count” and banging on the windows in 2020. Philadelphia election staff will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-swing-states-officials-brace-conspiracy-theories-violence-2024-10-30/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=Daily-Briefing&amp;utm_term=103024&amp;user_email=38572e447ae2b3a943d6423dd3d8ad89c2e154a588929a92468b7914f3f4e88f&amp;lctg=66464e6f30f1bc62c305003b">count ballots in a warehouse</a> encircled by a fence with barbed wire, miles from the downtown area where protesters gathered in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, however, these preparations might not be enough to quell domestic violent extremist activity when Republican leaders are encouraging skepticism about the integrity of the election and are reportedly <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/speaker-johnson-appears-to-confirm-a-secret-election-plan-with-trump">making secret plans</a> to assure a second Trump term. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Being aware of the potential for violence and damage to the institutions we rely upon is important,” retired Gen. Joseph Votel, an executive board member of the Center for Ethics and the Rule of Law at the University of Pennsylvania, said in a statement. “But it is insufficient in the face of legislative acts that are open to broad interpretation, strong political rhetoric that dominates the public information space, and imperfect individuals acting in accordance with their oaths.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans are serious about cutting people’s health care]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/health-care/381484/2024-election-donald-trump-health-care-mike-johnson-obamacare" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381484</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T15:45:06-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T15:45:02-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re confused, it’s not an accident. Republicans are trying to have it both ways on health care during the 2024 campaign. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage. That two-step keeps getting them into [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Johnson stands behind and to the left of Trump as he speaks into a microphone." data-caption="House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2148449297.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re confused, it’s not an accident.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans are trying to have it both ways on <a href="https://www.vox.com/health-care">health care</a> during the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">2024 campaign</a>. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That two-step keeps getting them into trouble. House Speaker Mike Johnson was recently <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/house-speaker-mike-johnson-criticizes-obamacare-and-promises-massive-reform-if-trump-wins-223060037976">caught on a tape</a> promising to take “a blow torch to the regulatory state.” Donald Trump, Johnson said, would want to “go big” in his second term because he can’t run for a third one, the speaker told a group of Republican voters in Pennsylvania. And health care, Johnson said, would be “a big part” of the GOP’s agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One attendee directly asked Johnson: No Obamacare? “No Obamacare,” Johnson said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The ACA is so deeply ingrained, we need massive reform to make this work. We’ve got a lot of ideas,” the House speaker added. He wasn’t more specific than that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris’s campaign quickly <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1851604970992263224">flagged</a> Johnson’s comments, and Republicans backtracked. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> campaign <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-campaign-distances-house-speakers-plan-massive-reform/story?id=115313086">said</a> that was “not President Trump’s policy position” and Trump tried to distance himself further in a social media post.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Lyin’ Kamala is giving a News Conference now, saying that I want to end the Affordable Care Act. I never mentioned doing that, never even thought about such a thing. She also said I want to end Social Security. Likewise, never mentioned it, or thought of it. She is the one that…</p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033066157441249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/no-promise-johnson-blasts-dem-accusations-he-vowed-end-obamacare-dishonest">insisted</a> he had not actually promised to repeal Obamacare by emphasizing his comment that the 2010 law was “ingrained” while ignoring his subsequent promise of “massive reform.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself has alluded to having only “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/opinion/trump-harris-concepts-obamacare.html">concepts of a plan</a>” for American health care. That has left other Republicans to fill in the gaps and the party’s specific proposals remain poorly defined. But if there are a lot of details still to be filled in, the theme of the GOP’s health care agenda is clear: cuts. Cutting regulations. Cutting spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson’s comments were not an isolated incident. Just last month, Trump’s vice presidential nominee, JD Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions">hinted</a> at “a deregulatory agenda so that people can pick a health care plan that fits them.” If you actually parse his words about health insurance risk pools, it would be a return to a world where people could be charged more for coverage if they have preexisting medical conditions, the world before Obamacare.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was the same promise Johnson was making. That is the reality: Should they win control of the White House and Congress this election, Republicans will attempt to cut people’s health care.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Republicans still want to make big health care cuts</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Obamacare repeal <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/31/16055960/why-obamacare-repeal-failed">died in 2017</a>, it might have been tempting to think that a chapter had come to a close. Instead, the fight over the future of US health care had entered a new era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Make no mistake: Republican leaders still want to slash health care spending and unwind health insurance regulations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Trump, whatever he might say, has proven before to be malleable to conventional conservative health policy. His people continue to put health care in the crosshairs, sometimes in ways that may not be as obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk, who sometimes appears to be campaigning to be <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/elon-musk-eyes-a-shadow-presidency/">shadow president</a> of the United States, has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">pledged</a> to cut $2 trillion from the federal government’s $6.8 trillion budget. He has <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/the-reidout/reidout-blog/elon-musk-trump-hardship-austerity-taxes-rcna177732">acknowledged</a> that the cuts would result in “temporary” hardship, but insisted they would be to the long-term benefit of the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nationalpriorities.org/budget-basics/federal-budget-101/spending/">About $1 in every $5</a> in the federal budget goes to health care. Barring a severe cut to the US military (unlikely), such a plan would require massive cuts to the health care programs. Trump has often said he will protect Medicare, which covers seniors, but he has in the past endorsed enormous cuts to Medicaid, the program for low-income people that insures <a href="https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/medicaid-and-chip-monthly-enrollment/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">73 million Americans</a>, as part of the 2017 ACA repeal-and-replace bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main Republican bill to repeal and replace the ACA that nearly passed in 2017 was in fact <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/9/15579654/medicaid-cuts-ahca">as much about making massive Medicaid cuts</a> by capping the program’s funding as it was about loosening health insurance regulations or repealing the individual mandate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans could try to pass another Obamacare repeal bill with a comprehensive Medicaid overhaul. Or they could chip away at health care in incremental ways, as we saw during the first Trump term after the Obamacare repeal bill failed. Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/8/16268572/trump-obamacare-navigators">cut funding for enrollment outreach</a> for the ACA markets while <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/8/2/17639124/trump-obamacare-short-term-insurance-plans-36-months">rolling back rules</a> for noncomprehensive plans, which resulted in <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21275498/trump-obamacare-repeal-short-term-health-care-insurance-scam">catastrophic results for some patients</a> who didn’t know what they were signing up for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over Trump’s four years in office, the number of people covered by the ACA <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/state-indicator/marketplace-enrollment/?activeTab=graph&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;startTimeframe=10&amp;selectedRows=%7B%22wrapups%22:%7B%22united-states%22:%7B%7D%7D%7D&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">fell</a> by more than 1 million, to 11.4 million. Since Joe Biden became president, and Democrats expanded the law’s insurance subsidies as part of the Inflation Reduction Act, the number of people covered by marketplace plans has nearly doubled to 21.4 million.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump takes office again, a repeat of that previous sabotage seems likely even if a bigger repeal effort fails to materialize. Republicans could cut outreach funding again. They could make subtler tweaks to the health insurance rules, such as increasing the premiums that older people can be charged compared to younger people or giving insurers more leniency in restricting benefits, networks, and other aspects of a person’s health coverage. They could make more targeted cuts to Medicaid or <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/5/12/23712447/medicaid-work-requirements-us-debt-ceiling">permit states to set up Medicaid work requirements again</a>, as they did in the first Trump term only to be <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/3/13/18263675/medicaid-work-requirements-lawsuit-donald-trump">obstructed by the courts</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Republicans can’t be honest about their health care plan</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The failure of Obamacare repeal is the reason Republicans keep insisting that their health care agenda is not what it plainly is whenever they accidentally reveal their intentions too clearly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s easy to forget now, but Obamacare was a winning issue for Republicans at first. They <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/blogs/washington-whispers/2011/04/12/healthcare-vote-doomed-13-democrats-in-2010-elections">stormed to historic congressional wins in the 2010 midterms</a> by rallying voters against the new health care law. They then took <a href="https://time.com/4712725/ahca-house-repeal-votes-obamacare/">dozens of votes to repeal all or parts of it</a> while Barack Obama still held the veto pen. For most of its first decade, the ACA was deeply unpopular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then Trump won the presidency and the Republicans had to deliver on their promises to repeal and replace the law. GOP leaders did get the new president on board with <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/3/15531494/american-health-care-act-explained">a pretty conservative plan</a>: It would have left the skeleton of the ACA, but pared back its rules and financial aid, while making those huge cuts to Medicaid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then something changed. As the repeal plan started to move through Congress, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/24/15685760/ahca-cbo-score-new">projections</a> of millions of Americans losing health insurance dominated news coverage, the politics of health care flipped. The law had quietly grown to cover a sizable chunk of people —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/issue-briefs/2016/may/americans-experiences-aca-marketplace-and-medicaid-coverage">more than 25 million</a> —&nbsp;and, as importantly, it had started to <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/4708/healthcare-system.aspx#:~:text=During%20most%20of%20the%20years,it%20shouldn't%20be).">change Americans’ minds about the government’s role in providing health care</a>. “Preexisting conditions” became a loaded term, and when people understood that the GOP wanted to unwind the ACA’s health insurance rules, they <a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/2017/5/3/15530008/health-care-preexisting-conditions-insurance">loudly objected</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Medicaid also flexed a political salience not seen before, with <a href="https://time.com/4831386/disability-advocate-protest-gop-health-care-bill/">disability advocates in particular</a> fearful of what cuts to that program would mean for them and drawing widespread coverage for their protests. Senate Republicans from states that expanded Medicaid through the health care law were ultimately responsible for stopping the repeal effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the 2018 midterms, Democrats were <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/11/7/18070152/midterm-elections-2018-results-trump-obamacare-repeal">hammering Republicans over health care</a> and scoring surprising electoral wins. Today, the ACA is <a href="https://www.kff.org/interactive/kff-health-tracking-poll-the-publics-views-on-the-aca/#?response=Favorable--Unfavorable&amp;aRange=twoYear">as popular as it’s ever been</a> and US voters say they <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/poll-finding/kff-health-tracking-poll-may-2024-voters-views-of-health-policy-issues-in-context-of-presidential-campaigns/">trust Democrats more on health care</a> than the GOP.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This series of events has left Republicans in a bind. The relative success of the ACA has expanded the welfare state and influenced Americans’ perceptions of the role of government in ways that are antithetical to conservative economic thinking. They want to claw back some of those progressive wins. But they also have to be mindful of the changed politics of health care.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once in a while, particularly in “safe” conservative spaces, they slip up, admit they want to unwind the ACA, and then have to backtrack. Mike Johnson’s only mistake was being candid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 3:45 pm ET:</strong> This story was originally published earlier on October 31 and has been updated to include Trump’s social media post about the ACA.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump really could empower RFK Jr. to wreck public health]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381470/trump-rfk-cabinet-hhs-vaccines-health" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381470</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T17:01:35-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T14:25:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the most part, Donald Trump has been mum on who he’d appoint to his administration if he wins. But he has made one pretty clear promise: Trump has said he’ll let conspiracy theorist and vaccine skeptic Robert F. Kennedy Jr. “go wild” on health, food, and drug regulation. That could have massive consequences for [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump stands and smiles onstage with his hand on Robert Kennedy’s shoulder." data-caption="Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2180628742_f78212.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, Donald Trump has been mum on who he’d appoint to his administration if he wins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he has made one pretty clear promise: Trump has said he’ll let <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/07/13/1187272781/rfk-jr-kennedy-conspiracy-theories-social-media-presidential-campaign">conspiracy theorist</a> and <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/08/30/rfk-jr-trump-campaign-public-health-policy-issue/">vaccine skeptic</a> Robert F. Kennedy Jr. “<a href="https://www.politico.com/video/2024/10/28/trump-says-he-would-let-rfk-jr-go-wild-on-medicines-1466853">go wild</a>” on health, food, and drug regulation. That could have massive consequences for public health and vaccine policy in America. If Kennedy were to completely get his way and deter vaccination, vaccine-preventable diseases like <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23438552/covid-vaccine-refusal-hesitancy-politics-polarization-pandemic-mandates">measles and polio could make a comeback</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy, who ended his third-party presidential run to endorse Trump <a href="https://apnews.com/article/rfk-jr-trump-speech-arizona-a2638f89ddcb5de03edbe4574ca17d45">in August</a>, expects big things. He <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/30/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/robert-f-kennedy-jr-trump-administration-00186227">told supporters</a> at a recent virtual event that Trump “promised” him “control of the public health agencies, which are HHS and its sub-agencies, CDC, FDA, NIH, and a few others,” as well as the Department of Agriculture. Kennedy has also <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">said</a> he’d be “deeply involved in helping to choose the people” heading those agencies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump transition co-chair Howard Lutnick <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/robert-f-kennedy-trump-transition-chair-vaccines-public-health.html">said Wednesday on CNN</a> that Kennedy is “not getting a job” at the Department of Health and Human Services, but Lutnick voiced complete sympathy with Kennedy’s beliefs that vaccines cause autism. “I spent two and a half hours this week with Bobby Kennedy Jr. and it was the most extraordinary thing,” Lutnick said, proceeding to say he believes in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/5/11/15508006/what-causes-autism-spectrum-disorder-vaccine-theory">debunked theory</a> that vaccines cause autism.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Trump has a <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/366472/2024-election-donald-trump-vaccines-schools">muddled stance</a> on the Covid-19 vaccines his administration approved, he’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/9/17/9346685/republican-debate-trump-autism">long been a believer</a> that childhood vaccines cause autism. He reiterated that belief in a call seeking Kennedy’s endorsement this summer (which was recorded and posted publicly by Kennedy’s son): Trump complained that babies now get too many vaccines and then “change radically.” He added: “I’ve seen it too many times.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to make it clearer that Kennedy’s views would have deep sympathy at the top of Trump’s administration. In his first term, experts, scientists, and professionals remained in charge of such issues — hence the Covid vaccine development. But given the right-wing backlash against such experts that the pandemic brought, Trump’s second term could well be quite different. The risk that Kennedy would take a wrecking ball to public health regulation and especially vaccine policy is very real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tucker Carlson, appearing at an event with Kennedy this week, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/23/health/video/the-lead-dr-paul-offit-trump-rfk-jr-vaccine-covid-government-medicine-regulations-jake-tapper">was positively gleeful</a> about that prospect. “Can you imagine if you’re at FDA or NIH and Bobby Kennedy all of a sudden” came in, Carlson said, breaking off in laughter. “I mean, they must be dying!”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">RFK probably couldn’t be confirmed by the Senate. He could exercise vast influence anyway.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Public health leaders, including some <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">former GOP</a> and <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">Trump appointees</a>, have been quite alarmed at the prospect of giving Kennedy sway over public health policy. Jerome Adams, who was Trump’s surgeon general in his first term, <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">said Monday</a> this “could further erode people&#8217;s willingness to get up to date with recommended vaccines” and that he was “worried” about the impact on Americans’ health.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others have reacted with skepticism to the prospect of Kennedy getting a top agency job, pointing out that a post like HHS secretary <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/10/30/2024/senate-republicans-could-block-trump-from-putting-rfk-jr-in-the-cabinet">requires Senate confirmation,</a> a prospect that would seem unlikely even if the GOP regains control of the chamber. Sens. Susan Collins (R-ME) and Lisa Murkowski (R-AK), the two most moderate Republican senators, serve on the committee that would consider that nomination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet there is a model for how Kennedy could serve in government and exercise vast influence despite not being Senate-confirmed. Call it the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373479/stephen-miller-mass-deportation-camps-trump-agenda">Stephen Miller model</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Miller, an extreme anti-immigration ideologue, served as a White House senior adviser (a job that doesn’t require Senate confirmation). But he exercised vast influence at federal agencies that handled immigration policy so much that he was dubbed “<a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2018/08/29/stephen-miller-immigration-policy-white-house-trump-799199">the president of immigration</a>.” He <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/02/stephen-miller-green-card-immigration-1630406">berated</a> agency officials to carry out his preferred policies and, when he felt some Trump appointees weren’t getting the job done, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/08/opinions/stephen-miller-immigration-white-house-purge-elliot-williams/index.html">engineered their ouster</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is entirely possible that Trump could appoint Kennedy to a similar role if he wanted one. It’s far from clear whether Kennedy would prove as effective a bureaucratic operator as Miller, but he certainly matches Miller in obsessive monomania over his particular issue, having argued <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/robert-kennedy-jrs-belief-in-autism-vaccine-connection-and-its-political-peril/2014/07/16/f21c01ee-f70b-11e3-a606-946fd632f9f1_story.html">for two decades</a> that vaccines cause autism, as a writer, an activist, and then as a political candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another reason Miller had such influence is that it was believed throughout the Trump administration that he was speaking for Trump, that they had a “mind-meld” on immigration. And Trump’s comments have long made it clear he agrees with Kennedy on childhood vaccinations. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Kennedy does not officially join the government, he could still have a major impact on policy. If accurate, his claim that he’ll be “deeply involved” in Trump’s public health appointment decisions means he could choose like-minded allies to try and overhaul public health agencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The real question is whether Trump would stake political capital on what would surely be an intensely controversial overhaul of US vaccine policies. Despite his belief in the autism link, Trump simply didn’t choose to really do anything about it in his first term. If he were to win a second term, though, he would owe Kennedy for his support, and anti-vaccine sentiment has been rising on the right.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the biggest mystery hanging over a potential Trump second term is just how out of control he has gotten since he left office. The Republican establishment would like to believe that, in practice, Trump will still heavily rely on them and appoint capable people rather than kooks to top posts. But perhaps Trump will feel less beholden to that establishment than ever and more willing to reward his extreme supporters. That’s certainly what Kennedy is betting on.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Google a bigger threat to democracy than Trump? A debate.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/380978/trump-google-democracy-big-tech-monopoly-lina-khan" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=380978</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T13:29:41-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T13:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Biden era has witnessed a revolution in the Democratic Party’s approach to policing large corporations. Under the leadership of chair Lina Khan, the Federal Trade Commission has grown markedly more aggressive in blocking mergers and cracking down on big business’s exploitative practices. This has earned Khan’s FTC plaudits from critics of corporate power. But [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A sign with the Google logo on it. " data-caption="Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2180164057.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden era has witnessed a revolution in the Democratic Party’s approach to policing large corporations. Under the leadership of chair Lina Khan, the Federal Trade Commission has grown markedly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-10-09/lina-khan-on-a-second-ftc-term-ai-price-gouging-data-privacy">more aggressive in blocking mergers</a> and <a href="https://www.economicliberties.us/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/FTC-Accomplishments.pdf">cracking down on big business’s exploitative practices</a>. This has earned Khan’s FTC <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/09/lina-khan-federal-trade-commission-antitrust-monopolies">plaudits</a> from critics of corporate power. But Khan’s policies have also attracted the indignation of the Democratic Party’s <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/kamala-harris-linkedin-reid-hoffman-ftc-chair-lina-khan-rcna163897">supporters in Silicon Valley,</a> as well as concerns from <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/12/lina-khans-rough-year-running-the-federal-trade-commission.html">some longtime civil servants at the FTC</a>, who question the strategic and substantive wisdom of Khan’s approach to antitrust enforcement. Both these factions are now bitterly fighting for presidential nominee Kamala Harris’s favor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a cover story for Harper’s Magazine this month, Barry Lynn makes the case for the “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2024/10/the-antitrust-revolution-big-tech-barry-c-lynn/">antitrust revolution</a>.” Lynn is the intellectual godfather of the modern antimonopoly movement. Once a business reporter, he has spent the better part of two decades chronicling the evils of corporate concentration. His antimonopoly think tank, the <a href="https://www.openmarketsinstitute.org/">Open Markets Institute</a>, employed Khan as its legal director before she entered government.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his Harper’s essay, Lynn frames the fight against Big Tech in apocalyptic terms. He argues that the power of Google and Amazon today is analogous to that of absolute monarchs in the 17th century — and that such corporate titans pose an even more pressing threat to American democracy than Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I sympathize with many of Lynn’s concerns and think that Khan’s FTC has done a lot of good. But I also found parts of Lynn’s Harper’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly">piece hyperbolic and unconvincing</a>. So I spoke with him about my objections, the impact of Big Tech on journalism and publishing, the political power of small business, whether monopolies have made America more racist, and other topics. Our conversation has been edited for concision and clarity. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>In your Harper’s essay, you suggested t</strong><strong>hat Google, Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, and Apple wield power analogous to that of absolute monarchs, and that together they constitute a greater threat to political liberty in the United States than Donald Trump.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there not a categorical difference between wielding a lot of influence over commerce and controlling a monopoly on the legitimate use of violence, as monarchs and, to an extent, presidents do? Google doesn’t have the power to selectively prosecute and imprison public officials it does not like. But an authoritarian president plausibly could. So why do you think Big Tech is ultimately the bigger threat?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think the clear point I was trying to make is that these are both really disturbing, terrifying concentrations of power. In the case of Trump, the White House, even after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">recent decision in the Supreme Court,</a> there&#8217;s still an immense number of restraints on the presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What you&#8217;re talking about — we&#8217;re not there yet. And whatever Trump has said, it&#8217;s going to take him a few steps at least to get there. Whereas what we&#8217;re talking about right now with big tech is where we are now. This is not theoretical. This is the power they have <em>now</em>, so that&#8217;s a really key thing to keep in mind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But would you agree that there are constraints on the power of these companies in the current context? I think even before the recent revival of aggressive enforcement at the FTC, the government </strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/24/apple-google-settle-antitrust-lawsuit-hiring-collusion"><strong>sussed out collusion in terms of hiring practices</strong></a><strong> among these big tech companies. So are there not limits that these companies need to operate within, just as the president currently does?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In that case, what you had is, some tens of thousands of employees who were being restricted in their ability to go from one company to another through no-poach agreements. Yes, they did win that case. But I think it was like a $5 million fine, and a little pretend slap on the wrist, don&#8217;t do it again. <em>[Editor’s note: The companies </em><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/tech-industry/apple-google-others-settle-anti-poaching-lawsuit-for-415-million/"><em>paid $415 million</em></a><em> to settle a civil suit over the no-poach agreements.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That was affecting the lives of a lot of people, and they got a little slap on the wrist. I don&#8217;t think that that case in itself had very much effect on their sense of the power of the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I&#8217;m talking about their power, it&#8217;s not just the power over their workers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I first got into this work, not through Google, but through Amazon. When I published my book, <em>Cornered</em>, it was 2010. And in the process of writing that book, I had really spent a lot of time talking to my editor, to my agent, and then, to other people who were writing books and to their editors. And I realized that American publishers with Amazon were facing a situation in which you had a company that controlled the gate to the marketplace — and was unconstrained by any traditional laws requiring them to keep the gate open equally for all comers. They had the ability to open and close the gate arbitrarily to the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were there any examples of them doing that in an egregious way that illustrates the danger of that kind of power?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh, yes. I spent a lot of time talking to CEOs and publishers back then, David Young at Hachette USA. I spoke to Drake McFeely at Norton. These are one-on-one meetings. And the basic thing was: When the door was open, they would say, “Amazon is our absolute best customer.” When the door was closed, they&#8217;d say “Amazon is a dictator that was entirely interfering in our business in arbitrary ways. We don&#8217;t have access to the marketplace. We don&#8217;t connect with the reader, the buyer, because Amazon&#8217;s determining how we&#8217;re connecting.” And that&#8217;s only gotten worse over the last 15 years. <em>[Editor’s note: </em><em>Young neither confirmed nor denied this account, saying he did not remember meeting Lynn, as it would have been more than 15 years ago. McFeely could not be reached for comment.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In February 2010, Amazon shut off the buy buttons for McMillan. McMillan was complaining <em>[that Amazon was devaluing its authors’ work by </em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/01/30/technology/30amazon.html"><em>charging only $9.99 for ebooks</em></a><em>]</em>. What Amazon did is they just said no more “buy” buttons. It&#8217;s like: You&#8217;re not selling on Amazon. Back then, Amazon was probably responsible for 40, 50 percent of their book sales in the United States. It&#8217;s now higher, much higher. But even if it&#8217;s only 40, 50 percent, you can&#8217;t stand to lose that much of your capacity for sales, so they gave up.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were any of the conflicts between publishers and Amazon explicitly about the content of work, as opposed to terms of compensation for ebooks?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">About the content? There was some point at which, I think it was Tom Cotton or somebody who was on TV or Fox — a politician who was having a fit about how they&#8217;re being suppressed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But let&#8217;s just say there is no evidence of Amazon ever trying to suppress a particular viewpoint, right? But, there&#8217;s two things. One is, when you either suppress a particular publisher because they don&#8217;t have the money to pay you the extortionary rates of advertising, then you&#8217;re less likely to be found. You have less opportunity to make your way to the market. Two, when you promote one book, you suppress every other book in the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s a two-way amplification of a book — amplification of a publisher — so that there&#8217;s de facto suppression of all the books, de facto suppression of all other publishers. You can have very large effects on what books are being published, how they&#8217;re being sold, what ideas people are connecting with. The effects can be a byproduct of a business model, a byproduct of unconscious decisions that were somewhat automated that have no political intent in and of themselves. But they have a political effect.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I imagine there’s an analogy there to your view of the role that algorithms on social media play, in terms of amplifying. Maybe it&#8217;s a completely neutral algorithm that is just amplifying whatever gets the most engagement. But that has implications for what content ultimately gets the most attention.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. But the thing is that as these middlemen — who are in between the people who are speaking and the people who are listening, in between the author and the readers, the author and the voter, in between the creator and the buyer, the seller and the buyer — as these masters in the middle gather more and more and more information about each individual person, and about each individual company, they use that information to manipulate both sides of the market.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More and more perfectly, they use it to push you as a reader: Oh, you liked a book about this battle in World War II. Well, you&#8217;re going to like another book about this battle in World War II, and you&#8217;re going to like this third book about this battle in World War II. And then, you know what, there’s this guy who&#8217;s used an analogy to that battle in World War II to talk about Trump politics, maybe you&#8217;ll like him too. So you can see how a couple of things happen when you have this kind of a system, which is that as they feed off their knowledge of you, they drag you more and more to what we used to call filter bubbles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I feel like there’s an argument that what you’re describing isn’t that different from organic processes of knowledge acquisition, which existed before the internet. Like, say you are a left wing-minded person, and you read a book by Tom Frank in the early 2000s or something. And that gets you interested in other books that he&#8217;s written, and authors that he cites, and you start subscribing to certain magazines, and that self-reinforcing kind of interest or ideology is a natural process that humans engage in when learning about the world, and developing interests, and that this isn&#8217;t necessarily such an insidious</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, absolutely. You&#8217;re absolutely right, and that&#8217;s a good thing. That&#8217;s how we educate ourselves. But, there&#8217;s a huge difference between when Tom Frank wrote <em>What&#8217;s the Matter With Kansas?</em> and then that leads you to a review of it in the Nation; I started reading the Nation. I had to take out a subscription to the Nation, maybe. I take out a subscription to Mother Jones. But maybe, I learned that there&#8217;s actually a left-wing bookstore in Chicago, and I go to that bookstore, and I find a whole bunch of other books. And so, then suddenly, it&#8217;s like I found a bunch of work, and a bunch of people that helped me answer the questions that I&#8217;ve been asking. And so, that&#8217;s fantastic, and I certainly live that life.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, when you have fewer and fewer, and fewer places that you&#8217;re interacting with, when you get down to one major place where you&#8217;re going to buy books online, when you get down to one major place or two major places — if you&#8217;re getting most of your news off of TikTok or you get it off of Facebook — you&#8217;re not going to read the New York Times, and that&#8217;s going to make it very hard for you to link out to the New York Times site. You&#8217;re getting most of your news off the platform.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At that point, exploration is not something you control. You have then actually lost your sovereignty. You&#8217;ve lost your ability to control your own destiny in this process, and you go where they take you. Now, you went to a really good college; you know how to protect yourself against some of this bullshit. But I bet that sometimes you find yourself getting suckered in on it. But a lot of folks don&#8217;t know how to protect themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To get to a separate claim in your Harper’s piece: You write that monopolists are a leading driver of &#8220;the surge in racism and homophobia&#8221; and &#8220;the attacks on reproductive choice&#8221; in the United States. I was wondering what you were thinking about specifically here. To me, it is not clear that there has even been a surge in racism and anti-gay bigotry in the United States; support for marriage for </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646202/sex-relations-marriage-supported.aspx#:~:text=Same%2DSex%20Marriage%20Support%20Near,recorded%20in%202022%20and%202023."><strong>same-sex</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/354638/approval-interracial-marriage-new-high.aspx"><strong>interracial couples</strong></a><strong> remains near record highs in Gallup&#8217;s polling. And in any case, certainly America has grown more progressive on race and gender since 1981 — the year that you believe that antitrust policy changed for the worse.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what&#8217;s your timeline here? I mean, you gotta separate out the different things. Okay? It&#8217;s like, yeah, okay, in 1981, Reagan makes it easier for General Electric to roll up control over televisions, or he makes it easier for Walmart to roll up control over retail. So at that point, you&#8217;re not actually dealing with communications platforms. So there&#8217;s a revolutionary change in how we do competition policy, which is applied initially to industrial and retail firms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it didn&#8217;t happen all at once. Reagan starts the process. Clinton then extends it to banking, to the defense industrial base, to oil and gas, to telecommunications. And then what you have over time with telecommunications, you have a shift in business models, which takes place around 15 years ago — 10 to 15 years ago — from relatively unobtrusive forms of manipulation, to manipulation as the foundation of the business model. So to say that, well, between 1981 and 2011, racism and homophobia went down in the United States, and then even though it has increased radically in the years since, that my thesis is somehow wrong, I don&#8217;t follow.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I think it&#8217;s an open question to me whether they&#8217;ve increased radically since then versus becoming more visible because of the way these platforms amplify certain speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re taking parts of the thesis out and you&#8217;re saying, &#8220;Well, I&#8217;m not sure that it works.&#8221; So it&#8217;s like, if you take the thesis apart, then yeah, then maybe things start to fall apart. But the thesis is that the reason that these people have these abilities is because we fail to apply traditional anti-monopoly laws.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Yeah, I agree that that&#8217;s the overarching thesis.</strong><strong><br></strong><br>Yeah. Okay. So what&#8217;s the issue then?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>So I also wanted to touch on the claim about reproductive choice. I agree that large businesses are involved in </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/6/3/18632438/federalist-society-leonard-leo-brett-kavanaugh"><strong>the Federalist Society</strong></a><strong>, and the right’s project there is both to empower big business and to restrict abortion rights. At the same time, when I look at </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/google-inc/totals?id=D000022008"><strong>FEC filings</strong></a><strong>, the </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/apple-inc/totals?id=D000021754"><strong>large</strong></a><strong> tech </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/amazon-com/totals?id=D000023883"><strong>monopolists</strong></a><strong> of our age throughout the past 10 years have generally given a lot more money to the Democratic Party — the pro-choice party — then to the pro-life party. If their money determined these elections, then Dobbs wouldn&#8217;t have happened. And there&#8217;s lots of small businesses and regional businesses that fund the American right.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Eric, corporations are complicated things. They do a lot of different things at the same time. They curry favor on both sides. Look at Mr. Horowitz from Andreessen Horowitz, right? Two months ago, he was all in for Trump. Now it looks like his friend, Harris, may win. So suddenly, he&#8217;s like, &#8220;Oh, poor Harris.&#8221; Andreessen is still out there, totally 100% in. Crazy-ass Andreessen is still out there 100% in for Trump. Musk is leaping up and down like a maniac on the stage in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So really, you&#8217;re going to say because Google threw some money behind some Democrats — and even then, it&#8217;s like, was it Google or is it the individuals in the corporation? Corporations, they do with their money what makes sense for them politically.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Do you think that small- and regional-sized businesses are any different in that respect?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Small- and medium-sized business, they&#8217;re different because they&#8217;re less politically powerful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But can&#8217;t small business interests pool together in the Chamber of Commerce, in various other systems to &#8230;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, of course, that&#8217;s their right. But it&#8217;s very different. A Chamber of Commerce is generally much less powerful as an organization than a large corporation. You got a whole bunch of different people who are working through an issue. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to agree on. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to disagree on. So the things they disagree on, they tend not to take political positions. So it&#8217;s just a basic rule of democracy that dividing power is going to make it less likely that an actor is going to rise up and threaten the democratic system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To play devil’s advocate, what do you make of the </strong><strong>idea that actually, small businesses — precisely because in this country, we have this deep-seated yeoman farmer ideal, and the small proprietor has cultural cache —&nbsp; that this actually gives them pretty significant power over politics.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god, you&#8217;re repeating to me ancient libertarian truisms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, but there are </strong><a href="https://genlawgroup.com/do-you-know-which-laws-dont-apply-to-small-businesses/#:~:text=Small%20businesses%20may%20be%20exempt,%2C%20national%20origin%2C%20and%20religion."><strong>lots of federal regulations</strong></a><strong> — labor regulations — that small businesses are exempt from while large businesses have to abide by them. And so there are these ways in which arguably, the government shows some degree of affection for small businesses that maybe is not extended to large corporations.</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I have no understanding of how you could actually come to that conclusion. I mean, it&#8217;s like the affection for small business is just some little crumbs that Congress tosses to the little people once every four years or once every two years. And almost any one of these, they&#8217;re recent. Go do your homework, go actually look at how the SBA operates. Look at how every one of these laws that&#8217;s designed for farming support, where that money goes to. Very little of it goes to the small actor. It&#8217;s just enough to shut them up. Other than, say, Vance and Hawley, and Warren and Klobuchar, who&#8217;s really making their business taking on big corporations? So where is this imaginary world in which the government is favoring small business over big business?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I guess I&#8217;m just referring specifically to both proposed legislation and actual laws that exempt companies with, say, less than 25 employees from this or that federal regulation. There seems to be a sensitivity</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wait, wait, wait, listen. The point of this conversation is not to go in and re-litigate antiquated conversations that the libertarians put together in the 1970s. If you want to have this, you go read my book. You can read my first book, you can read my second book, you can read my third book. You can read all kinds of other work that&#8217;s out there. We don&#8217;t have to waste our time — while I&#8217;m driving down the highway — having these arguments. Go do some reading.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I mean, I’m partially speaking for readers who haven&#8217;t necessarily done all that reading and would like to know what</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No, no, this is your job. You can go read and you can explain it. Like I said, go read <em>Cornered</em>. Go read <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. Go read Sally Hubbard&#8217;s or Jasper T. Scott&#8217;s books. There&#8217;s a lot of books that get it just from different levels, different angles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s all kinds of articles you can read up on. There&#8217;s been just a broad destruction of independent business across America over the last 40 years. If you want to learn some of the math, you can go get a copy of <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. I do the math about Walmart.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Retail was designed in the old days to serve everybody. The business was regulated to ensure that any family with some wherewithal could get into it, go out and start a business, to start a grocery. And these weren&#8217;t little rinky-dink groceries. They&#8217;re family-owned supermarkets.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a long period of time, all of the great technological advances that were made in groceries were made by independent people trying to get ahead of their rival down the street. Now, if you are Walmart and your rival down the street is Walmart, and down the next town, the rival is Walmart, you don&#8217;t have to do a damn thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Isn&#8217;t Walmart under competitive pressure from Amazon?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god. Yeah, of course, they&#8217;re under a little bit of competitive pressure from Amazon. And Google&#8217;s under a little bit of competitive pressure on certain lines of business from Apple. Right? But it doesn&#8217;t mean that this is an open and democratic system. It doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s a system that is designed to prevent fascism and the absolute concentration of power over. Again, Eric, you got to do your homework. If you wanted to have a conversation, you want to be the devil&#8217;s advocate, come at me with something that&#8217;s worthwhile.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. I will ask you a question that maybe you&#8217;ll like better. So, the other thing I wanted to ask about from your Harper&#8217;s piece: You discussed the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision in Moody versus NetChoice. A colleague of mine </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/2/26/24083652/supreme-court-netchoice-paxton-moody-texas-florida-first-amendment-social-media-facebook-youtube"><strong>wrote about it as well</strong></a><strong>. At issue in that case was whether the governments of Florida and Texas could prohibit social media platforms from taking down posts based on the viewpoint represented in the user&#8217;s expression or another person&#8217;s expression. Justice Elena Kagan argued that Texas’s proposed restrictions on content moderation would effectively compel Facebook to tolerate neo-Nazi and pro-teen suicide content on their platforms and this would constitute a violation of those firms’ rights of free speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You suggested that by making this ruling, the liberal justices mounted as “outriders for autocracy,” and you argued that giving social media platforms the right to moderate content at their own whim was as antithetical to democracy as giving the president criminal immunity from official acts. And so, what would you say to a liberal, like my colleague, Ian Millhiser, who believes that allowing major platforms to bar pro-anorexia and pro-genocide content is actually in the public interest, and that enabling right-wing state governments to dictate which points of view private companies must platform would itself put us on a slippery slope to authoritarianism?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you go read the decision, a corporation has First Amendment rights as a corporation. Publishers have First Amendment rights as publishers. The case that we are making and what many other people are making — and this can give you a misunderstanding — is that these are platforms, not publishers. Platforms are curators. And so platforms are places where people come together to communicate with each other, where publishers come to gather with readers to share information with each other. And if you allow the master in the middle, the middle man, to manipulate that, then you have grossly interfered with the rights of the 330 million people in America — I guess, some of them are babies, so they&#8217;re not necessarily using these platforms — but every American youth relies on these platforms to communicate with other Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I&#8217;d say that Kagan&#8217;s thinking is that she&#8217;s basically advocating for the suppression of the First Amendment rights of every citizen of the United States who relies on these platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the idea that Florida and Texas and Ohio are going to force these platforms to carry what the states want them to, no. It&#8217;s like there&#8217;s a missing part of this conversation, and it&#8217;s called the terms of service. All these people have a right to publish terms of service. And under terms of service, they can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to carry racist material.&#8221; We can say, “We&#8217;re not going to carry stuff that we believe is harmful to kids, that seems to promote eating disorders or suicide.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So then, once you publish your terms of service, you can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to publish anything that seems to advocate violence.&#8221; And it&#8217;s like, as long as you apply the terms of service equally without favor to all of your users, then you can shut down whatever you want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there any principle that binds what they can put into a terms of service? It seems to me that, by this logic, if the social media company establishes a politically biased term of service, then that could result in what you&#8217;re concerned about — and I&#8217;m concerned about as well — in terms of deplatforming legitimate points of view. So what legally binds a company from just crafting the terms of service so they can discriminate against whichever point of view they want to suppress?&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well, the thing is that at a certain point, the Essential Facilities Doctrine, traditional American communications doctrine, is once you get to a certain size, that would be discriminatory. Political discrimination is illegal.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I just want to clarify the principles here. It seems to me there&#8217;s no way to permit all political speech regardless of its perspective on social media platforms </strong><strong><em>and</em></strong><strong> prohibit racist speech from them (since there is a lot of racist, political speech). So I guess, how do you see resolving that? I took you as saying that basically: We should have a situation where you can express any viewpoint on these platforms — no matter how vile — if it isn&#8217;t direct harassment or a direct violent threat, but that the platform shouldn&#8217;t be amplifying that speech. Is that correct? Or what is your view?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People can go to the branded publications, right? If you wanted to hear a certain kind of speech — if your morning&#8217;s not going to be complete without a big plate of racism along with your eggs and your coffee — then you can have a racist publication. You can have a Nazi publication. And the people who need that, they can go sit on the website of the publication and get what they want. That&#8217;s the beauty of America, is that you don&#8217;t need the middleman to boost it. And you can still get it, you can still go find it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. Well, there are a few other questions I had, but you&#8217;re running close to time, right?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. I appreciate you trying to be a devil&#8217;s advocate, but I just encourage you, as you&#8217;re working through this — because you&#8217;re smart, you&#8217;re clearly asking a lot of the right questions — is just continue to do your research. Don&#8217;t react. And whenever you&#8217;re starting to see stuff that is reacting against the kind of stuff that we&#8217;re doing, just question, “Who is paying for that?” Just question who it is. Because almost every single person who&#8217;s coming at us, someone is paying for that person to come at us.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Who came out looking the worst on Love Is Blind season 7]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/381017/love-is-blind-season-7-reunion-winners-losers-hannah-nick-ramses-leo" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381017</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T17:30:38-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T10:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Reality TV" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="TV" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another season of Love Is Blind has come and gone, and in its wake we were left with two marriages, five breakups, a villain who bullies, a gold-digging hero, and at least one secret father who never mentioned his children to his partner. Initially, season seven didn’t look like it was ever going to peak [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman holding a cup and a man face each other" data-caption="Hannah and Nick, one of Love Is Blind’s worst couples on season seven. Behold their absolute incompatibility. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E6_00_41_56_16R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Hannah and Nick, one of Love Is Blind’s worst couples on season seven. Behold their absolute incompatibility. | Courtesy of Netflix</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Another season of <em>Love Is Blind</em> has come and gone, and in its wake we were left with two marriages, five breakups, a villain who bullies, a gold-digging hero, and at least one secret father who never mentioned his children to his partner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Initially, season seven didn’t look like it was ever going to peak — a mini letdown since it was <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/375548/love-is-blind-dc-season-7-recap-review">shot in DC</a> and DC is notoriously one of the more annoying places to date. But it eventually ramped into one of the more memorable seasons of <em>Love Is Blind</em>. Mess, drama, dysfunction — this season had it all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This season&#8217;s slow build, the shenanigans that later ensued, and the attention and discourse it eventually generated bring up a question inherent to the existence of the show: What does it mean when we say <em>Love Is Blind</em> had a “good” season?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Contrary to the show’s mission, a good season doesn’t mean that couples found love, it means people found strangers to break up with. The more outrageous and awful the breakups, the more viewers watch and keep the show in conversations. <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/love-blind-tops-nielsen-streaming-193036816.html">Higher ratings for Netflix</a> are negatively correlated with marital bliss for anyone on the show. <em>Love Is Blind</em> has never really been about love being blind; it’s just a window for viewers to get a glimpse into some regrettable relationships. Now, in season seven, we’re getting pure chaos, the real, unfiltered stuff.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while romantic success might not be on the table, it’s still possible to win the show, in a sense. And it’s certainly possible to lose. With that in mind, here’s who came out on top, who came out looking awful, who found love, and all those who didn’t on season seven of <em>Love Is Blind</em>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: For the 7th season running, the experiment to see if love is indeed blind</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since its inception, <em>Love Is Blind</em> has purported to be an “experiment” to see if true love is a real thing that can transcend the superficiality of physical attraction. Also since its inception, <em>Love Is Blind</em> has never really been about what it says it’s about. The show has <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23464762/love-is-blind-cole-zanab-season-3">always had an eye for mess</a>, and with each season, it has allowed more and more messiness to bloom.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E1_00_04_39_07R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="Women sitting on the Love Is Blind set listening to the two hosts standing on a platform in front of them." title="Women sitting on the Love Is Blind set listening to the two hosts standing on a platform in front of them." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="&lt;em&gt;Love Is Blind&lt;/em&gt; is not really about whether love is blind. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In this seventh installment, several of the participants appear to have been chosen because of their potential for drama rather than their earnest desire to be loved. From men who claim to be insecure about having so much money, to women who talk about their relationships in corporate HR speak, to trophy wives and men who live in their parents’ basement, it seems as though the casting department went out of their way to find a group of people who would yield the most incompatible couples and messiest breakups possible. That’s fine — and it makes wonderful television — but we&#8217;re still rooting a little for the scientists.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: Netflix</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the season, there were two weddings. Both couples — Garrett and Taylor, Tyler and Ashley — got married. Going by the show’s body count of people getting rejected at the ceremony, that’s a successful end-of-season! No one was dumped in front of their family, and everyone seemed so happy at the end.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s unclear, however, is whether Ashley and Tyler will stay together. In the show, post-pods, Tyler finally told Ashley he donated his sperm to a same-sex couple. While the show was airing, <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/10/20/entertainment/mother-of-love-is-blind-star-tyler-francis-3-kids-claims-they-had-unplanned-twins-naturally/">tabloids reported</a> that the relationship between Tyler, his children, and their mother was more involved than Tyler let on. In the reunion, which aired Wednesday on Netflix, the two said they were still together and that despite how it seemed on camera, Ashley was not blindsided but was aware of the situation. Ashley said she and Tyler were still together and would continue their marriage. &#8220;This is a once-in-a-lifetime kind of love, and it&#8217;s worth risking anything,&#8221; she said. &#8220;It&#8217;s worth it all.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the engine of the show is mess. Sure, there were two happy endings, but there were seven couples to begin with. That means five relationships went up in flames. That’s very good for Netflix! Here’s how they all ended:</p>

<ul>
<li>Stephen texted a random internet woman behind Monica’s back and tried to excuse it as being drunk at a sleep study</li>



<li>Ramses told Marissa he didn’t vibe with her energy after living with her for a couple of weeks</li>



<li>Hannah finally cut it off with Nick after berating him for weeks about being a child </li>



<li>Tim told Alex she was disrespectful to his parents because she was sleepy, even after he promised her dad, who has MS, that he would take care of his daughter</li>



<li>Brittany and Leo never even made it to Mexico!&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These love implosions are far more watchable than the happy endings, and they keep viewers interested in the show. Maybe they’re tuning in to see Hannah reckon with the person she was during the season or to figure out what really happened between Brittany and Leo, but everyone wants to know the gritty details of why things didn’t work out and what really happens to the show’s losers. And of course, that’s why Netflix has a reunion special (and has its participants <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@/video/7341121404177255723?_r=1&amp;_d=secCgYIASAHKAESPgo8JwJxy53D6YvZv5w%2FY3qnJ%2BxrfBI5jPF1eBBEMeP2hRHCA%2F%2BadLOOdWtxwkrBQhOR95qQf%2BmJnjCFUrpKGgA%3D&amp;u_code=dbffejkjeg2367&amp;share_item_id=7341121404177255723&amp;timestamp=1710108685&amp;utm_campaign=client_share&amp;utm_source=short_fallback&amp;share_app_id=1233">signed to contracts</a>).&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winners: Immature men</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear: Reality TV shows are heavily edited. There have been a few seasons of the show in which men (see: <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23464762/love-is-blind-cole-zanab-season-3">season five Cole</a>) are portrayed as innocent but good-hearted idiots and women as harsh shrews. Further, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/380186/toxic-men-love-is-blind-the-bachelorette">one of the long-running criticisms</a><em> </em>of <em>Love Is Blind </em>and other dating shows is that producers and editors are harsher on women than they are on men. Season seven, in all its turbulent glory, followed that pattern.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nick, Tim, and Stephen all were too immature to be in relationships. Whether it was the inability to talk about a problem, not telling your partner about <a href="https://www.today.com/popculture/tv/love-is-blind-season-7-tyler-francis-kids-rcna174614">the children you fathered</a>, or sending lewd texts to a random woman from the internet, the men this season were not a prize bunch. The bar for <em>Love Is Blind</em> men is subterranean<em>,</em> yet they managed to scoot under it.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E8_00_02_43_01R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A man and a woman hold up glass ornamentation made from pressed flowers." title="A man and a woman hold up glass ornamentation made from pressed flowers." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Stephen and Monica. Monica nagged Stephen for talking too much and not buying her flowers. Stephen responded by texting “kinky” things to a random woman and lying about being drunk at a sleep study. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there was also a lot of focus on how the women in their lives were extremely scoldy, if not bullies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hannah seemed to delight in being mean to Nick instead of dumping him. Alex, Tim’s partner, got into an off-camera fight with him in which she allegedly covered his mouth with her hand. Monica, Stephen’s partner, got mad at him for talking too much and brought up not buying her flowers (multiple times) that he had promised in the pod.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While only the two people in these relationships know the entire truth about the ups and downs of their courtship, it seemed as though the show spent more time portraying the women being harsher and more severe than the immature men they were with. A lot of that has to do with how easy it is to capture the women’s active confrontations and complaints on camera versus the passive, less-visible behavior from men — like being inattentive or lacking initiative. The takeaway is that it felt as though being an unserious goof was better than being an overly serious scold, with some of the men coming away from the show looking less culpable. Not Stephen or Tyler, though; those guys were still at fault.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: Hannah</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every season of <em>Love Is Blind </em>has a villain, and this series that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LoveIsBlindNetflix/comments/1g7ixet/hannahs_comment_section_is_brutal/">title belongs to Hannah</a>. The 26-year-old quit her “dream” job as a medical device sales associate to be on the show, and it was worth it because she gave us a show. After rolling through the pods — where she strategically gave hints about how good-looking she was (e.g., telling men she was a cheerleader who dates athletes, that she didn’t want to be seen just as someone who was “hot,” etc.) — she paired up with Nick, a real estate agent and ex-football player. To be fair, he also embellished about his appearance (Nick claimed to look like a “less buff” Henry Cavill).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Calling this coupling a disaster is an understatement and unfair to disasters. So why is Hannah the bad guy?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, Nick is an adult baby and shouldn’t be in a relationship. And at the reunion, a few cast members intimated that he told them off-camera he wasn’t attracted to Hannah — a crucial tidbit that may have changed the way he was portrayed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, watching Hannah scold him about everything, from 401(k)s to boiling water to phone bills, from ordering him to walk a dog that doesn’t belong to him to telling him that riding hotel pool furniture would give her the ick, was painful. After being icked one evening, Hannah leaves a cryptic, bulleted note of eight or so mantras for Nick to find, with each bullet representing one thing she hates about him. At one point, she tells him that she won’t address him as an equal because she doesn’t see him as an equal.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E4_00_52_33_19R_c3d471.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A smiling blonde woman." title="A smiling blonde woman." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="While the show tends to portray women as harsher partners than the men, Hannah seemed intent on bullying Nick at every opportunity. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">What Hannah was doing wasn’t like the one or two aforementioned instances in which some of the show’s women called out their partners for dropping the ball. It seemed like every segment that focused on the two featured Hannah haranguing Nick. Again, this could all be part of an edit, but Hannah sure gave them a lot of material.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The longer this season went on, the more I wondered why Hannah — who kept talking about how unhappy she was and reminding her partner that he was inadequate — didn’t call the whole thing off sooner.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The thing is, Nick has the opportunity to learn how to boil water and contribute 15 percent to his retirement. And it seems like he’d be able to learn that faster than Hannah could unlearn some of the unpleasant behavior she showed on TV.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: Brittany, the trophy wife</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On a show full of deceit (see: Tyler), it’s nice to know there are participants like Brittany who state, plainly and honestly, that they’re there for all the wrong reasons. When we first meet Brittany, we find out that she wants to be a trophy wife and that she has only dated high-profile, very successful wealthy men. Brittany does not care about finding love or meeting her soulmate. Brittany wants a man who will take care of her and let her live a life of leisure, shopping, and unlimited group fitness classes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Luckily for Brittany, she made a connection with Leo. Leo’s main storyline was that he felt insecure about inheriting tons and tons of money from his family’s art dealing business. In Brittany, he found someone who would listen to these concerns. He was so happy that someone would finally be supportive of the hardships in his life!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Granted, Brittany was probably trying to figure out just how rich Leo was, but she was very invested in each conversation. Even though the two eventually picked each other for marriage, producers said cameras would no longer be following the couple — a true loss for the show and viewers at home.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winners: That one argument Ramses and Marissa had over politics</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there was one moment of the show that felt genuine and important, it was the <a href="https://time.com/7071826/love-is-blind-season-7-marissa-ramses-military/">fight Marissa and Ramses had</a> over her military service. The gist: Ramses vocally condemned the actions of the American military, specifically in destabilizing less-powerful countries and inflicting violence on people living in said countries. Marissa served in the Navy and is proud of her service, even though she said there were moments that she regretted “pushing a button” (e.g., performing military acts that caused harm to civilians). He said he wouldn’t want his child to enlist, and she disagreed. She said she felt like he was judgmental of her military tenure, he said he empathized with her because she voiced her concerns about her participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Marissa and Ramses eventually moved forward with their relationship, the conflict seemed to simmer beneath the surface of all of their problems. Ramses, who said he didn’t vibe with Marissa’s energy after living with her for a couple of weeks, called off the relationship before the wedding.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E12_00_06_33_01R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A man sits with his hand to his chin, speaking to a woman we see in profile." title="A man sits with his hand to his chin, speaking to a woman we see in profile." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Ramses did not like Marissa’s military service — a very real deal-breaker for many real-life couples. But Ramses also was very unserious when it came to other parts of their relationship. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Though they didn’t end up together, Marissa and Ramses thoughtfully articulated the politics of a serious and complicated topic.&nbsp;Their disagreement is the type of stuff <em>Love Is Blind </em>says it wants to be about — being able to fall in love or not with a person based on who they are, what they believe in, and shared values. And sometimes, just like in real life, there are some deal-breakers that you just can’t get past, no matter how much you love a person.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 10 am ET: </strong>This article, originally published on October 30, has been updated with revelations from the </em>Love Is Blind<em> reunion.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Anna North</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Halloween less scary than it used to be?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/life/380705/halloween-scary-stories-kids-spooky" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=380705</id>
			<updated>2024-10-30T17:27:51-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T07:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Family" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story originally appeared in&#160;Kids Today, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&#160;Sign up here for future editions. I remember the first time I encountered Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark. It was second grade, and another kid had smuggled a copy of the Alvin Schwartz horror collection out to the playground during recess. We [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A person in a sheet, carrying a book, walking down a dark street lit with Halloween decorations." data-caption="A child wearing a costume goes trick or treating. | Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1438023413_badcfe.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A child wearing a costume goes trick or treating. | Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/family/369020/kids-children-generation-alpha-gen-school" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kids Today</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/kids-today-newsletter-policy-childhood-policy-culture" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I remember the first time I encountered <em>Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark</em>. It was second grade, and another kid had smuggled a copy of the Alvin Schwartz horror collection out to the playground during recess. We gathered around, repulsed yet compelled by the ghoulish illustrations, unaware that what we read next would form the script of our nightmares for the next 30 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Scary Stories</em>, first released in 1981 but still ubiquitous at sleepovers and back-of-the-bus scare sessions throughout the ’90s, is famous among millennials for inducing utter terror.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The one that haunts me to this day is “<a href="https://scary-stories.fandom.com/wiki/The_Dead_Hand">The Dead Hand</a>,” about a devil-may-care young lad who goes walking in a swamp at night, only to be attacked by a disembodied arm that yanks the boy’s own hand off, leaving nothing but a bloody stump. The story, with its <a href="https://scary-stories.fandom.com/wiki/The_Dead_Hand?file=The_dead_hand.jpg">accompanying illustration</a> of a howling, gap-toothed corpse head rising from a bog, kept me awake for at least a week. I still remember huddling in my bed with eyes peeled, absolutely certain that an oozing hand was about to float through my bedroom door.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Halloween approached this year, I started wondering if <em>Scary Stories</em> was still popular, or if my children would have their own equivalent — a horror tale so powerful it could leave a mark on a generation’s subconscious. So I reached out to booksellers, librarians, and my older kid’s favorite horror author to find out what’s scaring kids these days and what role, if any, spooky stories play in their lives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I thought the children of Gen Alpha, obsessed with the frenetic doomsday fantasy <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/369953/skibidi-tweens-gen-alpha-brainrot-ipad-kids">Skibidi Toilet</a>, might be too jaded to be scared. In fact, experts told me the opposite — that popular titles today, like <a href="https://www.bookfair.org/series/s-michael-dahls-really-scary-stories/"><em>Michael Dahl’s Really Scary Stories</em></a> or the <a href="https://freddy-fazbears-pizza.fandom.com/wiki/Five_Nights_at_Freddy%27s_(Novel_Trilogy)"><em>Five Nights at Freddy’s</em> series</a> — are a little tamer than the ones I read as a kid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We had serious, gripping fear that kept you up at night,” Jean Darnell, the director of library science for the Philadelphia School District and a lifelong horror reader, told me. “The psychological fear was a little bit more in-depth.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s something to be said for a lighter touch in children’s horror. As much as I now consider <em>Scary Stories</em> part of my education as a writer and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/31/opinion/a-ghost-story-for-the-golden-state.html">horror fan</a>, I don’t actually want my kids to lie awake night after night, terrified of being attacked by a disembodied limb.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the differences between my kids’ horror landscape and my own have me thinking about what kids really get out of scary stories, and the value of such tales in a legitimately scary world.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The taming of scary stories&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I didn’t know it at the time, but I came of age during a <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">children’s horror boom</a>. <em>Scary Stories</em>, which eventually grew to&nbsp;three volumes, kicked off the trend, with authors Christopher Pike and R.L. Stine soon following suit, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">according to Mental Floss</a>. The latter wrote the iconic Goosebumps series, which, with its accompanying mid-’90s TV series, still looms large in the imagination of many millennials.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While some were silly or <a href="https://goosebumps.fandom.com/wiki/The_Horror_at_Camp_Jellyjam">bizarre</a>, many were legitimately terrifying. The one that sticks in my mind is <a href="https://goosebumps.fandom.com/wiki/Welcome_to_Camp_Nightmare"><em>Welcome to Camp Nightmare</em></a>, in which a boy arrives at sleepaway camp only to be menaced and gaslit by weird counselors and ultimately pressured to hunt his fellow campers with a tranquilizer gun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though wildly popular, the Goosebumps books became a victim of their own success, with a <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">saturated market and declining sales</a>. By the 2000s, horror had taken a back seat to fantasy, most notably the Harry Potter series.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But like a zombie, the genre has risen from the grave in recent years, even as <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/childrens/childrens-book-news/article/93142-buzzy-middle-grade-genres-fall-2023.html">book sales for elementary- and middle-schoolers struggle</a> overall. Anna Hersh, co-owner of Wild Rumpus Bookstore, a children’s bookshop in Minneapolis, told me that horror books are selling well, enough to keep the store’s dedicated “Spooky Shed” stocked year-round.&nbsp;Popular titles include <a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/tales-from-cabin-23-the-boo-hag-flex-justina-ireland?variant=41096253177890"><em>Tales From Cabin 23</em></a>, an anthology series with each installment written by a different bestselling author, and <a href="https://mattmcmann.com/all-books/"><em>Monsterious</em></a><em>, </em>whose monster-of-the-week vibe makes it the most obvious contemporary successor to Goosebumps, Hersh said. These are aimed at 8- to 12-year-olds, but younger readers enjoy the <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/series/Creepy-Tales!">Creepy Tales picture books</a>, about everyday objects and foodstuffs (underwear, carrots) that come alive and stalk Jasper, an unsuspecting rabbit.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also popular, according to Hersh, is <a href="https://www.flaviazdrago.com/gustavo-the-shy-ghost"><em>Gustavo the Shy Ghost</em></a>, a 2020 bestseller (and a favorite in my house) about a sweet ghost who struggles to connect with his fellow paranormal beings. <em>Gustavo</em> and <a href="https://www.flaviazdrago.com/books">its sequels</a> are more heartwarming than scary, but they take place in a world in which werewolves, calavera-style skeletons, and invisible girls with floating eyeglasses are simply the norm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the classics of my youth, Wild Rumpus still stocks some Goosebumps titles, but they’re mostly <a href="https://kids.scholastic.com/content/kids64/en/books/goosebumps/series/goosebumps-graphix.html">graphic novel adaptations</a> released in the 2010s. Some of the original Goosebumps plots feel dated today —&nbsp;Gen Alpha readers might wonder why some of the terrified protagonists didn’t just “use their cellphone and call their mom,” Hersh said. Today’s spooky stories are more likely to include heroes doing online research into the monsters and ghouls plaguing them, or they take place in fantasy worlds where such technology doesn’t exist, Hersh said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scary stories are also just less scary than they were in the ’80s and ’90s, said Darnell, the library science director, who added that the horror simply “feels watered down.” Grown-ups are more concerned about age-appropriate subject matter than they once were, and school organizations and psychologists would be up in arms if kids’ authors today delved too deep into psychological horror, Darnell said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Young readers today are also “sort of more conservative in many ways” than kids in decades past, said Max Brallier, author (under the pen name Jack Chabert) of the <a href="https://www.scholastic.com/site/branches/eerie-elementary.html">Eerie Elementary books</a> and several other spooky series. While ’90s kids were drawn in by the frightening <em>Scary Stories</em> covers, today’s young people might be more put off. In fact, a 2011 re-release of the books featured <a href="https://darkartandcraft.com/blogs/news/stephen-gammell-illustrations">much less disturbing art</a> (although fan backlash eventually led to a restoration of the original images).</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What spooky tales do for kids</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s nothing wrong with a little concern over children’s mental health and ability to sleep at night. After all, there’s always been a fine line between a fun scare and a traumatic memory. After Brallier saw <em>Jaws</em> as a child, he recalls, “The ocean and the lake and the swimming pool were ruined for me for, like, 15 years.” And as an author, he said, “You don&#8217;t want to really screw someone up.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some adult efforts to scare children do just feel sadistic in retrospect. I had a neighbor growing up who used to answer the door on Halloween wearing a very scary werewolf mask with glowing red eyes. I do not remember this with any fondness, and I think it’s fine that such costumes for adults seem less common during trick-or-treating today.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/brooding-halloween-scary-for-kids.html">Kathryn Jezer-Morton of the Cut</a> recalls a complex parental stunt from her youth, complete with a cemetery, a chainsaw, and a disembodied voice coming from beneath fallen leaves. “It was an <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/haunted-bars-nyc-fraunces-tavern-financial-district-ghosts.html">ecstatic moment of terror</a> alongside the delicious relief of safety,” Jezer-Morton writes, and she worries that kids today are missing “the feeling of a thinning veil between worlds that is hard to describe in words but vividly conjured in memories.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Darnell, meanwhile, scary stories are about learning to live in this world, with all its horrors. “When I&#8217;m reading a scary story, I&#8217;m looking at how that main character strategizes,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fear “forces you to problem-solve with the resources around you,” Darnell said. “I think that&#8217;s a skill that kids need.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t want my kids to be psychologically scarred by the books they read — after all, the realities of a <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/375996/extreme-heat-october-climate-change">warming planet</a> and widespread <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/15/23990986/trump-2024-democracy-consolidated-culture-campaign">democratic backsliding</a> are scary enough. What I want them to get from scary stories is a sense of a universe charged with mystery, the unknown always sneaking up behind us, its cold breath raising goosebumps on the backs of our necks.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or maybe that’s just what I got from scary stories. Today’s young readers will have their own relationships to horror and their own ways of seeking out what they want to feel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even in this post-Goosebumps era, Hersh says she still encounters readers who love to be scared. “It&#8217;ll be this kid who comes in who&#8217;s just like, in the cutest little outfit, and so well-mannered, and is like, ‘What is your scariest book?’” she said. “Some people just kind of have it in them.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What I’m reading</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Olympian Allyson Felix is partnering with the nonprofit Chamber of Mothers to <a href="https://19thnews.org/2024/10/child-care-while-you-vote/">cover the cost of child care</a> while parents vote (the program is available in North Carolina, New York, and Los Angeles).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One Las Vegas high school made the decision to <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/education/2024/10/28/teachers-swing-states-young-voters-election/75781988007/">give students the day off</a> on Election Day — and many will be volunteering at the polls.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Do kids need “<a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/boo-baskets-for-kids-trend-for-parents-couples.html">boo baskets?</a>” Probably <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/mom-not-doing-boo-baskets-halloween-2024-10">no</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My older kid and I are reading <em><a href="https://flyingeyebooks.com/book/season-of-the-witch-a-spellbinding-history-of-witches-and-other-magical-folk/">Season of the Witch: A Spellbinding History of Witches and Other Magical Folk</a></em>, a library find. It is not scary, but it does include a lot of cool spells.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From my inbox</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, I asked for your experiences with <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/379082/school-tracking-apps-grades-google-classroom-classdojo">apps that track kids’ grades</a> and assignments in school. “My sons all struggled with keeping track of assignments and turning them in,” one reader wrote. “For us, the ability to see which assignments had 0’s has been the major benefit of the grade-tracking apps. I check their grades daily and can tell them when they need to check their own grades. Then they can figure out how to rectify the omissions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For kids with better <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/articles/executive-function">executive functioning</a> issues, this might be a non-issue,” she wrote. “But my very bright kids would probably have ended up with a lot of failing grades if we weren’t checking the apps!”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Next Tuesday, as you, um, <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/379814/election-anxiety-stress-coping-strategies-control-community" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/even-better/379814/election-anxiety-stress-coping-strategies-control-community">may be aware</a>, is <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">Election Day</a> in the US. Have you ever taken the kids in your life to vote with you? If so, what did they think of the experience? Also, if you’re a young person voting for the first time this year, please write in and tell me how it felt! You can get in touch at anna.north@vox.com.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Should you feel guilty about using AI?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/381158/should-you-feel-guilty-about-using-ai" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381158</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T10:56:45-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T07:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Emerging Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls Apple Intelligence this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users who opt in. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2172386617.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/10/apple-intelligence-is-available-today-on-iphone-ipad-and-mac/">Apple Intelligence</a> this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/121115#:~:text=To%20get%20started%20with%20Apple,though%20wait%20times%20can%20vary.">who opt in</a>. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple months now, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/370836/apple-intelligence-iphone-16-ios-update-siri">they’re pretty mediocre</a>. But this is only the beginning.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Generative AI, once a parlor trick for the tech-obsessed, is fast becoming the main event for major software releases. As Apple pushes its version of the technology, Google <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/google-ai-android-update-io-2024/">is building AI into its Android operating system</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/357247/why-are-ai-search-engines-so-bad">forcing everyone to look at AI Overviews</a> at the top of virtually every Google Search. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24205701/openai-searchgpt-ai-search-engine-google-perplexity-rival">OpenAI</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/28/24282017/meta-ai-powered-search-engine-report">Meta</a> are building their own AI-powered search engines, while the startup <a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/">Perplexity</a> already has one. <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/10/21/new-autonomous-agents-scale-your-team-like-never-before/">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/22/anthropic-announces-ai-agents-for-complex-tasks-racing-openai.html">Anthropic</a> recently announced new, super-powerful AI agents that can complete complex tasks much like humans would. (Disclosure: Vox Media is one of several publishers that has signed partnership agreements with OpenAI. Our reporting remains editorially independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While some companies have had generative AI products out in the wild for over a year, the arrival of Apple Intelligence marks an inflection point for the mainstreaming of the technology. Apple Intelligence is only available on the latest Apple devices, but over half the phones in the United States <a href="https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/dont-blame-apple-for-the-us-smartphone-market-blame-the-us-carriers">are iPhones</a>. As people upgrade, millions more can tap into the new technology.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re not already using AI, you probably will be soon — whether you like it or not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re getting AI, especially generative AI, shoved down our throats with little to no transparency, and honestly, the opt-out mechanisms are either nonexistent or complicated,” said Sasha Luccioni, AI researcher and climate lead at Hugging Face, a platform for sharing AI and machine learning tools.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If that fills you with dread, it’s understandable. Maybe you feel bad participating in the race <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/19/23879648/americans-artificial-general-intelligence-ai-policy-poll">to build a superintelligent AI</a> nobody asked for. You may feel complicit for using <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/technology/openai-copyright-law.html">AI models trained on copyrighted material</a> without paying the creators. You probably feel just plain bad about the flood of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/378855/ai-slop-fall-autumn-inspiration-vibes-pinterest">AI slop that’s ruining the internet</a> even if you did not personally create the slop. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the climate consequences of it all. AI, in its many shapes and forms, requires a lot of <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/28/24111721/climate-ai-tech-energy-demand-rising">energy and water to work</a>. A <em>lot</em>. That might make you feel downright guilty about using AI.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI’s big energy appetite</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a chance Apple Intelligence is more guilt-free than the other big AI options as far as energy is concerned. Apple says it keeps the processing for certain AI features, like GenMoji and Image Playground, entirely on your device. That means less reliance on energy-intensive data centers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t know exactly how much energy AI uses at these data centers. Using data from a recent Microsoft Research study, Shaolei Ren, an engineering professor at the University of California Riverside, came up with this: Asking ChatGPT to write two 200-word emails uses roughly the same amount of energy as a Tesla Model 3 would need to drive one mile. Because they generate so much heat, the processors that generated those emails would also require <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/18/energy-ai-use-electricity-water-data-centers/">about four half-liter bottles of water</a> to cool down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The consequences of such energy profligacy become clearer if you scale up. The amount of electricity used by data centers, where AI processing largely takes place, is <a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/AI-poised-to-drive-160-increase-in-power-demand">predicted to grow by 160 percent</a> by the end of the decade, and carbon dioxide emissions could more than double as a result, according to Goldman Sachs. Meanwhile, the amount of water needed will also spike, so much so that by 2027, AI’s thirst <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03271">could be equal to half the annual water withdrawal of the United Kingdom</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are all estimates based on limited data because the tech companies building AI systems, including Apple, Google, Microsoft, and OpenAI, do not share exactly how much energy or water their models use.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re just looking at the black box because we have absolutely no idea of the energy consumption for interacting with the large language models,” Ren said. He compared the situation to searching for flights on Google and being able <a href="https://support.google.com/travel/answer/9671620?hl=en">to see the carbon emissions for each leg</a>. “But when it comes to these large language models, there&#8217;s absolutely none, zero, no information.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lack of transparency about AI’s energy demands also runs counter to these tech companies’ sustainability promises. There’s good reason to believe that AI is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">leading directly to those promises being broken</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to increases in data center energy usage, Google saw its greenhouse gas emissions <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-02/google-s-emissions-shot-up-48-over-five-years-due-to-ai?sref=qYiz2hd0">increase by 48 percent</a> from 2019 to 2023, despite a pledge to cut emissions by 50 percent from its 2019 levels <a href="https://sustainability.google/operating-sustainably/net-zero-carbon/">by 2030</a>. The company <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-08/google-is-no-longer-claiming-to-be-carbon-neutral?sref=qYiz2hd0">no longer claims to be carbon neutral</a>. Microsoft similarly <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">saw a 29 percent jump in emissions</a> from 2020 to 2023. While Microsoft has promised to be carbon negative by 2030, it <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/microsoft-wrestles-with-rising-emissions-from-ai-ahead-of-its-2030-net-zero-goal-b53d4cf4">is now openly struggling</a> with ways to make that happen while keeping pace with AI innovation.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the AI dealers aren’t telling us</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is what an arms race looks like. It’s worth pointing out here that all energy usages started to spike around the time that OpenAI knocked the world’s socks off with its <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/05/technology/chatgpt-ai-twitter.html">surprise release of ChatGPT</a> in November 2022. The chatbot <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/6/23948386/chatgpt-active-user-count-openai-developer-conference">became the fastest-growing app ever</a>, capturing 100 million users <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-sets-record-fastest-growing-user-base-analyst-note-2023-02-01/">in two months</a> and kick-starting the AI gold rush in Silicon Valley. Now, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/16/generative-ai-startups-get-40percent-of-all-vc-investment-in-cloud-accel.html#:~:text=Generative%20artificial%20intelligence%20startups%20are,the%20startup%20at%20$157%20billion.">40 percent of all venture capital money</a> in cloud computing goes to generative AI companies. OpenAI itself announced a $6.6 billion funding round in early October — the <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/openai-raises-record--6-6-billion-investors-back-its-ai-dominance">largest venture capital round of all time</a> — giving it a $157 billion valuation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With such staggering amounts of money at play, it’s perhaps no surprise that energy efficiency takes a back seat to growth and innovation. Companies like OpenAI want the models that power their AI technology to get bigger so they can get better and outperform competitors. And the bigger the model, the greater the energy demand — at least for now. Over time, it’s likely that performance will get more efficient thanks to advances in chip technology, data center cooling, and engineering.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Because the innovation happened so quickly around when ChatGPT burst onto the scene, you would expect, initially, for the efficiency to be at its lowest point,” Josh Parker, head of sustainability at chipmaker Nvidia, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the most energy-intensive products are now what companies like OpenAI, Google, and Meta are pushing the hardest. Those include real-time chatbots, voice assistants, and search engines. These features <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24066646/ai-electricity-energy-watts-generative-consumption">enlist larger models and require more advanced chips</a> to work at the same time to reduce latency, or lag. Put simply, they have to do a lot of hard math problems all at once and very quickly. That’s why it takes as much electricity as it does to run a Tesla.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple, however, seems to present itself as an exception. As part of its promise to protect user privacy, the company says it handles as many Apple Intelligence tasks as it can on your device without sending queries to data centers. That means when you opt in to Apple Intelligence, you download a small generative AI model that can handle pretty simple tasks on your phone. Your iPhone battery, unlike a grid-connected cloud data center, has a limited amount of power, which forces Apple Intelligence to handle these tasks with some efficiency. Maybe on-device AI is the guilt-free version of the future after all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem, of course, is that we don’t know exactly how Apple Intelligence works. We don’t know which tasks are handled on the device, which are sent to energy-hungry Apple servers, or how much energy it all requires. I asked Apple about this, but the company did not provide specifics. Then again, not providing specifics is a bit of a theme when it comes to big tech companies explaining their AI offerings.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So again, if you’re feeling dread or guilt about AI in your life, that’s understandable. It is clear that this technology, in its current state, consumes vast and increasing amounts of energy, contributing to greenhouse gas emissions and worsening human-caused climate change. It is also true that you might not have a choice, as big tech companies make generative AI more foundational to their products. You can opt out of Apple Intelligence or never opt in. But you’ll find it’s more difficult, if not impossible, to opt out of AI products from Google, Meta, and Microsoft. (If you want to try, here’s <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/05/31/opt-out-ai-training-meta-chatgpt/">a helpful guide</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a reason to feel guilty,” Luccioni said. “But I do think there&#8217;s a reason — as with climate change in general — to ask for more information, to ask for accountability on behalf of the companies that are selling us this stuff.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If AI is supposed to solve all our problems or destroy us all <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/2024/3/3/24083523/artificial-intelligence-ai-doomsday-panic-extinction-climate-change-utopia-tech-bros-silicon-valley">or both</a>, it would be nice to know the details. We could ask ChatGPT, but that might be a huge waste of energy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Inside Trump’s ominous plan to turn civil rights law against vulnerable Americans]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381094/trump-second-term-2024-election-justice-department-civil-rights" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381094</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T10:43:02-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2016, Christy Lopez was living her dream. She was an attorney at the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division working on policing where, among other things, she led the team that investigated the Ferguson Police Department in Missouri after the 2014 killing of Michael Brown. Lopez believes that her work spurred meaningful policing reforms, both [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Illustration of the presidential seal covered in red, with superimposed architectural columns falling on it." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/DOJ_Vox_10-30.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2016, <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/christy-e-lopez/">Christy Lopez</a> was living her dream. She was an attorney at the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division working on policing where, among other things, she led the team that investigated the Ferguson Police Department in Missouri after the 2014 killing of Michael Brown. Lopez believes that her work spurred meaningful policing reforms, both in Ferguson and nationwide.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when Donald Trump won the 2016 election, Lopez quit. Trump, she thought, would block her team from doing any worthwhile investigation into police use of force. Lopez was right. In Trump’s first year in office, Attorney General Jeff Sessions <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/trump-administration-rolls-back-civil-rights-efforts-federal-government">sharply restricted the use of consent decrees</a> — the legal tool Lopez and her colleagues used to force change in Ferguson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, she is sounding the alarm: Whatever the dangers of a first Trump term were, the risks of a second dwarf them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If Trump is elected, I would like to look back five years from now and say, ‘Oh, we were really alarmist,’” Lopez, now a Georgetown University law professor, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“But I do worry that it’s actually going to be far worse.”</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many, many people have warned that Trump is a threat to American democracy. Many others have argued that these warnings are politically inert, that focusing on abstract concepts like “democracy” and “the rule of law” removes political debate from the concrete concerns people want addressed by government. Do people struggling to pay the bills have time to care about such matters of principle?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet in reality, the two things are inseparable. Trump’s plan to turn the government into a tool of his own personal will would have extraordinary consequences for Americans’ everyday lives. It would disrupt, or potentially even devastate, core functions of government that we’ve long taken for granted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division is a case in point.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Founded by the 1957 Civil Rights Act, the Division is tasked with enforcing federal law regarding anti-discrimination and civil equality. This is a mammoth responsibility, covering areas of law that shape the fundamental experience of American democracy. Its attorneys launch hate crimes prosecutions, investigate discrimination in employment and housing, and sue states when their voting rules run afoul of the 1965 Voting Rights Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump returns to power, the department could easily be turned from a tool for protecting civil rights into a means of undoing them. Trump and his allies have laid out fairly specific plans for doing just that — plans that, if enacted, would mean a far more radical and methodical transformation of the federal rights civil apparatus than what we saw in Trump’s shambolic first term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The department’s Voting Section&nbsp;— which played a critical role in defending the integrity of the 2020 election —&nbsp;would be twisted,&nbsp;its attorneys replaced with cronies working to validate Trump’s lies and shield Republican-controlled states from federal scrutiny. Its anti-discrimination litigators would be tasked with investigating “anti-white” discrimination, effectively turning the Civil Rights Act on the minority citizens it was written to defend. And Lopez’s former colleagues working on policing would not only let abusive cops skate, but potentially even investigate local law enforcement Trump believed weren’t aggressive enough toward alleged criminals.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can see here that a second Trump administration would likely mean the inversion of the traditional purpose of federal civil rights law. Its guardrails against authoritarianism, discrimination, and abuse of power will be twisted toward advancing them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it’s just one of many ways in which Trump’s pursuit of power at any cost would have tangible and direct consequences for ordinary Americans’ lives.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Trump’s plan to invert the Civil Rights Division, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has vowed to use a second term to enact “retribution” against his enemies.  The Justice Department, and specifically the current Civil Rights Division staff, are at the top of the list. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of Trump’s first term, he issued an executive order creating a new classification for civil service jobs — called Schedule F — that would have allowed him <a href="https://protectdemocracy.org/work/trumps-schedule-f-plan-explained/">to fire as many as 50,000 civil servants</a> and replace them with handpicked allies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Trump left office before his team could implement Schedule F, he has promised to reissue the order “<a href="https://www.donaldjtrump.com/agenda47/agenda47-president-trumps-plan-to-dismantle-the-deep-state-and-return-power-to-the-american-people">immediately</a>” upon returning to office. In anticipation, his allies have compiled <a href="https://www.govexec.com/management/2024/09/trumps-second-term-agenda-breaking-bureaucracy/399533/">long lists</a> of civil servants they’d like to fire and loyalists they’d like to put in their place — preparations that have led one expert on federal administration to conclude that 50,000 firings is now “<a href="https://protectdemocracy.org/work/trumps-schedule-f-plan-explained/">probably a floor rather than a ceiling.</a>”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s allies have focused on the Civil Rights Division as one of their chief targets for Schedule F and other power grabs. <a href="https://static.project2025.org/2025_MandateForLeadership_FULL.pdf">Project 2025</a> — <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/373485/project-2025-abortion-ban-trump-comstock-mifepristone">widely seen</a> as the chief planning document for a Trump second term <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/article/project-2025.html">despite the campaign’s disavowals</a> — has an explicit, detailed plan for taking it over.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The document calls on the next Republican president to “reorganize and refocus” the division, aiming to make it into “the vanguard” of the administration’s crusade against “an unholy alliance of special interests, radicals in government, and the far Left.” It is one of three Department of Justice divisions singled out in the document’s call for “a vast expansion of the number of [political] appointees” overseeing and directing its conduct. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is all part of a broader plan for eroding the Justice Department’s traditional independence. While the attorney general is appointed by the president, their staff is given wide leeway to follow the law rather than the president’s dictates. Political personnel are strictly prohibited from interfering with specific investigations and cases. That’s why the current Justice Department could pursue <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/354842/hunter-biden-guilty-politics-david-weiss">a case against Hunter Biden</a> with no fear of retaliation from his father.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and top deputies have declared their intent to change this.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/AP24214674291537.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Trump stands next to a man behind a podium" title="Trump stands next to a man behind a podium" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Then-President Donald Trump listens as acting director of the Office of Management and Budget Russel Vought speaks during an event on &quot;transparency in Federal guidance and enforcement&quot; in the Roosevelt Room of the White House, October 9, 2019. | Evan Vucci/AP Photo" data-portal-copyright="Evan Vucci/AP Photo" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“The notion of an independent agency — whether that&#8217;s a flat-out independent agency like the FCC or an agency that has parts of it that view itself as independent, like the Department of Justice — we&#8217;re planting a flag and saying we reject that notion completely,” Russ Vought, a key second-term Trump planner, <a href="https://www.npr.org/transcripts/1192432628">said in a 2023 interview</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you put these three proposals together — seeding the Civil Rights Division with Trump political appointees, using Schedule F to replace career prosecutors with ideological allies, and ending department independence — the full picture becomes clear. If Trump has his way, a second term means a Civil Rights Division operating not as a (relatively) neutral division dedicated to enforcing civil rights law, but as a tool of the Trump agenda in all the areas it covers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is very threatening for government employees and obviously offensive to the notion of a neutral civil service. But what would this mean for most Americans in practice? What does it matter, really, if one bureaucrat is swapped out for another?</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Election law politicized</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On November 9, 2020, Attorney General Bill Barr directed the Justice Department to investigate Trump’s allegations of fraud in the just-concluded presidential election. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The probe, announced after the election had been called for Joe Biden, was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/11/09/politics/william-barr-voting-irregularities/index.html">controversial inside the Department</a>. It raised fears that Barr, no stranger to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2020-election/fact-check-echoing-trump-barr-misleads-voter-fraud-attack-expanded-n1240144">conspiracy theories about voter fraud</a>, was trying to validate Trump’s claims of a stolen election.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet the professional probe, staffed by veteran investigators in the Civil Rights Division and elsewhere, found no evidence of mass fraud. On November 23, Barr told Trump the investigation was “<a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/GPO-J6-REPORT/pdf/GPO-J6-REPORT.pdf">not panning out</a>.” The neutral, competent investigation gave the attorney general the ammunition he needed to stand up to the president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now imagine if things were different, if these career investigators had been Schedule F’d out, replaced instead with Trump-aligned attorneys.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What if they had come to Barr and said that, actually, the <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2103619118">bogus statistical arguments</a> that the election was stolen had merit? What would he have done then? How would reports of such findings, however bogus, influence the rest of the country — including Vice President Mike Pence and members of Congress?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s an example that illustrates the importance of the Civil Rights Division. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The American system is unusual, in global terms, by granting most power over election administration to state and local authorities. While this system makes it hard for the federal government to rig elections, it makes it comparatively easy for state-level officials to cheat and discriminate (Jim Crow being the signature example).</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2138366391.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.749025795501,100,76.501948408999" alt="Black and white photo of Black people in a long line outside a small rural building labeled “the sugar shack.”" title="Black and white photo of Black people in a long line outside a small rural building labeled “the sugar shack.”" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Following the passage of the Voting Rights Act of 1965, people line up to vote — many for the first time — at the Sugar Shack store, Peachtree, Alabama, May 3, 1966. | National Archives of Fort Worth/PhotoQuest/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="National Archives of Fort Worth/PhotoQuest/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division’s election work is one of the primary checks on such abuses. It protects the right to vote, enforcing laws like the Voting Rights Act. It also works to protect the sanctity of the results after elections, identifying and investigating allegations of illegal conduct by state and local administrators during the voting process. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Its main area of responsibility is allegations of discrimination, but it also regularly cooperates with other divisions in investigating other kinds of allegations like voting fraud (as happened in November 2020). While the Supreme Court has significantly <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/11/28/23978226/supreme-court-trump-judges-voting-rights-act-arkansas-rose-secretary">weakened the Voting Rights Act</a>, the Civil Rights Division is still able to bring cases that matter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a second Trump term, this work could be turned on its head. Instead of trying to stop abuses at the state and local level, they might at best ignore them — and at worst try to force local officials to engage in them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The chapter of Project 2025 on the Justice Department, authored by former Trump DOJ official Gene Hamilton, sketches out how this would work in detail. It argues that Kathy Boockvar, who was Pennsylvania’s secretary of state in 2020, “should have been (and still should be) investigated and prosecuted” under a post-Civil War law called the Klan Act — designed, as you might guess, to break the first incarnation of the Ku Klux Klan. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Boockvar’s crime, per Hamilton, was issuing a legal interpretation designed to address the unprecedented increase in mail-in ballots during the pandemic. She issued guidance to counties that if a provisional mail-in ballot were “spoiled” — meaning rendered defective through, for example, damage during the shipping process — that voters would have an opportunity to correct them. Hamilton calls this a “conspiracy against rights,” a crime laid out in the Klan Act. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I spoke to <a href="https://newsroom.lmu.edu/expert-profile/levitt-justin/">Justin Levitt</a>, an election law expert and former deputy assistant attorney general in the Civil Rights Division, he told me “it’s difficult to convey how crazy” such a case would be.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Pennsylvania rule is, in his mind, a very reasonable interpretation of a constitutional obligation to avoid disenfranchising people over minor ballot issues. Even if Boockvar’s interpretation were dubious, nothing in the Klan Act suggests that the DOJ would be empowered to prosecute her for it (as the law simply doesn’t cover good-faith mistakes by elected officials trying to count more ballots).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know an awful lot of federal prosecutors [and] I don’t know one who would bring this case,” he tells me.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1229479862.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.794243288056,100,78.411513423888" alt="Protesters in an urban street carry signs that read “Count every vote.“" title="Protesters in an urban street carry signs that read “Count every vote.“" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Demonstrators at a protest in front of the Philadelphia Convention Center during the 2020 presidential election, November 5, 2020. | Jennifer Huxta/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jennifer Huxta/Bloomberg via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Hence why Schedule F is so important. It’s almost certain that no experienced Justice Department prosecutor would bring this case, be they Democrat or Republican, because they would recognize it’s an absurd reading of the law. But if Trump can put the Division under his thumb, inserting cronies in oversight positions and firing a huge swath of the career staff, he can get people like Hamilton in a position to do what they want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://csde.washington.edu/affiliates/jake-grumbach/">Jake Grumbach</a>, a political scientist who studies state-level voting laws, tells me that such politically motivated prosecutions of state officials is “the most dangerous thing” the Justice Department can do. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even the threat of a civil rights investigation can scare state-level administrators into compliance with what the feds want. A weaponized Justice Department would mean these officials would feel significant pressure to twist their election administration systems into whatever contorted shape Trump was calling for at the moment — with potentially devastating consequences for electoral fairness.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Civil wrongs</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While voting rights law is an especially significant area of the Civil Rights Division’s work, it’s far from the only one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division’s raison d’etre, the entire point of it being a separate and distinct component of the federal government, is to enforce the modern consensus that discrimination on the basis of identity is a pervasive and systematic problem that requires significant federal resources to address.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and his closest allies believe something more like the opposite, that federal civil rights law isn’t a solution to the problem of discrimination against minorities but an agent of discrimination against whites, men, and Christians. As such, they aim to flip the entire civil rights code on its head by using the Civil Rights Division as “the vanguard,” in Hamilton’s language.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Anything [in law] can be weaponized,” says Kristy Parker, a former Civil Rights Division attorney who worked on policing. “That’s the problem.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the last Trump administration ended, top Trump aide Stephen Miller has worked with Hamilton at a new law firm — America First Legal — that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/21/us/politics/stephen-miller-america-first-legal.html">focuses on “anti-white” discrimination</a> in employment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">America First filed a suit that successfully blocked a pandemic-era program to distribute financial aid to <a href="https://thehill.com/regulation/554361-federal-judge-says-biden-restaurant-fund-discriminated-against-white-male/">minority- and woman-owned restaurants</a>. It sued the NFL over the Rooney Rule, which requires that teams interview at least one nonwhite candidate for high-level coaching vacancies, and it went after <a href="https://aflegal.org/litigation/fasorp-v-northwestern-university/">Northwestern University</a> for allegedly prioritizing hires of minority and non-male faculty members.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In April, Axios’ Alex Thompson reported that <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/01/trump-reverse-racism-civil-rights">America First was “laying legal groundwork”</a> for a full-court press against “anti-white racism” in the event that Trump retakes control of the Civil Rights Division.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is something that Hamilton explicitly calls for in his Project 2025 chapter. He writes:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Civil Rights Division should spend its first year under the next Administration using the full force of federal prosecutorial resources to investigate and prosecute all state and local governments, institutions of higher education, corporations, and any other private employers who are engaged in discrimination in violation of constitutional and legal requirements.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In reality, what Hamilton calls “discrimination” are actually efforts to address discrimination. There is overwhelming evidence that American society continues to <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/pager/files/annualreview_discrimination.pdf">allocate resources unfairly on the basis of race</a>. Without affirmative steps to rectify this situation, entrenched inequalities like the racial gap will never disappear. What Trump and his team call “anti-white discrimination” are efforts to close gaps between groups, not open them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Trump team aims to invert federal oversight over local prosecutors in a similar fashion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2023, the campaign released a policy video in which <a href="https://www.donaldjtrump.com/agenda47/agenda47-president-trump-announces-plan-to-end-crime-and-restore-law-and-order">Trump vows to task the Civil Rights Division</a> with investigating “progressive prosecutors.” The basic argument is that these prosecutors, who see part of their mission as reducing the effects of mass incarceration on the Black community, are effectively engaging in race-based discrimination in favor of Black offenders.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I will direct the DOJ to open civil rights investigations into radical left prosecutor’s offices, such as those in Chicago, LA, and San Francisco, to determine whether they have illegally engaged in race-based enforcement of the law,” Trump said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much like the attempt to prosecute Boockvar, trying to jail “progressive prosecutors” is not something the department’s professional staff would ordinarily contemplate doing. Even if Trump succeeded in replacing them via Schedule F, it’s hard to imagine any such investigation yielding charges that could stand up in court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact that such investigations would almost certainly fail to yield charges <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/185487/trump-maga-legal-war-slow-burn-authoritarianism">does not make them harmless</a>. Even spurious investigations entail coercive measures — like subpoenas, searches, and audits — that can make it difficult for “progressive prosecutors” to do their jobs. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also a political aspect to the threat, as many of Trump’s proposed targets are in elected posts. Elected officials are generally responsive to threats to their reelection chances, and being a target of a DOJ civil rights probe looks really bad to prospective voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21281041/trump-justice-department-consent-decrees-jeff-sessions-police-violence-abuse">Consent decrees</a>, the mechanism Lopez used to deal with bias in Ferguson, are one of the most powerful tools available to federal prosecutors for addressing bias in policing — and another target in a second Trump term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The process begins with a fact-finding investigation, uncovering evidence of systematic use-of-force problems and/or racial discrimination. The next stage involves lengthy negotiations with police departments that culminate in a tangible and enforceable set of reform benchmarks for the department. If the benchmarks aren’t being met to the Civil Rights Division’s satisfaction, its attorneys can haul cops in front of a judge and demand answers.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/AP119714094153.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.514716612012,100,76.970566775976" alt="The back of a man who holds both hands up while police in riot gear approach him" title="The back of a man who holds both hands up while police in riot gear approach him" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Police wearing riot gear and pointing guns approach a man with his hands raised in Ferguson, Missouri, August 11, 2014. | Jeff Roberson/AP Photo" data-portal-copyright="Jeff Roberson/AP Photo" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The previous Trump administration limited their use going forward, but a second one might roll them back.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Obama administration negotiated a historic number of consent decrees, but these are approaching their negotiated sunset dates. The Biden administration has tried to bargain with departments for extensions, as well as implement new ones, but police departments have been dragging their feet. Lopez believes they are anticipating the possibility of a Trump victory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Almost any jurisdiction that is currently negotiating a consent decree is going to wait to see what happens in November,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If this delaying tactic works and Trump’s Civil Rights Division vacates consent decrees across the board, Lopez warns of aggressive police being unleashed across the country. Trump’s wild rhetoric about policing — his recent statement that cops should be permitted “<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/29/trump-violent-day-policing-crime-00181619">one really violent day</a>” to combat crime — would further encourage abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The attorneys tasked with limiting police abuses would, in a second Trump administration, be responsible for encouraging them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A government “for the people” —&nbsp;for now</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As important as the Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division is, it is far from the totality of government work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Justice Department has eight other litigating departments beyond the Civil Rights Division, where attorneys prosecute everyone from terrorists to tax cheats. It has five separate police agencies, including the FBI and US Marshals Service. It oversees all federal prisons and studies federal criminal convictions to see if any merit presidential pardons. It has nine separate grantmaking authorities, which provide funding for local authorities supporting everything from assisting sex trafficking victims to encouraging innovation in <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/topics/community-violence-intervention/resources">local alternatives to policing</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2172231777.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="A US flag on a pole flies in front of a federal building" title="A US flag on a pole flies in front of a federal building" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A US flag flies in front of the Department of Justice (DOJ) headquarters building on September 15, 2024, in Washington, DC. | J. David Ake/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="J. David Ake/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Department of Justice is one of 15 federal departments, each of which has its own diverse and important set of responsibilities. There are also important agencies separate from the department structure, like the CIA and the Environmental Protection Agency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of them perform critical work that contributes to the standard of living Americans have come to take for granted. This work depends on experienced, dedicated civil servants who know how to do the job, and all of it could be disrupted by Trump’s plans to give their jobs to partisan hacks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every day, the EPA works to monitor and address pollution poisoning our rivers and drinkable water. The Bureau of Labor Statistics churns out job numbers and other reports that the Fed and other places depend on to make good economic policy. US Citizenship and Immigration Services helps keep families together, approving permanent residency and citizenship applications for foreign spouses of American citizens. The Department of Energy manages America’s nuclear weapons and power plants, making sure we don’t experience a Fukushima or Chernobyl-level disaster.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now imagine the people who know how to do this routine stuff are either thrown out of office or put under the thumbs of political commissars. That’s the danger here.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump and his team have laid out their plans in detail, in official statements proposing a revival of Schedule F and semi-official documents like Project 2025. Even if you agree with many of their policy ideas, they need to be implemented competently and lawfully in order to work. Throughout history, in the United States and elsewhere, the imposition of political control on a civil service has been a recipe for incompetence and anti-democratic abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The United States has a democratic government:&nbsp;a deeply flawed one, but one by the people and for the people. Trump’s plan is to make it for him and his alone, and he has a decent chance of succeeding if elected. We often take our <a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/zack-beauchamp/the-reactionary-spirit/9781541704411/">relatively novel form of government</a> for granted; if we lose it, we’ll miss it when it’s gone.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How safe is your vote from manipulation?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378648/election-deniers-vote-count-security-certification-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378648</id>
			<updated>2024-10-30T20:16:43-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-30T20:16:43-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explain It to Me" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vox reader Jason Taylor writes: Should voters be concerned about the possibility of Trump election deniers being in positions of power to count votes in Trump&#8217;s favor that he did not receive in the upcoming election? Thank you for your time and consideration of my question. One of the defining — and troubling — facts [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="People standing at a double line of voting booths." data-caption="Voters make selections at their voting booths inside an early voting site on October 17, 2024, in Hendersonville, North Carolina. | &lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2178247386.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Voters make selections at their voting booths inside an early voting site on October 17, 2024, in Hendersonville, North Carolina. | &lt;p&gt;Melissa Sue Gerrits/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Vox reader Jason Taylor writes</em>: <em>Should voters be concerned about the possibility of Trump election deniers being in positions of power to count votes in Trump&#8217;s favor that he did not receive in the upcoming election? Thank you for your time and consideration of my question.</em></p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the defining — and troubling — facts of our current political era is that the loser of the previous election maintains he didn’t lose it at all. To this day, Donald Trump refuses to admit he lost the 2020 election to Joe Biden, a stance that many of his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372863/2024-election-lies-trump-overturn-harris">followers have gotten in line behind</a>, including some who’ll <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/25137148-swing-state-election-deniers-center-for-media-and-democracy-91324">hold positions of power</a> in this November’s contest.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has understandably spurred concerns like the ones you’ve raised about the current cycle.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up">Explain It to Me newsletter</a></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The newsletter is part of Vox’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me">Explain It to Me</a>. Each week, we tackle a question from our audience and deliver a digestible explainer from one of our journalists. Have a question you want us to answer? Ask us <a href="http://www.vox.com/ask-vox">here</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite these troubling developments, however, election law experts say that voters should know ample protections are in place to bar election deniers from messing with the vote count or its eventual certification.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There are multiple safeguards built into the process to prevent that kind of thing from happening,” says Gowri Ramachandran, the director of elections and security at the Brennan Center for Justice, a nonpartisan think tank dedicated to voting rights.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What safeguards are in place for ballot counting?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s start with the process of counting ballots. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The count involves so many steps, so many layers of double-checking and supervision, that it would be virtually impossible to fake even a single ballot,” <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2020/11/05/vote-count-michigan-no-fraud/?_pml=1">Evelyn Smith, an election worker in Michigan</a>, told the Washington Post in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These safeguards include the presence of <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers#table">independent observers</a> at ballot counts, post-election audits to verify the results, and <a href="https://www.eac.gov/sites/default/files/electionofficials/security/Voting_System_Security_Measures_508_EAC.pdf">rigorous record-keeping</a> to keep tabs on voter participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This all starts with the submission of ballots. When people vote in person, poll workers <a href="https://www.eac.gov/sites/default/files/electionofficials/security/Voting_System_Security_Measures_508_EAC.pdf">keep a clear tally of how many people</a> have voted, which is later checked against the number of ballots coming from each precinct. Similarly, when people vote by mail, election workers confirm that each <a href="https://apnews.com/article/2022-midterm-elections-voting-voter-registration-government-and-politics-609866267baef89dd1513e7c9e2f7509">ballot corresponds to a real person</a> and keep track of <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/report/mail-voting-is-safe-secure/">how many ballots are coming in</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In most cases, the ballots are counted by machines, and those have to undergo their own rigorous <a href="https://www.votebeat.org/arizona/2022/7/18/23268819/logic-accuracy-tests-county-elections-equipment-yuma-voting/">“logic and accuracy” tests</a> by election officials before they can ever be used.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots cast in person are often tabulated on location at the precinct, and that information is <a href="https://campaignlegal.org/update/what-happens-my-ballot-after-i-vote?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwo8S3BhDeARIsAFRmkOMI1xfUcumUJLCHfZuPnu2bEIFWQV3IsYI7du_0a04Qvi_er2oDsyQaAgrjEALw_wcB">printed out on a physical receipt</a> and stored on a memory card. Typically, these results are recorded at the precinct, and both the receipt and memory card are also transmitted in a secure box to a central location.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mail-in ballots are also tabulated at either a polling station or central location after being verified. In rare instances — <a href="https://verifiedvoting.org/election-system/hand-counted-paper-ballots/" data-type="link" data-id="https://verifiedvoting.org/election-system/hand-counted-paper-ballots/">usually in much smaller counties and towns</a> — ballots are counted by hand, a practice that’s increasingly less <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/pittsburgh/news/hand-counting-ballots-explained/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.cbsnews.com/pittsburgh/news/hand-counting-ballots-explained/">common because it’s prone to errors and delays</a>. When hand counting is used, it’s usually done in teams to reduce mistakes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of whether ballots are counted by machine or by hand, independent observers, or members of both parties, are able to watch as votes are submitted and tallied, adding another layer of security.&nbsp;(These policies <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.ncsl.org/elections-and-campaigns/policies-for-election-observers#table">vary by state</a> but most places allow some transparency into different steps of the process.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such protocols make it difficult for potential bad actors to manipulate the count.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many states have post-election audits as well to catch if something is amiss with the vote tally. In these audits, state or county officials will hand count a sample of the ballots in each precinct to spot-check for discrepancies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Audits would find out if bogus votes were added to the real vote totals,” says Ciara Torres-Spelliscy, a Stetson University law professor and elections expert.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Candidates, as well as the two parties, are also able to lodge a complaint or mount a legal challenge if they believe there have been any irregularities.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What about election certification?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent elections, certification of the results has been another point in the process when some officials have caused delays or questioned the outcome.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, certification is a routine part of any election and basically just involves county and state election boards verifying the results after they’ve been tallied. In 2020 and 2022, however, there were examples of officials and federal lawmakers refusing to do so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, the Wayne County, Michigan, Board of Canvassers <a href="https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/politics/2020/11/17/wayne-county-canvassers-deadlock-certifying-november-3-election-results/6324274002/">initially deadlocked</a> 2–2 when two Republican commissioners refused to declare Biden the winner. Following significant backlash, they eventually changed their votes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Shortly after that, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/1/6/22218058/republicans-objections-election-results">147 federal Republican lawmakers infamously voted to challenge</a> the election results during Congress’s certification process on January 6, 2021. Despite their objections, the certification was completed, and since then, Congress has passed updates to the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/21/23520649/electoral-count-reform-act-omnibus-trump">Electoral Count Act </a>to make the threshold for challenging the results much higher.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, the Republican-led election commission in <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/06/15/gop-commission-refuses-to-certify-new-mexico-primary-vote-00039771">Otero County, New Mexico</a>, also refused to certify primary results due to their alleged distrust in Dominion voting machines. The New Mexico secretary of state ultimately obtained a state Supreme Court order requiring the commission to certify, and they later did.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In past instances, local officials either relented or were ordered by a court or state officials to move forward with the certification of the results. Experts note that the same is likely to occur this time around if there are more attempts to delay or deny certification.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If state-level officials like the secretary of state tried to block a legitimate outcome from moving forward, the candidates and parties could similarly take the issue to court.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts note that they aren’t especially concerned that efforts to stymie certification would be successful, though they do note that bad actors could cause delays and confusion that might fuel misinformation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a potential for there to be uncertainty,” says UCLA election law professor Rick Hasen.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>So, what should we be worried about this election?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The experts I spoke to broadly emphasized that they have faith in the election system.&nbsp;Despite this, Trump could still foment distrust much like he did in 2020 and gin up violence or unrest as a result.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That possibility, and a potential reprisal of the January 6 insurrection, is <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372863/2024-election-lies-trump-overturn-harris">unfortunately its own concern</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When people hear this kind of disinformation over and over and over again, it does lead to real harmful consequences,” Ramachandran told Vox.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this is to say that one of the largest threats this election faces is many voters’ lack of confidence in the legitimacy of the outcome, even if counting and certification all go according to plan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was featured in the Explain It to Me newsletter. Sign up&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em>&nbsp;<em>For more from Explain It to Me,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site"><em>check out the podcast</em></a><em>. New episodes drop every Wednesday.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The big lie behind Biden’s “garbage” gaffe scandal]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381150</id>
			<updated>2024-10-30T18:12:44-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-30T18:15:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden is no longer competent at speaking in public. This makes him a poor surrogate for Kamala Harris’s campaign, but he is also the president, and therefore an extremely prominent surrogate for the Democratic nominee.&#160; This generated a problem for Harris Tuesday night when Biden set out to criticize dehumanizing rhetoric at a recent [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Joe Biden during a meeting with Nikos Christodoulides, Cyprus’s president, not pictured, in the Oval Office of the White House on October 30, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2181247572.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Joe Biden during a meeting with Nikos Christodoulides, Cyprus’s president, not pictured, in the Oval Office of the White House on October 30, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Joe Biden is no longer competent at speaking in public. This makes him a poor surrogate for Kamala Harris’s campaign, but he is also the president, and therefore an extremely prominent surrogate for the Democratic nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This generated a problem for Harris Tuesday night when Biden set out to criticize dehumanizing rhetoric at a recent Trump rally and ended up spouting a garbled stream of words that may or may not have dehumanized all Trump supporters as “garbage.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Conservatives have thus <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/10/30/us-news/republicans-erupt-over-biden-calling-trump-supporters-garbage-its-what-he-and-kamala-harris-genuinely-think-about-you/">expressed their collective horror</a> at the spectacle of a US president disparaging Americans whose only sin was disagreeing with him politically. But even if one stipulates that Republicans’ tendentious reading of Biden is correct, their professed outrage is not merely hypocritical but perniciously misleading.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At worst, the president disparaged conservative voters momentarily, before disavowing that sentiment in his very next breath. During his time in office, meanwhile, Biden has showered federal resources on heavily Republican parts of the country. Trump, by contrast, derides progressives and immigrants as “enemies” and “vermin” without apology, and reportedly sought to block disaster aid to <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">Democratic</a> <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/25/trump-ignored-disaster-aid-request-from-democratic-governor-00185542">strongholds</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is one candidate in the 2024 race who sees wide swaths of the American public as less than human, and it is not Kamala Harris. The furor over Biden’s disjointed remarks serves to obscure this reality.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump dehumanizes his political adversaries without apology or equivocation. Biden does not.&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Sunday, at a rally for Trump at Madison Square Garden, the comedian Tony Hinchcliffe referred to Puerto Rico as a “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/380818/trump-rally-puerto-rico-tony-hinchcliffe-groypers">floating island of garbage</a>.” During a video call with Latino supporters Tuesday night, Biden said of the incident:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">And just the other day, a speaker at [Trump&#8217;s] rally called Puerto Rico a &#8216;floating island of garbage.&#8217; Well, let me tell you something. I don&#8217;t — I — I don&#8217;t know the Puerto Rican that — that I know — or a Puerto Rico, where I&#8217;m fr— in my home state of Delaware, they&#8217;re good, decent, honorable people.<br><br>The only garbage I see floating out there is his supporter&#8217;s — his — his demonization of Latinos is unconscionable, and it&#8217;s un-American. It&#8217;s totally contrary to everything we&#8217;ve done, everything we&#8217;ve been.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is the official White House transcript of the remarks, at least. Republicans argue that what Biden <em>actually</em> said was, “the only garbage I see floating out there is his [i.e., Trump’s] <em>supporters</em>.” In other words, Biden says he was calling Hinchcliffe’s demonization of Puerto Rico garbage, while Republicans say he was calling all Trump supporters trash.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is impossible to distinguish “supporter’s” from “supporters” by ear. So, it cannot be known with certainty what Biden intended in the moment that those words escaped his lips. The surrounding context, however, undercuts the GOP’s interpretation. Immediately after uttering his controversial statement, the president said the following:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Trump has di— tried to divide the country based on race, ethnicity, anything that does harm, to take their eye off the ball about what the terrible things he&#8217;s done and will do. But Kamala Harris has fought for all Americans and will be a president for all of America.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is possible that Biden intended to 1) deride all Trump supporters as “garbage,” and then 2) immediately tout Harris’s commitment to fighting for human trash. But that strikes me as unlikely, particularly since the president has never said anything like that before during his half-century in public life.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whatever Biden intended though, it is indisputable that his very next sentences disavowed the idea that Republican voters are “garbage” whose interests should be ignored. And after his event was over, Biden <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1851436643498037614">insisted</a> that his intention had merely been to describe Hinchcliffe’s rhetoric as “garbage.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, meanwhile, is unequivocal in his belief that Democrats constitute <a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-enemies-from-within-5c4a34776469a55e71d3ba4d4e68cf62">“enemies from within” </a>who must be vanquished.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Fox News last weekend, Howard Kurtz told Trump that “enemies from within” is “a pretty ominous phrase, if you’re talking about other Americans.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think it’s accurate,” Trump replied.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican nominee has also suggested that some of these enemies might need to be <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/13/politics/trump-military-enemy-from-within-election-day/index.html">“handled” by “the military</a>,” likened his political opponents to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/14/23958866/trump-vermin-authoritarian-democracy">“vermin,”</a> and claimed that undocumented immigrants are <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/trump-says-immigrants-are-poisoning-blood-country-biden-campaign-liken-rcna130141">“poisoning the blood of our country.” </a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just last week, Trump described America as <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-trump-calls-the-u-s-a-garbage-can-for-the-world-at-campaign-event-in-austin-texas">“a garbage can for the world,”</a> arguing that other nations deposit their human refuse into the United States through immigration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, Trump’s demonization of immigrants is not confined to those who lack legal status or even citizenship. He has baselessly accused legal US residents <a href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/372206/springfield-ohio-pets-haitian-immigrants-conspiracy">from Haiti of eating people’s pets</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K7i17bZnJeI">vowed to deport them</a>. And he has described American citizens who came to this country through the diversity visa lottery as “<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2018/02/trump-americans-who-came-here-via-lottery-are-horrendous.html">horrendous</a>” and “<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-says-visa-lottery-rewards-the-worst-immigrants-thats-inaccurate/">the worst of the worst</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump did not feel compelled to disavow any of these statements after making them, nor to reassure the country that he wants to fight for every American. To the contrary, he is unabashedly committed to <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/21/nx-s1-5134924/trump-election-2024-kamala-harris-elizabeth-cheney-threat-civil-liberties">directing the power of the federal government</a> against his political opponents and the millions of US residents whose presence in this country he abhors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There isn’t the slightest equivalence between Biden’s rhetorical posture toward Republican voters and Trump’s toward Democrats and immigrants. And a similar gap surfaces when one examines each president’s actual governance.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump doesn’t just compare Americans he dislikes to garbage — he tries to treat them like it</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During his time in office, Trump explicitly sought to aid Americans who’d voted for him while spurning those who dared to oppose him, multiple administration officials told <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">Politico’s E&amp;E News</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As deadly wildfires ripped through California, Trump <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">initially refused</a> to approve disaster aid because the state had voted overwhelmingly for Democrats, according to Mark Harvey, his administration’s senior director for resilience policy on the National Security Council. Harvey says that Trump only changed his mind after being shown vote totals demonstrating that there were more Trump supporters in Orange County, California, than in Iowa.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Olivia Troye and Kevin Carroll, former homeland security officials in the Trump administration, both back up Harvey’s story.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Trump absolutely didn’t want to give aid to California or Puerto Rico purely for partisan politics — because they didn’t vote for him,” Carroll told <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/13/trump-disaster-funding-warning">The Guardian</a>  earlier this month. Carroll went on to say that his former boss, then-White House Chief of Staff John Kelly, had to “twist Trump’s arm” to get him to release federal funding to those areas following the wildfires and Hurricane Maria, respectively.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump also withheld millions in <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/25/trump-ignored-disaster-aid-request-from-democratic-governor-00185542">wildfire aid</a> from Washington in September 2020 because the state’s governor had criticized him, and the aid ultimately was not approved until Biden took office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis’s memoir lends further credence to these claims. In 2019, after Hurricane Michael devastated the Florida Panhandle, DeSantis <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/10/03/helene-trump-politics-natural-disaster-00182419">asked</a> then-President Trump to order the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to pay 100 percent of the state’s recovery costs, instead of 75 percent, as was customary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to DeSantis’s book, Trump replied, “They love me in the Panhandle.&nbsp; I must have won 90 percent of the vote out there. Huge crowds. What do they need?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump proceeded to order FEMA to pay 100 percent of Florida’s recovery costs. And yet, just two months earlier, he threatened to veto legislation that would have extended the same courtesy to Puerto Rico. And his administration proceeded to withhold <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/new-probe-confirms-trump-officials-blocked-puerto-rico-receiving-hurri-rcna749">$20 billion</a> in hurricane relief from the island for a protracted period of time, while Trump <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/economy/top-hud-officials-departure-follows-disagreements-over-housing-policy-and-puerto-rico-disaster-funds/2019/01/16/e6ba5be4-1839-11e9-9ebf-c5fed1b7a081_story.html">reportedly told</a> Kelly and then-Office of Management and Budget Director Mick Mulvaney that he did not want a “single dollar going to Puerto Rico.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration has shown no comparable favoritism. To the contrary, its response to Hurricane Helene — which ravaged many conservative communities on the East Coast — has earned <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/03/politics/fact-check-trump-biden-hurricane-response/index.html">plaudits from Republican officials</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Biden’s signature piece of legislation — the Inflation Reduction Act — has actually <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2023-red-states-will-reap-the-biggest-rewards-from-biden-s-climate-package/">directed disproportionate funds to red states</a>. And Biden has also directed considerable federal funds toward <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/politics/articles/2024-09-05/biden-promotes-administrations-rural-electrification-funding-in-wisconsin">improving infrastructure</a> in conservative-leaning rural areas. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump supporters who profess outrage at Biden’s words are guilty of more than hypocrisy</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In sum, one presidential candidate is associated with a man who might have once referred to Republican voters as garbage momentarily — before immediately disavowing that idea, and after dutifully advancing the interests of conservative regions during his time as president. That candidate herself, meanwhile, has said, “I strongly disagree with any criticism of people based on who they vote for” and “I believe the work that I do is about representing all the people, whether they support me or not.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The other presidential candidate has personally likened large swaths of the American public to “vermin” and “garbage” — repeatedly, and without apology — after seeking to choke off federal aid to Democratic victims of wildfires, and pledging to prosecute his political opponents the next chance he gets.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Any public official who condemns Harris for somehow abetting the dehumanization of ordinary Americans is not merely guilty of hypocrisy, but of wildly misleading voters about an issue of vital importance: which presidential hopeful would — and would not — treat their least favorite segments of the American public like trash.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
