<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-27T15:21:31Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Did Ukraine just call Putin’s nuclear bluff?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369035/kursk-nuclear-escalation-zelenskyy-putin" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369035</id>
			<updated>2024-08-27T15:21:31Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T15:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia-Ukraine war" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Three weeks ago, Ukraine’s military launched a stunning operation to take the war in Ukraine back onto the territory of the country that launched it. Three weeks later, the Ukrainians still occupy hundreds of miles of territory in Russia’s western Kursk region.   The incursion had a number of goals: to force Russia to divert its [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A statue of Lenin with the face blown off." data-caption="A damaged statue of Vladimir Lenin in the Ukrainian-controlled Russian town of Sudzha on August 16, 2024. | Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166323213.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A damaged statue of Vladimir Lenin in the Ukrainian-controlled Russian town of Sudzha on August 16, 2024. | Yan Dobronosov/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Three weeks ago, Ukraine’s military launched a <a href="https://www.vox.com/russia-ukraine/367298/ukraine-russia-incursion-kursk-war-putin-zelenskyy-crimea">stunning operation</a> to take the war in Ukraine back onto the territory of the country that launched it. Three weeks later, the Ukrainians still occupy hundreds of miles of territory in Russia’s western Kursk region.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The incursion had a number of goals: to force Russia to divert its forces from Ukraine to defend its own towns and cities; to seize territory that might later be used for bargaining leverage in peace negotiations; and to send a political message to the Russian people and their leaders that they are not safe from the consequences of the war launched by Russian President Vladimir Putin nearly two-and-a-half years ago. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there was also a less obvious objective: Leaders in Kyiv likely hoped to send a message to their friends in the United States and Europe that their approach to the war has been overly cautious — that fears about “escalation,” “red lines,” and Russian nuclear use — a threat that Putin himself has voiced repeatedly — have been overblown.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy acknowledged this explicitly in a <a href="https://www.president.gov.ua/en/news/vid-nashoyi-spilnoyi-roboti-zalezhit-yaka-zbroya-v-rukah-u-n-92669">speech on August 19</a>, saying, “We are now witnessing a significant ideological shift, namely, the whole naive, illusory concept of so-called ‘red lines’ refs somewhere near Sudzha” — a town near the border now <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/18/ukraine-russia-sudzha-kursk/">under the control of Ukrainian forces</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He also confirmed that Ukraine had not informed its Western partners about the operation ahead of time, anticipating that they would be told “it was impossible and that it would cross the strictest of all the red lines that Russia has.” According to <a href="https://www.economist.com/europe/2024/08/18/russias-double-punch-back-against-ukraines-shock-raid">press reports</a>, the Ukrainians predicted — correctly, as it turned out — that the West would not object too strongly once presented with a fait accompli.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They were trying to push a boundary with their Western partners and what we’ve seen is that these partners have quietly accepted the new boundary,” said Liana Fix, fellow for Europe and the Council on Foreign Relations. In particular, they’re hoping the US will lift restrictions on using American-provided long-range missiles to strike deep into Russia, a step Washington has so far avoided. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In apparent retaliation for the Kursk invasion, Moscow on Monday launched the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/26/europe/ukraine-russia-air-attacks-intl-hnk/index.html?oref=d_brief_nl&amp;utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=The%20D%20Brief:%20August%2026%2C%202024&amp;utm_term=newsletter_d1_dbrief">largest missile and drone barrage</a> on Ukraine since the start of the war. But that still fell far short of the nuclear escalation that Putin has often threatened.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his speech, Zelenskyy was arguing, in effect, that he had called Putin’s bluff and that it’s time for Ukraine’s allies to become much more aggressive in giving Ukraine the kind of support it needs to win the war.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Are Russia’s threats still working?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Russia’s full-scale invasion in 2022, Ukraine’s Western backers, including the United States, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/interactive/2022/ukraine-road-to-war/">have had two priorities</a>: preventing Russian victory and avoiding “escalation” — meaning avoiding direct combat between Russia and NATO militaries or, in a worst-case scenario, use of nuclear weapons. At times, the second priority has taken precedence over the first. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Russian government has certainly done everything in its power to add nuclear uncertainty to Western leaders’ calculations. From the very first day of the invasion, Putin has made repeated references to his country’s nuclear arsenal — the largest in the world — and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putins-nuclear-warnings-since-russia-invaded-ukraine-2024-03-13/">warned</a>  countries that get in Russia’s way of “consequences that you have never faced in your history.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the course of the war, Putin and other Russian officials have made repeated references to “<a href="https://www.kyivpost.com/analysis/23308">red lines</a>” that should not be crossed if Western governments don’t want to face a catastrophic response. Former Russian President Dmitry Medvedev has been particularly active in threatening foreign powers with “nuclear apocalypse” via his <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russias-medvedev-western-arms-ukraine-make-nuclear-apocalypse-more-likely-2023-05-23/">social media accounts</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not all rhetoric: The Russian government has taken steps such as <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/03/14/russia-nuclear-weapons-belarus-putin/">moving some of its nuclear weapons</a> to Belarus and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russia-says-its-non-strategic-nuclear-drills-involve-iskander-missiles-2024-06-12/">conducting realistic drills</a> for using tactical nuclear weapons — seemingly in an effort to remind Ukraine’s allies of Russia’s capabilities.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Beyond North Korea, the Russians have been the country that has used nuclear threats most vigorously,” said Nicole Grajewski, a fellow in the Nuclear Policy Program at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The threats work — but only to a certain extent and only for a time. Escalation fears were the reason Western countries ruled out taking actions like <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/2/27/22952220/ukraine-russia-no-fly-zone-nuclear-war">imposing a no-fly zone in Ukraine</a> or sending NATO troops into the country. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Escalation fears have also made them reluctant to provide certain weapons systems to Ukraine, though system-by-system, that reluctance has faded over time. There was a time when even shoulder-mounted stinger missiles were <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/national-security/didnt-us-allies-provide-ukraine-better-air-defense-system-rcna17317">viewed as too provocative</a>. Now, the Ukrainians are using <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/ukraine-uses-long-range-atacms-russia-first-time-rcna148309">US-provided long-range missiles</a> and recently received their <a href="https://www.defensenews.com/global/2024/08/01/first-group-of-us-made-f-16-jets-arrive-in-ukraine-officials-say/#:~:text=BERLIN%20%E2%80%93%20Ukraine%20has%20received%20its,several%20officials%20confirmed%20on%20Wednesday.">first batch of F-16 fighter jets</a>.   </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That these capabilities have often been provided only after months of contentious political debate has been an endless source of frustration to Ukrainians.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’ve been hearing about nuclear escalation since the first day,” Oleksandra Ustinova, a Ukrainian member of parliament who chairs a committee monitoring arms supplies, <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/353796/us-weapons-ukraine-russia-putin-escalation-nuclear">told Vox last June</a>. “First it was, it was ‘if Ukraine gets MIGs from Poland, he’s going to use nukes.’ Then it was the HIMARS, then Patriots, then tanks.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She added: “It’s like we’re running behind the train. Every time we ask for something, we get it months or a year later when it won’t make as much of a difference as it would have before.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fact that none of the steps Western countries have taken so far have resulted in Russia using a nuclear weapon or directly attacking a NATO country is taken by many Ukrainians and their international supporters as evidence that these threats were never real to begin with. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Are there any more “red lines”?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If anything could be considered crossing a “red line,” one would think it would be the first military invasion of Russian territory since World War II.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Russia’s <a href="https://archive.mid.ru/en/web/guest/foreign_policy/international_safety/disarmament/-/asset_publisher/rp0fiUBmANaH/content/id/4152094">official nuclear doctrine</a> permits the use of nuclear weapons under circumstances in which the “very existence of the state is in jeopardy.” Ukraine’s incursion into the Kursk region, which has <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/8/22/russia-faces-manpower-woes-after-failing-to-stop-ukraines-kursk-incursion">seized hundreds of square miles of territory</a>, might not be a direct threat to the regime in Moscow, but it certainly threatens that regime’s ability to defend its own territory and sovereignty — the basic function of any state. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moreover, the Ukrainians appear to be using <a href="https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2024/08/23/ukraines-military-says-it-used-us-glide-bombs-for-strikes-in-russias-kursk-region">US-provided weapons inside Russian territory</a>, in apparent <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2024/08/23/ukraine-kursk-offensive-russia-weapons/">violation of US policy</a>. (The Biden administration agreed in May to allow the Ukrainians to use American weapons for <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/30/us/politics/biden-ukraine-russia-weapons.html?oref=d_brief_nl&amp;utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=The%20D%20Brief:%20May%2031%2C%202024&amp;utm_term=newsletter_d1_dbrief">limited strikes into Russia,</a> but only to defend against attacks on Ukraine.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, there’s been markedly little saber-rattling from Putin and the Kremlin since the Kursk operation began. The president has downplayed what he calls a “<a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/blogs/ukrainealert/invasion-what-invasion-putin-is-downplaying-ukraines-kursk-offensive/">large-scale provocation</a>” and has taken a few seemingly unrelated trips in what appears to be an effort to project normalcy. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The picture in the Russian media has been a bit more mixed: Vladimir Solovyov, host of the flagship pro-Kremlin talk show<em> Sunday Evening</em>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GA5wp9p7V5s">used one monologue</a> to both call on Russians to “calm down a bit” about the incursion and to call for nuclear strikes on European capitals. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of what Solovyov says, it does not appear that Russia is planning to respond to the events in Kursk by using nuclear weapons, attacking NATO countries, or taking steps beyond — as we saw with Monday’s massive barrage — destroying more of Ukraine with conventional weapons. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This doesn’t, however, mean that Ukraine’s backers are ready to take the gloves off.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2024/08/23/on-the-record-press-gaggle-by-white-house-national-security-communications-advisor-john-kirby-23/">press call on Friday</a>, Vox asked US National Security Spokesperson John Kirby whether Zelenskyy was right that it was time to move beyond fears of escalation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’ve been watching escalation risks since the beginning of this conflict, and that ain’t gonna change,” Kirby responded. “We’re always going to be concerned about the potential for the aggression in Ukraine to lead to escalation on the European continent.” He added that “it’s too soon to know whether what’s going on in Kursk…[what] potential impact that that could have in terms of escalation. But it is something that we remain concerned about.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The thinking in the administration appears to be that, as Pentagon Deputy Spokesperson Sabrina Singh recently put it, “just because Russia hasn’t responded to something doesn’t mean that they can’t or won’t in the future.” And given that it’s nuclear weapons we’re talking about, that’s a risk that has to be taken seriously. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Even if it’s only a 10 percent chance or 5 percent chance that they actually mean it, or they’re actually planning to act on it, that’s concerning enough,” said Carnegie’s Grajewski. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Does Putin have a breaking point?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pavel Podvig, senior researcher on Russia’s nuclear arsenal at the United Nations Institute for Disarmament Research in Geneva, argues that “this whole kind of a business of red lines is actually quite misleading and not helpful.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his view, there are few useful military applications for nuclear weapons inside Ukraine and given the catastrophic risks involved, Putin would be unlikely to consider any sort of nuclear use unless the very existence of the Russian state were threatened. “Even the loss of a region like Kursk technically would not qualify,” Podvig said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Putin has certainly implied, however, that his threshold for escalation was much lower. Just last May, for instance, he warned Western countries against allowing their weapons to be used to strike Russian territory, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/putin-warns-west-not-let-ukraine-use-its-missiles-hit-russia-2024-05-28/">saying they should</a> “bear in mind our parity in the field of strategic weapons.&#8221; (“Strategic” is a euphemism for nuclear in this case.) These threats are getting harder to take seriously. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kyiv’s current campaign is to get the US to lift its restrictions on using US-supplied long-range missiles to strike deep into Russia, which would allow them to press the offensive in Kursk further and hit more Russian military targets than they are currently able to with domestically produced weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Ukraine is separated from halting the advance of the Russian army on the front by only one decision we await from our partners: the decision on long-range capabilities,” Zelenskyy said in his speech. In a post on Twitter following Monday’s strikes, Ukraine’s defense minister said <a href="https://x.com/rustem_umerov/status/1828028537791500413">the attack showed </a>why “Ukraine needs long-range capabilities and the lifting of restrictions on strikes on the enemy’s military facilities.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If this debate follows the trajectory of those that preceded it, Washington will eventually come around to giving the Ukrainians what they’re asking for. But while the risky incursion into Kursk may have given Ukraine some more ammunition in these debates going forward, Western leaders are not about to simply abandon their caution and give Ukraine everything it wants. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the Council on Foreign Relations’s Fix put it, Western “red lines” on aid to Ukraine have clearly shifted. The problem is “we don’t know how the red lines are shifting in Putin’s mind.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What immigration policies do Americans actually want?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/368889/immigration-border-polls-election-2024-trump-harris" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368889</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T21:49:25Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Immigration has loomed large over the presidential election. After going on the offensive against former President Donald Trump’s immigration policies in 2020, the Democratic Party has seen public opinion shift in recent years, with more people taking a dim view of immigration and favoring more restrictive border policies. Trump has pounced on this shift, promising [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Donald Trump, wearing a red tie and navy suit and with a section of border wall to his right, stands behind a podium labeled “The Southern Border” to give remarks." data-caption="Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump speaks about immigration and border security near Coronado National Memorial in Montezuma Pass, Arizona, on August 22, 2024. | Olivier Touron/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Olivier Touron/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2167160569.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump speaks about immigration and border security near Coronado National Memorial in Montezuma Pass, Arizona, on August 22, 2024. | Olivier Touron/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Immigration has loomed large over the presidential election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After going on the offensive against former President Donald Trump’s immigration policies in 2020, the Democratic Party has seen public opinion shift in recent years, with more people taking a dim view of immigration and favoring more restrictive border policies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has pounced on this shift, promising to revive — and expand — the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24080265/trump-immigration-policies-2024">draconian immigration platform</a> of his first administration. That includes his 2024 pledges of <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce9z0lm48ngo">mass deportations</a> and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-vows-end-birthright-citizenship-children-immigrants-us-illegally-2023-05-30/">ending birthright citizenship</a>. He has blamed Harris for the surge in migrants arriving at the border for much of her vice presidency, mislabeling her as President Joe Biden’s “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">border czar</a>,” as <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">many others also have</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question of what to do about immigration animates voters across the political spectrum. It’s an especially potent topic for Republicans, <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/644570/immigration-named-top-problem-third-straight-month.aspx">48 percent</a> of whom say it’s the most important issue facing the country in a running Gallup poll.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s less so for independents and Democrats, but notably, it’s the first time in more than a decade that such a large share of independents say it’s their top issue. And independents will likely decide the election: The US has seen its share of independent voters swell in recent years, particularly in <a href="https://www.usnews.com/opinion/articles/2024-04-04/what-surging-numbers-of-independent-voters-could-mean-for-this-falls-election">Sunbelt swing states</a> like Arizona and Nevada that have seen <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2024/04/where-do-immigrants-live.html">high levels of immigration</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, an overwhelming majority of registered voters said in a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/1660/immigration.aspx">June Gallup poll</a> that they will only vote for a candidate who shares their views on immigration, or that it is one of many important factors determining who they support.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/sF7nh-republicans-are-more-likely-to-prioritize-immigration-1.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,18.050459661129,100,63.899080677743" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Nicole Narea/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">More voters of all stripes now want to see <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/1660/immigration.aspx">immigration levels decrease</a> than at any point since the early 2000s, after the 9/11 terrorist attacks <a href="https://ccrjustice.org/home/blog/2021/09/01/legacy-911-reckoning-20-year-ideology-war-nativism-and-authoritarianism">fueled a rise in nativism</a>. This is in part a reaction to record levels of migrant crossings over the past few years — unauthorized migrant crossings hit a <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/02/15/migrant-encounters-at-the-us-mexico-border-hit-a-record-high-at-the-end-of-2023/">record high in December</a> — and the resulting pressures in cities and border communities that have absorbed them. (However, it is worth noting that border crossings have declined for <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2024/08/16/united-states-mexico-border-apprehensions-july/">five straight months</a>.)&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/qABNL-americans-have-become-significantly-more-anti-immigrant-in-four-years-1.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,19.719465499727,100,60.561069000547" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Nicole Narea/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In response to record crossings, the Biden administration shifted from its previous focus on implementing a more humane US immigration system to limiting the flow of people across the US-Mexico border. Biden has pursued some <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/353835/asylum-border-biden-policy-trump-shutdown">policies to curb asylum</a> that put little daylight between him and Trump, and has <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/20/read-the-entire-transcript-of-president-joe-bidens-dnc-speech/74867260007/">credited those policies for the recent decline in crossings</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Simultaneously, Biden has advanced efforts to protect undocumented immigrants living in the US. Now, Democrats’ <a href="https://democrats.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/FINAL-MASTER-PLATFORM.pdf">2024 platform</a> emphasizes border security and deterring unauthorized immigration while expanding legal pathways to the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Larger shifts in immigration have little to do with Biden’s policies. Rather, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24153132/us-border-crisis-mexico-migrant-immigration-asylum">migration patterns have significantly shifted</a> in only a few years, and the US immigration system just wasn’t designed to deal with it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, migrants came alone seeking work, mainly from Mexico. Now, more people are coming from South America, the Caribbean, and even China and Europe. They’re increasingly bringing their families and seeking asylum. Many of them are fleeing persecution or instability in their home countries.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But regardless of what voters think is behind the surge, it’s clear American public opinion on immigration has taken a sharp rightward turn in the last four years, and that a bipartisan consensus has emerged in Washington around further restricting immigration. The polling suggests that’s broadly what most voters want, too — but how exactly they think the US should go about it isn’t as clear-cut.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Voters want to see even tougher immigration enforcement, but don’t agree on what that means</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some proposals for immigration enforcement that were controversial just a few years ago now have mainstream appeal.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That includes Trump’s efforts to build a border wall, a defining policy of his 2016 campaign. While in office, he erected about <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/rnc-trump-speech-biden-election-2024/card/did-trump-build-the-wall--0MOGuZRPjtpeCGpZClpT">500 miles of a 30-foot border fence</a>, most of which replaced preexisting fencing or provided another layer of barrier where some already existed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At that time, support for the project <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/02/27/border-wall-has-never-been-more-popular/">hovered around a third of Americans</a>. But that share has since seemed to balloon. <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/02/15/how-americans-view-the-situation-at-the-u-s-mexico-border-its-causes-and-consequences/">Multiple</a> polls <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/02/27/border-wall-has-never-been-more-popular/">conducted</a> in recent months have shown that a majority of Americans want a wall, and that support has grown substantially among independents. In a separate April Axios-Ipsos poll, &nbsp;<a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/11/poll-latino-support-border-wall-deportations-jumps">42 percent of Latinos</a>, despite many of them having ties to the immigrant experience, supported building the wall.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters don’t even draw the line at the kind of mass deportation scheme that Trump is proposing anymore. He has promised the “<a href="https://www.foxcarolina.com/2024/02/11/trump-calls-largest-domestic-deportation-operation/">largest domestic deportation operation in American history</a>,” targeting millions of undocumented immigrants in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/us/politics/trump-2025-immigration-agenda.html">large-scale raids</a> and then forcibly detaining them in new camps.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whereas in 2016, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2016/09/07/politics/2016-election-presidential-poll-immigration-donald-trump-hillary-clinton/index.html">66 percent of Americans</a> opposed mass deportations in a CNN poll, an <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/25/trump-biden-americans-illegal-immigration-poll">Axios Vibes survey by the Harris Poll</a> and a <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/poll-trump-biden-neck-and-neck-06-09-2024/">CBS/YouGov poll</a> conducted earlier this year showed that between <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/25/trump-biden-americans-illegal-immigration-poll">51</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/poll-trump-biden-neck-and-neck-06-09-2024/">62 percent</a> of Americans support such measures. That also includes large shares of Hispanics and Latinos, who support mass deportations at rates between 45 and 53 percent depending on the poll.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Gfh0q-mass-deportations-are-increasingly-popular-3.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4946518849668,100,93.010696230066" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Nicole Narea/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Significant shares of voters have also warmed to the idea of ending birthright citizenship (meaning if someone is born in the US, they are automatically a citizen),<strong> </strong>with the <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/25/trump-biden-americans-illegal-immigration-poll">Axios/Harris poll</a> showing that 30 percent of Democrats and 46 percent of Republicans support it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters appear less sure of Biden’s efforts to limit access to asylum, which federal law guarantees to those who face credible fear of harm or persecution in their home countries no matter how they cross the border.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden introduced a <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/353835/asylum-border-biden-policy-trump-shutdown">new policy earlier this year</a> that bars asylum seekers who cross the border without permission from applying for protections in the US when migrant crossings exceed a daily average of 2,500 in a week. Less than half of Americans supported the move in a <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/12/biden-border-immigration-poll-00162933">June Monmouth University poll</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it didn’t seem to inspire acute opposition among his base either: 38 percent of Democrats and 40 percent of independents approved. In another June Fox News poll, <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/official-polls/fox-news-poll-voters-approve-restrictions-asylum-seekers-biden-cuts-trumps-edge-immigration">57 percent of Americans overall</a> supported the policy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this seems to indicate that Trump’s approach to immigration might be more popular than the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2018/06/30/us/june-30-immigration-protests/index.html">widespread protests</a> against his immigration policies while he was in office previously suggested.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Voters have sympathy for undocumented immigrants already living in the US</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While voters support tougher immigration enforcement, they seem torn about what to do with undocumented immigrants who have put down roots in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In apparent contradiction to the polling on mass deportations, most Americans appear to support a path to citizenship or legal status for the population of about <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/07/22/what-we-know-about-unauthorized-immigrants-living-in-the-us/">11 million undocumented immigrants</a> living in the US as of 2022. An April Pew Research Center poll found that <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/06/06/immigration-attitudes-and-the-2024-election/">59 percent of Americans</a>, including 32 percent of Trump supporters, said that undocumented immigrants should be allowed to remain in the US legally.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/FGGSD-legalizing-undocumented-immigrants-is-popular.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=11.8,0,76.4,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Nicole Narea/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Support for a pathway to citizenship for DREAMers — the <a href="https://immigrationforum.org/article/fact-sheet-on-deferred-action-for-childhood-arrivals-daca/#:~:text=There%20are%20as%20many%20as,are%20currently%20protected%20under%20DACA.">estimated 3.6 million undocumented immigrants </a>who came to the US as children — is even higher, according to a <a href="https://immigrationforum.org/article/new-survey-americans-want-a-legislative-solution-for-dreamers/">June National Immigration Forum/Bullfinch Group survey</a>. Only about 530,000 DREAMers are currently shielded from deportation under the Obama-era Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program, and legislative attempts to provide them with a pathway to citizenship have repeatedly failed over the last decade.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/355662/biden-path-citizenship-spouses-children-undocumented-legalization-green-card">new program to legalize undocumented spouses</a> of Americans gives these populations some relief and represents the biggest legalization push since DACA. But only about 500,000 spouses and 50,000 stepchildren could be eligible for the new program.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The polling suggests that there may be room for the next president to pair further legalization efforts with stronger immigration enforcement, as Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/5/24062710/senate-immigration-bill-border-security-ukraine-2024">attempted</a>, but ultimately failed, to do in a deal with Congress earlier this year. The question is whether Democrats and Republicans can break from the long-entrenched sides they have staked out on the issue of immigration now that their voters are coalescing around certain policies.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[An inside look at how the far right is mainstreaming itself]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368884/online-right-l0m3z-jonathan-keeperman-interview-razib-khan" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368884</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T22:45:58Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-27T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before the era of Donald Trump, the right’s very online radicals yelled at the Republican Party from the cheap seats. Now, they’ve become players within the conservative power structure, as the walls that once kept them at bay have crumbled. The Republican nominee for vice president has explicitly cited a neo-monarchist blogger as an influence [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Jonathan Keeperman, a.k.a. “l0m3z,” speaks at the National Conservative Conference in Washington, DC, on July 10, 2024. | Dominic Gwinn/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Dominic Gwinn/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2164097884.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Jonathan Keeperman, a.k.a. “l0m3z,” speaks at the National Conservative Conference in Washington, DC, on July 10, 2024. | Dominic Gwinn/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Before the era of Donald Trump, the right’s very online radicals yelled at the Republican Party from the cheap seats. Now, they’ve become players within the conservative power structure, as the walls that once kept them at bay have crumbled. The Republican nominee for vice president has <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23373795/curtis-yarvin-neoreaction-redpill-moldbug">explicitly cited a neo-monarchist blogger</a> as an influence on his thinking about the executive branch; junior Trump White House staffers were <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/03/magazine/claremont-institute-conservative.html">reportedly all reading</a> a writer called “Bronze Age Pervert.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The influence of these fringe ideas on the right is, at this point, unmistakable. But most people don’t understand the particulars of how it happened —&nbsp;and, in fact, is continuing to happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a whole network of campaigners, often invisible to mainstream observers, who are actively working to bring radical ideas into the American mainstream. Their goal is to (re)introduce ideas, like the notion that Black people are generally less intelligent than white people, into the mainstream intellectual world —&nbsp;and, in doing so, ultimately transform for the worse the contours of what’s permissible in our politics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I listened with interest when a prominent figure in this world, a book publisher and secret Twitter troll named Jonathan Keeperman, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h0aQXTcqaI0">went on an obscure podcast to explain exactly how his mainstreaming strategy works</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At its core, it is about creating an alternative set of social institutions, ones that are sufficiently robust and well-established that people who espouse extreme ideas can rely on them to help weather attacks and social sanctions from the mainstream. But it also depends on building ties with more mainstream figures,&nbsp;such as Tucker Carlson, who serve as go-betweens to pump the radical right’s ideas into the political bloodstream.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Keeperman runs an outfit called Passage Press, which releases tomes from right-wingers historic (like the <a href="https://passage.press/products/the-storm-of-steel-original-1929-translation-by-ernst-junger-translated-by-basil-creighton" rel="nofollow">inter-war German radical Ernst Jünger</a>) and contemporary (<a href="https://passage.press/products/gray-mirror-fascicle-i-disturbance-by-curtis-yarvin-patrician-edition" rel="nofollow">aforementioned neo-monarchist blogger Curtis Yarvin</a>). He’s treated as a respectable figure by the mainstream, speaking at the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dHtMM-8myU">same National Conservatism conference</a> this July that hosted Sens. JD Vance, Josh Hawley, and Mike Lee. Tucker Carlson once <a href="https://passage.press/products/noticingpaperback" rel="nofollow">blurbed a Passage Press book</a>, a collection of essays by writer Steve Sailer, who <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2024/08/race-science-far-right-charlie-kirk/679527/">promotes the debunked belief</a> that racial inequalities are biological. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Keeperman has been living a dual life.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/may/14/far-right-twitter-identity-revealed?CMP=Share_AndroidApp_Other">May piece in the Guardian</a> revealed that he’s the person behind the prominent online right persona <a href="https://x.com/L0m3z" rel="nofollow">L0m3z</a>, whose X account <a href="https://archive.ph/ffHHr#selection-3479.0-3479.141" rel="nofollow">calls gay people the F-slur</a>, Asians “<a href="https://x.com/L0m3z/status/1758531485710123224" rel="nofollow">mongoloids</a>,” and (jokingly?) <a href="https://archive.ph/r6y1S#selection-7239.28-7239.259">suggests journalists should be lynched</a>. L0m3z is obsessed with the specter of something he calls “gay race communism,” which <a href="https://x.com/L0m3z/status/1651331312190644224" rel="nofollow">he describes</a> as “a civilizational scale shit-test that operates on the … implicit threat of feminine hysterics.” He casually references <a href="https://x.com/L0m3z/status/1624232652739080192" rel="nofollow">white nationalist</a> <a href="https://hatepedia.ca/guide/explicit/dindu-nuffin">memes</a>, conspiracy theories that <a href="https://x.com/L0m3z/status/1699440405581124009" rel="nofollow">Barack Obama is gay</a>, and something called “<a href="https://x.com/L0m3z/status/1722305465672204751" rel="nofollow">retard strength</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his appearance on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/ca/podcast/razib-khans-unsupervised-learning/id1542136715"><em>Unsupervised Learning</em></a>, a podcast hosted by conservative geneticist Razib Khan, Keeperman addresses this duality — explaining how and why his shitposting under the L0m3z handle connects to his broader strategy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Keeperman says that his work is built on a central premise: that any quest to convince mainstream cultural institutions to discuss “outer right topics” is doomed to fail. People on the right who wish to discuss taboo topics, like the link between race and IQ, must instead “form our own self-verifying and self-credentialing networks.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Passage Publishing is designed to be a foundational institution in this network. So too is the online community of anonymous right-wing posters in which L0m3z flourishes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The “anons,” as they’re called, create a self-reinforcing world to discuss extreme ideas, one that’s largely impervious to mainstream efforts to expose and shame them. This community wields offensive language as an ideological weapon, intentionally using slurs to break down boundaries about the public discussion of far-right ideas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You use these words just because you’re not supposed to,” Keeperman says on the podcast. “You want to demystify this language and strip this language of … its ability to manage what people can say and how they say it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For this reason, he shrugs off the Guardian’s criticism of him using the F-slur and similarly offensive words.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t regret using that language [and] I don’t apologize for it,” he says. “When you are online speaking in these discourse communities, this is the kind of language you use. And that’s fine — in fact, I think it’s a good thing.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This strategy of breaking down boundaries appears to have worked: Keeperman has published under the L0m3z moniker in <a href="https://www.firstthings.com/web-exclusives/2023/02/what-is-the-longhouse">multiple</a> <a href="https://thefederalist.com/2024/02/29/if-memes-are-illegal-all-speech-will-become-illegal/">different</a> <a href="https://amgreatness.com/2020/12/10/play-the-game-or-be-played/">right-wing</a> <a href="https://americanmind.org/features/afghanistan-doomed-from-the-start/how-the-lizard-people-took-over-americas-war/">publications</a>, proof positive that the sort of vicious language his account regularly deploys is no longer disqualifying even in relatively respectable conservative outlets like <a href="https://www.firstthings.com/web-exclusives/2023/02/what-is-the-longhouse">First Things magazine</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The twinned work of high-brow and low-brow outreach has helped Keeperman weather the storm of his unmasking at the Guardian’s hands. By cultivating key ideological allies he describes as having “one foot in the credible institutional world,” Keeperman can count on elite defenders to ensure that his performative online cruelty doesn’t have any true professional consequences. In the podcast, Keeperman names <a href="https://www.vox.com/23811277/christopher-rufo-culture-wars-ron-desantis-florida-critical-race-theory-anti-wokeness">Chris Rufo</a> — one of the right’s most prominent activists —&nbsp;as one such ally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s former top strategist (who’s currently in <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/01/politics/steve-bannon-report-to-prison/index.html">federal prison</a>) Steve Bannon is another such ally. After the Guardian exposé, <a href="https://rumble.com/v4vdqg9-jonathan-keeperman-details-his-triggering-of-the-guardian.html">Bannon hosted Keeperman on his podcast</a> and vowed to defend him: “We’re gonna have your back, and others are going to have your back,” Bannon said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t want to overemphasize Keeperman’s personal influence. Passage Press is a relatively small publishing house; L0m3z’s 85,000-person following on X is large but not gigantic.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But his interview with Khan is notable because it lays out, in unusually blunt terms, how a much larger network of influence operates. He bluntly describes how abstruse high-brow publishing works hand-in-glove with online shitposting to mainstream radical ideas; he also shows how figures in the conservative mainstream provide cover for this kind of work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the podcast, Keeperman doesn’t spell out a detailed vision of what his ideal&nbsp;America would look like. But there’s one belief he’s clear on: that women have gained too much power in universities and other cultural institutions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you’re being an honest observer, you look around at the way that these institutions have been managed with this kind of feminine superstructure over them, and you would very easily determine that it’s not good,” he says. “I think we just need to be honest about this, say it out loud, and then make corrections for it.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Telegram’s CEO was detained in France]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/368896/telegram-pavel-durov-france-cyber-crimes-terrorism-content-moderation-macron-elon-musk" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368896</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T22:14:24Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T22:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Privacy &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Media" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pavel Durov, the CEO and founder of messaging app Telegram, was detained in Paris on Saturday as part of an ongoing French investigation into financial and cyber crimes. On Monday, French officials said he remains under arrest, though he has not been charged with any crime.&#160; French President Emmanuel Macron denied the arrest was politically [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Pavel Durov of Telegram." data-caption="Pavel Durov, CEO and co-founder of Telegram, speaks onstage during day one of TechCrunch Disrupt on September 21, 2015, in San Francisco, California. | Steve Jennings/Getty Images for Tech Crunch" data-portal-copyright="Steve Jennings/Getty Images for Tech Crunch" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-489468026.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pavel Durov, CEO and co-founder of Telegram, speaks onstage during day one of TechCrunch Disrupt on September 21, 2015, in San Francisco, California. | Steve Jennings/Getty Images for Tech Crunch</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Pavel Durov, the CEO and founder of messaging app Telegram, was detained in Paris on Saturday as part of an ongoing French investigation into financial and cyber crimes. On Monday, French officials said he remains under arrest, though he has not been charged with any crime.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">French President Emmanuel Macron denied the <a href="https://twitter.com/EmmanuelMacron/status/1828077245606342672">arrest was politically motivated</a>. Durov holds French and United Arab Emirates citizenship but is originally from Russia; France has been highly critical of Russia’s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/pavel-durov-has-nothing-hide-telegram-says-arrested-founder-2024-08-26/">invasion of Ukraine</a> and has enforced sanctions on its economy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Details on exactly what led to the arrest are limited. However, according to French prosecutors, Durov is being held as part of a larger French investigation. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/26/business/telegram-founder-arrest-france.html">The New York Times</a> reported that prosecutors said they are looking into a “person unnamed” who they believe may have committed <a href="https://www.tribunal-de-paris.justice.fr/sites/default/files/2024-08/2024-08-26%20-%20CP%20TELEGRAM%20.pdf">an extensive list of crimes</a> — apparently with the aid of Telegram — that include the distribution of child sexual abuse material, money laundering, and drug trafficking. <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/26/pavel-durov-telegram-france-detention/">The Washington Post</a> has reported that French police have suggested that “child sex crimes” are an area of particular focus for officials.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is unclear what Durov’s relationship, if any, is to the “<a href="https://www.tribunal-de-paris.justice.fr/sites/default/files/2024-08/2024-08-26%20-%20CP%20TELEGRAM%20.pdf">person unnamed</a>.” Unless formally charged, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/pavel-durov-has-nothing-hide-telegram-says-arrested-founder-2024-08-26/">Durov can only be held until Wednesday</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t the first time Telegram has been linked to illegal activity. It is a <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/pavel-durov-russia-telegram-ceo-facebook-elon-musk-tech/">globally popular platform</a> that offers both broadcast channels (in which users can send text and media to large groups of people) and user-to-user chats. It also offers what it calls&nbsp;“<a href="https://core.telegram.org/api/end-to-end">secret chat</a>” conversations that are end-to-end encrypted —&nbsp;meaning that the messages sent are only decipherable to the conversation participants and that no one else, not even Telegram, can see the content.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That feature, as well as <a href="https://telegram.org/faq#:~:text=Telegram's%20special%20secret%20chats%20use,on%20their%20devices%20of%20origin.">other privacy features</a> like self-deleting messages, make the app extremely useful for political dissidents and journalists trying to work under repressive regimes or protect sources. But the app has also, over the years, become a space where extremists can radicalize users and <a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2017/6/30/15886506/terrorism-isis-telegram-social-media-russia-pavel-durov-twitter">organize terror attacks.</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has led to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/telegram-pavel-durov-arrest-2c8015c102cce23c23d55c6ca82641c5">some pressure on the part of governments</a> for Telegram to be more collaborative in the data it shares with authorities. Despite this, however, Telegram has largely been able to avoid dramatic legal encounters — until now. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Durov’s arrest is renewing scrutiny on the app and reigniting the hotly debated issues of free speech and the challenges of content moderation on social media.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Telegram and the problem of content moderation</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Durov and his brother Nikolai founded Telegram to offer an app that centered user privacy following Russia’s “<a href="https://meduza.io/en/feature/2022/02/05/remembering-the-winter-of-protests">Snow Revolution</a>” in 2011 and 2012, when blatant election fraud ignited months of protests, culminating in a harsh and ever-evolving government crackdown. Previously, Durov quarreled with Russian authorities who wanted to suppress speech on the Facebook-like service he <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/article/2024/aug/26/telegram-founder-suspected-allowing-criminal-activity-pavel-durov-prosecutors">founded called VKontakte</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the years since its founding, Telegram has allegedly enabled some truly shocking crimes. Perhaps most infamously, it was used to <a href="https://www.vox.com/world/2017/6/30/15886506/terrorism-isis-telegram-social-media-russia-pavel-durov-twitter">coordinate ISIS attacks in Paris and Berlin</a>. It cracked down on ISIS-based activity on the app after those attacks, but its content moderation policies have faced a lot of scrutiny.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/22238755/telegram-messaging-social-media-extremists">Vox has noted</a>, those policies are laxer than those of other social media groups, and outlets such as the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/26/telegram-founder-pavel-durov-what-to-know/">Washington Post</a> have reported that Telegram has played host to a variety of criminal content, including child pornography. Keeping that sort of material off of a platform is an arduous — but not impossible — task,&nbsp; Alessandro Accorsi, a researcher at the International Crisis Group, told Vox.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The effectiveness of content moderation is largely dependent on the platform and the resources it allocates to safety,” Accorsi said. “Social media companies are generally reactive. They want to limit the financial resources dedicated to moderation, as well as possible legal, political, and ethical headaches. So what usually happens is that they will focus their efforts on a few groups or issues for which inaction on their part carries legal or reputational costs.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, when ISIS uses a service for terror attacks, that service focuses on stopping ISIS from using its products.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In communications that aren’t end-to-end encrypted, tech companies use a combination of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/6/20/18692912/recode-daily-facebook-content-moderators">human investigators</a> as well as algorithm-powered <a href="https://themarkup.org/automated-censorship/2024/03/01/how-automated-content-moderation-works-even-when-it-doesnt-work">programs</a> to sort through content. The sort of end-to-end encryption used in Telegram’s “secret chats,” however, makes that type of moderation all but impossible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also complicating matters is the varied nature of internet law across the globe. In the US, publishers are generally <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/24121461/myanmar-genocide-section-230-facebook-internet-social-media-moderation">legally shielded from liability</a> over what users post. But that’s not universally the case; many countries have much <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2022/05/platform-liability-trends-around-globe-recent-noteworthy-developments">stricter legal frameworks around intermediary liability</a>. France’s <a href="https://www.sciencespo.fr/public/chaire-numerique/en/2024/05/15/article-what-future-for-the-sren-law/">SREN Act</a> is extremely stringent and can levy fines against publishers for content violations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s a really hard thing to do, especially in comparative context, because what’s hateful or extreme or radical speech in some place like the US is going to be different from Myanmar or Bangladesh or other countries,” <a href="https://inta.gatech.edu/people/person/david-muchlinski">David Muchlinski</a>, professor of international affairs at Georgia Tech, told Vox. That makes content moderation “a clumsy tool at best.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Telegram has, in response to recent outside <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/10/31/1208800238/the-telegram-app-has-been-a-key-platform-for-hamas-now-its-being-restricted-ther">pressure</a>,&nbsp;employed some content moderation, Accorsi told Vox. It has banned channels associated with a handful of organizations (most recently Hamas and far-right groups in the UK), but thousands of problematic groups are still present.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">France’s investigation suggests Telegram may not be doing enough to keep bad actors from using the platform to commit crimes.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The huge stakes in the Supreme Court’s new abortion case]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/368902/supreme-court-title-x-abortion-oklahoma-hhs" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368902</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T20:39:40Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T20:39:40Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oklahoma v. Department of Health and Human Services is the sort of case that keeps health policy wonks up late at night. On the surface, it involves a relatively low-stakes fight over abortion. The Biden administration requires recipients of federal Title X grants — a federal program that funds family-planning services — to present patients [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Protesters in front of the Supreme Court building face each other, one with a microphone and one with a bullhorn." data-caption="Pro-abortion rights activists and anti-abortion protesters clash outside of the US Supreme Court in Washington, DC, on June 24, 2024. | Celal Gunes/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Celal Gunes/Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2158552985.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-abortion rights activists and anti-abortion protesters clash outside of the US Supreme Court in Washington, DC, on June 24, 2024. | Celal Gunes/Anadolu via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/oklahoma-v-department-of-health-and-human-services/"><em>Oklahoma v. Department of Health and Human Services</em></a> is the sort of case that keeps health policy wonks up late at night.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the surface, it involves a relatively low-stakes fight over abortion. The Biden administration requires recipients of federal Title X grants — a federal program that funds family-planning services — to present patients with “neutral, factual information” about all of their family-planning options, including abortion. Grant recipients can comply with this requirement by <a href="https://www.ca10.uscourts.gov/sites/ca10/files/opinions/010111079171.pdf">giving patients a national call-in number</a> that can inform those patients about abortion providers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oklahoma had long received Title X grants to fund health programs in the state. After receiving a $4.5 million grant in 2023, however, the state decided it would no longer comply with the requirement to give patients the call-in number. Accordingly, the administration terminated Oklahoma’s grant.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, however, Oklahoma wants the Supreme Court to allow it to receive Title X funds without complying with the call-in number rule. Its suit has landed on the Court’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/8/11/21356913/supreme-court-shadow-docket-jail-asylum-covid-immigrants-sonia-sotomayor-barnes-ahlman">shadow docket</a>, a mix of emergency motions and other expedited matters that the justices sometimes decide without full briefing or oral argument.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oklahoma raises two arguments to justify its preferred outcome, one of which could potentially sabotage much of Medicare and Medicaid. Briefly, the state claims that federal agencies may not set the rules that states must comply with when they receive federal grant money, even if Congress has explicitly authorized an agency to do so. Taken seriously, Oklahoma’s proposed limit on federal agencies’ power would profoundly transform how many of the biggest and most consequential federal programs operate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the Justice Department points out in its <em>Oklahoma</em> brief, “Medicare’s ‘Conditions of Participation’ for hospitals alone <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A146/322562/20240815142705829_Oklahoma%20v%20HHS%20Stay%20Opposition%20-%2024A146.pdf">span some 48 pages</a> in the Code of Federal Regulations.” All of those rules, plus countless other federal regulations for Medicare, Medicaid, and other programs, could cease to function overnight if the justices accept Oklahoma’s more radical argument. (Oklahoma’s second argument, which contends that the call-in rule is contrary to a different federal law, is less radical and more plausible than its first.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This fight over whether Title X grant recipients must provide some abortion-related information to patients who seek it will be familiar to anyone who closely follows abortion politics. In 1988, the Reagan administration forbade Title X grant recipients from providing any counseling on abortion, and the Supreme Court upheld the Reagan administration’s authority to do so in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/500/173/"><em>Rust v. Sullivan</em></a> (1991).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since then, the policy has sometimes <a href="https://www.ca10.uscourts.gov/sites/ca10/files/opinions/010111079171.pdf">changed depending on which party controls the White House</a>. The Reagan-era policy was eliminated during the Clinton administration, and then revived in 2019 by the Trump administration. Biden’s administration shifted the policy again during his first year in office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, the state of Oklahoma argues that the current administration exceeded its authority when it enacted a rule that is similar to the regulations that were in effect for most of the last several decades.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The huge stakes in the <em>Oklahoma</em> case, briefly explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Supreme Court has long held that Congress may place conditions on a federal grant program and that states must comply with those conditions if they wish to receive a grant. In <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/483/203/"><em>South Dakota v. Dole</em></a> (1987), however, the Court laid out a few limits on this power to impose conditions on grants, including a requirement these conditions must be unambiguous so that states may “exercise their choice knowingly, cognizant of the consequences of their participation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Rust</em> held that the federal statute governing Title X, which provides that “[n]one of the funds appropriated under this subchapter shall be used in programs where abortion is a method of family planning,” <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/500/173/">does not speak</a> to whether Title X programs may refer patients to other medical providers who do offer abortions. Thus, the law is “ambiguous” regarding such referrals, and the Court concluded that the Reagan administration could resolve this ambiguity by banning abortion-related referrals.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If that were all the statute said, Oklahoma would have a strong argument in its pending case before the Supreme Court. <em>Dole</em> ruled that conditions on federal grants must be unambiguous, and <em>Rust</em> ruled that Title X is ambiguous with respect to whether patients should be provided information about abortions. So the naked statute doesn’t unambiguously convey to Oklahoma that it must refer Title X patients to a call-in number if they need information about abortion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Title X statute also <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/42/300a-4">contains a provision</a> that states that “grants and contracts made under this subchapter shall be made in accordance with such regulations as the [Health and Human Services (HHS)] Secretary may promulgate,” and that Title X grants are “subject to such conditions as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate to assure that such grants will be effectively utilized for the purposes for which made.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, the statute unambiguously gives HHS the authority to write binding rules. And Oklahoma knew when it accepted a Title X grant that it was subject to those rules, including the Biden administration’s rule requiring grant recipients to provide the call-in number to patients.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oklahoma, however, argues that Congress <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/DocketPDF/24/24A146/321886/20240807153835634_Application%20-%20v4%20-%20Final%20-%202024.08.05.pdf">cannot delegate this kind of rulemaking power to a federal agency</a>. If it wants to impose a condition on a federal grant, Congress must write the exact terms of that condition into the statute itself.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The implications of this argument are breathtaking, as there are scads of agency-drafted rules governing federal grant programs. The Medicare rules mentioned in the Justice Department’s brief, for example, cover everything from <a href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-42/chapter-IV/subchapter-G/part-482/subpart-B/section-482.11">hospital licensure</a> to <a href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-42/chapter-IV/subchapter-G/part-482/subpart-B/section-482.13">grievances filed by patients</a> to the <a href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-42/chapter-IV/subchapter-G/part-482/subpart-B/section-482.12">corporate governance of hospitals receiving Medicare funds</a>. The rules governing Medicaid can be even more complicated. These are more vulnerable to a legal challenge under Oklahoma’s legal theory because Medicaid is administered almost entirely by states receiving federal grants.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oklahoma, in other words, is asking the Court to fundamentally alter how nearly every single aspect of hospital and health care administration and provision works in the United States — and that’s not even accounting for all the federal grant programs that are not health care-related.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is unfortunate, to say the least, that this issue arises in the context of an abortion dispute. About a year ago, the Supreme Court rejected a similar — and similarly radical — legal theory that would have <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/8/23754267/supreme-court-ketanji-brown-jackson-medicaid-health-hospital-talevski">rendered huge swaths of federal Medicaid law practically unenforceable</a>. The facts of that case, however, involved allegations of elder abuse by a nursing home and not the politically fraught issue of abortion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question in <em>Oklahoma</em> is whether this Court, with its 6-3 Republican supermajority, will show similar wisdom in an abortion-related case.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">If the justices are determined to rule in Oklahoma’s favor, there’s a way to do it without breaking Medicare and Medicaid</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oklahoma does raise a second legal argument in its suit that would allow it to receive a Title X grant, but that would not require the Court to throw much of the US health system into chaos. The Biden administration’s requirement that Title X providers must give patients seeking abortion information a call-in number arguably conflicts with a federal law called the Weldon Amendment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/108/plaws/publ447/PLAW-108publ447.pdf">Weldon Amendment</a> prohibits Title X funds from being distributed to government agencies that subject “any institutional or individual health care entity to discrimination on the basis that the health care entity does not provide, pay for, provide coverage of, or refer for abortions.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The three appellate judges who previously heard the <em>Oklahoma</em> case <a href="https://www.ca10.uscourts.gov/sites/ca10/files/opinions/010111079171.pdf">split on whether the Weldon Amendment prohibits the Biden administration’s rule</a>. Two judges concluded, among other things, that providing a patient with a phone number that will allow them to learn about abortion is not the same thing as referring a patient for an abortion, and thus that the Biden rule was permissible. One judge (who is, notably, a Biden appointee) disagreed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any event, Oklahoma’s Weldon Amendment argument gives this Supreme Court a way to rule against the Biden administration&#8217;s pro-abortion access policy without doing the kind of violence to Medicare and Medicaid contemplated by Oklahoma’s other argument. If the justices are determined to rule in Oklahoma’s favor, anyone who cares about maintaining a stable health system in the United States should root for the Court to take this less radical option.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The staggering death toll of scientific lies]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/368350/scientific-research-fraud-crime-jail-time" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368350</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T19:35:41Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T19:35:39Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Education" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You probably haven’t heard of cardiologist Don Poldermans, but experts who study scientific misconduct believe that thousands of people may be dead because of him.&#160; Poldermans was a prolific medical researcher at Erasmus Medical Center in the Netherlands, where he analyzed the standards of care for cardiac events after surgery, publishing a series of definitive [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A photo shows a metal statue of a blindfolded woman representing Justice, holding a metal scale, in front of a white stone column. " data-caption="Scientific fraud can have devastating consequences, including the loss of life. Should it come with criminal consequences?" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1494529981.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Scientific fraud can have devastating consequences, including the loss of life. Should it come with criminal consequences?</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">You probably haven’t heard of cardiologist Don Poldermans, but experts who study scientific misconduct believe that <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/larryhusten/2014/01/15/medicine-or-mass-murder-guideline-based-on-discredited-research-may-have-caused-800000-deaths-in-europe-over-the-last-5-years/">thousands of people may be dead</a> because of him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Poldermans was a prolific medical researcher at Erasmus Medical Center in the Netherlands, where he analyzed the standards of care for cardiac events after surgery, publishing a series of definitive studies from 1999 until the early 2010s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One crucial question he studied: Should you give patients a beta blocker, which lowers blood pressure, before certain surgeries? Poldermans’s research said yes. European medical guidelines (and to a lesser extent US guidelines) <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20068416/">recommended it accordingly</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem? Poldermans’s data <a href="https://cardiobrief.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/integrity-report-2012-10-english-translation.pdf">was reportedly<strong> </strong>fake</a>. A <a href="https://cardiobrief.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/integrity-report-2012-10-english-translation.pdf">2012 inquiry by Erasmus Medical School, his employer, into allegations of misconduct</a> found that he “used patient data without written permission, used fictitious data and… submitted to conferences [reports] which included knowingly unreliable data.” Poldermans <a href="https://retractionwatch.com/2011/11/17/breaking-news-prolific-dutch-heart-researcher-fired-over-misconduct-concerns/">admitted the allegations and apologized</a>, while stressing that the use of fictitious data was accidental.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After the revelations, a new meta-analysis was published in 2014, evaluating whether to use beta blockers before non-cardiac surgery. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3932762/">It found</a> that a course of beta blockers made it 27 percent more likely that someone would die within 30 days of their surgery. That is, the policy which Poldermans had recommended using falsified data, adopted in Europe on the basis of his research, was actually dramatically increasing the odds people would die in surgery.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Millions of surgeries were conducted across the US and Europe during the years from 2009 to 2013 when those misguided guidelines were in place. One provocative analysis from cardiologists Graham Cole and Darrel Francis estimated that there were <a href="https://drmalcolmkendrick.org/tag/don-poldermans/">800,000 deaths</a> compared to if the best practices had been established five years sooner. While that exact number is hotly contested, a 27 percent increase in mortality for a common procedure for years on end can add up to an extraordinary death toll.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I learned about the Poldermans case when I reached out to some scientific misconduct researchers, asking them a provocative question: Should scientific fraud be prosecuted?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unfortunately, fraud and misconduct in the scientific community isn’t nearly as rare as one might like to believe. We also know that the consequences of being caught are frequently underwhelming. It can take years to get a bad paper retracted, even if the flaws are readily apparent. Sometimes, scientists alleged to have falsified their data <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24107889/francesca-gino-lawsuit-harvard-dishonesty-researcher-academic-fraud">file frivolous lawsuits</a> against their peers who point it out, further silencing anyone who would speak out about bad data. And we know that this behavior can have high stakes, and can dramatically <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22776428/ivermectin-science-publication-research-fraud">affect treatment options for patients</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In cases where research dishonesty is literally killing people, shouldn’t it be appropriate to resort to the criminal justice system?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The question of whether research fraud should be a crime</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In some cases, research misconduct may be hard to distinguish from carelessness.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If a researcher fails to apply the appropriate statistical correction for multiple hypothesis testing, they will probably get some spurious results. In some cases, researchers are heavily incentivized to be careless in these ways by an academic culture that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/14/12016710/science-challeges-research-funding-peer-review-process">puts non-null results above all else</a> (that is, rewarding researchers for finding an effect even if it is not a methodologically sound one, while being unwilling to publish sound research if it finds no effect).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I’d argue it’s a bad idea to prosecute such behavior. It would produce a serious chilling effect on research, and likely make the scientific process slower and more legalistic — which also results in more deaths that could be avoided if science moved more freely.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So the conversation about whether to criminalize research fraud tends to focus on the most clear-cut cases: intentional falsification of data. Elisabeth Bik, a scientific researcher who studies fraud, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-01363-z">made a name for herself</a> by demonstrating that photographs of test results in many medical journals were <a href="https://www.vox.com/unexplainable/23945153/how-to-catch-a-scientific-fraud">clearly altered</a>. That’s not the kind of thing that can be an innocent mistake, so it represents something of a baseline for how often manipulated data is published.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While technically some scientific fraud could fall under existing statutes that prohibit lying on, say, a grant application, in practice scientific fraud is more or less never prosecuted. Poldermans eventually lost his job in 2011, but most of his papers weren’t even retracted, and he faced no further consequences.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in response to growing awareness of fraud’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/aug/09/scientific-misconduct-retraction-watch">frequency</a> and its harms, some scientists and scientific-fraud watchdogs have <a href="https://chris-said.io/2024/06/17/the-case-for-criminalizing-scientific-misconduct/">proposed changing that</a>. A new statute, narrowly tailored to scientific fakery, could make it clearer where to draw the line between carelessness and fraud.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question is whether legal consequences would actually help with our fraud problem. I asked Bik what she thought about proposals to criminalize the misconduct that she studied.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her reaction was that, while it’s not clear whether criminalization is the right approach, people should understand that currently there are almost no consequences for wrongdoers. “It’s maddening when you see people cheat,” she told me, “And even if it involves grant money from the NIH, there’s very little punishment. Even with people who have been caught cheating, the punishment is super light. You are not eligible to apply for new grants for the next year or sometimes three years. It’s very rare that people lose jobs over it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Why is that? Fundamentally, it’s a problem of incentives. It is embarrassing for institutions when one of their researchers commits misconduct, so they’d rather impose a mild penalty and not keep digging. There’s little incentive for anyone to get to the bottom of misconduct. “If the most serious consequence for speeding was a police officer saying ‘Don’t do that again,’ everyone would be speeding,” Bik told me. “This is the situation we have in science. Do whatever you want. If you get caught, it’ll take years to investigate.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In some ways, a legal statute isn’t the ideal solution. Courts are also guilty of taking years to deliver justice in complex cases. They also aren’t well suited to answering detailed scientific questions, and would almost certainly be relying on scientific institutions that conduct investigations — so what really matters is those institutions, not whether they’re attached to a court, a nonprofit, or to the NIH.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in sufficiently severe cases of misconduct, it does seem to me that it’d be a major advantage to have an institution outside academia at work on getting to the bottom of these cases. If well designed, a statute that allowed prosecution for scientific fraud could shift the overwhelming incentives to let misconduct go unpunished and move on.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there were ongoing investigations conducted by an outside agency (like a prosecutor), it would no longer be easiest for institutions to maintain their reputation by sweeping incidents of fraud under the rug. But the outside agency would not actually have to be a prosecutor; an independent scientific review board would probably also suffice, Bik said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, prosecution is a blunt tool. It might help provide accountability in cases where no one is incentivized to provide it — and I do think in cases of misconduct that lead to thousands of deaths, it would be a matter of justice. But it’s neither the only way to solve our fraud problem nor necessarily the best one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far, however, efforts to build institutions within the scientific community that police misconduct have had only limited success. At this point, I’d consider it a positive if there were efforts to allow external institutions to police misconduct as well.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, August 26, 3:30 pm:</strong> This story, originally published August 23, misstated the types of surgeries reviewed by Poldermans and affected by guidelines based on his false data; they were non-cardiac surgeries.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Amanda Lewellyn</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The surprisingly subdued resurrection of Abercrombie &#038; Fitch]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/consumerism/368168/abercrombie-fitch-retailers-fashion-revival" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368168</id>
			<updated>2024-08-26T18:46:31Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Consumerism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Stock market" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s bachelorette season in America. A couple of months ago, I was at one such party in Florida: nine women, one house, a zillion group activities to get dressed for. And something strange started to happen. Almost every time I complimented someone’s outfit — a cute jumpsuit or matching set — inevitably the response was: [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="An Abercrombie &amp; Fitch store in New York in 2023. | Stephanie Keith/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephanie Keith/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1793800848-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>An Abercrombie &amp; Fitch store in New York in 2023. | Stephanie Keith/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s bachelorette season in America.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A couple of months ago, I was at one such party in Florida: nine women, one house, a zillion group activities to get dressed for. And something strange started to happen. Almost every time I complimented someone’s outfit — a cute jumpsuit or matching set — inevitably the response was: “Thanks, it’s from Abercrombie.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wait, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/7Kkqc6NmMGnvH05ZnI6nlF" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Abercrombie &amp; Fitch</a>? The dark store at the mall that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/08/13/business/why-stores-smell-good-abercrombie-victorias-secret/index.html">reeked of cologne</a> and had salespeople who were hot and white and wearing practically nothing? What year is it?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back home in New York, I stumbled upon a real-life Abercrombie store and decided to investigate. The first thing I noticed was that it didn’t smell. Like anything. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, I was impressed by the clothes: pretty good quality, decent price, and styles that worked for the 86 weddings I’ll be attending in the next calendar year.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I bought an engagement party-appropriate dress, then headed up to Central Park for a softball game with some of my old colleagues. One of them noticed my shopping bag and informed me that I was not alone in my rediscovery of Abercrombie.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So many people are getting reacquainted with the brand that its stock quietly <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/hyunsoorim/2024/05/31/the-beloved-90s-fashion-brand-is-making-a-turnaround-even-beating-nvidia-over-the-past-year/">gained</a> 285 percent&nbsp;last year,&nbsp;making it the best-performing stock on the S&amp;P index. It even <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-12-29/abercrombie-s-300-surge-in-2023-beats-even-sizzling-hot-nvidia?sref=qYiz2hd0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">beat</a> out AI chipmaker Nvidia. And it’s not like it’s just a meme stock: Abercrombie has generated <a href="https://stockanalysis.com/stocks/anf/revenue/">more than $4 billion</a> in revenue in the last fiscal year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, how did Abercrombie pull off its stunning renaissance — seemingly under the radar?&nbsp;</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9428824883" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">“Are we exclusionary? Absolutely.”</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not Abercrombie’s first comeback. One of the original American clothing brands, <a href="https://americanhistory.si.edu/explore/stories/20th-century-camping-abercrombie-fitch-catalog">founded in 1892</a>, it dressed everyone from President Theodore Roosevelt to Amelia Earhart. But the company’s star turned and it ultimately <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1976/08/07/archives/abercrombie-fitch-in-bankruptcy-step-abercrombie-fitch-planning-to.html">filed for bankruptcy</a> in 1976.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, in 1988, it was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1988/01/16/business/company-news-abercrombie-chain-bought.html">acquired</a> by The Limited, the owner of big mall clothing brands like Victoria’s Secret. It put a new CEO in charge, Mike Jeffries. Jeffries turned Abercrombie into a mall staple by targeting a new teenage clientele with American prep and a new, hypersexualized flavor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In every school there are the cool and popular kids, and then there are the not-so-cool kids,” Jeffries <a href="https://www.salon.com/2006/01/24/jeffries/">told</a> Salon in 2006. “Candidly, we go after the cool kids … A lot of people don’t belong [in our clothes], and they can’t belong. Are we exclusionary? Absolutely.”&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-149832839.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.206537304612,100,77.586925390776" alt=" " title=" " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A woman takes a photo of a group of shirtless male models outside an  Abercrombie &amp; Fitch flagship store that was preparing to open in Hong Kong in 2012. | Laurent Fievet/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Laurent Fievet/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">That exclusionary ethos worked in some ways — Abercrombie &amp; Fitch became an iconic part of culture, getting name-dropped in shows like <em>Friends</em>, for example. But in much bigger ways, it ran the company directly into hot water. Over. And. Over. Again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2002, it sold thongs emblazoned with phrases like “eye candy” and “wink wink” —&nbsp;in the <a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-2002-may-23-na-thong23-story.html">children’s section</a>. Later that year, it dropped a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2002/04/20/business/abercrombie-reacts-to-t-shirt-protests.html">T-shirt</a> designed to look like advertising for a Chinese laundromat, with the racist slogan “Two Wongs can make it white.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There was even a Supreme Court case. Samantha Elauf, a Muslim woman, alleged that the company refused to hire her because her hijab didn&#8217;t comply with their “looks policy” for employees. (“This is really easy,” Justice Antonin Scalia <a href="https://www.oyez.org/cases/2014/14-86">said</a> when he handed down a victory for Elauf in 2015.)&nbsp;<br><br>This was all happening in contrast to a growing <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/catherineerdly/2023/12/19/is-body-positivity-actually-changing-the-clothing-industry/">body positivity movement</a>. Eventually, the dissonance —&nbsp;combined with economic fallout from the Great Recession —&nbsp;proved to be too much. Its share price dwindled until finally, in 2016, Abercrombie became America’s <a href="https://money.cnn.com/2016/02/24/pf/worst-retailers-customer-satisfaction/index.html">most hated retailer</a>. RIP.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-103256719.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.613273748238,100,74.773452503523" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A model stands at the entrance of an Abercrombie &amp; Fitch store in New York in 2010 in a photo that shows how the brand once marketed to young shoppers with an almost embarrassing amount of skin. | Jin Lee/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jin Lee/Bloomberg via Getty Images" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Abercrom-back&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After the brand’s fall from grace, Abercrombie’s C-suite got a makeover. Jeffries was <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/abercrombie-fitch-mike-jeffries-trafficking-operation-lawsuit/">pushed out</a> in the 2010s, and new executives took his place. Their first priority was undoing some of the damage Abercrombie had wrought on its image in the aughts.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The old Abercrombie (in)famously <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2013/05/23/living/abercrombie-attractive-and-fat/index.html">refused</a> to sell clothes in sizes larger than L, or above a women’s size 10. The new Abercrombie goes up to size 32. Now, instead of overly sexy photoshoots, its ads are more tasteful, featuring models more representative of a broader range of potential customers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The new Abercrombie is also <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91010945/how-abercrombie-went-from-americas-most-hated-retailer-to-a-gen-z-favorite">less focused</a> on reacting to fashion trends and appeasing high school hierarchies, and more on equipping a new generation of 20-somethings with basic, quality pieces appropriate for weddings and work, well-fitting denim, and sturdy workout apparel.&nbsp;<br><br>“They’re using a lot of higher-end materials like wool and cotton and cashmere, and there’s also been a lot of focus on fit,” Fast Company senior writer Elizabeth Segran <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/7Kkqc6NmMGnvH05ZnI6nlF?si=fb9232bb9c6f4e50">told <em>Today, Explained</em></a>. “This is all really important because this is all happening in the context of fast fashion. And the fast fashion world is famously about making clothes as cheap as possible and making them so trendy that you can throw them out after a few wears. This is very distinctly going against all of that.”&nbsp;<br><br>Segran says there’s a reason you haven&#8217;t seen big, splashy ads announcing Abercrombie’s return. Rather than do a whole public reintroduction to the brand — which probably would have required some sort of acknowledgment of its sordid history — Abercrombie executives have said they wanted the products to lead.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They wanted customers to feel like they had discovered the new Abercrombie for themselves. So they partnered with content creators on social media, opened up new (scentless) stores in strategic locations, and relied on word of mouth to do the rest.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1801107940.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.75214828329,100,78.49570343342" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="An Abercrombie &amp; Fitch store today: muted colors, lots of light, absolutely no underdressed young men. And no obnoxious scent. | Yuki Iwamura/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Yuki Iwamura/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“Our plan is to go from being the best-kept secret in fashion to their favorite brand,” Abercrombie’s head of merchandising Carey Krug <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91010945/how-abercrombie-went-from-americas-most-hated-retailer-to-a-gen-z-favorite">told</a> Fast Company.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far, it’s working.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Segran told <em>Today, Explained </em>that this revival is not just an Abercrombie story. Legacy retailers like J. Crew and Gap — which have struggled to compete with younger direct-to-consumer brands like Everlane and Reformation —&nbsp;could learn a thing or two from Abercrombie’s revival.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Abercrombie’s story shows us that if a brand has this long history and a place in American retail history, it can come back.”<br><br><em>This story&nbsp;originally appeared&nbsp;in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today, Explained</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jack Titus</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How would we even know if AI went rogue?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/368537/ai-artificial-intelligence-capabilities-risks-warning-system" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368537</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T20:41:52Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tech policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the frontier of artificial intelligence advances at a breakneck pace, the US government is struggling to keep up. Working on AI policy in Washington, DC, I can tell you that before we can decide how to govern frontier AI systems, we first need to see them clearly. Right now, we’re navigating in a fog. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An emergency road sign surrounded by orange cones on a deserted strip of highway reads “A.I. ahead.”" data-caption="Congress needs to understand artificial intelligence capabilities better in order to mitigate future risks." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1479589931.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Congress needs to understand artificial intelligence capabilities better in order to mitigate future risks.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">As the frontier of artificial intelligence advances at a breakneck pace, the US government is struggling to keep up. Working on AI policy in Washington, DC, I can tell you that before we can decide how to govern frontier AI systems, we first need to see them clearly. Right now, we’re navigating in a fog.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My role as an AI policy fellow at the Federation of American Scientists (FAS) involves developing bipartisan ideas for improving the government’s ability to analyze current and future systems. In this work, I interact with experts across government, academia, civil society, and the AI industry. What I’ve learned is that there is no broad consensus on how to manage the potential risks of breakthrough AI systems without hampering innovation. However, there is broad agreement that the US government needs <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2108.12427">better information about AI companies’ technologies and practices</a>, and more capacity to respond to both catastrophic and more insidious risks as they arise. Without detailed knowledge of the latest AI capabilities, policymakers can’t effectively assess whether current regulations are sufficient to prevent misuses and accidents, or whether companies need to take additional steps to safeguard their systems. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When it comes to <a href="https://www.nrc.gov/reading-rm/doc-collections/fact-sheets/oversight.html">nuclear power</a> or <a href="https://www.faa.gov/about/office_org/headquarters_offices/avs">airline safety</a>, the federal government demands timely information from the private companies in those industries to ensure the public’s welfare. We need the same insight into the emerging AI field. Otherwise, this information gap could leave us vulnerable to unforeseen risks to national security or lead to overly restrictive policies that stifle innovation.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Progress in Washington</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Encouragingly, Congress is making gradual progress in improving the government’s ability to understand and respond to novel developments in AI. Since ChatGPT’s debut in late 2022, AI has been taken more seriously by legislators from both parties and both chambers on Capitol Hill. The House formed a <a href="https://fedscoop.com/house-leaders-announce-new-bipartisan-ai-task-force/">bipartisan AI task force</a> with a directive to balance innovation, national security, and safety. Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) organized a series of <a href="https://www.techpolicy.press/us-senate-ai-insight-forum-tracker/">AI Insight Forums</a> to collect outside input and build a foundation for AI policy. These events informed the bipartisan Senate AI working group’s <a href="https://www.schumer.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Roadmap_Electronic1.32pm.pdf">AI Roadmap</a> that outlined areas of consensus, including “development and standardization of risk testing and evaluation methodologies and mechanisms” and an AI-focused Information Sharing and Analysis Center.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several bills have been introduced that would enhance information sharing about AI and bolster the government’s response capabilities. The Senate’s bipartisan <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/senate-bill/3312/text">AI Research, Innovation, and Accountability Act</a> would require companies to submit risk assessments to the Department of Commerce before deploying AI systems that may impact critical infrastructure, criminal justice, or biometric identification. Another bipartisan bill, the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/senate-bill/4769/text/is?overview=closed&amp;format=txt">VET AI Act</a> (which FAS <a href="https://www.hickenlooper.senate.gov/press_releases/hickenlooper-capito-introduce-bipartisan-bill-to-create-guidelines-for-third-party-audits-of-ai/#:~:text=The%20VET%20AI%20Act%20would,in%20compliance%20with%20established%20guardrails.">endorsed</a>), proposes a system for independent evaluators to audit and verify AI companies&#8217; compliance with established guidelines, similar to existing practices in the financial industry. These bills cleared the Senate Commerce committee in July and may receive a floor vote in the Senate before the 2024 election. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There has also been promising progress in other parts of the world. In May, the UK and Korean governments announced that most of the world’s leading AI companies agreed to a new set of <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/frontier-ai-safety-commitments-ai-seoul-summit-2024/frontier-ai-safety-commitments-ai-seoul-summit-2024">voluntary safety commitments</a> at the AI Seoul Summit. These pledges include identifying, assessing, and managing risks associated with developing the most advanced AI models, drawing on companies’ <a href="https://fas.org/publication/scaling-ai-safety/">Responsible Scaling Policies</a> pioneered in the past year that provide a roadmap for future risk mitigation as AI capabilities develop. The AI developers also agreed to provide transparency on their approaches to frontier AI safety, including “sharing more detailed information which cannot be shared publicly with trusted actors, including their respective home governments.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, these commitments lack enforcement mechanisms and standardized reporting requirements, making it difficult to assess whether or not companies are adhering to them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even some industry leaders have voiced support for increased government oversight. Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, <a href="https://time.com/6280372/sam-altman-chatgpt-regulate-ai/">emphasized this point</a> early last year in testimony before Congress, stating, “I think if this technology goes wrong, it can go quite wrong, and we want to be vocal about that. We want to work with the government to prevent that from happening.” Dario Amodei, CEO of Anthropic, has taken that sentiment one step further; after the publication of Anthropic’s <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/anthropics-responsible-scaling-policy">Responsible Scaling Policy</a>, he <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/uk-ai-safety-summit">expressed his hope</a> that governments would turn elements from the policy into “well-crafted testing and auditing regimes with accountability and oversight.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite these encouraging signs from Washington and the private sector, significant gaps remain in the US government’s ability to understand and respond to rapid advancements in AI technology. Specifically, three critical areas require immediate attention: protections for independent research on AI safety, early warning systems for AI capabilities improvements, and comprehensive reporting mechanisms for real-world AI incidents. Addressing these gaps is key for protecting national security, fostering innovation, and ensuring that AI development advances the public interest.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">A safe harbor for independent AI safety research</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AI companies often discourage or even <a href="https://crfm.stanford.edu/2024/04/08/aups.html">threaten to ban</a> researchers who identify safety flaws from using their products, creating a chilling effect on essential independent research. This leaves the public and policymakers in the dark about possible dangers from widely used AI systems, including threats to US national security. Independent research is vital because it provides an external check on the claims made by AI developers, helping to identify risks or limitations that may not be apparent to the companies themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One significant proposal to address this issue is that companies should offer <a href="https://fas.org/publication/safe-harbor-for-ai-researchers/">legal safe harbor and financial incentives for good-faith AI safety and trustworthiness research</a>. Congress could offer “<a href="https://www.ajl.org/bugs">bug</a>” <a href="https://www.anthropic.com/news/model-safety-bug-bounty">bounties</a> to AI safety researchers who identify vulnerabilities and extend legal protections to experts studying AI platforms, similar to those proposed for social media researchers in the <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/senate-bill/1876/text">Platform Accountability and Transparency Act</a>. In an <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/03/05/ai-research-letter-openai-meta-midjourney/">open letter</a> earlier this year, over 350 leading researchers and advocates called for companies to give such protections for safety researchers, but <a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=dLojMSgSFW&amp;referrer=%5BAuthor%20Console%5D(%2Fgroup%3Fid%3DICML.cc%2F2024%2FConference%2FAuthors%23your-submissions)">no company</a> has yet done so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With these protections and incentives, thousands of American researchers could be empowered to stress-test AI systems, allowing real-time assessments of AI products and systems. The US AI Safety Institute has included similar protections for AI researchers in its draft guidelines on “<a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.800-1.ipd.pdf">Managing Misuse Risk for Dual-Use Foundation Models</a>,” and Congress should consider codifying these best practices.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">An early warning system for AI capability improvements</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The US government’s approach to identifying and responding to frontier AI systems’ potentially dangerous capabilities is limited and unlikely to keep pace with new AI capabilities if they continue to rapidly increase. The knowledge gap within the industry leaves policymakers and security agencies unprepared to address emerging AI risks. Worse, the potential consequences of this asymmetry will compound over time as AI systems become both more risky and more widely used. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Establishing an <a href="https://fas.org/publication/an-early-warning-system-for-ai/">AI early warning system</a> would equip the government with the information it needs to get ahead of threats from artificial intelligence. Such a system would create a formalized channel for AI developers, researchers, and other relevant parties to report <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2023-11-01/pdf/2023-24283.pdf#page=4">AI capabilities</a> that have both civilian and military applications (such as <a href="https://openai.com/index/building-an-early-warning-system-for-llm-aided-biological-threat-creation/">uplift for biological weapons research</a> or <a href="https://apnews.com/article/microsoft-generative-ai-offensive-cyber-operations-3482b8467c81830012a9283fd6b5f529">cyber offense</a>) to the government. The Commerce Department’s Bureau of Industry and Security could serve as an information clearinghouse, receiving, triaging, and forwarding these reports to other relevant agencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This proactive approach would provide government stakeholders with up-to-date information about the latest AI capabilities, enabling them to assess whether current regulations are sufficient or whether new safeguards are needed. For instance, if advancements in AI systems posed an increased risk of biological weapons attacks, relevant parts of the government would be promptly alerted, allowing for a rapid response to safeguard the public’s welfare.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Reporting mechanisms for real-world AI incidents</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The US government currently lacks a comprehensive understanding of adverse incidents where AI systems have caused harm, hindering its ability to identify patterns of risky use, assess government guidelines, and respond to threats effectively. This blind spot leaves policymakers ill-equipped to craft timely and informed response measures.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Establishing a voluntary national <a href="https://fas.org/publication/establishing-an-ai-incident-reporting-system/">AI incident reporting hub</a> would create a standardized channel for companies, researchers, and the public to confidentially report AI incidents, including system failures, accidents, misuse, and potential hazards. This hub would be housed at the National Institute of Standards and Technology, leveraging existing expertise in incident reporting and standards-setting while avoiding mandates; this will encourage collaborative industry participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Combining this real-world data on adverse AI incidents with forward-looking capabilities reporting and researcher protections would enable the government to develop better informed policy responses to emerging AI issues and further empower developers to better understand the threats.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The path forward</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These three proposals strike a balance between oversight and innovation in AI development. By incentivizing independent research and improving government visibility into AI capabilities and incidents, they could support both safety and technological advancement. The government could foster public trust and potentially accelerate AI adoption across sectors while preventing the regulatory backlash that could follow preventable high-profile incidents. Policymakers would be able to craft targeted regulations that address specific risks — such as AI-enhanced cyber threats or potential misuse in critical infrastructure — while preserving the flexibility needed for continued innovation in fields like health care diagnostics and climate modeling.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Passing legislation in these areas requires bipartisan cooperation in Congress. Stakeholders from industry, academia, and civil society must advocate for and engage in this process, offering their expertise to refine and implement these proposals. There is a short <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/chuck-schumer-eyes-opportunities-pass-deepfake-ai-bills-2024-elections-rcna164915">window for action</a> in what remains of the 118th Congress, with the potential to attach some AI transparency policies to must-pass legislation like the National Defense Authorization Act. The clock is ticking, and swift, decisive action now could set the stage for better AI governance for years to come.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Imagine a future in which our government has the tools to understand and responsibly guide AI development and a future in which we can harness AI’s potential to solve grand challenges while safeguarding against risks. This future is within our grasp — but only if we act now to clear the fog and sharpen our collective vision of how AI is developed and used. By improving our collective understanding and oversight of AI, we increase our chances of steering this powerful technology toward beneficial outcomes for society.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Umair Irfan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Democrats aren’t talking much about one of their biggest issues]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368706/kamala-harris-dnc-climate-change-policy-poll" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368706</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T21:48:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Climate change remains a major platform issue for Democrats, but you’d hardly know it listening to the hours of speeches at the Democratic National Convention last week in Chicago.&#160; Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting her party’s nomination for president, gave a brief nod to the fundamental freedom to “live free from the pollution that fuels [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris standing and speaking at a lectern flanked by flags in front of a blue backdrop that says Leaders Summit on Climate." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Al Drago/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1313836905.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Climate change remains a major <a href="https://democrats.org/where-we-stand/party-platform/combating-the-climate-crisis-and-pursuing-environmental-justice/">platform issue for Democrats</a>, but you’d hardly know it listening to the hours of speeches at the Democratic National Convention last week in Chicago.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris, accepting her party’s nomination for president, gave a brief nod to the fundamental freedom to “live free from the pollution that fuels the climate crisis.”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">“Many other fundamental freedoms are at stake…the freedom to breathe clean air and drink clean water and live free from the pollution that fuels the climate crisis.” —<a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHarris?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@KamalaHarris</a> is fighting for your freedom <a href="https://t.co/q81kHmEl9A">pic.twitter.com/q81kHmEl9A</a></p>&mdash; Climate Power (@ClimatePower) <a href="https://twitter.com/ClimatePower/status/1826817665492553803?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 23, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet even after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/23969523/climate-change-cop28-paris-1-5-c-uae-2023-record-warm">hottest year on record</a> and following a wave of disasters <a href="https://www.climatecentral.org/report/hurricane-beryl">worsened by rising average temperatures</a>, climate change received just a few passing mentions from a <a href="https://x.com/sunrisemvmt/status/1826792372551754000">handful of speakers</a> on the main stage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s all in stark contrast to the last presidential campaign. In 2019, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/3/20847535/cnn-climate-town-hall-2020-presidential-democrats">CNN gave seven hours of airtime</a> to Democratic presidential hopefuls just to talk about their plans to address climate change. Harris put out <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/4/20847387/kamala-harris-2020-climate-change-policy">her own detailed</a> plan to address environmental disparities and hold polluters accountable for their greenhouse gas emissions, drawing on her record as a prosecutor. The eventual nominee and winner Joe Biden made addressing climate change a <a href="https://www.vox.com/22242572/biden-climate-change-plan-explained">tentpole of his campaign</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/362478/joe-biden-climate-change-legacy">his time in office</a>. In particular, Biden signed the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23281757/whats-in-climate-bill-inflation-reduction-act">Inflation Reduction Act</a>, which he described as “the biggest step forward on climate ever.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of the reason for the minimal mentions of climate is the nature of the race itself. <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">President Biden dropped out of the running</a> just over a month ago, leaving little time for Harris and other Democrats to flesh out a distinct, detailed agenda on many issues, including climate, so there’s less to talk about.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lack of a primary also changes Harris’s incentives. In the 2020 primary, Harris had to try to distinguish herself from a crowded field of primary candidates. Now, Harris only needs to draw a contrast with the Republican presidential nominee Donald Trump, who has <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/trump-has-big-plans-for-climate-and-energy-policy-but-can-he-implement-them/">promised to boost fossil fuel production</a> and undo support for clean energy.&nbsp;He used <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/04/24/politics/fact-check-trump-sea-levels-ocean-climate-change/index.html">made-up numbers</a> to downplay the consequences of climate change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s another reason why Harris isn’t emphasizing climate change in the campaign: The topic is spurring fewer voters than before, and for those who are motivated by it, the choice is clear. “Very few voters say this issue is determinative to their presidential vote this year,” <a href="https://www.monmouth.edu/directory/profiles/pdmurray/">Patrick Murray</a>, who leads the Polling Institute at Monmouth University, wrote in an email. “Among this small group, they have a clear choice in the race even if the issue isn’t being discussed. Their position seems to be that Democrats have to win this election first and then we’ll push the issue.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Climate change is not the defining issue it was just a few years ago</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the last presidential election, climate change has dropped as a priority for voters in general and Democrats in particular. “We’ve seen a big dip in concerns about climate change since 2020,” Murray said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-23-at-2.32.48 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.1513961605585,100,81.697207678883" alt="Graph of polling on climate change." title="Graph of polling on climate change." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Concern about climate change has declined in the US since the last presidential election. | Monmouth University" data-portal-copyright="Monmouth University" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Most Americans do think that climate change is a real concern, but the urgency around it has declined. According to a poll conducted in April, Monmouth University found that 46 percent of Americans thought of climate change as a “very serious” issue, down from 56 percent in 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Republicans, climate change consistently <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/03/01/how-republicans-view-climate-change-and-energy-issues/">ranks as a low concern</a>, if it registers at all, and for Democrats, it has <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/362478/joe-biden-climate-change-legacy">slid down the list of priorities</a> as issues like the economy and immigration have climbed up. “For Democrats, there are multiple issues that compete for their highest attention. This includes things like gun violence, health care affordability, racial inequality, education, and, of course, inflation,” said <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/staff/alec-tyson/">Alec Tyson</a>, associate director at the Pew Research Center. “That was an issue that maybe was not on the public radar a couple years ago, but it is now.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Support for climate policies, such as promoting more wind and solar energy, remains high across the board, but it has declined since 2020 as well, with the sharpest drops among Republicans.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-23-at-2.36.26 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,28.272601750808,100,43.454796498384" alt="Graph of support for renewable energy. " title="Graph of support for renewable energy. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Americans generally favor clean energy, but support is declining. | Pew Research Center" data-portal-copyright="Pew Research Center" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For Democrats, the key fissure that’s emerged is how quickly to shift the US economy from fossil fuels to renewable sources. Tyson said that Pew’s polling shows there’s “almost a unanimous belief” in the transition to clean energy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We asked this follow-up question, do you think we should essentially break with fossil fuels entirely and rely solely on renewables, or do you think that fossil fuel should still be part of a mix, even though we prioritize renewables?” Tyson said. “That’s really about a 50-50 divide within the Democratic Party.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That divide has manifested in Democratic policies over the past four years. The Biden administration has set a goal of <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-harris-administration-releases-first-ever-blueprint-decarbonize-americas">net-zero emissions from the energy sector by 2035</a> and imposed <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24106924/epa-vehicle-emissions-carbon-pollution-climate-ev-hybrid">new vehicle pollution regulations</a> that could make more than half of new cars sold electric in the next decade. Biden also signed into law <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/7/28/23281757/whats-in-climate-bill-inflation-reduction-act">the largest investments to address climate change in US history</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the Biden White House has also presided over the country’s rise to becoming the <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24098983/biden-oil-production-climate-fossil-fuel-renewables">world’s largest oil and gas producer</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/22/icymi-biden-to-release-1-million-barrels-of-gasoline-to-reduce-prices-at-the-pump-ahead-of-july-4/">bragged about tapping the strategic petroleum reserve</a> to keep gasoline prices low.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These policies didn’t yield many dividends for Biden among voters, with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/27/climate/biden-climate-campaign.html">few who are even aware</a> of legislation like the Inflation Reduction Act and its provisions to deploy wind turbines, solar panels, and electric vehicle charging stations. Even <a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2024-05-07/biden-climate-bill-young-voters">young voters</a>, who typically rank climate change as a higher-tier concern, didn’t give much credit to Biden’s environmental bona fides before he dropped out. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So for the Democrats onstage at the convention, there wasn’t much upside to talking about global warming. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Kamala’s California crew is coming</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, there’s more to a political convention than the main stage during primetime. Aaron McCall, the federal advocacy coordinator at California Environmental Voters, said that climate change was still a major topic in the side rooms dedicated to discussing issues like LGBTQ rights, vulnerable populations, and economics. In addition, climate change and the energy transition are critical elements in other high-priority issues for Democrats: High gasoline prices <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/inflation-cpi-consumer-price-index-march-2024/">contribute to inflation</a>, more extreme natural disasters are <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/articles/housing-market-2023:-natural-disasters-will-make-affordability-crisis-even-more-dire">raising housing costs</a>, the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/jobs-us-energy-grew-38-2022-led-by-work-clean-energy-2023-06-28/">clean energy sector is driving job growth</a>, and so on.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In all of the caucus meetings I went to, climate comes up,” McCall said from the convention. “Because those communities are the frontline communities, and they&#8217;re being impacted.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The DNC also provided some hints as to who would join Harris’s team or have her ear if she moves into the White House next year. As a former attorney general in California, Harris has a deep bench of allies who have worked on climate policies. California in recent years has passed laws demanding <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23916295/california-climate-change-greenhouse-emissions-disclosure-risk-business-newsom">companies publish their greenhouse gas emissions</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/23320166/california-gasoline-ban-electric-vehicle-car-diesel-climate">banning the sale of new gasoline- and diesel-powered cars and trucks by 2035</a>. Harris herself oversaw an <a href="https://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-exxon-global-warming-20160120-story.html">investigation into Exxon Mobil’s statements</a> about the oil company’s contributions to climate change. These personnel will shape her policies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a large California presence — Gov. Newsom, Lt. Gov. Kounalakis, Sen. Padilla,” McCall said. “California activists and organizational leaders, as we&#8217;re coming to talk about Kamala Harris, our next president, we&#8217;re also talking about the priorities and the issues that we care about, especially climate.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How much will climate change matter in the runup to the election? Given the polls, it’s unlikely to alter anyone’s choice of candidate, though it could convince a few more people to get to the ballot box. “Within the Democratic coalition, it has more potential to operate as a turnout issue,” Tyson said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But since the outcome of the election could put the <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/interactive-chart-shows-changes-worlds-top-10-emitters">world’s second-largest greenhouse gas emitter</a> on a radically different course, it definitely matters for the climate.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I changed my mind about volunteering]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/368201/volunteer-charity-donations-systemic-change-activism-nonprofits-loneliness-philanthropy" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=368201</id>
			<updated>2024-08-23T15:42:49Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-26T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Features" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last fall, a reader asked me what they could really do, as one person, to aid people living on the streets. “I often feel helpless to enact change,” they wrote. I&#8217;d been covering homelessness in America and knew that even the sprawling support organizations that have been working on outreach for decades had failed to [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/EleniKalorkoti_Vox-Volunteering.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Last fall, a reader asked me what they could really do, as one person, to aid people living on the streets. “I often feel helpless to enact change,” they wrote.<br><br>I&#8217;d been covering homelessness in America and knew that even the sprawling support organizations that have been working on outreach for decades had failed to end the crisis. My mind immediately went to systemic solutions, like voting for candidates who prioritize building more housing, or supporting efforts to loosen zoning codes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when I called experts, their answers surprised me. Some of our ideas overlapped, but <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/25/24010207/homeless-shelter-winter-housing-volunteer-donation">many of their suggestions</a> were ones I had admittedly not entertained: passing out socks or hand-warmers, donating items like sleeping bags to local shelters, or giving office supplies and bus passes to nonprofits serving unhoused people.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The reporting left me uneasy. Why did I think only about structural change and disregard more immediate help? And why don’t <em>I</em> do more of those day-to-day charitable things, or know many people who do, either?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I did growing up. I have clear memories of bagging meals at food pantries, of cleaning up parks, of Walking for the Cure. I sold lemonade for Darfur and baked brownies for victims of Katrina. In Hebrew school, I learned about giving <em>tzedakah, </em>a form of charity, and our obligation to “repair the world.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But over time, those childhood activities started to look, well, childish. My coming of age in the 2010s coincided with critiques of individual action that were gaining prominence in media, politics, and academia — overlapping with a growing national focus on inequality and the climate crisis. It was the era of Occupy Wall Street and Bernie Sanders’ 2016 presidential campaign, and our whole country grew more fluent in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/06/opinion/abolish-billionaires-tax.html">rebukes of billionaires</a> and plutocracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Different arguments began to emerge: Volunteering, donating, and modifying one’s personal behavior were, at best, unproductive; at worst, they were harmful distractions from the change we really need. Be wary of those tote-bag shoppers at Whole Foods, championing recycling and reducing one’s carbon footprint. Didn’t they know that BP <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/23/big-oil-coined-carbon-footprints-to-blame-us-for-their-greed-keep-them-on-the-hook">coined the idea</a> of the “carbon footprint” to shift blame off its own oil production? Didn’t they understand that “<a href="https://www.dissentmagazine.org/blog/oprah-is-not-your-friend-a-qa-with-nicole-aschoff/">lifestyle politics</a>” was not the answer? Volunteering or bake sales didn’t threaten the status quo. They were what people in power <em>wanted</em> you to be doing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Real social change would come only from mass protest and collective pressure on governments and corporations. It didn’t hurt that such protests against poverty, police brutality, and rising global temperatures were also exciting, and seemed to offer young people better and more visible ways of making a difference.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a left-leaning college student, I was persuaded by leaders who warned that personal consumer choices would never amount to real social change. I also grew familiar with arguments by activists and intellectuals that nonprofits were too often complacent and even disincentivized to solve real problems, since doing so could threaten their own funding streams. Contributing my time and money to this “<a href="https://dukeupress.edu/the-revolution-will-not-be-funded">nonprofit industrial complex</a>” would be a mistake. Cutting checks wouldn’t change anything other than the balance in my savings account. For real social progress, we’d need systematic policy shifts, comprehensive legislation, and political power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since I received the reader’s note about homelessness last fall, I’ve been thinking more about the cost of all this cynicism. Were the arguments against individual action even helpful?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I also started to wonder if these beliefs contributed to the American “<a href="https://www.americansurveycenter.org/newsletter/americas-friendship-recession-is-weakening-civic-life/">friendship recession</a>” and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/5/3/23707936/surgeon-general-loneliness-epidemic-report">loneliness crisis</a> I kept hearing about. Back in 2000, in his book <a href="http://bowlingalone.com/"><em>Bowling Alone</em></a>, political scientist Robert Putnam highlighted declines in American church attendance, volunteering, civic associations, and team sports<em>; </em>it seems our “social cohesion” had only gotten worse since then. Gen Z and millennials volunteer at <a href="https://americorps.gov/about/our-impact/volunteering-civic-life">lower rates</a> than adults born in earlier generations, even though there is pretty overwhelming research that volunteering and donating makes <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/2020/07/29/volunteer-happy-mental-health/">people happier</a>, and boosts their <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_lookup?journal=J+Health+Soc+Behav&amp;title=Volunteer+work+and+well-being&amp;author=PA+Thoits&amp;author=LN+Hewitt&amp;volume=42&amp;issue=2&amp;publication_year=2001&amp;pages=115-131&amp;pmid=11467248&amp;doi=10.2307/3090173&amp;">self-esteem</a>, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5504679/">physical</a> <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5504679/">health</a>, and lifespan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not considered socially acceptable to tout personal benefits derived from charitable acts. It’d be unusual to hear volunteers say they’re going to a soup kitchen to improve their self-esteem. Perhaps this is because those gains suggest that there are more selfish motivations for behaviors we want to think of primarily as selfless. But wealthy philanthropists don’t seem shy about citing their self-interest, and <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/533633/the-givers-by-david-callahan/">often say</a> their humanitarian work leaves them with deep feelings of pleasure, optimism, and agency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It struck me as rather sad that those of us who are not billionaires may have convinced ourselves that volunteering or fundraising was mostly a waste of time.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When did I become someone who placed such exhausting value on optimizing<em> </em>my time, anyway? It suddenly felt much more arrogant than altruistic. Convenient, and uncaring.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps most importantly, had distancing ourselves from charity and service made the world a better place? Has it made my own life better?</p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">A few developments helped sour so many in my <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2018/03/01/the-generation-gap-in-american-politics/">left-leaning generation</a> on individual action.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The climate movement over the last 15 years played a leading role, rejecting solutions based on individual responsibility, and emphasizing the limits of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362224/environment-groups-meat-industry-lies-global-warming-climate-change-wwf">forgoing meat</a> or driving hybrid cars. Activists organized worldwide <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/9/20/20875523/youth-climate-strike-fridays-future-photos-global">youth climate strikes</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/11/7/9684012/keystone-pipeline-won">pipeline protests</a>, focusing the public’s attention on governments, oil companies, and fossil fuel lobbyists.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2156348551.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="People protesting in front of a Hilton with a banner that says “stop funding fossil fuels.”" title="People protesting in front of a Hilton with a banner that says “stop funding fossil fuels.”" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Climate advocates chant slogans during a protest demanding that the US Import Bank stop financing Fossil Fuels outside of the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) 2024 Annual Conference at the Washington Hilton on June 6, 2024, in Washington, DC. | Jemal Countess/Getty Images for Friends of the EarthJemal Countess/Getty Images for Friends of the Earth" data-portal-copyright="Jemal Countess/Getty Images for Friends of the EarthJemal Countess/Getty Images for Friends of the Earth" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In the 2016 presidential primary, where he <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/6/2/11818320/bernie-sanders-barack-obama-2008">captured over 70 percent of the Democratic youth vote</a>, Vermont Sen. Bernie Sanders took aim at “corporate polluters” driving the climate emergency. And perhaps no claim had more cultural influence than the widely shared, though <a href="https://www.politifact.com/factchecks/2022/jul/22/instagram-posts/no-100-corporations-do-not-produce-70-total-greenh/">misleading</a>, statistic that just 100 companies <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2017/jul/10/100-fossil-fuel-companies-investors-responsible-71-global-emissions-cdp-study-climate-change">were responsible for 70 percent of the world’s emissions</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There was also a largely successful effort to link curbing climate change with anti-capitalism. The 2011 Occupy protests got an even bigger boost following Thomas Piketty’s <em>Capital in the Twenty-First Century</em>, published in English in 2014. (<a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/4/8/5592198/the-short-guide-to-capital-in-the-21st-century">Vox called</a> it “the most important economics book of the year, if not the decade.”) Naomi Klein’s influential book <a href="https://thischangeseverything.org/"><em>This Changes Everything</em></a><em>, </em>also published in 2014,<em> </em>made the case that capitalism itself was an existential threat, that saving the planet would not be possible without overhauling the economic order.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In many ways, the growing emphasis on collective action felt clarifying, righteous, and long overdue. Student debt activists who emerged from Occupy helped millions of people process their feelings of shame and guilt over falling victim to predatory loans. New and <a href="https://www.cjr.org/special_report/the-abcs-of-jacobin-socialist-magazine.php">influential</a> left-wing outlets, like Jacobin, helped shape my generation’s consciousness and inspire us to demand more from those in power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At their best, these collectivist messages inspired hope, agency, and empathy — spelling out a concrete playbook for a more just planet. At their worst, though, they fueled despair, cynicism, and nihilism, promising a better world only if near-impossible political changes were made, and fast. Social and economic conditions were characterized as terribly as possible, to galvanize more people to upend them. Even those who weren’t necessarily looking to foment a revolution contributed to growing negative attitudes around individual action. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/8/8/23150496/effective-altruism-sam-bankman-fried-dustin-moskovitz-billionaire-philanthropy-crytocurrency#:~:text=I%20was%20fascinated%20by%20effective,moral%20seriousness%20of%20its%20practitioners.">Effective Altruist movement</a>, for example, argued that <em>most</em> charities were wasteful and ineffective, save for some rare exceptions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A <a href="https://iop.harvard.edu/sites/default/files/2023-05/Harvard%20IOP%20Youth%20Poll%20Spring%202023%20Toplines.pdf">recent Harvard Institute of Politics poll</a> found that young people are far more fearful than hopeful about the future: They worry about the moral direction of the country, don’t think their vote will make a real difference, and don’t volunteer for community service. It’s not that people today are choosing to protest instead of recycling; it’s that in our current environment, many people are doing neither. Despite all the attention on collective action and solidarity, many young adults are isolated and pessimistic about social change.</p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">I set a New Year’s resolution to volunteer. Here I was, a self-motivated journalist with professional research skills; finding charitable work I could donate my time to shouldn’t have been too hard.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it was more difficult than I expected. I’m not a member of a faith-based organization, neither my workplace nor my union organizes volunteer events, and my initial inquiries to nonprofits through <a href="http://volunteermatch.org">volunteermatch.org</a> went ignored. Lacking something I could easily plug into, I felt the poverty of my institutional connections in a new way. Robert Putnam would be nodding sagely, I thought.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, I stumbled on something called a “giving circle,” where people donate money collectively, mostly to local nonprofits. It resembled a book club but for philanthropy, and <a href="https://manyhandsdc.org/">I found one</a> focused on women and children in the DC area.<br><br>The full group, roughly 250 people, convenes annually to vote on donating their pooled membership funds, though those who want to be more involved can participate in subcommittees that review grant applications to help narrow down the list. Since I report on housing, I decided to join the housing subcommittee and our group of roughly 20 began meeting weekly on Tuesday nights. ​​It was unfamiliar work, but I appreciated it and all the women involved who took the reviews so seriously. I learned about extraordinary groups in the DC area, like <a href="https://togetherwebake.org/">Together We Bake</a>, which has trained hundreds of women in food production, and <a href="https://www.safespotfairfax.org/">SafeSpotDC</a>, which helps victims of child abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I also started reading books on volunteering, grasping for new ways to make sense of what I was feeling. I read in Arthur Brooks’s book, <a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/who-really-cares-the-surprising-truth-about-compassionate-conservatism-america-s-charity-divide-who-gives-who-doesn-t-and-why-i-arthur-c-brooks/12379882"><em>Who Really Cares</em></a>, that secular liberals like myself are stingier givers — less likely to donate to charity or volunteer than the general population, and much less likely to donate or volunteer than religious conservatives. The larger <a href="https://www.philanthropy.com/article/what-philanthropy-and-nonprofits-lose-as-religion-fades">decline in organized religion</a> loomed over this research.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For many Americans, political opinions are a substitute for personal checks,” Brooks writes. He even observed that proponents of income redistribution were less likely to give blood. “If everyone in the population gave at the same rate as government aid advocates, the supply would drop by about 30 percent,” he reported.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I squirmed when I read this. I’d never given blood. I found a study that said among first-time blood donors, the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18171329/">most frequently cited reason</a> for giving was “influence from a friend.” I couldn’t think of anyone encouraging me to donate, but that felt like a weak excuse.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around the same time, the Red Cross declared an <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/01/09/1223734878/red-cross-blood-shortage-national-blood-donor-month">emergency blood shortage</a>; donors had dropped by 40 percent over the last two decades. With Brooks’ book fresh in my mind, I decided to sign up. In early February, I went downtown to a blood donation center; the whole thing was relatively quick, and I felt happy when I left.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I caught a charitable bug. None of this was hard, I realized. I just hadn’t prioritized any of it. I found a local homeless organization that had an <a href="https://www.amazon.com/hz/wishlist/ls/JW4R9PLPVO3W/ref=cm_go_nav_hz">Amazon wish list</a> of needed items. I sent them tampons, pads, wipes, underwear, and hand-warmers, and chided myself for not having done such easy things sooner.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">The US has long been defined by its culture of volunteerism. When French philosopher Alexis de Tocqueville came to America in the 1830s he marveled at the many civic groups, later arguing that such volunteer organizations were integral to American democracy. Our bustling nonprofit sector would become a global symbol of entrepreneurialism and freedom.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s become common to say this vibrant civic fabric has since frayed. America is hanging out less. <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/02/america-decline-hanging-out/677451/">Our “social fitness” in shambles</a>. But over the last year, I’ve found plenty of data that complicates this narrative.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Volunteer rates have not fluctuated very much over the last 75 years. There were declines in the 1980s, then surges following the 9/11 attacks and again during the Trump presidency. Researchers <a href="https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/708941">find mixed evidence</a> that social capital is declining, though there’s more consensus that volunteering itself has become more episodic and time-limited than before. Nonprofit donations <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/359526/charitable-giving-generosity-crisis-report-americans-young">are down</a>, but crowdfunding contributions <a href="https://www.fundera.com/resources/crowdfunding-statistics">keep soaring</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some scholars say the <em>Bowling Alone </em>thesis was always missing the forest for the trees, that Putnam’s analysis privileged the kinds of activities white people of means were most likely to do.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You had the largest <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2006/05/02/us/02immig.html">immigration rights mobilization in 2006</a> ever, and then the white people were all reading Putnam,” Erica Kohl-Arenas, a professor of American Studies at the University of California, Davis, told me. “Numbers are not down in terms of people as part of associations, groups, or affiliated networks, but they might be down in terms of those who say, ‘I’m going to go look at the Yellow Pages to do five hours of service a week.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In contrast to the Yellow Pages form of service, so-called informal volunteering — meaning unpaid acts of service not coordinated through legal nonprofits — is harder to track, practiced more by communities of color, and almost never included in official counts of philanthropy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There’s lots of volunteering that doesn’t involve an organization,” said Mark Snyder, the director of the Center for the Study of the Individual and Society at the University of Minnesota. “When neighbors on a block shoot a message to your group text asking if someone can keep an eye on your kid, or bring over a meal, these things aren’t considered volunteering. But do you get paid for it? Do you get a sense of benefit by helping?”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Paul Schervish, a retired sociologist who directed the Center on Wealth and Philanthropy at Boston College, spent his career urging colleagues to take interpersonal and intra-family caregiving more seriously. He noted that while charitable giving is measured at <a href="https://www.nptrust.org/philanthropic-resources/charitable-giving-statistics/">roughly $500 billion</a> annually in the US, remittances to relatives in poorer countries exceed $100 billion per year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“None of those payments are included in what we talk about when we talk about philanthropy,” he told me. “Furthermore, Hispanics rank lower on charitable giving than other ethnic groups, but part of that is they are offering their homes up to family and living with extended family members so much more often, and carrying out these remittances. Care for each other, and even within your own family, is something that we don’t pay attention to.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Schervish argues that a proper understanding of philanthropy has always been more vast than the way Putnam and conventional theorists have sliced and diced it. It should encompass both informal aid for friends and family, and acts of service for people more distant from you. Look no further than the Greek word <em>philia</em>, he says, referring to non-romantic love, that shares the same root as our modern word philanthropy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“<em>Philia</em> or friendship love, for Aristotle, extends out in concentric circles from the family to the entire species,” Schervish has written. “Friendship love is a relation of mutual nourishment that leads to the virtuous flourishing of both parties.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or put differently, rather than debate whether acts of philanthropy are motivated by selfishness or selflessness, or whether it “counts” if it’s service for your aunt versus your neighbor versus a child in Africa, Schervish encourages thinking about donors, volunteers, and all caregivers as people who take action in connection with others, who “view others in need as familial.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">I took the point that the popular view on social cohesion may have oversights. But I couldn’t shake the feeling that people today are feeling more despair, especially younger people.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I know firsthand that many Americans are overwhelmed by negative news stories, which compound in exhausting ways. It’s become far too hard to know what’s true, and all the contradictory information <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2056305119872956">leads some to give up</a> trying to make sense of the world altogether. The proportion of readers <a href="https://reutersinstitute.politics.ox.ac.uk/digital-news-report/2023/dnr-executive-summary">who say they avoid news</a> is close to an all-time high.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Volunteering wouldn’t solve<em> </em>these problems, but given what we know about volunteering’s benefits, it seems it could certainly help. One University of Oxford researcher <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/15/health/employee-wellness-benefits.html">surveyed over 45,000 employees</a> whose companies offered wellness benefits like massage classes, coaching sessions, and mindfulness workshops. The only option that seemed to actually have a positive effect on well-being, the study found, were those jobs that provided workers with opportunities for charity or volunteering.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-177178879.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Volunteers help bag to-go meals at Catherdral Kitchen on August 21, 2013, in Camden, New Jersey. Cathedral Kitchen is a multi-service soup kitchen that has been serving the Camden homeless community since 1976. They serve between 300 and 600 dinners each night, as well as offering biweekly dental services, and periodic medical and legal services as well. | Andrew Burton/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Burton/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">A friend from my giving circle pointed out that the vast number of activities billed as self-care are pricey beauty treatments, boutique fitness classes, and other ways to “treat” ourselves. They all <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/350424/self-care-isolation-loneliness-epidemic">tend to advance the idea</a> that feeling better, and even simply feeling good, is found in helping oneself rather than each other.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, it can be harder for young people today to volunteer, Snyder, from the University of Minnesota, told me. “Young people are scrambling more than cohorts before to make a living, making ends meet through multiple jobs,” he said. “There are fewer discretionary hours available in a day.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I reached out to the <a href="https://mcc.gse.harvard.edu/">Making Caring Common Project</a> at Harvard’s Graduate School of Education. In 2014, <a href="https://mcc.gse.harvard.edu/reports/children-mean-raise">it found</a> that a large majority of American teenagers value personal achievement and happiness over caring for others, priorities they felt their parents also shared. Richard Weissbourd, who directs the center, told me they’ve re-surveyed youths several times over the last decade and found similar results. Teens consistently rank happiness and personal achievement most highly, and caring for others and concern for the common good at the bottom.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The irony of course is that by encouraging everyone to prioritize individual success and happiness, people are getting further from the kinds of activities and mental frameworks that drive satisfaction, fulfillment, community, and peace,” Weissbourd said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While most news stories on mental health tend to focus on youth struggling in middle and high school, Weissbourd said <a href="https://mcc.gse.harvard.edu/reports/on-edge">his research</a> has him worrying most about people ages 18 to 25, who he finds doing “twice as badly” as younger teens. “There’s a lot of apocalyptic thinking and not a lot of action there,” he said. “It’s like a deep tiredness, a feeling like people are in deep winter.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, though the climate crisis drove people like me to be more distrusting of calls for individual action, some climate leaders have been calling for a different approach. More activists now stress that systemic and individual change <a href="https://www.climateworks.org/blog/debunking-the-false-choice-between-individual-behavior-change-and-systems-change/">should be understood as two sides of the same coin</a>, and that individual action <a href="https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/yes-actually-individual-responsibility-essential-solving-climate-crisis">can be necessary</a> for building sustainable, transparent political movements.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“A fixation on system change alone opens the door to a kind of cynical self-absolution that divorces personal commitment from political belief,” Jason Mark, the editor of Sierra<em> </em>magazine, <a href="https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/yes-actually-individual-responsibility-essential-solving-climate-crisis">wrote in 2019</a>. “This is its own kind of false consciousness, one that threatens to create a cheapened climate politics incommensurate with this urgent moment.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his book <a href="https://cep.org/giving-done-right/"><em>Giving Done Right</em></a>, Phil Buchanan, the president of the Center for Effective Philanthropy, refers to a longstanding debate over whether it’s useful for donors to spend money on alleviating effects of problems, rather than attacking the problems’ underlying causes. Philanthropy certainly has <a href="https://www.foundationlaunch.com/case-studies/john-dorr-striping-the-nations-highways">some great victories</a> in funding “root” solutions, but Buchanan urges against the mentality that only permanently eradicating a problem is worth doing. “You shouldn’t assume that a focus on roots is necessarily superior,” he writes. “Trimming branches is also important.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a way, it can feel safe to distrust the value of individual action. Being wary of philanthropy and charitable groups that promise to better the world resonates with the skepticism I’ve been trained to have, professionally and culturally. It also allows me to avoid making sacrifices; there’s no real vulnerability or bets required.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as time goes on, and as I think about the family I <a href="https://www.vox.com/features/23979357/millennials-motherhood-dread-parenting-birthrate-women-policy">might one day raise</a>, I’m coming to appreciate the value of letting go and taking gambles on hope, as long as they point generally in the moral direction I want to go.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With all these questions swirling in my head, I cold-emailed a local rabbi. She offered to meet and pointed me to a story in Exodus about Jews who agreed to accept the Torah from God before really knowing what was in it. “Naaseh v’nishma,” the Israelites said, which roughly translates to “we’ll do, and then we’ll understand.” The lesson, the rabbi told me, is about diving in with imperfect information, of learning through doing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Schervish, the retired sociologist, thinks I should worry less about carving time outside of my regular routine to volunteer, and to count acts of service I take for my friends, partner, colleagues, and others just as much as philanthropy organized through 501c(3)s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Meeting the true needs of others is how you nourish somebody, but what that nourishment is, and what those true needs are — we’re always going to find people debating about that,” he told me. “And you’re going to have debates within yourself. But it’s always the right question.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This was his gentle reminder that determining how to live morally requires wrestling that is messy, personal, and evolving. I haven’t figured it all out yet. But I don’t want imperfect information to stop me from diving in, now.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Naaseh v’nishma, I signed up to donate blood again.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
