<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-31T21:50:37Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is there a winner in Bennifer’s divorce PR battle?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/369574/ben-affleck-jennifer-lopez-publicity-divorce-battle-celebrity" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369574</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T15:35:36Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-31T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[An event as seismic as Bennifer 2.0 could only end in a PR showdown. After months of breakup rumors, real-estate news, and a canceled tour, Jennifer Lopez finally filed for divorce from her husband Ben Affleck on August 20, citing “irreconcilable differences.” That date also marks the second anniversary of their lavish wedding ceremony in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Ben Affleck and Jennifer Lopez smiling together." data-caption="Ben Affleck and Jennifer Lopez at the Los Angeles premiere of This Is Me… Now: A Love Story." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2009471528.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Ben Affleck and Jennifer Lopez at the Los Angeles premiere of This Is Me… Now: A Love Story.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">An event as seismic as <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/351720/ben-affleck-jennifer-lopez-bennifer-timeline-divorce-rumors">Bennifer 2.0</a> could only end in a PR showdown. After months of breakup rumors, <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/08/02/lifestyle/inside-ben-afflecks-new-20m-la-mansion-amid-jennifer-lopez-split-rumors/">real-estate news</a>, and a canceled tour, Jennifer Lopez finally <a href="https://people.com/jennifer-lopez-ben-affleck-divorce-8649120">filed for divorce</a> from her husband Ben Affleck on August 20, citing “irreconcilable differences.” That date also marks the second anniversary of their lavish wedding ceremony in Georgia. It seems like this breakup isn’t just a sad affair but a bitter one, too. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their antics in the press say as much. If you pay attention to how celebrities use the tabloid press and their own lore to shape public opinion, a couple of narratives are forming. There are already <a href="https://people.com/ben-affleck-jennifer-lopez-split-what-went-wrong-exclusive-8701617">numerous reports</a> from unnamed sources alleging <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/08/21/entertainment/ben-affleck-showed-no-interest-in-fixing-jennifer-lopez-marriage/#:~:text=Jennifer%20Lopez%20is%20ready%20to,Now%E2%80%9D%20star%20pulled%20the%20plug.">Affleck’s cold behavior</a> toward Lopez, acting <a href="https://www.lifeandstylemag.com/posts/ben-affleck-and-jennifer-lopez-only-talk-through-lawyers/">distant</a> toward her while they supposedly tried to work through their issues. Meanwhile, Affleck has remained mostly quiet, with sources claiming he wants a more “civilized” divorce. Given the public’s perception of Lopez as the more attention-seeking partner in their marriage, this is most likely a PR strategy of its own.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a publicity angle, it looks like Lopez has more to lose. For a singer whose image violently swings between Hollywood icon and celebrity laughingstock, divorcing the so-called love of her life — also, the subject of her <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24075110/jennifer-lopez-movie-this-is-me-now-love-story-review">latest musical era,</a> which turned into an epic failure — puts her in a vulnerable position yet again. We haven’t even gotten to the inevitable battle over money, considering the former couple wed reportedly without a prenuptial agreement. If the <a href="https://www.cosmopolitan.com/entertainment/celebs/a29833912/jennifer-lopez-net-worth/#">estimates</a> <a href="https://pagesix.com/entertainment/ben-affleck-jennifer-lopez-net-worth/">tossed around</a> for their net worths are true — and if you can’t trust CelebrityNetWorth.com, who can you trust? — Lopez has significantly more to lose than Affleck. She’s also forgoing legal representation, which seems like a worse decision than a self-funded $20 million movie. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like most celebrity divorces, mudslinging and tabloid leaks are baked into the process. Still, for two seasoned A-listers who have already experienced personal and professional challenges in the limelight, another media circus seems like a waste of energy. Beyond maybe entertaining the public, there aren’t any new stakes. The Bennifer drama forces us to ask the question: Does anyone win in a celebrity divorce?&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What are Affleck and Lopez saying about each other?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far, neither party has commented directly on the divorce (although a rep for Affleck <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/celebrities/2024/08/28/ben-affleck-kick-kennedy-rfk-daughter-dating-rumor/74977777007/">shut down rumors</a> that he was dating RFK Jr.’s daughter Kick Kennedy). Instead, it appears that they’re letting anonymously sourced reports and photographed outings create narratives for them. Most of the “sources” seem to be working on Lopez’s behalf, which isn’t a surprise given that she initiated the divorce and seems, well, <a href="https://people.com/jennifer-lopez-upset-disappointed-ben-affleck-exclusive-source-8703655">frustrated</a>. It’s also notable that several of these exclusives are coming from People, a tabloid with a reputation for working directly with celebrities and their publicists. Meanwhile, Affleck is seemingly trying to avoid looking like the “most divorced man,” a title he earned after his split with Jennifer Garner in 2015. Days after Lopez’s divorce filing, he was photographed picking up a Jack in the Box delivery at his new LA home, a throwback to his days picking up Dunkin’ Donuts during the pandemic where his relatable dad persona really took shape.  </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2159269153.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,14.391473251104,100,71.217053497791" alt="Jennifer Lopez walking on the street, looking stylish in sunglasses and a white button-down top tucked into high-waisted pants." title="Jennifer Lopez walking on the street, looking stylish in sunglasses and a white button-down top tucked into high-waisted pants." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Jennifer Lopez in Los Angeles, California on June 29, 2024. | Bellocqimages/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images" data-portal-copyright="Bellocqimages/Bauer-Griffin/GC Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">These accounts suggest that Lopez was neglected by Affleck in the marriage and tried her best to make things work, a narrative that mimics the ending of their first go-around in 2001. Earlier this week, an exclusive from People said that Affleck had not given her “any signs that he wants to continue their marriage.” (Court documents revealed that the couple had been separated since April.) Likewise, a source close to Lopez told the magazine that the singer spent “a lot of time making sure Ben was happy,” despite the actor being “<a href="https://people.com/jennifer-lopez-helped-ben-affleck-navigate-dark-side-source-exclusive-8701932">moody and dark.</a>” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another narrative that seems to be taking shape is that Lopez is making more of an effort to manage their blended family amid the current chaos. That includes Lopez’s twins Max and Emme, from her previous marriage to singer Marc Anthony, and Affleck’s three children, Violet, Fin, and Samuel, with his ex-wife Garner, who all lived together in their former mansion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The last time Lopez and Affleck were <a href="https://people.com/jennifer-lopez-jennifer-garner-visit-ben-affleck-rental-house-son-samuel-graduation-party-8662839">spotted together</a> was in June for Affleck’s son Samuel’s graduation, when rumors of a breakup first started to emerge. Since then, Lopez has been spotted or photographed on <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/08/12/parents/jennifer-lopez-visits-ben-afflecks-rental-home-after-taking-his-son-samuel-shopping/">several outings</a> with Max and Violet, including a <a href="https://people.com/jennifer-lopez-hamptons-without-ben-affleck-fourth-of-july-8673175">4th of July trip</a> to the Hamptons. (People noted that Affleck was back in LA at the time.) Most recently, the magazine <a href="https://people.com/ben-affleck-has-not-been-in-touch-with-jennifer-lopez-kids-exclusive-source-8701044">reported</a> that Affleck “has not been in touch” with Lopez’s children.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While we haven’t been bombarded with claims about Lopez’s part in their demise or photo ops with his children, the fact that Affleck is not saying much, while allowing Lopez to make more of a show out of their divorce, seems like its own strategy, too.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong><em>The Greatest Love Story Never Told</em> foreshadowed this PR chaos&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since their first breakup, Affleck has given the public the impression that Lopez was more comfortable in the limelight than him. It’s something he reiterates throughout Lopez’s Prime documentary <em>The Greatest Love Story Never Told, </em>which premiered in February. The actor joked about Lopez’s impulse to publicize everything — including the stack of love letters he sent her before their 2021 reunion — but claimed that he was now willing to sacrifice his privacy to be with her. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Likewise, Lopez is portrayed as more needy for public attention, while Affleck is reluctant to participate in her projects and public antics. The sheer amount of paparazzi photos of Affleck would immediately dispel this claim, including those famous pap walks with his ex-girlfriend Ana de Armas during the pandemic. Days after the divorce, People <a href="https://people.com/ben-affleck-had-control-over-documentary-about-marriage-to-jennifer-lopez-exclusive-8701006">reported that multiple unnamed sources</a> had told the publication that Affleck, whose production company Artists Equity took on Lopez’s documentary, had creative control over the project.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2121052565.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Affleck and Lopez walking out of a brownstone on March 30, 2024 in New York." title="Affleck and Lopez walking out of a brownstone on March 30, 2024 in New York." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Ben Affleck and Jennifer Lopez out and about in New York. | MEGA/GC Images" data-portal-copyright="MEGA/GC Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Looking back on the film through this lens, you can see how dedicated they both are to protecting their image, while also seemingly a bit clumsy at it. The documentary, which follows the behind-the-scenes making of Lopez’s visual album <em>This Is Me… Now</em>, is full of humiliating and awkward (but extremely amusing) moments that the average pop star nowadays wouldn’t dream of being broadcast. At the time, the documentary seemed like the one saving grace in an era of misfires for Lopez, including a low-performing visual album and a canceled tour. Nevertheless, memes about Lopez — including a scene where she’s mythologizing her childhood hairdo — took off, in addition to random clips of Lopez supposedly displaying diva behavior. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Lopez struggled to make the public care about her new music, she kept people invested in her personal life with Affleck. The odd-couple dynamic they portrayed in the film was sweet and admirable. Lopez was depicted as the outgoing partner with unrealistic ambitions, while Affleck looked like the pragmatic but doting husband who supported his wife’s dreams. A memorable scene in the documentary shows Affleck boosting Lopez’s confidence when she’s feeling doubtful during the filmmaking process. Now, it’s hard not to wonder how much of this documentary factors into Affleck’s seeming escape plan.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Does either party have anything to gain?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With new exclusives about the details of their relationship arriving each day, it seems like the couple may be buckling up for a war that might leave both of their reputations a little scathed. For now, though, the media circus mostly feels gratuitous. But it’s sort of a humiliating ritual that these two celebrities from the ’90s would default to. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For one thing, this is not the sort of explosive divorce that’s immediately inciting fans to take sides. Some<a href="https://x.com/TheyCallMeN1ka/status/1828238592214196329"> social media</a> <a href="https://x.com/MariaArriola4/status/1829181780458668194">users</a> are already <a href="https://x.com/SoumDesigns/status/1827778510397579317">calling</a> <a href="https://x.com/m0mmy_1ssues_/status/1827595484636016759">BS</a> on the narrative that Lopez was too public-facing for Affleck. But for the most part, Lopez and Affleck are two sometimes-loved-sometimes-hated celebrities, whose reputations are constantly in flux. Right now, it doesn’t seem like the public at large is jumping to demonize either one of them. The fact that their romantic history is reportedly<strong> </strong>riddled with dysfunction seems to be what makes them relatable and easy to root for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The divorce announcement itself also doesn’t seem that controversial. The details being revealed currently aren’t that explosive, besides the suggestion that Affleck has commitment issues. It certainly is not anything like the years-long fallout between <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2022/10/4/23388000/angelina-jolie-brad-pitt-physical-domestic-abuse-allegations">Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie</a> following their divorce, which involves domestic and child abuse allegations and has left Pitt’s image with a stain — even if he’s still booked and busy in Hollywood. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to imagine these image-altering outcomes for Affleck simply for opting out of a marriage, even if the dissolution was as frosty on his end as some glossy celeb weeklies have depicted it. And after all, after all the breakups and career hits Lopez has experienced in the public eye, she has proven to be one of our most invincible celebrities. It’s all very predictable and not totally surprising — just like if they decided to get back together 20 years from now.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sigal Samuel</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Matthews</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[California’s governor has the chance to make AI history]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/369628/ai-safety-bill-sb-1047-gavin-newsom-california" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369628</id>
			<updated>2024-08-31T21:50:37Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-31T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tech policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advocates say it is a modest law setting &#8220;clear, predictable, common-sense safety standards&#8221; for artificial intelligence. Opponents say it is a dangerous and arrogant step that will “stifle innovation.” In any event, SB 1047 — California state Sen. Scott Wiener’s proposal to regulate advanced AI models offered by companies doing business in the state — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="California Gov.Gavin Newsom speaks during a press conference with the California Highway Patrol announcing new efforts to boost public safety in the East Bay, in Oakland, California, July 11, 2024. | Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161013764_474f9c.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>California Gov.Gavin Newsom speaks during a press conference with the California Highway Patrol announcing new efforts to boost public safety in the East Bay, in Oakland, California, July 11, 2024. | Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Advocates say it is a modest law setting &#8220;clear, predictable, <a href="https://time.com/7015197/ai-legislation-protects-more-than-just-people/">common-sense safety standards</a>&#8221; for artificial intelligence. Opponents say it is a dangerous and arrogant step that will “<a href="https://pelosi.house.gov/news/press-releases/pelosi-statement-opposition-california-senate-bill-1047">stifle innovation</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any event, SB 1047 — California state Sen. <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/361562/california-ai-bill-scott-wiener-sb-1047">Scott Wiener’s proposal</a> to regulate advanced AI models offered by companies doing business in the state — has now passed the California State Assembly by a <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billVotesClient.xhtml?bill_id=202320240SB1047">margin of 48 to 16</a>. Back in May, it passed the Senate by 32 to 1. Once the Senate agrees to the assembly’s changes to the bill, which it is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/28/24229068/california-sb-1047-ai-safety-bill-passed-state-assembly-governor-newsom-signature">expected</a> to do shortly, the measure goes to Gov. Gavin Newsom’s desk.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The bill, which would hold AI companies liable for catastrophic harms their “frontier” models may cause, is backed by a wide array of AI safety groups, as well as luminaries in the field like <a href="https://sd11.senate.ca.gov/news/senator-wieners-landmark-ai-bill-passes-assembly">Geoffrey Hinton</a>, <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/08/15/yoshua-bengio-californias-ai-safety-bill-will-protect-consumers-innovation-tech/">Yoshua Bengio</a>, and <a href="https://safesecureai.org/experts">Stuart Russell</a>, who have warned of the technology’s potential to pose massive, even existential dangers to humankind. It got a surprise last-minute endorsement from <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1828205685386936567">Elon Musk</a>, who among his other ventures runs the AI firm <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/27/24165619/elon-musk-xai-startup-6-billion-funding">xAI</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lined up against SB 1047 is nearly all of the tech industry, including <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/21/24225648/openai-letter-california-ai-safety-bill-sb-1047">OpenAI</a>, <a href="https://static.politico.com/e0/fd/e56dfaad40b39f29dd1dfa1164da/sb-1047-letter-6-25-24.pdf">Facebook</a>, the powerful investors <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91175604/big-tech-lobbyists-ai-safety-bill-gavin-newsom">Y Combinator and Andreessen Horowitz</a>, and some <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1E2yDGXryPhhlwS4OdkzMpNeaG5r6_Jxa/view">academic researchers</a> who fear it threatens <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/2/2/24058484/open-source-artificial-intelligence-ai-risk-meta-llama-2-chatgpt-openai-deepfake">open source</a> AI models. Anthropic, another AI heavyweight, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/364384/its-practically-impossible-to-run-a-big-ai-company-ethically">lobbied to water down the bill</a>. After many of its proposed amendments were adopted in August, the company said the bill’s <a href="https://cdn.sanity.io/files/4zrzovbb/website/6a3b14a98a781a6b69b9a3c5b65da26a44ecddc6.pdf">“benefits likely outweigh its costs.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite the industry backlash, the bill seems to be popular with Californians, though all surveys on it have been funded by interested parties. A recent poll by the pro-bill AI Policy Institute <a href="https://theaipi.org/april-voters-prefer-ai-regulation-over-self-regulation-2-3-2/">found 70 percent of residents</a> in favor, with even higher approval ratings among Californians working in tech. The California Chamber of Commerce commissioned a bill <a href="https://prospect.org/power/2024-08-28-tech-industry-push-poll-california-ai-bill/">finding a plurality of Californians opposed</a>, but the poll’s wording was slanted, to say the least, describing the bill as requiring developers to “pay tens of millions of dollars in fines if they don’t implement orders from state bureaucrats.” The AI Policy Institute’s poll presented pro and con arguments, but the California Chamber of Commerce only bothered with a “con” argument.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The wide, bipartisan margins by which the bill passed the Assembly and Senate, and the public’s general support (when not asked in a biased way), might suggest that Gov. Newsom is likely to sign. But it’s not so simple. Andreessen Horowitz, the <a href="https://a16z.com/about/">$43 billion venture capital giant</a>,&nbsp;has <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91175604/big-tech-lobbyists-ai-safety-bill-gavin-newsom">hired Newsom&#8217;s close friend and Democratic operative Jason Kinney to lobby</a> against the bill, and a number of powerful Democrats, including <a href="https://democrats-science.house.gov/imo/media/doc/2024-08-15%20to%20Gov%20Newsom_SB1047.pdf">eight members of the US House</a> from California and former Speaker <a href="https://pelosi.house.gov/news/press-releases/pelosi-statement-opposition-california-senate-bill-1047">Nancy Pelosi</a>, have urged a veto, echoing <a href="https://x.com/GarrisonLovely/status/1824236448310022453">talking points from the tech industry</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So there’s a strong chance that Newsom will veto the bill, keeping California — the center of the AI industry — from becoming the first state with robust AI liability rules. At stake is not just AI safety in California, but also in the US and potentially the world.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s inside SB 1047</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To have attracted all of this intense lobbying, one might think that SB 1047 is an aggressive, heavy-handed bill — but, especially after several rounds of revisions in the State Assembly, the actual law does fairly little.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It would offer <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/353933/openai-open-letter-safety-whistleblowers-right-to-warn">whistleblower protections to tech workers</a>, along with a process for people who have confidential information about risky behavior at an AI lab to take their complaint to the state Attorney General without fear of prosecution. It also requires AI companies that spend more than $100 million to train an AI model to develop safety plans. (The extraordinarily high ceiling for this requirement to kick in is meant to protect California’s startup industry, which objected that the compliance burden would be too high for small companies.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what about this bill would possibly prompt months of hysteria, intense lobbying from the California business community, and unprecedented intervention by California’s federal representatives? Part of the answer is that the bill used to be stronger. The initial version of the law was based the threshold for compliance on computing power, meaning that over time, more companies would have become subject to the law as computers continue to get cheaper (and more powerful). It would also have established a state agency called the “Frontier Models Division” to review safety plans; the industry objected to the perceived power grab.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another part of the answer is that a lot of people were falsely told the bill does more. One prominent critic <a href="https://www.hyperdimensional.co/p/californias-effort-to-strangle-ai">inaccurately claimed</a> that AI developers could be guilty of a felony, regardless of whether they were involved in a harmful incident, when the bill only had provisions for criminal liability in the event that the developer <a href="https://safesecureai.org/responseletter">knowingly lied under oath</a>. (Those provisions were subsequently removed anyway). <a href="https://lofgren.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/lofgren.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/8.7.24%20to%20Senator%20Wiener.pdf">Congressional representative Zoe Lofgren of the science, space, and technology committee wrote a letter</a> in opposition falsely claiming that the bill requires adherence to guidance that doesn’t exist yet.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the standards do exist (<a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ai/NIST.AI.800-1.ipd.pdf">you can read them in full here</a>), and<em> </em>the bill does not require firms to adhere to them. It says only that “a developer shall consider industry best practices and applicable guidance” from the US Artificial Intelligence Safety Institute, National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Government Operations Agency, and other reputable organizations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of the discussion of SB 1047 unfortunately centered around straightforwardly incorrect claims like these, in many cases propounded by people who should have known better.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SB 1047 is premised on the idea that near-future AI systems might be extraordinarily powerful, that they accordingly <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/12/21/18126576/ai-artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-safety-alignment">might be dangerous</a>, and that some oversight is required. That core proposition is extraordinarily <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/12/21/18126576/ai-artificial-intelligence-machine-learning-safety-alignment">controversial</a> among AI researchers. Nothing exemplifies the split more than the three men frequently called the “godfathers of machine learning,” Turing Award winners Yoshua Bengio, Geoffrey Hinton, and Yann LeCun. Bengio — a <a href="https://www.vox.com/23924495/yoshua-bengio-scientific-director-mila-quebec-ai-institute-future-perfect-50-2023">Future Perfect 2023 honoree</a> — and Hinton have both in the last few years become convinced that the technology they created may kill us all and argued for regulation and oversight. Hinton <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/01/technology/ai-google-chatbot-engineer-quits-hinton.html">stepped down</a> from Google in 2023 to speak openly about his fears.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">LeCun, who is chief AI scientist at Meta, has taken the opposite tack, declaring that such worries are nonsensical science fiction and that any regulation would strangle innovation. Where Bengio and Hinton find themselves supporting the bill, LeCun opposes it, especially the idea that AI companies should face liability if AI is used in a mass casualty event.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In this sense, SB 1047 is the center of a symbolic tug-of-war: Does government take AI safety concerns seriously, or not? The actual text of the bill may be limited, but to the extent that it suggests government is listening to the half of experts that think that AI might be extraordinarily dangerous, the implications are big.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s that sentiment that has likely driven some of the fiercest lobbying against the bill by venture capitalists Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz, whose firm a16z has been working relentlessly to kill the bill, and some of the highly unusual outreach to federal legislators to demand they oppose a state bill. More mundane politics likely plays a role, too: <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/california-playbook/2024/08/19/ai-pelosi-house-seat-00174542">Politico reported</a> that Pelosi opposed the bill because she’s trying to court tech VCs for her daughter, who is likely to run against Scott Wiener for a House of Representatives seat.)</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Why SB 1047 is so important&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It might seem strange that legislation in just one US state has so many people wringing their hands. But remember: California is not just any state. It’s where several of the world’s leading AI companies are based.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And what happens there is especially important because, at the federal level, lawmakers have been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/15/technology/ai-schumer-roadmap-congress.html">dragging out</a> the process of regulating AI. Between Washington’s hesitation and the looming election, it’s falling to states to pass new laws. The California bill, if Newsom gives it the green light, would be one big piece of that puzzle, setting the direction for the US more broadly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rest of the world is watching, too. “Countries around the world are looking at these drafts for ideas that can influence their decisions on AI laws,” Victoria Espinel, the chief executive of the Business Software Alliance, a lobbying group representing major software companies, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/10/technology/california-ai-regulation.html">told</a> the New York Times in June.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even China —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23621198/artificial-intelligence-chatgpt-openai-existential-risk-china-ai-safety-technology">often invoked as the boogeyman in American conversations</a> about AI development (because “we don’t want to lose an arms race with China”) — is showing signs of <a href="https://www.economist.com/china/2024/08/25/is-xi-jinping-an-ai-doomer">caring about safety</a>, not just wanting to run ahead. Bills like SB 1047 could telegraph to others that Americans also care about safety.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Frankly, it’s refreshing to see legislators wise up to the tech world’s favorite gambit:&nbsp;claiming that it can regulate itself. That claim may have held sway in the era of social media, but it’s become increasingly untenable.&nbsp;We need to regulate Big Tech. That means not just carrots, but sticks, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Newsom has the opportunity to do something historic. And if he doesn’t? Well, he’ll face some sticks of his own. The <a href="https://theaipi.org/april-voters-prefer-ai-regulation-over-self-regulation-2-3-2/">AI Policy Institute’s poll</a> shows that 60 percent of voters are prepared to blame him for future AI-related incidents if he vetoes SB 1047. In fact, they’d punish him at the ballot box if he runs for higher office: 40 percent of California voters say they would be less likely to vote for Newsom in a future presidential primary election if he vetoes the bill.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel has launched a major operation in the West Bank. Here’s what to know.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/palestine/369736/west-bank-violence-jenin-raid-settler-idf-israel-gaza-hamas" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369736</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T22:29:18Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T22:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Terrorism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Israeli military launched the largest, deadliest West Bank attack&#160;of the year on Wednesday, killing at least 16 people, including a high-ranking militia commander, over the course of several days. Violence in the West Bank —&#160;perpetrated by the military, Israeli settlers, and Palestinian fighters —&#160;has been steadily accelerating over the past 10 months. Since the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Soldiers descending from troop transport vans in a bare field outside a town." data-caption="Israeli soldiers operate during a raid in the Nur Shams camp for Palestinian refugees near the city of Tulkarem in the Israeli-occupied West Bank on August 28, 2024. | Jaafar Ashtiyeh for AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jaafar Ashtiyeh for AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2168054048.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli soldiers operate during a raid in the Nur Shams camp for Palestinian refugees near the city of Tulkarem in the Israeli-occupied West Bank on August 28, 2024. | Jaafar Ashtiyeh for AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Israeli military launched the largest, deadliest West Bank attack&nbsp;of the year on Wednesday, killing at least 16 people, including a high-ranking militia commander, over the course of several days. Violence in the West Bank —&nbsp;perpetrated by the military, Israeli settlers, and Palestinian fighters —&nbsp;has been steadily accelerating over the past 10 months.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the October 7 Hamas raid on Israel, at least <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-forces-say-they-kill-local-hamas-commander-west-bank-2024-08-30/">660 Palestinians</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/israel-west-bank-operation-death-toll-climbs/#:~:text=At%20least%2015%20Israelis%2C%20including,the%20attacks%2C%20the%20United%20Nations">15 Israelis</a> have been killed in the West Bank, according to the United Nations. It’s a smaller number than the more than 40,000 Palestinians killed in Gaza over the past 10 months, but it is still a reminder of how intense ongoing violence in the West Bank is.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Israeli military has conducted several raids in Palestinian refugee camps since the start of the war in Gaza. The <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/29/israel-operation-west-bank-gaza-war/">latest operation</a> started early Wednesday morning: Air and ground forces targeted Tulkarm in the northwest, Jenin at the territory’s northern border, and Far’a refugee camp <a href="https://www.unrwa.org/where-we-work/west-bank/fara-camp">in the territory’s east</a>. Shin Bet, an Israeli security service affiliated with the country’s intelligence groups, and the Israel Border Police were also involved in the raids, which ostensibly targeted what Israeli officials called “terrorist infrastructure.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel claims Mohamed Jaber — a commander of a group affiliated with Palestinian Islamic Jihad — and Hamas commander Wassem Hazem were both killed, along with other militants during the raid. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israeli-forces-say-they-kill-local-hamas-commander-west-bank-2024-08-3">Israeli officials accused Hazem of plotting,</a> along with other militia members, attacks within the West Bank. Like Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad helped commit the October 7 attacks; both groups also claimed responsibility for<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/19/world/middleeast/tel-aviv-bomb-hamas.html"> a suicide attack in Tel Aviv earlier this month</a>, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-blast-hamas-war-palestinians-3f491deecaa3dab14047c7ab982c2dd8">which wounded one Israeli</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you think about it from this sort of tactical perspective, suicide bombers are most likely to be coming from the West Bank, more so than Gaza, probably because Gaza is already a war zone,” Raphael Cohen, director of the strategy and doctrine program of RAND Project Air Force, told Vox, adding that Hamas officials have called for increased suicide attacks against Israeli territory. That may be part of what motivated Israel’s recent operation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is also a rising number of Palestinians taking up arms in the West Bank generally, some due to anger and horror over the brutal destruction of Gaza, but also because military raids and attacks by Jewish settlers in the West Bank are increasingly violent and terrorizing. Saif Aqel, a youth leader with the Fatah political group, told the Washington Post that Jaber had been radicalized by Israel’s repeated West Bank raids, saying, “The environment he was living in made him like this.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As part of its operation this week, the Israeli military has blocked and destroyed roads and blocked entrances to hospitals, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/29/israel-operation-west-bank-gaza-war/">according to witnesses</a>, as well as shut off electricity, water, mobile, and internet service. The Israeli military has disputed that it blocked access to medical facilities.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Violence in the West Bank has been going on for decades</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The West Bank sits to Israel’s east, bordering Jordan and the western shore of the Dead Sea. Before 1967, Jordan controlled the region; Israel then captured the territory and held it under military occupation until the 1993 Oslo Accords, when it was carved up into three “areas,” supposedly under the control of the Palestinian Authority. However, <a href="https://israelpolicyforum.org/west-bank-settlements-explained/">Jewish Israeli settlement of the area</a> accelerated,&nbsp;and the Israeli military also moved in to protect them. Now, the Palestinian Authority, which is the nominal government, has little actual control in the West Bank.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gaza, Jerusalem, and the West Bank are recognized as occupied territory under international law, and therefore Israel is obligated to protect the people living there. Israel denies that it is occupying Palestinian lands, but just last month, the <a href="https://www.icj-cij.org/sites/default/files/case-related/186/186-20240719-pre-01-00-en.pdf">International Court of Justice</a> ruled that Israel is occupying Palestinian lands and should end that occupation immediately.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under that order, which is enforceable by the UN Security Council, “Israel must withdraw its forces from all parts of the occupied territories, including the Gaza Strip and remove all settlers from the West Bank, including from the illegally annexed East Jerusalem,” Erika Guevara Rosas,&nbsp;Amnesty International’s senior director for research, advocacy, policy and campaigns, <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2024/07/icj-opinion-declaring-israels-occupation-of-palestinian-territories-unlawful-is-historic-vindication-of-palestinians-rights/">said in a statement</a>. Israel’s allies on the security council, including the United States, have given no indication they intend to enforce the court’s decision.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has allowed Israel to continue its war in Gaza, and left Palestinians living in the West Bank trapped in a cycle of violence: There have been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/28/world/middleeast/israel-palestinian-west-bank-clashes-timeline.html">at least five major Israeli military operations</a> in the West Bank since October 7, and settler violence has increased as well.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These settlers are Israelis — often aligned with the country’s right wing and often heavily armed&nbsp;“to the teeth,” according to Diana Buttu, a Palestinian-Canadian lawyer specializing in international human rights law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They have increasingly expanded the number of settlements into land the United Nations has said is supposed to be off-limits to Israeli control. Israel refers to them as “illegal” settlements but does not stop people from building outposts, or from <a href="https://www.btselem.org/topic/settlements">forcing Palestinians out of their homes and off their land</a>. Some settlers have begun to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/04/16/israel-settlers-attack-violence-palestinians/">push closer to cities as well</a>. Settlements are also frequently subsidized by the Israeli government, which provides them with higher-quality infrastructure, roads, water, and schools in their settlements than what the government provides Palestinian villages.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some Palestinians have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/08/28/west-bank-palestinians-militants-israel-raid/">taken up arms against these settlers</a>, and sanctioned Israeli military operations have encouraged vigilantism and new anti-Israel militant groups as well. Israel has sent in more troops in response, creating what seems to be an inescapable cycle.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The cities [in the West Bank] are supposed to be free of army presence, but the army has been carrying out these raids, so these [militant] groups arose in response,” Joost Hiltermann, director of the Middle East program at the International Crisis Group, told Vox. “So then the army responds to these groups, and you&#8217;ll see an escalation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jenin city and the refugee camp on its outskirts — two sites that saw fighting this week — are <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/7/4/the-occupied-west-bank-city-of-jenin-a-focal-point-of-conflict-2">frequent targets</a> since, as Buttu explained, they and all of Gaza are the main sites of Palestinian resistance in the occupied territories.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, there’s little sign either the militants or Israel will change their strategies in the West Bank, and that has some countries — particularly <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/08/30/world/israel-hamas-gaza-war/israeli-forces-pull-back-from-tulkarm-but-press-on-with-their-raid-of-jenin-officials-say?smid=url-share">France and Britain</a> — worried that the increasing violence will turn the West Bank into another Gaza.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Trump Arlington National Cemetery controversy, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/369711/trump-arlington-cemetery-controversy-army" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369711</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T21:38:05Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T20:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A controversy over the Trump campaign’s behavior during a visit by Trump to Arlington National Cemetery last Monday has stretched for days with no end in sight. In part, the controversy is about the law: Federal law prohibits campaign or election activity at military cemeteries. In a larger sense, it’s yet another example of Trump [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Donald Trump walking with Secret Service agents over a green lawn at the edge of rows of white gravestones." data-caption="Donald Trump leaves Arlington National Cemetery after he attended a ceremony honoring the lives of those who died at the Abbey Gate Bombing, on August 26, 2024. | Kevin Carter/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Carter/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2168274420.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Donald Trump leaves Arlington National Cemetery after he attended a ceremony honoring the lives of those who died at the Abbey Gate Bombing, on August 26, 2024. | Kevin Carter/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A controversy over the Trump campaign’s behavior during a visit by Trump to Arlington National Cemetery last Monday has stretched for days with no end in sight.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In part, the controversy is about the law: Federal law prohibits campaign or election activity at military cemeteries. In a larger sense, it’s yet another example of Trump flouting longstanding norms of decorum and ethical conduct — to the outrage of many, but not all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s team, it seems clear, wanted to use the military cemetery visit for political benefit. When a cemetery staff member tried to prevent Trump campaign aides from taking photographs and filming near servicemembers’ graves, a Trump aide physically pushed her aside.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Furthermore, once word of this incident leaked out, Trump’s campaign aides viciously insulted the cemetery staffer in startlingly personal terms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In one fell swoop, Trump’s team managed to violate norms against politicizing veterans’ sacrifices, shoving people, and ugly personal attacks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Trump campaign has defended itself by pointing out that the family members of the servicemembers being memorialized that day have not protested his actions. Several of them <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/113037529550199315">have defended</a> Trump, and they’re the ones who invited Trump to the cemetery in the first place, in part because <a href="https://nypost.com/2023/08/29/gold-star-families-rip-biden-over-kabul-airport-blast/">they blame</a> Biden’s handling of the Afghanistan withdrawal for their loved ones’ deaths.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What exactly happened with Trump at Arlington National Cemetery?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Monday was the third anniversary of the August 26, 2021, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/8/27/22643461/isis-k-kabul-airport-afghanistan-taliban">Kabul airport attack</a> — a suicide bombing during the chaotic US withdrawal from Afghanistan that left 13 US service members dead.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some family members of those killed have blamed the attack on the Biden administration’s handling of the withdrawal, and have aligned with the Trump campaign — including by appearing <a href="https://www.politifact.com/article/2024/jul/18/families-of-13-fallen-us-service-members-emotional/">at the Republican national convention</a> in July. And when planning an Arlington cemetery event to mark the attack’s third anniversary, they invited Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since it is the height of the presidential campaign season, and since Trump has long criticized the Biden administration’s <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-michigan-afghanistan-war-46eb2b0861939bf022747920c0ee0234">handling</a> of the Afghanistan withdrawal, US defense officials were concerned that the event could become inappropriately or even illegally political, the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/28/trump-arlington-cemetery-section-60/">Washington Post reports</a> — that it was a campaign event in disguise.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, officials laid down some restrictions. One was that Trump wasn’t supposed to bring his campaign staff. Another was that, after an initial ceremony at the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier that was open to the press, Trump’s visits to individual veterans’ graves, in a section of the cemetery <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/28/nx-s1-5092041/arlington-trump-section60-veterans-altercation">reserved primarily for veterans of Iraq and Afghanistan</a>, would be private.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Trump brought campaign aides anyway. And two of those aides — a campaign photographer and a videographer — tried to go with Trump to the individual graves. An Arlington cemetery staff member tried to stop the aides, but, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/28/trump-arlington-cemetery-section-60/">per the Post</a>, “a larger male campaign aide insisted the camera was allowed and pushed past the cemetery employee, leaving her shocked.” <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/27/nx-s1-5091154/trump-arlington-cemetery">According to NPR</a>, Trump campaign staff also “verbally abused” the official.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After the ceremony, the Trump campaign organized a press call in which several family members of the servicemembers killed at Kabul praised Trump and <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/biden-harris-have-never-once-reached-out-gold-star-families-13-fallen-servicemembers-say">criticized</a> Biden and Harris.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What has happened since then?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">News of the altercation became public on Tuesday, when <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/27/nx-s1-5091154/trump-arlington-cemetery">NPR reported on the incident</a>. Trump campaign spokespeople <a href="https://x.com/TheStevenCheung/status/1828575389783933439">claimed</a> they had permission to bring a photographer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They also claimed the cemetery staff member wasn’t pushed — but viciously derided her anyway. Trump spokesperson Steven Cheung asserted that she was “clearly suffering from a <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/27/nx-s1-5091154/trump-arlington-cemetery">mental health episode</a>,” and co-campaign manager Chris LaCivita called her “despicable.” (Her name has not been made public, and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/29/us/politics/trump-arlington-cemetery-army.html">the New York Times reported</a> that military officials “feared that the employee would face retaliation from Trump supporters if her identity became known.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s team also <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/113037529550199315">posted a statement</a> from several family members of two of the soldiers who died in the Kabul attack. “We had given our approval for President Trump’s official videographer and photographer to attend the event,” the statement says. (The permission of the families, however, has no bearing on the federal law prohibiting campaign activity at the cemetery.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The president and his team conducted themselves with nothing but the utmost respect and dignity,” the family members’ statement continues.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Utah Gov. Spencer Cox, a Republican who was also in attendance, <a href="https://x.com/GovCox/status/1828089276359414118/photo/2">posted a photo</a> in which Trump stood with some veterans and family members by a grave, giving a thumbs-up. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s team subsequently <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@realdonaldtrump/video/7407571442088430878?lang=en">made a TikTok video</a> including footage from the grave visits, with a voiceover from Trump blaming the Biden administration for the veterans’ deaths — clearly using the event for political purposes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Family members of one Green Beret whose grave was seen in these photos and videos (but who was not killed in the Kabul attack) issued a statement <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/28/us/politics/trump-arlington-cemetery.html">expressing concern</a> that Trump aides did not follow cemetery rules on filming and taking photos.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Thursday, the US Army — which manages Arlington National Cemetery — <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/29/politics/us-army-rebukes-trump-campaign-arlington-incident/index.html">issued its own statement</a> backing the cemetery staff member and asserting that she was indeed “abruptly pushed aside” for attempting to assure adherence to the ban on political activities on cemetery grounds.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This incident was unfortunate, and it is also unfortunate that the ANC employee and her professionalism has been unfairly attacked,” the statement said. However, it went on, the employee decided not to press charges, so the Army now “considers this matter closed.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Serial’s Adnan Syed has once again had his conviction reinstated. Here’s what that really means.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23662123/adnan-syed-conviction-reinstated-appeal-lee-zoom" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/culture/23662123/adnan-syed-conviction-reinstated-appeal-lee-zoom</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T16:54:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T16:54:27Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="True crime" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The case of Adnan Syed, true crime cause célèbre, has been unresolved for the last two years thanks to a complex appeals process over the question of victims’ rights. The state vacated his conviction for the murder of Hae Min Lee in 2022, only for an appellate court to reverse this decision and reinstate his [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Adnan Syed. | Lloyd Fox/Baltimore Sun/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Lloyd Fox/Baltimore Sun/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24545689/1246490054.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Adnan Syed. | Lloyd Fox/Baltimore Sun/Tribune News Service via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The case of Adnan Syed, true crime cause célèbre, has been unresolved for the last two years thanks to a complex appeals process over the question of victims’ rights. The state <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23361826/adnan-syed-free-maryland-baltimore-criminal-justice">vacated his conviction</a> for the murder of Hae Min Lee in 2022, only for an appellate court to reverse this decision and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2023/03/28/adnan-syed-conviction-reinstated/">reinstate his conviction</a> a few months later. Now the Maryland Supreme Court, after hearing arguments on all sides, has upheld Syed’s reinstated conviction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At issue was the question of whether Lee’s brother, Young Lee, her family’s court representative in the proceedings, had been given sufficient notice before the 2022 hearing on the motion to vacate Syed’s conviction — a hearing that lasted just minutes and saw Lee signing into the court via Zoom. Pleas filed directly by the victims or their families are rare, but this one was successful, with <a href="https://www.thebaltimorebanner.com/community/criminal-justice/adnan-syed-conviction-reinstated-F644C7ZF45HW3O5TKL7NXHHWWM/">two courts</a> <a href="https://www.thebaltimorebanner.com/community/criminal-justice/adnan-syed-maryland-supreme-court-decision-JYLH7HPSO5GP5IG2KKXRUDBPUA/">in a row</a> finding that Lee had not been afforded enough time to prepare for the hearing or attend it in person.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a 4-3 decision, the state Supreme Court found that the swift decision to vacate had “<a href="https://www.wisn.com/article/maryland-court-orders-redo-of-hearing-that-freed-adnan-syed-in-serial-case/62018582">worked an injustice</a>” against Lee.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because the issue concerns the right of the victim’s family to be present, rather than the actual question of Syed’s guilt or innocence — which the courts seem to have ultimately decided in his favor — the upholding of his conviction<strong> </strong>is mainly procedural. That means it likely won’t affect the ultimate outcome of Syed’s case. Prosecutors <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/10/11/us/adnan-syed-charges-dropped/index.html">formally dropped charges</a> against him during the brief period in 2022 when his conviction had been overturned, citing new DNA testing of Hae Min’s clothing that returned results for four different people — none of which was a match for Syed.  </p>

<p>The back-and-forth debate over Young Lee’s rights is important, however: It serves as a useful reminder to the court to prioritize victims’ rights — even in a case where it appears a wrongful conviction may have occurred.</p>

<p>To the average onlooker, it might have seemed as though <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23361826/adnan-syed-free-maryland-baltimore-criminal-justice">Syed’s release from prison</a> was a long time coming.&nbsp;The subject of the revolutionary first season of <a href="https://www.vox.com/serial-podcast"><em>Serial</em></a> finally had his conviction for the 1999 murder of Lee, his ex-girlfriend, vacated in September 2022. The push to vacate, which was spearheaded in part by the Baltimore prosecutor’s office, arose after a special case review uncovered new evidence, including two new suspects, that cast reasonable doubt on his trial and conviction. Prosecutors dropped all charges against Syed just days later.</p>

<p>However, the circumstances that led to Syed’s release were fairly unusual, coming only after years of exhausted appeals and, finally, a new case review that stemmed from a wider effort to bring desperately needed reform to Baltimore’s criminal justice system and sentencing procedures. The situation was so unusual, in fact, that it seems to have led to a pretty unusual exclusion: The victim’s family was given almost no time to prepare for the hearing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Hae Min’s brother, Young Lee, who was acting as victim’s advocate, was only given one day’s notice to prepare for the hearing, which included arranging for travel to and from Baltimore. According to the <a href="https://www.courts.state.md.us/data/opinions/cosa/2023/1291s22.pdf">appellate decision</a>, the lower court originally assumed that Lee would be attending via a Zoom link — but Lee apparently only agreed to attend the hearing via Zoom as a last resort, since he’d had no time to prepare to attend in person.</p>

<p>“I’ve never heard of a victim’s family being contacted a day before,” former Brooklyn prosecutor <a href="https://www.rendelmanlaw.com/about-julie-rendelman/">Julie Rendelman</a> told Vox. “We usually let them know way in advance if any issues are arising. They would have been following along in the process way before a hearing had taken place.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Lee “wanted more time, because he wanted an opportunity to speak to his attorney and to have a better understanding of what the evidence was” supporting Syed’s innocence, she said. “But he couldn’t do that in a timely fashion, and so instead, last minute, he got on a Zoom call. So the question was whether that was sufficient notice.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>The court found that it was not. On Tuesday, March 28, the appellate panel, in a 2-1 decision, reversed the earlier decision to vacate, temporarily reinstating Syed’s conviction. The court stayed the new decision for 60 days, meaning it doesn’t take effect for another two months, in order to give the prosecution and the defense in Syed’s case time to adjust to the reinstated verdict.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Effectively, the stayed ruling keeps Syed from heading back to jail. Instead, it requires a redo of the original September hearing on the motion to vacate — a redo the appellate court found necessary so that the victim’s family could be present in person for the hearing.</p>

<p>Rendelman told Vox it’s rare for this type of appeal by a victim’s family to be brought forward, and rare for such a ruling to be granted. “At the same time,” she stressed, “it’s also rare [not to] provide the victim’s family with notice.”</p>

<p>“If a prosecutor did not reach out to the family letting them know way in advance that a hearing was coming down the pike in which the potential was that the individual who allegedly killed their loved one was going to get out of jail, that is preposterous.”</p>

<p>She pointed out that although the court’s motion is basically a technicality, it does raise questions about the role of technology in a modern criminal justice setting. “It’s interesting,” Rendelman said, “because we really are in a different time than we were three years ago, where Zoom has become an acceptable form of participating in a court proceeding.” The appellate court, however, noted that not only was Lee’s family given short notice, but all the other relevant parties were able to attend in person, which created an unfair situation.</p>

<p>“The exception here is that he didn’t want to be on Zoom and he wasn’t given any time to appear,” she said of Lee.</p>

<p>Still, the fact that the victim’s family brought the appeal directly to the state seems to be a sticking point for some in the criminal justice community. “This is a case in which the victims rights proponents are looking to expand the rights that they already have in our criminal justice system,” University of Maryland professor Doug Colbert, who was one of Syed’s original lawyers, <a href="https://www.wmar2news.com/infocus/law-professor-gives-his-take-ahead-of-lee-appeal-hearing-in-adnan-syed-case">told WMAR</a> prior to a February hearing on the appeal. “They’re saying that a crime victim should have basically the same rights and role as a prosecuting attorney.” He described any ruling in favor of Lee’s family as “extraordinary.”</p>

<p>But Rendelman points out that Lee’s family isn’t actually asking for more power — just to exercise their right to be present. “They’re not asking for any control over the decision; they just want to be present for it, which is what they have a right to do. The law doesn’t require them to have a say in what happens. The law just requires them to be able to attend.</p>

<p>“Those who have issues with the ruling question whether the victims should have such a big say in what goes on in a criminal procedure. But those on the other side are quite victorious because their position is that victims’ rights should be respected, particularly in a case like this, where they’ve been living with the loss of a family member for 20 years and would like some transparency in how the hearing proceeds.”</p>

<p>Because the prosecution has already decided to drop all charges against Syed, it would be highly unlikely for anything to change the ultimate outcome of a new hearing to vacate his conviction. Indeed, it’s unlikely this hearing, as rare as it is, would even make the news had the families involved not been so high-profile.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This wouldn’t have made the paper had it not been [related to] Adnan Syed,” Rendelman said. “No matter what the case is, each victim’s family deserves the same respect regardless.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The decision to accede to Young Lee’s request to be present at the hearing wasn’t unanimous; the appellate court was <a href="https://www.courts.state.md.us/data/opinions/cosa/2023/1291s22.pdf">divided 2-1</a> over the issue, and the Maryland Supreme Court was divided 4-3, with dissenting Justice Michele D. Hotten <a href="https://www.wisn.com/article/maryland-court-orders-redo-of-hearing-that-freed-adnan-syed-in-serial-case/62018582">writing</a>, “this case exists as a procedural zombie” and that the “doctrine of mootness” — a <a href="https://constitution.findlaw.com/article3/the-mootness-doctrine.html">procedural determination</a> about the actual relevance of the appeal — “was designed to prevent such judicial necromancy.” Effectively, Hotten was arguing that since the decision to vacate Syed’s conviction had already been decided, the back-and-forth in the higher courts over Lee’s right to attend was all superfluous.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What happens next? For now, Syed will likely remain out of jail until the 2022 hearing that freed him can be redone, this time with Young Lee in the court room. All in all, although Syed’s conviction remains reinstated, nothing suggests that Lee’s ability to attend and participate in a new hearing on the motion to vacate will change the already established outcome. If that happened, it would be an utterly extraordinary and unprecedented moment in an already extraordinary case. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, August 30, 12:45 pm ET: </strong>This article was originally published on March 29, 2023. It has been updated to reflect the most recent court decision in Syed’s case.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Matthews</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The case of the nearly 7,000 missing pancreases]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/367812/organ-donation-loophole-pancreas-opo" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367812</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T14:00:50Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T14:00:48Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are some mysteries that I fear I’ll never see resolved. Who was DB Cooper and what happened to him? Who robbed the Gardner Museum of its Vermeer and Rembrandts in 1990? And, most pressingly: where are the thousands of pancreases taken out of Americans’ dead bodies in 2021, 2022, and 2023 that were never [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Valerie Rodriguez (left), one of the first patients in France to receive a pancreatic islets transplant as part of routine care, speaks with Laurence Kessler, professor of diabetology at the University Hospital of Strasbourg (HUS) and member of the French-speaking diabetes society, in Strasbourg, eastern France, on November 14, 2022. | Frederick Florin/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Frederick Florin/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1244771286.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Valerie Rodriguez (left), one of the first patients in France to receive a pancreatic islets transplant as part of routine care, speaks with Laurence Kessler, professor of diabetology at the University Hospital of Strasbourg (HUS) and member of the French-speaking diabetes society, in Strasbourg, eastern France, on November 14, 2022. | Frederick Florin/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There are some mysteries that I fear I’ll never see resolved. Who was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/D._B._Cooper">DB Cooper</a> and what happened to him? Who <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isabella_Stewart_Gardner_Museum_theft">robbed the Gardner Museum</a> of its Vermeer and Rembrandts in 1990? And, most pressingly: where are the <a href="https://www.amjtransplant.org/article/S1600-6135(23)00462-8/abstract">thousands of pancreases</a> taken out of Americans’ dead bodies in 2021, 2022, and 2023 that were never transplanted into anybody?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let me back up. Pancreata (the correct plural form of “pancreas”) are one of those organs that are difficult to live without. Without one, you don’t have insulin to regulate blood sugar or enzymes necessary to digest food. So all donated pancreata come from dead people who register as organ donors. In the US, we outsource the job of collecting organs from dead bodies to private groups called organ procurement organizations, or OPOs. Each OPO has a monopoly on organs in a particular geographic area; there are <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/about/search-membership/?memberType=Organ%20Procurement%20Organizations&amp;organType=%27AL%27&amp;state=0&amp;region=0">56 groups total</a>, some of which only cover part of a state and some of which cover multiple states.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For some time now, independent analysts and investigative reporters have argued that OPOs are underusing deceased donor organs by the tens of thousands. One report from 2019 estimated that every year <a href="https://www.bridgespan.org/bridgespan/Images/articles/reforming-organ-donation-in-america/reforming-organ-donation-in-america-12-2018.pdf">28,000 usable organs</a> (mostly kidneys but also pancreata, hearts, livers, etc.) from deceased donors are never used; another put <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2018/national/organ-transplant-shortages/?utm_term=.806b23dd755d">the number at 75,000</a>. This, when the national waitlist for organs is <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/learn/organ-donation-statistics">more than 100,000 people long</a>.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, OPOs have faced perverse incentives. For instance, they were most often evaluated on the basis of how many organs are recovered per “eligible death,” but “eligible death” is a determination made by the OPOs themselves. That made it easy to juice the stats by, for instance, classifying some deaths as “ineligible” even when the organs were perfectly usable. That made “organs recovered per eligible deaths” go up without actually getting more people organs. OPO contracts with the federal government are <a href="https://archive.triblive.com/local/pittsburgh-allegheny/taxpayers-help-pay-for-organ-donor-groups-parties-rose-parade-expenses/">quite lucrative</a>, which means OPO executives have ample reason to <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/heartless-organ-donation-contractors-lobby-against-a-popular-health-care-initiative-while-pocketing-pandemic-relief-loans">fight hard</a> to retain them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2019, President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/7/10/20687507/triump-kidney-disease-transplant">issued a quite good executive order</a> instructing the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), which oversees OPOs, to change the way they’re evaluated. The order led to two new metrics that were meant to be harder to game. The rule was finalized in December 2020, and — after also being reviewed and approved by the <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/americas-transformative-new-organ-donation-rule-goes-into-effect-over-objections-from-monopolistic-contractors#:~:text=The%20Centers%20for%20Medicare%20and,effective%20on%20March%2030%2C%202021.">Biden administration</a> — <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/02/02/2021-02180/medicare-and-medicaid-programs-organ-procurement-organizations-conditions-for-coverage-revisions-to">took effect in March 2021</a>. It came with real teeth: OPOs that did particularly badly would face decertification, meaning another OPO with a better track record of serving patients would take over their territory.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule had the potential to force OPOs to collect more organs and save thousands more lives every year. But the OPOs quickly figured out a new loophole. And now, a little more than a week after this story was originally published, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/qso-24-19-opo.pdf" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/qso-24-19-opo.pdf">federal regulators are acting to close it</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The birth of the pancreas loophole</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule’s new metrics were meant to be based on objective criteria. It asked OPOs to tally the total number of deceased people 75 and younger with causes of death compatible with donation, and then estimate the number of deceased donors each year as a share of that total population, and the number of organs actually used as a share of that total population. The denominator was now something that OPOs couldn’t tamper with. That meant, hopefully, that they’d be judged solely on how many organs they recovered and transplanted into people — on how many thousands of lives they saved.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while OPOs couldn’t muck with the denominator anymore, they could still muck with the numerators. Being a donor generally means that your organs are used in a transplant, but there’s a carveout for one organ: the pancreas. A <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/app/details/PLAW-108publ362">narrow 2004 law</a> allows researchers running clinical trials to conduct transplants of islet cells (the parts of the pancreas that produce insulin) as a potential cure for diabetes. Because of that law, OPOs could “recover” pancreases for islet cell transplant research, and get credit for recovering more organs under the new rule. But the federal government never asked for any proof that these organs were part of any FDA-approved research.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sure enough, the total number of pancreata that OPOs labeled as for “research” grew from 513 in 2020 to a whopping 3,238 in 2023. The number of donors whose only recovered organ was a pancreas designated for research grew from 25 to 429, according to the <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/">Organ Procurement &amp; Transplantation Network</a>. That’s an over tenfold increase in three years.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-datawrapper wp-block-embed-datawrapper"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="OPOs reported many more pancreas recoveries right after the government started judging them on how many organs they recovered" src="https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/QrbaT/1/" frameborder="0" height="412"></iframe>!function(){"use strict";window.addEventListener("message",(function(a){if(void 0!==a.data["datawrapper-height"]){var e=document.querySelectorAll("iframe");for(var t in a.data["datawrapper-height"])for(var r=0;r&lt;e.length;r++)if(e[r].contentWindow===a.source){var i=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][t]+&quot;px&quot;;e[r].style.height=i}}}))}();
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, Lenny Bernstein, a reporter at the Washington Post who’s been watching this scandal closely, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2023/03/20/organ-transplant-groups-pancreas-collection/">talked to pancreatic researchers</a> who all reported there was no sudden surge in need for pancreases in research projects. Indeed, if you look at the <a href="https://optn.transplant.hrsa.gov/about/search-membership/?memberType=Transplant+Centers&amp;state=-1&amp;region=0">small handful of medical centers</a> that use research pancreata for islet cell transplants, you find that there were only 24 transplants conducted in all of 2023: 22 at the University of Chicago Medical Center, and one each at City of Hope Medical Center outside Los Angeles, and at the Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s 3,238 pancreata recovered for islet cell transplant research in 2023, and only 24 actual transplants conducted that year. Where did the other 3,214 pancreata go? Where did the nearly 7,000 pancreata taken from dead Americans’ bodies over the past three years and not used for transplants go?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The waiting list for people needing just pancreata is <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/learn/organ-donation-statistics/detailed-description#fig1">barely 800 people</a>. That number could be zero if these organs were better allocated. Where are they?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I asked the Association of Organ Procurement Organizations (AOPO), a kind of trade group for the organ procurers, for an explanation. “CMS developed and implemented the current rule governing the use of pancreata for research in 2021. As is required, OPOs have been complying with the rule since that time,” AOPO’s president Dorrie Dils told Vox in a statement. “OPOs have always followed CMS guidance and will continue to do so.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one interpretation. Another is that we could be seeing an attempt by OPOs to get around regulations, and avoid being decertified because they don’t facilitate enough donations. That’s certainly how the <a href="https://www.finance.senate.gov/chairmans-news/wyden-grassley-cardin-young-raise-alarm-over-dramatic-increase-in-pancreata-procurement-">Senate Finance Committee</a>, where a bipartisan group of senators has been investigating the matter, sees it. In a letter to OPOs sent last year, the committee quoted from a listserv of OPO employees. In a thread discussing the new rules, an OPO employee wrote, “If you have a donor with only a pancreas for research, that is an organ donor for the Donor Rate. Otherwise, a donor is any donor with at least 1 organ transplanted. Savvy (or cynical?) OPOs ought to start a pancreas for research program immediately.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Savvy (or cynical?) indeed! In a <a href="https://aopo.org/wp-content/uploads/AOPO-SFC-Pancreas-Research-Statement-03-21-2023.pdf">reply to the committee</a>, AOPO protested that “OPOs have been operating according to the rule” and that the research donations mean “the organ does not go to waste.” Have they not gone to waste? The committee asked OPOs to report back which specific research studies they gave the pancreata to; I know of no OPO that has put out data formally tying each pancreas to a specific study.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This past January, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/qso-24-04-opo.pdf">CMS sent a letter to OPOs</a> reminding them that they could only count pancreases that were actually used for research. But the <a href="https://www.finance.senate.gov/chairmans-news/wyden-grassley-cardin-and-young-call-on-cms-to-strengthen-protections-against-excessive-and-unnecessary-recoveries-of-pancreata-from-organ-donors">Senate committee urged it to take a further step</a>: clarify that only pancreata donated to research approved by the FDA counts under the rule. That is, OPOs cannot make themselves look better and avoid decertification just by recovering pancreata and then sticking them in a freezer. They have to actually get the pancreata into the hands of scientists.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On August 29, CMS took the Senate committee’s advice, <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/qso-24-19-opo.pdf">issuing a memorandum</a> clarifying that “pancreata will be considered ‘used’ for research if they are accepted for use in bona fide islet cell research conducted by a qualified researcher, such as research approved by the National Institutes of Health.” That is, the 24 islet cell transplants in 2023 will count when CMS evaluates OPOs; the other 3,214 pancreata recovered that year might not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a very simple change, but it means greater accountability for OPOs — accountability that could lead to thousands more organs going to people who need them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, August 30, 10 am:</strong> This story was originally published on August 21, 2024, and has been updated to reflect new information that the CMS issued a memorandum, updating its pancreata policy.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Correction, August 22, 1:20 pm: </em></strong><em>A previous version of this story misstated whether a person can live without a pancreas. It’s possible, but difficult.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m an AI skeptic. But one critique misses the mark.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/369502/chatgpt-ai-image-generator-regulation-debate" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369502</id>
			<updated>2024-08-29T20:27:43Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Living in an AI world" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As California advances new AI regulations and companies continue to pour billions of dollars into building the most powerful systems yet, I hear a recurring grumble online: Why is AI being shoved down our throats? What is this good for? Does anyone actually want this?&#160; In one recent Gallup poll, the percentage of Americans who [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A photo of a man wearing glasses. A screen showing Chat GPT and its logo are reflected in the lenses of his glasses. " data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Frank Rumpenhorst/picture alliance via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165203047.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">As California advances new <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/355212/ai-artificial-intelligence-1047-bill-safety-liability">AI regulations</a> and companies continue to pour billions of dollars into building the most powerful systems yet, I hear a recurring grumble online: Why is AI being shoved down our throats? What is this good for? <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91033052/does-anyone-even-want-an-ai-search-engine">Does anyone actually want this</a>?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/648953/americans-express-real-concerns-artificial-intelligence.aspx">one recent Gallup poll</a>, the percentage of Americans who think AI does more harm than good is twice that of those who think it does more good than harm. (However, ‘“neutral” is the most popular answer.) Fed up with AI hype and with AI-generated text everywhere, a lot of us feel like AI is something tech companies are imposing on people who were perfectly happy before, thank you very much.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tech companies are definitely, unambiguously, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/04/technology/openai-culture-whistleblowers.html">being reckless</a>. Only in the field of AI will people claim that their work is <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/1/10/24032987/ai-impacts-survey-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt-openai-existential-risk-superintelligence">moderately likely to lead to mass deaths</a> or even human extinction and then argue they should get to keep doing it totally unregulated anyway. I see where the public’s skepticism is coming from, and I’m skeptical too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But these very real problems with AI don’t make every single complaint about AI correct, and something about the “this is being shoved down our throats” complaint doesn’t sit right with me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One thing that’s easy to forget about <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2023/1/5/23539055/generative-ai-chatgpt-stable-diffusion-lensa-dall-e">generative AI</a> is how new it all is. Ten years ago, none of the tools now in everyday use existed at all. Most of them didn’t exist five years ago, or they were little more than useless party tricks. Two years ago, some early versions of these tools had been developed — but almost no one knew about them. Then, OpenAI gave ChatGPT a friendly (rather than forbiddingly scientific) interface. Two months after its launch, the app had <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-sets-record-fastest-growing-user-base-analyst-note-2023-02-01/">100 million active users</a>.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Organic enthusiasm created a world seemingly replete with AIs. A new AI technology captured the public imagination overnight and droves of people started using it. It’s <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2023/03/21/1070111/google-bard-chatgpt-openai-microsoft-bing-search/#:~:text=Artificial%20intelligence-,Google%20just%20launched%20Bard%2C%20its%20answer%20to%20ChatGPT%E2%80%94and%20it,sidekick%20to%20its%20search%20engine.&amp;text=Google%20has%20launched%20Bard%2C%20the,ChatGPT%20and%20Microsoft's%20Bing%20Chat.">in response to ChatGPT</a> that competitors doubled down on their own AI programs and released their own chatbots.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don’t have to like AI. Your skepticism is profoundly warranted. But the world we live in today is a direct product of ChatGPT’s meteoric rise — and like it or not, that rise was driven by the massive number of people who want to use it.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">There are good reasons for generative AI enthusiasm — and very real drawbacks</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of the resentment of AI I see bubbles up when you try to learn about something and run into a shoddy, AI-generated article mass produced for SEO. It is undeniably deeply annoying for high-quality text to be replaced by low-quality AI text. Especially when, as is often the case, it looks fine at first glance and only upon closer reading do you realize it is incoherent. Many of us have had that experience, and it does pose a serious threat to the culture of sharing authentic work that made the internet great.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While “people trying to put AI slop in our faces” is a highly visible consequence of the AI boom, as is <a href="https://www.bestcolleges.com/research/most-college-students-have-used-ai-survey/">cheating on tests</a> and the purported <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/09/02/technology/ai-artificial-intelligence-artists.html">death of the arts</a>, AI’s valuable uses are often less apparent. But it does have them: It’s <a href="https://github.blog/ai-and-ml/generative-ai/how-generative-ai-is-changing-the-way-developers-work/">ridiculously helpful to programmers</a>, enables new kinds of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/04/arts/infinite-craft-ai-video-game.html">cool and imaginative games</a>, and functions as a crude copy editor for people who could never afford one.&nbsp;<strong> </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I find AI useless for writing, but I frequently use it to extract text from a screenshot or picture that I’d previously have had to type out myself or pay for a service to handle. It’s great at inventing fantasy character names for my weekend D&amp;D game. It’s handy for rewriting text at an easier reading level so I can design activities for my kids. In the right niches, it does feel like a tool for the imagination, letting you skip from vague concepts to real results.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And — again — this technology is incredibly new. It does feel a bit like we’re watching the first light bulbs and <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/people-had-to-be-convinced-of-the-usefulness-of-electricity-21221094/">debating whether electricity is really an improvement</a> or a party trick. Even if we manage to cease the race to build more and more powerful AI systems without oversight (and I really think we should), there is so much more to discover about how to effectively make use of the systems we have.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AI chatbots are mocked while they’re mediocre, but if every single small business could cheaply have a functional live 24/7 customer service chat, that’d actually make it easier for them to compete with large businesses that already have those services. AI might well make that happen in the next few years. If people can more easily realize their ideas, that’s a good thing. If text they found unreadably confusing is now accessible to them, that’s a good thing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AI can be used to check the quality of work, not just generate mediocre-quality work. We don’t have <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.10917">high-quality automated text review</a> for statistical errors and misconduct in scientific papers yet, but it’d be enormously valuable if we did. AI can be used to produce cheap, lousy essays, but it can also give fairly useful feedback on the first draft of a piece — something many authors wish they could receive but can’t.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And many of the most annoying things about AI are a product of a culture that hasn’t yet adjusted to them and responded, both with regulation and with further innovation. I wish that AI companies had been more careful about deploying technologies that overnight made the internet less usable, but I also believe in our ability to adapt. Facebook spent three months full of baffling AI spam, but the company adjusted some content filters and now (on my feed, at least) the spam is mostly gone.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ease of pumping out meaningless marketing copy is a challenge for search engines, which used to assume that having a lot of text made a source more authoritative. But frankly, that was a bad assumption even before ChatGPT, and search engines will simply need to adapt and figure out how to surface high-quality work.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over time, all of the backlash and grumbling and consumer behavior will shape the future AI — and we can collectively shape it for the better.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s why the AI outcomes that tend to worry me have to do with building extremely powerful systems without oversight. Our society can adjust to a lot — if we have time to react, adjust, regulate where appropriate, and learn new habits. AI may currently have more bad applications than good ones, but with time we can find and invest in the good ones. We’re only in real trouble if human values stop being a major input: if we stumble into giving away more and more <a href="https://www.cold-takes.com/how-we-could-stumble-into-ai-catastrophe/">decision-making power to AI</a>. We might do that! I’m nervous!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I’m not too worried about there being lots of bad AI content, or the absurd number of pitch emails I get for unnecessary AI products. We’re in the early stages of figuring out how to make this tool useful, and that’s okay.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Marin Cogan</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why a leading expert on gun violence is sounding alarms about the 2024 election]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369441/political-violence-2024-election" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369441</id>
			<updated>2024-08-29T20:48:33Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s been less than two months since the assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, and while lawmakers and law enforcement are continuing to investigate what happened, the presidential campaign has largely moved on.  Investigators say that the shooter was likely less motivated by political ideology than he was [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Former President Trump on the ground moments after being shot at." data-caption="Former President Donald Trump moments after being shot at during a rally on July 13, 2024 in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161922590.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Former President Donald Trump moments after being shot at during a rally on July 13, 2024 in Butler, Pennsylvania. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s been less than two months since the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360390/trump-shot-assassination-attempt-shooter-bullet-butler-pennsylvania-biden-secret-service-updates">assassination attempt on former President Donald Trump</a> at a rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, and while lawmakers and law enforcement are continuing <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2024/08/26/trump-assassination-house-task-force-butler/">to investigate what happened,</a> the presidential campaign <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368004/donald-trump-policy-positions-issues-guide">has largely</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/367990/kamala-harris-policy-positions-issues-guide">moved on</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Investigators say that the shooter was likely <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/28/us/politics/thomas-crooks-trump-fbi.html">less motivated by political ideology</a> than he was by a desire to commit a mass shooting. But for researchers who study <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360792/political-violence-trump-shooting-rally-butler-assassination">political violence</a>, there are <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360557/trump-assassination-attempt-republican-response-political-violence-irresponsible">still concerns about the risk</a> that the US will experience more dangerous incidents this election cycle and beyond. The assassination attempt is the latest event — after the <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-66540466">intimidation of election officials and workers</a> by Trump supporters in 2020 and the attempted <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23513019/january-6-committee-report-trump-2020-election-insurrection">insurrection</a> on January 6, 2021, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/how-hateful-rhetoric-connects-to-real-world-violence/">not to mention rhetoric from the Republican candidate and his allies</a> — to heighten their worries. In July, a group of legal scholars, national security experts, and law enforcement called on elected <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/national-security/4836866-a-plan-to-address-political-violence-before-election-day/">officials to create</a> election safety task forces on a state and national level to respond to and monitor threats pertaining to the election. (The Department of Justice launched an <a href="https://www.justice.gov/voting/election-threats">election threat task force in 2021</a>, but <a href="https://oregoncapitalchronicle.com/2024/06/14/election-workers-worry-that-federal-threats-task-force-isnt-enough-to-keep-them-safe/">election workers</a> and officials still say they are <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/poll-election-officials-finds-concerns-about-safety-political">worried for their safety</a>.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gun violence researchers are also concerned. Garen Wintemute, a physician and founder of <a href="https://health.ucdavis.edu/vprp/aboutus/">UC Davis’s Violence Prevention Research Program</a>, has been studying gun violence <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/496412a">since the 1980s</a>. In late 2021, the center turned its attention to political violence. Last year, it <a href="https://health.ucdavis.edu/vprp/news/headlines/new-study-looks-at-attitudes-towards-political-violence/2023/09">published the results of a large survey</a> digging into Americans’ beliefs on the issue. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Small but concerning proportions of the population consider violence, including lethal violence, to be usually or always justified to advance political objectives,” Wintemute and his colleagues <a href="https://injepijournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40621-023-00456-3">write</a>. Nearly 19 percent of respondents <a href="https://health.ucdavis.edu/vprp/news/headlines/new-study-looks-at-attitudes-towards-political-violence/2023/09">said that</a> “having a strong leader” was more important than having a democracy. Almost 14 percent predicted a civil war in the United States in the next few years, and just under eight percent said that in the next few years, if they found themselves in a situation where they believed political violence was justified, they planned to be armed with a gun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The center is preparing to release a new survey this fall, with its latest insights on the appetite for political violence in the United States. Before they do, Wintemute shared with Vox some early takeaways from its findings, along with some ideas about what people can do to create a country less vulnerable to political violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What does the 2024 data reveal about the risk for political violence in the US?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Garen Wintemute:</strong> We’re continuing to see a sustained level of support for the idea of political violence, and of willingness to be a combatant if civil war comes about. There is a clear connection with some subsets of firearm ownership, but also with racism and sexism and homophobia — pretty much any brand of fear and loathing you might want to mention. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What we’re seeing bears out hunches and predictions people had years ago, but there are two pieces of good news: One is that gun purchasing did eventually fall back to essentially baseline levels [from <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/353878/new-guns-us-violence">2020 and 2021</a>.] It’s a leading indicator and we watch it like a hawk. The other piece of good news is that rates of gun violence were frighteningly high in 2020 and 2021, but fell in 2022 and 2023. So far, we’re not seeing an increase from 2023 in 2024.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I’ll put an asterisk on that. We’re living through this in real time. I think there’s probably agreement among the people who look at this closely that the set of circumstances most likely to produce political violence in this country in the next few months are a closely contested election, with momentum swinging to Democrats, and with high-profile instances of political violence having already occurred.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those are the circumstances we are in today. The barometer fluctuates a little, but right after the assassination attempt I got asked, did you think this was going to happen, what happened to Donald Trump in Pennsylvania? You can&#8217;t predict the specifics, but for weeks, I’d been ending every day, thinking: Wow, we made it another day. Yes, it’s going to happen. With that same level of certainty, I think it will happen again. Whether it will involve an elected official as a target, I can’t say. But we’ve opened the door to political violence this election season, and there are still some leaders using rhetoric that enables violence. And we will all pay a price for that, I suspect. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You don’t think this is the last we’ve seen of political violence this election cycle?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I personally think that large-scale political violence is really, really unlikely. I feel more sanguine about that prediction, given our 2024 data. We asked people, suppose that there were a right-wing insurgency or a left-wing insurgency. Would you support either over the government? In both cases, most respondents said neither. I take that as good news. Large-scale violence is really unlikely. A few months from now, I might feel differently. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But sporadic outbreaks, particularly if the battleground states remain really close — is it possible? Sure. Might there be attempts to intimidate election officials? Absolutely.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most of us, most of the time, and some of us, all of the time, do not think that violence is how we solve problems in this country. We will react negatively when people use violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What we really need to work on is producing a culture that is not receptive to the propagation of political violence, so it might happen here and there but we won&#8217;t see a sustained chain of events.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Where is political violence most likely to come from?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Probably the most influential social movement in the US right now is <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/10/8/17941066/the-trump-prophecy-liberty-university-christian-nationalism">Christian nationalism</a>, which holds not just that the United States, by tradition, is and ought to be a Christian nation, but that end times are coming and we need to be ready. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think of this partly as a researcher, and partly as a clinician. Psychological injury is like physical injury; it can heal, but it leaves a scar. It leaves the person changed. So people who have sustained psychological injury after injury, or they’ve seen their privileged status in this society erode, need to make sense of it all. So how do some make sense of it all? They find somebody to blame, which is where you get xenophobia and replacement theory, and so on. You find a way to make it right. You start to think, I’m willing to kill and be killed in order to preserve the thing I believe in. That is how wars start.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What works at preventing political violence? Do we know?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We do have some data on this. We asked people: If a civil war broke out, how likely would you be to do any of the following things? They started with leaving the country and ended with killing a noncombatant from the other side, with a bunch of options in between. In the middle was participate as a combatant. It was a small number of people who said yes. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We asked the people who said it was not at all likely that they’d participate as a combatant, would you change your position from if you were urged to do so by family, friends, religious leaders, community leaders, or the media? And conversely, we asked the people who said they would be combatant, would you change your position in response to those same groups?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The people who started with saying “I’m not going to be a combatant” were not open to change. It didn’t matter the source of influence. For the would-be combatants, a big number would switch if their family asked them not to, or friends, or even some media sources. I was literally dancing around this office, seeing the numbers on the screen, because that leads directly to intervention. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Basically, the vast majority of people out there who do not think violence is justified need to talk it up, because you’re not going to change your mind and we can prove it. But the people on the other side, if you talk to them — whether we’re talking about individuals talking to family and friends, or media outlets putting it in their programming — we can create a climate of nonacceptance for political violence. And in doing that, we can expect that it will work.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris’s big housing plan has a big problem]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369525/kamala-harris-housing-plan-corporate-landlords-homeownership" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369525</id>
			<updated>2024-08-30T15:47:05Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-30T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris wants to make housing more affordable — and to help more Americans build wealth by investing in real estate. These are the twin goals of the Democratic nominee’s recently unveiled housing agenda. And they are largely incompatible. Harris aims to reduce Americans’ housing costs by making residences more abundant: She wants [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kamala Harris points while smiling, standing on a stage and wearing a navy suit." data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris gestures after speaking on the fourth and last day of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, on August 22, 2024. | Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2167183195.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris gestures after speaking on the fourth and last day of the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, on August 22, 2024. | Saul Loeb/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris wants to make housing more affordable — <em>and</em> to help more Americans build wealth by investing in real estate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are the twin goals of the Democratic nominee’s recently unveiled housing agenda. And they are largely incompatible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/16/business/harris-housing-plan/index.html">aims</a> to reduce Americans’ housing costs by making residences more abundant: She wants to incentivize localities to allow more multifamily housing construction, open up federal lands for residential development, and provide tax incentives to builders who construct low-cost “starter” homes for first-time buyers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, Harris has <a href="https://x.com/MediumBuying/status/1822241289737281962">declared</a> that “a home is more than simply a house” as it provides “the opportunity to build wealth.” To help Americans who currently cannot afford to build wealth through homeownership, Harris has vowed to provide first-time homebuyers with up to $25,000 in down-payment support. To expand the number of single-family homes available to families looking to buy, meanwhile, Harris would deny tax benefits to investors <a href="https://nlihc.org/resource/harris-campaign-releases-plans-lower-housing-costs">who buy large numbers</a> of single-family homes and turn them into rental properties.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of this platform is laudable. Certainly, Harris has articulated a more coherent vision for cutting Americans’ housing costs than her Republican counterpart has offered. And it is also refreshing to see a Democrat put America’s housing shortage at the center of their campaign: This week, Harris is promoting her plans for achieving housing affordability through a tour of swing states and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mHgmtsNxT8c">a new TV ad</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, there is a profound tension at the heart of Harris’s agenda, one that reflects the core contradiction in America’s broader housing politics: The easier it is for people to afford housing, the harder it will be for homeowners to build significant wealth through their real-estate investments.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To no small extent, Democrats must therefore choose between Harris’s two imperatives: Do they want to make housing more affordable, or ensure that investing in housing is a sound wealth-building strategy?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the merits, there is little question that liberals should prioritize making housing cheaper. There is nothing progressive about putting property owners’ return-on-investment above less privileged Americans’ access to shelter. Further, promoting homeownership as a wealth building strategy also fails many homeowners. Concentrating one’s savings in a single asset is a perilous investment strategy, especially for America’s least privileged groups.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, what’s substantively ideal is not always politically wise. And this is especially true in the realm of housing policy.&nbsp;The Democratic Party cannot afford to ignore homeowners’ interests, since they <a href="https://nlihc.org/resource/new-census-data-reveal-voter-turnout-disparities-2022-midterm-elections">comprise a large majority of registered voters</a>. If Democrats somehow succeeded in making housing so abundant that it tanked home values, Republicans might win California and New York soon after.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, although tanking home prices isn’t politically tenable, slowing their growth in the name of affordability probably is. And for people looking to buy or rent a home, it makes a big difference whether home values rise faster or slower than wages. If paychecks grow more rapidly than home values, then housing becomes more affordable for workers, even if the nominal price of a house goes up. In that scenario, fewer renters would struggle to keep roofs over their heads, while homeowner backlash to increasing affordability would be limited, since, on paper, houses would appear more valuable than when they were purchased.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pursuing that outcome, however, means making housing a worse investment for new buyers, especially relative to putting their savings into diversified index funds. Democrats therefore should not go out of their way to encourage middle-class Americans to invest in housing. And they certainly should not adopt policies that privilege homeowners over renters. Unfortunately, some aspects of Harris’s housing agenda do both.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Some of Harris’s policies put homeowners above renters</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Through both her rhetoric and her policy proposals, Harris is encouraging Americans in general — and lower middle-class ones, in particular — to build wealth through homeownership.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider a family that can just barely afford to purchase a starter home. If they choose to plow nearly all their savings into such a property, Harris’s plan would give them $25,000. If they decide to rent and put their savings in the stock market instead, Harris’s agenda would provide them with no comparable cash assistance.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris’s plan further incentivizes homebuying over renting by deterring large investors from renting out single-family homes, a policy that would expand the supply of housing available to homebuyers at the cost of shrinking the supply available to renters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are not sound or progressive policies for three reasons. First, they prioritize the needs of homebuyers over renters, despite the fact that the latter are generally less economically privileged. Second, if Harris succeeds in making housing a lot more affordable, then many of the first-time buyers attracted into homeownership will have made an unwise investment. And third, homeownership is a perilous wealth-building strategy for less privileged Americans even today, when prices are high and housing is scarce.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To appreciate the inequitable nature of Harris’s plan, consider this: If you are economically secure enough to afford homeownership with a little bit of assistance, then Harris would give you $25,000. If you’re too poor to buy a home even with that aid, her plan would give you $0 in wealth-building subsidies. By contrast, some of congressional Democrats’ ideas for promoting wealth creation — such as “<a href="https://www.vox.com/22268500/baby-bonds-black-white-wealth-gap-booker-pressley">baby bonds</a>,” a program that would provide Americans with a lump sum of investment capital when they turn 18 — do not deny aid to the very neediest.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More counterintuitively, it is not necessarily equitable to bar large investors from buying and leasing single-family homes, as such a policy effectively reduces the supply of such housing available to renters.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Curiously, Harris’s agenda would allow investors to rent out large numbers of apartments, but punish them if they choose to buy and lease single-family homes. Why should we support corporations expanding the rental stock of apartments, but oppose them increasing that of houses? Put differently, why is there a presumption that homebuyers should enjoy privileged access to single-family homes?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I suspect that this assumption reflects the profoundly regressive values that undergird single-family zoning itself: As Dartmouth economist William Fischel <a href="https://bpb-us-e1.wpmucdn.com/sites.dartmouth.edu/dist/6/2312/files/2021/03/02-03.pdf">has persuasively argued</a>, affluent suburbs first started banning multifamily housing partially in response to the advent of buses, which made it possible for low-income workers to live in their towns. The point of the single-family norm was therefore to keep poor people out of rich areas. When large real-estate holders buy or build such homes and rent them out, they marginally undermine class segregation by making it possible for a group of lower-income workers to pool resources and rent a home in a middle-class area.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, I do not think that reinforcing class segregation is the conscious aim of Harris’s policy. There is a <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/01/housing-crisis-hedge-funds-private-equity-scapegoat/672839/">widespread belief</a> among progressive Democrats that large investors buying up homes is a major driver of rent growth. The theory is that when a big corporation owns lots of housing in an area, they have more price-setting power, as there is less competition among different landlords.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As an account of why housing costs are high today, however, this is <a href="https://www.vox.com/22524829/wall-street-housing-market-blackrock-bubble">totally implausible</a>. As of 2022, institutional investors owned <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/06/realestate/wall-street-housing-market.html">only 3 percent</a> of all single-family rental units in America. That year, the largest owner of single-family rental homes, Invitation Homes, owned just 0.6 percent of all such houses on the rental market. Monopoly ownership of single-family rental housing cannot be a leading driver of housing costs because it does not exist. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats should certainly combat any instance of collusion between landlords, such as that <a href="https://www.curbed.com/article/real-page-justice-department-landlord-software-price-fixing.html">alleged in the lawsuit</a> against property management software company RealPage. And they should also impose stiff penalties on all landlords — large or small — who fail to honor all of their legal obligations to their tenants. But it does not follow that the party should make it harder for renters to find a single-family home to lease by arbitrarily discouraging companies from buying (or building) and then renting out such properties.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>To make housing affordable, you need to make it a worse investment</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second problem with Harris’s plan is that — if the laudable parts of her agenda succeed in making housing more abundant — then many first-time homebuyers will regret investing in a house.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, housing is only a good investment if its value rises faster than inflation and wages. Otherwise, in real terms, it loses value. If housing becomes more affordable over time, then it becomes a bad investment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s true that homeownership can theoretically aid wealth-building merely by forcing workers to save a significant portion of their incomes (since it compels them to dedicate a chunk of each paycheck to paying down a mortgage). But this alone does not make housing a sound vehicle for wealth creation. Between 2011 and 2022, 86 percent of the median homeowner’s gain in housing wealth derived from rising prices, while only 14 percent came from paying down their mortgage, according to a <a href="http://www.nar.realtor/blogs/economists-outlook/single-family-homeowners-typically-accumulated-225K-in-housing-wealth-over-10-years">report</a> by the National Association of Realtors.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And for housing to become affordable, we need the rate of home price appreciation to slow by a lot. The share of working-class renters who are severely rent-burdened — meaning more than 50 percent of their income goes to housing costs — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/11/us/politics/rent-burdens-low-income-life.html">has nearly tripled</a> over the past two decades to 17 percent, a record high.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A massive housing shortage is also elevating costs for those higher up the income spectrum. According to Zillow, the United States currently <a href="https://www.zillow.com/research/affordability-housing-shortage-34153/">has about 4.5 million fewer homes</a> than aspiring households. Were that number to fall anywhere near zero, housing would become a drastically worse investment, even as it became much easier and cheaper for tenants and would-be homebuyers to secure.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Homeownership is already a risky investment strategy, especially for the disadvantaged</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Harris fails to make housing more affordable, many Americans would still be better off not tying up their savings in a house. And this is especially true of lower-income and Black Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the Atlantic’s Jerusalem Demsas <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2022/12/homeownership-real-estate-investment-renting/672511/">has written</a>, homeownership is already a perilous financial strategy. It effectively requires households to make an enormous bet on price trends in a single real-estate market. Yet it is difficult for real-estate analysts — much less ordinary working-class families — to anticipate which cities will see their home values rise over a two-decade period, and which will not. Thirty years ago, Cleveland’s home prices <a href="https://www.clevelandfed.org/publications/economic-commentary/2021/ec-202122-evaluating-homeownership-as-the-solution-to-wealth-inequality">were higher</a> than both San Francisco’s and America’s national average. Yet investing in Cleveland real estate in 1994 would have been a bad financial decision. Between that year and April 2024, the typical Cleveland home saw its <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CEXRNSA">value grow by 142 percent</a> in nominal terms. Over that same period, by contrast, the <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/quote/%5EGSPC/history/?period1=757382400&amp;period2=1724878580">S&amp;P 500’s value shot</a> up by roughly 1,000 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For affluent households, the unpredictable whims of real-estate markets aren’t that big of a problem. The upper middle-class can afford both homeownership and a diversified portfolio of financial products. Indeed, according to the <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2022/12/homeownership-real-estate-investment-renting/672511/">Atlantic’s analysis</a> of Federal Reserve data, the top 10 percent stores more wealth in stocks and mutual funds than in housing. And this is even more true of the richest 1 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But less affluent households can’t buy a home without concentrating their savings in a single asset. Yet it is precisely this population that Harris’s plan is ostensibly trying to nudge into homeownership by subsidizing starter-home purchases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If homeownership is perilous for lower middle-class households in general, this is especially true for Black ones. Houses in communities with large Black populations tend to <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/racial-disparities-home-appreciation/">increase in value</a> at a much lower rate than those in overwhelmingly white communities. This partly reflects the fact that Black Americans are disproportionately economically disadvantaged, but also reflects the persistence of white racism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Demsas notes, a <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/devaluation-of-assets-in-black-neighborhoods/">2018 Brookings Institution study</a> found that homes in majority-Black neighborhoods are worth 23 percent less than homes in communities with little to no Black residents — even when controlling for amenities (such as school performance, economic opportunity, and crime).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, the value of a house is determined by the subjective perceptions of homebuyers. In the US, most potential homebuyers are not Black. And Brookings’ research suggests that, whether consciously or not, many white Americans prefer white neighbors to Black ones, and this racial preference ends up getting priced into real-estate values.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For this reason, many Black working-class and middle-class households would be better off investing in stocks than a house. When you buy an S&amp;P 500 index fund, the return on your investment will be unaffected by your skin color. White investors do not (and cannot) put a premium on purchasing stocks from other white people. Your pigmentation is not visible on E-trade.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Add in that an index fund also diversifies an investor’s risk — effectively allowing them to bet on the future performance of the US economy writ large, rather than, say, the future performance of housing prices in Cleveland — and it seems clear that many Black households are poorly served by homeownership.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, the strongest counter to every financial argument against homeownership is that — in today’s economy — renting may be even worse. People need a place to live more than they need safe financial assets. Homeownership eventually enables people to enjoy more affordable and stable housing than they could secure on the rental market. If the alternative to buying a home is being forced to move every couple years as shifting demand prices you out of your neighborhood, then homeownership is liable to make sense from both a financial and quality-of-life perspective.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this is less a good argument for subsidizing home purchases than one for making rental housing cheaper. In a world of abundant rental housing, families will be able to enjoy some of homeownership’s present benefits without its attendant costs. When the supply of rentals is large relative to demand, rental price growth is slow, reducing tenants’ vulnerability to displacement. Unlike homeownership, however, the stability provided by cheap rental housing comes paired with flexibility. Selling a home and buying a new one tends to be more expensive than merely moving. And such costs can make it harder for people to pursue unexpected opportunities or meet emergent needs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, as already noted, in a world where Harris achieves what she promises — and makes housing affordable for renters and buyers alike — most Americans will be better off investing in a diverse array of financial assets than staking most of their wealth on a single piece of real estate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, if Harris genuinely believes that she can actually deliver housing affordability, then she should not encourage lower middle-class Americans to buy a home.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The politics of housing in America are bad</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Roughly <a href="https://www.census.gov/housing/hvs/current/index.html">65 percent of American</a> households own a home. And since homeowners <a href="https://www.gsb.stanford.edu/insights/if-you-lived-here-you-might-be-voter-now">vote at a higher rate than renters,</a> they account for even more than 65 percent of the electorate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Clearly, then, Democrats cannot afford to engineer a collapse in housing prices. And even slowing the rate of housing price growth could come at a political cost. A <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/08965803.2023.2184910">2023 study</a> found that counties where housing prices rose the most over the four years before Election Day were significantly more likely to support incumbents than counties where home values rose less.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, making housing more affordable — without making it so cheap that housing prices fall in nominal terms — probably wouldn’t be politically detrimental. Many homeowners are future homebuyers. And some do not live where they would ideally like to, as they were priced out of a more desirable market. If Democrats make it possible for them to afford a condo in their favorite city, they probably won’t be too upset about that. More broadly, making it more tenable for people to move to major cities would <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/09/06/opinion/housing-regulations-us-economy.html">increase economic growth and productivity</a>, developments that voters tend to reward.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, Harris’s impulse to try to bring down housing costs — without challenging the idea that homeownership should be financially lucrative — is a sound one. And her proposals for increasing housing supply are all commendable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But subsidizing down payments for homebuyers and shrinking the stock of single-family rental properties are neither politically necessary nor substantively worthwhile. If Democrats want to help young people build wealth, they can provide cash grants to renters and homebuyers alike. If they want to reduce the profit margins of corporate landlords, they can erode regulatory obstacles to building, thereby increasing construction and reducing the value of existing rental housing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What they should <em>not </em>do is make American housing policy even more biased against renters, or nudge lower middle-class families into making investments that will only pay off if our nation’s housing crisis never ends.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, August 30, 8:30 am ET:</strong> An earlier version of this article said that institutional investors own 3 percent of all rental units in America. They own 3 percent of the rental market in single-family homes.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Your guide to the Brittany Mahomes-Donald Trump drama, such as it is]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/369543/brittany-mahomes-likes-trump-instagram" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=369543</id>
			<updated>2024-08-29T23:26:28Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-29T21:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[At any given second, millions of people are liking various things on Instagram. Pictures of sunsets and sunrises, recipes for keto brownies, videos of viral K-pop dances — there’s something for everyone. But right now there’s one specific semi-famous woman whose social media activity (liking, unliking, posting) has drawn widespread attention: Brittany Mahomes.  Best known [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Two women hugging and smiling from inside a suite at a football game." data-caption="Taylor Swift and Brittany Mahomes hanging out at a Chiefs game in 2023. | Stacy Revere/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stacy Revere/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1829598694_848f0a.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Taylor Swift and Brittany Mahomes hanging out at a Chiefs game in 2023. | Stacy Revere/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">At any given second, millions of people are liking various things on Instagram. Pictures of sunsets and sunrises, recipes for keto brownies, videos of viral K-pop dances — there’s something for everyone. But right now there’s one specific semi-famous woman whose social media activity (liking, unliking, posting) has drawn widespread attention: <a href="https://nypost.com/2024/08/29/sports/brittany-mahomes-is-brushing-off-haters-after-patrick-mahomes-advice/">Brittany Mahomes</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Best known as the wife of Super Bowl-winning Kansas City Chiefs quarterback Patrick Mahomes, Brittany Mahomes’s national profile has, for the moment, eclipsed her husband’s. That’s due to her perceived support for former President Donald Trump and his promised political policies. This all started when Mahomes liked and then unliked an Instagram post from the former president that <a href="https://www.tmz.com/2024/08/28/brittany-mahomes-trump-support/">outlined his 2024 platform</a>.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under any normal circumstances, only <a href="https://www.instagram.com/brittanylynne/?hl=en">Brittany Mahomes’s biggest fans</a> would be deeply invested in whether she desires mass deportation and an Iron Dome missile defense system built over America. But Mahomes has connections to Taylor Swift, the most famous woman in the world. That very valuable association is why the social media likes and dislikes of an American football WAG (that’s “wives and girlfriends”) has become a pop culture saga. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re here to answer your most pressing questions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Wait, what happened?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Brittany Mahomes has become a moment in this news cycle because she has been liking and unliking social media posts supporting former President Donald Trump and his various policies. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-m53xGu3MY/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;ig_rid=a69d4fdc-9933-4d07-904b-7e88d71753a8">August 13</a>, Trump’s Instagram account posted a platform promising to “seal the border and stop the migrant invasion,” “keep men OUT of women’s sports,” and “Carry out the largest deportation operation in American history.” He also plans to cut “federal funding for any school pushing Critical Race Theory, Radical Gender Ideology, and other inappropriate racial, sexual, or political content on our children.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://x.com/tiredasslesbian/status/1826972546052325629">Eagle-eyed internet sleuths</a> spotted that Mahomes “liked” and “unliked” the xenophobic and transphobic dog whistle salad last week. And though Mahomes doesn’t follow Trump on her account, it seems as though the narrative was already set: Mahomes supports some of Trump’s most pernicious and divisive politics. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The news that people saw Mahomes’s social media activity eventually circled its way back to Mahomes, who was not pleased that people noticed her public actions. To that, she posted a message via <a href="https://www.glamour.com/story/brittany-mahomes-message-haters-liking-pro-trump-instagram-post">Instagram Story</a> (Instagram Stories are temporary), denouncing her haters and telling them they were emotionally damaged adults: </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>I mean honestly, to be a hater as an adult, you have to have some deep rooted issues you refuse to heal from childhood. There’s no reason your brain is fully developed and you hate to see others doing well.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/brittany-mahomes-slams-haters-instagram-015629071.html?.tsrc=daily_mail&amp;segment_id=DY_GOLDLIST_TEST&amp;ncid=crm_19908-1202929-20240825-0&amp;bt_user_id=6JRyBTwoYQzmdnLH3pN2QzNZuI5lUW99eij89uny52Y9VmIpDsEpGGO5JWIe&amp;bt_ts=1724580120381&amp;guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAKBxQxF-fo9Px30l0B6tcZu6KwckIA3BbKQcCQTyBfmdE-eLjhpbxsDzUFDj5U0riA9M2Jsg-zMbF58SDN42jXuDiD764vw6o2Wv0F_tzmN_zscfp-UWDMzLVQM4dRmTihmI2MylQw9k_ZcZWJAySNmtqdVp7JDgb2AdfXCpwmLA">Mahomes seemed</a> to see the negativity surrounding her social media proclivities as a sign that people were mad that she was succeeding, rather than that people were disappointed in her presumed politics, that is to say what appeared to be her beliefs about how the country should be run and how others should be treated. Mahomes also <a href="https://x.com/PopCrave/status/1828870083847884899">liked a pro-Trump comment</a> under a recent post, eliminating any ambiguity that her previous liking and unliking spree might be an accident. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, Mahomes doubled down and <a href="https://people.com/brittany-mahomes-doubles-down-calling-out-critics-after-backlash-8701908">shared a post</a> that read, “Contrary to the tone of the world today … You can disagree with someone, and still love them. You can have differing views, and still be kind.” She did not comment on or explain the relative kindness of the views she appeared to support.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>And sorry, who is Brittany Mahomes again? Do people regularly care about Brittany Mahomes in general?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Brittany Mahomes is primarily famous because she’s married to Kansas City Chiefs quarterback Patrick Mahomes, who was her high school sweetheart. She’s also the <a href="https://www.elle.com/culture/celebrities/a45601704/who-is-patrick-mahomes-wife-brittany-mahomes/">co-owner</a> of the Kansas City Current, a team in the National Women’s Soccer League, which was the sport she excelled in through college, and she was a Sports Illustrated <a href="https://www.si.com/sports-illustrated/brittany-mahomes-makes-her-sports-illustrated-swimsuit-debut-01hxt4v7tp05">swimsuit model</a> in May of this year. She and Patrick have two children and are currently expecting a third. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore/TIMESERIES/1724935800?hl=en-US&amp;tz=300&amp;geo=US&amp;hl=en&amp;q=brittany+mahomes,brittany+mahomes+trump&amp;sni=3">biggest “Brittany Mahomes” search spike</a> of the past year was during the Super Bowl when people were ostensibly trying to figure out whether Patrick Mahomes had a wife and if she was hanging out with Taylor Swift (more on this in a bit). </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2160725206.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.696771244586,100,78.606457510828" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Patrick Mahomes and Brittany Mahomes at Wimbledon this year. | Karwai Tang/WireImage via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Karwai Tang/WireImage via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, the name Brittany Mahomes is not one the average American gives a lot of thought to, and her political views would probably warrant even less consideration. She’s not a political scholar nor is she some kind of kingmaker. Prior to her online statements about “haters,” the <a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/explore/TIMESERIES/1724935800?hl=en-US&amp;tz=300&amp;geo=US&amp;hl=en&amp;q=brittany+mahomes,brittany+mahomes+trump&amp;sni=3">American public wasn’t furiously Googling</a> “Brittany Mahomes loves Trump?” or “Brittany Mahomes Republican.” There’s a bit of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Streisand_effect">Streisand effect</a> happening, where the more Mahomes doubles down, the more attention she draws to the kerfuffle. There’s possibly a timeline in which Mahomes lets the entire saga run its course and fade away as football season begins. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One thing to note is that her pro-Trump political stance appears to many to be at odds with Patrick’s identity. Patrick is biracial, with a Black father and a white mother. And it would seem that Brittany’s liking that pro-Trump post, especially his bits about attacking critical race theory (an attack that would minimize the historical <a href="https://www.vox.com/22443822/critical-race-theory-controversy">Black American experience</a>) would be insensitive if not incongruent with her husband’s identity. <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/364172/trump-nabj-black-voter-journalist-racist-kamala-harris-indian-american">Trump has recently attacked</a> Vice President Kamala Harris’s biracial ethnicity, claiming that she “turned” Black for political gain. Harris’s father is Jamaican.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Patrick hasn’t been open about who he’s voting for, but he has spoken up about police brutality and <a href="https://andscape.com/features/patrick-mahomes-saw-george-floyds-death-and-chiefs-quarterback-knew-he-couldnt-stay-on-the-sideline/">supported Black Lives Matter</a>. In 2020, he <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/watch-patrick-mahomes-and-other-nfl-stars-demand-the-nfl-condemn-racism-and-admit-wrong-in-silencing-players-from-peacefully-protesting-2020-06-05">urged the NFL</a> to denounce and separate itself from racism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But more important than her husband and the reason everyone’s talking about Brittany at all is that she’s allegedly friends with Taylor Swift — the most famous person on the planet. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>So this is all because she’s friends with Taylor Swift?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pretty much!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How long have they been friends?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift and Mahomes seem to have formed their close bond after Swift started dating <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2023/9/25/23889682/taylor-swift-travis-kelces-date-nfl-chiefs-game">Travis Kelce</a>, a Chiefs tight end who plays with Patrick Mahomes. The two women likely cultivated their relationship during Chiefs games last year, when they <a href="https://www.today.com/popculture/taylor-swift-brittany-mahomes-rcna121662">were photographed</a> together multiple times at the VIP suites, even potentially wearing matching necklaces. It wasn’t long until they took their friendship on the road, with Taylor including Brittany on a <a href="https://www.eonline.com/photos/36639/taylor-swifts-nyc-night-out-with-selena-gomez-brittany-mahomes-more">girls’ night in NYC</a> with the rest of her squad. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Wait, what does Taylor have to say about Trump?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift has spoken up against Trump in the past, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2020/01/24/taylor-swift-politics-miss-americana-donald-trump">acknowledging in her 2020 documentary</a><em> Miss Americana</em> that she regretted not speaking up about him and his policies during the 2016 election. Ahead of the 2020 election, <a href="https://x.com/taylorswift13/status/1266392274549776387">Swift tweeted</a> that Trump was cavorting with white supremacists and promised “we will vote you out in November.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But ahead of the upcoming 2024 election, Swift has been less vocal about Trump and publicly more non-partisan.<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/taylor-swift-urges-282-million-instagram-followers-vote-super-tuesday-rcna141848">In March</a>, she urged her fans to vote for “the people who most represent YOU into power.” Kelce, her boyfriend, has appeared in Covid-19 vaccine and <a href="https://www.thestreet.com/restaurants/bud-light-boycott-movement-goes-after-taylor-swift-and-travis-kelce">Budweiser</a> commercials, <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/2023/4/12/23680135/bud-light-boycott-dylan-mulvaney-travis-tritt-trans">two targets</a> of right-wing protests. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At last year’s Super Bowl, Swift and Kelce found themselves in the middle of a kooky <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/12/us/politics/biden-tiktok-super-bowl.html">right-wing conspiracy theory</a> that President Joe Biden rigged the game in Kelce and Kansas City’s favor, all to get some of that sweet Swift attention. The gist: that Kelce and Swift were liberal, so Biden tilted the game in their favor.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/19/politics/donald-trump-taylor-swift-ai/index.html">Trump also recently posted an AI image</a> falsely suggesting he has the support of her fans. Swift has not <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/24/us/ai-content-laws-taylor-swift-trump/index.html">officially responded</a> to that “acceptance.”<strong> </strong>Still, Swift has yet to endorse a presidential candidate. In what’s likely to be a close election, <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/08/swifties-kamala-harris-zoom/679637/">some of Swift’s biggest fans</a> are urging her to throw her support behind Harris. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Okay, so … Brittany Mahomes isn’t actually Taylor Swift, she’s just a friend. Why do her perceived politics matter?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mahomes’s social media meltdown came at a peculiar time for megastar Swift. Mahomes and her husband spent the weekend with Taylor Swift at the singer’s Rhode Island estate on August 24. Swift was reportedly hosting a birthday party for pal Blake Lively that weekend. Lively has been having a difficult time in the press recently because of a <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/367451/blake-lively-it-ends-with-us-press-tour-controversy">feud with co-star Justin Baldoni</a> during the filming of their movie <em>It Ends With Us</em>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift’s getaway weekends are famous for being luxurious and over the top, but also as invitations only her very best friends receive. Swift is known for picking and choosing her friends from the world of beautiful and notable people and then visibly hanging out with them. Ever since Swift’s <em>1989</em> tour, where her pals — ranging from Fifth Harmony to Gigi Hadid — joined her onstage, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/24134809/taylor-swift-tortured-poets-department-matty-healy-joe-alwyn">Swift’s friendships</a> with the hippest, smartest, kindest, and most beautiful women in pop culture have become a crucial part of her image. All these people who call Swift friends are culturally cool, which makes Swift culturally cool. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1717057814.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.7460602225,100,78.507879555" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Taylor Swift, Brittany Mahomes, and Blake Lively hanging out! One of these women may or may not be deeply into mass deportation! | Kevin Sabitus/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Sabitus/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, Swift’s friendships are the most human thing about her. They’re her way of signaling to the public that as different as she is from the rest of the population — a billionaire making hit music and selling all kinds of albums — she’s relatable as a good friend. Arguably, Swift’s friends have defined the singer almost as much as she’s defined herself. The Mahomes’s presence in Rhode Island would indicate that Brittany is indeed a bestie. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, not unlike how fans are trying to puzzle out the dynamic of Brittany’s relationship with her husband, Swifties are trying to figure out how Brittany’s politics figure into her friendship with Swift. Since the singer has been relatively quiet, they’re trying to get a read on Swift’s current feelings about Trump. Or, possibly, get a read on how much longer Brittany and Swift will remain friends. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift’s friendships have always been a crucial and visible part of her image.<strong> </strong>And Brittany Mahomes may have just made a mark on that image that Taylor Swift didn’t agree to.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
