<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-11-21T19:02:57+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump wants to stack the DOJ’s leadership with his personal lawyers]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/criminal-justice/385714/donald-trump-blanche-sauer-bove-justice-department" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=385714</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T14:02:57-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T14:01:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Investigations into Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Former Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL), an accused sex offender known for his firm loyalty to Trump, will not lead the Department of Justice. (Gaetz has denied wrongdoing.) Several other lawyers President-elect Donald Trump has close personal ties to, however, remain up for top DOJ jobs. This means that, regardless of who eventually becomes attorney general, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump and his attorney Todd Blanche" data-caption="President-elect Donald Trump has chosen Todd Blanche, the criminal defense lawyer in his New York hush money trial, to hold the No. 2 role in the Justice Department. | Mark Peterson/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Mark Peterson/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2154742600.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President-elect Donald Trump has chosen Todd Blanche, the criminal defense lawyer in his New York hush money trial, to hold the No. 2 role in the Justice Department. | Mark Peterson/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Former Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL), an <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/384967/matt-gaetz-donald-trump-attorney-general">accused sex offender known for his firm loyalty to Trump</a>, will not lead the Department of Justice. (Gaetz has denied wrongdoing.) Several other lawyers President-elect Donald Trump has close personal ties to, however, remain up for<strong> </strong>top DOJ jobs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This means that, regardless of who eventually becomes attorney general, at least three of the highest jobs in the Justice Department, the office that brings federal prosecutions, will be held by people whose records suggest they will advance Trump’s personal interest. And unlike Gaetz, Trump’s nominees for these three jobs have serious legal credentials and institutional knowledge, and thus are likely to be effective in advancing those interests.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/14/us/politics/todd-blanche-deputy-attorney-general-trump.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">chose Todd Blanche</a>, the criminal defense lawyer in his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24126338/trump-new-york-trial-stormy-daniels">New York hush money trial</a> (the one where he faced charges related to money paid to keep a sexual encounter quiet), to be deputy attorney general. That’s the No. 2 job in the Justice Department. The DAG, as this position is known within the department, wields tremendous power over federal criminal prosecutions. If successfully appointed, Blanche will <a href="https://www.justice.gov/doj/office-deputy-attorney-general#:~:text=The%20mission%20of%20the%20ODAG,organizational%20units%20of%20the%20Department.">supervise the 93 regional US attorneys</a> who bring the bulk of all federal prosecutions in the United States. So Blanche will have a great deal of authority over who is prosecuted.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Trump wants <a href="https://x.com/kleavittnh/status/1857199006146822425">John Sauer</a>, the lawyer who represented him in the Supreme Court case holding that Trump is allowed to use the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">powers of the president to commit crimes</a>, to serve as solicitor general. The role <a href="https://www.justice.gov/osg/about-office">oversees the Justice Department’s legal strategy in the Supreme Court</a>, including arguing many of the most important cases. They also decide which cases the DOJ will appeal if the federal government loses a case in a trial court.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another one of Trump’s personal criminal defense lawyers, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/11/14/trump-todd-blanche-deputy-attorney-general">Emil Bove</a>, will serve as principal associate deputy attorney general, and will hold the DAG spot on an acting basis until Blanche or some other Trump nominee is <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/384356/trump-recess-appointments-explained-senate-confirmation-thune-scott-cornyn-cabinet">confirmed or otherwise formally appointed to the job</a>. Unlike the DAG and the solicitor general, Bove’s new role <a href="https://rollcall.com/2024/11/14/trump-picks-legal-defense-team-for-top-justice-department-roles/">does not require Senate confirmation</a>. So he will be able to move into this job on the first day of Trump’s second presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t the first time a president has tried to put one of his personal lawyers in a position of high responsibility within government. President Lyndon Johnson, for example, <a href="https://thinkwy.org/columns/justice-abe-fortas-life-as-a-lawyers-lawyer-and-a-greek-tragedy/">named Abe Fortas</a>, his friend and personal lawyer, to the Supreme Court in 1965. If you know anything about Fortas’s very brief tenure on the Court, you may know that <a href="https://www.brennancenter.org/our-work/analysis-opinion/cautionary-tale-abe-fortas">appointment didn’t end well</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Based strictly on their résumés, all three men are conventionally qualified for these jobs. Both <a href="https://04q.7c7.myftpupload.com/betsy-wright-2/">Blanche</a> and <a href="https://blanchelaw.com/emil-bove/">Bove</a> previously worked as federal prosecutors for nine years before entering private practice. Sauer is a former law clerk to Justice Antonin Scalia who <a href="https://fedsoc.org/contributors/d-john-sauer">previously served Missouri’s solicitor general</a>. It’s easy to see all three joining the Justice Department without much controversy if they were picked by, say, President Nikki Haley.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Trump talks often about using the DOJ to target his political adversaries and people he views as foes. An NPR report on October 22 found that Trump “<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/21/nx-s1-5134924/trump-election-2024-kamala-harris-elizabeth-cheney-threat-civil-liberties">made more than 100 threats to prosecute or punish perceived enemies</a>.” That includes a threat to, in Trump’s words, “appoint a real special prosecutor to go after the most corrupt president in the history of the United States of America, Joe Biden, and the entire Biden crime family.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump also accused former Rep. Liz Cheney, a prominent Republican critic of the incoming president, of “TREASON” and threatened “<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/21/nx-s1-5134924/trump-election-2024-kamala-harris-elizabeth-cheney-threat-civil-liberties">TELEVISED MILITARY TRIBUNALS</a>.” (Which, if they were to actually happen, would presumably take place in the Defense Department’s legal structure, but could involve some DOJ personnel.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s decision to name Gaetz, a staunch loyalist, to lead the Justice Department created <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/384967/matt-gaetz-donald-trump-attorney-general">considerable alarm</a>. Historically, the White House has <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/383152/donald-trump-criminal-indictments-supreme-court-reelected">obeyed strong norms</a> against interfering with Justice Department prosecutorial decisions, but these norms have no legal force. A Trump loyalist like Gaetz could have torn down this barrier altogether. (If someone like him is confirmed atop the Justice Department, that barrier could still go.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s decision to appoint his personal lawyers to top DOJ jobs is equally concerning. Federal lawyers are supposed to represent the interests of the United States, not of any particular politician, while they work for the government. But Trump has selected three people who aren’t simply accustomed to representing his personal interests, but who have also likely collected considerable legal fees from him.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Blanche, Sauer, and Bove’s conventional résumés also mean that, if they use their DOJ posts to pursue Trump’s personal campaign of vengeance, they are likely to be fairly effective in doing so. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Blanche and Sauer still need to be confirmed — assuming that Trump doesn’t <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/384356/trump-recess-appointments-explained-senate-confirmation-thune-scott-cornyn-cabinet">use recess appointments</a> or some other method to get around the Senate confirmation process. But if Trump gets his way, his attorney general will now be backed by people who know the Justice Department and the culture of elite federal lawyers quite well.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, November 21, 2 pm ET: </em></strong><em>This story, originally published November 15, has been updated to reflect the fact that former Rep. Matt Gaetz is no longer the nominee for attorney general.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Gaetz, Trump’s uniquely unqualified pick for attorney general, withdraws]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/384967/matt-gaetz-donald-trump-attorney-general" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=384967</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T13:55:09-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T13:55:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Donald Trump’s nominee for attorney general, former Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL), has withdrawn from consideration. He was nominated just over a week ago. Since then, numerous details of a House investigation into alleged sexual misconduct — including a CNN report on Thursday that investigators were told Gaetz twice had sex with a 17-year-old girl — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Gaetz speaking into a microphone and pointing." data-caption="Matt Gaetz posted on X that he’s withdrawing his name from consideration as attorney general because “my confirmation was unfairly becoming a distraction to the critical work of the Trump/Vance Transition.” | Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2178146087.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Matt Gaetz posted on X that he’s withdrawing his name from consideration as attorney general because “my confirmation was unfairly becoming a distraction to the critical work of the Trump/Vance Transition.” | Mario Tama/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Donald Trump’s nominee for attorney general, former<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/13/politics/matt-gaetz-attorney-general?cid=external-feeds_iluminar_google">Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL)</a>, has withdrawn from consideration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was nominated just over a week ago. Since then, numerous details of a House investigation into alleged sexual misconduct — including a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/21/politics/matt-gaetz-second-sexual-encounter-minor/index.html">CNN report</a> on Thursday that investigators were told Gaetz twice had sex with a 17-year-old girl — have been made public. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gaetz has repeatedly denied any wrongdoing, but <a href="https://x.com/mattgaetz/status/1859649045553402285">posted Thursday afternoon on X</a> that he was removing himself from consideration as attorney general because “my confirmation was unfairly becoming a distraction to the critical work of the Trump/Vance Transition.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gaetz was a startling pick, not just because of the sexual misconduct allegations that have long loomed over him. He is also<strong> </strong>a longtime Trump loyalist who could have tried to remake the Department of Justice. The department has traditionally adhered to strong norms against interference by the president; Trump and his allies have been explicit <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381094/trump-second-term-2024-election-justice-department-civil-rights">in arguing that should change</a>. Trump has also repeatedly called for legal action against his political enemies, including <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/21/nx-s1-5134924/trump-election-2024-kamala-harris-elizabeth-cheney-threat-civil-liberties">promising</a> to “appoint a real special prosecutor to go after the most corrupt president in the history of the United States of America, Joe Biden, and the entire Biden crime family,” in 2023.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Enforcing those sorts of threats would have fallen to Gaetz, had he been confirmed by the Senate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before being nominated to be attorney general, Gaetz received press primarily for two things. One is his <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/1/23898555/kevinn-mccarthy-speakership-matt-gaetz">longstanding feud with former House Speaker Kevin McCarthy</a> (R-CA), who was eventually ousted in no small part because of Gaetz. The other is the aforementioned<strong> </strong>string of sexual misconduct allegations. Again, Gaetz denied these allegations, and the Justice Department <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/doj-decides-not-charge-rep-matt-gaetz-sex-trafficking-investigation-rcna70839">dropped its investigation into them in 2023</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Gaetz had ended up running that same department, he’d be in a uniquely powerful role. The attorney general is be tasked with overseeing all federal prosecutions, providing legal advice to the president and the Cabinet, and has the final say on any legal stance that the United States takes in court. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of greater significance perhaps is the fact that the attorney general has enormous authority over who is prosecuted, who is allowed to get away with committing federal crimes, and who might be targeted for politically motivated prosecutions in an authoritarian administration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has repeatedly promised “<a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/382696/donald-trump-wins-2024-election-results-democracy">retribution</a>” against his Democratic rivals. And his fellow Republicans on the Supreme Court ruled last July that he can order the Justice Department to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/366855/supreme-court-trump-immunity-betrayal-worst-decisions-anticanon">bring politically motivated prosecutions without consequence</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the first Trump administration, Trump reportedly wanted to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/11/20/18105462/trump-clinton-comey-order-justice">order the Justice Department to prosecute</a> his former political opponent Hillary Clinton and former FBI Director James Comey, but was dissuaded from doing so by White House Counsel Don McGahn. Gaetz’s strong support for Trump, by contrast, made it seem he’d have been much less likely to resist such an order. Whether Trump’s next nominee is cut from the same loyalist cloth remains to be seen.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Just who is Matt Gaetz?<strong>&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gaetz has a law degree, and he <a href="https://gaetz.house.gov/about">did previously practice law in northwest Florida</a>. He’s been a representative since 2017, and became known both for stunts on the House floor — like wearing a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/03/04/politics/gaetz-coronavirus-gas-mask/index.html">gas mask</a> to protest masking policies during the coronavirus pandemic — as well as his <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/10/23/20929023/house-republicans-impeachment-stunt-trump">staunch support for Trump</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2021, it was revealed that Gaetz was the subject of an <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/30/us/politics/matt-gaetz-sex-trafficking-investigation.html">investigation into allegations of sexual misconduct</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The allegations arose out of his relationship with Joel Greenberg, a former county-level tax collector who was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/12/01/politics/joel-greenberg-sentencing/index.html">sentenced to 11 years in prison</a> by a federal judge in 2022. Greenberg pled guilty to a wide range of crimes, including underage sex trafficking, wire fraud, identity theft, and conspiring to defraud the federal government. Judge Gregory Presnell, who sentenced Greenberg, said he’s “never seen a defendant who has committed so many different types of crimes in such a relatively short period.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to CNN, Greenberg also “cooperated extensively with the Justice Department’s <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/12/01/politics/joel-greenberg-sentencing/index.html">sex-trafficking probe into GOP Rep. Matt Gaetz</a>.” Among other things, Greenberg reportedly told investigators that he <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4751778-matt-gaetz-joel-greenberg-sex-trafficking-florida/">witnessed Gaetz having sex with a 17-year-old girl</a>. (Gaetz in 2021 issued a blanket denial of the allegations via a statement from his office, writing: &#8220;No part of the allegations against me are true.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a general rule, sex offenses such as soliciting prostitution are handled by state-level prosecutors, as the Constitution only gives the federal government <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3801442224983217117&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr">limited authority over sex crimes</a>. The Justice Department can get involved, however, in narrow circumstances.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The department’s investigation into Gaetz looked into <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/30/us/politics/matt-gaetz-sex-trafficking-investigation.html">whether he had sex with this teenager and paid for her to travel with him</a>. It is a <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/2423#g">federal crime to transport someone</a> someone across state lines, with the intent that they engage in prostitution or “illicit sexual conduct.” The most serious violations of this statute carry a maximum sentence of 30 years in prison.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any event, the Justice Department <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/congress/doj-decides-not-charge-rep-matt-gaetz-sex-trafficking-investigation-rcna70839">eventually decided not to charge Gaetz</a>. Its reasons for declining to do so have not been made public, but the lack of charges does not necessarily clear him of the allegations. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There was also a separate <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/witness-tells-house-ethics-committee-matt-gaetz-paid/story?id=111217102">House ethics investigation into Gaetz</a>. A report on that investigation’s findings was nearly complete when Gaetz resigned from the House upon being nominated for attorney general. That report hasn’t been made public, though reporters have begun to obtain information gathered by House investigators.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Besides CNN’s reporting on allegations of sexual encounters with a minor, other outlets, have reported that investigators were told Gaetz <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/11/20/gaetz-investigation-house-ethics-committee-vance/">compensated a number of women for sex</a>. The House is reportedly in <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/19/politics/matt-gaetz-house-ethics-testimony-lawyer/index.html">possession of photos</a> taken during times two women who said they were paid for sex were in Gaetz’s company. Other witnesses called by the ethics committee said they were paid to <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cew2z48rp70o">attend parties that Gaetz also attended</a>, where attendees used drugs and had sex. Again, Gaetz has denied any misconduct.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reports also emerged that <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/11/20/congress/readout-from-vance-gaetz-meetings-00190682">some Republican senators</a> were growing concerned by these allegations, raising questions of whether Gaetz could get the votes needed for confirmation. Also complicating matters was Gaetz’s generally poor reputation on Capitol Hill. In 2023, for example, Sen. Markwayne Mullin (R-OK) said that “<a href="https://x.com/mkraju/status/1709765049051381761">there’s a reason why no one in the [Republican] conference defended</a>” Gaetz after seeing some of the evidence against him.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sen. Markwayne Mullin on Matt Gaetz: “We had all seen the videos he was showing on the House floor … of the girls that he had slept with. He’d brag about how he would crush ED medicine and chase it with an energy drink so he could go all night.”<br><br>Gaetz responds: “This is a lie” <a href="https://t.co/h55hj0ag29">pic.twitter.com/h55hj0ag29</a></p>&mdash; Manu Raju (@mkraju) <a href="https://twitter.com/mkraju/status/1709765049051381761?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2023</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As <a href="https://x.com/ezraklein/status/1856798502484910130">New York Times columnist Ezra Klein writes</a>, Trump’s decision to nominate Gaetz should be read as an effort to gauge whether Republican senators will permit him to take absurd and dangerous actions. “These aren&#8217;t just appointments,” Klein writes of Gaetz and Defense Secretary nominee Pete Hegseth, who also faces sexual misconduct allegations, “They&#8217;re loyalty tests.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Depending on who Trump choses in Gaetz’s stead, senators may have one less test to take.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, November 21, 1:55 pm ET:</em></strong><em> This story was originally published on November 13 and has been updated with Gaetz withdrawing his nomination for attorney general and the circumstances leading up to it.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kenny Torrella</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Americans are eating less meat. And more meat. How?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386374/grocery-store-meat-purchasing" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=386374</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T11:51:52-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T12:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Animal Welfare" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future of Meat" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent decades, the average American has steadily increased their consumption of meat, milk, and eggs, to a staggering 224 pounds of red meat and poultry, 280 eggs, 20.5 pounds of fish, and 667 pounds of dairy per year — among the highest rates in the world. The dominance of animal products on Americans’ plates [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Meat in the deli section" data-caption="The average American’s meat consumption is among the highest in the world. | Jeffrey Greenberg/Education Images/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Jeffrey Greenberg/Education Images/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-1189380056.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The average American’s meat consumption is among the highest in the world. | Jeffrey Greenberg/Education Images/Universal Images Group via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent decades, the average American has steadily increased their consumption of meat, milk, and eggs, to a staggering <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/gallery/chart-detail/?chartId=103767">224 pounds of red meat and poultry</a>, <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/183678/per-capita-consumption-of-eggs-in-the-us-since-2000/#:~:text=The%20demand%20of%20eggs%20has,eggs%20per%20capita%20by%202024.">280 eggs</a>, <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/charts-of-note/charts-of-note/?topicId=46955c72-296b-46cc-993a-43a016a66d7b#:~:text=U.S.%20residents%20consumed%20an%20average,shellfish%E2%80%94per%20capita%20in%202021.">20.5 pounds of fish</a>, and <a href="https://www.idfa.org/news/recorddairyconsumption#:~:text=The%20average%20American%20consumed%20667,and%20yogurt%20adding%200.7%20pounds.">667 pounds of dairy</a> per year — among the highest rates in the world. The dominance of animal products on Americans’ plates has had grave consequences for animals, nearly all of which are <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24079424/factory-farming-facts-meat-usda-agriculture-census">factory-farmed</a>, and has also accelerated <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/3/20/24105735/peak-meat-livestock-emissions-plant-based-climate-deadline">climate change</a> and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/8/31/23852325/farming-myths-agricultural-exceptionalism-pollution-labor-animal-welfare-laws">polluting</a> of America’s waterways.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But these numbers are just population-wide averages — they don’t tell us much about the diverse range of dietary habits among 335 million Americans, nor about how many people swear off meat and other animal products altogether.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Understanding rates of vegetarianism and veganism, in particular, is tricky because people aren’t always reliable narrators of their own diets. Somewhere between <a href="https://animalcharityevaluators.org/blog/is-the-percentage-of-vegetarians-and-vegans-in-the-u-s-increasing/">2</a> to <a href="https://www.vrg.org/journal/vj2020issue4/2020_issue4_poll_results.php">6 percent</a> of Americans surveyed say they’re vegetarian, but many of these same people also report they’ve <a href="https://animalcharityevaluators.org/blog/is-the-percentage-of-vegetarians-and-vegans-in-the-u-s-increasing/">recently consumed meat</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/processing-meat-newsletter-signup" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/pages/processing-meat-newsletter-signup">Processing Meat newsletter</a></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/processing-meat-newsletter-signup" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/pages/processing-meat-newsletter-signup">here</a> for <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect">Future Perfect</a>’s biweekly newsletter from <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/marina-bolotnikova" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/authors/marina-bolotnikova">Marina Bolotnikova</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/kenny-torrella" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/authors/kenny-torrella">Kenny Torrella</a>, exploring how the meat and dairy industries shape our health, politics, culture, environment, and more. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Have questions or comments on this newsletter?</strong> Email us at futureperfect@vox.com!</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Surveys on vegetarianism and meat consumption are “notoriously unreliable,” <a href="https://www.zachfreitasgroff.com/">Zach Freitas-Groff</a>, an economist at the University of Texas at Austin, told me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an attempt to understand what people are actually eating, Freitas-Groff and two fellow economists — <a href="https://www.trevorwoolley.com/">Trevor Woolley</a> at the University of California, Berkeley and Carl Meyer at Stanford University — reviewed people’s grocery receipts. The team analyzed tens of thousands of households’ grocery purchases from 2005 to 2020 to see how Americans’ meat consumption had changed over time. Their findings were <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4867295">published in June</a> as a working paper — not yet peer-reviewed, so the results should be viewed as tentative — by the University of Chicago Booth School of Business. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their findings represent a growing chasm in American meat consumption: The number of households that avoid meat has increased slightly, while all other households have increased their meat purchases by an average of nearly 15 percent by weight relative to other foods. Overall grocery sales declined during this period, as Americans ate more of their meals outside the home, but as a share of groceries, meat purchases increased significantly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From 2005 to 2020, the share of households that didn’t purchase any meat at the grocery store increased from 4.1 to 4.6 percent — a 12 percent jump. The share of households purchasing no animal products — meat, milk, or eggs — doubled, from a tiny 0.5 percent to a still-tiny 1 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The increase in meat avoiders is promising, but over 15 years, the increase appears very modest,” <a href="https://www.cgu.edu/people/joshua-tasoff/">Joshua Tasoff</a>, an economics professor at Claremont Graduate University who was not involved in the study, told Vox in an email.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-20-at-4.20.04%E2%80%AFPM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.364279160145,100,73.271441679711" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="From 2005 to 2020, the average share of groceries that were meat (by weight) rose from 7.7 percent to 8.8 percent — a 14.3 percent increase. | Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" data-portal-copyright="Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-20-at-4.21.50%E2%80%AFPM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,5.3773811322767,100,89.245237735447" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="From 2005 to 2020, the share of households that didn’t purchase meat at the grocery store rose from 4.1 percent to 4.6 percent — a 12 percent increase. | Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" data-portal-copyright="Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" /></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The authors are hesitant to make sweeping generalizations about the state of American meat consumption based on these findings. The study only looked at food purchased at the grocery store, they note, which accounts for about <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/gallery/chart-detail/?chartId=109781">two-thirds of caloric intake</a>, while the other third is eaten at restaurants and schools, which was not included in the study. The data also excludes meat sold at grocery store deli counters, including both raw meat and meat in prepared deli dishes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the paper provides a more granular view into consumers’ relationship with meat than we’ve had before, dovetailing with other recent research findings, like a 2023 study showing that just <a href="https://news.tulane.edu/pr/how-mere-12-americans-eat-half-nations-beef-creating-significant-health-and-environmental">12 percent</a> of Americans — mostly men and older people — eat 50 percent of the nation’s beef.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tasoff called the study an “impressive paper” that uses the best available data for consumer analysis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The study’s time period, from 2005 to 2020, coincides with a growth in news coverage of farm animal welfare — a time in which numerous animal rights groups grew from tiny grassroots organizations into well-oiled machines; <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/8/31/9223391/undercover-videos-meat-america">undercover investigations into factory farms</a> gained national attention; around a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23745935/proposition-12-pigs-pork-california-eggs-veal-hens">dozen states</a> passed farm animal welfare laws; cultural icons like <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/newsbeat-47085214#">Beyoncé</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384508/billie-eilish-singer-songwriter-vegan-climate-animal-rights-activism-future-perfect-50">Billie Eilish</a> promoted the benefits of plant-based eating; and plant-based meat and milk, made by companies such as Beyond Meat, Impossible Foods, and Oatly, went <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/5/28/18626859/meatless-meat-explained-vegan-impossible-burger">mainstream</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But can increased media attention on factory farming — resulting from a growth in animal rights activism — and better vegetarian products explain the shift away from meat among a small but increasing share of American households? That might be part of it, the researchers concluded, but most of the shift, they found, can be attributed to other factors, including rising meat prices.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Digging into the data on America’s shifting meat consumption</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around two-thirds of the increase in meat avoidance, the researchers estimate, is attributable to higher meat prices and to people buying less food at grocery stores and more at restaurants and elsewhere.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The remaining third? Some of it could stem from older generations dying and younger people becoming heads of households. According to the paper, households in which the head was born after 1980 are 50 percent more likely to avoid meat and around twice as likely not to buy any animal products compared to other households.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2004, these households made up just 1 percent of the sample; by 2020, they accounted for 15 percent. If this trend holds, it could lead to a continued increase in households abstaining from meat in the decades to come, representing a bright spot in the paper’s otherwise discouraging findings. (<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/738851/vegan-vegetarian-consumers-us/">Younger generations</a> also tend to <a href="https://today.yougov.com/consumer/articles/27440-veggie-meat-burger-poll">report higher rates</a> of vegetarianism, flexitarianism, pescetarianism, and veganism in surveys.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The difference among age groups is even more stark when looking at rates of all animal product avoidance. About 2.5 percent of households whose heads were born after 1990 didn’t purchase any animal products; for other age groups, the share hovers around 0.5 to 1 percent.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-2 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-20-at-4.15.29%E2%80%AFPM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,14.094998106827,100,71.810003786346" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-20-at-4.15.44%E2%80%AFPM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.631907332556,100,74.736185334889" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="“AP” is short for animal product. | Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" data-portal-copyright="Freitas-Groff et al (2024)" /></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the study didn’t attempt to explain why younger people are avoiding animal products at such higher rates, it’s not unreasonable to think that animal advocacy — often directed at younger generations — could be changing social mores. That said, younger consumers have less money, so they could be more sensitive to rising meat prices, and they’re also <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/webdocs/publications/86401/eib-186.pdf">more likely to eat away from home</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The researchers also looked at whether the growth in media coverage of factory farming played a role in meat avoidance.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It “depends on the model we use,” Woolley wrote in an email. “Taken all together, it looks like media coverage probably played a role, but it&#8217;s hard to determine the magnitude of the effect given that it isn&#8217;t consistently statistically significant (unlike the effect of prices and total grocery purchase volume). It does seem to hold some explanatory power though.”&nbsp; </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/j.1477-9552.2010.00266.x">2011 study</a> found that from 1991 to 2008, media coverage of cruelty on pig and poultry farms led to reduced demand for pork and poultry by <a href="https://agmanager.info/sites/default/files/AW%2520Media%2520Demand%2520Impacts%2520%28NIAA%2520_4.12.2011%29.pdf">2.6 percent and 5 percent</a>, respectively.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the role of plant-based meat alternatives, while they’ve generated a lot of buzz in the media and pop culture, and the sector’s sales have grown significantly in recent years, it’s still far too small a market to explain why more households have moved away from meat. The study found that plant-based meat products had no discernible displacement effect on animal meat sales. However, some of the most popular brands, like Beyond Meat and Impossible, didn’t become widely available in grocery stores until the final years of the data used in the paper.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plant-based milks like oat and soy, however, displaced cow’s milk on a nearly 1-to-1 basis.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Meat’s price isn’t right</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The overall picture painted by the study is grim for factory-farmed animals and our warming planet. A small number of households have started avoiding meat at the grocery store in recent decades, but they’re overshadowed by all other households, which seem to be buying more meat.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The findings illustrate how critical the price of meat is to consumer behavior — a reality that’s painfully obvious to economists but often neglected in advocacy focused on animal cruelty. Work to change people’s hearts and minds may only go so far; changing the sticker price consumers see at the grocery store would likely have a much greater impact.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite rising food prices over the last two decades, meat and other animal products remain relatively cheap. That’s not because raising and slaughtering animals is an inexpensive endeavor, but because livestock companies have been <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/8/31/23852325/farming-myths-agricultural-exceptionalism-pollution-labor-animal-welfare-laws">exhaustively deregulated</a>, which in turn has diffused their costs throughout society.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Farmed animals pay the cost with their <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/3/9/22967328/animal-cruelty-laws-state-federal-exemptions-pennsylvania-martin-farms-dairy-calves-dehorning">suffering</a>, as do wild animals in the form of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22287498/meat-wildlife-biodiversity-species-plantbased">mass deforestation</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/8/31/23852325/farming-myths-agricultural-exceptionalism-pollution-labor-animal-welfare-laws">polluted rivers</a>. Many farmers pay the cost by taking on a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect-podcast/21363914/chicken-factory-farming-debt">mountain of debt</a>, while slaughterhouse workers pay the cost in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2018/jul/05/amputations-serious-injuries-us-meat-industry-plant">lost fingers and limbs</a>. Ultimately, all of us pay it in the form of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22905381/meat-dairy-eggs-climate-change-emissions-rewilding">climate change</a> and increasingly <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/1/8/23542789/big-meat-antibiotics-resistance-fda">ineffective antibiotics</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If livestock producers were to internalize these costs — and if we were to <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/11/22/23471771/cory-booker-meat-farming-industrial-agriculture-accountability-act">do away</a> with much of the <a href="https://www.ewg.org/news-insights/news/2024/10/usda-livestock-subsidies-top-59-billion">subsidies</a> doled out to industry — meat would cost a lot more, causing some consumers to reduce or eliminate their meat purchasing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to True Price, a Dutch nonprofit that estimates the environmental cost of food, internalizing the environmental harms alone (excluding costs like animal cruelty and public health) of certain animal products would increase their price between <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2024/09/19/climate/food-costs-protein-environment.html">two- and five-fold</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Beef increases from $5.34 to $27.36 per pound</li>



<li>Cheese increases from $3.74 to $7.50 per pound</li>



<li>Chicken increases from $2.20 to $4.03 per pound</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Advocating for raising meat prices, especially after an election in which inflation and rising grocery bills played a <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/385932/biden-inflation-record-worse-unpopular-mistakes">major role</a> in ousting the incumbent party, feels — to put it lightly — insensitive and politically risky. But at the same time, consumers enjoy low meat prices at a steep cost to society, while polluting meat companies <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/meat-packers-profit-margins-jumped-300-during-pandemic-white-house-economics-2021-12-10/">celebrate record profits</a>. Some governments are reconsidering this longstanding deregulatory paradigm.<br><br>Just this week, the Danish government passed a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20nq8qgep3o">modest tax</a> on livestock emissions, and it’s also <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384515/rune-christoffer-dragsdahl-vegetarian-society-denmark-animal-welfare-future-perfect-50">investing in programs</a> to make plant-based foods, which are much more environmentally friendly than meat, more affordable. If we’re serious about ensuring planet Earth is habitable for future generations, and mitigating one of humanity’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/363550/factory-farming-human-progress-sustainable-food-movement">greatest moral crimes</a>, the rest of us will need to follow their lead.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Communications</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Vox Releases 2024 Future Perfect 50 List Celebrating Inspiring Changemakers]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/press-room/386975/vox-releases-2024-future-perfect-50-list-celebrating-inspiring-changemakers" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=386975</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T09:06:06-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T08:15:16-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vox Press Room" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vox today released the 2024 Future Perfect 50 list, its third annual celebration of the thinkers, innovators, and changemakers who are working to make the future a better place. This year’s project is Vox’s most ambitious yet, including dedicated profiles of each honoree and interviews with a select few. The Future Perfect 50 includes both [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Option2_LeadArt_FP50.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Vox </strong>today released the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation"><strong>2024 Future Perfect 50</strong></a> list, its third annual celebration of the thinkers, innovators, and changemakers who are working to make the future a better place. This year’s project is Vox’s most ambitious yet, including dedicated profiles of each honoree and interviews with a select few. The Future Perfect 50 includes both familiar names such as director <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384510/christopher-nolan-director-writer-producer-oppenheimer-storytelling-future-perfect-50"><strong>Christopher Nolan</strong></a>, recording artist <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384508/billie-eilish-singer-songwriter-vegan-climate-animal-rights-activism-future-perfect-50"><strong>Billie Eilish</strong></a>, and Michelin-starred chef and founder of World Central Kitchen <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386585/jose-andres-world-central-kitchen-gaza-asheville-sevilla-trump"><strong>José Andrés</strong></a>, and up-and-coming changemakers such as climate educator <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation?section=isaiashernandez"><strong>Isaias Hernandez</strong></a>, neuroscientist <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384522/kaela-singleton-neuroscience-alzheimers-black-in-neuro-future-perfect-50"><strong>Kaela Singleton</strong></a>, and AI justice advocate <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation?section=sneharevanur"><strong>Sneha Revanur</strong></a>. The list honors individuals doing groundbreaking work across six categories:</p>

<ul>
<li>Protecting animal rights</li>



<li>Aligning on AI</li>



<li>Fighting global poverty and health threats</li>



<li>Expanding the mind</li>



<li>Combating climate change</li>



<li>Imagining the future</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Future Perfect 50 has always been more than just a list — it&#8217;s a snapshot of human potential and a roadmap to a better tomorrow,” writes <strong>Bryan Walsh</strong>, Vox editorial director, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation?section=editorsletter">in an introductory essay</a>. “As you read about this year&#8217;s honorees, we hope you&#8217;ll be inspired not just by their achievements, but also by their fundamental belief that progress is possible and that individual actions can catalyze systemic change.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to the list, video interviews with author and philanthropist <strong>John Green </strong>and chef <strong>José Andrés </strong>will be shared across Vox’s social media channels.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The full list of this year’s honorees is below:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Protecting animal rights&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Rune-Christoffer Drasgdahl</li>



<li>Katie Cantrell</li>



<li>Brenda Sanders</li>



<li>Elissa Lane and Jayasimha Nuggehalli</li>



<li>Billie Eilish</li>



<li>Monica Chen</li>



<li>Dulce Ramirez</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Imagining the future&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Christopher Nolan</li>



<li>L.M. Sacasas</li>



<li>Niko McCarty</li>



<li>C. Thi Nguyen</li>



<li>Patrick Hsu and Silvana Konermann</li>



<li>Liu Cixin</li>



<li>Deb Chachra</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Aligning on artificial intelligence&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Anton Korinek</li>



<li>Ellie Pavlick</li>



<li>Jaime Sevilla</li>



<li>Shannon Vallor</li>



<li>Daniel Kokotajlo</li>



<li>Nora Belrose</li>



<li>Scott Wiener</li>



<li>Dan Hendrycks</li>



<li>Sneha Revanur</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Fighting global poverty and health threats&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>John Green</li>



<li>Adar Poonawalla</li>



<li>Shruti Rajagopalan</li>



<li>Andrew Chan and Yin Cao</li>



<li>José Andrés</li>



<li>Christian Happi</li>



<li>Lillian Musila</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Combating climate change&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Matthew Hayek</li>



<li>Daniel Swain</li>



<li>Ayana Elizabeth Johnson</li>



<li>Isaias Hernandez</li>



<li>David Keith</li>



<li>Vaclav Smil</li>



<li>Emma Hakansson</li>



<li>Robin Wall Kimmerer</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Expanding the mind&nbsp;</strong>
<ul>
<li>Rafael Yuste</li>



<li>Nita Farahay</li>



<li>Jonathan Birch</li>



<li>Kaela Singleton</li>



<li>Jeff Sebo</li>



<li>Sara Imari Walker</li>



<li>Michael Levin</li>



<li>Alison Gopnik</li>



<li>Iain Couzin</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Anna North</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[America’s literacy crisis isn’t what you think]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/386286/kids-reading-literacy-crisis-books" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=386286</id>
			<updated>2024-11-20T18:53:30-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T07:45:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Books" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Education" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story originally appeared in&#160;Kids Today, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&#160;Sign up here for future editions. “Kids can’t read anymore.” We heard this refrain earlier this month, when some connected a decline in reading among young people, as well as a shift toward getting news and information from short-form video, with the recent presidential [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Students in the library at PS 124 in New York City on February 2, 2022." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-1368286123.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Students in the library at PS 124 in New York City on February 2, 2022.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/family/369020/kids-children-generation-alpha-gen-school" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kids Today</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/kids-today-newsletter-policy-childhood-policy-culture" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Kids can’t read anymore.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We heard this refrain earlier this month, when some <a href="https://x.com/ishaantharoor/status/1854187377943515637">connected a decline in reading</a> among young people, as well as a shift toward getting news and information from short-form video, with the recent presidential election victory of Donald Trump. But the concerns about kids’ reading have been piling up for years, with educators and other commentators worrying that students can’t recognize letters, that kids’ novels are falling out of fashion, and that young people are getting into college without being able to <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2024/11/the-elite-college-students-who-cant-read-books/679945/">read a full book</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I know that the pandemic took a toll on <a href="https://www.vox.com/education/372475/math-reading-school-covid-education-learning-loss-kids">kids’ test scores in reading and math</a>. But I also know that older generations love to complain about ne’er-do-well young folks who can’t be bothered to crack open a book. So I reached out to educators and literacy scholars to find out how far behind kids really are, and what their reading skills (or lack thereof) mean for their future as voters, news consumers, and citizens of the world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While kids’ reading performance has slid in recent years, some experts say <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2024/12/lucy-calkins-child-literacy-teaching-methodology/680394/">the language of “crisis”</a> is overblown. In fact, reading scores on the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP), one of the most widely used nationwide measures of student achievement, <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/ltt/2022/">haven’t changed that much</a> since the tests were introduced in 1969, <a href="https://www.gse.harvard.edu/directory/faculty/catherine-snow">Catherine Snow</a>, a professor of cognition and education at Harvard Graduate School of Education, told me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They haven&#8217;t plummeted,” Snow said. “They didn&#8217;t even plummet during Covid. They went down a little bit.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What has plummeted, however, is how much kids read, especially outside of school. In 1984, the first year for which data is available, 35 percent of 13-year-olds reported reading for fun “almost every day,” <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/ltt/reading/student-experiences/?age=13">according to NAEP</a>. By 2023, that figure was down to 14 percent, and 31 percent of respondents said they never read for fun at all. Kids are also faring worse on <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/icils/icils2023/international.asp">tests that measure their information literacy</a>, including their ability to recognize reliable sources.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><iframe title="Today, Explained" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/show/3pXx5SXzXwJxnf4A5pWN2A?utm_source=oembed" allowfullscreen allow="clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture;"></iframe></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those results are indicative of a broader problem. Kids may be learning basic literacy, but “they&#8217;re not reading in the ways that they need to read in order to be prepared for the tasks of learning and critical thinking,” Snow said. And a decline in those critical thinking skills has big implications not just for young people today, but for society as a whole.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These are our voters,” Christina Cover, a special education teacher in the Bronx who leads the <a href="https://seekcommonground.org/pal">Project for Adolescent Literacy</a> at the nonprofit Seek Common Ground, told me. “These are people that are really going to be taking us into what&#8217;s next for our country and for our world.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Kids’ reading scores have been (relatively) stable for decades</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The NAEP tests, administered every two years for five decades, <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/ltt/2022/">offer a bird’s-eye view</a> of how American kids’ reading proficiency has changed over time. After climbing through the 2000s, scores began to dip around 2012, a trend that <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/reading/2022/">intensified with the pandemic</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That drop has educators concerned, with many calling for expanded tutoring, summer school, and other supports to help kids get back on track. At the same time, even the post-Covid numbers aren’t that far off from historical norms. In 1971, the first year for which data is available, the <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/highlights/ltt/2022/">average NAEP score for 9-year-olds</a> was 208 out of a possible 500. In 2022, it was 215.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, those scores aren’t great. It’s also disappointing to see students losing some of the ground they gained through the 2000s, and the pandemic dealt <a href="https://www.vox.com/education/372475/math-reading-school-covid-education-learning-loss-kids">very real setbacks</a>, especially for low-income students and other already-underserved groups. Teachers now have to “reach back, and maybe grab or review those previous standards” that students should have been taught in 2020 and 2021, Evelyn Rudolph, a reading interventionist at LEAD Academy, a public charter school in Montgomery, Alabama, told me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the story of students’ reading scores over the last several decades is one of “a very stable level of mediocrity,” <a href="https://www.harvardmagazine.com/2024/09/harvard-reading-wars-literacy-education">Snow has said</a>, not of sudden crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">But reading for pleasure has plummeted</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s the good-ish news. More worrisome — or at least more precipitous — is the decline in kids’ reading for pleasure. While there were <a href="https://www.nationsreportcard.gov/ltt/reading/student-experiences/?age=13">hints of a decrease</a> in the ’90s, the slide seems to have started in earnest in the 2010s — in 2012, 27 percent of 13-year-olds read for fun every day, compared with just 17 percent in 2020.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts aren’t exactly sure why so many kids stopped reading, but the trend coincides with the widespread adoption of smartphones, said <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/staff/staffdetl.asp?empid=698">Ebony Walton</a>, a statistician at the National Center for Education Statistics, which administers the NAEP tests. Other hypotheses include <a href="https://theconversation.com/children-arent-reading-for-pleasure-according-to-new-research-heres-how-you-can-help-them-love-books-243108">funding cuts to libraries</a>, and an <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2023/03/children-reading-books-english-middle-grade/673457/">excessive focus on standardized testing</a> that has crowded out practices that instill a love of reading, like teachers reading books aloud to students.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whatever the case, the decline of reading for fun is a problem, and not just for <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2023/03/children-reading-books-english-middle-grade/673457/">children’s authors</a>. “When a student reads for fun and enjoys reading outside of school, there are so many benefits that they might not even realize,” from learning new vocabulary to gaining “the background knowledge needed to approach different academic areas in school,” Cover said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The skills that students use when reading for fun — especially reading longer texts — are also the same ones they need for everything from reading car manuals to “listening to political discourse and making sense of it,” Snow said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The importance of reading skills for civic engagement has been a hot-button topic lately, with <a href="https://x.com/ishaantharoor/status/1854187377943515637">Washington Post columnist Ishaan Tharoor</a> calling young people today a “generation trending toward post-literacy” that “gets its information from bits and bobs of video while scrolling.” While “post-literacy” might be a stretch, Snow and other experts are concerned that the decline in reading could make young people more susceptible to disinformation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s some evidence that this is already happening. US eighth-graders’ average score on the <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/icils/icils2023/international.asp">International Computer and Information Literacy Study assessment</a>, which measures skills including recognizing reliable online sources, dropped 37 points between 2018 and 2023, to 482 out of a possible 700. American students fared worse on the assessment than students in most European countries, as well as South Korea and Taiwan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The decline in reading for pleasure can feel impossible to reverse, given the number of alternatives available to kids today. But experts say some simple strategies can help. For Snow, it’s about treating reading not simply as an academic skill to master, but “as a tool for engaging in important activities, like learning about things you&#8217;re interested in.” Reading can be a way to engage with the social justice issues that many tweens and teens are <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/369953/skibidi-tweens-gen-alpha-brainrot-ipad-kids">passionate about</a> — “but those connections are not always made in schools,” Snow said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also important to encourage students to read what they like, in the way they like, whether that’s in a book or on an iPad or other device, Cover said. More companies are springing up to create reading materials specifically for Gen Alpha audiences, like <a href="https://www.storyshares.org/">Storyshares</a>, which offers books written by young people themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kids “are reading in the world around them every single day,” Cover said. It’s up to educators to show them that “it&#8217;s not just something in isolation, but something that can enrich every other area of their life.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What I’m reading</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The accessories retailer Claire’s, a staple of many ’90s mall outings, is <a href="https://www.glossy.co/beauty/claires-double-downs-on-fragrance-to-target-gen-zalpha-consumers/?utm_campaign=glossydis&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=general-rss">launching a fragrance collection</a> in an effort to appeal to what it calls “Gen Zalpha” customers. The scents, priced at $24.99 or less, include one that smells like pistachio and vanilla.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Schools in <a href="https://calmatters.org/education/k-12-education/2024/11/education-policy/">California</a> and <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/education/4988623-trump-return-colleges-universities-k-12-dei-trans-students/">around the country</a> are racing to prepare for the Trump administration and its potential effects on undocumented and LGBTQ students.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/health/385541/rfk-jr-trump-hhs-vaccines-fluoride">Trump Health and Human Services pick Robert F. Kennedy Jr.</a> is correct that chronic diseases like <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/15/health/rfk-chronic-diseases-children.html">diabetes and asthma</a> are worryingly common in American children, according to the New York Times. He is wrong, however, to blame vaccines and <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/369470/fluoride-iq-kids-brain-development-toothpaste-water-science-study">fluoridated water</a> for the problem.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My 2-year-old and I have been enjoying <em><a href="https://www.littleowlsnight.com/">Little Owl’s Night</a></em>, a very sweet board book that flips the bedtime story script by having its protagonist go to sleep when morning comes. It also includes the eerie line, “Mama, tell me again how night ends.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From my inbox</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, I asked about your kids’ experiences with reading, and one reader, Kelly, had an experience that might be helpful for kids who struggle with reading for fun. “Two of my four children have dyslexia, so we were a little slower to become a ‘read to yourself’ family,” Kelly wrote. “But audiobooks meant they still grew up loving reading from an early age&#8230; just in a different form.” The kids’ grandmother “introduced my then-3-year-old daughter to Peter Pan on audiobook on her iPod, earbuds attached, and my daughter was hooked,” Kelly wrote. “In the nine years since, we&#8217;ve checked out literal thousands of audiobooks on <a href="https://libbyapp.com/interview/welcome#doYouHaveACard">Libby</a> — for free thanks to the Los Angeles Public Library — and my kids listen for several hours every day.”&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[John Green’s crusade to make the world “suck less”]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384524/john-green-author-youtuber-tuberculosis-advocacy-future-perfect-50" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=384524</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T09:29:29-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T07:01:34-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future Perfect 50" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whether he is writing novels about young love, contemplating our species’ long-term prospects, or supporting public health projects abroad, John Green is driven by one mission: “I&#8217;m trying to make the case that humanity is worth it.” It began with a YouTube channel, Vlogbrothers, in which he and his brother, Hank, an author and entrepreneur, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Vox_DiegoMallo_JohnGreen.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<a href='https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation' target='_blank' rel="noopener"><img src='https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/CenteredTag_2_FP50_8f0cf5.png' class='p-block-image alignnone wp-image-386498'></a>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether he is writing novels about young love, contemplating our species’ long-term prospects, or supporting public health projects abroad, <a href="https://www.johngreenbooks.com/">John Green</a> is driven by one mission: “I&#8217;m trying to make the case that humanity is worth it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It began with a YouTube channel, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/vlogbrothers">Vlogbrothers</a>, in which he and his brother, Hank, an author and entrepreneur, exchanged messages with each other and their audience ranging from the mundane to the esoteric, and in doing so, nurtured a massive community focused on global problems.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">John Green’s 2012 young adult novel, <a href="https://www.johngreenbooks.com/the-fault-in-our-stars"><em>The Fault in Our Stars</em></a>, became <a href="https://www.indystar.com/story/entertainment/arts/2017/10/20/john-green-book-event-balances-anxiety-laughs/769477001/">one of the best-selling books</a> of this century and propelled him to celebrity status, giving him the metaphorical equivalent of a “giant robot suit,” as he put it in his characteristically nerdy parlance. With the newfound fame, the brothers aspired to make the world “suck less.”(Green credits their parents, both activists, for that passion.)&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-12_5fd0bf.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.232055519596,100,73.535888960808" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In the intervening years, their YouTube following has grown to 3.8 million, and they have become genuine forces in global health philanthropy, organizing massive fundraising drives for their chosen causes and <a href="https://kffhealthnews.org/news/podcast/john-green-vs-johnson-johnson-part-1/">confronting global pharmaceutical giants</a>. These interests have inspired Green’s creative pursuits, including <a href="https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/anthropocene-reviewed">the podcast <em>The Anthropocene Reviewed</em></a> and its <a href="https://anthropocenereviewedbook.com/">follow-up book</a>, both of which grapple with the world as humanity has made it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His next book, <a href="https://www.johngreenbooks.com/everything-is-tuberculosis"><em>Everything Is Tuberculosis</em></a>, which is set to come out in March, will center on Green’s latest obsession: TB, the infectious disease that kills <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/the-top-10-causes-of-death">more people than any other</a>. Last year, Green launched <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/how-advocates-pushed-big-pharma-to-cut-tuberculosis-drug-prices/">a successful campaign</a> to pressure pharmaceutical company Johnson &amp; Johnson to stop reported patent abuses that were inflating the cost of a lifesaving tuberculosis drug. He has also raised <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NgQEKHBg5g0">more than $35 million</a> for a Partners in Health project to reduce maternal mortality in Sierra Leone, which until <a href="https://www.afro.who.int/countries/sierra-leone/news/sierra-leones-determination-stem-maternal-and-child-mortality">recently</a> had <a href="https://www.unicef.org/sierraleone/maternal-neonatal-child-and-adolescent-health#:~:text=The%20maternal%20mortality%20rate%20in,in%20every%20100%2C000%20live%20births.">the highest rate</a> of women dying in childbirth in the world. That money will help pay for a new government hospital set to open in the coming months.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Green and I spoke in October about his humanitarian work, how it has complicated his awkward relationship with celebrity, and why he retains a stubborn optimism about humankind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You started Vlogbrothers with </strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oeAUQslfFP4"><strong>this idea</strong></a><strong> that “We want to make the world suck less.” How do you conceptualize why the world sucks?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are ways that the world sucks that the world just sucks. This species has been around for 250,000 years; for 249,800 of those years, about half of children died before the age of 5. That just sucks. It&#8217;s completely unfair. It&#8217;s wildly unjust. But there was nothing that we could do about it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ways the world sucks that most interest me are the ways the world sucks because of human-built systems, because those problems have human-buildable solutions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Your forthcoming book is called </strong><strong><em>Everything Is Tuberculosis</em></strong><strong>. What does that mean exactly?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24128530/tuberculosis-vaccine-efficacy-solutions-tb-bcg">Tuberculosis</a> is the deadliest infectious disease in the world. It kills <a href="https://www.who.int/news/item/29-10-2024-tuberculosis-resurges-as-top-infectious-disease-killer">about 1.3 million people</a> every year. It&#8217;s gonna kill over 100,000 people this month. All of those deaths are needless because we&#8217;ve had the cure to tuberculosis since the mid-1950s.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-13_626ff4.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,27.710962259551,100,44.578075480898" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">What does it mean to live in that world? What does it mean to live in a world <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/9/28/17914344/tuberculosis-united-nations-funding-india-china">where the deadliest infectious disease</a> has been curable since my father was born?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It means that we&#8217;re doing an extraordinarily poor job of distributing resources. Our systems of marshaling and distributing resources have obviously failed in this case. It&#8217;s clearly a human-built problem that has a human-buildable solution, which is encouraging to me. We are the cause of tuberculosis, which also means that we can be the cure of tuberculosis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I say in the book title that everything is tuberculosis, I really do mean it. Tuberculosis radically shaped American geography. It&#8217;s the reason that cities like Pasadena and Colorado Springs and <a href="https://www.citizen-times.com/story/life/2015/07/20/ashevilles-growth-began-th-century-tb-treatment/30408281/">Asheville, North Carolina</a>, exist. It&#8217;s the reason <a href="https://www.historicsantafe.org/imported-products/chasing-the-cure">New Mexico</a> is a state. It&#8217;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wddYMBNv40o">one of the reasons World War I happened</a>. It radically reshaped almost everything about our lives. It&#8217;s been this quiet force throughout human history that&#8217;s pushing us this way and that, that we often don&#8217;t notice, but it&#8217;s a really, really profound force in human history.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I just listened to </strong><a href="https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/anthropocene-reviewed/episodes/anthropocene-reviewed-humanitys-temporal-range"><strong>your podcast episode about humanity’s temporal range</strong></a><strong>. I&#8217;ve more than once heard you describe how your existence would be completely unrecognizable to somebody who lived a couple of centuries ago.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Why is it so challenging for us to remember that context, the long history that has created the world in which we now live?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well, in the dreary grind of daily living, as I think <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/robert-penn-warren">Robert Penn Warren</a> called it, it&#8217;s really hard to remember historical context because we&#8217;re busy trying to pay the mortgage and trying to make sure our kids get to school on time and trying to get them to eat some breakfast before they go. I feel that too. Believe me, I struggled to get my kids to eat breakfast this morning.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s so easy to feel hopeless in our current moment. I&#8217;m someone who&#8217;s unusually prone to despair. Maybe I&#8217;ve been fighting this for a long time, which is why I&#8217;m so focused on it. Part of the reason we feel despair is because we don&#8217;t see long-term change when we&#8217;re just looking at crisis after crisis after crisis after crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I try to contextualize my life and the world and our place in that world, I feel more hopeful because I see more examples that give me cause for hope. In the last 30 years, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24100883/child-mortality-rate-worldwide-united-nations">we&#8217;ve reduced child mortality by over 50 percent</a>, the fastest decline in human history.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, the last 30 years have sucked terribly. Both of these things are true at the same time and holding those competing ideas together is really challenging, but I also think it&#8217;s essential.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You&#8217;ve touched on something I wanted to ask you about, that I think about a lot. I have three kids under the age of 6. They are ignorant of all of the world&#8217;s problems.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">God bless you.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Something that we talk about at Future Perfect is </strong><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/fifty-six-percent-of-young-people-think-humanity-is-doomed/"><strong>the perception among a lot of young people that the world sucks</strong></a><strong>, that it&#8217;s getting worse, and that it could end catastrophically, maybe even pretty soon, whether that&#8217;s because of climate change or some other existential risk.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What do you hear from your audience about their outlook on humanity&#8217;s future and how do you respond to their concerns? How do you resolve that tension for yourself?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of the people I hear from feel very hopeless and very scared, and they do feel like the world sucks and is getting worse. In important ways, they&#8217;re right, and I think it&#8217;s really important to acknowledge that they&#8217;re right. I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to have my high school graduation ruined by a global pandemic. I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to see <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24113340/biden-housing-2024-election-campaign-renters-tenants-mortgage">housing</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/2023/10/6/23903808/student-loan-payments-debt-budget">education</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/17/21024614/us-health-care-costs-medical-prices">health care</a> all become progressively less affordable than they&#8217;ve ever been. I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to grow up in the world that they&#8217;re growing up in.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-14_2e9677.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,24.343144408008,100,51.313711183984" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, they don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to grow up in a world where 12 million kids die every year before the age of 5, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24100883/child-mortality-rate-worldwide-united-nations">whereas now fewer than 6 million do</a>. When I talk to young people about this, I try not to minimize their concerns because I think their concerns are real. Climate change is a catastrophe and it has the potential to be a catastrophe beyond our current imagining. There are profound and growing inequities in our world today. That&#8217;s all real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But at the same time, it is also true that people have been predicting the end of the world since the moment that they realized the world might end. By the end of the world, of course, I don&#8217;t mean the end of life on Earth. Life on Earth will be just fine without us — arguably, from its perspective, better. I mean the end of humanity in the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m very afraid of that. It&#8217;s my biggest fear because I think we are good news or have the potential to be good news. It&#8217;s my biggest fear because I think we&#8217;re the most interesting thing that ever happened to this planet. It&#8217;s my biggest fear because I love humanity and I think we&#8217;re worth fighting for.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What exactly is the human endeavor?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We started out, as I think somebody once put it, as an animal of no consequence. Now we know approximately what&#8217;s keeping the stars apart and approximately how far away our star is from our planet. We know that we&#8217;re on a planet and we know that we can read <em>Hamlet</em> anytime we want. We can listen to Billie Holiday records and communicate with the dead.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That&#8217;s a pretty impressive series of accomplishments to me and I think it&#8217;s worth celebrating. That&#8217;s what I mean by the human endeavor: the overall attempt by each member of our species to take care of each other and to push us forward in our knowledge and understanding of the world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I find our ability to make art everywhere all the time, no matter what, really fascinating and really encouraging. My son and I were just on a tour of World War I battle sites last week, and we saw all of this so-called trench art, which is art that was made in the trenches by soldiers on both sides of World War I, often taking exploded shells and carving onto them beautiful sunrises or landscapes or portraits. Some of these works of art are astonishing and nobody made those works of art hoping to get rich. Nobody made those works of art hoping to find an audience of millions of people. They made those works of art because there was value in the making and value in the sharing even if it was only sharing it with your buddies in the trenches.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Last year, </strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tMhgw5SW0h4"><strong>you targeted Johnson &amp; Johnson</strong></a><strong> for its patent practices and artificially inflating prices for life-saving treatments. That is a different tactic than encouraging people&#8217;s curiosity, empathy, and optimism. When is confrontation the right approach?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I really dislike any form of confrontation, including confrontation with big pharmaceutical companies that have a lot of power and employ a lot of nice people. I find that very stressful.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-15_56ecba.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,15.924216878161,100,68.151566243677" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">But when Doctors Without Borders and Partners in Health and Treatment Action Group were all reaching out saying this is a huge problem and it&#8217;s making it really difficult for us to get the medicine to the people we need to get it to, I felt like I had to listen. I&#8217;m a big believer in listening to people who know a lot more than I do. That&#8217;s kind of the foundational concept of my philanthropy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;ll be honest, I tried to have some private conversations [with Johnson &amp; Johnson], and they didn&#8217;t go anywhere. So then I felt the only conversation I can really have is a public conversation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I was thinking about the people I&#8217;ve known who died of drug-resistant tuberculosis and feeling angry on their behalf, feeling frustrated by the systemic failures on their behalf. Maybe that gave me a little more strength of conviction than I might otherwise have had.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What is your project with Partners in Health in Sierra Leone?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Our project is centered around the maternal mortality crisis, which is also a child mortality crisis because children are much more likely to die or otherwise experience serious disability and serious illness if their mothers die in childbirth. At the time <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfpXgkKTwmg">we started this in 2019</a>, Sierra Leone had the highest maternal mortality rate in the world. About 1 in 17 women could expect to die in pregnancy or childbirth, which wasn&#8217;t that different from the rate we would have seen 500 or 5,000 years ago. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the arguments that Partners in Health and our community wanted to make is that there are no excuses for not expanding access to maternal health care. That means not just in Sierra Leone — it means everywhere. But our hope is that this project could provide a blueprint for how to do that with more community health workers, with more nurses, and also ultimately with a world-class maternal care center at Koidu Government Hospital. That is where the lion&#8217;s share of the money that we&#8217;ve raised so far will go.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the first time, there will be a neonatal intensive care unit. There will also be adequate operating theaters for emergency C-sections. So many people die in Sierra Leone for want of an emergency C-section, or they die because they have high blood pressure, or they die because of hemorrhaging after giving birth. All things that are very treatable in rich countries and that should be treatable no matter who you are or where you live.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Five years ago, when </strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfpXgkKTwmg"><strong>you were announcing your and Hank’s initial $6.5 million donation to Partners in Health</strong></a><strong> for the Sierra Leone project, you said you were trying to take lessons that you had learned from earlier philanthropic ventures and apply them to this effort in Sierra Leone. Now that you&#8217;ve had five more years of experience trying to stand this up, what else have you learned?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The biggest thing I&#8217;ve learned is that when you get community buy-in, things go much better than when you don&#8217;t.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most of the people building the Maternal Center of Excellence are women. Most of the welders, the masons, the steel workers. But they all had to be trained. I had no idea about the complexity of that. That was something that never crossed my mind, that you&#8217;re going to need to train up a workforce alongside building a hospital. Now that turns out to be an amazingly good investment because those people now have skills that they&#8217;re going to take with them the rest of their lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People from rich countries or especially rich individuals kind of come into a community thinking that they have the solutions, which generally means that they don&#8217;t really understand the complexity of the problems.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How do you know when your work is effective?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We&#8217;re obsessed with quantifying the good that we&#8217;re doing, with testing it, with making sure that we can evaluate kids and making sure that we know that they&#8217;re learning what we think they&#8217;re learning.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The risk is that it&#8217;s easy to conflate what is important with what is easily measurable. We need to be very careful not to apply what&#8217;s easily measurable and assume that it is therefore what&#8217;s most important.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-16_066c51.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,20.364516447693,100,59.270967104613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The obvious way that we measure the success of this project is by how many kids are surviving childbirth and how many mothers are surviving childbirth. But I also think you need to look at what, if anything, is the overall effect on reducing poverty. Is it improving educational access? Because we know that kids are more likely to be in school if their moms survive childbirth, but we haven&#8217;t yet proven that lower maternal mortality will lead to higher educational attainment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I want to look at that through a 20- or 30-year lens, not through a three- to five-year lens. I&#8217;m pretty tired of health care interventions that attempt to prove something in 18 months or with a three-year grant.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What do you think is the biggest blind spot people today have that future generations will look back on and think, “What were they doing?”</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think there are a lot of ways that people in the future will look back on us and think, “How did they do that?” The way that we think, “How did they let everybody smoke on airplanes?” The way that we treat non-human animals, especially the animals that we consume as meat, will be one.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ways we distribute resources and build systems will be another. I hope people of the future will be absolutely astonished that within a single country, depending on your zip code, your life expectancy <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2017/05/08/health/life-expectancy-by-county-study/index.html#:~:text=Life%20expectancy%20at%20birth%20differs,medical%20journal%20JAMA%20Internal%20Medicine">could vary by 25 or 30 years</a>. I think people will be astonished that there were places where health care systems were so robust that someone like my brother could get diagnosed with cancer and be in remission within six months and other places where somebody diagnosed with that same cancer would be dead within six months.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What advice do you have for ethically minded people who are trying to figure out how to contribute to this project of improving humanity?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, it&#8217;s so easy to get overwhelmed and have decision paralysis. There are so many problems and there are so many people trying to address them and it can be so <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/10/15/17924288/future-perfect-explained">hard to know who&#8217;s addressing them most effectively</a> or what the problems beneath all the other problems are. And that&#8217;s okay. I think it&#8217;s okay to pick a problem and trust that other people are going to be addressing other problems with the same passion and interest that you&#8217;re addressing yours.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-17_6642d6.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,18.228963271358,100,63.542073457285" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">I don&#8217;t labor under the delusion that tuberculosis is the biggest problem in the world or that it&#8217;s the only problem that we should be paying attention to. I just think it&#8217;s one that we should be paying attention to and it&#8217;s the one that I happen to pay attention to.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My second piece of advice would be <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23627382/progress-climate-change-poverty-global-health-doom-industrial-revolution-vaccines">don&#8217;t listen to the doomsayers</a>. Don&#8217;t buy into the people who are telling you that none of this matters because it&#8217;s all worthless anyway.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That&#8217;s a really compelling ethical argument in some ways because it&#8217;s so simple, it&#8217;s so straightforward. “This is all dumb.” “None of it matters.” “We should give up” is chef&#8217;s kiss from the perspective of wanting to have an explanation that has extraordinary explanatory power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem with despair, of course, is that it&#8217;s untrue, like any super-simplistic worldview. Fight against despair and believe that together we can make the world better for each other.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Please do not judge me: I love U2, and therefore I love Bono. I think he&#8217;s a notable example of how perilous this transition can be from pop-culture curio to being an actual expert who can influence even more influential people.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, I think about Bono a lot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Okay, there you go. How have you managed that transition?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I want to approach it with real humility because you can do so much unintended damage when you have a lot of power and when you have a really loud voice. It&#8217;s so easy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My brother described it to me once as having a giant robot suit. I have this giant robot suit and it makes me super powerful. But when I walk around, it&#8217;s really easy for me to step on houses.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;ve been given a lot of power, and I don&#8217;t think that I should have it, to be honest with you. I think that our social order gives way too much power to celebrities, even like seventh-tier celebrities like myself. It freaks me out and I think we should be freaked out by it. I just try to remember that I&#8217;m very, very rarely the smartest person in the room.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Do you see a unifying thread across your work, from </strong><strong><em>The Fault in Our Stars</em></strong><strong> to </strong><strong><em>The Anthropocene Reviewed</em></strong><strong> and Vlogbrothers to the maternal health project in Sierra Leone?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m trying to make the case that humanity is worth it. That humanity is worth the trial and travail and suffering and injustice and oppression, the catastrophe and horrors that we visit upon ourselves and each other. That, despite all of that, it&#8217;s a blessing to be here and humanity can be good news. I really believe that. I don&#8217;t know that we are good news, but I think we can be.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don&#8217;t want to sound too pretentious about it, but I need to make that case for myself as much as I need to make it for anybody else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What do you mean by that?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m very prone to desperate hopelessness, and I need every morning to be able to make the case to myself that it&#8217;s a good idea to get out of bed and go on.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You talk about resiliency being one of humanity&#8217;s defining traits.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I love how resilient we are. We&#8217;re so underrated as a species, Dylan. It drives me crazy. Does anybody think raccoons would be better at having this kind of power? Does anybody think dolphins would be better at having this kind of power? <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1999/07/06/health/evidence-puts-dolphins-in-new-light-as-killers.html">Have you read about dolphins?</a>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Which is not to say in any way that we aren&#8217;t terrible. I want to be clear that I&#8217;m very pissed off. I&#8217;m infuriated by humanity&#8217;s many failures. What kind of insanity is it to have the deadliest infectious disease in the world be something that we&#8217;ve known how to cure for 75 years? That&#8217;s monstrous.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s just that we rate ourselves so lowly. There&#8217;s a lot to recommend about us.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[There’s never been a better time to buy a used phone]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/386772/black-friday-used-phone-apple-watch" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=386772</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T10:01:42-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T07:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Consumerism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology &amp; Media" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple years ago, just before Black Friday, I decided to replace my old, cracked Apple Watch with a non-cracked equivalent. One thing led to another, and I had spent less than I’d planned on a nicer watch than I thought I could afford. The catch: It was refurbished.&#160; The “r” word used to be [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Two phones sit on a table, and while the one on the left is broken, the one on the right is not." data-caption="Not unlike a used car, the average iPhone has three owners throughout its lifespan." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/AdamEstes_Phone.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Not unlike a used car, the average iPhone has three owners throughout its lifespan.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A couple years ago, just before Black Friday, I decided to replace my old, cracked Apple Watch with a non-cracked equivalent. One thing led to another, and I had spent less than I’d planned on a nicer watch than I thought I could afford. The catch: It was refurbished.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The “r” word used to be a bad one in the gadget world. A decade ago, to many people, refurbished meant used, scuffed, and maybe a little bit broken. Secondhand devices didn’t always have the best reputation. However, as <a href="https://pirg.org/campaigns/right-to-repair/">the right to repair movement</a> has pushed consumer technology companies to make their products easier to fix, a new crop of marketplaces for used and refurbished goods has captured the attention of anyone who either loves a deal or cares about the environment, or both. And these cheaper options are better than ever.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You may have heard of <a href="https://www.backmarket.com/en-us">Back Market</a>, a Paris-based refurbished marketplace that promises to sell you “tech that’s better for the planet.” Then there are more specialized sites, like <a href="https://www.gazelle.com/">Gazelle</a>, which primarily sells refurbished phones and laptops, and <a href="https://vipoutlet.com/">VIP Outlet</a>, which specializes in refurbishing retail returns. <a href="https://www.decluttr.com/">Decluttr</a> sells old CDs and DVDs alongside refurbished tablets and gaming consoles. Even big retailers, including Amazon, eBay, Walmart, and Best Buy, are in the refurbished marketplace game now, too. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prices and warranties vary, based on what you&#8217;re buying and when, but no matter where you shop, purchasing secondhand <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/refurbished-iphones-market-apple-sales-slump-android-cell-phones-cheaper-2024-10">comes with a certain cachet</a>. It’s the sensible thing to do, according to Lucas Gutterman, director of the Designed to Last Campaign at the US PIRG Education Fund.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s not a bad thing for people to buy new phones,” Gutterman told me. “It’s just the idea that we should buy them every year, every other year — that seems like it&#8217;s way too much for the environment.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We certainly can’t make an infinite amount of devices with <a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/10/22/7031243/china-grip-rare-earth-metals-supply-weakening">the finite number of rare earth metals</a> on this planet. And extending the lives of phones already on the market comes with huge upside. A <a href="https://labo.societenumerique.gouv.fr/en/articles/environmental-impact-of-smartphones-what-benefits-of-reconditioning-relate-to-nine/">recent study</a> from the French government claimed that buying a refurbished phone instead of a new one avoids the extraction of 180 pounds of raw materials and emitted 50 pounds of greenhouse gasses. Put differently, buying the refurbished device over the new one lowers the overall environmental impact by as much as 91 percent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Taking the refurbished route wasn’t always framed as a way to fight climate change. The practice grew out of corporate IT departments&#8217; constant need to supply machines to employees in the early days of personal computers. If an employee left the company, rather than buy a new computer, IT wiped their machines, repaired it if needed, and then assigned it to a new employee. It didn’t take long before a cottage industry emerged to sell used but restored devices to consumers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That industry is now huge and getting bigger every year. The number of used and refurbished smartphone shipments <a href="https://www.telecoms.com/mobile-devices/used-smartphone-market-shipments-topped-300-million-in-2023">grew nearly 10 percent</a> from 2022 to 2023, while the number of new smartphone shipments declined by over 3 percent, according to the market intelligence firm IDC. That adds up to the secondary market for phones being worth about $65 billion in 2023, and it&#8217;s expected to grow to nearly $110 billion by 2027.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These big numbers reflect an industry that’s gone from mom-and-pop shops selling fixed-up laptops to multiple mainstream marketplaces where millions of people buy everything from phones and computers to watches and video game consoles. The competition between those marketplaces also means that quality and customer experience is vastly improved. Now, refurbished gadgets often come with the same long warranties, trade-in options, and payment plans as new devices.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">One surprising thing</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The logistics of online shopping <a href="https://earth.org/online-shopping-and-its-environmental-impact/">comes with a significant carbon footprint</a>. However, the original manufacturing process for devices like phones are much more significant. Shipping a phone in a 1-pound package 500 miles <a href="https://consumerecology.com/carbon-footprint-of-package-shipping-transport/#:~:text=The%20carbon%20footprint%20of%20a,0.98%20kg%20CO2e.">produces</a> about 1.3 pounds of greenhouse gas emissions. Manufacturing an iPhone 16 Plus, <a href="https://www.apple.com/environment/pdf/products/iphone/iPhone_16_and_iPhone_16_Plus_PER_Sept2024.pdf">according to Apple</a>, produces 110 to 167 pounds of emissions.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plus, the latest devices tend to have fewer new features that would make upgrading worthwhile.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People are less excited about getting another camera lens on their phone or getting a new button on the side of the iPhone,” Gutterman said. Spending less on a refurbished phone and feeling better about your environmental impact is just a better choice for a growing number of people, he explained.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The refurbished market is also more transparent than it’s ever been. It all starts with a gadget that ended up in the inventory of a refurbisher or original equipment manufacturer. Often, it’s simply a device <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/why-apple-and-the-carriers-want-your-old-iphone-4279cc8d">that someone else traded in</a> or sent back for a warranty or insurance claim. Both refurbishers and manufacturers refurbish these kinds of devices by wiping them, fixing any hardware issues, repairing any cosmetic damage, cleaning them, and boxing them back up. (This can happen several times over the lifespan of a product.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then the device goes on the market. Most marketplaces also give you options to buy items in different conditions, from poor to premium, at different prices. Some devices sold on the secondhand market are actually new, too. Cleland explained to me that some of the inventory that ends up in the refurbishers’ hands includes products that were sold and returned but never used.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s thanks, in part, to the boom in online returns, especially since the pandemic, which has led to a liquidation market <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ddbb2nPwC-c">worth hundreds of billions of dollars</a> that’s finding new homes for all kinds of secondhand goods, from furniture to construction equipment. For phones and tablets, there’s even a <a href="https://www.ctia.org/news/ctia-updates-wireless-device-grading-standard-to-help-extend-the-lifecycle-of-pre-owned-wireless-devices">standardized method for grading the condition of used devices</a> to streamline the process of reselling and refurbishing them. It all adds up to better, cheaper secondhand goods.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s estimated now that anytime a new iPhone comes out, it&#8217;s going to have at least three different users over its lifespan, because it&#8217;s going to get either traded or dropped and then resold,” <a href="https://www.ctia.org/news/blog-member-spotlight-meet-sean-cleland-of-b-stock-solutions">Sean Cleland</a>, vice president of mobile at the marketplace B-Stock Solutions, told me. “Like, back in the day, people would just put their old phone in the drawer.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you zoom out, what’s happening with refurbished phones and other electronics is a shining example of what a circular economy can do.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A circular economy aims to keep products in use as long as possible through refurbishing, repairing, and recycling <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/5-opportunities-circular-economy">to conserve resources</a> and open up new economic opportunities. While the term has been around since the late 1980s, the circular economy concept has gained popularity in recent years. The European Union even adopted a <a href="https://environment.ec.europa.eu/strategy/circular-economy-action-plan_en">circular economy action plan in 2020</a> that set forth a number of policies and strategies to promote sustainable development. These government incentives have perhaps helped marketplaces such as the Back Market to thrive in France and across Europe.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Going circular and finding ways to reuse the old inventory to create new things, I think, is necessary,” Cleland said. “As resources dip but consumer demand increases, you’ve got to figure out a new way.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">American companies are embracing the circular economy model as well. Amazon now has Amazon Renewed, which launched in 2017 and features the same fast shipping you get with other Amazon products as well as a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=G4ZAA22U35N373NX">90-day free return policy</a>, which goes up to one year for some premium products. Meanwhile, eBay offers a <a href="https://pages.ebay.com/refurbishedprogramwarranty/index.html">two-year warranty</a> on certified refurbished products, which are delivered like new, as well as one year on lower-grade used goods. Walmart Restored similarly has a <a href="https://www.walmart.com/help/article/walmart-restored/1cd5cc0c3cef40c79a4b2305890b1370">one-year minimum warranty</a> on premium refurbished goods, and 90 days on everything else. Target sells items refurbished by the original manufacturer with a <a href="https://www.target.com/c/target-refurbished-pre-owned/-/N-l6d4n">six-month minimum warranty</a>. Back Market’s warranty is <a href="https://www.backmarket.com/en-us/legal/warranty">good for one year</a> across the board.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Warranty is only one factor to consider when choosing where to buy refurbished goods, says PIRG’s Gutterman. You should avoid buying refurbished items that aren’t designed to last, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/9/16/23875582/apple-airpod-repair-battery-right-to-repair-act">like Apple AirPods</a>, as well as bulky items like TVs, which can be easily damaged. You should also make sure manufacturers still support software updates on older devices. Here’s <a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/iphone/iphone-models-compatible-with-ios-18-iphe3fa5df43/ios">a list of iPhone models</a> that support the latest iOS 18 software, for instance. (You can find more tips in this recently updated <a href="https://pirg.org/edfund/resources/fixed-for-the-holidays/">guide to buying — and gifting — refurbished products</a> that Gutterman co-authored.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re like me, you might just want to find the best deal. My Apple Watch battery is starting to fail, so I’m actually thinking about <a href="https://support.apple.com/watch/repair">getting it repaired</a> or getting a new one. Since the market for refurbished gadgets has blown up so much in the past few years, I have more options to upgrade than I did a few years ago.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And as much as I’d like to try the new features, it might feel better to trade mine in, let it find its way to a new owner, and live a little longer.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here</a></em></strong><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Izzie Ramirez</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Gen Z superstar Billie Eilish doesn&#8217;t separate climate activism from animal welfare]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384508/billie-eilish-singer-songwriter-vegan-climate-animal-rights-activism-future-perfect-50" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=384508</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T12:57:35-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future Perfect 50" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Billie Eilish could eat that girl for lunch — but she’s certainly not eating any animals for dinner. The 22-year-old pop star has a lot of triumphs under her belt: nine Grammys, two Oscars, and two Golden Globes. Her music has been nearly inescapable in the last year, from a sultry feature on Charli XCX’s [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustrated portrait of Billie Eilish" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Diego Mallo for Vox" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/DiegoMallo_BillieEilish.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<a href='https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation' target='_blank' rel="noopener"><img src='https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/CenteredTag_2_FP50_8f0cf5.png' class='p-block-image alignnone wp-image-386498'></a>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Billie Eilish could <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MB3VkzPdgLA">eat that girl for lunch</a> — but she’s certainly not eating any animals for dinner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 22-year-old pop star has a lot of triumphs under her belt: nine Grammys, two Oscars, and two Golden Globes. Her music has been nearly inescapable in the last year, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=huGd4efgdPA">from a sultry feature</a> on <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/354634/charli-xcx-brat-album-review">Charli XCX’</a>s “Guess” remix to the emotive “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cW8VLC9nnTo">What Was I Made For</a>” for the blockbuster <em>Barbie </em>movie. But arguably one of her biggest — yet under-recognized —&nbsp;achievements is making caring about animal welfare more accessible <em>… </em>and cool<em>.</em></p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-06_758c61.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,28.917038546681,100,42.165922906638" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">A vegan of almost a decade, Eilish has dedicated a large portion of her career to improving the music industry’s sustainability, as well as encouraging her fans to consider plant-based diets. While she grew up vegetarian and had never eaten meat, she understands what it means to give up something you enjoy. “With dairy, my God, did I love cheese and milk,” <a href="https://lamag.com/music/billie-eilish-december-cover-story-growing-up">she told Los Angeles Magazine</a><em> </em>in 2023. “I was very, very against going vegan. [Then] my mom went vegan, then my brother, then my dad.”<br><br>The shift came as she learned about the horrifying consequences of the meat and dairy industries. Researchers estimate that animal agriculture is responsible for <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/3/20/24105735/peak-meat-livestock-emissions-plant-based-climate-deadline">between 15 and 20 percent</a> of global greenhouse gas emissions and takes up more than a third of the planet’s <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/global-land-for-agriculture">habitable land</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/364288/how-factory-farming-ends-animal-rights-vegans-climate-ethics">The factory farm system</a> brutally kills more than <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/data-insights/billions-of-chickens-ducks-and-pigs-are-slaughtered-for-meat-every-year">80 billion</a> land animals a year, as Future Perfect has long reported — animals that are crammed in tiny cages, forced to endure cruel abuses, and generally never go outside. It also takes a toll on the communities living near factory farms. One <a href="https://corporate.dukehealth.org/news/nc-residents-living-near-large-hog-farms-have-elevated-disease-death-risks?h=nl">study</a> found that in eastern North Carolina — a major <a href="https://www.nass.usda.gov/Charts_and_Maps/Poultry/brlmap.php">chicken</a> and <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/gallery/chart-detail/?chartId=108733">pig</a> factory farm state —&nbsp;residents who live near these farms experience higher rates of kidney disease and infant mortality compared to other rural residents. Workers, too, face higher risks of exposure to <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362271/factory-farming-climate-movement-public-health-pandemics">potential new viruses</a>: So far, sick workers account for nearly all of California’s <a href="https://apnews.com/us-news/california-bird-flu-general-news-230d0b315960ed895b62525806f4cde9">cattle-to-human transmissions of bird flu</a> in October.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;Once you know that kind of thing and you see it, it&#8217;s really hard to go back,&#8221; Eilish said in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MVpAp3A8Ed8&amp;t=106s">2021 video interview with Vogue</a><em>.</em> &#8220;And now, even though I have lots of friends that eat dairy and meat and I don&#8217;t ever want to tell anybody what to do, I just can&#8217;t go on in my life knowing what&#8217;s going on in the animal world and like, not doing anything about it.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Celebrity advocacy often boils down to raising awareness, which can be effective, especially when you have <a href="https://www.instagram.com/billieeilish/">120 million Instagram</a> followers and a sold-out 83-stop world tour. Eilish, the first singer born in the 21st century to have a single top the Billboard 100, also has a palpable Gen Z<em> </em>je nais se quoi when talking about animal rights. She’s relatable. When she went on the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YDr4ITrp7YI">YouTube talk show <em>Hot Ones</em></a><em> </em>(where guests are challenged to eat spicy chicken wings) five years ago<em>,</em> she joked about growing up with the internet and bad talent shows, all while noshing on very spicy (vegan!) chicken nuggets and without making a big deal about the swap.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Vegans have a reputation of being incredibly annoying,” she told <a href="https://lamag.com/music/billie-eilish-december-cover-story-growing-up">Los Angeles Magazine</a>. “And a lot of the time, they are. Sorry. Because you know why? Nobody wants to be told what to do … I want it to be clear that I’m not preaching.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Eilish’s work for animals also extends far beyond just speaking up about the conditions in <a href="https://www.speciesunite.com/news-stories/billie-eilish-speak-out-against-horrendous-animal-agriculture">factory farms</a> or <a href="https://www.idausa.org/campaign/wild-animals-and-habitats/latest-news/media-release-billie-eilish-wants-to-save-abused-memphis-zoo-pandas/">zoos</a>. She subtly nudges her fans to make more environmentally friendly choices by spotlighting her <a href="https://spoonuniversity.com/lifestyle/billie-eilishs-favorite-restaurants/">120 favorite vegan restaurants</a> in tour cities, ensuring that <a href="https://store.billieeilish.com/pages/sustainability?srsltid=AfmBOoowSYB0Txl1Vj058dMjCXQl4Z3lbRT-1bTmJVBm3owPFPMnzBGf">plant-based meals are available at every venue</a>, and <a href="https://www.billboard.com/music/pop/billie-eilish-sustainability-eco-friendly-initiatives-mom-1235642455/">limiting her merch drops</a> to focus on affordable, sustainable options. (<a href="https://billieeilishfragrances.com/">Her perfumes</a>, too, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/370457/animal-testing-science-medicine-vaccines-cruelty-free">do not test on animals</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Sometimes people have the idea of when things are more ethical, they’re more expensive, and so it’s harder to be plant-based or environmentally conscious if you don’t have as much money,” Eilish told <a href="https://www.billboard.com/music/pop/billie-eilish-sustainability-eco-friendly-initiatives-mom-1235642455/">Billboard in March</a>. “And so what we’re trying to do is make it more universally accessible.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Billie_01_51d983.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=25.37890625,0,49.2421875,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">On a larger scale, the “Birds of a Feather” singer fights for progress by forcing change within large institutions, like major fashion brands. The fashion industry&nbsp;— from wool to leather to down —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.collectivefashionjustice.org/non-humans">maims and kills billions</a> of animals for clothing and footwear every year. There’s also a pervasive <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24008053/wool-marketing-environment-sustainable-claims-sheep-animal-cruelty-fast-fashion">misconception</a> that fabrics like leather and wool are merely byproducts of meat production, rather than co-products that make up a meaningful share of animal agriculture’s profits. The problem has only accelerated with the normalization of hyperconsumerism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, <a href="https://www.speciesunite.com/news-stories/billie-eilish-launches-vegan-nike-air-force-ones">Eilish worked with Nike</a> to create the first vegan leather Air Force 1 sneakers, made with 18 percent recycled materials. More notably, when Eilish was a co-chair for the Met Gala in 2021, she pushed for designer Oscar de la Renta to permanently stop using fur — otherwise she wouldn’t work with them. They did.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That was really important to me,” <a href="https://www.billboard.com/music/pop/billie-eilish-sustainability-eco-friendly-initiatives-mom-1235642455/">Eilish told Billboard</a>. “It’s tough as a person who loves fashion. I’ve tried to be a big advocate of no animal products in clothing, and it’s hard. People really like classic things. I get it, I’m one of them. But what’s more important: things being original or our kids being able to live on the planet and them having kids?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To Eilish, veganism isn’t a diet. It’s a way of interacting with the world. Change can be as small as opting for a mushroom burger at a concert or as big as changing an entire business model. In a culture increasingly shaped by celebrity tastes and influence, Eilish stands out as one who is using <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fzeWc3zh01g">her power</a> for good. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Clarification, November 21, 11:30 am ET: </em></strong><em>A previous version of this story misrepresented the significance of dairy in Eilish’s family’s life.</em> </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Bryan Walsh</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Christopher Nolan made the threat of nuclear extinction feel real]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384510/christopher-nolan-director-writer-producer-oppenheimer-storytelling-future-perfect-50" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=384510</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T11:39:44-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future Perfect 50" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Christopher Nolan began writing the screenplay for Oppenheimer in the early 2020s, his teenage son questioned whether anyone still cared about nuclear weapons. By the time the film was released in 2023, Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine and Vladimir Putin&#8217;s nuclear saber-rattling had thrust atomic anxieties back into public consciousness.&#160; The timing was coincidental, but [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Illustrated portrait of Christopher Nolan wearing a suit and red bow tie." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/43_Christopher_Nolan.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<a href='https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation' target='_blank' rel="noopener"><img src='https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/CenteredTag_2_FP50_8f0cf5.png' class='p-block-image alignnone wp-image-386498'></a>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Christopher Nolan began writing the screenplay for <em>Oppenheimer</em> in the early 2020s, his teenage son questioned whether anyone still cared about nuclear weapons. By the time the film was released in 2023, Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine and Vladimir Putin&#8217;s nuclear saber-rattling had thrust atomic anxieties back into public consciousness.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The timing was coincidental, but it highlighted precisely why Nolan&#8217;s recent work matters: He creates true blockbusters that force audiences to grapple with humanity&#8217;s most profound existential challenges.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Nolan_01_8a0d1a.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=27.269010416667,0,45.461979166667,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Oppenheimer</em>, which <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24093819/oppenheimer-oscar-winner-nuclear-war-christopher-nolan-los-alamos-manhattan-project-academy-awards">won both Best Picture and Best Director</a> in 2024, represented the culmination of Nolan&#8217;s long-running artistic exploration of how scientific advancement can simultaneously fulfill humanity&#8217;s greatest hopes and create its most terrible dangers. The film chronicles J. Robert Oppenheimer&#8217;s journey from brilliant theoretical physicist to &#8220;father of the atomic bomb,&#8221; capturing both the intoxicating intellectual achievements of the Manhattan Project — what Oppenheimer himself <a href="https://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/j_robert_oppenheimer_159316">called</a> the “technically sweet” — and the moral horror of unleashing nuclear weapons on the world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;Part of the intention of the film is to reiterate the unique and extraordinary danger of nuclear weapons. That&#8217;s something we should all be thinking about all the time and care about very, very deeply,&#8221; Nolan <a href="https://thebulletin.org/premium/2023-07/an-extended-interview-with-christopher-nolan-director-of-oppenheimer/">told</a> the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists<em> </em>in 2023. But beyond just raising awareness, the director aimed to strip away decades of dry policy papers and arcane philosophical frameworks that have normalized the existence of nuclear arsenals quite literally capable of destroying the world. In <em>Oppenheimer</em>, Nolan renewed the terror at the heart of these weapons viewed through the eyes of those scientists who oversaw their terrible birth.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This focus on making existential risk real and immediate rather than abstract has been found throughout Nolan&#8217;s recent work. His 2014 film <em>Interstellar</em> envisioned humanity&#8217;s desperate search for habitable planets as environmental catastrophe renders Earth increasingly uninhabitable. 2020’s <em>Tenet</em>, released in the teeth of the Covid pandemic, explored themes of technological knowledge that, once uncovered, cannot be put back in the box. (And even if you struggle, as I initially did, with <em>Tenet</em>’s non-linear chronology, you can appreciate how great stars John David Washington and Robert Pattinson <a href="https://variety.com/video/tenet-costumes-jeffrey-kurland/">look in those suits</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nolan’s films refuse to paint scientists as either heroes or villains, instead showing them as brilliant but fallible humans wrestling with the consequences of their discoveries — consequences we all now have to live with. But <em>Oppenheimer</em> represented his most direct confrontation yet with how scientific progress creates unprecedented moral burdens.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The film’s pivotal moment — the moment that initially inspired Nolan to begin the project — comes when Oppenheimer&#8217;s team at Los Alamos <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/8/11/23827500/trinity-site-oppenheimer-nuclear-missiles-christopher-nolan-manhattan-project">realizes</a> there was a small but real possibility that the first nuclear test might ignite the atmosphere and destroy all life on Earth. After some debate — with Matt Damon’s brusque Gen. Leslie Groves playing the shocked audience surrogate — they proceed anyway. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;That struck me as the most dramatic situation in the history of the world,&#8221; Nolan told the Bulletin. &#8220;That&#8217;s a responsibility that nobody else in the history of the world had ever faced.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What makes Nolan&#8217;s treatment of these weighty themes remarkable is his insistence on tackling them through the lens of mass-market entertainment rather than niche documentary. He employs the cutting edge of big-budget filmmaking — from practical effects to IMAX cameras — to make abstract dangers feel immediate and real. For <em>Oppenheimer</em>, he even <a href="https://www.hindustantimes.com/entertainment/hollywood/christopher-nolan-claims-his-nuclear-explosion-film-oppenheimer-has-zero-cgi-shots-101688805750030.html#:~:text=Nolan%20confirms%20there's%20no%20CGI,of%20New%20Mexico%20in%201945.">refused</a> to use computer graphics for the nuclear explosions, believing that only practical effects could convey the genuine terror such weapons should inspire. And audiences’ reactions <a href="https://screenrant.com/oppenheimer-movie-trinity-test-christopher-nolan-audience-reaction/">proved him right</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-28_87c7bd.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,23.944126436126,100,52.111747127747" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The approach has proved remarkably effective at reaching audiences that might otherwise tune out discussions of existential risk — and as someone who has <a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/bryan-walsh/end-times/9780316449618/?lens=hachette-books">written a book</a> on precisely that subject, I can tell you that’s no easy feat<em>. Oppenheimer</em> earned over $950 million globally while sparking <a href="https://www.nti.org/news/hollywood-voices-sound-alarm-on-nuclear-threat-as-oppenheimer-sweeps-the-academy-awards/">meaningful public discourse</a> about nuclear weapons.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The director&#8217;s greatest concern now is how easily society can normalize even the most terrible risks, and why it is so important to fight back. When he <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZlJXZzSLIjA">accepted</a> a BAFTA award for <em>Oppneheimer</em>, Nolan told the audience, “Our film ends on what is a dramatically necessary note of despair, but in the world all kinds of individuals and organizations have fought long and hard to reduce the number of nuclear weapons.” Still, he continued, “of late, that has gone the wrong way,” as the nuclear arms control regime <a href="https://time.com/6334258/putin-nuclear-arms-control/">teeters on collapse</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Through films that marry entertainment with ethical weight, Nolan has emerged as one of Hollywood&#8217;s most effective voices for keeping humanity&#8217;s greatest challenges squarely in the public consciousness. He reminds us that existential risks aren&#8217;t just abstract policy issues — they&#8217;re profound human dramas that demand our attention and moral consideration. In an era when many choose to look away from humanity&#8217;s gravest threats, Nolan insists we look directly at them, in all their terrifying scope and complexity. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sam Delgado</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The climate crisis is a big problem. Marine biologist Ayana Elizabeth Johnson is dreaming of even bigger solutions.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384512/ayana-elizabeth-johnson-marine-biology-climate-solutions-future-perfect-50" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=384512</id>
			<updated>2024-11-21T11:35:55-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-21T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future Perfect 50" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s an exercise for you: Imagine the trajectory of our current climate crisis.&#160; You probably don’t need to imagine very hard what this future looks like because we’re seeing it play out in the present: towns torn apart by massive hurricanes, thousands displaced by wildfires, lives taken by extreme heat. All of it is enough [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of black woman wearing red glasses" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/37_Ayana_Elizabeth_Johnson-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<a href='https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/386449/2024-future-perfect-50-progress-ai-climate-animal-welfare-innovation' target='_blank' rel="noopener"><img src='https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/CenteredTag_2_FP50_8f0cf5.png' class='p-block-image alignnone wp-image-386498'></a>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here’s an exercise for you: Imagine the trajectory of our current <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate">climate</a> crisis.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You probably don’t need to imagine very hard what this future looks like because we’re seeing it play out in the present: towns torn apart by <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/377313/hurricane-milton-landfall-florida">massive hurricanes</a>, thousands displaced by <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/363880/park-fire-california-evacuations-housing-crisis">wildfires</a>, lives taken by <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23805954/extreme-heat-waves-explained-climate-change-solutions">extreme heat</a>. All of it is enough to make a person freeze with fear.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there is a flip side to this terror.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/PQ_0-25_fa8280.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,2.3133016084326,100,95.373396783135" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Such an all-consuming problem inherently requires innovative solutions and adaptations of epic proportions. So here’s another exercise: Close your eyes and think, what could a world that hasn’t just taken the climate crisis seriously but also risen to the challenge look like?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Envisioning a better future in the face of serious climate threats might seem like lofty daydreaming, especially when we take into consideration our <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23864312/climate-change-stocktake-cop28-dubai">world</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/373316/plastics-microplastics-humans-water-environment-health">leaders’</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/22434172/us-cbd-treaty-biological-diversity-nature-conservation">inaction</a>. But Ayana Elizabeth Johnson, a marine biologist and climate policy wonk, has spent much of her career dreaming and coming up with climate solutions — and she knows that nihilism and avoidance won’t get us anywhere.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her recently published book, <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/645855/what-if-we-get-it-right-by-ayana-elizabeth-johnson/"><em>What If We Get It Right? Visions of Climate Futures</em></a><em>, </em>Johnson tackles how we can transform our ways of being, thinking, and doing to stop the worst of climate change. She expertly intertwines her conversations with scientists, artists, and activists to create a practical and accessible guidebook for a more just future brimming with possibilities — a salve for even the most environmentally anxious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Peril and possibility coexist,” she writes in the book. Of course, she’s well aware of just how big of an environmental mess our world is in, but you won’t catch her dwelling on the worst-case scenarios for long. “We’re pretty fucked,” Johnson said in her September <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/374637/climate-ayana-elizabeth-johnson-what-if-we-get-it-right-gray-area">interview</a> on Vox’s <em>The Gray Area</em>, “but there’s a lot we could do to have a better possible future.”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-megaphone-fm wp-block-embed-megaphone-fm"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><iframe title="What if we get climate change right? by The Gray Area with Sean Illing" src="https://player.megaphone.fm/VMP1736669009" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson is particularly adept at speaking to those who know the climate crisis is real but have the instinct to bury their head in the sand at the thought of such a massive existential crisis.<strong> </strong>Though she is frank about the state of our world’s environmental health, she speaks and writes with an energizing clarity — whether it’s conversing with climate advocates for her <a href="https://ayanaelizabeth.substack.com/podcast">book tour</a> or breaking down big environmental questions as a co-host of the podcast <a href="https://gimletmedia.com/shows/howtosaveaplanet/episodes"><em>How to Save a Planet</em></a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s Johnson’s understanding of our instinct to flee the climate problems that has made it essential for her to explore the possibilities to address it and take action that goes beyond protesting or voting. These are important measures, Johnson believes, but also broad ones that aren’t necessarily fine-tuned to our individual experiences, skills, and interests.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Johnson, a Brooklyn native who calls the ocean her love before it became her career, that looked like co-founding <a href="https://urbanoceanlab.org/">Urban Ocean Lab</a> (UOL) in 2018. The nonprofit think tank specializes in researching coastal cities in the United States — places that <a href="https://urbanoceanlab.org/resource/coastal-cities">1 in 5 Americans call home</a> and are often vulnerable to some of the worst environmental disasters — and developing equitable, pragmatic policy recommendations for these regions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One such recommendation is UOL’s <a href="https://urbanoceanlab.org/climate-readiness-framework">climate readiness framework</a> for coastal cities. It’s a comprehensive collection of over 70 actions that coastal communities can apply to better adapt to current and future climate risks, such as working with community-based organizations to strengthen disaster preparedness plans and developing home relocation programs for low-income residents and people of color living in climate-vulnerable places.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Johnson_01_193dc5.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.097077749844,100,73.805844500311" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Caribbean region in particular has a special place in Johnson’s heart — her late father hailed from Jamaica, whose <a href="https://news.mongabay.com/2021/06/conservation-solutions-in-paradise-jamaicas-oracabessa-bay-fishing-sanctuary/#:~:text=The%20increase%20in%20pollutants%20like,Photo%20by%20Gladstone%20Taylor.">waters have suffered from pollution and overfishing</a>. “To me, ocean conservation is in part about cultural preservation,” she writes after reflecting on her father’s life between Jamaica and New York City. “We are losing something more fundamental than a meal: a way of life.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It makes sense that Johnson has also worked to improve the waters surrounding these islands. Prior to founding UOL, she led an ocean management policy project called the Blue Halo Initiative at the Waitt Institute, where she served as executive director. Starting in <a href="https://www.waittinstitute.org/blue-halo-barbuda">Barbuda</a> in 2013, Johnson focused on engaging with the community, interviewing hundreds of fishers and residents to develop policy recommendations for better preserving the waters and the species within it. Just a year later, the <a href="https://www.blueclimateinitiative.org/sites/default/files/2020-07/Johnson%20et%20al%202020%20-%20Barbuda%20ocean%20zoning%20-%20Marine%20Policy%20(1).pdf">Barbuda Council signed into law</a> a set of ocean zoning policies to protect underwater ecosystems and ensure sustainable fishing. These efforts were soon replicated in Montserrat and Curaçao.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson’s reverence for the ocean and the career she’s made out of it has made its way into the American political sphere, too. Back in 2019, the Green New Deal, a <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/12/21/18144138/green-new-deal-alexandria-ocasio-cortez">set of proposed progressive climate policies</a>, was supported by left-leaning candidates up and down the ballot. Johnson had just one issue with it: It left out our seas almost entirely. “I was feeling bummed about the ocean getting short shrift in the Green New Deal Resolution — just a single, vague reference to the ocean,” Johnson wrote in <em>What If We Get It Right?</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That summer, Johnson co-authored an op-ed in Grist about this <a href="https://grist.org/article/the-big-blue-gap-in-the-green-new-deal/">big blue gap</a> and what solutions to fill it with. Within that year, Johnson was contacted by Sen. Elizabeth Warren’s 2020 presidential campaign to help write what would become the <a href="https://elizabethwarren.com/plans/blue-new-deal">Blue New Deal</a>, an official policy platform for the Warren campaign. It was an extensive list of actions, like expanding marine protected areas, building climate-smart ports, and holding Big Agriculture accountable for water pollution. When Johnson later metWarren, she wrote in <em>What If We Get It Right? </em>that she “told me it was the plan that got the most excited mentions in her selfie lines.” And while Joe Biden won the Democratic nomination and the election, his administration became the first to put out a federal <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Ocean-Climate-Action-Plan_Final.pdf">Ocean Climate Action</a> plan — which included similar elements to the Blue New Deal — after dozens of businesses and organizations (including UOL) pushed the White House to do so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a lot of studies that show engaging with nature helps our physical and mental well-being, so it’s not surprising that conserving our environment is important for many people. One word that Johnson often uses and embodies is “biophilia”: a love for nature and life, and in her words, “a powerful driving force for conservation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With this in mind, I have one more exercise for you: Think of moments you’ve felt biophilia. Maybe you once walked through a lush forest, swam in a pristine lake, or witnessed snow-capped mountains up close. Perhaps you’ve encountered one of the millions of amazing creatures that inhabit these ecosystems. But how can one hold onto this sense of biophilia if much of our ways of life are destroying the very essence of it?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s all the more reason not to let our worries immobilize us and instead try to get it right, just as Johnson has done. Her wide-ranging expertise on climate policy; deeply empathetic and inclusive lens for climate solutions; and her unwavering, contagious biophilia has made her a bold visionary to follow in the climate space.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How apt that a lover of the ocean is making waves.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
