<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-11-01T17:58:33+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Laura Bult</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Coleman Lowndes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What polls can actually tell us]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/videos/381712/what-polls-can-actually-tell-us" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381712</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T12:58:22-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T13:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Video" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For anyone closely watching the 2024 election, scrutinizing the daily drop of polls has become the norm. Each new data point gives people cause to celebrate or despair depending on how their candidate is faring. But if you understand what polls are actually capable of telling you, it might dispel any desire you have for [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="How polling works with blue bar above and red bar below" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/what-polls-can-actually-tell-us.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For anyone closely watching the 2024 election, scrutinizing the daily drop of polls has become the norm. Each new data point gives people cause to celebrate or despair depending on how their candidate is faring. But if you understand what polls are actually capable of telling you, it might dispel any desire you have for them to predict whether Kamala Harris or Donald Trump will be the next president. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For this video, we interviewed pollsters about their processes and explained the basics of how they turn small surveys into a way to measure the opinions and intentions of the American voting population. No matter what measures pollsters take to make their samples as representative as possible, there’s a limit to how precise they can be. And, sometimes, those same measures can make the poll numbers go awry.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Staff</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Take a mental break with the newest Vox crossword]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/21523212/crossword-puzzles-free-daily-printable" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/21523212/crossword-puzzles-free-daily-printable</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T11:31:57-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T11:31:55-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Crosswords" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Vox crossword! New puzzles are published daily, Monday through Saturday, and our moderated comments section is now live. The registration link is below every puzzle so get over there and add your two cents. Puzzle editors, constructors, and other solvers will be on hand to answer your questions and reply to your [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/18980610/crossword_yellow__1_.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Welcome to the Vox crossword! New puzzles are published daily, Monday through Saturday, and our moderated <strong>comments section is now live</strong>. The registration link is below every puzzle so get over there and add your two cents. Puzzle editors, constructors, and other solvers will be on hand to answer your questions and reply to your remarks. You can also register <a href="https://vox.coral.coralproject.net/embed/auth?view=SIGN_UP">right here</a>. Puzzles are constructed by <a href="https://www.vox.com/e/21273241">these great people</a> and edited by <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/elizabeth-crane">Elizabeth Crane</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Make sure to bookmark this page or <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/667910/how-to-add-a-website-to-your-iphone-or-ipad-home-screen/">add it to your phone’s home screen</a> to find a new challenge each day. You can also get a weekly email reminder by <a href="http://vox.com/crossword-newsletter">signing up for our crossword newsletter</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Need more puzzles? We have whole <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vox-Pop-Culture-Crosswords-Puzzles/dp/1454950064">books</a> of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Vox-Mega-Book-Mini-Crosswords/dp/1454950056/ref=pd_lpo_sccl_2/130-1400015-9235626?pd_rd_w=7UXxb&amp;content-id=amzn1.sym.4c8c52db-06f8-4e42-8e56-912796f2ea6c&amp;pf_rd_p=4c8c52db-06f8-4e42-8e56-912796f2ea6c&amp;pf_rd_r=5WNWY0GXSDT6CZQCQ1J7&amp;pd_rd_wg=acUYA&amp;pd_rd_r=79c1a273-f9d1-4614-9fc3-414aad1ccd14&amp;pd_rd_i=1454950056&amp;psc=1">Vox crosswords</a>!</p>

<div class="m-ad m-ad__editorial-athena-placement"></div>

<div id="xword-wrapper">
<iframe allowfullscreen="true" height="1000" width="375" src="https://cdn3.amuselabs.com/vox/date-picker?set=vox&amp;embed=1&amp;limit=30&amp;maxCols=1"></iframe>
</div>

var puzzlecontainer = document.getElementById('xword-wrapper');
var puzzle = document.getElementById('voxpuzzle').contentWindow;


function receiveMessage(event) {
if (event.origin !== "https://cdn3.amuselabs.com") return;
if (!event.data) return;
if (typeof event.data !== 'string') return;
var data = JSON.parse(event.data);
  if (data.src === "crossword" || data.src === "picker"){
  puzzlecontainer.style.height = data.frameHeight + 'px';
}
}
window.addEventListener("message", receiveMessage, false);


<p><a href="/pages/crossword-puzzles-free-archive" class="p-button">More crossword puzzles</a></p>

<div class="m-ad m-ad__editorial-leaderboard-placement"></div>

<div id="coral_thread"></div>

  (function() {
      var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');
      s.src = 'https://vox.coral.coralproject.net/assets/js/embed.js';
      s.async = false;
      s.defer = true;
      s.onload = function() {
          Coral.createStreamEmbed({
              id: "coral_thread",
              autoRender: true,
              rootURL: 'https://vox.coral.coralproject.net',
              // Uncomment these lines and replace with the ID of the
              // story's ID and URL from your CMS to provide the
              // tightest integration. Refer to our documentation at
              // https://docs.coralproject.net for all the configuration
              // options.
              // storyID: '${storyID}',
              // storyURL: '${storyURL}',
          });
      };
      (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
  })();
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Elon Musk assures voters that Trump’s victory would deliver “temporary hardship”]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381637/elon-musk-donald-trump-2024-election-temporary-hardship" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381637</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T13:49:56-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T11:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Elon Musk" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Influence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elon Musk has arguably done more than any single individual to aid Donald Trump’s campaign. The mega-billionaire has put more than $75 million toward electing the former president, turned America’s most politically influential social media platform into a vehicle for right-wing propaganda, orchestrated a (shambolic) get-out-the-vote effort, and repeatedly appeared beside Trump on the campaign [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Elon Musk shouts with his fists raised in front of a crowd." data-caption="Elon Musk gestures as he steps on stage during a rally for Donald Trump at Madison Square Garden in New York, October 27, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2180776978.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Elon Musk gestures as he steps on stage during a rally for Donald Trump at Madison Square Garden in New York, October 27, 2024. | Angela Weiss/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk has arguably done more than any single individual to aid Donald Trump’s campaign. The mega-billionaire has put more than <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/16/g-s1-28591/elon-musk-donald-trump-america-pac-fec">$75 million</a> toward electing the former president, turned America’s most politically influential social media platform <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/10/30/study-shows-elon-musk-tweets-pro-trump-appear-x-users-feeds-within-2-sessions/">into a vehicle for right-wing propaganda</a>, orchestrated <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-america-pac-blitz-canvassing-michigan-uhaul/">a (shambolic) get-out-the-vote effort,</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWSXmMiWTJ0">repeatedly appeared</a> beside Trump on the campaign trail.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, as the race enters the homestretch, Musk is trying to clinch Trump’s victory with a bracing closing argument: If our side wins, you will experience severe economic pain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If elected, Trump has vowed to put <a href="https://apnews.com/article/donald-trump-elon-musk-government-efficiency-commission-e831ed5dc2f6a56999e1a70bb0a4eaeb">Musk in charge of a “government efficiency commission,”</a> which would identify supposedly wasteful programs that should be eliminated or slashed. During a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">telephone town hall</a> last Friday, Musk said his commission’s work would “necessarily involve some temporary hardship.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Days later, Musk suggested that this budget cutting — combined with Trump’s mass deportation plan — would cause a market-crashing economic “storm.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On his social media platform, X (a.k.a. Twitter), an anonymous user <a href="https://x.com/AaronBlake/status/1851287697907744953">posted Tuesday</a> that, “If Trump succeeds in forcing through mass deportations, combined with Elon hacking away at the government, firing people and reducing the deficit &#8211; there will be an initial severe overreaction in the economy…Market will tumble. But when the storm passes and everyone realizes we are on sounder footing, there will be a rapid recovery to a healthier, sustainable economy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Musk replied, “Sounds about right.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is one of the more truthful arguments that Musk has made for Trump’s election, which is to say, only half of it is false. If Trump delivers on his stated plans, Americans will indeed suffer material hardship. But such deprivation would neither be necessary for — nor conducive to — achieving a healthier or more sustainable economy. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Already, US retailers are saying that they will <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/30/companies-tariffs-trump-prices/">increase prices if Trump is elected</a> in order to offset the impact of his 10 percent universal tariff on imports. And contrary to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/24/politics/trump-us-business-tariffs-taxes/index.html">Trump’s suggestion</a>, those painful price hikes would not yield a stronger US manufacturing industry in the long term. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s plans for mass deportation, meanwhile, would trigger severe labor shortages in the construction and agricultural sectors, rendering food and housing more expensive. And these immediate disruptions would not raise American wages in the long run, but rather, make the economy less productive, and Medicare and Social Security more difficult to sustain.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Musk’s plans for slashing federal spending would be similarly calamitous. He has offered few details about his vision for downsizing Uncle Sam, but recently suggested that the federal government’s $6.75 trillion budget should be cut by <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">at least $2 trillion</a>. Austerity on that scale would disrupt myriad government services on which Democrats and Republicans rely, while threatening to throw the US economy into severe recession. And there is little basis for believing that an economic paradise would rise from such ruins.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Trump’s tariffs would raise consumer prices without aiding the broader economy</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first component of the joint Trump-Musk economic vision is a sweeping tariff regime. Trump has promised to impose a 10 percent to 20 percent <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/20/trump-tariffs-election.html">universal tariff on all imports</a>, and an at least <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/02/04/trump-floats-more-than-60percent-tariffs-on-chinese-imports.html">60 percent tariff</a> on imports from China.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He claims that the cost of these duties would be borne by foreign producers. The theory behind that claim (to the extent that Trump has one) is that overseas companies would feel compelled to fully offset the impact of the tariff for US consumers: Since their goods would face a 10 percent sales tax in the US — while the goods of their American competitors would face no tax — exporters would cut the prices of their goods by 10 percent, and accept lower profit margins, in order to maintain their products’ competitiveness on the US market.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this idea is dubious in theory, and patently false in practice. For one thing, there are many products and commodities that cannot be produced in the United States. Putting a 10 percent tariff on Colombian coffee beans will not make it possible to grow coffee at scale in the US. A Colombian Arabica exporter would therefore have no incentive to lower their prices in response to Trump’s tariff, for fear of getting outcompeted by nonexistent US rivals.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another even larger problem for Trump’s theory is that American manufacturers cannot produce many of their wares without foreign-made components. Putting a tariff on all imports therefore increases domestic firms’ cost of production. And many American companies are already telling investors and the public that they will raise prices in order to offset that increase in costs. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If we get tariffs, we will pass those tariff costs back to the consumer,” the CEO of AutoZone, an American auto parts retailer, recently said on <a href="https://www.the-sun.com/motors/12788723/autozone-price-hikes-trump-tariffs/">an earnings call</a>. “We’ll generally raise prices ahead of — we know what the tariffs will be — we generally raise prices ahead of that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/30/companies-tariffs-trump-prices/">Washington Post</a> reported, Columbia Sportswear and Stanley Black &amp; Decker have announced similar plans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For these reasons, among others, <a href="https://budgetlab.yale.edu/research/fiscal-macroeconomic-and-price-estimates-tariffs-under-both-non-retaliation-and-retaliation">Yale’s Budget Lab estimates that Trump’s tariffs</a> would raise consumer prices by as much as 5.1 percent, or $7,600 per household (in 2023 dollars).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critically, this immediate pain for US consumers would not translate into durable gains for America’s manufacturers. To the contrary, Trump’s tariffs would likely hurt American exporters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As already mentioned, his tariff would raise input costs for American producers. And that would render such manufacturers less competitive in the global market, leading them to lose market share.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, the small-bore tariffs that Trump applied during his first term demonstrated this problem. Economists at the University of California San Diego, the Census Bureau, and the Federal Reserve studied the<a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3514349"> impacts of Trump’s tariffs</a> on steel, aluminum, solar panels, and various Chinese goods. They found that American exporters who were most exposed to tariffs on their inputs saw lower export growth in 2019 than exporters who were unaffected by the duties. And the impacts would likely be significantly larger for a universal tariff that raised the cost of every foreign input to the production process.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, Trump’s tariff would run afoul of America’s obligations under various free trade agreements. And other nations would respond by imposing retaliatory tariffs on American-made goods. Again, Trump’s far more modest experiments with protectionism in his first term illustrated the problem. As America’s trade partners imposed retaliatory duties on US agricultural products, <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/webdocs/publications/102980/err-304.pdf">American farmers suffered a $27 billion loss</a> in exports between mid-2018 and the end of 2019. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further, a <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/feds/files/2019086pap.pdf">2019 Federal Reserve analysis</a> found that US manufacturers exposed to tariffs saw relative reductions in employment as the harms of higher input costs and retaliatory tariffs outweighed the benefits of protection from import competition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, Trump’s tariffs would make life more expensive for consumers in the short term, and American manufacturing less competitive in the long run.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Deporting undocumented immigrants en masse would make America poorer</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump also plans to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373479/stephen-miller-mass-deportation-camps-trump-agenda">deport undocumented immigrants</a>, including law-abiding workers who’ve long lived in the US. In addition to the human suffering mass deportations would cause, such a plan would impose immediate economic pain with no compensating long-term benefit.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rapidly removing millions of undocumented workers from the economy would devastate the agricultural and construction sectors, where such immigrants make up <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/30/trump-deportation-plan-economic-disaster">roughly one-third and one-quarter of the workforce</a>, respectively. This would render both food and housing more scarce, and thus more expensive (at least in the immediate term).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The disappearance of millions of working-age people who pay Social Security and Medicare taxes would also <a href="https://www.americanimmigrationcouncil.org/sites/default/files/research/mass_deportation_report_0.pdf">expedite the insolvency of those programs.</a> As the American population ages over the next five years, it will need to add <a href="https://www.protectedincome.org/news/labor-day-peak-65-trades-hit-hardest/#:~:text=Washington%2C%20D.C.%2C%20August%2027%2C,of%20Peak%20Baby%20Boomer%20retirements.">240,000 workers each month</a> to keep pace with retirements, according to a recent study. Trump’s program would make this virtually impossible to achieve.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s supporters argue that these harms will be offset in the long run by huge wage gains for native-born Americans, who will no longer need to compete with undocumented workers for jobs. But this is a fallacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">American workers’ bargaining power is determined by the balance between the demand for labor in the economy and the supply of workers. When employers have a high appetite for labor but a limited pool of applicants, workers can secure better pay and conditions. This economic circumstance is commonly described as a “tight labor market.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mass deportation would reduce the supply of workers in the US economy. But it would also reduce <em>demand</em> for American labor: Immigrants are human beings who purchase goods and services in order to survive and enjoy themselves. Consequently, deporting millions of undocumented immigrants wouldn’t necessarily make labor markets tighter. And in any event, such a destructive policy is unnecessary for creating a favorable environment for US workers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s more than possible to simultaneously generate a tighter labor market and grow the population of workers through immigration. In fact, this just occurred: In 2022 and 2023, an estimated <a href="https://www.jchs.harvard.edu/blog/what-effects-will-recent-surge-immigration-have-household-growth">6 million people immigrated</a> to the US. Over that same period, <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/UNRATE">unemployment fell</a> to historic lows, while <a href="https://www.epi.org/blog/a-2023-census-data-preview-household-incomes-likely-rose-because-of-a-strong-labor-market-and-falling-inflation/">wages rose</a> and <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/05/29/low-income-wages-employment-00097135">pay inequality fell</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This was not an aberrant outcome. As economics blogger Noah Smith notes, economists have studied the <a href="https://www.noahpinion.blog/p/why-immigration-doesnt-reduce-wages">economic effects of myriad immigration waves</a>, and tend to find no negative impact on native-born workers’ wages or employment prospects.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, immigrants tend to increase an economy’s labor efficiency. This is because immigrant workers are <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/immigrants-contribute-greatly-to-us-economy-despite-administrations-public-charge-rule">far more willing to move</a> in response to shifting economic conditions than native workers who have deep roots in particular US communities. Immigrants are therefore uniquely effective at filling shortages in local labor markets. By plugging these holes, they render other workers in those places more productive. The Harvard economist <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2001/01/2001a_bpea_borjas.pdf">George Borjas has estimated that such productivity gains</a> generate between $5 billion and $10 billion of economic value for native-born workers each year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, Trump’s immigration plans would make US consumers poorer in the near term, while reducing the size and productivity of the American economy on a longer time horizon.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Gutting air safety, meat inspections, and food stamps will not make the economy healthier</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, Musk’s fiscal plans — which Trump supposedly intends to implement (at least, according to Musk) — would severely disrupt the provision of government services and increase unemployment, while hurting the economy’s long-term growth prospects.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At Trump’s rally at Madison Square Garden, Cantor Fitzgerald CEO Howard Lutnick <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">asked Musk,</a> “How much do you think we can rip out of this wasted, $6.5 trillion Harris-Biden budget?” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This was evidently a reference to the 2024 US federal budget, which is actually $6.75 trillion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think we can do at least $2 trillion,” Musk replied.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This proposal is so radical it has attracted criticism from fiscal conservatives who support the broad goal of cutting federal spending. Brian Riedl, a senior fellow at the right-wing Manhattan Institute, told the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">Washington Post</a> this week, “The idea that one can cut $2 trillion in wasteful and unnecessary programs is absolutely absurd.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The reason is simple. According to government watchdogs, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/blog/federal-government-made-236-billion-improper-payments-last-fiscal-year">actual waste and fraud amounts to</a> less than $300 billion a year. Shaving $2 trillion off the federal budget would therefore require draconian cuts to many popular federal programs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Were Trump to implement Musk’s vision while simultaneously honoring his promise to avoid cutting entitlements and the GOP’s commitment to avoiding defense spending cuts, then he would need to slash all other government programs by 80 percent. That would involve gutting all social services for low-income Americans, food inspections, air safety, health insurance subsidies, and infrastructure investments, among countless other things.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This would abruptly and massively reduce demand in the US economy, potentially triggering a recession.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is little reason to expect such severe and haphazard spending cuts to benefit the economy in the long term. After all, government investments in <a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4705468#:~:text=Findings%3A%20The%20results%20indicate%20a,but%20still%20significant%20positive%20effect.">education</a> and <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/the-potential-macroeconomic-benefits-from-increasing-infrastructure-investment/">infrastructure</a> often increase the economy’s growth potential — slashing funding for such programs could impair America’s economic performance in the coming decades.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The best argument for Trump’s economic agenda is that he might not act on it</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Musk is correct to say that Trump’s plans would impose hardship on the American people. But he’s wrong to describe such difficulties as temporary. If Trump and Musk get their way, America’s consumers will pay higher prices, its manufacturers will sell fewer exports, its agricultural industry will fall into chaos, its workforce will become less productive, its federal government will struggle to provide basic services, and its long-term economic growth potential will fall. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s supporters might reasonably argue that none of this should trouble us, since he rarely fulfills his campaign promises and will surely back away from his economically ruinous agenda once in office. But “don’t worry, our candidate is a huge liar” does not strike me as a much better message than “prepare for temporary hardship.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 election violence is already happening]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381520/2024-election-violence-trump-loses-extremism-civil-war" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381520</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T10:57:24-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T10:55:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Political violence has reached alarming levels in the US over the last few years.&#160; The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband, and multiple assassination attempts against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment.&#160; Now, the 2024 election could [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A protester flying a Trump flag and an upside down American flag on the lawn far in front of the Capitol Building." data-caption="Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1230734387.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Political violence has reached <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-politics-violence/">alarming levels </a>in the US over the last few years.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/david-depape-nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attacked-454cbde088fcae22a356f1f8dd0e9eba">attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club">multiple assassination attempts</a> against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the 2024 election could cause another flare-up, especially if Trump loses. Discussion of violence among right-wing extremists has also already <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">spiked online</a>, and unlike Vice President Kamala Harris, Trump has refused to say that he would concede.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has, however, employed violent rhetoric himself. On Thursday, Trump lambasted former Rep. Liz Cheney, an outspoken Republican critic of the former president who he described as a “radical war hawk.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Let’s put her with a rifle standing there with nine barrels shooting at her, okay?” he said at a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/01/politics/donald-trump-liz-cheney-war-hawk-battle/index.html">campaign event in Arizona</a>. “Let’s see how she feels about it, you know, when the guns are trained on her face.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The polls show a <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">tight race</a> between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, suggesting that this time, as in 2020, the results may be decided by narrow margins in a few battleground states. Trump has been priming Republican voters to reject the results if he comes up short, making <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/29/politics/trump-voter-fraud-claims-pennsylvania/index.html">unsubstantiated claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-noncitizen-voter-fraud-fact-check/">noncitizens voting on a widespread basis</a>. Billionaire Trump supporter Elon Musk has also set up a platform on his social media site X, formerly known as Twitter, for users to &#8220;<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/31/nx-s1-5165523/voting-election-conspiracy-theories-social-media">share potential incidents of voter fraud or irregularities</a> you see while voting in the 2024 election.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those tactics seem to be working. If Trump loses, about a quarter of Republicans said they think he should do whatever it takes to ensure he becomes president anyway, according to a <a href="https://www.prri.org/research/one-leader-under-god-the-connection-between-authoritarianism-and-christian-nationalism-in-america/?preview=true">September PRRI poll</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That may include resorting to violence. Among Republicans who don’t believe Biden’s win in 2020 was legitimate, almost one-third said in an <a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2024/08/07/snf-agora-poll-july-2024/">August poll</a> by the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University that they expected “a lot” or “a great deal” of political violence after the November election. More <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/30/voters-fear-violence-trump-loss/">recent polls</a> have found similar results, including an October <a href="https://apnorc.org/projects/many-voters-are-worried-about-the-electoral-process-and-transition-of-power/">AP-NORC poll</a> that found 27 percent of Republicans, and 42 percent of voters overall, “extremely” or “very” worried about post-election violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this has put law enforcement and national security officials on high alert about political violence in the days before and after the election. Earlier this month, a joint Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and FBI intelligence <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/election-violence-domestic-extremists-fbi-dhs-bulletin/">bulletin</a> said that domestic extremists &#8220;pose a threat of violence to a range of targets directly and indirectly associated with elections through at least the presidential inauguration&#8221; on January 20.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What kind of political violence might break out?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some incidents of political violence have already been recorded in the runup to Election Day.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots in mailboxes and drop boxes in <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-marty-walsh-boston-elections-crime-3d9dd32292187df91d73cb153b9c0a73">Massachusetts,</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballots-damaged-usps-mailbox-fire-phoenix-rcna177067">Arizona</a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballot-boxes-set-fire-portland-vancouver-rcna177611">Washington, and Oregon</a> have been damaged in suspected arson. DHS warned this might happen, based on its monitoring of comments made online in domestic violent extremist circles. In a series of <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">security bulletins</a> in the last few months, the agency noted, “Some threat actors may perceive ballot drop boxes as ‘soft targets’ because they are more accessible” and that some of these actors had discussed a variety of methods for damaging them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A man was also <a href="https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe/2024/10/29/grand-jury-indicts-man-accused-of-shooting-at-democratic-party-office/75924391007/">indicted on terrorism and gun charges</a> for allegedly shooting at the Democratic National Committee’s offices in Phoenix on three occasions since September.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things might only get worse from here. Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco has <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/u-s-news-decision-points/articles/2024-09-24/deputy-ag-u-s-faces-unprecedented-level-of-political-threats">warned</a> that the US is “facing an unprecedented level of, and increase in, threats of violence against public officials.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">DHS bulletins</a>, there is a “heightened risk” that domestic violent extremists could “attempt to initiate civil war.” That kind of chatter has become increasingly common in online spaces <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">frequented by right-wing extremist groups</a>. That said, the DHS noted that the prosecutions of those involved in the January 6 insurrection and hesitation about potential false flag operations designed to entrap them could serve as deterrents.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Law enforcement officials across the country are bracing for the possibility of escalation, particularly in Democratic population centers. For instance, Detroit’s election headquarters have reportedly been reinforced with bulletproof glass and will be protected by armed guards after Trump supporters tried to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/legal/michigan-still-counting-votes-angry-poll-watchers-barred-in-detroit-trump-sues-idUSKBN27K2AL/">interrupt ballot counting</a> by chanting “Stop the count” and banging on the windows in 2020. Philadelphia election staff will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-swing-states-officials-brace-conspiracy-theories-violence-2024-10-30/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=Daily-Briefing&amp;utm_term=103024&amp;user_email=38572e447ae2b3a943d6423dd3d8ad89c2e154a588929a92468b7914f3f4e88f&amp;lctg=66464e6f30f1bc62c305003b">count ballots in a warehouse</a> encircled by a fence with barbed wire, miles from the downtown area where protesters gathered in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, however, these preparations might not be enough to quell domestic violent extremist activity when Republican leaders are encouraging skepticism about the integrity of the election and are reportedly <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/speaker-johnson-appears-to-confirm-a-secret-election-plan-with-trump">making secret plans</a> to assure a second Trump term.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Being aware of the potential for violence and damage to the institutions we rely upon is important,” retired Gen. Joseph Votel, an executive board member of the Center for Ethics and the Rule of Law at the University of Pennsylvania, said in a statement. “But it is insufficient in the face of legislative acts that are open to broad interpretation, strong political rhetoric that dominates the public information space, and imperfect individuals acting in accordance with their oaths.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, November 1, 10:55 am ET:</strong> This story was originally published on October 31 and has been updated with Trump’s comments about Cheney.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Should you feel guilty about using AI?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/381158/should-you-feel-guilty-about-using-ai" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381158</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T10:41:48-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T10:41:13-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Emerging Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls Apple Intelligence this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users who opt in. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2172386617.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/10/apple-intelligence-is-available-today-on-iphone-ipad-and-mac/">Apple Intelligence</a> this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/121115#:~:text=To%20get%20started%20with%20Apple,though%20wait%20times%20can%20vary.">who opt in</a>. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple months now, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/370836/apple-intelligence-iphone-16-ios-update-siri">they’re pretty mediocre</a>. But this is only the beginning.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Generative AI, once a parlor trick for the tech-obsessed, is fast becoming the main event for major software releases. As Apple pushes its version of the technology, Google <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/google-ai-android-update-io-2024/">is building AI into its Android operating system</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/357247/why-are-ai-search-engines-so-bad">forcing everyone to look at AI Overviews</a> at the top of virtually every Google Search. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24205701/openai-searchgpt-ai-search-engine-google-perplexity-rival">OpenAI</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/28/24282017/meta-ai-powered-search-engine-report">Meta</a> are building their own AI-powered search engines, while the startup <a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/">Perplexity</a> already has one. <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/10/21/new-autonomous-agents-scale-your-team-like-never-before/">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/22/anthropic-announces-ai-agents-for-complex-tasks-racing-openai.html">Anthropic</a> recently announced new, super-powerful AI agents that can complete complex tasks much like humans would. (Disclosure: Vox Media is one of several publishers that has signed partnership agreements with OpenAI. Our reporting remains editorially independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While some companies have had generative AI products out in the wild for over a year, the arrival of Apple Intelligence marks an inflection point for the mainstreaming of the technology. Apple Intelligence is only available on the latest Apple devices, but over half the phones in the United States <a href="https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/dont-blame-apple-for-the-us-smartphone-market-blame-the-us-carriers">are iPhones</a>. As people upgrade, millions more can tap into the new technology.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re not already using AI, you probably will be soon — whether you like it or not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re getting AI, especially generative AI, shoved down our throats with little to no transparency, and honestly, the opt-out mechanisms are either nonexistent or complicated,” said Sasha Luccioni, AI researcher and climate lead at Hugging Face, a platform for sharing AI and machine learning tools.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If that fills you with dread, it’s understandable. Maybe you feel bad participating in the race <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/19/23879648/americans-artificial-general-intelligence-ai-policy-poll">to build a superintelligent AI</a> nobody asked for. You may feel complicit for using <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/technology/openai-copyright-law.html">AI models trained on copyrighted material</a> without paying the creators. You probably feel just plain bad about the flood of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/378855/ai-slop-fall-autumn-inspiration-vibes-pinterest">AI slop that’s ruining the internet</a> even if you did not personally create the slop.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the climate consequences of it all. AI, in its many shapes and forms, requires a lot of <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/28/24111721/climate-ai-tech-energy-demand-rising">energy and water to work</a>. A <em>lot</em>. That might make you feel downright guilty about using AI.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI’s big energy appetite</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a chance Apple Intelligence is more guilt-free than the other big AI options as far as energy is concerned. Apple says it keeps the processing for certain AI features, like GenMoji and Image Playground, entirely on your device. That means less reliance on energy-intensive data centers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t know exactly how much energy AI uses at these data centers. Using data from a recent Microsoft Research study, Shaolei Ren, an engineering professor at the University of California Riverside, came up with this: Asking ChatGPT to write two 200-word emails uses roughly the same amount of energy as a Tesla Model 3 would need to drive one mile. Because they generate so much heat, the processors that generated those emails would also require <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/18/energy-ai-use-electricity-water-data-centers/">about four half-liter bottles of water</a> to cool down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The consequences of such energy profligacy become clearer if you scale up. The amount of electricity used by data centers, where AI processing largely takes place, is <a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/AI-poised-to-drive-160-increase-in-power-demand">predicted to grow by 160 percent</a> by the end of the decade, and carbon dioxide emissions could more than double as a result, according to Goldman Sachs. Meanwhile, the amount of water needed will also spike, so much so that by 2027, AI’s thirst <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03271">could be equal to half the annual water withdrawal of the United Kingdom</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are all estimates based on limited data because the tech companies building AI systems, including Apple, Google, Microsoft, and OpenAI, do not share exactly how much energy or water their models use.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re just looking at the black box because we have absolutely no idea of the energy consumption for interacting with the large language models,” Ren said. He compared the situation to searching for flights on Google and being able <a href="https://support.google.com/travel/answer/9671620?hl=en">to see the carbon emissions for each leg</a>. “But when it comes to these large language models, there&#8217;s absolutely none, zero, no information.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lack of transparency about AI’s energy demands also runs counter to these tech companies’ sustainability promises. There’s good reason to believe that AI is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">leading directly to those promises being broken</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to increases in data center energy usage, Google saw its greenhouse gas emissions <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-02/google-s-emissions-shot-up-48-over-five-years-due-to-ai?sref=qYiz2hd0">increase by 48 percent</a> from 2019 to 2023, despite a pledge to cut emissions by 50 percent from its 2019 levels <a href="https://sustainability.google/operating-sustainably/net-zero-carbon/">by 2030</a>. The company <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-08/google-is-no-longer-claiming-to-be-carbon-neutral?sref=qYiz2hd0">no longer claims to be carbon neutral</a>. Microsoft similarly <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">saw a 29 percent jump in emissions</a> from 2020 to 2023. While Microsoft has promised to be carbon negative by 2030, it <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/microsoft-wrestles-with-rising-emissions-from-ai-ahead-of-its-2030-net-zero-goal-b53d4cf4">is now openly struggling</a> with ways to make that happen while keeping pace with AI innovation.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the AI dealers aren’t telling us</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is what an arms race looks like. It’s worth pointing out here that all energy usages started to spike around the time that OpenAI knocked the world’s socks off with its <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/05/technology/chatgpt-ai-twitter.html">surprise release of ChatGPT</a> in November 2022. The chatbot <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/6/23948386/chatgpt-active-user-count-openai-developer-conference">became the fastest-growing app ever</a>, capturing 100 million users <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-sets-record-fastest-growing-user-base-analyst-note-2023-02-01/">in two months</a> and kick-starting the AI gold rush in Silicon Valley. Now, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/16/generative-ai-startups-get-40percent-of-all-vc-investment-in-cloud-accel.html#:~:text=Generative%20artificial%20intelligence%20startups%20are,the%20startup%20at%20$157%20billion.">40 percent of all venture capital money</a> in cloud computing goes to generative AI companies. OpenAI itself announced a $6.6 billion funding round in early October — the <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/openai-raises-record--6-6-billion-investors-back-its-ai-dominance">largest venture capital round of all time</a> — giving it a $157 billion valuation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With such staggering amounts of money at play, it’s perhaps no surprise that energy efficiency takes a back seat to growth and innovation. Companies like OpenAI want the models that power their AI technology to get bigger so they can get better and outperform competitors. And the bigger the model, the greater the energy demand — at least for now. Over time, it’s likely that performance will get more efficient thanks to advances in chip technology, data center cooling, and engineering.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Because the innovation happened so quickly around when ChatGPT burst onto the scene, you would expect, initially, for the efficiency to be at its lowest point,” Josh Parker, head of sustainability at chipmaker Nvidia, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the most energy-intensive products are now what companies like OpenAI, Google, and Meta are pushing the hardest. Those include real-time chatbots, voice assistants, and search engines. These features <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24066646/ai-electricity-energy-watts-generative-consumption">enlist larger models and require more advanced chips</a> to work at the same time to reduce latency, or lag. Put simply, they have to do a lot of hard math problems all at once and very quickly. That’s why it takes as much electricity as it does to run a Tesla.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple, however, seems to present itself as an exception. As part of its promise to protect user privacy, the company says it handles as many Apple Intelligence tasks as it can on your device without sending queries to data centers. That means when you opt in to Apple Intelligence, you download a small generative AI model that can handle pretty simple tasks on your phone. Your iPhone battery, unlike a grid-connected cloud data center, has a limited amount of power, which forces Apple Intelligence to handle these tasks with some efficiency. Maybe on-device AI is the guilt-free version of the future after all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem, of course, is that we don’t know exactly how Apple Intelligence works. But there is some insight you can gain: You can actually access a log of your activity on Apple Intelligence by going to Settings and then Privacy and Security. There, you’ll see an option to export an Apple Intelligence Report. Unless you’re a developer, the file you download will be hard to read, since it’s full of code, but it does technically reveal <a href="https://eclecticlight.co/2024/10/29/check-writing-tools-using-air/">which tasks are handled on your device</a> and which ones get sent up to Apple’s Private Cloud Compute servers, giving them a bigger carbon footprint. Apple also says its servers run on 100 percent renewable energy, part of the company’s <a href="https://www.apple.com/environment/pdf/Apples_Product_Use_Electricity_Strategy.pdf">broader commitment to be carbon neutral</a> by the end of the decade.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So again, if you’re feeling dread or guilt about AI in your life, that’s understandable. It is clear that this technology, in its current state, consumes vast and increasing amounts of energy, contributing to greenhouse gas emissions and worsening human-caused climate change. It is also true that you might not have a choice, as big tech companies make generative AI more foundational to their products. You can opt out of Apple Intelligence or never opt in. But you’ll find it’s more difficult, if not impossible, to opt out of AI products from Google, Meta, and Microsoft. (If you want to try, here’s <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/05/31/opt-out-ai-training-meta-chatgpt/">a helpful guide</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a reason to feel guilty,” Luccioni said. “But I do think there&#8217;s a reason — as with climate change in general — to ask for more information, to ask for accountability on behalf of the companies that are selling us this stuff.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If AI is supposed to solve all our problems or destroy us all <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/2024/3/3/24083523/artificial-intelligence-ai-doomsday-panic-extinction-climate-change-utopia-tech-bros-silicon-valley">or both</a>, it would be nice to know the details. We could ask ChatGPT, but that might be a huge waste of energy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, 10:40 am, November 1, 2023:</strong> This story, originally published October 31, has been updated with additional details about Apple Intelligence and its energy use.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get through election season without despair]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/381475/elections-donald-trump-kamala-harris-anxiety-progress-voting" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381475</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T13:53:59-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T08:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When election season rolls around I always run into a lot of people who are having a pretty bad time. It’s the drumbeat of dire news and last-minute plot twists and scandals. It’s the absurdly close polls. It’s the feeling that we — especially people like me in California — are approximately powerless while a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An overhead view of a Donald Trump rally, with Trump on the stage and a large screen above him showing him speaking." data-caption="Many of the things that matter the most for our lives don’t get decided in elections." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2181524866.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Many of the things that matter the most for our lives don’t get decided in elections.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When election season rolls around I always run into a lot of people who are having a pretty bad time. It’s the drumbeat of dire news and <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/the-reidout/reidout-blog/trump-madison-square-garden-rally-rap-sports-50-cent-rcna178064">last-minute plot twists</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters">scandals</a>. It’s the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/378909/election-2024-polls-harris-trump-winning-odds">absurdly close polls</a>. It’s the feeling that we — especially people like me in California — are <a href="https://ash.harvard.edu/articles/the-electoral-college-and-our-broken-presidential-election-system/">approximately powerless</a> while a decision of enormous importance gets made. There’s nothing to do but wait and see what happens — not that that stops me from frequently refreshing all the models and squinting at the internals of all the polls.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I wanted to talk about how to keep perspective on presidential elections without pretending they don’t matter or letting them become the sole verdict on whether our world is headed in the right direction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It does matter a great deal who wins on Tuesday, obviously. Kamala Harris and Donald Trump have very different views on Ukraine, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368462/kamala-harris-israel-palestine-gaza-dnc-speech">Gaza</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/24137666/trump-agenda-inflation-prices-dollar-devaluation-tariffs">tariffs</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369177/democrats-kamala-harris-truce-immigration-progressive-border-security">legal immigration</a>,<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/trump-cia-venezuela-maduro-regime-change-plot/"> Latin American coup attempts</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/videos/370668/how-trump-could-ban-abortion-medication-president">abortion</a>, whether you should get election boards to discard the results of legitimate elections, and much more. I’m not here to argue you should be zen about the election because it doesn’t matter — it matters enormously.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I do think that when you step back and take some perspective, it’s clear that many of the things that matter the most for our lives — the lives of our loved ones, and the lives of everyone on Earth — don’t get decided in elections. And how those things go are much easier to affect than elections are.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Looking back at what actually mattered</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Often the most important gears that turned to affect people’s lives — for better or for worse — did that without a single mention on a debate stage or a campaign platform. <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/child-mortality">Antibiotics. Vaccination</a>. <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28076">Mass electrification</a>. <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3684076/#:~:text=Hock%20(2008)%20and%20Ananat%20and,representation%20in%20nontraditionally%20female%20professions.">Contraception</a>. <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w29102/w29102.pdf">The internet</a>. <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/356044/nuclear-annihilation-annie-jacobsen">The nuclear bomb</a>. <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/379527/livestock-auctions-animal-abuse-investigation-cow-sheep-goats">Factory farming</a>. Most of the ways that we are <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23632673/against-doomerism">fortunate to live in the 2020s instead of the 1920s</a> — and most of the ways that the 2020s are far more horrifying than the 1920s — happened despite the lousy presidents and without much aid from the good ones.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even when an issue is hotly contested, the key thing that ends up driving change is often only tangentially related to the part everyone is arguing about. We’re on a much better footing in the fight against climate change <a href="https://x.com/AlecStapp/status/1803810075909161296">because solar is so cheap</a> — most of the debates over everything else end up being a rounding error compared to that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of my colleague Dylan Matthews’s most famous <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/7/8/8894019/george-w-bush-pepfar">contrarian Future Perfect-flavored takes</a> was that George W. Bush was actually, if you do the math, an awesome president because of PEPFAR, his AIDS program that saved at least 1 million lives in Africa at a time when no one was giving AIDS the prioritization it deserved. Sure, he also started a couple of unnecessary wars in the Middle East and the pointless expansion of the surveillance state in the name of liberty; sure, his domestic policy agenda was mostly a flop or got forgotten about in the aftermath of 9/11. But still, he saved a lot of children.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How much to consider this a defense of Bush is mostly a philosophical question, and frankly I don’t care — I’m not the judge of his soul. But I do think that it’s an important point if you are thinking about how to do good in the world. Things that no one is paying attention to, neglected programs that a dedicated visionary can make happen — these are often where the enormous effects on the world are.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Remember what matters</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elections matter. But they are far from being the only thing that matters. And it’s hard among the noise and chaos and fury of any given moment to guess which of the many issues contested in an election are the ones that will really matter. (Pandemic prevention, just to take one example, was not much of an issue in 2016, just a few years before Covid hit.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So if you find yourself feeling paralyzed and helpless about elections, refreshing news sites instead of doing real substantive work toward a better world, my advice — which I have had only mixed success at taking for myself — is to stay oriented to all of the other things that matter just as much and that are much, much easier to change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead of letting every twist and swing of the polls in Wisconsin control your mood, work on something that really matters and that none of our politicians are bothering to solve. This is an important decision you don’t have much control over. But the direction of our country and our world is an important decision you do have an enormous amount of control over. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many great people are alive today because of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/21493812/smallpox-eradication-vaccines-infectious-disease-covid-19">individual efforts of dedicated people</a> who decided to solve some problem they could no longer bear. There are a great many important scientific projects that need volunteers. There are <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/364288/how-factory-farming-ends-animal-rights-vegans-climate-ethics">horrible evils to work on ending</a>, and horrible dilemmas that will become less of a dilemma as <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22652782/roots-of-progress-jason-crawford">advancing technology and human creativity</a> give all of us better options. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So next time you want to hit “refresh” on the polls, think about if you’ll find it more empowering — and the world will find it more useful — for you to pick something<em> </em>else that also really matters, and do that instead.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How much should kids know about politics?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/381410/kids-teens-politics-election-misinformation" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381410</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T18:23:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T07:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the midst of a heated presidential election, political coverage and commentary can feel unavoidable. Kids are not immune — they might be picking up information about the race from the adults in their lives, at recess, or on social media. As much as parents may think their children are oblivious, research shows kids, including [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of a father casting a paper ballot in a box. He is holding his daughter’s hand. She holds a toy bear." data-caption="Children as young as 5 have shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1277323587.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Children as young as 5 have shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In the midst of a heated presidential election, political coverage and commentary can feel unavoidable. Kids are not immune — they might be picking up information about the race from the adults in their lives, at recess, or on social media. As much as parents may think their children are oblivious, research shows kids, including very young ones, are paying attention. One study found that nearly all of the surveyed kids between the ages of 5 and 11<a href="https://news.ku.edu/news/article/2019/08/06/researchers-find-youths-knowledgeable-about-politics-call-even-better-early-political"> could name the candidates</a> running for president in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Kids as young as kindergarten and first grade can name candidates when they see their pictures,” says <a href="https://www.whitman.edu/academics/majors-and-programs/psychology/faculty-and-staff/erin-pahlke">Erin Pahlke</a>, an associate professor of psychology at Whitman College and a co-author of the study, “and they have a sense of what the candidates believe.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don’t have to have an in-depth discussion with your child every time they encounter a political topic. When it comes to political conversations with kids, experts say you should answer their questions about the civic process and quell any fears they may have — but avoid telling them how to think.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When kids are young, teach them about civic engagement</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since children as young as 5 are shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections, you can use this early exposure to guide and inform their knowledge. Kids of all ages can learn about civic engagement through activities like mock elections in school or accompanying their parents to the polls on Election Day, says clinical psychologist <a href="https://melissagoldbergmintz.com/">Melissa Goldberg Mintz</a>, author of<em> </em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/dp/1462547494"><em>Has Your Child </em></a><em><a href="https://www.guilford.com/books/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/Melissa-Goldberg-Mintz/9781462547494?srsltid=AfmBOopzU8cgP9dUWxCAgcx6boSaYPYd55-fu1OnB0NLCoFBcjd1EPcy">Been</a></em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/dp/1462547494"><em> Traumatized? How to Know and What to do to Promote Healing and Recovery</em></a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can use this experience to teach kids how elections work. Children as young as 5 can grasp that voters are choosing between two major candidates from opposite parties and for laws that affect where they live, Pahlke says. If an elementary school-aged child has particular interests — maybe they love trains and buses — you could explain how proposed legislation would impact transportation in your city or town, Goldberg Mintz says. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But don’t get too in the weeds or too prescriptive. “Something we would not want to do,” she says, “is talk about ‘With global climate change and increasing natural disasters, our city is doomed if we don&#8217;t have these protective flood measures.’”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Allow kids to lead the dialogue</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although children are exposed to more political information than their parents realize, their understanding or the conclusions they draw is sometimes incorrect, Pahlke says. Parents have a responsibility to clear up these misunderstandings, she continues, so ask your kids what they know about certain topics. Watching or reading the news together can be an effective way to start a conversation, says <a href="https://www.american.edu/cas/faculty/caporino.cfm">Nicole Caporino</a>, an associate professor of psychology at American University. If any stories trigger fear or confusion, you can discuss the likelihood that their fears will materialize, point out hopeful news stories, and assure them the family will cope with any potential challenges together, Caporino says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Caporino’s research has suggested that <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32100153/">most children and adolescents were worried</a> about political issues. Don’t downplay their concerns, Goldberg Mintz says. Do your best to give them an honest answer, but try not to give into fear or negativity, even if you are feeling scared. You might say, “I hear that you’re worried about that, and I have some concerns too. But we’ll figure out ways to get through it if that happens.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parents should open the door to these conversations, because chances are children might already be thinking about these topics, Pahlke says. However, you shouldn’t offer up too many details if your child isn’t interested. For example, if you ask your elementary-aged kid, “The presidential election is coming up. Have you heard anything?” and they don’t have a strong opinion or say they haven’t talked about it with their friends, you can leave it at that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We don&#8217;t ever want to volunteer bloody details or gory information that kids don&#8217;t already know about,” Goldberg Mintz says. “We want to be a trustworthy source for them. And if we don&#8217;t know the answer, we want to show them how to get to a trustworthy source.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens who are closer to voting age can handle discussions about specific policies, Pahlke says, and parents can explain various perspectives and potential outcomes. Parents can also talk with their teens about the importance of voting, Goldberg Mintz says.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Encourage them to fact-check what they see on social media</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html">increasingly turning to social media</a> to stay informed, with one 2022 survey finding that half of Gen Z adolescents <a href="https://deloitte.wsj.com/cmo/digital-social-media-power-gen-z-teens-news-consumption-01655136478">source their news from online platforms</a>. If your kid asks you a question about something they’ve seen on social media (or sounds as if it originated there), use this as an opportunity to fact-check those claims with them. Check sources like <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html">AP </a><a href="https://apnews.com/ap-fact-check">Fact</a><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html"> Check</a>, <a href="https://www.politifact.com/">Politifact</a>, and <a href="https://www.snopes.com/">Snopes</a> and show them where they can find trusted reporting. To <a href="https://newslit.org/educators/resources/is-it-legit/">determine a source’s credibility</a>, the News Literacy Project recommends quickly researching the source of your news, determining if the organization has ethical standards, and assessing the quality of the outlet’s other coverage. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“We don&#8217;t ever want to volunteer bloody details or gory information that kids don&#8217;t already know about.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If your teen doesn’t come to you directly with what they’ve been watching online, you might need to gently broach the conversation. In the case of viral disinformation campaigns, you can ask your child, “Did you see people talking about this on social media?” This way you can glean information about what your kid is seeing online and correct any inaccuracies.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Let them come to their own conclusions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">High schoolers will have more nuanced understandings about certain current events and policies and it’s appropriate to discuss these topics with them, Pahlke says. But rather than paint various candidates or points of view as “good” or “bad,” help them consider different perspectives. Explain why people with various experiences would have different opinions on a topic. It’s fine if they align with a particular candidate or policy, but they should also be able to see where the other side is coming from. Perspective-taking can help them in other relationships, too, Pahlke says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens may also have a clear understanding of their personal values and can reflect on how certain candidates or policies reflect these values and goals, Goldberg Mintz says. You can show your teen where to find <a href="https://newslit.org/educators/resources/is-it-legit/">credible information</a> from <a href="https://libguides.rutgers.edu/fake_news">trusted news sources</a> on specific candidates and policies and let them make up their minds. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Rather than trying to get in the weeds about ‘This is the candidate that our family can support, and it&#8217;s because XYZ’ is trying to define a kid&#8217;s beliefs for them,” Goldberg Mintz says. “We let our kids come to their own decisions.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[5 mysteries that might determine the 2024 election]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381399/electorate-demographics-2024-election-women-republican-black-latino-voter" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381399</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T18:22:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2024 election cycle has produced some stunning and sometimes counterintuitive narratives about how demographic subgroups might end up voting. We may just see a historic gulf in the way men and women vote — or not. Polls suggest we’re in for the greatest racial realignment since the Civil Rights Act was passed — or [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="People in a line in the back with a floor sign that reads early voting here" data-caption="Early voters line up at the polls in Stamford, Connecticut. | John Moore / Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="John Moore / Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2180058118.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Early voters line up at the polls in Stamford, Connecticut. | John Moore / Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The 2024 election cycle has produced some stunning and sometimes counterintuitive narratives about how demographic subgroups might end up voting. We may just see a historic gulf in the way men and women vote — or not. Polls suggest we’re in for the greatest racial realignment since the Civil Rights Act was passed — or it could be a mirage. Young people might sit out the election because they’re disillusioned and vote for a third party — or they could turn out in record numbers for Kamala Harris. The more diverse Sun Belt states might pave the way for a Donald Trump victory — but the predominantly older and whiter “Blue Wall” states might elect the first Black woman president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’ll know soon enough. Though Election Day is mere days away,<a href="https://election.lab.ufl.edu/early-vote/2024-early-voting/"> at least 60 million people have already voted</a>. Battleground states are hitting or exceeding their records for early voting. And with polls of likely voters still showing an evenly tied race, any combination of factors, events, or movements within the electorate could swing the outcome.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To that end, I’ve assembled a handful of questions we at Vox have been tracking for the last year. Their eventual answers could determine who wins the White House.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will there be late deciders? And what might change their minds?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The story of the closing weeks of the 2024 election has been a scramble for undecided voters, a shrinking number in poll after poll. That share includes two groups: voters who are undecided between either candidate and voters who might have a preference but are undecided about voting at all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t exactly know who these late deciders are, though. Could they be the same kind of working class and non-college educated (primarily white) voters who boosted Trump to victory in Rust Belt states in 2016 (thus scrambling the polls)? Or are they going to be the scores of new and young (primarily nonwhite) voters who could give Harris an edge in Sun Belt states?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And for all these subgroups — what kind of message or campaign development might get them to vote that hasn’t persuaded them already? Could Harris’s late-in-the-game revival of democracy and Trump’s authoritarian bend resonate with them? Is something like the racist and extreme rhetoric at <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378299/trump-military-threat-dancing-town-hall">Trump’s Madison Square Garden rally</a> a factor that could make up their minds? Or is something like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters">President Joe Biden’s “garbage” gaffe</a> this week something that could juice more Trump support?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless, these late-deciders will be pivotal. They’ve <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/revenge-of-the-late-deciders/">broken for Trump</a> by massive margins in each of the last two elections he’s been a part of. But things might be different this third time.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will there be Republican crossover to Harris?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Along those lines, Harris’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/379686/trump-fascist-kamala-harris-campaigns-biden-democracy-familiar-closing-argument-campaign-2024">fate-of-democracy appeal</a> and juxtaposition of her “to-do” list against Trump’s “enemies” list are the clearest examples of how the Democrat’s campaign has zeroed in on Trump-skeptical Republicans as a key part of preventing a Trump win. But will these registered Republicans cross party lines, or simply repeat as reluctant Trump voters?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Somewhere between 15 and 20 percent of Republican primary voters <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/04/04/trump-uncommitted-protest-vote/">did not vote for Trump</a>, and even after she dropped out, large shares of these voters opted to vote for former South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley. Many of them are women, which explains part of the focus <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/10/liz-cheney-kamala-harris-campaign/680367/">Harris has put on touting Republican endorsers</a> like former GOP Rep. Liz Cheney, her father and former vice president Dick Cheney, and scores of <a href="https://www.thebulwark.com/p/a-message-for-haley-voters-still">former Never-Trump Republican politicians</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Partisanship is one hell of a drug, however. Republicans, even if they dislike Trump personally, routinely stick with their party’s nominee. Harris keeps asking these Trump-wary Republicans to put “<a href="https://www.facebook.com/KamalaHarris/posts/country-over-party/1092139625605807/">country over party</a>.” But if they don’t and Harris’s argument about Trump’s threat to democracy is right, they may have to throw a “country <em>over</em>” party.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Arab American voters drift toward Republicans?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Gaza War, and Israel’s treatment of Palestinians, has been one of the defining issues of the last year, including in the electoral realm. Biden’s handling and response drove a significant amount of dissatisfaction from more progressive and left-leaning members of the Democratic coalition, and that antipathy seems to have stuck around, to a lesser degree, toward Harris. That includes a voting group influential in a pivotal swing state: Arab American voters in Michigan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polls specifically of Arab Americans suggest that these voters will not turn out for Harris to the same degree that they boosted Democratic candidates in the past: An Arab News-YouGov poll this week found <a href="https://www.arabnews.com/node/2576167/media">Trump leading Harris among Arab Americans</a> 45 to 43. That’s a stark reversal from 2020, when Biden led Trump by <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/the-arab-american-vote-2020">24 points</a>, and especially 2016, when Hillary Clinton led Trump by 34 points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this wasn’t always the case. <a href="https://unherd.com/newsroom/arab-americans-are-drifting-back-to-the-republicans/">Before 9/11, Arab American voters</a> leaned Republican. Only after the GOP’s <a href="https://researchblog.duke.edu/2024/10/07/emgage-educates-on-muslim-voter-dynamics-endorses-harris-for-2024/">anti-Muslim and anti-Arab</a> turn during the George W. Bush years did this voting segment swing toward Democrats, reaching a <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna6056602">high point in 2004</a>. And since that high point, these voters have been trending toward the GOP, with the share supporting John McCain, Mitt Romney, and Trump growing from 2008 to 2012 and into 2020 (support dipped slightly in 2016). The Gaza War may be accelerating a latent rightward shift that was already happening as the GOP changed its foreign policy priorities, championed conservative culture war issues, and talked up economic populism as Democrats became more culturally progressive, including on issues of gender and sexuality.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Trump’s gamble on younger Black men pay off?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For much of the last year, the Trump campaign has played up its targeted outreach to a specific segment of the electorate: <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373535/3-theories-gop-donald-trump-nonwhite-voters-hispanic-black-latino-asian">Black men</a>. With an avalanche of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/trump-allies-launch-20-million-effort-to-reach-young-men-e65aeb31">digital advertising aimed</a> at <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/10/us/politics/2024-election-gop-black-men-voters.html">younger Black men</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/375904/pennsylvania-kamala-harris-donald-trumplose-by-less-rural-black-suburb-voters">deployment</a> of surrogates and outside groups to reach young Black voters, the campaign has hoped to exploit two dynamics: Harris’s apparent weakness with Black men, and an overarching vulnerability Democrats have with younger Black Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Traditional polling suggests Harris has been facing a challenge in hitting the same margin of support that past Democratic candidates have enjoyed among Black voters, and specifically Black men. Both <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378521/democrats-black-men-support">social</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/23873568/biden-polling-black-latino-voters-2024-election-trump">economic</a> reasons explain this, including former <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/10/obama-harris-rally-pittsburgh/">President Barack Obama’s theory that a degree of misogyny</a> is keeping some Black men from supporting a Black woman.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there is also a larger Democratic weakness, based on surveys finding that younger Black voters specifically may have <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/04/09/age-generational-cohorts-and-party-identification/">weaker ties</a> to the party than <a href="https://x.com/jburnmurdoch/status/1767198806259470540">older cohorts</a> of Black voters, and may be <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/14/g-s1-16261/young-black-voters-generation-democrats-conservative-trump-harris-gen-z-millennials">more conservative</a> than their elders. And <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/23/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/genforward-poll-black-latino-voters-00185161">young Black men</a> appear more <a href="https://www.scholarsandstorytellers.com/2024election">likely</a> this year to support Trump, perhaps as a product of that weaker bond.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this is also among the cohort of voters least likely to vote and which, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/28/nx-s1-5169193/2024-election-kamala-harris-black-voters-donald-trump">some polling suggests</a>, is consolidating for Harris as they tune into the election. And with more outright racist remarks and prejudiced speech being deployed by Trump and his supporters in the final weeks of the campaign, it’s not clear that this investment will materialize large enough gains on Election Day to swing races in battleground states.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Latino voters shift right in the states that matter?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether Latino voters are shifting toward the Republican Party since the start of the Trump years isn’t really contestable. Trump’s gains in 2020 stuck around for Republican candidates during the 2022 midterms, and polls suggest he will, at the very least, hang on to much of the support in a week. But because the election is decided by the Electoral College and not the popular vote, the more interesting question is whether those gains will stick around or grow in the states that matter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, much of the political media was captivated by the massive inroads Trump made in South Florida and south Texas, places that had given Democrats an advantage in Latino support for years. But Trump’s Hispanic gains also happened across the country, in primarily immigrant communities, and in both Democratic and Republican strongholds that <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2024/10/trump-electoral-college-edge-shrinks-pennsylvania-wisconsin-polls.html">don’t necessarily impact</a> the results of the Electoral College map.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year, it appears that states that are already likely to <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/4909335-florida-hispanic-trump-lead/">solidly</a><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/10/election-latino-voters-texas-trump"> back</a> Trump or <a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2024-10-10/california-voters-poll-harris-trump-presidential-race">Harris</a> might see their Latino populations continue shifting to the right (as is most obvious in Florida), even as Latino voters in <a href="https://whyy.org/articles/north-philadelphia-latino-voters-pennsylvania-elections-2024/">swing states</a> like <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/22/harris-trump-hispanic-voters-00175772">Arizona</a>, Nevada, and Pennsylvania, according to polling, buck that trend and move toward Democrats (or at least keep Democratic margins from 2020 intact).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That could result in Trump making larger national inroads among Latinos, but not enough in swing states to boost him in the presidential races that matter. It would make for more evidence of an ongoing racial realignment between parties, but one driven by Hispanic and Latino voters in California, New York, and Texas. That has real implications for control of Congress, but, unless the Latinos switching their party affiliations are in swing states, it won’t affect who wins the White House.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Abdallah Fayyad</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Punish Democrats or Stop Trump? Arab Americans are agonizing over their votes.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/381550/arab-americans-protest-vote-harris-gaza-palestine-israel" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381550</id>
			<updated>2024-11-01T13:58:33-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T06:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arab Americans are one voting bloc that’s used to being slighted by both major parties. In 1984, Walter Mondale, the Democratic candidate for president, returned donations made by Arab Americans; a campaign official at the time said it was the campaign’s policy to refuse contributions from that community. In 1988, Democratic candidate Michael Dukakis rejected [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Older man posting a blue Abandon Harris ‘24 sign" data-caption="A demonstrator holds an “Abandon Harris” sign outside the Israeli Consulate during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois. | &lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin/&lt;/span&gt;Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin/&lt;/span&gt;Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2166943399.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A demonstrator holds an “Abandon Harris” sign outside the Israeli Consulate during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois. | &lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin/&lt;/span&gt;Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Arab Americans are one voting bloc that’s used to being slighted by both major parties. In 1984, Walter Mondale, the Democratic candidate for president, returned donations made by Arab Americans; a campaign official at the time <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1984/08/28/opinion/slighting-arab-americans.html">said it was the campaign’s policy</a> to refuse contributions from that community. In 1988, Democratic candidate Michael Dukakis <a href="https://www.csmonitor.com/2000/0404/p2s1.html">rejected an endorsement</a> by an Arab American group. And in 2016, Donald Trump campaigned on <a href="https://www.npr.org/2015/12/07/458836388/trump-calls-for-total-and-complete-shutdown-of-muslims-entering-u-s">banning Muslims</a> from the country and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fact-checker/wp/2015/11/22/donald-trumps-outrageous-claim-that-thousands-of-new-jersey-muslims-celebrated-the-911-attacks/">claimed that Arabs</a> in New Jersey cheered as the World Trade Center collapsed on 9/11.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Arab Americans feel deliberately ignored and disrespected yet again. The Biden administration’s unflinching political and financial support for Israel — despite the rising death tolls and humanitarian crisis that the war in Gaza has wrought — has roiled the community, and the general <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/10/27/biden-israel-palestine-muslim-americans-war/">lack of empathy</a> the administration has shown for Palestinians has left a bitter taste in people’s mouths.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When President Joe Biden dropped out and Vice President Kamala Harris became the party’s nominee, Democrats had a chance at a reset with a voting bloc that could very well tip the election. (Arab Americans make up <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/demographics">hundreds of thousands of voters</a> in key swing states.) But many feel the Harris campaign’s outreach to Arab Americans has been, to put it mildly, lackluster at best.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was like, ‘All right, you have a blank slate, let’s see what you’re going to do with that,’” said Rowan Imran, a Palestinian American who lives in Phoenix. “That was very disappointing to see her dig her heels further in the ground and just uphold every single [Biden] policy … It was very clear that we’re just getting a different face with the same policies.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Harris rose to the top of the ticket, she had to find a delicate balance: distance herself enough from Biden to convince some voters she wouldn&#8217;t be the same as him on Gaza while still representing the US government’s policies as the sitting vice president. It’s a balance she never quite struck. At times, she criticized Israel’s actions that <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn0lx2xgn55o">led to “far too many”</a> civilian deaths and acknowledged the human toll in Gaza, but she would always couple those kinds of remarks with justifications for the war. Recently, after being asked about the prospect of losing Arab and Muslim voters because of Israel’s conduct, Harris <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/harris-the-first-and-most-tragic-story-coming-out-of-gaza-is-oct-7-onslaught/">said</a>, “There are so many tragic stories coming from Gaza,” but that “the first and most tragic story is October 7.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The numbers reflect a dissatisfaction with her approach: A recent poll showed Harris <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/press-release-new-poll-arab-american-voters-evenly-divided-in-race-for-white-house-f989m">effectively tied</a> with Trump among Arab Americans, leaving her nearly 20 points behind Biden’s numbers in 2020. Another poll showed Trump <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/top-stories/latest/arab-american-muslim-voters-trump-harris-michigan-gaza-israel-rcna177647">with a slight lead</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has been trying to take advantage of that. Earlier this week, for example, he <a href="https://x.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1851658527187550629" rel="nofollow">tweeted</a> that he would “stop the suffering and destruction in Lebanon,” referring to Israel’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/israel/373428/lebanon-hezbollah-israel-hamas-gaza">escalating attacks</a> in the region. He then directly appealed to Lebanese American voters by adding, “Your friends and family in Lebanon deserve to live in peace, prosperity, and harmony with their neighbors.” He also <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dcwpdPfQvJU">touted an endorsement</a> he received from Amer Ghalib, the mayor of Hamtramck, Michigan, a Muslim-majority city outside Detroit.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given how close the election has been — with poll after poll showing a neck-and-neck race in swing states — it’s clear that Arab Americans, who make up a meaningful number of voters in must-win states like Michigan and Pennsylvania, can’t be taken for granted. And some liberals have been <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/10/revenge-voting-over-gaza-is-a-mistake/680446/">expressing frustration toward</a> Arab American voters who refuse to vote for Harris, saying that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/opinion/gaza-harris-trump.html">Trump is worse for them</a> because of policies like the Muslim ban. Harris echoed that frustration when she responded to pro-Palestinian protesters at <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/07/harris-to-protesters-if-you-want-donald-trump-to-win-then-say-that/74714086007/">a rally in August</a>, telling them, “You know what? If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But many Arab Americans are well aware of who Trump is and do resent the prospect of another Trump presidency. What they feel is that they’ve been pushed between a rock and a hard place.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A difficult choice</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some have dismissed Arab Americans’ concerns and potential protest votes as irresponsible, but the reality is much more complicated. Israel has been <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378913/israel-gaza-genocide-icj">credibly accused of genocide</a>, and if you’re a voter who genuinely believes that what’s happening in Gaza is a genocide, then the choice next week might not be so easy: On the one hand, your vote can be used to hold the Biden administration accountable. On the other hand, it can be used to stop Trump’s assault on American democracy. And if you choose the latter, does voting for Harris mean that&nbsp;you’re&nbsp;giving the Biden administration a pass for its handling of Gaza?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those are the kinds of questions haunting many liberal Arab Americans as they approach the voting booth. But democracy, the voters I spoke with argued, requires politicians to cater to the electorate, not the other way around.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Imran, a 35-year-old psychiatric nurse practitioner, had been a reliable Democratic voter. “I remember crying when Biden won and just feeling this sense of relief and, you know, someone that&#8217;s gonna reflect our values, be the voice of the people. And so that&#8217;s why a lot of this is so disappointing, because voting and supporting Kamala Harris, it should be a natural decision for me,” she said. “But because of the constant betrayal that we feel, the unconditional aid to Israel, the indifference to the lives of Palestinians, this has become the most complicated, impossible decision of my life.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Imran is now planning to vote third party. And part of the reason that it’s been a difficult decision for her is because she acknowledges the dangers of a second Trump presidency. “We do not support a Trump presidency. We understand the dangers, the harm,” she said. But “people again feel abandoned, they feel betrayed. We&#8217;re seeing our leaders prioritize foreign interests over the lives of people who look like us. And that&#8217;s not something we can overlook. You know, votes are not just a given, they need to be earned.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her view, it’s not her personal responsibility to stop Trump; it’s Harris’s and the Democrats’. And if Trump has another go at the presidency, then it’s only the Democrats to blame, not the voters who defected. Choosing to sit out or vote third party is a way to remind the major parties that they aren’t doing enough.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even those who might be voting for Harris have agonized over their decision, and some don’t even feel comfortable speaking about it because she was, after all, part of the administration that financed Israel’s war.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asma, a 50-year-old medical professional in North Carolina, has voted in every election since she was 18. (Asma asked that Vox use only her first name so she can speak more freely.) And though she usually votes early, this time she’s still holding out in the hopes that she hears some commitment from Harris that she’ll deviate from Biden’s Israel policy. “I’m just looking for validation. I’m looking for basically Harris to do anything, something to show that she has some compassion or some interest in the views that Muslims hold,” Asma told me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Harris never seemed to deliver. “We just wonder, what would she lose by being a little more inclusive in her humanity or her compassion or her empathy toward the Palestinians or toward Muslims?” Asma said. “When asked about Gaza, she doesn’t always have to talk about the October 7 hostages. Yes, we understand how you feel about that — you’ve made that plain and clear. Maybe you need to say something about the Palestinians and their plight, exclusive of [the hostages’] situation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asma said the election has divided many in her community, with many people judging others for how they’re voting, and some saying that a vote for Harris is essentially a vote for genocide. But a lot of people, Asma said, would still prefer voting for Harris over Trump because they believe Trump would make the situation in Gaza even worse. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, some voters feel a certain level of guilt holding them back. If Gaza isn’t their red line, then what would be?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s how Houston Brown, a 33-year-old Atlanta resident, is thinking of his vote. “The most inconceivable thing you can think of is genocide. It&#8217;s horrific,” Brown, whose mother is Palestinian, said. “And if there are no consequences for that, there will be no consequences for anything.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Brown was hopeful that Harris would distance herself from Biden on Gaza. And though he views her as more conservative than he’d prefer the Democratic candidate to be, he was still willing to vote for her, he said, because he doesn’t agree with any of Trump’s policies. “I would still vote for her regardless of that, regardless of my disagreements with her policies, if there was an arms embargo and a commitment to hold Israel accountable for what they&#8217;ve done,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris, of course, made no such commitment, and other moves by her campaign — such as <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368411/dnc-palestinian-speaker-uncommitted-democratic-national-convention">refusing to give a speaking slot</a> to a Palestinian American at the Democratic National Convention —&nbsp;made Brown feel like the vice president was not taking Gaza seriously. Now, Brown is likely going to vote third party, and if that means Trump might be back in the White House, that’s a risk Brown accepts. “The repercussions are what they are, and we’ll cross that bridge when we get there,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I understand that it could be worse under Trump,” he added. “But 40,000 dead Palestinians isn’t any different than 40,000 dead Americans to me. And our policies have led to the murder of over 40,000 Palestinians.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Trump has tried to make appeals to disaffected Arab Americans, he’s also been saying he’d be even more supportive of Israel than Biden has been. Recently, <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/187332/trump-biden-tough-netanyahu">Trump said</a> that Benjamin Netanyahu was “doing a good job” and that Biden was, if anything, holding the Israeli prime minister back. Trump’s own record on Israel has also been bad for Palestinians. For example, he moved the Israeli embassy to Jerusalem — making the US <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-recognizes-jerusalem-israel-s-capital-n827096">officially recognize</a> the city as Israel’s capital, despite the fact that East Jerusalem is still occupied Palestinian territory — and his State Department <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/11/18/politics/pompeo-west-bank-settlements-announcement/index.html">declared</a> that the United States would no longer deem settlements in the West Bank to be illegal under international law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But many voters who are sitting out or voting third party aren’t under the illusion that Trump is in any way a better alternative for Palestinians. For them, what’s happened in Gaza over the past year already constitutes the worst of outcomes: Israel has killed tens of thousands of innocent people, obliterated educational, religious, and health care infrastructure, created conditions for <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369872/polio-gaza-who-vaccination-campaign-israel">preventable diseases to spread</a>, and targeted and killed journalists at an <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/10/25/1208019720/journalist-deaths-gaza-israel-hamas">unprecedented rate</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In no way do I imagine Trump is better for Palestine,” Brown said. But “I can’t imagine it worse. I don’t think the Democrats are doing anything to stop it — they’re actively supporting it. So if there’s no real change for Palestine, why would I reward the people who are doing this now?”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Where the Harris campaign goes from here</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Arab Americans didn’t always lean toward Democrats. In 2000, Arab Americans <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/08/arab-american-muslim-vote-2016-trump-bush-dearborn-detroit-michigan-214134/">predominantly voted</a> for George W. Bush, and Republicans viewed them as a winnable demographic. But since the aftermath of 9/11 and the surveillance of Arabs and Muslims, the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, and Republicans’ xenophobic and Islamophobic overtures to white voters, Arabs have steadily moved toward Democrats. In 2020, Biden <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/keystatespoll">won about 60 percent</a> of the Arab American vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats’ progress, however, seems to have all but evaporated. Now, there’s no question that there is a protest vote in the making among Arab Americans and others who, like Brown, feel like a vote for Harris is an endorsement of the status quo. Since the primaries, Democratic voters have organized around this issue, launching an “uncommitted” movement where hundreds of thousands of voters selected “uncommitted” instead of Biden during the Democratic primaries to register their discontent over his handling of Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question is whether the protest vote will be big enough to swing the election in Trump’s favor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a ‘punish’ sense, and you hear that a lot, right? ‘We&#8217;re, we&#8217;re going to punish the Dems. They don&#8217;t deserve to win after what they’ve done,’” said James Zogby, president of the Arab American Institute. “I think that&#8217;s a smaller number than one might be led to believe, but if it comes out to a tie as it is right now, those are a lot of votes Democrats will have left on the table … losing 60,000, 70,000 votes in Michigan — that&#8217;s a lot of votes to lose in the state that&#8217;s going to be close.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recently, Harris did address Arab Americans specifically and spoke more candidly about the suffering in Gaza and Lebanon that’s happening as a result of Israel’s assaults.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know this year has been very difficult given the scale of death and destruction in Gaza, and given the civilian casualties and displacement in Lebanon. It is devastating,” she <a href="https://x.com/bintlabaratte/status/1847484011930853731?s=46">said</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this point, it might seem too little too late for Harris to change people’s minds. And for many Arab Americans and other supporters of the Palestinian cause, actions speak louder than words. And the lack of willingness on the part of the Biden administration to use the levers at its disposal to restrain Israel now leaves voters with a choice: take a unique opportunity to show that there can be electoral consequences for an administration facilitating the kind of war Israel has waged on Palestinians or help end Trump’s political career. But they can’t have both — at least not at the ballot box.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans are serious about cutting people’s health care]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/health-care/381484/2024-election-donald-trump-health-care-mike-johnson-obamacare" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381484</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T15:45:06-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T15:45:02-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re confused, it’s not an accident. Republicans are trying to have it both ways on health care during the 2024 campaign. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage. That two-step keeps getting them into [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Johnson stands behind and to the left of Trump as he speaks into a microphone." data-caption="House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2148449297.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re confused, it’s not an accident.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans are trying to have it both ways on <a href="https://www.vox.com/health-care">health care</a> during the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">2024 campaign</a>. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That two-step keeps getting them into trouble. House Speaker Mike Johnson was recently <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/house-speaker-mike-johnson-criticizes-obamacare-and-promises-massive-reform-if-trump-wins-223060037976">caught on a tape</a> promising to take “a blow torch to the regulatory state.” Donald Trump, Johnson said, would want to “go big” in his second term because he can’t run for a third one, the speaker told a group of Republican voters in Pennsylvania. And health care, Johnson said, would be “a big part” of the GOP’s agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One attendee directly asked Johnson: No Obamacare? “No Obamacare,” Johnson said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The ACA is so deeply ingrained, we need massive reform to make this work. We’ve got a lot of ideas,” the House speaker added. He wasn’t more specific than that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris’s campaign quickly <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1851604970992263224">flagged</a> Johnson’s comments, and Republicans backtracked. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> campaign <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-campaign-distances-house-speakers-plan-massive-reform/story?id=115313086">said</a> that was “not President Trump’s policy position” and Trump tried to distance himself further in a social media post.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Lyin’ Kamala is giving a News Conference now, saying that I want to end the Affordable Care Act. I never mentioned doing that, never even thought about such a thing. She also said I want to end Social Security. Likewise, never mentioned it, or thought of it. She is the one that…</p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033066157441249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/no-promise-johnson-blasts-dem-accusations-he-vowed-end-obamacare-dishonest">insisted</a> he had not actually promised to repeal Obamacare by emphasizing his comment that the 2010 law was “ingrained” while ignoring his subsequent promise of “massive reform.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself has alluded to having only “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/opinion/trump-harris-concepts-obamacare.html">concepts of a plan</a>” for American health care. That has left other Republicans to fill in the gaps and the party’s specific proposals remain poorly defined. But if there are a lot of details still to be filled in, the theme of the GOP’s health care agenda is clear: cuts. Cutting regulations. Cutting spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson’s comments were not an isolated incident. Just last month, Trump’s vice presidential nominee, JD Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions">hinted</a> at “a deregulatory agenda so that people can pick a health care plan that fits them.” If you actually parse his words about health insurance risk pools, it would be a return to a world where people could be charged more for coverage if they have preexisting medical conditions, the world before Obamacare.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was the same promise Johnson was making. That is the reality: Should they win control of the White House and Congress this election, Republicans will attempt to cut people’s health care.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Republicans still want to make big health care cuts</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Obamacare repeal <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/31/16055960/why-obamacare-repeal-failed">died in 2017</a>, it might have been tempting to think that a chapter had come to a close. Instead, the fight over the future of US health care had entered a new era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Make no mistake: Republican leaders still want to slash health care spending and unwind health insurance regulations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Trump, whatever he might say, has proven before to be malleable to conventional conservative health policy. His people continue to put health care in the crosshairs, sometimes in ways that may not be as obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk, who sometimes appears to be campaigning to be <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/elon-musk-eyes-a-shadow-presidency/">shadow president</a> of the United States, has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">pledged</a> to cut $2 trillion from the federal government’s $6.8 trillion budget. He has <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/the-reidout/reidout-blog/elon-musk-trump-hardship-austerity-taxes-rcna177732">acknowledged</a> that the cuts would result in “temporary” hardship, but insisted they would be to the long-term benefit of the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nationalpriorities.org/budget-basics/federal-budget-101/spending/">About $1 in every $5</a> in the federal budget goes to health care. Barring a severe cut to the US military (unlikely), such a plan would require massive cuts to the health care programs. Trump has often said he will protect Medicare, which covers seniors, but he has in the past endorsed enormous cuts to Medicaid, the program for low-income people that insures <a href="https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/medicaid-and-chip-monthly-enrollment/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">73 million Americans</a>, as part of the 2017 ACA repeal-and-replace bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main Republican bill to repeal and replace the ACA that nearly passed in 2017 was in fact <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/9/15579654/medicaid-cuts-ahca">as much about making massive Medicaid cuts</a> by capping the program’s funding as it was about loosening health insurance regulations or repealing the individual mandate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans could try to pass another Obamacare repeal bill with a comprehensive Medicaid overhaul. Or they could chip away at health care in incremental ways, as we saw during the first Trump term after the Obamacare repeal bill failed. Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/8/16268572/trump-obamacare-navigators">cut funding for enrollment outreach</a> for the ACA markets while <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/8/2/17639124/trump-obamacare-short-term-insurance-plans-36-months">rolling back rules</a> for noncomprehensive plans, which resulted in <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21275498/trump-obamacare-repeal-short-term-health-care-insurance-scam">catastrophic results for some patients</a> who didn’t know what they were signing up for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over Trump’s four years in office, the number of people covered by the ACA <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/state-indicator/marketplace-enrollment/?activeTab=graph&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;startTimeframe=10&amp;selectedRows=%7B%22wrapups%22:%7B%22united-states%22:%7B%7D%7D%7D&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">fell</a> by more than 1 million, to 11.4 million. Since Joe Biden became president, and Democrats expanded the law’s insurance subsidies as part of the Inflation Reduction Act, the number of people covered by marketplace plans has nearly doubled to 21.4 million.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump takes office again, a repeat of that previous sabotage seems likely even if a bigger repeal effort fails to materialize. Republicans could cut outreach funding again. They could make subtler tweaks to the health insurance rules, such as increasing the premiums that older people can be charged compared to younger people or giving insurers more leniency in restricting benefits, networks, and other aspects of a person’s health coverage. They could make more targeted cuts to Medicaid or <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/5/12/23712447/medicaid-work-requirements-us-debt-ceiling">permit states to set up Medicaid work requirements again</a>, as they did in the first Trump term only to be <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/3/13/18263675/medicaid-work-requirements-lawsuit-donald-trump">obstructed by the courts</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Republicans can’t be honest about their health care plan</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The failure of Obamacare repeal is the reason Republicans keep insisting that their health care agenda is not what it plainly is whenever they accidentally reveal their intentions too clearly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s easy to forget now, but Obamacare was a winning issue for Republicans at first. They <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/blogs/washington-whispers/2011/04/12/healthcare-vote-doomed-13-democrats-in-2010-elections">stormed to historic congressional wins in the 2010 midterms</a> by rallying voters against the new health care law. They then took <a href="https://time.com/4712725/ahca-house-repeal-votes-obamacare/">dozens of votes to repeal all or parts of it</a> while Barack Obama still held the veto pen. For most of its first decade, the ACA was deeply unpopular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then Trump won the presidency and the Republicans had to deliver on their promises to repeal and replace the law. GOP leaders did get the new president on board with <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/3/15531494/american-health-care-act-explained">a pretty conservative plan</a>: It would have left the skeleton of the ACA, but pared back its rules and financial aid, while making those huge cuts to Medicaid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then something changed. As the repeal plan started to move through Congress, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/24/15685760/ahca-cbo-score-new">projections</a> of millions of Americans losing health insurance dominated news coverage, the politics of health care flipped. The law had quietly grown to cover a sizable chunk of people —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/issue-briefs/2016/may/americans-experiences-aca-marketplace-and-medicaid-coverage">more than 25 million</a> —&nbsp;and, as importantly, it had started to <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/4708/healthcare-system.aspx#:~:text=During%20most%20of%20the%20years,it%20shouldn't%20be).">change Americans’ minds about the government’s role in providing health care</a>. “Preexisting conditions” became a loaded term, and when people understood that the GOP wanted to unwind the ACA’s health insurance rules, they <a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/2017/5/3/15530008/health-care-preexisting-conditions-insurance">loudly objected</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Medicaid also flexed a political salience not seen before, with <a href="https://time.com/4831386/disability-advocate-protest-gop-health-care-bill/">disability advocates in particular</a> fearful of what cuts to that program would mean for them and drawing widespread coverage for their protests. Senate Republicans from states that expanded Medicaid through the health care law were ultimately responsible for stopping the repeal effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the 2018 midterms, Democrats were <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/11/7/18070152/midterm-elections-2018-results-trump-obamacare-repeal">hammering Republicans over health care</a> and scoring surprising electoral wins. Today, the ACA is <a href="https://www.kff.org/interactive/kff-health-tracking-poll-the-publics-views-on-the-aca/#?response=Favorable--Unfavorable&amp;aRange=twoYear">as popular as it’s ever been</a> and US voters say they <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/poll-finding/kff-health-tracking-poll-may-2024-voters-views-of-health-policy-issues-in-context-of-presidential-campaigns/">trust Democrats more on health care</a> than the GOP.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This series of events has left Republicans in a bind. The relative success of the ACA has expanded the welfare state and influenced Americans’ perceptions of the role of government in ways that are antithetical to conservative economic thinking. They want to claw back some of those progressive wins. But they also have to be mindful of the changed politics of health care.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once in a while, particularly in “safe” conservative spaces, they slip up, admit they want to unwind the ACA, and then have to backtrack. Mike Johnson’s only mistake was being candid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 3:45 pm ET:</strong> This story was originally published earlier on October 31 and has been updated to include Trump’s social media post about the ACA.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
