<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-10-16T15:01:36+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Matthews</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why some economists are skeptical of this year’s Nobelists]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/378007/nobel-economics-acemoglu-johnson-robinson-institutions" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=378007</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T11:01:36-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T08:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Poverty" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Nobel Prize in Economics awarded this week to Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson, and James Robinson allows a lot of people to feel like winners. (Especially those in the know who refer to the group by the acronym “AJR.”) The general public wins in that all three have, unusually for academic economists, written extensively for [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="The 2024 Nobel Prize in Economics is announced in Stockholm, Sweden, October 14, 2024. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Zhang Yuliang/Xinhua via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Zhang Yuliang/Xinhua via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2177779385.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The 2024 Nobel Prize in Economics is announced in Stockholm, Sweden, October 14, 2024. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Zhang Yuliang/Xinhua via Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/economic-sciences/2024/press-release/">Nobel Prize in Economics</a> awarded this week to Daron Acemoglu, Simon Johnson, and James Robinson allows a lot of people to feel like winners. (Especially those in the know who refer to the group by the acronym “AJR.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The general public wins in that all three have, unusually for academic economists, written extensively for lay audiences; Acemoglu and Robinson’s 2012 book <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Why_Nations_Fail"><em>Why Nations Fail</em></a> was a bestseller, and Johnson has had several prominent books on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/13-Bankers-Takeover-Financial-Meltdown/dp/030747660X">financial regulation</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Jump-Starting-America-Breakthrough-Economic-American-ebook/dp/B07G73QHY5?ref_=ast_author_mpb">innovation</a>. Economic historians get a win, in that Acemoglu, Johnson, and Robinson’s most famous work was on historical <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.91.5.1369">processes of development</a> in <a href="https://economics.mit.edu/sites/default/files/publications/reversal-of-fortune.pdf">former colonies</a>. Lefties win, in that Acemoglu has of late become a vocal proponent of <a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/in-conversation-with-daron-acemoglu/">policies to expand worker power</a> and has mused about the possibility of “<a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ai-central-planning-versus-decentralization-by-daron-acemoglu-2023-06">AI-enabled communism</a>.”</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, you don’t get to <a href="https://ideas.repec.org/a/aea/aecrev/v91y2001i5p1369-1401.html">4,400 citations</a> without earning a few critics. The fairest hit against the three is that while their theories are elegant, the data underlying them are shaky at best, and the results don’t hold up to scrutiny.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s not as terrible as it might sound. All science progresses through new findings that themselves are later overturned. I think Acemoglu, Johnson, and Robinson are great economists and even flawed empirical findings can be important in advancing a field. The physicist JJ Thomson — another Nobel winner — famously and erroneously <a href="https://www.britannica.com/science/Thomson-atomic-model">proposed</a> that atoms lacked a nucleus, but that doesn&#8217;t make his previous discovery of the electron any less important.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this week, with considerable and mostly uncritical public attention on the Nobel winners’ work, I think it’s important to talk about its shortcomings, and the need to subject influential findings like theirs to further testing.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AJR for beginners</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AJR’s most famous work was an intervention into one of the longest-running debates in economics: Why are some nations so rich and other nations so poor? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The collaborators sought to rebut geographic determinists (notably Jared Diamond) who argued that the characteristics of the land were responsible for, say, Europe being richer than Africa. AJR’s answer was that some countries had better, more “inclusive” institutions that allowed the fruits of economic growth to be broadly shared, whereas others had “extractive” institutions where a small cabal could capture all the gains. The former grow over the long run; the latter don’t.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their most famous paper, “<a href="https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/aer.91.5.1369">The Colonial Origins of Comparative Development: An Empirical Investigation</a>,” sought to measure the effect of inclusive versus extractive institutions. To do this, they had to find some factor that caused certain areas to have certain kinds of institutions, but that was otherwise unlinked to their economic development. In econometrics this is called an “instrumental variable,” and the theory is that controlling for such variables lets you isolate the causal effect of the independent variable (in this case, institution type) that you’re studying.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their instrument was “how often European settlers died.” Think about Australia on the one hand and Nigeria on the other. Both were colonized by the United Kingdom; Australia has, I think it&#8217;s fair to say, <a href="https://www.transparency.org/en/countries/australia">stronger, less corrupt institutions</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What AJR proposed was that Australia became Australia because it was reasonably hospitable terrain for the European colonizers, the many sharks and spiders notwithstanding; they could, and did, move there in large numbers. They then had incentives to build institutions that benefited white settlers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Nigeria, by contrast, diseases like malaria and yellow fever <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10021769/">killed off</a> huge numbers of British settlers, so a similar settlement project couldn&#8217;t get off the ground. With comparatively few white settlers, the British didn&#8217;t give a shit about building fair institutions, because they were effectively building them for Africans — and the British cared far less about black people&#8217;s welfare than white people&#8217;s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sure enough, AJR found that countries with high European settler mortality during colonization have lower per-capita incomes today, which they saw as evidence for their view that institution type is determinative. A nearly as-famous paper the following year, “<a href="https://economics.mit.edu/sites/default/files/publications/reversal-of-fortune.pdf">Reversal of Fortune</a>,” extended the argument, finding that among countries colonized by Europeans, those that were most successful in 1500 (where &#8220;success&#8221; is measured by urbanization or population density) are disproportionately poor today.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those results point against geographic explanations, AJR argued, and toward institutional changes wrought by European colonization.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why the finding is shaky</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a lot that’s appealing about the AJR worldview. Government institutions do seem important; there’s no other plausible reason why South Korea is <a href="https://www.imf.org/external/datamapper/profile/KOR">one of the richest places</a> on Earth and North Korea is <a href="https://data.un.org/en/iso/kp.html">perhaps the poorest</a>. The theory is a hopeful one: While countries cannot change their geographies, they can adopt new, better institutions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But do the specific empirical claims AJR made hold up? It doesn’t seem like it. Economist David Albouy offered the <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/aer.102.6.3059">most persuasive reply</a> to their 2001 “Colonial Origins” paper by digging into the actual data. AJR used a sample of 64 countries, but only had real data for 28 of them. The other 36 had data that were assigned based on “conjectures the authors make as to which countries have similar disease environments.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As you might expect, making up data on settler mortality for places where we have no data is difficult, and Albouy finds serious flaws in how AJR do it; for six countries, he finds, their estimates “are based on an incorrect interpretation of former colonial names for Mali.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once you only look at the 28 countries with non-synthetic data, there’s no relationship between settler mortality and present-day economic outcomes. Worse, even the real data tends to be about soldiers rather than civilian settlers, and soldiers are <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5421788/">more likely to die</a> from disease when actively fighting than civilians are.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This biases the results in AJR&#8217;s favor, and makes the underlying relationship they posit (that places with higher death rates developed worse institutions) much weaker.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/shleifer/files/do_institutions_cause_growth.pdf">Another reply</a>, by Ed Glaeser, Rafael La Porta, Florencio López de Silanes, and Andrei Shleifer noted that AJR’s data doesn’t distinguish between the effects of institutions and the effects of human capital: Settler colonies like Australia and Canada didn’t merely get more inclusive institutions, but also settlers who were generally much richer and better-educated (at least from a modern capitalist vantage point) than native inhabitants. The researchers conduct their own tests and argue that human capital does a better job explaining growth trajectories than institutions. That doesn’t necessarily make for a bleaker story than AJR (countries can invest in schools and boost human capital), but it’s a <em>different</em> story.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Glaeser and co. also highlight problems with the measure of &#8220;expropriation risk&#8221; (the risk that the government takes all your stuff) used in AJR’s work. This is an important indicator for AJR of whether institutions are inclusive or extractive, but it turns out to just be a subjective 0 to 10 ratings system AJR took from the private firm Political Risk Services, and one with huge problems. &#8220;In 1984, the top ten countries with the lowest expropriation risk include Singapore and the USSR,&#8221; Glaeser et al note. Are we really expected to believe that your risk of getting your stuff taken by the government was low in the Soviet Union?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">AJR’s claim of a &#8220;reversal of fortune,&#8221; with the leading nations of 1500 becoming laggards today, has similarly withered under scrutiny.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Areendam Chanda, C. Justin Cook, and Louis Putterman <a href="https://www.aeaweb.org/articles?id=10.1257/mac.6.3.1">reevaluated the claim</a> but measured what happened to the descendents of those actual 1500s people, not just the geographic places where they lived. There have been huge movements of people from 1500 to the present, and it doesn&#8217;t strictly make sense to compare the Incan Empire to Peru today given how wildly different the people in each were. Chanda et al find that fortune has not reversed, but persisted when you account for population movements: People descended from countries thriving in 1500 were doing better in the 21st century. That’s evidence, they conclude, for the Glaeser et al claim that human capital rather than institutions is the crucial factor here.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, my takeaway here is not “Acemoglu, Johnson, and Robinson, Nobel-winning economists, are useless.” They’re incredibly useful, and greatly amplified the prestige of these kinds of tough economic history questions within the economics profession.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I also think their work is a reminder of the old academic cliché that you can either learn something very small about something very big, or something very big about something very small. They were tackling a very big topic, and seemed for a second to grasp something very big about it. Upon inspection, though, it looks a great deal smaller.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is every car dealer trying to rip me off?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me/374186/car-dealerships-sales-tactics-shady-practices" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=374186</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T16:42:49-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T07:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explain It to Me" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Vox reader writes: “Why are car dealers so shady? How do consumers avoid them? Is it frustrating for everyone?” Americans have long hated the car-buying experience. It’s not uncommon to spend hours (or even the whole day) at a dealership, finally reaching a deal and still walking away feeling vaguely hoodwinked. “It&#8217;s a process [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-869345488.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A Vox reader writes: “Why are car dealers so shady? How do consumers avoid them? Is it frustrating for everyone?”</em></p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">Americans have long <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/when-it-comes-to-car-shopping-edmundscom-finds-that-americans-hate-the-haggle-so-much-theyd-give-up-sex-facebook-and-smartphones-to-avoid-it-261647461.html">hated</a> the <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/study-americans-feel-taken-advantage-of-at-the-car-dealership-300301866.html">car-buying</a> <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/caredge-study-finds-auto-consumers-105800203.html">experience</a>. It’s not uncommon to spend hours (or even the whole day) at a dealership, finally reaching a deal and still walking away feeling vaguely hoodwinked.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s a process that generally stinks, and it&#8217;s designed that way,” says Tom McParland, founder of <a href="https://automatchconsulting.com/">Automatch Consulting</a>, a service that helps car buyers find the best price on the vehicle they want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of the distaste comes down to the uncertainty of what you’ll end up paying. In an age when you can buy almost anything online without interacting with another human being, where you can easily shop around for the best deal, cars remain one of the few purchases where your personal negotiation skills — as well as, sometimes, your race, gender, and income — can determine the price.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Sign up for the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up">Explain It to Me newsletter</a></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The newsletter is part of Vox’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me">Explain It to Me</a>. Each week, we tackle a question from our audience and deliver a digestible explainer from one of our journalists. Have a question you want us to answer? Ask us <a href="http://www.vox.com/ask-vox">here</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes, the tactics car salespeople use go beyond just the hard sell to the downright deceptive. One common trap is <a href="https://www.theconsumerlawgroup.com/blog/consumers-beware-of-bait-and-switch-tactics-by-car-dealers.cfm">bait and switch</a> prices, where a car is initially advertised as one price (usually achieved by piling on discounts that you may not qualify for). When you run to the dealership to snag the deal, you’re told the vehicle has already been sold but there’s a similar one that’s more expensive. Or take <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/02/07/1155014842/how-car-buyers-can-become-entrapped-in-whats-known-as-a-yo-yo-sale">yo-yo sales</a>, in which you drive your new car home only to be told a few days later that the financing fell through so you’ll have to accept a higher interest rate or make a bigger down payment. A dealer might also try to sneak unneeded <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/blog/2024/08/car-dealers-included-add-ons-without-consumers-consent-discriminated-against-black-latino-buyers">add-ons</a> — like extended warranties or protective coatings — onto the total price of the car.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, the Federal Trade Commission received more than <a href="https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/federal.trade.commission/viz/TheBigViewAllSentinelReports/TopReports">184,000</a> auto-related consumer complaints, making it the third most common category after complaints about credit bureaus, as well as banks and lenders.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While there are some fair dealers, the car marketplace has “a lot of sharp and unethical business practices, and consumers are hurt by it,” says Chuck Bell, programs director of advocacy at Consumer Reports. “By the time that the consumer gets out the door, they feel like they’ve been doing battle.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why is shopping for cars done this way?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first hint that you’re on unequal footing with a car salesperson comes when they’re cagey about giving a price quote even over the phone, let alone in writing. McParland says that the dealers he calls around to for clients often tell him that he has to come to the dealership for a price. “They’re basically just telling us to go pound sand,” he says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dealers want you to come in because it’s much easier to upsell you that way. You’ve invested some effort into the process, and the salesperson can get a better read on how impatient you are to buy a car, how inexperienced you are with car shopping, and plenty of other factors to wield to their advantage. On the other hand, if they offer you an out-the-door price — which includes all extras and fees — before you ever meet in person, you could easily take the price to a competing dealer and ask if they can do better.&nbsp;While online used car dealers like CarMax and Carvana did make “no haggle” car prices more popular, they often come at a premium, according to McParland. Some traditional car dealers now offer fixed prices too, but it’s probably to your benefit to try to negotiate down.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How did the system get to be like this?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The general practice of negotiating car prices instead of paying a fixed price may actually stem from <a href="https://priceonomics.com/why-do-we-haggle-for-cars/">horse trading</a>, in which sellers and buyers also haggled and buyers would even trade in their old horse to offset the price of the new one, much as we do with cars today.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The model has endured for so long, though, in part thanks to state franchise laws that ensure these middlemen car dealerships can’t be easily cut out. Most states ban carmakers from selling directly to consumers. Tesla is the rare exception of a car company that sells directly, and it has <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2013/12/23/ohio-car-dealers-challenge-teslas-business-model.html">battled</a> with <a href="https://apnews.com/article/tesla-louisiana-car-dealers-federal-court-1dc44a5917731954de18f8455b9bad0b">car dealers</a> for the right to do so. Car dealer trade groups have considerable <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2023/05/rich-republicans-party-car-dealers-2024-desantis.html">political power</a>, and they’re organized enough and deep-pocketed enough to lobby against reforms that would threaten the status quo, such as changing franchise laws that give them exclusive rights to sell a certain car brand in a particular territory. The National Automobile Dealers Association (NADA), for its part, argues that <a href="https://www.nada.org/nada/issues/franchise-system">franchise laws</a> in fact increase competitiveness and benefit the consumer, all the while creating local jobs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They’re an enormously powerful lobby,” says Bell.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just look at how the industry pushed back against enforcement curtailing auto lending discrimination. Car dealers often arrange financing for customers, but they add a mark-up to the interest rate offered by banks because they can pocket that extra money for themselves. How much of a mark-up is applied is at the dealer’s discretion, and unlike mortgage lenders, they’re not required to collect data on the race of their customers, making it much harder to see if they’re complying with fair lending laws. Research shows that car dealers often charge <a href="https://www.nclc.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/report-time-to-stop-racing-cars-april2019.pdf">higher interest rates</a> to <a href="https://www.chicagofed.org/publications/profitwise-news-and-views/2023/discrimination-auto-loan-market">people of color</a>. When the Consumer Finance Protection Bureau started cracking down on this practice in 2013, the industry <a href="https://theintercept.com/2015/11/23/car-dealers-have-their-way-with-congress/">fought back</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/4/17/17248340/congressional-review-act-auto-loan-discrimination-cfpb">won</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Is there any hope for making the car-buying process better?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there’s reason to be optimistic about the future of shopping for cars. Late last year, the FTC announced <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/business-guidance/resources/ftc-cars-rule-combating-auto-retail-scams-dealers-guide">new regulation</a> that takes aim at the most rampant deceptive practices used by car dealers. It would, for one, require dealers to disclose the full, out-the-door price of a car, including all add-ons, before a customer visits the dealership. The price and other terms related to purchase of the car also have to be expressed in simple language. Dealers also wouldn’t be allowed to charge customers for useless add-ons. The FTC estimates the rule will <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/12/ftc-announces-cars-rule-fight-scams-vehicle-shopping">save customers $3.4 billion</a> and cut down the time spent shopping for cars by 72 million hours.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rule was supposed to go into effect this summer but was delayed after two car dealer trade groups, including NADA, <a href="https://www.nada.org/nada/nada-headlines/nada-files-federal-court-challenge-stop-ftcs-vehicle-shopping-rule">filed a challenge</a>.<strong> </strong>The association told Vox that the rule would make the car-buying experience worse. “Consumers will have to spend an additional 60-80 minutes at the dealership, complete up to five new, untested forms, and will lose at least $1.3 billion a year in time as a result of this rule,” a spokesperson wrote in an email.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Bell is confident that the rule will ultimately go into effect, and if you’re looking for a car, you should behave as though these protections already apply. McParland advises asking dealers to provide, over email, an “itemized out-the-door price” on the vehicle you’re interested in. If they refuse, “that’s usually a red flag, so move on to somebody else,” he says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was featured in the Explain It to Me newsletter. Sign up&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/explain-it-to-me-newsletter-sign-up"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em>&nbsp;<em>For more from Explain It to Me,&nbsp;</em><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site"><em>check out the podcast</em></a><em>. New episodes drop every Wednesday.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Seraphina Seow</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to prepare for growing older if you don’t have kids]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/377964/seniors-child-free-no-kids-retirement-planning-caregiving" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377964</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T17:05:34-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T07:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[My husband and I have been married for five years. During that time, a battalion of well-meaning relatives — starting with my parents and extending all the way to aunts and uncles — have tried to convince us to have children. Despite these persistent pleas, we aren&#8217;t convinced. The world just feels too chaotic and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Drawing of an older woman sitting comfortably by a window while looking at her phone." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1875377682.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">My husband and I have been married for five years. During that time, a battalion of well-meaning relatives — starting with my parents and extending all the way to aunts and uncles — have tried to convince us to have children. Despite these persistent pleas, we aren&#8217;t convinced. The world just feels too chaotic and we’re unsure if we want to subject a child to it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Increasingly, other American adults are making a similar choice. As of 2018, <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/12/no-kids-no-care-childlessness-among-older-americans.html">16.5 percent of adults 55 and over</a> in the US didn’t have children. According to a Pew Research Center survey released in July, the number of US adults younger than 50 who don’t have children and say <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2024/07/25/the-experiences-of-u-s-adults-who-dont-have-children/">they are unlikely ever to have them</a> rose from 37 percent in 2018 to 47 percent in 2023. The <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2024/07/25/the-experiences-of-u-s-adults-who-dont-have-children/">top reason</a> cited by this group is that they just don’t want to. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chances are, well-meaning folks (like my parents) have asked child-free adults at some stage: “You may be carefree now, but what happens when you get old?” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Does having no children place us at a disadvantage? The <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/social-trends/2024/07/25/the-experiences-of-u-s-adults-who-dont-have-children/">Pew survey</a> also found that one in four adults aged 50 and older without children frequently worry about who will care for them as they age, and one in three worry about having enough money. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Certainly, children can offer peace of mind, a person to lean on as you face the realities of aging. But the truth is, “even when people have children, those children <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/research/surveys_statistics/life-leisure/2023/solo-agers-attitudes-experiences-report-2023.doi.10.26419-2Fres.00602.001.pdf">don&#8217;t always become</a> the safety net that one might think,” says Kate Granigan, chief executive officer of <a href="https://www.lcadvocates.com/">LifeCare Advocates</a> and president of the <a href="http://aginglifecare.org">Aging Life Care</a> Association Board. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Seniors can live flourishing lives without kids, experts say, but they need to be prepared to lean on other people, financially plan for the future, and make use of support services. Presently, the <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/research/surveys_statistics/life-leisure/2023/solo-agers-attitudes-experiences-report-2023.doi.10.26419-2Fres.00602.001.pdf">majority of older adults</a> without involved partners or children are not adequately prepared for their future care and end of life, according to the AARP. This needs to change. “Being able to have some foresight … and [knowing] how to prepare in the best way possible can really help people thrive and age well,” says Granigan. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ensure you have people who will watch out for you</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many adult children tend to be the ones who keep an eye on their parents and coordinate necessary help. You want to find people to fill this role, says <a href="https://www.eagenandassociates.com/testimonials">Beth Eagen</a>, a Seattle-based geriatric social worker. Befriend people in the communities you’re in and invest in the relationships in your life, advises <a href="https://www.drstacyreger.com/">Stacy Reger</a>, a geropsychologist in Los Angeles, California.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These people may not be doing all your care, but they can watch your back. “You may have a friend or colleague or someone that you’re close with that is also in your same position … and you can create a group that checks in on each other,” says Granigan. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not only are these relationships fulfilling, they mean you have someone to call for ad hoc assistance, like a ride back from the supermarket if you have a particularly heavy shop or a lift to the emergency room. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As you form new connections, be open to <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23961005/intergenerational-friendship-all-ages-friends-older-younger">multi-generational friendships</a>. If everyone in your life is your age and people start getting ill at similar times, it will be harder for them to help when you need it, Eagen explains.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When planning where you will retire, Eagen and Granigan also encourage choosing an area with a “<a href="https://www.vtvnetwork.org/content.aspx?page_id=22&amp;club_id=691012&amp;module_id=238482">village</a>” and signing up for it. Villages are not-for-profit associations around the country that connect seniors with others in the neighborhood to create a community that looks out for one another. If you need a car ride, help with household tasks, or want to participate in social activities, the village will coordinate. Annual membership <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/ppi/2022/10/village-model-current-trends-challenges.doi.10.26419-2Fppi.00169.001.pdf">fees can be up to $1,000</a>, but increasing numbers of villages are introducing a “pay as you can” model and subsidizing fees for those who can’t afford it.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get your finances in order to pay for support&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://childfreewealth.com/about">Jay Zigmont</a>, a certified financial planner for child-free adults, advises clients in their mid-40s to purchase long-term care insurance.<strong> </strong>In general, <a href="https://www.nia.nih.gov/health/long-term-care/paying-long-term-care">long-term care insurance covers</a> the nonmedical support you may need to perform activities of daily living, like eating, bathing, walking, and taking medication. It pays for <a href="https://www.aarp.org/caregiving/financial-legal/info-2021/understanding-long-term-care-insurance.html?cmp=KNC-DSO-CAREGIVING-Caregiving-LongTermCareInsurance-NonBrand-Exact-45403-GOOG-Long-TermCareInsurance-Exact-NonBrand&amp;gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwsJO4BhDoARIsADDv4vAEKYEBdgPPZNV6ICemmInqv9RFnr3-sUR8eV74ZYW7JMTU4sc2CZgaAmOjEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">the costs</a> of at-home caregivers, adult day care, transportation, and senior living arrangements, like <a href="https://www.aaltci.org/news/long-term-care-insurance-association-news/2024-long-term-care-insurance-claims">nursing homes</a> and assisted living facilities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/documents/08b8b7825f7bc12d2c79261fd7641c88/ltss-risks-financing-2022.pdf">More than half of US adults turning 65</a> are expected to require some sort of long-term services and support as they age, and many people are unaware that Medicare, the government health program for seniors, <a href="https://www.aarp.org/caregiving/health/info-2022/medicare-medicaid-long-term-care.html">does not cover</a> these supports. The earlier you buy a long-term care policy, the better the price, and the smaller the likelihood of having a <a href="https://www.americanbar.org/groups/law_aging/publications/bifocal/vol45/vol45issue1/ltc-insurance-qual/">condition that disqualifies</a> you from coverage, Zigmont says. Paying for it upfront is expensive, but the price is locked in, he says. Alternatively, you can pay for it annually. If you miss a payment, the policy gets canceled, and you will not get a comparable policy again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you don’t purchase insurance, you will likely be paying for long-term care out of pocket, says Zigmont, author of the upcoming book <a href="https://www.amazon.com.au/dp/1728297346?ref_=mr_referred_us_au_au"><em>The Childfree Guide to Life and Money</em></a>. Medicaid, a government health program for low-income people, <a href="https://www.aarp.org/caregiving/health/info-2022/medicare-medicaid-long-term-care.html">only covers care</a> once you’ve burned through your assets. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re paying out of pocket, bear in mind that long-term care costs can quickly add up: A private room in a nursing home, for instance, can cost around <a href="https://www.genworth.com/aging-and-you/finances/cost-of-care/cost-of-care-trends-and-insights">$115,000 a year</a> and goes up by about 5 percent every year, says Zigmont.<strong> </strong>Do what you need to do to start saving and investing your money now so that “it grows at least 5 percent per year in order to cover your long-term care costs” plus any impending taxes, says Zigmont.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get excited about your senior years</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Remind yourself that your senior years can absolutely be fulfilling, says <a href="https://zsfgdgim.ucsf.edu/people/anna-chodos#Publications">Anna Chodos</a>, a geriatrician in the UCSF Department of Medicine. So, start dreaming.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Build a mental image of your future self, advises Chodos and <a href="https://ajaevanscounseling.com/">Aja Evans</a>, a financial therapist in New York City and author of <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/759700/feel-good-finance-by-aja-evans/"><em>Feel-Good Finance</em></a>. “Who and where do you want older you to be? What do you want your lifestyle to be? What&#8217;s really important to older you?” are some of the questions Evans poses to her clients. She finds this practice can make saving money for the future feel more imperative and purposeful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As you inch closer to your senior years, brainstorm what you enjoy doing that also gives you purpose — “something meaningful that gives you a reason for getting up every day,” says Chodos. Learn an instrument, write stories, volunteer as a museum guide. Add activities that involve meeting people on a regular basis, like a dinner party club, board games night, or walking group, to foster friendships.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Be intentional about where you will retire</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you’re a senior without kids, you will either live in your own place or in <a href="https://www.aarp.org/caregiving/basics/info-2022/housing-options.html">one of the many types</a> of senior living arrangements. In assisted living or nursing homes, you are often getting most of the support you need for your daily living. When you live in your own place or in an independent-living community, you can engage support services to help with meal prepping, bathing, medication management, <a href="https://www.aarp.org/home-family/your-home/info-2021/aging-in-place-checklist.html">home modifications</a> (if the accommodation allows it), and more, says Eagen. <a href="https://www.dfs.ny.gov/system/files/documents/2020/05/ltc_guide.pdf">Long-term care insurance</a> can cover the cost of these services, depending on the policy. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Granigan says it’s essential to find out how accessible these support services are in the area you wish to retire, and their associated costs. To get this information, consult the local <a href="https://eldercare.acl.gov/Public/About/Aging_Network/AAA.aspx">Area Agency on Aging</a> (use this <a href="https://eldercare.acl.gov/Public/Index.aspx">Eldercare Locator</a> database to find one), a local <a href="https://www.aginglifecare.org/">aging life care professional</a>, or local <a href="https://www.vtvnetwork.org/">“villages.”</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also consider the opportunities for social connections that will be available to you and how easy it will be to participate in fun, meaningful activities. Are these easily accessible on foot if you can no longer drive? What about public transit, supermarkets, banks, gyms, parks, libraries, faith-based communities, malls, senior centers, and eateries?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Prioritize your health&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For adults without children heading into their golden years, it&#8217;s especially important to mind your physical and mental health, as well as pay attention to keeping your cognitive abilities sharp, so you can remain independent for as long as possible. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stay on top of exercising, and do your best to maintain your bone health, balance, muscle mass, strength, and mobility, advises Chodos and Granigan. Control risk factors like diabetes, high blood pressure, and high cholesterol, <a href="https://www.nia.nih.gov/health/alcohol-misuse-or-alcohol-use-disorder/facts-about-aging-and-alcohol#:~:text=Drinking%20too%20much%20alcohol%20over,memory%20loss%2C%20and%20mood%20disorders">watch your alcohol intake</a>, and keep up with medical visits. If you’re otherwise healthy, see your primary care physician annually to screen for chronic conditions once you turn 60, says Chodos. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might also consider entrusting your medical care to providers who are younger than you, says Reger, as they are more likely to be able to see your care through to the end.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for exercising the mind, crossword puzzles and Sudoku are all fine and good, but they aren’t the most effective in helping to preserve your brain function, says Reger. Instead, she says to focus on “engag[ing] in activities that keep you interested and thinking … something where you’re still using the parts of your brain that are active in problem solving and thinking creatively.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s really good if whatever you&#8217;re doing involves a social aspect because socializing with other people naturally stimulates our brain,” she emphasizes. “We have to be engaged, processing, and mentally flexible to have even a simple conversation … Speaking to new people, doing outreach, explaining ideas, any of that kind of mental activity is good for our brain.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Hearing loss is a very strong <a href="https://www.audiology.org/consumers-and-patients/hearing-and-balance/dementia-and-hearing-loss/#:~:text=Is%20There%20a%20Link%20Between,et%20al.%2C%202013">risk factor for cognitive decline</a>,” Chodos adds, so any changes to your hearing need to be corrected, stat. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gather a team to help you navigate the aging journey</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Eagen and Granigan say another option is assembling a team of professionals who can guide you through most of the processes outlined above, from financial management to engaging support services. The team may include an <a href="https://www.naela.org/">elder law attorney</a>, <a href="https://www.aginglifecare.org/">aging life care professional</a>, geriatric social worker, primary care doctor and/or geriatrician, and a financial planner who specializes in the child-free population. These professionals are all experienced at anticipating and steering you away from common pitfalls.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Set up advance directives</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With an elder law attorney, spell out what you envision for your assets, medical care, and end of life in legal documents <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23911624/elder-care-aging-power-of-attorney-will-estate-planning">like advance directives and a will</a>. As part of this, you will need to nominate people who’ll make decisions on your behalf if you become incapacitated. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Your senior years can and should be an exciting new phase of your life, whether or not you have children. With a little foresight and thoughtful planning, they can be every bit as fulfilling as you’ve always hoped.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jonquilyn Hill</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m Gen Z. ​​How can I save for retirement and still enjoy my life?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/explain-it-to-me/377960/saving-retirement-gen-z-401k-advice" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377960</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T06:21:30-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explain It to Me" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Personal finance is hard no matter what stage of life you&#8217;re in. But for Zoomers just entering the workforce, the challenges are also coupled with a lot of uncertainty. And that combination is what brought Carolina to us with her question on this week’s episode of Explain It to Me, Vox’s go-to hotline for all [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A hand is shown dropping coins into another hand, against a pink and purple background." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1359132050.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Personal finance is hard no matter what stage of life you&#8217;re in. But for Zoomers just entering the workforce, the challenges are also coupled with a lot of uncertainty. And that combination is what brought Carolina to us with her question on this week’s episode of <em>Explain It to Me</em>, Vox’s go-to hotline for all your questions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Carolina is fresh out of college and already stressing about retirement. The older people in her life give her the same advice that generations before her have gotten: start saving immediately, contribute to your 401(k), and don’t touch it for decades until you’re ready to stop working.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s sound advice, but Carolina wonders if it applies to her and the rest of her cohort. She knows the havoc the Great Recession wreaked on everyday people and the economy at-large. “I think people assume the stock market is always safe,” she says. “But then it keeps crashing.” It&#8217;s understandable why someone might be hesitant to put their trust in a financial system that had <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed">a scare as recently as this summer</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To answer this question, we enlisted <a href="https://www.yourrichbff.com/about-me">Vivian Tu, AKA Your Rich BFF.</a> Vivian is a former Wall Street daytrader and currently hosts <em>Networth and Chill</em> (<em>Explain It to Me </em>and <em>Networth and Chill</em> are both part of the Vox Media Podcast Network).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Can you enjoy today while preparing for the future? “You&#8217;ve got the folks who say ‘I&#8217;m going to blow all my cash today. I&#8217;m going to go on a shopping spree, because who knows if I get to retire in however many years.’” Tu says. “Then there are folks on the opposite side of the spectrum that say, ‘I need to prepare. I need to only think about retirement…I will have the worst life today so I can have a better future.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We sat down with Tu to discuss how to plan for the future while enjoying the now, how to protect yourself from financial uncertainty, and how younger generations can adjust to a changing financial landscape.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is an excerpt of our conversation, edited for length and clarity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can listen to <em>Explain It to Me</em> on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/explain-it-to-me/id1042433083">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1vSUO6Bg4abtjRF7fnGpT1">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://link.chtbl.com/explainit?sid=site">wherever you get podcasts</a>. If you’d like to submit a question, send an email to askvox@vox.com or call 1-800-618-8545.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP2602588043" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How should we think about balancing living in the now and preparing for the future?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I ask folks to find the middle of that barbell. You are allowed to enjoy your life today. I promise you, you are not put on this big green earth to work a 9 to 5 to hate your life. That is not your ultimate purpose. You are allowed to have the little treat. You are allowed to take that trip. You are allowed to go and grab a manicure with a friend because it is fun.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You do not want to have so much fun today at the expense of future you. You want to be able to have fun today and tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Practically, what tips do you have for young people who are thinking about retirement?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I always tell everyone, there is a special Your Rich BFF method: you need to STRIP. Everyone says, “Oh, did I pick the wrong career?” No, strip is an acronym.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">S stands for savings. First and foremost you want to set aside an emergency fund. In particular, I recommend putting your emergency fund into a <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/best/banking/high-yield-online-savings-accounts">high yield savings account</a> so that your money waiting for that rainy day earns interest in the meantime. If you are a singleton, 3 to 6 months of living expenses is a good bet. If you are head of household, you have dependents, I would say closer to 6 to 12.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">T is total debt. A lot of us have debt – that is not a bad word. It is just a tool. What I say is rank it from highest to lowest interest rate. Make the minimum payment across everything to keep your credit score high. But then any additional funds you have for debt paydown goes towards the interest rate that is the highest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Up next R: retirement. Take advantage of tax-advantaged accounts through your job. You can also open up an IRA or a Roth IRA.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then I. This is important; it&#8217;s not enough to just open those accounts, you actually have to invest. Take the cash that you&#8217;re putting into those accounts and make investments that make sense based on your risk profile. <a href="https://www.blackrock.com/us/individual/education/retirement/what-is-a-target-date-fund">Target date retirement funds</a> or <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/i/indexfund.asp">index funds</a> often make sense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the last step is so critically important: P – plan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don&#8217;t get to have happily ever after, you don&#8217;t get to ride off into the sunset if you do not have a plan. Write down what your goals are, what those milestones are, what you’d like to accomplish, the amount of money it&#8217;s going to take to get you there, and then back into what you need to do to get there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How do you protect yourself and those investments from another financial crisis?</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s really important that your portfolio makes sense for how far you are away from retirement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So when you&#8217;re 20, yeah, you can be 100% or 90% in the stock market and have 0% or 10% in bonds. When you&#8217;re 50, it should look almost flipped.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it really depends on how much you&#8217;re making and how much you already have. Every single person is a little different.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What about people who are just getting by? How should they prioritize retirement savings?</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If they are just getting by, first and foremost we want to try and maximize that income. People always balk when I say this: You need to be asking for a raise somewhere between 10 to 15% every single year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Ooof.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re getting it&nbsp; But if you ask for 10 to 15 and you get eight, that&#8217;s good, because eight is still going to help keep you above the inflation rate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Retirement and savings in general are often presented as this sacrifice. You&#8217;re going without your fancy groceries now so that future you can go on cruises and golf and do whatever it is that people do when they&#8217;re retired.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">JQ&#8217;s moving to Naples in her retirement!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But how do you find that balance? How do you prioritize those things?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think it&#8217;s about providing yourself with a life that you are happy with today while also thinking, “Hey, it&#8217;s not like saving for retirement means this money goes into a black hole.” You still get to spend it just later.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re not just setting this money aside and then getting that same number back in retirement. When you start investing your money, when it has a little bit of room and time to grow, that money gets to work really hard for you. And so you might put in $100,000. That $100,000 could be a couple million dollars in retirement.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Critiquing Trump’s economics — from the right]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/377972/friedrich-hayek-donald-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377972</id>
			<updated>2024-10-16T10:11:57-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are few more influential right-wing scholars than the economist Friedrich Hayek — and few whose work is less compatible with the right’s ascendant Trumpian strain. Born in Austria in 1899, Hayek spent his career developing a wide-ranging libertarian social theory. Societies, for Hayek, emerge from the interplay of countless different systems and logics — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A black-and-white photo of an older white man wearing frameless glasses and a suit jacket and tie, seated in front of a bookshelf. " data-caption="University of Chicago professor Friedrich Hayek. | Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-515257540.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>University of Chicago professor Friedrich Hayek. | Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There are few more influential right-wing scholars than the economist Friedrich Hayek — and few whose work is <em>less</em> compatible with the right’s ascendant Trumpian strain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Born in Austria in 1899, Hayek spent his career developing a wide-ranging libertarian social theory. Societies, for Hayek, emerge from the interplay of countless different systems and logics — creating an order so complex that no single entity, not even a government, can fully understand how it all operates. He believed that any attempt to transform such a thing by policy would invariably break part of this system, leading to unintended and often disastrous consequences.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t a good argument against <em>all</em> government interference in the marketplace (as a shallow read of Hayek might suggest). But it is a powerful insight into how societies work, one that provides an especially clear explanation for why planned economies failed so badly during Hayek’s lifetime.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It also helps us understand why there’s an authentic strain of right-wing resistance to Trump’s “tariffs and deportations” economic agenda —&nbsp;one that attentive liberals could learn from.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hayek’s “spontaneous order” and the case against regulation</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Hayek, there were basically two different types of system or order. The first is an organization, meaning a top-down planned effort where one person or entity lays out the rules for everyone to follow. The second is a “spontaneous order,” a bottom-up system in which the rules are determined over time by enormous numbers of micro-interactions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take, for example, the ecosystem of the American West. No one person set the rules by which bison, wolves, moose, prairie dogs, and the like breed and interact; in fact, no one dictated that this particular place needed to have those particular species at all. Instead, a system emerged out of thousands of years of interactions between flora and fauna, prey and predator. It has predictable rules and outcomes, but no hand at the tiller.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hayek believed that humanity operated in a similar, but even more complex, fashion.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Our own social order, according to Hayek, reflects centuries of interactions between hundreds of millions of different people and an impossibly diverse set of institutions, ranging from organized religion to different economic sectors to artist collectives. What we call “society” is the spontaneous order that emerges from individuals and organizations interacting and developing oft-unwritten rules that govern those interactions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The structure of human activities constantly adapts itself, and functions through adapting itself, to millions of facts which in their entirety are not known to anybody,” he wrote in <em>Law, Legislation, and Liberty, Volume 1</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Government, Hayek argued, plays a special role in spontaneous order: It “becomes indispensable in order to assure that [social] rules are obeyed.” The state both protects people’s rights to participate in their corner of the spontaneous order and, at times, can even guide the order toward adopting a different (and perhaps better) set of rules.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What the state cannot do well, in Hayek’s eyes, is interfere with discrete and specific interactions inside the spontaneous order.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the government issues “commands” telling people where and for how much they can sell their goods, for example, it is engaging in an enterprise that bureaucrats and politicians cannot and never will have sufficient knowledge to do adequately. Most economic regulation, for Hayek, is akin to the mass slaughter of wolves in the American West —&nbsp;a shortsighted move with <a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/74/7/430/7687410?login=false" data-type="link" data-id="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/74/7/430/7687410?login=false">destabilizing long-term consequences.</a> (Recent efforts to reintroduce wolves have been <a href="https://www.yellowstonepark.com/things-to-do/wildlife/wolf-reintroduction-changes-ecosystem/">an extraordinary success</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The spontaneous order arises from each element balancing all the various factors operating on it and by adjusting all its various actions to each other, a balance which will be destroyed if some of the actions are determined by another agency on the basis of different knowledge and in the service of different ends,” Hayek wrote.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hayek versus Trump</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is very easy to take this pro-market line of thinking too far.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We know that certain elements of the economy, like the money supply, can in fact be effectively managed by governments. Hayek’s skepticism of government could bleed over into paranoia, as with his argument in <em>The Road to Serfdom</em> asserting that social democracy would invariably bleed into authoritarianism. In fact, he even went so far as to endorse Augusto Pinochet’s dictatorship in Chile on grounds that <a href="https://www.opendemocracy.net/en/friedrich-hayek-dictatorship/">its free-market policies</a> were worth the loss of political liberty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Hayek’s argument is essential to understanding why some government projects, like Soviet-style command economies, tend to fail so spectacularly. When an economic policy aims at fundamental transformation, one in which humans are put in charge of managing a vast swath of ordinary economic activity, the potential for the state to exceed the bounds of its knowledge is obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hayek did not believe that this was only a problem for socialists. In <em>The Constitution of Liberty</em>, Hayek argued that conservatives’ emphasis on preserving tradition and the nation inclined them toward dangerous forms of state control over society.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It is this nationalistic bias which frequently provides the bridge from conservatism to collectivism: to think in terms of ‘our’ industry or resource is only a short step away from demanding that these national assets be directed in the national interest,” he wrote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So despite unquestionably being a man of the right, Hayek rejected the label “conservative” for his politics (he preferred “liberal” on grounds that “libertarian” was too clunky). Conservatives, he argued, were dogmatic and nationalistic — useful allies against the left, but&nbsp;skeptical enough of liberty that they posed their own set of collectivist dangers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Were Hayek still alive, he would see the vindication of his concerns in the person of Donald Trump. The former president’s two most consistent policy proposals — deporting millions of migrants and imposing a 10-percent tariff on all foreign-made goods — are far more aggressive efforts at reshaping America’s spontaneous order than any tax-and-spend proposals offered by the Harris campaign. Each, in its own way, amounts to a fundamental revision of how the American state and economy operate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, there’s a reason that some of the most effective critics of Trump’s <a href="https://www.cato.org/people/scott-lincicome">trade</a> and <a href="https://www.cato.org/people/alex-nowrasteh">immigration</a> policies work for the libertarian Cato Institute. Hayek’s heirs, at least those who take his ideas seriously, understand that Trump represents something anathema to their tradition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was adapted from the On the Right newsletter.</em>&nbsp;<em>New editions drop every Wednesday. Sign up&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/on-the-right-newsletter-whats-driving-conservative-ideas" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The nightmare facing Democrats, even if Harris wins]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/377729/kamala-harris-supreme-court-electoral-college-senate-constitution" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377729</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T18:00:49-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-16T06:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="US Federal Courts" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the course of its last few terms, the Supreme Court has effectively placed itself in charge of the executive branch.&#160; It’s given itself an extra-constitutional veto power over virtually any policy decision made by a federal agency. Even when it ultimately rules in favor of President Joe Biden’s policies, it often sits on those [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Democratic presidential nominee Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to the media before boarding Air Force Two after assessing the Hurricane Helene recovery response in North Carolina on October 5, 2024, in Charlotte, North Carolina. | Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Mario Tama/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2177013366.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Democratic presidential nominee Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to the media before boarding Air Force Two after assessing the Hurricane Helene recovery response in North Carolina on October 5, 2024, in Charlotte, North Carolina. | Mario Tama/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the course of its last few terms, the Supreme Court has effectively placed itself in charge of the executive branch.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s given itself an <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">extra-constitutional veto power</a> over virtually any policy decision made by a federal agency. Even when it ultimately rules in favor of President Joe Biden’s policies, it often <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/29/23530842/supreme-court-arizona-mayorkas-title-42-mexican-border-immigration">sits on those cases for months</a>, allowing a lower court order to suspend Biden’s programs for as much as a year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, the Court has done extraordinary favors for America’s only recent Republican president. Just look at the Republican justices’ decision to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">immunize former President Donald Trump from prosecution</a> for criminal actions he committed while in office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The president, in other words, is increasingly subordinate to the courts. Yet, as the judiciary seizes more and more power, the battle over who gets to shape it grows increasingly lopsided.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/cook-pvi/2022-partisan-voter-index/republican-electoral-college-advantage">enjoy an advantage in the Electoral College</a>. Just how <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/25/upshot/trump-electoral-college-harris.html?unlocked_article_code=1.PU4.nFhX.g0QJHoVkVyWg&amp;smid=url-share">much is up for debate</a>, but that advantage does mean that even if the American people hand Vice President Kamala Harris a modest victory in the popular vote this November, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">Donald Trump could still become president</a>. He’d then get to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/373084/supreme-court-trump-judges-federalist-society">nominate loyal Republican judges</a> eager to implement his party’s agenda from the bench, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/9/20962980/trump-supreme-court-federal-judges">much as he did during his first term</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Harris wins by a large enough margin to overcome the Electoral College’s Republican bias, she still may not get to have much of an impact on the judiciary. Her presidency — and specifically her ability to name judges — is likely to be restricted by a Republican Senate. For Democrats to control even a tied 50-50 Senate, one in which Vice President Tim Walz would hold the deciding vote if Harris prevails, they must not just win in every single blue and swing state Senate race this year, but also Senate races in at least two of the red states of Ohio, Florida, Montana, and Texas. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That <em>could</em> happen, but it would require the kind of unusually triumphant Democratic election year that the party hasn’t seen <a href="https://www.270towin.com/2008_Election/">since at least 2008</a> and possibly not since President Bill Clinton’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1996_United_States_presidential_election">landslide reelection victory in 1996</a>. And that seems <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">quite unlikely</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Harris victory could halt America’s slide into a MAGA-dominated future but it is unlikely to give her the power to reshape the judiciary in the way <a href="https://www.vox.com/22233051/biden-courts-republican-trump-supreme-court-judicial-nominations-senate-dick-durbin">Trump was able to during his first term</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Electoral College and Senate malapportionment has completely warped the judiciary&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During the Biden administration, the Republican Supreme Court wielded its power aggressively. It <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/24/23181720/supreme-court-dobbs-jackson-womens-health-samuel-alito-roe-wade-abortion-marriage-contraception">greenlit abortion bans</a> in numerous red states. It <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23616868/supreme-court-affirmative-action-harvard-unc-students-fair-admissions-john-roberts">abolished affirmative action</a> at nearly all universities. It has turned itself into a printing press for <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/27/23184848/supreme-court-kennedy-bremerton-school-football-coach-prayer-neil-gorsuch">court orders benefiting the Christian right</a>. It’s given itself <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/357900/supreme-court-loper-bright-raimondo-chevron-power-grab">sweeping veto power over literally anything done by a federal agency</a> that should be controlled by the president. And then there was that whole affair where the Republican justices said that <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/366855/supreme-court-trump-immunity-betrayal-worst-decisions-anticanon">Donald Trump was allowed to commit crimes while he was in office</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Along the way, the Court has pulled <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">new legal rules</a> out of thin air, then used these newly invented rules to nullify many of Biden’s most ambitious programs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the American people had voted for this agenda then it would be difficult to criticize the Republican Party for pushing it. But the electorate did nothing of the sort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After 2016, Trump was in a position to nominate three Supreme Court justices not because most Americans wanted him to be president but because enough Americans in the right places did. The Electoral College system means each American’s vote is not equal: Hillary Clinton, after all, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/elections/2016/results/president">won nearly 3 million more votes than Trump in 2016</a>, but still lost the presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump had a Republican Senate willing to put his choices on the bench because Republicans have an enduring advantage in the upper chamber, one that makes it more difficult for Democrats to control the Senate. Each state, regardless of population, gets two senators.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/1/30/20997046/constitution-electoral-college-senate-popular-vote-trump">antidemocratic features of the US Constitution</a> have been with the United States almost from the beginning, but they have an increasingly pronounced effect today, largely because <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/22/21293168/dc-statehood-vote-filibuster-supreme-court-joe-biden">the parties have sorted based on population density</a>. People in cities and other densely populated areas tend to vote for Democrats, while outlying areas become more and more Republican as they become less dense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That means that a system that effectively gives extra representation to the most sparsely populated states will unfairly favor the Republican Party. In 2021, for example, when the Senate split evenly between Democrats and Republicans, the Democratic “half” <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/11/6/21550979/senate-malapportionment-20-million-democrats-republicans-supreme-court">represented nearly 42 million more people</a> than the Republican “half.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the trend appears to be accelerating, this antidemocratic skew long predates the Trump presidency. Senate malapportionment has been one of the most consequential factors shaping US politics for decades. By some counts, if senators were distributed equally according to how the majority of Americans voted, Democrats would have <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/2/14/22925457/supreme-court-senate-confirmation-ketanji-brown-jackson-leondra-kruger-michelle-childs">controlled the Senate in every single year since the late 1990s</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/image_392068.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.602842183994,100,74.794315632012" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Wolf/Daily Kos Elections" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In that world, Democrats not only may have enacted more significant legislation, they would also almost certainly control the courts. Obama would have confirmed a justice to fill the vacancy created when Justice Antonin Scalia died in Obama’s last year in office, and none of Trump’s nominees would have likely been confirmed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, while Republicans probably would have still filled some Supreme Court seats during the 1990s and 2000s, it’s unlikely that they would have successfully confirmed an <a href="https://archive.thinkprogress.org/clarence-thomas-most-important-legal-thinker-in-america-c12af3d08c98/">ideologue like Justice Clarence Thomas</a> or an <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/350339/samuel-alito-republican-party-scotus">unapologetic GOP partisan like Justice Samuel Alito</a> if Senate seats were distributed fairly by population. In a fair Senate, Republican presidents would have to negotiate with Democrats to choose moderate nominees in the vein of, say, Justices Lewis Powell and Sandra Day O’Connor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That is to say, the impact of recent population sorting is felt acutely in the courts. In all of US history, only three justices were nominated by a president who lost the popular vote and confirmed by a bloc of senators who represent less than half of the nation’s populace. <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/10/26/21534358/supreme-court-amy-coney-barrett-constitution-anti-democratic-electoral-college-senate">All three of them currently sit on the Supreme Court</a>; they are Gorsuch, Brett Kavanaugh, and Amy Coney Barrett, Trump’s three appointees to the Court.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What a broken Senate means for a potential Harris administration&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the event that Harris wins the presidency but Republicans capture the Senate, we only need to turn the clock back less than a decade to predict what is likely to happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obama’s final two years in office were the only two when Republicans controlled the Senate. And shortly after Scalia’s death in February 2016, Senate Republicans announced that they would confirm no one Obama nominated to fill that seat. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“<a href="https://www.vox.com/21448904/senate-republicans-supreme-court-vacancy-election-ruth-bader-ginsburg">This vacancy should not be filled until we have a new president</a>,” then-Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell announced at the time. (Four years later, when Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg’s death allowed Trump to fill a vacancy in the final months of his presidency, Republicans abandoned the position they adopted in 2016 and swiftly confirmed Trump’s nominee.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The GOP’s blockade on Supreme Court confirmations should have surprised no one who watched the Senate closely because Senate Republicans had already imposed a near-total halt on all confirmations to federal appellate courts, powerful bodies that hand down precedential decisions that determine what the law is in multiple states at a time. In Obama’s last two years in office, he <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/12/9/20962980/trump-supreme-court-federal-judges">successfully appointed only two judges to the appellate bench</a>, and one of these judges was confirmed to a highly specialized, relatively nonpolitical court that primarily deals with patent law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By contrast, President George W. Bush confirmed 10 appellate judges during his last two terms in office, during a period when Democrats controlled the Senate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, during Obama’s last two years in office, he appointed only 18 judges to federal district courts, the lowest rank of federal judge who enjoys a lifetime appointment. That compares to 58 judges during Bush’s final two years in office, according to <a href="https://www.fjc.gov/history/judges/search/advanced-search">data from the Federal Judicial Center</a>. In Trump’s final two years in office, when Republicans controlled both the White House and the Senate, an astonishing 121 district judges were confirmed, including some infamously partisan judges like <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/6/13/23757893/aileen-cannon-donald-trump-jack-smith-indictment-mar-a-lago-maga">Aileen Cannon</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/17/23512766/supreme-court-matthew-kacsmaryk-judge-trump-abortion-immigration-birth-control">Matthew Kacsmaryk</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">President Biden, for what it’s worth, has confirmed more than 200 judges thanks to Democrats&#8217; narrow majority in the Senate, including a total of 116 since the current Congress took office. Over his entire presidency, he’s filled 44 appellate seats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without the power to confirm judges, Harris will have no way to dilute the influence of judges like Cannon or Kacsmaryk, and Republicans could easily refuse to confirm anyone to any judicial vacancy that comes open until the GOP regains the White House. Alternatively, Harris may be able to strike deals with Republicans to confirm a few of her preferred judges, but the GOP has a history of demanding a very high price to confirm even a single Democratic judge. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2014, for example, thanks in part to a now-weakened Senate process that allowed senators to veto anyone nominated to a federal judgeship in their state, Georgia’s Republican senators convinced Obama to <a href="https://archive.findlaw.com/blog/rumored-bipartisan-deal-for-11th-cir-seats-just-went-through/">nominate four Republican judicial choices</a> — including a Republican appellate judge — in return for confirming only two Democrats. One of the Republican nominees was eventually dropped because his <a href="https://thehill.com/blogs/blog-briefing-room/228303-obama-drops-controversial-nominee-opposed-by-black-caucus/">views on abortion, marriage equality, and the Confederate Flag offended Democrats</a>, but Republicans still walked away with more confirmed judges than Obama did. Harris could very well find herself in a similar situation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problems for Harris likely wouldn’t stop there. Because Republicans continue to dominate the judiciary, Harris would likely spend her presidency watching her policies get <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">struck down on dubious legal theories</a> invented by GOP judges, much as the Supreme Court struck down President Biden’s student loan forgiveness policy despite the fact that it was <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">unambiguously authorized by an act of Congress</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Democrats are starting to awaken to the threat of a Republican judiciary, but they haven’t yet found a solution to their constitutional problem</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Absent constitutional reform, Democrats have good reason to fear a Republican judiciary for decades to come. A malapportioned Senate means that Democrats are increasingly defenseless against the GOP’s efforts to control the bench. In recent years, however, Democrats have become more aware of a GOP judiciary’s power to thwart their agenda and have started to try to explore ways around it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, elected Republicans have viewed the courts as a favorable issue that rallies their base, while Democrats have behaved much more cautiously. Many Republicans credit Trump’s decision to delegate judicial selection to the Federalist Society, a bar association for right-wing lawyers, and to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/373084/supreme-court-trump-judges-federalist-society">release a list of potential Supreme Court nominees during his 2016 candidacy</a>, for giving him enough support to prevail in that year’s election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden, by contrast, began his presidency very reluctant to take on the courts. After many Democrats called for Supreme Court reform in the wake of the Senate’s disparate treatment of the Scalia and Ginsburg vacancies, Biden tried to take the wind out of the sails of reform by promising to appoint a commission to study the issue — and then filling the commission with Republicans and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/4/10/22375792/supreme-court-biden-commission-reform-court-packing-federalist-society">scholars who historically have not supported reform</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, as <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/supreme-court/">the Supreme Court’s polling numbers collapsed</a> and as the Court <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">outraged elected Democrats with opinions like its <em>Trump</em> immunity decision</a>, Democrats have grown more aggressive. Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/363557/supreme-court-biden-kamala-harris-reform-term-limits-ethics">proposed term-limiting the justices and imposing a binding ethics code on the Court</a>, proposals also supported by Harris. Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) has a bill that would <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/364438/supreme-court-chuck-schumer-trump-immunity">strip the Court of jurisdiction to enforce its immunity decision</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the most <a href="https://www.wyden.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/judicial_modernization_and_transparency_act_one-pager.pdf">ambitious recent Supreme Court reform proposals</a>, from Sen. Ron Wyden (D-OR), includes a number of very aggressive reforms. Wyden’s proposal would make every justice submit to a tax audit each year, require a two-thirds supermajority for the Court to overrule an act of Congress, and gradually expand the size of the Court to 15 seats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, while these proposals show that Democrats are moving in a more court-skeptical direction than they were four years ago, they would not solve the structural problems with US democracy that gave us the courts we have today. And they have virtually no chance of passing, especially in a world where it is increasingly difficult for Democrats to win the Senate even when they convincingly win the national popular vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, turning the United States into a nation where every vote counts equally — and where each voter is actually able to shape the judiciary —&nbsp;would require rewriting its Constitution. Until that happens, Democrats like Harris will struggle to win elections even when most Americans support them. And Democratic presidents will increasingly be at the mercy of Republicans in both the Senate and the courts.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Cities face daunting challenges. Mike Bloomberg wants to help them help each other.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/377923/cities-mike-bloomberg-policy-exchange-urban-development" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377923</id>
			<updated>2024-10-15T10:49:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-15T11:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Cities &amp; Urbanism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Philanthropy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cities represent the future of humanity — and that means we must figure out how to make them more livable. The share of people who live in urbanized areas more than doubled in the US and across the world from 1900 to 2000. More than eight in 10 Americans live in cities today, as do [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="mike bloomberg new york city urban development subway public health corruption schools" data-caption="Mike Bloomberg, as New York City mayor, takes the subway during his last week in office. In 2024, the billionaire is supporting a new project to help the world’s cities share good policies." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-539606656.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Mike Bloomberg, as New York City mayor, takes the subway during his last week in office. In 2024, the billionaire is supporting a new project to help the world’s cities share good policies.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/cities-and-urbanism">Cities</a> represent the future of humanity — and that means we must figure out how to make them more livable. The share of people who live in urbanized areas <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/urbanization#:~:text=By%201800%2C%20still%2C%20over%2090,people%20lived%20in%20urban%20areas.">more than doubled</a> in the US and across the world from 1900 to 2000. More than eight in 10 Americans live in cities today, as do the majority of people worldwide. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These densely populated places have created tremendous opportunities for innovation, economic growth, more efficient infrastructure and transit, and the curation of arts and culture. But the density that gives cities their power also creates new challenges: Cities have struggled to build enough <a href="https://www.vox.com/housing">housing</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22937366/air-polluted-city-smog-india-china-beijing">pollution</a> abounds, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/22347029/covid-19-pandemic-sunset-park-new-york">diseases</a> can spread more quickly. Cities must also manage the massive amounts of traffic — automobile, train, bike, and pedestrian — that can <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23496462/crisis-american-roads-pedestrian-traffic-deaths-safety">clash and result in deadly accidents.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The world’s cities are constantly experimenting and generating new ideas about how to solve those problems. The difficulty for policymakers has long been: <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/elements/abs/why-bad-policies-spread-and-good-ones-dont/401F57B534423A2D3889674F5FC1CC8E">How do we get good ideas to spread?</a> Municipal leaders sometimes labor under the mistaken belief that they have nothing to learn from their peers a few miles away or across the globe. How can we encourage more cross-pollination? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Billionaire Michael Bloomberg, former mayor of New York City, has launched <a href="https://www.bloomberg.org/press/bloomberg-philanthropies-launches-the-bloomberg-cities-idea-exchange-to-accelerate-the-spread-of-successful-civic-innovation-between-cities-across-the-globe/">a $50 million global idea-sharing project</a> to facilitate the migration of effective urban policies to allow cities around the world to address their biggest issues.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s called the Bloomberg Cities Idea Exchange, a curated marketplace of policy ideas for municipal leaders with hands-on support to help cities implement them. On Tuesday, the project announced the first set of policies that would be added to the exchange, selected by its staff based on <a href="https://www.nesta.org.uk/report/nesta-standards-of-evidence/">assessments of their effectiveness</a>, their cost and complexity, and the perceived interest among city leaders.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While <a href="https://www.ahrq.gov/innovations/index.html">ideas exchanges</a> are <a href="https://leitner.yale.edu/sites/default/files/files/resources/docs/2003-03.pdf">not a new concept</a> among <a href="https://stateinnovation.org/">policymakers</a>, they risk functioning as little more than passive warehouses, where ideas are placed on a shelf and may never be picked up again <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/9781119316916.ch16">if they cannot be easily adapted to a new setting</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Bloomberg group believes that by including only proven interventions and providing technical support for implementation, their policy-sharing network can thrive. The new exchange will provide grants to support implementation, offer how-to guides from the officials who have already put these policies into place and technical advice from Bloomberg staff, and pay for city leaders to visit other jurisdictions and see the policies in action.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The idea is “to take all of the lessons that have been learned from many experiments all over the globe,” said James Anderson, head of government innovation at Bloomberg Philanthropies. “To create an infrastructure that frankly does not exist in the world that takes good ideas, but marries them with the critical supports necessary to get them into the hands of people who want them when they want them and to help them stand them up so that they survive.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>11 proven policies that could help cities</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Urban development has long been one of Bloomberg’s top philanthropic priorities, the target of hundreds of millions of dollars in giving since 2011. He has supported <a href="https://cityleadership.harvard.edu/">a city leadership program at Harvard</a> and various initiatives focused on <a href="https://www.bloomberg.org/government-innovation/spurring-innovation-in-cities/mayors-challenge/">US mayors</a>, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.org/environment/supporting-sustainable-cities/bloomberg-american-sustainable-cities/">US cities</a>, and <a href="https://www.globalcities.org/">cities around the world</a>. He has paid particular attention to efforts to <a href="https://www.beyondcarbon.org/">better adapt cities to climate change</a> and to support <a href="https://publicartchallenge.bloomberg.org/">public art projects</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s a natural fit for the former New York mayor, who has a deep interest and expertise in the challenges cities face. While in office, he <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2007/09/30/nyregion/30mayor.html">traveled to Paris</a> and decided to test out a bike share in New York like the one he saw there; he turned to Bogotá for inspiration on <a href="https://nyc.streetsblog.org/2008/03/25/nyc-to-launch-bus-rapid-transit-in-the-bronx">bus rapid transit</a>, jumpstarting <a href="https://www.thecity.nyc/2024/09/18/mta-capital-plan-interborough-express/">a new era of public transit improvements</a> that continued beyond his term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bloomberg Philanthropies is stocking the ideas exchange with 11 policy interventions to start, covering the breadth of issues that city leaders contend with, from transportation to air quality to public corruption to infectious diseases:</p>

<ul>
<li>Installing low-cost air quality sensors in schools and children’s health centers</li>



<li>Renovating public buildings to be more energy-efficient</li>



<li>Supplying school lunches with sustainably grown produce and meat</li>



<li>Digitizing the process for business licenses and other permits to reduce corruption</li>



<li>Providing cold storage units for local merchants who sell produce</li>



<li>Offering more summer education programs for kids</li>



<li>Connecting people in need with neighbors who can help them access aid</li>



<li>Adopting smoking bans and other smoke-free policies in public places</li>



<li>Converting shipping containers into temporary shelter for unhoused people</li>



<li>Piloting reduced speed limits to prevent car crashes</li>



<li>Incorporating people who informally pick up trash into the public workforce</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of these ideas aren’t particularly novel — NYC’s first smoking ban was instituted <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2003/03/27/nyregion/new-york-state-adopts-strict-ban-on-workplace-smoking.html">while Bloomberg was mayor in 2003</a> — but the policies themselves aren’t really the selling point of the exchange.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, the potential value is the knowledge that city officials have accumulated in trying to implement policy solutions and the ability to share those experiences with others who want to try them out. That is where the need truly lies, Yonah Freemark, principal research associate at the Metropolitan Housing and Communities Policy Center at the Urban Institute, told me. He described attending a meeting that brought together leaders from seven neighboring jurisdictions in Minnesota; before that day, the officials said, they had never met collectively before.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“My experience is that every city and the staff who work for that city think that their city is the most unique place in the world,” Freemark said. “That there is nothing they can fundamentally learn from other cities because their specific problems are problems unto themselves.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Bloomberg project hopes to break down those silos. Freemark gave the example of low-cost air quality sensors in schools and other areas frequented by children. That policy has <a href="https://breathelife2030.org/news/lima-builds-ambitious-air-quality-monitoring-system/">already been implemented in Lima, Peru</a>, and has shown <a href="https://www.c40.org/case-studies/c40-bloomberg-awards-lima/">a 45-percent improvement in air quality</a>, providing the empirical foundation for its inclusion in Bloomberg’s exchange.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the real opportunity, Freemark said, would be officials from Lima sharing with their peers in other countries how they found the manufacturer of the low-cost sensors, giving other cities the actionable information that officials are often looking for when they want to adapt policies to their own communities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People in other cities may care about air pollution, but they don&#8217;t know who to contact about that. They don&#8217;t know who [Lima] got in touch with,” he said. “That person in Lima is going to tell them who their contact was at Microsoft or whatever company gave them the air sensor and is going to help to make that connection. That would never happen without this kind of direct communication.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Josh Humphries, Atlanta Mayor Andre Dickens&#8217;s top housing adviser, who has consulted with multiple cities on <a href="https://atlanta.urbanize.city/post/downtown-homeless-housing-melody-initiative-opens-today">building homes</a> for the unhoused, told me that the package offered by the Bloomberg exchange “probably solves 80 to 90 percent of the questions that we might get talking one-on-one with 25 different cities.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Bloomberg team has tried to anticipate the problems that could hamper such a project, studying the science of implementation and idea replication “to learn about why ideas do and don&#8217;t spread,” Anderson said. Every city must navigate its own administrative labyrinth of funding, procurement, rulemaking, and public comment, creating friction for getting any new idea off the ground. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many ideas clearinghouses, Anderson said, are primarily focused on supplying the policy ideas. The Bloomberg project is equally focused on the demand side, on generating interest in policy ideas among the people who would actually implement them and then providing support for their efforts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The cities of the future face daunting challenges, from the planetary (climate change) to the painfully human (political polarization and corruption). We won’t know whether the Bloomberg exchange was a well-intentioned flop or a catalyst for real change until its own evaluation comes in — and that could be many years into the future, given the slow pace of urban policy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We want to make sure every city that wants one of these ideas and wants to use it well, that we can support them and give them the dedicated resources and support that we think is so fundamental to successful idea replication,” Anderson told me. “We are going to be watching closely and figuring out how we meet the demand that exists.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nebraska is the only state with two abortion measures on the ballot. Confusion is the point.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/377639/nebraska-abortion-ballot-measure-trimester-ban-election-reproductive-freedom" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377639</id>
			<updated>2024-10-11T17:37:02-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-15T07:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voters in 10 states will weigh in on abortion-rights ballot measures this November, but only Nebraskans will cast ballots on two competing initiatives. Initiative 439 would establish a state constitutional right to abortion up to fetal viability or when necessary to protect the “health or life” of the pregnant patient. Initiative 434, however, would ban [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Two people in inflatable Lego minifig suits, one blue and one green, stand on a street with signs that read “Protect abortion. Sign the petition.”" data-caption="Petitioners gather signatures for the Protect Our Rights campaign on Saturday, March 9, 2024, in Omaha, Nebraska." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/20240309_petition_50.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Petitioners gather signatures for the Protect Our Rights campaign on Saturday, March 9, 2024, in Omaha, Nebraska.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Voters in 10 states will weigh in on abortion-rights ballot measures this November, but only Nebraskans will cast ballots on two competing initiatives. <a href="https://voterguide.flatwaterfreepress.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Protect-the-Right-to-Abortion-Constitutional-Amendment-no-contact.pdf">Initiative 439</a> would establish a state constitutional right to abortion up to fetal viability or when necessary to protect the “health or life” of the pregnant patient. <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Nebraska_Initiative_434,_Prohibit_Abortions_After_the_First_Trimester_Amendment_(2024)">Initiative 434</a>, however, would ban abortion in the second and third trimesters, with exceptions for sexual assault, incest, or medical emergencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We hear all the time how confusing the two measures are and folks are very afraid of accidentally checking the wrong one,” said Shelley Mann, the executive director of Nebraska Abortion Resources (NEAR), the only statewide abortion fund in Nebraska.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of the confusion surrounding the competing proposals is intentional, and likely a preview of new tactics in the evolving anti-abortion playbook. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since May 2023, abortion in Nebraska has been banned past the first trimester, and last fall reproductive choice advocates launched a ballot measure campaign to restore and expand access. Anti-abortion leaders introduced a competing measure <a href="https://nebraskapublicmedia.org/en/news/news-articles/new-abortion-petition-looks-to-enshrine-bans-in-nebraska-constitution/">four months later</a>. (The proposed anti-abortion ballot measure wouldn’t expand current restrictions, but it would embed existing second- and third-trimester bans into Nebraska’s state constitution. This would make it significantly more difficult for the legislature or courts to roll back those restrictions later.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While collecting signatures, some canvassers from the Protect Women and Children campaign misrepresented themselves as being in favor of expanding abortion access, leading hundreds of Nebraskans to erroneously sign their petition. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Upon realizing their mistake, more than 300 of those voters signed affidavits to have their names removed from the anti-abortion petition, marking the highest number of removal requests in the state&#8217;s history. (Over <a href="https://nebraskafamilyalliance.org/breaking-over-205k-signatures-collected-to-protect-women-children/">205,000</a> people signed the anti-abortion petition in total.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More recently, Catherine Brooks — a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_Sp7WLVTt0">neonatal pediatrician</a> who <a href="https://www.ketv.com/article/nebraska-neonatologist-files-amendments-over-abortion-initiative/62020812">filed legal objections</a> to block the pro-abortion rights measure from appearing on Nebraska’s ballot — appeared in <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/4xp2bbsgyro9hxedzb6zp/PWCNE01H.mpg?rlkey=js63t4w45tdzj48ezdtclu0hj&amp;st=gowuymbk&amp;dl=0">a TV ad</a> in which she portrayed herself as an advocate for reproductive freedom fighting against government intrusion in medicine. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“As a doctor, I want compassionate, clear, scientific standards of care,” Brooks said in the ad. “As a mom, I want to keep the government out of the relationship between a woman and her physician. Initiative 439 pretends to protect our rights but it does the opposite. It lets government officials interfere in medical decisions and takes care out of the hands of licensed physicians, when women in crisis need them most.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s little doubt that Republicans in Nebraska hope to restrict abortion beyond the existing <a href="https://governor.nebraska.gov/press/governor-pillen-signs-lb574-law-abortion-ban-takes-effect-immediately">12-week ban, which was</a> passed shortly after lawmakers <a href="https://apnews.com/article/abortion-heartbeat-bill-nebraska-78b861951e8cc0ca92fa320820e2cbee">narrowly failed</a> to impose a six-week limit. Nebraska’s Republican Gov. Jim Pillen <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/2023/06/29/nebraska-gov-jim-pillen-says-he-wont-stop-on-abortion-seeks-total-ban/">has publicly pledged</a> to continue fighting until abortion is fully banned in his state.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The outcome of these dueling ballot proposals could affect not just those in Nebraska but pregnant people nationwide. Abortion rights activists have been sounding the alarm, warning that if Initiative 434 succeeds in November, anti-abortion leaders will export their winning strategy elsewhere — using the language of reproductive freedom to advance seemingly moderate measures that obscure long-term goals of deeper bans.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Nebraska’s 12-week abortion ban is already causing harm</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 12-week abortion ban Nebraska lawmakers passed in May 2023 included exceptions for pregnancies caused by rape or incest, or to save the life of the mother.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As in other states, these exceptions have proved ambiguous for doctors on the ground, and many patients who need abortion care have been unable to get it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kim Paseka, a 34-year-old woman based in Lincoln, Nebraska, was one of those patients. Paseka lives with her husband and their 3-year-old son, and though they wanted at least two children, they were unsure about pursuing that in Nebraska after <em>Roe </em>was overturned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We knew it was probably inevitable that our state government was going to work on banning reproductive health care in some capacity and it definitely gave us pause, like should we move, do we stay and fight? Those were our dinner table conversations,” she told Vox. In the summer of 2023, just after Nebraska lawmakers passed their 12-week ban, Paseka learned she was pregnant again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Initial blood tests looked fine, but following a routine ultrasound, Paseka was informed that her baby’s heartbeat was slower than expected. In subsequent appointments, the doctors determined the heartbeat was diminishing and that Paseka was carrying a nonviable pregnancy. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because of the new ban and the fact that Paseka’s life was not immediately threatened, her doctors weren’t comfortable ending the pregnancy. They sent her home with instructions for “<a href="https://www.tommys.org/baby-loss-support/miscarriage-information-and-support/your-options-and-decisions/expectant-management">expectant management</a>” — meaning to wait until she’d bleed out eventually with a miscarriage. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I had to go back to the hospital for three more scans, where I had to see the heartbeat weaken further week by week, and during this whole time I’m so nauseous, I’m tired, I’m experiencing all the regular pregnancy symptoms, but I was carrying a nonviable pregnancy,” she said. It took roughly a month for Paseka to finally bleed out the pregnancy at home.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In Nebraska, we have these exceptions, but in my situation it wasn’t assault, it wasn’t incest, and my life wasn’t in immediate danger, so I automatically just lose health care,” she said. “They’re forgetting how detrimental that can be to mental health, that it’s not just about physical endangerment. &#8230; I felt like a walking coffin.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mann, the executive director of Nebraska’s statewide abortion fund, emphasized that the 12-week ban has had far-reaching consequences that most people underestimate. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Not only are folks now restricted in how and when they can get the care they need, but it&#8217;s additionally problematic that these rules are designed to be confusing and were brought about during a time when confusion was at an all-time high,” she told Vox. “We talk to callers and members of the community all the time who have no idea when and if abortion is even legal here in Nebraska.”<br><br>There are two remaining abortion clinics in the state, though both only perform abortions part-time, meaning there sometimes are not enough appointments to go around, including for patients traveling in from states with near-total bans like Iowa and South Dakota.<br><br>“This means that not only are patients who are past the 12-week mark forced to flee the state for care, but even patients under that ban restriction are sometimes having to travel just to get an appointment in a timely manner,” Mann explained. “These patients are going to places like Minneapolis, Chicago, and Denver … this travel is often expensive, inconvenient, and overall an enormous burden on pregnant people.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Anti-abortion leaders plan to push for further restrictions in Nebraska</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Initiative 434, also known as the Prohibit Abortions After the First Trimester Amendment, sounds almost like a measure to protect abortion access in the first 12 weeks of a pregnancy. The proposal, which is being <a href="https://nebraskaexaminer.com/briefs/sen-pete-ricketts-funds-competing-abortion-ban-petition-effort/">primarily funded</a> by Nebraska <a href="https://www.ricketts.senate.gov/news/press-releases/ricketts-announces-co-sponsorships-of-three-pro-life-bills-following-nebraska-march-for-life/">billionaire and US Sen</a>. Pete Ricketts, does not in fact do that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On top of codifying the state’s existing ban on abortion past 12 weeks into Nebraska’s constitution, the measure allows lawmakers to pass further legislative bans on top. Put differently, it strengthens abortion bans but provides no meaningful increase in abortion access.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Marion Miner, the associate director for “pro-life and family policy” at the Nebraska Catholic Conference, emphasized in a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PHpHjqyEPcQ">video posted over the summer</a> that he does not see Initiative 434 as “an acceptable final resolution” because it does “not protect all unborn children” including those born from sexual assault or incest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It is an imperfect proposal … an incremental pro-life initiative that takes a small step to protect unborn life without restraining us from doing more,” Miner said, stressing Initiative 434 would “allow for additional protections to be passed in the future.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over a century ago, Nebraska lawmakers enacted a law stating that if two conflicting state constitutional ballot measures pass, the measure with the most votes will be adopted. According to Nebraska Secretary of State Bob Evnen, if both Initiative 439 and Initiative 434 pass, it would mark the first time this 1912 law could be used.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s possible that one of the proposals could get approved and not be adopted,” Evnen <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/05/27/nx-s1-4977662/nebraska-abortion-ballot-voters-viability-12-week-ban">told NPR in May</a>. “It’ll come down to, whichever one receives the most votes is the one that would go into Nebraska’s constitution.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even the existing 12-week ban, often described by conservatives as <a href="https://www.vox.com/23741997/republicans-12-week-abortion-bans-europe-roe-dobbs">a moderate compromise</a>, appears out of step with what Nebraskans want. The ACLU of Nebraska <a href="https://www.aclunebraska.org/en/press-releases/new-poll-shows-most-nebraskans-oppose-more-abortion-bans">found in late 2022</a> that 59 percent of respondents opposed lawmakers enacting abortion bans, with opposition in both rural and urban areas and every congressional district.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the more than two years since the Supreme Court overturned <em>Roe v. Wade, </em>abortion rights ballot measures <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/8/23952090/ohio-election-results-issue-1-abortion-virginia-kentucky-roe-dobbs">have succeeded</a> in all seven states in which they’ve appeared, including red and purple states like Kentucky, Ohio, Kansas, Michigan, and Montana. This year, high-profile abortion rights measures are on the ballot in states like Florida, Arizona, and Missouri. Nebraska’s contests, relative to these other states, have received less attention. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They know public opinion is on our side so they’re doing everything they can to muddy the waters,” said Allie Berry, the manager for the Protect Our Rights campaign, which is leading Nebraska’s ballot measure to expand abortion rights. While Berry feels cautiously optimistic, she understands her opponents are striving to trip up voters. “If they succeed here,” Berry predicts, “they’ll try this in every other state.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aubrey Hirsch</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Miscarriages are incredibly common. Abortion bans have made them less safe.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/life/377657/pregnancy-miscarriage-care-abortion-bans" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377657</id>
			<updated>2024-10-11T16:57:20-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-15T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="In an illustration, a pregnant woman holds her stomach against a background of blue and purple trees." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriageHEADER.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-1.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: rows of babies. Text: Miscarriages can be deeply heartbreaking. They are the most common early pregnancy complication, occuring in as many as 20% of known pregnancies." title="Image: rows of babies. Text: Miscarriages can be deeply heartbreaking. They are the most common early pregnancy complication, occuring in as many as 20% of known pregnancies." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-2.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A woman sits on a couch as her husband comforts her. Text: Many people experiencing miscarriage choose to speed up the process and make it more predictable by choosing medical intervention. This can offer a patient some semblance of control in an overwhelming situation. " title="Image: A woman sits on a couch as her husband comforts her. Text: Many people experiencing miscarriage choose to speed up the process and make it more predictable by choosing medical intervention. This can offer a patient some semblance of control in an overwhelming situation. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-3.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A torn daily calendar shows the image of a crying woman. Text: Without medical intervention, the process can be easy and quick, or it can be painful and prolonged, taking up to eight weeks. And a fifth of miscarriages occurring before week 13 require treatment to prevent harm to the pregnant person." title="Image: A torn daily calendar shows the image of a crying woman. Text: Without medical intervention, the process can be easy and quick, or it can be painful and prolonged, taking up to eight weeks. And a fifth of miscarriages occurring before week 13 require treatment to prevent harm to the pregnant person." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-4.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A clump of cells in a uterus. Text: Medically, any termination of a pregnancy before the fetus is viable is called an  “abortion,” whether it’s spontaneous — like miscarriage — or induced. " title="Image: A clump of cells in a uterus. Text: Medically, any termination of a pregnancy before the fetus is viable is called an  “abortion,” whether it’s spontaneous — like miscarriage — or induced. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-5.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: mifepristone and misoprostol, used in miscarriages and abortions up to 10 weeks; dilation and curettage (D&amp;C), used for miscarriages and abortions after 10 weeks. Text: Because the medical interventions used in miscarriage and abortion care are identical, the restrictions on abortions imposed since the Supreme Court overturned Roe v. Wade have had devastating consequences for miscarriage care." title="Image: mifepristone and misoprostol, used in miscarriages and abortions up to 10 weeks; dilation and curettage (D&amp;C), used for miscarriages and abortions after 10 weeks. Text: Because the medical interventions used in miscarriage and abortion care are identical, the restrictions on abortions imposed since the Supreme Court overturned Roe v. Wade have had devastating consequences for miscarriage care." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-6.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A pharmacist tells a woman,  “Abortion pills are illegal here.” The woman replies, “But I have a prescription!” Text: In the weeks following that 2022 decision, some women reported being denied miscarriage treatment at pharmacies. Denials have continued despite warnings from the Biden administration that refusing to fill these prescriptions could violate federal anti-discrimination laws.
" title="Image: A pharmacist tells a woman,  “Abortion pills are illegal here.” The woman replies, “But I have a prescription!” Text: In the weeks following that 2022 decision, some women reported being denied miscarriage treatment at pharmacies. Denials have continued despite warnings from the Biden administration that refusing to fill these prescriptions could violate federal anti-discrimination laws.
" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-7.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A woman tells her doctor, “I just want to be on the other side of this.” The doctor replies, “Come back if you have dizziness, fever, or really heavy bleeding.” Text: Doctors in states with abortion bans may be more likely to recommend waiting for pregnancy tissue to pass naturally out of fear of being accused of facilitating an abortion.
" title="Image: A woman tells her doctor, “I just want to be on the other side of this.” The doctor replies, “Come back if you have dizziness, fever, or really heavy bleeding.” Text: Doctors in states with abortion bans may be more likely to recommend waiting for pregnancy tissue to pass naturally out of fear of being accused of facilitating an abortion.
" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-8_a0e93c.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: 6 doctors, with one with a red mark over her face. Text: In fact, almost 1 in 6 OB-GYNs nationwide report constraints on their ability to care for pregnant patients experiencing complications or miscarriage. " title="Image: 6 doctors, with one with a red mark over her face. Text: In fact, almost 1 in 6 OB-GYNs nationwide report constraints on their ability to care for pregnant patients experiencing complications or miscarriage. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-9_c3a635.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A chart showing OB-GYNs reporting constraints on care they can offer patients. Text: That number is significantly higher in states with abortion bans. Source: Kaiser Family Foundation" title="Image: A chart showing OB-GYNs reporting constraints on care they can offer patients. Text: That number is significantly higher in states with abortion bans. Source: Kaiser Family Foundation" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-10.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Text: Risks of delayed care for miscarriage complications can be life-threatening and include blood clots, severe blood loss, infection, and sepsis. Image shows these complications." title="Text: Risks of delayed care for miscarriage complications can be life-threatening and include blood clots, severe blood loss, infection, and sepsis. Image shows these complications." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-11.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A fetus in a uterus behind shattered glass. Text: These risks are even higher in cases of “inevitable miscarriage,” where the fetus is no longer viable but cardiac activity is still detectable.
" title="Image: A fetus in a uterus behind shattered glass. Text: These risks are even higher in cases of “inevitable miscarriage,” where the fetus is no longer viable but cardiac activity is still detectable.
" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-12.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A pregnant woman holds her stomach. Text: In states with strict bans, people facing this kind of loss have been forced to carry fetuses with no chance of survival until cardiac activity ceases or until they become dangerously ill. " title="Image: A pregnant woman holds her stomach. Text: In states with strict bans, people facing this kind of loss have been forced to carry fetuses with no chance of survival until cardiac activity ceases or until they become dangerously ill. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-13.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A prescription pad constrained by chains reads “medical termination.” Text: Only then do some doctors feel confident they can justify an abortion under the laws’ very narrow exceptions to protect a pregnant person’s life." title="Image: A prescription pad constrained by chains reads “medical termination.” Text: Only then do some doctors feel confident they can justify an abortion under the laws’ very narrow exceptions to protect a pregnant person’s life." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-14.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: An infant with a sheet over them on a gurney. Text: These constraints on maternal care contribute to alarming trends in infant and maternal mortality rates in states with abortion bans. Babies born in states with abortion bans were 30% more likely to die in the first month of life than those born in states with more expansive reproductive freedoms." title="Image: An infant with a sheet over them on a gurney. Text: These constraints on maternal care contribute to alarming trends in infant and maternal mortality rates in states with abortion bans. Babies born in states with abortion bans were 30% more likely to die in the first month of life than those born in states with more expansive reproductive freedoms." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-15_5d1a45.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A chart of maternal deaths showing the difference in states where abortion is banned, restricted, and allowed. Text: People in states with abortion bans are more than twice as likely to die while pregnant, birthing, or newly postpartum. Source: Gender Equity Policy Institute analysis of CDC (2018-2021)" title="Image: A chart of maternal deaths showing the difference in states where abortion is banned, restricted, and allowed. Text: People in states with abortion bans are more than twice as likely to die while pregnant, birthing, or newly postpartum. Source: Gender Equity Policy Institute analysis of CDC (2018-2021)" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-16.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A pregnant woman stands alone. Text: Abortion bans remove options for people enduring the grief of pregnancy loss, turning an already vulnerable moment into a perilous one and make the world less safe for all pregnant people. " title="Image: A pregnant woman stands alone. Text: Abortion bans remove options for people enduring the grief of pregnancy loss, turning an already vulnerable moment into a perilous one and make the world less safe for all pregnant people. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-17.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A scale with a heart on one side and a pile of papers reading “law” on the other, heavier side. Text: Doctors should be focused on providing patients with compassionate care, not on the fear of legal repercussions." title="Image: A scale with a heart on one side and a pile of papers reading “law” on the other, heavier side. Text: Doctors should be focused on providing patients with compassionate care, not on the fear of legal repercussions." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/miscarriagePanel-18.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,29.057591623037,100,41.884816753927" alt="Image: A pregnant woman’s stomach. Text: Prolonging the physical and emotional suffering of miscarriage is a cruel disregard for the health and humanity of pregnant people. " title="Image: A pregnant woman’s stomach. Text: Prolonging the physical and emotional suffering of miscarriage is a cruel disregard for the health and humanity of pregnant people. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sean Illing</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Ta-Nehisi Coates on complexity, clarity, and truth]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/377773/ta-nehisi-coates-palestine-moral-clarity" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=377773</id>
			<updated>2024-10-14T15:15:52-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-15T06:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Gray Area" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve always believed that the world is complicated and that our desire for simplicity is understandable but dangerous.&#160; But when does the impulse to embrace ambiguity become its own pathology? Sure, the world is complex, but sometimes we have to pass judgment. We have to be willing to say that something is true and something [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Ta-Nehisi Coates wearing a suit and a collared shirt with no tie smiles while holding a microphone." data-caption="Author Ta-Nehisi Coates during the Alight Align Arise: Advancing the Movement for Repair conference on June 7, 2023, in Atlanta, Georgia. | Carol Lee Rose/Getty Images for Decolonizing Wealth Project" data-portal-copyright="Carol Lee Rose/Getty Images for Decolonizing Wealth Project" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1496820855.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Author Ta-Nehisi Coates during the Alight Align Arise: Advancing the Movement for Repair conference on June 7, 2023, in Atlanta, Georgia. | Carol Lee Rose/Getty Images for Decolonizing Wealth Project</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve always believed that the world is complicated and that our desire for simplicity is understandable but dangerous.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But when does the impulse to embrace ambiguity become its own pathology? Sure, the world is complex, but sometimes we have to pass judgment. We have to be willing to say that something is true and something is false, that something is right and something is wrong.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how do we know when things really are that clear? And how do we avoid the impulse to lie to ourselves when we know they’re not?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ta-Nehisi Coates is an author, essayist, and one of our most celebrated living writers. He’s just published a new book called <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/653438/the-message-by-ta-nehisi-coates/"><em>The Message</em></a> that has <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/07/media/cbs-ta-nehisi-coates-tony-dokoupil-interview/index.html">stirred up quite a bit of controversy</a> because the longest essay in it is about his trip to Palestine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you know almost nothing about the conflict between Israel and Palestine, the one thing you’d probably be comfortable saying is that it’s complicated. This is an assertion Coates challenges directly. For him, the moral arithmetic is simple and Israel&#8217;s treatment of the Palestinian population is fundamentally wrong.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I invited Coates on <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area"><em>The Gray Area</em></a> to explore where he’s coming from and why he felt it was important to write this book. But the point wasn’t to have a debate or an argument. I invited Coates because I think he’s smart and sincere and doesn’t write anything without seriously thinking about it. This conversation is really about the role of the writer and the intellectual and what it means to describe the world with moral clarity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As always, there’s <em>much</em> more in the full podcast, so listen and follow <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area"><em>The Gray Area</em></a> on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-gray-area-with-sean-illing/id1081584611">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/6NOJ6IkTb2GWMj1RpmtnxP">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://www.pandora.com/podcast/the-gray-area-with-sean-illing/PC:30793?source=stitcher-sunset">Pandora</a>, or wherever you find podcasts. New episodes drop every Monday.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3349092239" width="100%"></iframe>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What&#8217;s been the most surprising thing to you about the reaction to this book so far?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m surprised at the surprise. So, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/07/media/cbs-ta-nehisi-coates-tony-dokoupil-interview/index.html">the CBS interview</a> was the first live interview. I was not surprised by the aggression, tenacity, whatever you want to call it. Or, I should say, I knew that was going to happen eventually. I didn&#8217;t know it was going to happen there. So I was surprised in the sense that, “Oh, it&#8217;s right now.” And it took me a minute to catch up with it and realize that it’s actually happening right now, but this is what it is.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m surprised that people are like, “I can&#8217;t believe that happened.” I understand I am going to go into some arenas where you don&#8217;t usually say the state of Israel is practicing apartheid. That&#8217;s just not a thing that you usually hear people saying in places like that, and so I am going to say that. And what&#8217;s going to come out of that, I have no idea, but I hope people understand that this is what&#8217;s happening.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You made a deliberate choice to write about Palestine, which, as you know, is an impossibly charged issue. Why wade into these waters? Why this conflict? Why now?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s impossibly charged. This is so clear. It was so clear. And when I saw that — and maybe this is naive, maybe you&#8217;re right, maybe it is impossibly charged — but I was just like, &#8220;Oh, this is easy.&#8221; Not easy like easy to do, easy to write, but the math is clear. You know what I mean?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The word I used at the time when I saw it was Jim Crow, because it was so obviously Jim Crow. You tell me you got one set of roads for one group of people, another set of roads for another group of people, and the roads you have for the other group of people are impossibly longer. They take more to get from point A to point B. Those roads have checkpoints, and the checkpoints sometimes materialize out of nowhere. This is all fact.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whatever you think about it, maybe you think that&#8217;s the way it should be, but this is what it is. This is actually what it is. You&#8217;re telling me that one group of people has constant access to running water, and the other group of people don&#8217;t know when their water might be cut off?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re telling me that that other group of people, depending on where they live, if they&#8217;re in a particular area on the West Bank, it might be illegal for them even to collect rainwater? You&#8217;re telling me one group of people has access to a civil system of criminal justice, so that when they get arrested, they know their rights, they&#8217;re told why they&#8217;re arrested, lawyer, etc. You&#8217;re telling me the other group has no access to that? That they can be arrested, that no one needs to tell them why they&#8217;re being arrested? No one needs to tell their families that if they are killed, you don&#8217;t even have to return their bodies? What is that?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So when you compare Palestine to the Jim Crow South, my reaction is that these are both moral obscenities, but they&#8217;re different. And I do think it&#8217;s complicated —</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tell me why you think it’s complicated.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think it matters that many Palestinians still support the attacks on October 7. I think it matters that Black people in the Jim Crow South wanted to be treated as equal citizens in a fully democratic America.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s generally true that Palestinians want equal rights in a fully democratic Israel. And if they had that they might vote to end its existence as a Jewish State. And you know what? If I was a Palestinian who was pulling my friends and my family out of the fucking rubble, I&#8217;d probably vote the same way. I understand that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Personally, I hate the idea of a state based entirely on religious or ethnic identity. But I&#8217;m not Jewish and I don&#8217;t live in Israel and I understand why the people who do live there would have these concerns. And I also think it matters that Jews are indigenous to that land and have nowhere else to go. I just think that complicates the picture in other ways.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I am of the mind that discrimination on the basis of race, ethnicity, religion is never acceptable. There is nothing in this world that will make separate and unequal okay, and there’s nothing — and I’ll use this word — that makes apartheid okay. That&#8217;s not complex for me. It&#8217;s like the death penalty is not really complex for me, because you cannot guarantee to me that the state will not execute an innocent person. You just can&#8217;t. So I&#8217;m against it, period. There aren&#8217;t any exceptions to that.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I haven&#8217;t been to Palestine but I know it&#8217;s bad and I know what you saw there is wrong. And I don&#8217;t believe there is any such thing as a moral occupation, because whatever the reasons for it, you cannot occupy a people without visiting cruelties upon them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But for me, the main question isn’t necessarily the badness of the situation, which is incontestable. It&#8217;s how the hell do we end this? And all these complications that I was mentioning earlier, that&#8217;s the stuff that has to be accounted for if there&#8217;s any hope of a way forward.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We are sitting here asking ourselves why we don&#8217;t have a workable solution, while we exclude one of the two significant parties, and I guess my politics would say the most significant party, because that&#8217;s just where I come from in terms of the oppressed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How can you decide what is going to be the solution when every night when I watch reports from the region, I can name only one person who is of Palestinian heritage, who I regularly see articulate a solution or an idea? How do we get to a solution when our journals, our newspapers, our literature that dominate the conversation is not just devoid of Palestinian perspectives, but it&#8217;s devoid of Palestinians themselves?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We are not having a conversation about solutions because we&#8217;ve basically prevented a whole group of people from entering into the frame. And so it&#8217;s like we&#8217;re putting the cart before the horse. We&#8217;re frustrated that we don&#8217;t have a solution, but we&#8217;re not actually talking to somebody.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I agree that our moral imagination needs to extend in both directions as far as possible. I understand writing this as a kind of corrective, feeling like there was a lack of empathy for the Palestinian experience because their story hasn&#8217;t been told enough, hasn&#8217;t been represented enough. I can understand that, I really can. And if I&#8217;m being honest, I think if I went there and saw the suffering firsthand, all of this would feel a whole lot less abstract to me and it would hit differently. And I don&#8217;t know how that would change how I think about it —</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So when are you going to go, Sean?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a fair question, and the only honest answer is I don’t know.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You should go. I know it&#8217;s hard. And look, I&#8217;m putting you on the spot, but it was extremely hard. First of all, you are a journalist. That&#8217;s the first thing. That&#8217;s my first case for you going. The second case is this is being done in your name. And we&#8217;re going to pay for it. We&#8217;re going to pay for it one way or the other. We will pay for this. We will pay for this.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">God, now I think it&#8217;s your responsibility to go. I&#8217;m sorry, but I really do believe that. I really do believe that because you are someone who is obviously curious, obviously wants to know things. And the reason why I&#8217;m pushing you is because that vague sense of injustice is exactly what I had. That is exactly how I felt, man.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I’ll push you a little on that because it runs in both directions. If I went to Israel and toured the villages that were plundered on October 7, I&#8217;d feel this same kind of indignation and rage.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You should, though. You should see that, too. I don’t think those feelings are contrary.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No, I don&#8217;t mean to say they&#8217;re contrary. I&#8217;m just saying I would still be left feeling the sense of hopelessness at the tragedy of it all.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think you would know more, though. I think you would know more. You sound like me. This is what I thought. Even on the eve of the trip, I was like, &#8220;Boy, this is going to be really complicated.&#8221; I thought the morality of it would be complicated. And there&#8217;s a reason why I began that chapter in [World Holocaust Remembrance Center] Yad Vashem, and it is because the fact of existential violence and industrial genocide brought to the Jewish people of this world is a very, very real thing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it&#8217;s like, how do you confront that and reconcile that with Israel? Because you want that group of people to be okay. You feel like maybe that group of people is entitled to certain things. And I mean that in the best kind of way. They&#8217;re entitled to a kind of safety, given what happened to them. You feel deep, deep sympathy. And so before I went, I was like, &#8220;Wow, this is going to be morally dicey.&#8221; </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think you should go. I&#8217;m not even saying you&#8217;re going to agree with me. I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re going to end up where I ended up, but I think you should go.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Do you think both sides of this conflict can tell a story about it that makes them right and the other side wrong? Because there are so many victims and perpetrators on both sides, because the cycle of violence and retaliation stretches back so far.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don&#8217;t think it stretches back that far. It&#8217;s 1948. It&#8217;s not even 100 years. I mean, I interviewed people that were very much alive in 1948, so I don&#8217;t even think it&#8217;s back that far. I think that when we say things like that, no disrespect, but I think we say things like that to make it harder than it actually is. It&#8217;s a lifetime that is not even over yet. And what I would say is my opposition to apartheid, to segregation, to oppression, does not emanate from a belief in the hypermorality of the oppressed or even the morality of the oppressed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The civil rights movement kind of fooled us with this because it was kind of a morality play and it was a very successful strategy. But whether Martin Luther King was nonviolent or not, segregation was wrong. Even when Malcolm X was yelling “by any means necessary,” segregation was still wrong. It was still wrong. So for me, it&#8217;s not even a matter of sides being right. The system that governs both sides is wrong.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I remember once hearing you talk about the vulgarities of punditry. Pundits are not in the truth-seeking business. Pundits make pronouncements. That&#8217;s the whole stupid, mindless game. But you&#8217;re not like that. You have never been like that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One reason I retreated into podcasting is that I don&#8217;t feel that pressure to pronounce in that way, and even doing it in a serious way for me felt futile. But I don&#8217;t have your stature and I don&#8217;t have your reach, so it&#8217;s different for you, I imagine. Do you think you can make a real difference here? Or is that not even part of the calculus?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I needed to write what I saw. This is uncomfortable to say, but I think this moment matters. I was talking to a good friend yesterday, a colleague, a very intelligent and sharp young writer. And we were actually sitting around a table. It was a Muslim woman and another writer there, and we were all in sympathy in terms of our politics. And she&#8217;s making the point that this thing that&#8217;s happening right now, it actually matters, it&#8217;s making a difference. And I was saying, I want out.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m doing this book tour and then I&#8217;m out of here, man. I&#8217;m going back to my French studies. I&#8217;m out. And I&#8217;m not out because I&#8217;m scared to say what I want to say. I&#8217;m not out because of the heat. I am out because it just feels unnatural. And part of it feels unnatural because I&#8217;m not Palestinian, but it also feels contrary to writing, which is always seeking, always trying to learn, always trying to figure it out, always asking questions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So when you&#8217;re making these pronouncements, as I admit I am now, you wonder, am I actually betraying the craft? Should I have just written a book, put it out, and be done with it? There&#8217;s always that voice in the back of your mind. But when I was over there, man, what they said to me over and over again was, “Tell them what you saw.”</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Sean Illing</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I come on this show every week and I praise the virtues of doubt and uncertainty and I believe in that. But refusing to describe things simply and clearly can become a kind of moral and intellectual crime. You&#8217;re right about that. And I still think sometimes things really are complicated and not so neat and maybe the challenge of being a writer and or just a human being is being honest and wise enough to know the difference. But it is hard sometimes, and I do think this situation is complicated, and it’s also true that sometimes withholding moral judgment can be its own kind of cowardice.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Ta-Nehisi Coates</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. And again, I just want to take it back. When that day comes, when the Palestinians are back in the frame, when they’re invited to tell their own stories, when they’re invited to take their place at the table, I have no doubt that what will come out of that will be quite complicated.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">South Africa&#8217;s complicated. They defeated apartheid, but did they change the basic economic arrangements? My understanding is not as much as a lot of people would&#8217;ve wished. Better than apartheid, but it&#8217;s not done. It is indeed quite complicated. The victory is indeed quite complicated, but the morality of apartheid is not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What is hard for me is I&#8217;ve been on a couple of shows now where I&#8217;ve had some debate about this with people, and they never challenge the fact of what&#8217;s going on. So when I say half the population is enshrined at the highest level of citizenship and everyone else is something less, they don&#8217;t say, “Ta-Nehisi, that&#8217;s not true.” But perhaps this is just where I sit. It&#8217;s like when your parents grew up in Jim Crow, when they were born in the Jim Crow, that is an immediate no-go. I feel like I don&#8217;t know what comes after this, but that is wrong. That&#8217;s wrong. You know what I mean? What is after that might be quite complicated and quite hard, but that is not the answer at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m sitting in a cave in the South Hebron Hills [in the West Bank] with a group of people, and they&#8217;re telling me about their fears of being evicted out of a cave, man. When I look at — &#8220;Hey, that&#8217;s complicated&#8221; — when I know full well it&#8217;s not. What to do about it is probably complicated. But you begin from the basis that this is wrong and the very difficult work of figuring it out can proceed after that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/ta-nehisi-coates-on-complexity-clarity-and-truth/id1081584611?i=1000672997115"><em>Listen to the rest of the conversation</em></a><em> and be sure to follow</em> <a href="https://www.vox.com/thegrayarea">The Gray Area</a><em> on</em><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-gray-area-with-sean-illing/id1081584611"><em> Apple Podcasts</em></a><em>,</em><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/6NOJ6IkTb2GWMj1RpmtnxP"><em> Spotify</em></a><em>,</em><a href="https://www.pandora.com/podcast/the-gray-area-with-sean-illing/PC:30793"><em> Pandora</em></a><em>, or wherever you listen to podcasts.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
