<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-07-22T15:09:51Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Oshan Jarow</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence isn’t a good argument for basic income]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/361749/universal-basic-income-sam-altman-open-ai-study" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361749</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T13:49:21Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-22T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Automation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future of Work" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Programs" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re flooded by guaranteed income pilot experiments that offer some promising results, but don’t seem to be moving us any closer to actual federal policy. Yet findings published today from the largest randomized basic income experiment in the US to date, backed by Sam Altman and OpenAI, should get your notice. The study, held from [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-640351099.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/magazine/2022/10/24/universal-basic-income/">flooded</a> by guaranteed income pilot experiments that offer some promising results, but <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/21/23882353/child-poverty-expanded-child-tax-credit-census-welfare-inflation-economy-data">don’t seem</a> to be moving us any closer to actual federal policy. Yet findings published today from the largest randomized basic income experiment in the US to date, backed by Sam Altman and OpenAI, should get your notice.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The study, held from November 2020 through October 2023, gave 1,000 recipients $1,000 per month, no strings attached. It’s one of the biggest and longest trials ever run on direct cash giving. Many other <a href="https://guaranteedincome.us/">basic income pilots</a> have given people $500 or less, and rarely for more than a year or two.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the study was run by a group of academics, it was <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/blog/basic-income">set in motion</a> by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman. For years, Altman has been publicly worrying that basic income will become necessary as AI eliminates traditional jobs while creating huge stockpiles of wealth held by a few. “If public policy doesn’t adapt accordingly, most people will end up worse off than they are today,” <a href="https://moores.samaltman.com/">he wrote</a> in 2021. (Disclosure: Vox Media is one of several publishers that have signed partnership agreements with OpenAI. Our reporting remains editorially independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Altman isn’t alone. Many major figures in the tech world, from <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/elon-musk-universal-basic-income-ubi-ai-automation-unemployment-quotes-2024-6">Elon Musk</a> to the “godfather of AI,” <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnd607ekl99o">Geoffrey Hinton</a>, believe AI will usher a wave of technological unemployment, and basic income will become necessary to keep us all afloat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On this, I’m conflicted. In general, unconditional cash can be <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23965898/child-poverty-expanded-child-tax-credit-economy-welfare-phase-ins">an effective anti-poverty policy</a>, but the extensive list of small experiments and accumulating evidence doesn’t seem to be furthering the case of basic income to becoming a reality. So maybe any press is good press, and all the attention AI leaders are bringing to basic income will help it along. Spreading the fear of AI stealing all our jobs seems to garner much more enthusiasm for basic income than continually <a href="https://www.economicpossibility.org/reports/basic-income">pointing at the evidence</a>. (Just look at Andrew Yang’s<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/10/18/20919322/basic-income-freedom-dividend-andrew-yang-automation"> 2020 presidential campaign</a>, which centered on universal basic income as a response to automation.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But hitching <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/17/15364546/universal-basic-income-review-stern-murray-automation">the case for basic income</a> to fears of rapid AI progress makes it far more vulnerable than it needs to be. If there’s no great wave of AI-driven unemployment, if the AI <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-18/goldman-s-top-stock-analyst-is-waiting-for-ai-bubble-to-burst">bubble bursts</a> and turns out to be <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/7/18/23794187/telephone-operator-switchboard-automation-att-feigenbaum-gross">hardly any different</a> than cycles of innovation and technological unemployment in the past, support for basic income would fall, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet the arguments for some kind of basic income are strong, no matter what happens with AI. There could be absolutely no further progress, AI could come to a complete and eternal standstill, and the case for basic income would remain as strong as ever: unconditional cash can be a simple and flexible way to style income-support policies that actually reach everyone in need (at the trade-off of higher taxes).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The basic income movement might be better off severing ties with speculations about AI altogether. Then, the conversation could focus on what basic income can actually be: an effective anti-poverty tool that would neither stave off dystopia nor usher in a leisurely paradise, but instead, just <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/10/13/23914745/basic-income-radical-economy-poverty-capitalism-taxes">a world with less poverty</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">News from the largest randomized study of basic income in the US to date</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many cash transfer advocates feel that the movement is <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/4/28/23044957/ubi-guaranteed-income-baltimore-new-york-mississippi">overdue to graduate</a> from research to actual policy. But the “Unconditional Income Study,” as this three-year endeavor by the nonprofit <a href="https://www.openresearchlab.org/approach">OpenResearch</a> has been dubbed, added some welcome substance to the otherwise slim pile of research on big cash transfers over long periods of time. (OpenResearch is not affiliated directly with OpenAI, but it grew out of the tech accelerator Y Combinator when Altman ran it, and has received a combined $24 million from Altman and OpenAI’s nonprofit organization.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The study gave out monthly checks to people between the ages of 21 and 40 living in Texas and Illinois. To qualify, their 2019 household income had to be less than 300 percent of the federal poverty line: that would mean $77,250 for a <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/topics/poverty-economic-mobility/poverty-guidelines/prior-hhs-poverty-guidelines-federal-register-references/2019-poverty-guidelines">family of four</a>, or $37,470 for an individual. The average participant’s household income in 2019 was about $30,000. One thousand people were randomized into the treatment group and received the full $1,000 per month, while another 2,000 were part of a control group that got $50 per month.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The results are coming out in batches, with <a href="https://www.openresearchlab.org/studies/unconditional-cash-study/study">two papers</a> out today — one on <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w32719">employment effects</a> and another on <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w32711">health outcomes</a> — and another on consumption still in the works. So far, the results are kind of scrambled, refusing to neatly fit into any particular view on basic income.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recipients spent an average of $310 more per month, mostly on housing, food, and car expenses. Overall, however, their incomes fell by about $125 per month, excluding the transfers.<strong> </strong>The drop in earnings was largely driven by people choosing to work a little less (since the transfers meant they still came out ahead). In total, labor market participation declined by 2 percent, cashing out as working about 1.3 hours less per week, or roughly eight fewer days of work over the course of a year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At first glance, this finding is somewhat at odds with <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w24337">other basic income experiments</a> in the US, and challenges <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23965898/child-poverty-expanded-child-tax-credit-economy-welfare-phase-ins">the narrative advocates</a> have been pushing that unconditional cash won’t make people choose less work. Sometimes, maybe it will. But eight fewer days of work per year doesn’t exactly look like the doomsday scenario of everyone choosing to live out their remaining days on welfare, <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2265291">surfing</a>, or playing video games on the taxpayer’s dime.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The cash’s impact on health was a little more straightforward: it didn’t seem to do much. Despite detailed data, including blood samples from some participants and nutritional intake, “We find essentially no evidence of improvements in physical health due to the transfers,” the paper states, “and can rule out even small improvements.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There were short-lived improvements in mental health, mostly through reductions in stress. But they faded by the end of the first year. Recipients also showed a major increase in food security during year one, which also faded by the second year. If there was any silver lining in the paper on health, it was that recipients went to hospitals, doctors, and dentists more often, and spent about $20 more per month on medical care as a result of the transfer, which the authors note could translate into indirect benefits in the long term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The appeal of cash transfers lies in the freedom that they give beneficiaries to make their own choices about what type of consumption to prioritize,” the authors conclude. “However, the nature of that freedom means that cash transfers are a blunt instrument for improving health and reducing health disparities specifically.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The results suggest that policymakers interested in improving particular health outcomes might be better off pursuing more targeted interventions, like expanding Medicaid eligibility, reducing prescription drug costs, or making it easier to make primary care appointments. Targeting health directly, in other words, rather than simple cash.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the researchers argue, “if policymakers seek to reduce poverty and improve the well-being of low-income groups more generally, cash transfers could still represent an important option, even if they do not improve health outcomes in the near term.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Basic income restored a little bit of capitalism’s forgotten promise: the freedom to choose more leisure time</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the most controversial and politically <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2022/01/04/manchin-wont-support-enhanced-child-tax-credit-without-work-requirement.html">charged</a> parts of the basic income debate is how it would affect work. Among critical economists and policy wonks, the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/20/opinion/child-tax-credit-basic-income.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">concern</a> isn’t that we’ll need basic income because there won’t be any jobs left after AI, but that basic income could itself be the thing that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/02/opinion/child-allowance-credit-romney.html">wipes away</a> our desire to work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether these results support that fear depends on how deeply you read into the details. The results clearly show that people do work a little less. But going a bit deeper, the employment effects were concentrated among young, single parents. Does the option for single parents to choose an extra eight days off per year constitute a policy failure — or success?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The project also captured pretty detailed time-use data, letting researchers figure out where recipients were re-allocating their newly chosen time away from work. Though 1,000 people obviously made a variety of choices over the course of three years, the dominant trade was clearly toward more leisure time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/24065976/economists-post-scarcity-abundance-industrial-revolution-socialism-capitalism">previously written</a> about how, until recently, Americans across the political spectrum used to see the promise of capitalism as exactly that: delivering people the choice of cashing in economic progress for more leisure time. Getting an economic boost and subsequently choosing to work a little less was not seen as a policy failure, but <a href="https://www.bostonreview.net/articles/mike-konczal-tk/">the whole point</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“But for decades, workers haven’t even been getting that choice because, for the most part, productivity growth has ended up as higher profits and more inequality,” sociologist Aaron Benanav <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/2023/10/10/23895776/four-day-workweek-leisure-progress-labor-economy-utopia-capitalism-burnout-worker-satisfaction">told me last year</a>. “It takes a political movement to cash that out in terms of a reduced workweek.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Apparently, a generous basic income can at least help nudge that choice back into workers’ lives. After getting an extra $1,000, recipients effectively traded in $125 to get five-and-a-half more hours per month outside of work.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Interviews with participants paint a much brighter picture than the numbers</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to the survey data, OpenResearch held voluntary interviews with participants after the transfers ended to hear more about their experiences. Though only nine were recorded, I kept hearing variations on a theme that wasn’t captured in the statistics. (All names were changed by OpenResearch to protect the identities of participants.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Alina, a single mom living in Chicago, put it: “My whole mind kinda began to shift &#8230; I had to stop myself so that I could have the mental mind shift, the paradigm shift to say, ok, we can actually engage in system planning.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or Celene, who lived with her ex-wife and their kids in a friend’s basement before the transfers helped them get their own home: “It helped my mind clear a little bit because I didn’t feel like as much of a failure.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or Dominic, who lost his job during the pandemic: “The biggest thing it did was allow me a time of peace of mind so I could explore what I really wanted out of life.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Everyone seemed to mention how getting unconditional cash was literally changing their minds for the better.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The mechanism doesn’t have to be all that mysterious. Everyone faces their own challenges, and people with low incomes especially so. But woven through all the differences is at least one shared consequence: stress. And we already know that stress can literally warp the mind, <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/24065976/economists-post-scarcity-abundance-industrial-revolution-socialism-capitalism">especially around scarcity</a>. Giving people cash comes with the flexibility to address whatever sources of stress are loudest in their lives, freeing up the mind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, according to the numbers, the sharp reductions in stress that recipients had in the first year didn’t last, even though they shared these powerful stories after the third year. Which raises an interesting tension: Why is there such a big difference between the extremely positive stories that people are telling about their experiences, and the story that the numbers tell, which basically amounts to a shrug?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of it could be sampling bias: since the interviews were voluntary, maybe only people who had powerful and positive experiences opted in to the voluntary interviews to talk more about them. More broadly, though, there are parts of the human experience —&nbsp;and more specifically, the experience of being a participant in a basic income experiment — that statistics either fail to capture, or even conceal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I spoke with Elizabeth Rhodes, who has a joint doctorate in social work and political science, and directed the study for OpenResearch, she explained that all the variation across how people used the money, or what a “good outcome” actually is based on someone’s particular circumstances, made them difficult to capture in top-line statistics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One person might wind up finding <a href="https://www.economicpossibility.org/insights/stockton-basic-income-employment">better work and taking on more hours</a> thanks to the cash, while another might scale back their hours to spend more time with their kids. Both cases can be good outcomes to the individuals involved, but “as an average treatment effect, where one person worked a lot more, while another worked less, it all kind of averages out.” she said.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">We should insulate the case for basic income from any potential AI bubbles</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite receiving funding from much of the tech world where talk of AI is everywhere, none of the papers published from the Unconditional Income Study mentioned AI at all. That’s a good thing, because as I mentioned earlier, we should insulate the case for basic income from the volatility and unknowns of AI.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Against the backdrop of all the “changing the world as we know it” talk, a number of analysts are beginning to think the AI <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-18/goldman-s-top-stock-analyst-is-waiting-for-ai-bubble-to-burst">bubble</a> is already <a href="https://www.ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2024/7/9/the-ai-summer">beginning</a> to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/apr/13/from-boom-to-burst-the-ai-bubble-is-only-heading-in-one-direction">burst</a>. Maybe it will, and then it’ll inflate again. And maybe one of these go-rounds will actually lead to changes that go beyond the cycles of innovation and technological unemployment <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/7/18/23794187/telephone-operator-switchboard-automation-att-feigenbaum-gross">we’ve weathered for centuries</a>. Or maybe they won’t. Who knows!</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The strongest arguments for unconditional income don’t need to rest on speculation. We have a <a href="https://basicincome.stanford.edu/research/ubi-visualization/">lot of evidence</a>. We have real-world experience from <a href="https://guaranteedincome.us/">a ton of pilot experiments</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23965898/child-poverty-expanded-child-tax-credit-economy-welfare-phase-ins">lapsed national policies</a>. And we already have <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23792854/poverty-mortality-study-public-health-antipoverty-america-deaths-poor-life-expectancy">an urgent need</a> for better anti-poverty policies, even if there wasn’t an iota more of AI development.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Breaking the link between basic income and automation would also force us to consider what — if not UBI — actually would be a good policy response to major technological unemployment. Because if we really do all lose our jobs to AI, $12,000 per year isn’t going to cushion the blow much. This is a persistent confusion in debate around basic income: if you’re talking about unconditionally giving people enough to live on indefinitely, you’re either imagining a society of monks, that everyone lives in rural West Virginia, or you aren’t actually talking about basic income at all, at least as it exists in any viable form.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The average living wage for a family of four in the US is about $104,000 per year, according to the MIT <a href="https://livingwage.mit.edu/articles/103-new-data-posted-2023-living-wage-calculator#:~:text=An%20analysis%20of%20the%20living,in%20the%20United%20States%20is">Living Wage calculator</a>. Even if a guaranteed income on the scale of this study gave the full amount to children (which most proposals do not), the same family would only get $48,000 per year, less than half the living wage. There is no realistic guaranteed income proposal that could serve as a substitute for wages altogether.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Altman himself <a href="https://moores.samaltman.com/">has argued</a> for something more nuanced in the past: taxes on AI companies and land values that feed into a <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/projects/social-wealth-fund/">social wealth fund</a> where every citizen holds an equal share, receiving a dividend that rises or falls with the fund value.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s basically a version of UBI that’s styled away from guaranteeing an end to poverty, and toward being able to adapt to <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24108787/ai-economic-growth-explosive-automation">runaway economic growth</a>. In addition, maybe we’ll need to consider <a href="https://pavlina-tcherneva.net/the-case-for-a-job-guarantee/">job guarantees</a>. Or maybe compulsory employment is an iron cage we’ll finally break by more deeply <a href="https://www.dissentmagazine.org/article/a-world-without-work/">democratizing</a> the economy, and whatever diminishing pools of work remain.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Either way, basic income advocates are left with a choice. You can welcome fears around AI as an incredibly effective marketing tool to spread awareness for basic income, and then try to jiu-jitsu that attention toward sturdier motivations, like <a href="https://jainfamilyinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/pdf/reweaving-the-safety-net-12.15.20.pdf">more effectively reducing poverty</a> than a patchwork of means-tested programs. Or, like me, you can try shouting into the void that we shouldn’t associate basic income and automation in the first place, since it sets the case for unconditional cash on shaky foundations, while there’s <a href="https://www.economicpossibility.org/reports/basic-income">an empirically sturdy basis</a> already established.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With the OpenResearch studies, that basis continues to grow. Whether or not that’ll lead to any policy breakthroughs before AI flops, fades into being just another new technology that shifts things around for a bit, or really does transform the economy, who knows?</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[With Biden out of the election, can US foreign policy be Trump-proofed?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/361768/2024-election-biden-foreign-policy-trump-china-ukraine-russia" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361768</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T15:09:51Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-22T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="China" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia-Ukraine war" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his 1924 novel The Magic Mountain, the German writer Thomas Mann used an idyllic alpine sanatorium as a metaphor for the torpor and self-delusion of the European elite in the years leading up to the cataclysm of World War I.&#160; I couldn’t help but think about the book a little while attending this year’s [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kelly, on the left in a red dress, speaks with Blinken, on the right in a dark suit. Both are seated and holding microphones." data-caption="NPR host Mary Louise Kelly, left, interviews Secretary of State Antony Blinken at the Aspen Security Forum on July 19. | Courtesy of the Aspen Institute" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of the Aspen Institute" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/ASF_D_Bayer.7.19.24.105.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>NPR host Mary Louise Kelly, left, interviews Secretary of State Antony Blinken at the Aspen Security Forum on July 19. | Courtesy of the Aspen Institute</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In his 1924 novel <em>The Magic Mountain</em>, the German writer Thomas Mann used an idyllic alpine sanatorium as a metaphor for the torpor and self-delusion of the European elite in the years leading up to the cataclysm of World War I.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I couldn’t help but think about the book a little while attending this year’s <a href="https://www.aspensecurityforum.org/">Aspen Security Forum</a>, which was held in the tony Colorado mountain town during one of the busiest and most destabilizing news weeks in recent memory, one that&nbsp;included the attempted assassination of former President Donald Trump, the selection of arch-populist Sen. J.D. Vance as Trump’s running mate, and polls showing the <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-biden">increasing likelihood</a> that Trump will return to office.<strong> </strong>It took place just <em>before </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361888/biden-drops-out-kamala-harris-endorsement-dnc-democratic-nominee">President Joe Biden dropped out of the race</a>, though questions about the future of the ticket were a constant backdrop to the conference. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike Mann’s somnambulant Europeans, of course, the international government officials, military officers, and corporate executives attending the annual gathering in the Rockies weren’t just there for their health and the mountain air, but for discussions on a range of pressing security topics from Gaza and Ukraine to the militarization of space and the role of AI in war.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, as attendees watched the sessions with one eye on their iPhones to keep up with developments from the Republican National Convention in Milwaukee, it was hard to avoid the assessment that the future trajectory of many of the issues under discussion hinges significantly on the election’s outcome in November — an election that, with Biden out, is more uncertain than ever before. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Trump contrast</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">President Biden had premised his case for reelection significantly on the <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/abc-news-anchor-george-stephanopoulos-exclusive-interview-biden/story?id=111695695">sort of accomplishments</a> promoted and celebrated at gatherings like Aspen: the expansion of NATO, the multilateral response to the invasion of Ukraine, and the building of a network of alliances in the Pacific to counter China. Vice President Kamala Harris enters the race with less foreign policy experience than Biden, though she <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">has been involved</a> in the administration’s diplomatic efforts in the Middle East and Central America, and would presumably draw her circle of advisers from either Biden’s current team or other names that Aspen attendees and speakers are very familiar with. A major shift from Biden’s approach in Europe, China, and the Middle East seems unlikely with a Harris presidency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, by contrast, has promised to quickly end the war in Ukraine — a pledge celebrated on placards waved in Milwaukee — most likely by pressuring Kyiv to negotiate away territory to Moscow. He is also a longtime skeptic of European security alliances, including NATO, and recently suggested Taiwan <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/jul/17/donald-trump-taiwan-pay-us-defence-china-national-convention">should “pay us for defense” </a>against an invasion by China, which sent the stock price of the island’s vital semiconductor manufacturers <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/tsmc-shares-fall-more-than-2-after-trump-says-taiwan-should-pay-defence-2024-07-17/">falling</a>. Vance, Trump’s new running mate, is one of Congress’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360283/jd-vance-trump-vp-vice-president-authoritarian">leading skeptics</a> of efforts to defend the “liberal international order,” particularly when it comes to the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Joe Biden dropped out of the 2024 race. Catch up on this story.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden surrendered to pressure from top Democrats and campaign donors who urged him to step aside amid concerns over his age and low polling numbers against Donald Trump.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">What happens now?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out">What happens to Biden’s campaign money? </a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How did Democrats get here?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">What can we learn from incumbents who stepped aside</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From the stage in Aspen, Sen. Dan Sullivan (R-AK) pushed back on the idea that the GOP has taken an isolationist turn, describing the <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/documents/2024-republican-party-platform">recently adopted Republican platform</a> as a “Reaganesque peace-through-strength” document that emphasizes building the US defense industry and modernizing the military.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Sen. Chris Coons (D-DE), a close ally of Biden, told me on the sidelines of the conference on Thursday (in between media appearances discussing Biden’s then-undetermined fate)<strong> </strong>that “in his time as president, Trump showed an unevenness and erratic nature in his foreign policy that can make it really hard to persuade our close and trusted allies that we were still a reliable partner.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While administration officials and allies abroad have been discussing what can be done to Trump-proof US foreign policy, there is a limit to those efforts. Even as he touted the Biden administration’s record on support for Ukraine and work to strengthen NATO, Secretary of State Antony Blinken conceded, “Every administration has an opportunity to set its policies. We can’t lock in the future.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Keep calm and carry on</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, the foreign officials who spoke at the conference refused to take the bait when asked if they were concerned about Trump’s return. Ukrainian Defense Minister Rustem Umerov, whose country is likely to be the one most directly impacted by the outcome of the election, told the Aspen audience, “We believe in American leadership and we believe that the American people want their partners and allies to be strong as well &#8230; Whatever will be the outcome, we’ll work with America.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There was a sense from several officials that a Trump presidency was a movie they’d seen before, and they were more prepared for it this time. Singapore Defense Minister Ng Eng Hen told the crowd, “I would remind you that we worked with the Trump administration for meetings in Singapore” — likely a reference to the 2018 summit between the former president and North Korean leader Kim Jong Un. “He was very happy with Singapore because we have a trade surplus with you … I’m not so concerned.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even less concerned about a new Republican administration were representatives of the defense and technology industries — also heavily represented at Aspen.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think it could potentially be positive to have a Trump administration for a tech company trying to work with” the Department of Defense, said Tara Dougherty, CEO of the defense software company Govini. “They’re already talking about <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/07/16/trump-ai-executive-order-regulations-military/">Manhattan Projects for [artificial intelligence]</a> which shows they’re serious about the development and adoption of AI for military purposes.” She added that in Vance, Trump had chosen “a running mate who comes from this space.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As with last week’s NATO summit, attendees frequently argued that one of Trump’s main complaints about US allies — that they free-ride on American security guarantees and don’t pay for their own defense — is less applicable today than it was during his term, with defense budgets increasing globally in the wake of the war in Ukraine and concerns about China’s growing power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is a different Europe than the Europe we complained about for years,” said Gen. Christopher Cavoli, commander of the US military’s Europe Command. “This is a Europe that recognizes what the burden is and that it’s got to be shared &#8230; This is exactly the moment when American interests will be advanced most by continued participation” in Europe’s defense.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coming down the mountain</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cavoli’s remarks (he didn’t specifically refer to Trump or the election) were met with applause in a room that didn’t need much convincing of the value of America’s global commitments. But Vance would likely argue that’s precisely the problem.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a <a href="https://www.vance.senate.gov/press-releases/senator-vance-delivers-a-wake-up-call-to-munich-security-conference/">speech at this year’s Munich Security Conference</a>, a gathering that draws a similar crowd to Aspen, the now-VP candidate described his view that continued military support to Ukraine is a dead end as representing “the majority of American public opinion, even though I don’t represent the majority of opinion of senators who come to Munich.” (For what it’s worth, <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2024/05/08/views-of-ukraine-and-u-s-involvement-with-the-russia-ukraine-war/">recent polls</a> show a majority of Americans still support continuing or increasing aid to Ukraine, though there’s a stark partisan divide.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Speaking to Vox, Coons dismissed the notion that an internationalist foreign policy might be a tough sell to voters. “The strength of our alliances around the world have been the linchpins of our security and our prosperity for decades,” he said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But on stage, former Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice, an exemplar of a previous generation of globally-focused Republicans who have now all but vanished, was a bit contrite. “Those of us who were internationalists and believed in globalization” didn’t always take into account the impact it would have on some American communities, she said. “There are unemployed coal miners and unemployed steelworkers and kids who can’t get a decent education who really do wonder why we are doing what we’re doing internationally.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At gatherings like Aspen, there’s always discussion about the importance of winning over international partners to American foreign policy priorities. Increasingly, there’s a sense in these conversations that America itself also has to be won over, whoever is at the top of the Democratic ticket. But as anyone who has read Mann’s book knows, the Magic Mountain can be a tough place to get down from.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Harris isn’t her party’s best candidate. Biden was still right to endorse her.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362033/biden-drop-out-endorse-harris-open-convention" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362033</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T14:40:25Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-22T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Joe Biden just relinquished his claim on the Democratic nomination and handed it to Vice President Kamala Harris. Since his disastrous debate performance last month, it has been clear that Biden could best prevent Donald Trump from retaking power by withdrawing from the presidential race. More than 70 percent of voters consider Biden unfit [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Up close photo of Kamala Harris smiling widely." data-caption="US Vice President Kamala Harris visits Smize &amp; Dream Ice Cream shop on July 19, 2024, in Washington, DC." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2162039073.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>US Vice President Kamala Harris visits Smize &amp; Dream Ice Cream shop on July 19, 2024, in Washington, DC.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden just <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">relinquished his claim</a> on the Democratic nomination and handed it to Vice President Kamala Harris.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">disastrous debate performance</a> last month, it has been clear that Biden could best prevent Donald Trump from retaking power by <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">withdrawing from the presidential race.</a> More <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/03/us/politics/poll-debate-biden-trump.html">than 70 percent</a> of voters consider Biden unfit to seek another term in office. His poll numbers in swing states have <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/show/new-polls-show-biden-slipping-further-behind-trump-in-critical-swing-states">fallen sharply</a> in recent weeks, while the Democrats’ <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/rnc-trump-speech-biden-election-2024/card/polling-report-shows-biden-losses-extending-beyond-swing-states-t3KKgzxLEFQqNT5WuCtI">internal data</a> has shown Trump only narrowly trailing in blue states such as Minnesota, New Mexico, and New Jersey.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plenty of candidates in American history have closed larger polling gaps than Biden’s in a campaign’s last four months. But in recent weeks, the president <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/359160/biden-abc-news-interview-drop-out">repeatedly</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360277/biden-nato-press-conference-democrats">demonstrated</a> a gross inability to effectively communicate, with each public performance generating multiple misstatements or brain freezes that reinforced the public’s doubts about his cognitive functioning.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden was undoubtedly right to step aside, but the wisdom of his decision to immediately endorse Harris — rather than clearing the way for a more open competition for the nomination at next month’s convention — is less clear.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, the vice president has many liabilities as a candidate, and the Democrats boast multiple popular swing-state governors whose hypothetical nomination might ease the party’s path to an Electoral College majority. Given the stakes of keeping Trump out of power, Democratic convention delegates may have been justified in picking whichever ticket seemed most likely to bring victory in November.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, I think Biden made the right call. If there were some mechanism for instantly achieving party unity around nominating Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer or Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro — or one of the party’s other top-tier talents — then Democrats would be wise to take it. But no such mechanism exists.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Failing to rally around Harris would have left Democrats bereft of a nominee until late August, giving Trump a month to campaign unopposed. And the vice president would have been highly likely to prevail at that convention anyway, given her official status as Biden’s heir apparent and the democratic legitimacy that comes with it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this point, it is unlikely that the most promising candidates on the Democratic bench would have chosen to compete, given the risks of alienating key constituencies within the party and the widespread sense that Republicans will be favored to win in November, irrespective of whom the Democrats nominate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden made a mistake in seeking a second term. And he made another by refusing to bow out swiftly once the debate made his unfitness plain. But on Sunday, he did the best he could to reverse some of the damage. It’s now incumbent on Harris — and all other Democrats — to put together a campaign strong enough to reverse the rest.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The (reasonable but probably wrong) case against Kamala</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before examining why endorsing Harris was (probably) the right call, it’s worth taking stock of the case for an open convention.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That argument boils down to three fundamental claims: 1) Harris is not an especially strong candidate, 2) nominating the vice president prevents Democrats from getting a clean break from Biden’s vulnerabilities, and 3) the party has several strong alternative candidates.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All these claims seem right to me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris currently has a net disapproval rating of <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">roughly negative 12 percent.</a> And her electoral track record is unimpressive.&nbsp; In her first <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/California_Attorney_General_election,_2010">statewide election in 2010</a>, Harris beat a Republican in the race for California attorney general by less than 1 percentage point (two years earlier, Barack Obama had <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2008_United_States_presidential_election_in_California">bested John McCain</a> by more than 23 points in that state). In 2020, Harris began her run for the Democratic nomination with <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/kamala-harris-more-billionaire-donors-than-any-other-democratic-candidate-2019-11">strong fundraising</a> and an <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/02/09/politics/kamala-harris-first-good-month-poll-of-the-week/index.html">early surge in the polls</a>. Yet her campaign collapsed before the primary’s first ballots were cast.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further, as a Californian whose Senate <a href="https://voteview.com/person/41701/kamala-devi-harris">voting record</a> put her on the left wing of her caucus, Harris is not an ideal figurehead for a party anxious to appeal to Trump-curious Midwesterners.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket">Who could be on Harris&#8217;s running mate?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Making matters worse, Harris’s candidacy did <a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">not fall out of a coconut tree.</a> It exists in the context of her current boss’s unpopularity and conspicuous cognitive decline. For many voters, Biden has become a byword for inflation and infirmity. A Democratic nominee with no connection to the Biden administration would have given the party distance from both of these liabilities: They would have faced much less of a compulsion to defend Biden’s record, while confronting few questions about their own hypothetical complicity in <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/joe-biden-age-public-election-campaign-343a47bf">concealing the president’s frailty.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On both these fronts, Harris could find herself saddled with her boss’s baggage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, the Democrats have some formidable politicians on their bench. Pennsylvania’s Josh Shapiro and Michigan’s Gretchen Whitmer both boast <a href="https://www.wlns.com/news/poll-majority-of-michiganders-approve-of-whitmers-performance/">majority</a> <a href="https://www.abc27.com/pennsylvania-politics/josh-shapiro-pennsylvanias-most-popular-governor-at-this-point-in-term-poll/">approval</a> in their critical swing states.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats would likely be better off with one of those governors as their standard-bearer, all else being equal. But this does not mean that the party would have been better off holding a completely open convention.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>An open convention probably would have resulted in Harris’s nomination</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problems with withholding endorsements from Harris and pursuing an open convention are threefold.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, the Democratic Party is poorly positioned to organize and legitimize a contested convention. It has been more than half a century since the Democrats chose a nominee through convention wrangling, rather than purely through the primary process. In that time, the institutional structure of the party has dramatically changed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the mid-20th century, Democratic delegates consisted in no small part of the leaders of trade unions and urban machines — individuals who were directly accountable to mass constituencies. This made it possible for them to credibly speak on behalf of key Democratic voting blocs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, since contested conventions were routine occurrences in American politics at that time, there was a great deal of institutional knowledge about how to broker such competitions and reach consensus.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, by contrast, Democratic delegates are largely volunteers who speak for <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/09/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-jamelle-bouie.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/09/podcasts/transcript-ezra-klein-interviews-jamelle-bouie.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">no one beyond the primary voters</a> in their areas. In this context, a contested convention could be chaotic, and its nominee lacking in democratic legitimacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be sure, anointing Harris is not especially democratic either. She was not elected by primary voters, any more than any other non-Biden Democrat. But the US electorate did vote to make her the president’s heir apparent, and this gives her a source of legitimacy that any other selection would lack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Second, and more importantly, failing to coalesce behind a nominee today would have left Democrats without a standard-bearer for a month. This would inhibit fundraising, at a time when the Trump-Vance ticket is <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/20/fundraising-july-election-trump-biden/">taking in serious cash</a>. And it would mean ceding swing-state airwaves to the Republican message — or else, running exclusively negative advertising — for the next four weeks. This is especially risky in a context where Democrats face the challenge of introducing a new nominee to the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Biden’s default replacement, having been elected to fill in for him in the event of his death or disability, Harris was uniquely capable of becoming her party’s consensus nominee in the absence of a protracted process.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, Harris would have been highly likely to win an open convention, anyway. Before Biden dropped out, South Carolina Rep. Jim Clyburn — a highly influential member of the Congressional Black Caucus (CBC) — let it be known that he would favor Harris were Biden to drop out.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to her uniquely high name recognition, meanwhile, Harris would likely outperform any other individual Democratic candidate in opinion polls. And as such polls, in combination with her title, rendered her the frontrunner for the nomination, various Democratic interest groups would have had an incentive to line up behind her, so as to ensure their influence in the likely Democratic nominee’s hypothetical administration.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Assuming that congressional caucuses, Democratic interest groups, and poll respondents did indeed all indicate their preference for Harris, Democratic delegates would almost certainly have felt compelled to back her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most critically, it seems unlikely that Shapiro, Whitmer, or other top-tier Democratic talents would have entered the fray in any case. For the reasons already stated, any non-Harris candidate would have faced an uphill battle for the nomination. And merely trying to win that nod would have come at the cost of potentially alienating constituencies that they would need to win during a future primary: A white candidate hoping to one day compete in the South Carolina primary might be wise to avoid being the person who tried and failed to block the first African-American vice president from claiming a nomination that was hers to inherit, at least from the perspective of some Black Democratic elected officials.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s more, even if the gamble of challenging Harris paid off initially, the prize would ultimately have been the mixed-blessing of serving as the Democratic nominee in a year when the Republican ticket is favored. We cannot know exactly how polls and betting markets would have shifted had Democrats endorsed Shapiro or Whitmer. But Republicans have long held an advantage over Democrats this cycle <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/511979/neither-party-liked-gop-holds-advantage-issues.aspx#:~:text=GOP%20Holds%20Edge%20for%20Handling%20Americans'%20Top%20Worry&amp;text=Forty%2Dfour%20percent%20say%20the,same%20or%20have%20no%20preference.">on the issues </a>most important to voters, chief of all inflation and immigration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given the balance of risks and benefits here, an ambitious and promising younger Democrat might prefer to sit back and position themselves for 2028 or 2032. At the very least, no swing-state Democrat let word of their interest in potentially running leak in the weeks since Biden’s bad debate.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris may be stronger than she looks</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, although Harris has weaknesses, she is not devoid of political gifts. At 59, she is young by the standards of American politics. She is an able speaker, whose recent appearances have brimmed with more vitality and coherence than either Biden or Trump have mustered in years. Her recent remarks debunking the GOP’s claims of being the party of “unity” were especially effective.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris does have a negative approval rating. But it is nevertheless <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">better than Biden’s</a>. And the public’s disapproval of her is less strongly held. As the political consultant Sarah Longwell <a href="https://x.com/SarahLongwell25/status/1814649334626971982">has reported,</a> voters in focus groups tend to have a negative impression of Harris — but it is just that, an impression, rather than a deep-seated evaluation. They do not know much about her and are aware of that fact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, Harris’s political brand is essentially indistinguishable from Biden’s. Many of her detractors may therefore be simply giving pollsters their views of the president. Those who are actually familiar with Harris, meanwhile, may see her through the lens of her 2020 primary campaign, during which she joined many other Democratic candidates in a bidding war for the allegiance of the party’s left wing. Now that she has been vaulted directly into the general election, Harris has the opportunity to reintroduce herself to the public in a manner tailored to the sensibilities of swing voters by, among other things, leaning into her experience as a <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/kamala-harris-wrote-a-good-book-about">“smart on crime</a>” prosecutor.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, if she can nail her campaign’s rollout, it is possible that Harris would see her numbers significantly improve.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Put all of this together and the case for uniting around Kamala is clear: Democrats can line up behind Biden’s logical successor today, put an end to their party’s internal chaos, and begin the work of rehabilitating Harris’s image — or they can pursue a path that likely ends with the same outcome, only after a month of internal disorganization, discord, and subpar fundraising.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The former isn’t a perfect option, but it was probably the best decision available to the Democrats at this late date. Joe Biden deserves credit for making it.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Who could be Kamala Harris’s VP? The potential list, briefly explained.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362043/kamala-harris-vice-running-mate-democratic-presidential-ticket" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362043</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T13:56:11Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-22T01:38:59Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following President Joe Biden’s exit from the 2024 presidential race, and his endorsement of Vice President Kamala Harris as his choice for the Democratic nominee, one of the next big questions that’s emerged is who could potentially be her running mate. Though Harris is not the nominee yet, Biden’s backing gives her a significant boost [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris, in a dark suit, stands behind a podium with the US presidential seal; she points and smiles. The US flag is behind her." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2161823241.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">Following President Joe Biden’s exit from the 2024 presidential race</a>, and his endorsement of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Vice President Kamala Harris</a> as his choice for the Democratic nominee, one of the next big questions that’s emerged is who could potentially be her running mate. Though Harris is not the nominee yet, Biden’s backing gives her a significant boost ahead of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">other potential contenders</a>, fueling speculation about who else could join the ticket.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Historically, vice presidents have been selected to complement the main candidate. Biden chose Harris because she would bring youth, diversity, and legal experience. And former President Donald Trump chose Vice President Mike Pence because he was a traditional conservative and offered legislative expertise that he didn’t have.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What might Harris look for? Based on that history, there are a few guesses: Her pick could be someone from a purple or red state, who offers geographic diversity given her roots in California. And — to assuage voters who still hold sexist or racist attitudes, as President Barack Obama did with Biden in 2008 — it might be a white man.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Below is a rundown of some of the possible candidates who might be considered — and what they’d bring to the ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159037882_26f6dd.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." title="Gov. Roy Cooper, in a navy suit, speaks from a podium to a large crowd holding Biden-Harris campaign signs." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="North Carolina Gov. Roy Cooper speaks before President Joe Biden at a post-debate campaign rally on June 28, in Raleigh, North Carolina. | Allison Joyce/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Allison Joyce/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Roy Cooper</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Cooper, 67, is the governor of North Carolina, a battleground state that Trump won narrowly in 2020 and 2016 that offers <a href="https://www.ncsbe.gov/about-elections/electoral-college">16 electoral votes</a> (of the 270 needed to win). He’s known for winning repeatedly statewide even as other Democratic candidates have struggled to do the same for roles like the Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s also vetoed Republican bills on abortion and guns, and has strong approval <a href="https://abc11.com/post/2024-elections-could-governor-roy-cooper-replace-president/15011995/">ratings overall</a>. Prior to becoming governor, he served as the state’s attorney general and in the state legislature.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Cooper could help improve Democrats’ chances in a battleground state, though it will still likely be an uphill battle given past contests in North Carolina. He’s also been pretty popular in his role, and has secured backing from some moderates and Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He previously collaborated with Harris while they each served as their states’ AG, meaning they have experience working alongside one another. And more recently, Harris and Cooper <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bsVNTI1BqZo">have campaigned together</a> in the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">Biden’s disastrous June debate</a>, during which the governor cautioned against the return of “Donald Trump’s America.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2150001600_c3763f.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.736744421098,100,78.526511157804" alt="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." title="Gov. Josh Shapiro, in glasses and a navy suit jacket, waves at reporters and a crowd." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Pennsylvania Gov. Josh Shapiro arrives to deliver remarks at a building trades union conference on April 24, in Washington, DC. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Josh Shapiro</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Shapiro, 51, is the governor of Pennsylvania, another likely battleground state (with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">19 Electoral College votes</a>), which Biden won in 2020 and which former Secretary of State Hillary Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He was elected in 2022, the same year that freshman Sen. John Fetterman (D-PA) was elected to the Senate. Shapiro ran far ahead of Fetterman, <a href="https://www.politico.com/2022-election/results/pennsylvania/">winning 57 percent of the vote, to Fetterman’s 51 percent</a>. Shapiro has established himself as a moderate who helped negotiate bipartisan deals when he was in the state legislature, and is also known for his work as attorney general, when he secured settlements for victims of sexual abuse by the Catholic Diocese. He’s also been a vocal supporter of Israel amid the country’s devastating military offensive in Gaza, following Hamas’ brutal October 7 attack.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him?</strong> Like Cooper, he’s the popular Democratic governor of a swing state and could help the party improve their chances there. He’s also seen as more of a centrist who could appeal to moderate voters and independents, though his staunch backing of Israel could turn away progressive Democrats.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161807297_5538e2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." title="Gov. Andy Beshear, in a light blue shirt and wearing a lapel mic, speaks to reporters while standing outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kentucky Gov. Andy Beshear speaks to reporters following a ribbon-cutting ceremony in Hazel, Kentucky, in October 2023. | Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Lexington Herald-Leader/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Andy Beshear</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Beshear, 46, is the governor of Kentucky and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/11/7/23950792/election-day-2023-kentucky-governors-race-results-democrats-republicans">has won twice in a red state that previously overwhelmingly voted for Trump</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, he’s been praised for his handling of the Covid-19 pandemic as well as multiple crises in the state, including <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/4/11/23679512/louisville-kentucky-shooting-workplace">a mass shooting at a bank</a> and severe flooding. Prior to this role, he also served as Kentucky’s attorney general.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Beshear is the rare Democrat who has been able to win multiple times in a red state and could offer additional appeal to some swing voters. In addition to the support he’s received for his leadership during various crises, he’s also touted infrastructure and private sector investment in the state during his tenure. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike other possibilities, though, he probably wouldn’t increase Harris’s chances of winning his home state, which is solidly GOP.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160763179.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." title="Gov. J.B. Pritzer, in a dark suit and pink striped tie, speaks into a microphone at a podium, with a screen lighting him from the back." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Illinois Gov. J.B. Pritzker speaks during to a Chicago-area chamber of commerce meeting on June 4, 2024, in Chicago. | Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Eileen T. Meslar/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. J.B. Pritzker</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>J.B. Pritzker, 59, is the governor of Illinois, a Democratic state that Biden and Clinton both won in 2020 and 2016. Before becoming governor, he was a businessman and philanthropist, and is a scion of the family behind Hyatt hotels, who’ve also been consistent and influential Democratic donors.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor, Pritzker has established a modest national profile, including remarks he’s given attacking Trump and calls he’s made for more federal resources to address immigration in Illinois.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Pritzker has already built some name recognition as a fixture on cable news, and has proven to be a vocal Trump antagonist. Pritzker’s personal wealth could also potentially be a boon to the campaign, though his own state is not a battleground that would expand the Democratic map.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2160744008_a0c39e.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " title="Sen. Mark Kelly, in a navy suit and blue-striped tie, wears a serious expression while speaking to a gaggle of reporters with microphones and smartphones. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sen. Mark Kelly (D-AZ) is questioned about the candidacy of President Joe Biden after a Senate luncheon on July 9. | Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tom Williams/CQ-Roll Call, Inc via Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Sen. Mark Kelly</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Kelly is the junior senator of Arizona — a swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">11 Electoral College votes</a> — <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/11/5/21537670/senate-2020-results-arizona-mark-kelly-winner">who was elected in 2020</a> by framing himself as a candidate willing to work across the aisle. Previously, Biden won Arizona in 2020, while Clinton lost the state in 2016. Kelly is also known for his career as an astronaut alongside his twin brother Scott Kelly, and as the husband of gun control advocate and former US Rep. Gabby Giffords.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Kelly has a higher profile than some of the other names on this list, and is respected both for his scientific expertise and contributions as an astronaut in addition to his time in the Senate. He’s been a prominent gun control advocate alongside Giffords and made pushing these policies a priority.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given his efforts to appeal to both Republicans and independents in Arizona, he’d be another option who could help with trying to reach those voters. Arizona also continues to be an important battleground this time around, including in its <a href="https://www.cookpolitical.com/ratings/senate-race-ratings">Senate race</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1247112367.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." title="Gov. Gretchen Whitmer, in a snakeskin-patterned blouse, speaks into a set of microphones, smillng, with the state seal of Michigan behind her." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer speaks at a press conference about an electric-vehicle battery plant in February 2023 in Romulus, Michigan. | Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Bill Pugliano/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gretchen Whitmer</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is she? </strong>Whitmer, 52, is the governor of Michigan, a key swing state with <a href="https://www.archives.gov/electoral-college/allocation">15 Electoral College votes</a> that Biden won in 2020 and that Clinton lost in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She’s been a popular leader in this role, and was initially known for how much she emphasized infrastructure and “fixing the damn roads.” Since then she’s been an outspoken advocate for abortion rights, and for gender equity, speaking openly about how she was sexually assaulted in college. Prior to being governor, Whitmer was a member of the state legislature and the first woman to become the Democratic leader of the state Senate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for her? </strong>She’s among the members of the list who have strong and positive national recognition, and who could help raise Democrats’ chances in a pivotal swing state. Whitmer has also focused on issues including infrastructure and health care, which could broaden Democrats’ appeal to moderate voters. And if Harris and Whitmer were on the same ticket, they would form a groundbreaking all-woman ticket — something that neither major party has run before.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1394802139.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " title="Pete Buttigieg, in a navy suit and white shirt, is shown from the side, while pinning an index card onto a wall full of similar cards with handwritten notes. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg attends a White House correspondents’ brunch on April 30, 2022, in Washington, DC. | Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" data-portal-copyright="Paul Morigi/Getty Images for White House Correspondents Insider" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Secretary Pete Buttigieg</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he?</strong> Buttigieg, 42, is the secretary of transportation who rose to prominence as a former 2020 presidential candidate. He’s staked out more moderate positions and was previously mayor of South Bend, Indiana. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He’s become known for his media savvy and strong television appearances as an advocate for the Biden-Harris administration. He’s also had to respond to crises including the train accident and <a href="https://www.vox.com/science/2023/2/18/23603471/east-palestine-ohio-derailment-water-contamination-health">chemical spill in East Palestine</a>, Ohio, as well as the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/1/8/24030677/boeing-alaska-airlines-plane-737-max-door-plug">Alaska Airlines mishap</a> when a door plug dropped out of a plane.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Buttigieg has been a strong spokesperson for the Biden-Harris White House and is well-established among the Democratic electorate. He’s among the youngest of possible choices, would contribute more representation from the Midwest,<strong> </strong>and could appeal to centrist voters. He’d also become the first openly LGBTQ person to be on a presidential ticket.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161013764_474f9c.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752616398754,100,78.494767202492" alt="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." title="Gov. Gavin Newsom, in a gray striped jacket and blue shirt, squints into the sun as he speaks outdoors." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="California Gov. Gavin Newsom speaks during a press conference in Oakland, California, on July 11. | Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Stephen Lam/San Francisco Chronicle/Getty Images" />
<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Gov. Gavin Newsom</strong></h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is he? </strong>Newsom, 56, is the governor of California, and a longstanding political personality. He’s been a vocal advocate for more progressive policies, and for Democrats to more directly confront Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prior to being governor, he was also lieutenant governor and mayor of San Francisco.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s the case for him? </strong>Newsom has already made clear that he wants to be a fighter for Democrats and has supporters who are interested in his approach. He’s also used opportunities like a debate against Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis to make some splashy points for the party and to get more attention, and could do the same for a possible campaign.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As governor of California, however, he wouldn’t bring additional geographic diversity to the ticket, and he also wouldn’t help with delivering a swing state, as his own is solidly Democratic.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, July 21, 2024, 11:59 pm ET: </strong>A previous version of this story misstated Gabby Giffords&#8217;s position on guns. She is a gun control advocate.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[It was not undemocratic for the Democrats to dump Joe Biden]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/362062/biden-drop-out-republicans-accuse-democrats-coup" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362062</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T01:08:26Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-22T00:59:29Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not long after President Joe Biden announced he was stepping aside from the presidential race Sunday, pro-Trump social media influencers had settled on one line of attack: that Democrats had carried out a coup against their own president.&#160; Biden “has now been deposed in a coup,” Trump-backing venture capitalist David Sacks wrote. “Undermining Democracy should [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Nancy Pelosi, in a white suit and pearl jewelry, smiles against a backdrop of a US flag." data-caption="Then-Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi (D-CA), in 2022. | Drew Angerer/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Drew Angerer/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1241165594.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Then-Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi (D-CA), in 2022. | Drew Angerer/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Not long after President Joe Biden announced he was stepping aside from the presidential race Sunday, pro-Trump social media influencers had settled on one line of attack: that Democrats <a href="https://www.mediaite.com/politics/its-a-coup-maga-world-melts-down-over-biden-dropping-out-of-race/">had carried out a coup</a> against their own president.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden “has now been deposed in a coup,” Trump-backing venture capitalist <a href="https://x.com/DavidSacks/status/1815168526602387674">David Sacks wrote</a>. “Undermining Democracy should never be condoned,” <a href="https://twitter.com/RichardGrenell/status/1815090797668347944?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1815090797668347944%7Ctwgr%5E13a36bbb3a548a03601a0d1dfabfab597f4072e8%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mediaite.com%2Fpolitics%2Fits-a-coup-maga-world-melts-down-over-biden-dropping-out-of-race%2F">Trump ally</a> Richard Grenell posted. “The coup is complete,” <a href="https://twitter.com/RepGosar/status/1815086422199767408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1815086422199767408%7Ctwgr%5E13a36bbb3a548a03601a0d1dfabfab597f4072e8%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.mediaite.com%2Fpolitics%2Fits-a-coup-maga-world-melts-down-over-biden-dropping-out-of-race%2F">wrote</a> Rep. Paul Gosar (R-AZ).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What you just witnessed is proof positive that when the most powerful Democrat institutions and oligarchs unite to topple an American regime, they expect to succeed,” conservative activist <a href="https://twitter.com/charliekirk11/status/1815091854351946189">Charlie Kirk wrote</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From people who support Donald Trump, the man who tried to steal the 2020 election, this is obviously a ridiculous and absurd thing to say. Yet it echoes a self-interested argument made by Biden himself just two weeks ago, when he argued that him dropping out would be tantamount to ignoring democracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The voters — and the voters alone — decide the nominee of the Democratic Party,” Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/359362/biden-dropout-2024-undemocratic-primaries-voters">wrote in a July 8 letter</a>. “Not the press, not the pundits, not the big donors, not any selected group of individuals, no matter how well intentioned.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s unfolded in the two weeks since has been a steadily intensifying pressure campaign from various members of the press, pundits, donors, and current and former elected officials aimed at making Biden quit. Some of these entreaties were made <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/nancy-pelosi-biden-conversation/index.html">in private</a> — and, when Biden didn’t appear to be listening, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/10/opinion/joe-biden-democratic-nominee.html">more</a> spilled <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/schumer-privately-urged-biden-step-aside-2024-election/story?id=112046011">out</a> into <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/18/us/politics/jamie-raskin-biden-letter.html">public</a> view. They argued that he couldn’t win and, eventually, he listened.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There may arguably be something a bit uncomfortable about the role of Democratic power brokers and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/18/us/politics/biden-fundraising.html">donors</a> in pushing Biden aside after his primary win. But while they’re doing this without voters’ explicit say, they’re doing so in an attempt to (belatedly) respond to voters’ beliefs that Biden is too old to serve another term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it may be undemocratic in practice, but in a sense it’s democratic in intention. Because the party isn’t avoiding an election, they’re trying to win one, by picking a nominee who (they hope) can win more people’s votes.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How democratic were the 2024 Democratic primaries?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic Party elites didn’t just fall out of a coconut tree after the debate. Up until that disaster, they’d been fully behind Biden, and their support of him was one major reason Democratic voters were presented with no credible alternatives in this year’s primaries.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because in reality, Biden won the primaries well before the people got to vote. Back in 2022 and 2023, some polls <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ap-norc-poll-biden-2024-presidential-prospects-c843c5af6775b4c8a0cff8e2b1db03f6">showed</a> a majority of Democratic voters saying he shouldn’t run again. The president never seems to have seriously considered bowing out, though. He ran again and (as is normal for an incumbent) solidly locked down support from Democratic elites. As a result, Democratic rising stars were deterred from challenging Biden, believing they likely would have lost, and then been blamed if Trump won in the general. </p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Joe Biden dropped out of the 2024 race. Catch up on this story.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden surrendered to pressure from top Democrats and campaign donors who urged him to step aside amid concerns over his age and low polling numbers against Donald Trump.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">What happens now?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out">What happens to Biden’s campaign money?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How did Democrats get here?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">What can we learn from incumbents who stepped aside</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, yes, 15 million people did indeed end up voting in those primaries. But how democratic was that process? Biden won the primaries because he won the inside game.&nbsp;It was party elites who determined the (few) options available to voters. Polls showed the voters would in theory have preferred someone else, but they weren’t offered a realistic opposing candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Furthermore, asserting that the primary result is all that matters, and that taking anything else into account is “undemocratic,” is a very limited and blinkered definition of democracy. After all, those 15 million people are a paltry sum compared to the 150 million people who may vote in the general election — people who, according to polls, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/01/us/politics/biden-age-democrats.html">overwhelmingly think</a> Biden is too old to serve another term. Many of those people wanted another candidate — shouldn’t their views matter?</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The “new information after the primaries” problem</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another issue is that primary voters did not have the information that Biden would perform so poorly in the debate when they cast their votes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And though what key Democratic Party figures just did to Biden is in some ways unprecedented, in other ways it’s very familiar. That is: it’s the standard playbook for how to force out a suddenly scandal-plagued elected official who is believed to be hurting the party.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This playbook involves a ratcheting up of pressure and condemnations as co-partisans gradually condemn or abandon that official, making sure they know that the battering will continue unless they quit — basically what we’ve seen over the past few weeks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">New York Democrats successfully employed it against <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/8/5/22607971/cuomo-impeachment-resignation-scandal">Gov. Andrew Cuomo</a> in 2021, Attorney General <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/four-women-accuse-new-yorks-attorney-general-of-physical-abuse">Eric Schneiderman</a> in 2018, and Gov. <a href="https://www.npr.org/2008/03/12/88134976/spitzer-resigns-after-sex-scandal-pressure">Eliot Spitzer</a> in 2008. Senate Democrats did it against <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2017/12/07/franken-resigns-285957">Sen. Al Franken</a> (D-MN) in 2017. (Though it doesn’t always work, as shown in the cases of Virginia Gov. <a href="https://www.vox.com/identities/2019/2/15/18224864/ralph-northam-virginia-blackface-apology-protests">Ralph Northam</a>, and 2016 GOP presidential nominee <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/politics/onpolitics/2016/10/08/donald-trump-debate-mike-crapo-mike-lee-barbara-comstock/91784714/">Donald Trump</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Your mileage may vary in how much you view Biden’s bad debate performance as a full-on scandal. But it was certainly new information that wasn’t clear during the primaries. Back then, Biden refused to participate in any debates and skipped some high-profile interview opportunities, leaving it ambiguous how he might perform in a high-stakes setting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the truth is that party elites didn’t just casually abandon the choice of the voters right after they made that choice. They defected later, because of new information — information that those primary voters did not have.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Party loyalty is a two-way street</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, it is also worth noting that party elites didn’t push Biden off the ticket in an effort to steal the power of the presidency from him. They abandoned him because they fear he is hurting the party’s electoral chances — that is, because he’s lost support from voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Party loyalty is a two-way street — it is not, or at least should not be, a blood oath or a cult of personality. Leading Democrats backed Biden when they thought he could win, and they ditched him when they thought he couldn’t.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, they’re trying to substitute a nominee they hope the American public will like a lot better. And there’s something very democratic about that. They are (finally, belatedly) trying to listen to the voters, who, according to polls at least, keep saying they don’t want to support Biden again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So maybe it would have been nice if Democrats had had an actual presidential primary process rather than this mess. But that didn’t happen — and, considering the options, party officials abandoning Biden to try and nudge him aside in favor of someone who can win was a reasonable response.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This is bigger than Joe Biden]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361999/joe-biden-drops-out-kamala-harris-2024-trump-democracy-hope" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361999</id>
			<updated>2024-07-22T01:53:23Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-21T23:40:09Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By dropping out of the 2024 race, President Joe Biden did what we all want our politicians to do: He put his country over his career. Knowing that his party had lost faith in his capacity to beat Donald Trump and that a second Trump term would threaten democracy itself, he chose to do the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="President Biden stands at a podium and speaks into a microphone, raising one finger in the air. Behind him stand a row of American flags." data-caption="President Joe Biden delivers remarks on reducing gun violence on March 14, 2023, in Monterey Park, California." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-1473595193.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President Joe Biden delivers remarks on reducing gun violence on March 14, 2023, in Monterey Park, California.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">By <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">dropping out of the 2024 race</a>, President Joe Biden did what we all want our politicians to do: He put his country over his career. Knowing that his party had lost faith in his capacity to beat Donald Trump and that a second Trump term <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/5/13/23708595/trump-second-term-cnn-town-hall">would threaten democracy itself</a>, he chose to do the right thing and step aside.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, it took him a long time to get here. While it’s only been 24 days since the disastrous debate with Trump, we don’t know how long Biden had been in decline prior to that. The earlier that clock starts, the worse it reflects on Biden and his team.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But ultimately, the story isn’t really about Joe Biden as a person. It’s about what he and his party did — and what their actions tell us about the state of American democracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And what they say is surprisingly hopeful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a country where many think politicians won’t do the right thing, Biden did (even if he exhausted all other options first). In a country where political parties seem to cower in the face of their own leaders, one party managed to challenge and push out a candidate whose campaign served neither party nor country. And in a country where polarization seemingly ground everything to a standstill, democracy showed it’s still capable of surprising us.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s announcement, and the Democratic effort to push him into it, shows America’s institutions might not be as broken as many think. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden (ultimately) does the right thing</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For years, voters have been telling pollsters that they thought Joe Biden was too old to serve a second term as president. The race remained competitive because voters were similarly wary of Trump, but there was clear unease about Biden’s future.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden could have chosen to listen to those fears. He could have stepped aside before the primary elections, or encouraged an open convention back when <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/16/opinion/ezra-klein-biden-audio-essay.html">the New York Times’s Ezra Klein sounded the alarm bell about age in February</a>. But he didn’t.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then the disastrous June debate happened, and the chorus became deafening. <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/biden-trump-2024-polls-drop-out-rcna161348">Poll after poll</a> found that large majorities of Americans&nbsp;—&nbsp;and even <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/07/11/poll-biden-drop-out-election/">majorities of <em>Democrats</em></a> — had concluded that Biden wasn’t competent to serve a second term. (This speaks to the absurdity of the narrative, popular among some Biden dead-enders and bad faith right-wingers, that the push against Biden is <a href="https://x.com/SpeakerJohnson/status/1815093011669516433">undemocratic</a> or <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/democrats-biden-step-down-kamala-harris-chuck-schumer-hakeem-jeffries-donald-trump-363a0701">even a kind of coup</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden was not just heading for defeat. He and his party were confirming nearly every negative stereotype the voters had about the political system: Politicians were selfish, aged fools unable to act in the public interest; political parties were creatures of a corrupt elite entirely out of touch with the public.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In stepping aside, Biden flips the script. He showed that, when push really came to shove, there was something more important to the president than power: the fortunes of the party and the fate of his country. Even if the actual sequence of events followed <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/itsallpolitics/2013/10/28/241295755/a-churchill-quote-that-u-s-politicians-will-never-surrender">the apocryphal quip</a> that “Americans will always do the right thing, only after they have tried everything else,” he did, ultimately, come to the right conclusion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s enough to make even the most jaded observer a little more optimistic about American democracy — for at least two big reasons.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, it shows that there can still be standards in politics.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Joe Biden dropped out of the 2024 race. Catch up on this story.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden surrendered to pressure from top Democrats and campaign donors who urged him to step aside amid concerns over his age and low polling numbers against Donald Trump.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">What happens now?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out">What happens to Biden&#8217;s campaign money?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How did Democrats get here?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">What can we learn from incumbents who stepped aside</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">American politics isn’t just made up of two parties, wholly owned by party elites, locked in a mortal and uncompromising struggle to the death. At least one of our parties is capable of policing its own: challenging an incumbent president and, ultimately, convincing him to step aside. The contrast with the GOP’s behavior after Trump’s many scandals — from the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/28/nyregion/access-hollywood-tape-trump-trial.html" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/28/nyregion/access-hollywood-tape-trump-trial.html">Access Hollywood tape</a> to the January 6 Capitol riot —&nbsp;is unmistakable.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Second, Biden’s departure shows that unexpected things can still happen.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is hard to prove, but I think so much of the polling showing public distrust in the American government is rooted in a sense that it’s stuck: that what’s happening right now isn’t working, and that no one is capable of doing anything surprising to right the ship. But a president abandoning a reelection campaign is nothing if not surprising.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politicians like Trump, in both the United States and elsewhere, thrive on the notion that the system is broken and nothing can be done to fix it. This is a problem not just because those specific politicians are dangerous, but because distrust rots democracy’s foundations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By showing that the system doesn’t only throw up unappealing options — that politics can be more than just a contest between two unpopular older men —&nbsp;Biden and the Democrats just did real work at repairing those foundations. They showed that a central promise of democracy, that it can self-correct after even grievous errors, remains intact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fully repairing American democracy will take a lot more work than this, of course. The problems run much deeper than the 2020 election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this is a big step in the right direction. And as a result, I’m feeling something that might seem unusual in the oft-gloomy world of American politics: hope.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden is out of the 2024 race. What happens to his campaign donations?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361991</id>
			<updated>2024-07-21T21:59:12Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-21T21:30:04Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Campaign Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President Joe Biden announced Sunday that he is dropping out of the 2024 presidential race and endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as his choice for the Democratic nominee. A practical question follows: What happens to his campaign funds? The Biden campaign said it had $240 million in cash on hand earlier this month, compared to [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Figures are silhouetted in front of a large blue, white, and red sign that reads DNC 2024." data-caption="Signage at the Democratic National Convention on May 22, 2024, at the United Center. | Brian Cassella/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brian Cassella/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2158794750.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Signage at the Democratic National Convention on May 22, 2024, at the United Center. | Brian Cassella/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">announced</a> Sunday that he is dropping out of the 2024 presidential race and <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">endorsed</a> Vice President Kamala Harris as his choice for the Democratic nominee. A practical question follows: What happens to his campaign funds?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden campaign said it had <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-biden-fundraising-democrats-8492425af85796ad77844b77db6d0f30">$240 million in cash on hand</a> earlier this month, compared to former President Donald Trump’s <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-biden-fundraising-democrats-8492425af85796ad77844b77db6d0f30">$331 million</a>. Campaign finance rules put some limits on what Biden can do with that money now that he’s no longer running for president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The money isn’t just in limbo, however. Though it’s not yet completely certain whether Harris will become the nominee — she’d need Biden’s delegates at the Democratic National Convention to assume the candidacy, though his endorsement certainly <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">puts her ahead of any possible competition</a> —&nbsp;she could access Biden’s funds more easily than another Democrat. And the campaign pot only seems to be growing: Major Democratic donors, some of whom had <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/12/briefing/biden-donor-pressure-trump-vice-president.html">paused their contributions</a> after Biden’s disastrous debate performance last month due to concerns about his candidacy, reportedly reopened their wallets after Biden’s announcement Sunday.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden and Harris already share funds in a campaign committee under campaign finance laws that allow the president and vice president to run together as one ticket, said Saurav Ghosh, the Campaign Legal Center’s director of federal campaign finance reform. If she were to remain on the ticket as the presidential nominee, “the new ticket would maintain access to all the funds in the campaign committee,” Ghosh added.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That would make Harris’s transition to the top of the ticket seamless — at least when it comes to the money.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What happens to Biden’s campaign funds if Harris isn’t the nominee?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While it currently seems that Harris has a decent chance of being Democrats’ choice for president, not everyone is on board. Some lawmakers have appeared to back an open process of some sort to select the new Democratic nominee, including <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/07/19/pelosi-support-open-nomination-biden-drop-out-00169893">former House Speaker Nancy Pelosi</a> and <a href="https://barackobama.medium.com/my-statement-on-president-bidens-announcement-1eb78b3ba3fc">former President Barack Obama</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It would be difficult for another Democrat to challenge Harris, given that she now has Biden’s endorsement and the support of millions of Americans who already voted for the Biden-Harris ticket. So even if there is an open process either at the Democratic Convention or before it, Harris would have a good shot at winning the nomination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if she doesn’t and drops off the ticket entirely, she and Biden couldn’t just transfer their millions to another Democrat. Campaign finance laws impose a limit of only $2,000 per election for transfers from one candidate to another. There are a few potential workarounds, but it is unlikely that any would allow the new candidate to take full advantage of the value of Biden’s campaign coffers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For one, Biden could “offer to refund the money to donors who could then contribute to the new candidate’s campaign,” Ghosh said. But this is an unreliable method: Refunding the money to donors is no guarantee that they will contribute to the Democratic ticket again and relies on them to do the legwork. </p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Joe Biden dropped out of the 2024 race. Catch up on this story.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden surrendered to pressure from top Democrats and campaign donors who urged him to step aside amid concerns over his age and low polling numbers against Donald Trump.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">What happens now?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How did Democrats get here</a>?</li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">What can we learn from incumbents who stepped aside</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alternatively, Biden could transfer all his funds to the Democratic National Committee. As much as <a href="https://www.fec.gov/help-candidates-and-committees/making-disbursements-political-party/coordinated-party-expenditures/coordinated-party-expenditure-limits/#:~:text=As%20detailed%20in%20the%20tables,archived%20limits%20from%20past%20years.&amp;text=For%20House%20nominees%20in%20all%20other%20states%2C%20the%20limit%20is%20%2461%2C800.">$32.3 million of that</a> could be spent in coordination with the nominee, and the DNC could also unilaterally spend the rest of the money to support the new nominee, Ghosh said. That’s in addition to the approximately <a href="https://www.fec.gov/data/committee/C00010603/">$65 million in cash</a> the DNC had on hand by the end of May. But that approach has a drawback: The DNC might not necessarily target its investments in the way the campaign would prefer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden could also potentially <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-biden-fundraising-democrats-8492425af85796ad77844b77db6d0f30">transfer his funds</a> to an independent super PAC if Harris is not on the ticket. But super PACs cannot coordinate with campaigns, and they are typically <a href="https://apnews.com/article/kamala-harris-biden-fundraising-election-campaign-donations-5709f07420b4f138caa884361653368e">charged more to take out ads</a> than campaigns. That means that the money wouldn’t go as far.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those are the campaign’s best options. Now, campaign finance rules aren’t likely to be the only determining factor in who ultimately succeeds Biden. But those rules do make Harris the most practical choice (at least from a campaign finance perspective) with months to go before the November election.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Does PAC money automatically go to Harris? What about other funding streams?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to the funds in his campaign coffers, Biden has also <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/07/09/240-million-who-gets-joe-bidens-campaign-money/74295593007/">relied on several joint fundraising committees</a>, essentially groups that fundraise across allied political organizations, including the Biden Victory Fund, which had about <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/jfc/summary.php?id=C00744946&amp;cycle=2024">$40 million on hand</a> as of the end of June.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These committees have signed agreements with Biden’s campaign fund indicating how the funds they raise together at joint fundraisers will be allocated. So long as all of them agree, those agreements can be changed so that they can support the new nominee.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are also several <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/2024-presidential-race/joe-biden/candidate?id=N00001669">major super PACs</a> currently supporting Biden, including <a href="https://www.fec.gov/data/committee/C00669259/">Future Forward</a>, which had about $92 million in cash on hand at the end of May. But since super PACs are independent of campaigns, they can change how their funds are allocated at any point.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden just quit the race and endorsed Kamala Harris. What happens now?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361827</id>
			<updated>2024-07-21T22:00:48Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-21T19:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[After weeks of pressure, conjecture, and handwringing at the highest levels of the Democratic Party, President Joe Biden has decided to step aside from the 2024 presidential race.&#160; The president issued a written statement Sunday afternoon, saying he believes it is in the country’s best interest for him to step down, adding that he will [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="President Joe Biden, in a navy suit and blue tie, speaks into a pair of microphones from a podium, looking down, with a US flag behind him." data-caption="President Joe Biden is pictured at the  NATO Summit in Washington DC in July, nearly two weeks after his disastrous debate performance set in motion efforts to get him to end his campaign for a second term. | Kent Nishimura/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kent Nishimura/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2161687527.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President Joe Biden is pictured at the  NATO Summit in Washington DC in July, nearly two weeks after his disastrous debate performance set in motion efforts to get him to end his campaign for a second term. | Kent Nishimura/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">After weeks of pressure, conjecture, and handwringing at the highest levels of the Democratic Party, President Joe Biden has decided to step aside from the 2024 presidential race.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The president issued a <a href="https://x.com/joebiden/status/1815080881981190320?s=46&amp;t=WDV3NvpmCLI-fO5R13Teug">written statement Sunday afternoon</a>, saying he believes it is in the country’s best interest for him to step down, adding that he will address the nation later in the week about his decision. Biden’s decision comes after weeks of public and private <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361597/biden-drop-out-democrats-obama-pelosi-schumer">entreaties from Democrats</a> who have concluded that he is unlikely to defeat former President Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moments later, Biden released <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">another statement endorsing Vice President Kamala Harris</a> to take his spot atop the ticket. Some other leading Democrats — <a href="https://x.com/BillClinton/status/1815102085198958657">Bill and Hillary Clinton</a>, the <a href="https://twitter.com/errinhaines/status/1815104279138509105" data-type="link" data-id="https://twitter.com/errinhaines/status/1815104279138509105">Congressional Black Caucus</a>, Sens. <a href="https://twitter.com/timkaine/status/1815103608419143947/history">Tim Kaine </a>(D-VA) and <a href="https://twitter.com/maxpcohen/status/1815102726826840560">Tammy Baldwin</a> (D-WI) — quickly endorsed Harris, too, revealing a desire in the party to quickly unite behind her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such endorsements do not make Harris the presidential nominee — the new nominee will be officially chosen by the thousands of delegates attending the Democratic National Convention beginning August 19. But if such endorsements keep piling up, they may deter any other prominent Democrats from challenging Harris and make her nomination all-but-assured.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alternatively, other Democrats could put their names in contention. What would happen after that is unclear. Some in the party have spoken of a “<a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/07/20/2024/democrats-detail-blitz-primary-options-to-replace-biden">blitz primary</a>” or a truly “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/21/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-elaine-kamarck.html">open convention</a>” where delegates are freed up to support whomever they like. Others view this as chaotic folly. Whether this is at all likely will first depend on whether anyone else jumps in, though.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What is clear is that the presidential contest is entering uncharted territory for the modern era. Since the rise of the modern nomination process in the 1970s, no winner of the primaries has quit the race before the convention. And no major-party nominee has entered the race so close to November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s worth pausing to appreciate just what a dramatic turn of events this has been. It was just a few short months ago that President Biden <a href="https://6abc.com/2024-super-tuesday-states-primary-results/14492343/">sailed through</a> the primary season with barely any opposition. But now, his party support has collapsed under him to the point where he effectively can’t continue his campaign.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Joe Biden dropped out of the 2024 race. Catch up on this story.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden surrendered to pressure from top Democrats and campaign donors who urged him to step aside amid concerns over his age and low polling numbers against Donald Trump.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">Do other Democrats actually poll better against Trump than Biden?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/joe-biden/361991/361991biden-campaign-funds-after-drops-out">What happens to Biden&#8217;s campaign money?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris">How did Democrats get here?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman">What can we learn from incumbents who stepped aside</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The catalyst for this collapse was Biden’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358652/biden-drop-out-debate-harris-convention">June 27 debate performance</a>, which will surely now go down as the most catastrophic general election debate in US presidential history. But what the debate actually did was supercharge concerns about Biden’s electoral prospects, stamina, health, and capacity that have long simmered below the surface of Democratic politics.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The doubts about Biden did not begin with the debate, but the debate suddenly made them impossible to ignore — and spurred the party to take action.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What will happen next, though, is far from clear. Some Democrats profess to believe that Biden was a uniquely flawed nominee because of his age, and that a different nominee could perform much better against the <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/favorability/donald-trump/">unpopular Trump</a>. But others are more pessimistic, suspecting that the party faces deeper electoral problems and that any replacement nominee is going to have a very tough road ahead.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden plowed ahead with his campaign despite party doubts. The debate made those doubts impossible to ignore.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the start of Biden’s first term, many in the political world questioned whether he would run for a second term, for two reasons: One is his age, since he’s already the oldest US president ever and would be 82 by Inauguration Day. The other is his bad polling numbers; his job approval has been dismal <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">since late 2021</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Biden doesn’t ever appear to have seriously considered not running. He said <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/biden-reelection-2024/2021/11/20/0779469c-4947-11ec-95dc-5f2a96e00fa3_story.html">from the start</a> of his term that he intended to run again, and when Democrats’ midterm election performance was better than many expected, it seemed to bolster his case that he could. So he made his reelection campaign official <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/04/25/1145679856/biden-president-announcement-2024-running-reelection">in April 2023</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All the party’s rising stars opted against launching a risky primary challenge to an incumbent president — doing otherwise would have earned them intense criticism in the party for dividing Democrats and damaging Biden’s chances in the general election. So Biden easily fended off challenges from the likes of Rep. Dean Phillips (D-MN) and author Marianne Williamson.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But doubts remained. Biden skeptics raised eyebrows at his <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/02/06/media/biden-skipping-super-bowl-interview/index.html">skipping the president’s</a> traditional pre-Super Bowl interview, at his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/21/us/politics/biden-public-appearances-media.html">reluctance</a> to do press conferences, and at a special counsel report’s claims that he <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2024/2/8/24066529/biden-special-counsel-report-memory">seemed to have</a> a poor memory. In February, New York Times columnist (and Vox co-founder) <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/16/opinion/ezra-klein-biden-audio-essay.html">Ezra Klein caused a stir</a> by writing that Democrats should choose a different nominee at the convention, because Biden did not seem up for the rigors of the campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, Biden gave a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/03/07/biden-state-of-the-union-2024/">reasonably spirited performance</a> at his State of the Union address in March, temporarily putting those concerns to rest. But it did not improve his polls — by then, he’d consistently trailed Trump nationally and in almost every swing state <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-biden">for months</a>. He looked on track for defeat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/15/us/politics/trump-biden-debate-june.html">reportedly why</a> Biden’s team made the surprising proposal to debate Trump so early, a very unusual move. The hope was that Biden could, with a vigorous performance, reset the race, refocus attention on Trump, and address concerns about his age again.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The opposite happened: Biden’s halting performance put a spotlight on his capacity to campaign (and serve another four years) that never went away.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He lost the media first.&nbsp;In the hours after the debate, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">various</a> liberal <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/25/opinion/joe-biden-drop-out.html">commentators</a> called on him <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/28/opinion/joe-biden-tom-friedman.html">to quit</a> the race. Mainstream journalists, sensing scandal and a cover-up, intensely focused on reporting out <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/359024/biden-age-leaks-lapses-polls">Biden’s true condition</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, Biden hoped that he could keep the party on board by doing a flurry of interviews and public events, showing the debate was a one-off. Some of these went <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360124/biden-dropout-defections-obama-pelosi">reasonably well</a>, others <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/17/politics/video/biden-youtube-complex-interview-tapper-lead-digvid">less so</a>. But his <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/18/us/politics/biden-fundraising.html">fundraising plummeted</a>, and the public and private pressure from Democrats urging him to step aside <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/19/us/politics/biden-democrats-campaign.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">just kept increasing</a> — until Biden finally saw the writing on the wall.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The big question going forward: Are Democrats’ electoral problems just about Biden?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what happens next?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obviously, much will depend on who the nominee is. Clearly, Vice President Harris is the top contender at the moment. If the party simply falls in line behind her, there may not be much suspense by the time the Democratic convention kicks off on August 19. If there is a serious contest, though, strap in for a roller coaster ride over the next month.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s another big underlying question that we don’t yet know the answer to. Namely, how much are Democrats’ electoral woes about Joe Biden himself — and how much reflect deeper problems for the party as a whole?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some argue that Democrats are doing fine, and that it’s only Biden that’s been the problem; that voters have soured on the president because of his age or perceived incapacity to serve another four years, and because Trump remains flawed and unpopular, and another Democratic nominee would likely beat him. For instance, Democratic Senate incumbents <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/17/briefing/biden-vs-the-democratic-party.html">are polling significantly better</a> than Biden. That implies to some that with a different name at the top of the ticket, the party would be in great shape.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others argue that Democrats’ problems will likely outlast Biden. Unhappiness with inflation under Biden, as well as unfolding foreign tumult<strong>,</strong> may have convinced voters that Trump wasn’t so bad after all. Public opinion on <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2024/07/the-changes-in-vibes-why-did-they-happen.html">key issues</a> has moved right. And there <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-whitmer">isn’t</a> much <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-newsom">polling</a> showing any possible Democratic <a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/president/general/2024/trump-vs-harris">alternative</a> beating Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of these pessimists still believe it was worth pushing out Biden since he had little prospect of turning things around, but they emphasize that any replacement would be the underdog and face a very tough road ahead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All we know for sure now is that Democrats have decided to roll the dice, ditching their unpopular nominee in hopes of improving their odds in a contest they were on track to lose.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, July 21, 3:50 pm: </em></strong><em>This piece was originally published earlier on July 21 and has been updated to include more information about the Democratic National Convention’s options going forward. </em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamala Harris’s strengths — and vulnerabilities — explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=360327</id>
			<updated>2024-07-21T23:03:23Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-21T19:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s official: President Joe Biden has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as his successor after announcing Sunday afternoon that he’s decided not to run again this year. “Today I want to offer my full support and endorsement for Kamala to be the nominee of our party this year. Democrats — it’s time to come together [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris, in a rose pink blazer and white shirt, smiles while holding both hands apart and speaking into a microphone." data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to members of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority on July 10, in Dallas, Texas. | Brandon Bell/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brandon Bell/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2161823387.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris speaks to members of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority on July 10, in Dallas, Texas. | Brandon Bell/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s official: President Joe Biden has endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris as his successor after announcing Sunday afternoon that he’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">decided not to run again this year</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Today I want to offer my full support and endorsement for Kamala to be the nominee of our party this year. Democrats — it’s time to come together and beat Trump. Let’s do this,” Biden wrote in a post on X, <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933" data-type="link" data-id="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">formerly known as Twitter.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That endorsement puts Harris in a prime position to assume her party’s presidential nomination ahead of a <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">wide field of other potential choices</a>, including<strong> </strong>Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer and California Gov. Gavin Newsom.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Democrats have a deep bench of talent, perhaps no one makes as much sense to replace Biden as Harris, who’s already in a role designed to take over for a president unable to continue their duties — and who now has his backing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As VP, she’s steeped in the policy work of this administration, and has extensive experience in the White House that she could bring to the job. And she could well be an energizing candidate for many Democratic voters as the first Black and South Asian woman to have the party’s presidential nomination, and as a younger, charismatic alternative to the 78-year-old Republican nominee, former President Donald Trump. Logistically, it would also be fairly easy to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/kamala-harris-biden-fundraising-election-campaign-donations-5709f07420b4f138caa884361653368e#">transfer Biden’s $91 million in campaign funds to Harris</a> (and more difficult to hand that money over to someone else).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, Harris has real vulnerabilities — which have been evident during her tenure as VP and as a 2020 presidential candidate — that could potentially bog her down in the general election. Notably, <a href="https://www.sacbee.com/news/politics-government/capitol-alert/article289792134.html">her favorability ratings have sometimes lagged Biden’s</a> while she’s been vice president, and a common critique she faces is that she hasn’t been able to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/10/magazine/kamala-harris.html" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/10/magazine/kamala-harris.html">carve out a distinct lane for herself</a>. When she ran for the presidency in 2020, she fielded similar issues, leaving people confused about what she stood for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Taken together, there’s plenty of evidence that Harris could be a strong nominee. Notably, though, there are also some key challenges she’ll have to overcome.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The case for Kamala Harris taking over for Biden</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the Democratic nominee, Harris would have some version of the incumbency advantage as the sitting vice president. Though there are important caveats, as detailed by <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23562688/joe-biden-2024-presidential-election-polls-democrats">my colleague Andrew Prokop</a>, roughly two of three incumbents have won reelection.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As part of that advantage, Harris would be able to tout her role in the Biden administration’s wins — like the Inflation Reduction Act, which will help lower prescription drug costs and invest in climate initiatives, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which includes historic funding for bridges and roads. She’d be able to point, too, to the experience she’s garnered as vice president and how it’s prepared her to become commander-in-chief.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a strategy Biden himself successfully employed in 2020, when he <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/16/20863343/joe-biden-barack-obama-2020-democratic-presidential-primary">linked himself to the Obama administration’s achievements</a> — and emphasized how <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/2012/04/26/remarks-vice-president-joe-biden-foreign-policy-camapaign-event">he was often the “last one in the room”</a> when key decisions were being made.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“When you think about all these legislative pieces that were passed in Congress, the vice president was part of the conversations with the president, with the Cabinet, whether it was the infrastructure bill, or the IRA, or the CHIPS bill,” <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/3/27/23655248/kamala-harris-vice-president-approval-criticism">former Labor Secretary Marty Walsh, who’s worked alongside Harris, previously told Vox</a>. That experience, in itself, is significant and invaluable.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her</strong></strong>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361827/biden-drops-out-2024-kamala-convention">What happens now?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc">Does Harris give Democrats a better chance in 2024?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the fall of <em>Roe, </em>Harris has also taken on the mantle of abortion rights, meeting with advocates and voters across the country, and rallying people on the issue in places like Wisconsin, Arizona, and Florida.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This subject has been particularly motivating for Democratic voters and women in recent elections, with multiple ballot initiatives — like <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23451074/abortion-ballot-measure-midterms-kentucky-montana-michigan">those in Vermont and Michigan</a> — passing with overwhelming support. During the 2022 midterm elections, protecting reproductive rights was a central policy for many voters, and a decisive one that helped boost Democrats. Harris’s defense of abortion access is a point that would allow her to paint a sharp contrast with Trump, who has taken credit for <em>Roe</em>’s demise and argued that abortion should be decided on a state-by-state basis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In addition to the experience she has in the White House, Harris also brings legislative expertise from her four years in the Senate, and background on criminal justice reform from her time as attorney general in California. Although some of her tenure as vice president has been plagued with communications missteps, she’d previously been known for her viral moments questioning Trump appointees as a member of the Senate Judiciary Committee and made a big splash in 2019 during a debate confrontation of Biden over his past stance on busing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris could infuse the ticket with new energy as well. Numerous polls have found that majorities of Americans didn&#8217;t want Biden on the ballot, including a <a href="https://maristpoll.marist.edu/polls/contest-for-president-still-up-for-grabs/">July 2024 PBS News/NPR/Marist</a> survey placing that number at 56 percent, and wanted to see <a href="https://wapo.st/469LlsL">options other than Biden or Trump</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris is well-positioned to be that alternative. At 59, she’s decades younger than both the current nominees. And she’s also emblematic of both an increasingly diverse Democratic Party and country, making her a candidate who could be especially motivating for key voting constituencies including Black women. (<a href="https://today.yougov.com/topics/politics/trackers/kamala-harris-favorability">In a July 2024 YouGov poll,</a> Harris’s favorability numbers were at 41 percent with adults overall, and 69 percent among Black respondents.) That could bode well for better turnout and enthusiasm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She’s the second Black woman elected to the Senate, which in a state like California is no small feat,” says University of Maryland public policy professor <a href="https://spp.umd.edu/our-community/faculty-staff/niambi-carter">Niambi Carter</a>. “So she’s shown that she can get voters, white, Black, Latino, and others, to come to the polls.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Experts note, too, that bypassing Harris for another candidate — especially a white one — could run the risk of fracturing support from Black voters and other key Democratic constituencies, says <a href="https://split-ticket.org/author/lakshyajain97/">Lakshya Jain</a>, the CEO of electoral analysis site Split Ticket.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think there would be significant voter backlash,” Jain told Vox. “It would rupture the party and create negative news cycles for quite a while, and the eventual nominee would emerge quite wounded and with a massive amount of ground to make up among Black voters.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, on the logistics front, Harris would be able to make the transition more seamlessly because she could inherit Biden’s fundraising apparatus and campaign staff, as former White House press secretary <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTNUhvweM/">Jen Psaki explained in a TikTok post</a>. “Structurally, she could just move the campaign staff, she could move all their resources over,” Psaki noted.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
 <blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@jenpsaki/video/7390544135414959391" data-video-id="7390544135414959391" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@jenpsaki" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@jenpsaki?refer=embed">@jenpsaki</a> <p>Kamala has been floated as the obvious pick to replace Biden, here are her strengths and weaknesses <a title="msnbc" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/msnbc?refer=embed">#msnbc</a> <a title="biden" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/biden?refer=embed">#biden</a> <a title="harris" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/harris?refer=embed">#harris</a> <a title="trump" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/trump?refer=embed">#trump</a> <a title="election2024" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/election2024?refer=embed">#election2024</a> @MSNBC </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - TheRealPsaki" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7390544158873750303?refer=embed">♬ original sound &#8211; TheRealPsaki</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris</strong>’s vulnerabilities, briefly explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For all the strengths she’d bring as a nominee, there have also been issues Harris has struggled with as vice president, and as a presidential candidate in 2020. And those could haunt her should she be Democrats’ 2024 pick.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, while she’s remained liked by a number of Democratic constituencies, her overall favorability and approval numbers haven’t been the strongest. As a <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">FiveThirtyEight aggregation</a> found, Biden has 37 percent approval from all US voters, while Harris has <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">38 percent</a>. And she’d be seen as a continuation of the Biden administration, meaning she could be simply viewed as “more of the same” by voters who aren’t happy with the policies or positions it’s represented. Per surveys from this past year, voters are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/14/podcasts/the-daily/trump-biden-poll.html">interested in change</a> and have expressed discontent with the status quo.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris also hasn’t always defined herself — and what she stands for — that clearly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, that was evident in how she sought to adopt both progressive and moderate policy stances, seemingly losing members of both constituencies. She’s especially struggled with the left and its often younger voters: Despite her self-described position as a progressive prosecutor, she was called out by grassroots progressives  during the 2019 campaign for actions she’d taken on truancy as well as wrongful convictions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This same overarching issue has emerged in her vice presidency, when some critics have argued that she hasn’t established what issues she owns or been clear about what she’s been able to achieve.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">White House officials have previously highlighted her extensive work on foreign policy, immigration, voting rights, and reproductive rights. That’s a broad portfolio, and staffers who’ve worked with her have described the catch-22 that it can feel like Harris faces: if she chose solely to work on one issue, for example, she risks getting pigeonholed. If she works more broadly, as she has opted to do, she’s criticized for not being dedicated to just one area.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And while she’s been an effective communicator in a number of high-profile cases ranging from her questioning of former Trump Attorney General Jeff Sessions to a major speech she gave on the 50th anniversary of <em>Roe</em>, she’s also been pilloried for statements that have been commonly derided as sounding like “<a href="https://nypost.com/2023/12/20/news/kamala-harris-serves-up-another-word-salad-as-discusses-most-election-of-our-lifetime/">word salad</a>.” Those remarks have prompted some to wonder if she’d be able to be a strong enough messenger for Democrats during this pivotal time.&nbsp;(Others online have embraced some of these remarks including, famously, by making <a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">memes about her coconut tree and venn diagram</a> comments.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her record with staff has been scrutinized by reporters, too, due to the turnover that’s taken place in her office across the roles she’s held, raising questions about her management style. Stories emerged about her <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/kamala-harris-staffers-toxic-office-culture-dysfunction-2021-7">attorney general</a> office and <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/06/30/kamala-harris-office-dissent-497290">her VP office</a> detailing what some staffers describe as a difficult work environment that stemmed from the top. Such reports fuel concerns about what leadership would look like in a Harris White House, though her office is far from the only one to have <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/tracking-turnover-in-the-biden-administration/#:~:text=President%20Biden's%20%E2%80%9CA%2DTeam%E2%80%9D,Biden's%20Cabinet%20turnover%20is%2013%25.">seen turnover</a> in these roles.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And latent sexism and racism among voters is a key worry some Democrats have raised. “I don&#8217;t know that a lot of people want to admit this, [but] I think there are a lot of people who are uncomfortable with a Black woman being the president,” says Carter. Candidates of color and women, including former President Barack Obama, have long had to navigate such biases &#8212; <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna24284188" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna24284188">and electability concerns</a> &#8212; though he was ultimately able to win in spite of them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Overall, these dynamics indicate that a Harris nomination, like any other, would come with both pros and cons. In the difficult situation that Democrats find themselves in, Harris’s strengths could well outweigh her vulnerabilities — if she can address them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, July 21, 3 pm ET: </em></strong><em>This story was originally published on July 13 and has been updated with news of Biden’s endorsement of Kamala Harris to be the Democratic nominee.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Does Kamala Harris give Democrats a better chance to win?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/361750/biden-drop-out-harris-endorse-polls-against-trump-democrats-dnc" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=361750</id>
			<updated>2024-07-21T19:27:40Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-21T18:27:41Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Presidential candidates, and their campaigns, are the sum of all in which they exist and what came before them.&#160; Just after he announced he was withdrawing from the 2024 presidential race, President Joe Biden endorsed his vice president, Kamala Harris, as the nominee in his place — giving her a huge leg up in whatever [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Biden, in a navy suit and blue shirt, and Harris, in a white jacket and navy blouse, clasp hands held high between them, both smiling and standing on a balcony." data-caption="President Joe Biden, left, and Vice President Kamala Harris, on the Truman Balcony of the White House, on July 4, 2024. | Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159971779.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>President Joe Biden, left, and Vice President Kamala Harris, on the Truman Balcony of the White House, on July 4, 2024. | Tierney L. Cross/Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Presidential candidates, and their campaigns, are the sum of all in which they exist and what came before them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just after he announced he was withdrawing from the 2024 presidential race, President Joe Biden <a href="https://x.com/JoeBiden/status/1815087772216303933">endorsed</a> his vice president, Kamala Harris, as the nominee in his place — giving her a huge leg up in whatever process could follow from here. But there are still many unknowns about the future of the Democratic ticket. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the past weeks, amid speculation about Biden&#8217;s future on the ticket, two debates have played out. The first big question is whether Harris will be President Joe Biden’s replacement, or if <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357936/biden-harris-buttigieg-newsom-whitmer-pritzker-convetion-debate-2024">another Democratic politician</a>, like Govs. Gretchen Whitmer (MI), Josh Shapiro (PA), or Gavin Newsom (CA) would do better. The <em>other</em> question circulating among pundits, pollsters, journalists, strategists, and regular folks is whether Harris would be a stronger presidential contender than Biden.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can answer this question in a few ways: looking at data on her prospects, her recent performance on the campaign trail, and her past candidacies. Each of these paths give us limited answers, but to borrow a phrase from former Defense Secretary <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/style/rumsfeld-dead-words-known-unknowns/2021/07/01/831175c2-d9df-11eb-bb9e-70fda8c37057_story.html">Donald Rumsfeld</a>, we can still identify a few “known unknowns” that make the future a bit more divinable.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Coconut-pilled</a> backers of a Kamala Harris presidential campaign argue that Harris runs about even or even better than Biden does against former President Donald Trump <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/">in polling</a>; they point to Harris’s performance on the campaign trail so far, making the case against Trump and the American right’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360318/project-2025-trump-policies-abortion-divorce">plans in Project 2025</a>; and at a base level, they argue that she has been tested on the national stage, while other alternative candidates have not.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>President Joe Biden endorsed Kamala Harris for president. Here’s what to know about her.</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice President Kamala Harris could replace Biden at the top of the Democratic ticket in 2024.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">What happened last time Harris ran for president</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Why is everyone talking about Harris and coconut trees?</a></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/360327/vice-president-kamala-harris-joe-biden-nominee">Harris’s strengths and vulnerabilities as a presidential candidate</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Critics of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/7/25/20697783/khive-twitter-kamala-harris-2020-candidate-doug-hive">KHive</a> — as the online superfans of the vice president call themselves — and the VP argue that Harris is still really unpopular with the American public. They argue that the polls don’t actually show that much of an advantage for Harris in battleground states or with the popular vote; they point to her failed 2019 presidential campaign and her tepid vice presidential tenure as proof she’s not a particularly good candidate or politician and would likely run an uneven campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They also argue that Biden’s flaws and foibles are already built into the electorate’s mind, while the chaos and uncertainty of swapping in Harris would expose the Democrats to even more risks (like how voters react to a woman of color as a nominee).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The debate was the roiling undercurrent of the will-he-or-won’t-he <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361597/biden-drop-out-democrats-obama-pelosi-schumer">drama over Biden</a> these last few weeks. How it resolves now that he is off the ticket could have enduring ramifications for both the Democratic Party and the country.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The upsides to swapping in Harris</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris backers have plenty to point to in the aftermath of June’s presidential debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s the obvious stuff: Harris is younger, can actually string sentences together, and has already been campaigning against Trump this year. These points were once again demonstrated this week —&nbsp;while Biden was forced to recover from Covid at his home in Delaware during the week of the Republican National Convention, Harris was on the trail with North Carolina Democratic Gov. Roy Cooper.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the data says: </strong>First, a caveat: comparing polling of reality to a hypothetical match-up is always a bit treacherous.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What we can say from head-to-head polling of Harris is that the general trend has gotten a lot better for her. A year ago <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/358559/biden-harris-whitmer-newsom-shapiro-buttigieg-alternative-nomination-candidate-2024">she was underperforming Biden in head-to-head polling against Trump</a> in a variety of surveys. Closer to the debate and right after, she began to perform about evenly. And more recently, in July, a few polls comparing Biden and Harris against Trump in battleground states and nationally have shown Harris even with Biden or slightly ahead of him.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first sign of this change came from <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/02/politics/cnn-poll-post-debate/index.html">CNN’s first post-debate poll</a>, finding the vice president trailing Trump by 2 percentage points (within the margin of error) while Biden trailed by 6 points. And in <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/538/kamala-harris-stronger-candidate-biden/story?id=111656941">FiveThirtyEight’s</a> polls-only post-debate comparison of Harris and Biden vs. Trump, Harris performs slightly better than the president in battleground states <em>— </em>though not in all of them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recent polling from Pennsylvania and Virginia also shows more positive signs for the vice president: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/15/us/politics/pennsylvania-virginia-polls-biden-trump.html">New York Times/Siena College</a> polls this month show that while Harris still trails Trump by 1 point in Pennsylvania, that’s a smaller gap than the 3 points that put Trump ahead of Biden there. Both of these results are within the polling’s margin of error, making the race in the state essentially tied. In Virginia, meanwhile, Harris’s lead over Trump is 2 points larger than the lead Biden has over the former president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And a post-assassination attempt <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/race-presidency-remains-unchanged-wake-assassination-attempt-trump">national poll from Reuters/Ipsos</a> shows a statistically tied presidential contest for either Biden or Harris against Trump.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under the hood, however, Harris backers can find an additional data point in their column: <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/sites/default/files/ct/news/documents/2024-07/Reuters%20Ipsos%20Post%20Trump%20Assasionation%20Attempt%20Poll%20Topline.pdf">69 percent of respondents think Biden is too old</a>; Harris doesn’t face that concern. And Biden is more unpopular than Harris, something that is consistently true: As of July 18, Biden has a net -17.7 <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/biden-approval-rating/">approval</a> rating in the FiveThirtyEight aggregate. Harris’s <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">disapproval</a> is at 11.8. And in RealClearPolitics’ average of favorability ratings, Biden (<a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/joe-biden">-16.3</a>) is also more unpopular than Harris (<a href="https://www.realclearpolling.com/polls/favorability/kamala-harris">-14.9</a>)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the campaign trail shows: </strong>Harris backers can point to the vice president’s performance on the road this year and argue that she has evolved as a politician since her presidential run in 2019, and especially since the overturning of <em>Roe v. Wade</em> in 2022 —&nbsp;when she became the White House’s go-to surrogate and messenger on reproductive rights.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She has dominated that issue, both in official visits to states where abortion and reproductive rights have been under threat, and also during campaign swings this year that have seen her become more willing to talk about the <a href="https://abc7.com/kamala-harris-friend-high-school-canada/7846815/">personal experiences</a> that pushed her to become a sex crimes prosecutor and be able to connect with voters in a way Biden can’t.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, she has been playing up that past as a prosecutor — something she was not able to do during her last national campaign against fellow Democrats. “Prosecuting the case against Donald Trump” is now a go-to part of her stump speeches, both in talking about his and his party’s record on abortion and in talking about Trump’s convictions and indictments.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the top of the ticket, she would be able to zero in on this approach against an unpopular Republican candidate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What history tells us: </strong>Before her doomed 2020 presidential bid, Harris had a successful electoral record in California: winning statewide races by tacking to the center or simply pointing out how weird or abnormal her opponents were.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Running as a center-left politician was part of her bid during her first statewide race in California — for attorney general —&nbsp;since she was facing a popular moderate Republican during a red-wave year in 2010, and she was viewed as a liberal Bay Area district attorney. She opposed right-wing positions on gay marriage and immigration enforcement, and cast her opponent as an extremist, while also attacking him for not prosecuting more cases, including sex crimes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her 2016 Senate campaign, meanwhile, showed how she’s able to remain on message and be disciplined —&nbsp;winning support from the Democratic establishment, consistently holding a fundraising advantage, and showing that her Democrat opponent was not a serious candidate. There wasn’t much of a policy difference between Harris and her opponent, former Los Angeles District Attorney Steve Cooley, but she was still able to deliver a landslide win.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even her 2020 campaign shows that she’s a pragmatic thinker — not necessarily tied to a specific ideology that influences the way she would approach issues. She fumbled on policy, and couldn’t make a distinctive, proactive case to the Democratic base in the primary, but she doesn’t have to do that now. Even during this cycle, she has shown moments of pragmatism, too — her position on the war in Gaza, for example, put her to the left of Biden on the issue —&nbsp;but she has found ways to speak to young progressives and voters critical of Israel’s approach while still representing the president.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The risks of swapping in Harris</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the data says: </strong>The major problem in comparing these Harris figures to Biden’s actual standing against Trump is that Biden’s numbers factor in every negative thing that he and his campaign have endured so far. Biden backers would point to the fact that opinions of Harris could still change for the worse as her theoretical campaign becomes not so theoretical anymore, and that her performing about as evenly as Biden against Trump is not that great of a sign when there is more uncertainty about how Harris would even campaign.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On that front, they point to the fact that Harris’s favorability numbers are not that different from Biden’s, and could still get worse. In recent polls, she performs worse than Biden in battleground states like <a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/west-wing-playbook/2024/07/18/so-you-wanted-some-harris-polling-00169524">Michigan</a>, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/kamala-harris-swing-state-poll-donald-trump-1927199">Arizona, and Nevada</a> — losing those states would likely doom a Democratic candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And she doesn’t necessarily do significantly better than Biden when looking at how subgroups of voters feel: She wins the same share of Black voters as Biden in head-to-head matchups with Trump in battleground states, <a href="https://split-ticket.org/2024/07/17/we-polled-black-voters-heres-what-we-found/">per Split-Ticket.org’s polling</a>, and does slightly worse than Biden <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/kamala-harris-biden-stronger-weaker-trump-nbc-news-poll-rcna161520">among white voters</a>, who still make up the majority of voters in swing states and nationally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What the campaign trail shows: </strong>Taking the Kamala-critical position on the data as is — that there’s essentially no difference according to polls in how Harris performs against Trump than Biden — you are justified in being worried about what the campaign trail might look like.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris has only recently, since 2022, been active on the campaign trail, in part because she’s not the most naturally gifted campaigner or communicator. She has found the issues she excels at championing, but that’s only after going through a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/11/14/politics/kamala-harris-frustrating-start-vice-president/index.html">rocky</a> first <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-60061473">year</a> as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/11/kamala-harris-first-six-months-vice-president-joe-biden">vice president</a> when her office saw a variety of staff departures, infighting, and missteps in message.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She received media training during that first year in order to get better at talking about the president’s agenda, but still struggled to define her portfolio —&nbsp;facing intense criticism on immigration and the border when that <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">wasn’t even her original assignment</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/05/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-kamala-harris.html">Reporters</a> who have been <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/10/magazine/kamala-harris.html">covering</a> her tenure point out that she seems most at home when she’s having more roundtable-style conversations, not necessarily in one-on-one interviews or while giving stump speeches.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris critics also point out that she will struggle to convince voters to see her as a legitimate candidate given biases against her because of her race, her gender, and the general idea that she’s not that plugged into the White House inner circle or aware of the day-to-day business of running the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then come the memes. While the genre of <a href="https://www.vox.com/kamala-harris/359072/kamala-harris-coconut-tree-context-unburden-meme-khive">Kamala Harris memes</a> has been exploding in popularity recently because of the chaos over Biden’s own candidacy, those jokes start from a kernel of truth: Harris is an awkward communicator. She’s prone to gaffes, to awkward jokes, to tortured analogies or stories, and is generally perceived as easy to mock.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What history tells us</strong>: Harris critics also have plenty to point to when criticizing her electoral history. Her toughest race was her first race, for California attorney general, when she was the worst-performing statewide Democratic candidate on the ballot, winning her seat by about <a href="https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/elections/2010/results/california.html?ref=politics">1 percentage point</a>.<strong> </strong>Read that again. She nearly lost to a Republican in California.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s the context that this was a red-wave year — the 2020 midterm elections were terrible for Democrats. But in California, she essentially had united Democratic support for her campaign, and still came close to failure — while every other Democratic candidate on the ticket performed significantly better.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She cruised to victory during the 2016 Senate race in part because the whole contest was “<a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/11/2016-california-senate-harris-sanchez-jungle-open-primary-reform-214429/">uninspiring</a>,” and neither Harris nor her opponent were able to excite voters during most of the campaign because Harris’s victory was assumed from the start. She also faced an easy, flawed candidate in that race: a wacky US representative <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1uuyTggFWYc">who famously “dabbed”</a> on stage during a debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And her 2020 presidential contest showed what happens when a candidate lacks clarity about her campaign and reasons for running. She struggled to define herself, and her position on the ideological spectrum, relative to her Democratic rivals. She could not run a disciplined campaign — two rival camps within her operation <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/359620/kamala-harris-2020-president-campaign-2024-failure-lesson">pulled the campaign in different directions</a> for much of the primary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This record shows the legitimate reasons to question whether Harris would be able to make a proactive case for herself —&nbsp;not just a negative case against Trump. She faces the struggle of convincing voters not to blame her for the unpopular results of the Biden-Harris administration, while still thinking of her as presidential material.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s one edge the governors and senators who have been talked about as potential alternatives to Biden have: They wouldn’t carry the same baggage from the Biden administration. Harris will likely be seen as tied to Biden’s legacy,&nbsp;which stands as another reason to look elsewhere.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
