<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-10-08T15:52:13Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Edward Vega</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The real reason cheese is yellow]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/videos/376628/why-is-cheese-yellow" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=376628</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T15:52:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T15:05:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Food" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Video" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[While making a grilled cheese the other day, a question popped into my mind: Why is cheese often yellow even though milk is white? Of course, this isn’t entirely true across the (cheese) board — cheese comes in a remarkable range of colors, from pale white to deep yellow-orange. Take cheddar, for instance — it [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Two photos side by side. Left: a carton of milk being poured into a glass, labeled WHITE. Right: a hamburger on the grill topped with a square of yellow cheese, labeled YELLOW?" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/the-real-reason-cheese-is-yellow.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">While making a grilled cheese the other day, a question popped into my mind: Why is cheese often yellow even though milk is white?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, this isn’t entirely true across the (cheese) board — cheese comes in a remarkable range of colors, from pale white to deep yellow-orange. Take cheddar, for instance — it can be found in both shades. So which color is the “real” cheese?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To unravel this mystery, I sat down with Paul Kindstedt, former president of the American Dairy Science Association and a professor emeritus at the University of Vermont. Our conversation spanned over an hour, delving into the fascinating history of cheese, its evolving colors, and the marketing influences that have shaped our perceptions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the latest Vox video, we dive into it all, shedding light on the surprising connections between color, culture, and the art of cheesemaking — all in less than seven minutes.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Hurricane Milton exploded into a terrifying Category 5 storm in just hours]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/376323/hurricane-milton-category-5-tampa-florida" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=376323</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T12:46:53Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T12:46:50Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between Sunday and Monday morning — a mere 24 hours — Hurricane Milton grew from a tropical storm to a fierce Category 5 hurricane. With wind speeds pushing 180 miles per hour Monday afternoon, before weakening Tuesday morning, Milton is one of the strongest hurricanes ever recorded in the Atlantic.  Forecasters expect Milton, which is [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A satellite image with a swirling storm, red in the middle and blue at the edges, overlaid on a map showing it in the Gulf of Mexico." data-caption="A satellite image shows Hurricane Milton, now a Category 5 storm, churning in the Gulf of Mexico. | NOAA" data-portal-copyright="NOAA" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/1000x1000-2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A satellite image shows Hurricane Milton, now a Category 5 storm, churning in the Gulf of Mexico. | NOAA</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Between Sunday and Monday morning — a mere 24 hours — Hurricane Milton grew from a tropical storm to a fierce <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCUAT4+shtml/071558.shtml?">Category 5 hurricane</a>. With wind speeds pushing <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT4+shtml/072057.shtml">180 miles per hour</a> Monday afternoon, before weakening Tuesday morning, Milton is one of the strongest hurricanes ever recorded in the Atlantic. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Forecasters expect Milton, which is now churning <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/live-updates/milton-forecast-hurricane-tracker/?id=114553995">as a Category 4 storm</a><strong> </strong>in the Gulf of Mexico, to make landfall in western Florida late<strong> </strong>on Wednesday. The storm may lose steam before then as it faces disruptive winds and dry air, yet Milton is still expected to be an “extremely dangerous” hurricane upon arrival, <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT4+shtml/071735.shtml?">according to</a> the National Hurricane Center. Storm surge in the densely populated Tampa Bay, which could see a direct hit, could reach <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT4+shtml/072057.shtml">15 feet</a>, the Center said in an advisory Monday. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Milton is not the typical Atlantic hurricane, according to <a href="https://www.engineering.cornell.edu/faculty-directory/jonathan-lin">Jonathan Lin</a>, an atmospheric scientist at Cornell University. “It is exceedingly rare for a hurricane to form in the western Gulf, track eastward, and make landfall on the Western coast of Florida,” he said in an email Monday. “There are not really any hurricanes on record that have done this and made landfall at a Category 3+ status.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s even more unusual is how quickly the storm intensified, defying forecasts and gaining more than 100 miles per hour in wind speed between Sunday morning and early Monday afternoon. Milton had “some of the most explosive intensification this forecaster has ever witnessed!” a National Weather Service forecaster <a href="https://x.com/NWSAtlanta/status/1843324138230014357">wrote on X Monday</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why Milton intensified so quickly</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The simplest explanation is unusually warm ocean water.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take a look at the chart below. It’s showing ocean heat in the Gulf of Mexico, which is near a record high. The red line is 2024 and the blue line is the average over the last decade.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And heat is a key ingredient in rapid intensification, according to <a href="https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/">Brian McNoldy</a>, a climatologist at the University of Miami, who made the chart below. Put simply, hotter water evaporates more readily, and rising columns of warm, moist air from that evaporation fuel rapid intensification.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/ohc_gulf-3.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.589156124409,100,74.821687751182" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A chart of ocean heat content in the Gulf of Mexico | Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/products.html&quot;&gt;Brian McNoldy&lt;/a&gt;" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bmcnoldy.earth.miami.edu/products.html&quot;&gt;Brian McNoldy&lt;/a&gt;" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not entirely clear what has caused the Gulf to warm, though scientists suspect a combination of factors, including climate change — which raises the baseline ocean temperature — as well as lingering effects of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23738846/el-nino-2023-weather-heat-wave-climate-change-disaster-flood-rain" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">El Niño</a>, natural climate variability, and perhaps even a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/tonga-volcano-eruption-raises-imminent-risk-of-temporary-1-5c-breach/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">volcanic eruption</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another key to Milton’s explosive growth is a lack of wind shear in its path, according to <a href="https://people.miami.edu/profile/be7abbba52c947423b8133238c7e7b68">Benjamin Kirtman</a>, director of the Cooperative Institute for Marine &amp; Atmospheric Studies, a joint initiative of the University of Miami and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). Wind shear describes the change of wind speed and direction —&nbsp;basically, chaotic air —&nbsp;and it can disrupt hurricanes. The storm is expected to encounter more shear as it approaches Florida, which will blunt its strength and make it likely to weaken before landfall.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s more, McNoldy said, is that Milton is also relatively small in width. As of Monday, Hurricane-force winds extended only about <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/text/refresh/MIATCPAT4+shtml/072057.shtml">30 miles</a> from the storm center. Small hurricanes are “generally more prone to ups and downs,” he told Vox, because they’re influenced more easily by weather phenomena.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although Milton is set to grow in size before it reaches Florida (in part, through a complex process of <a href="https://www.aoml.noaa.gov/hurricane_blog/paper-on-the-unusual-eyewall-replacement-cycles-in-hurricane-irma-released-online-in-monthly-weather-review/#:~:text=As%20a%20hurricane%20grows%20older,eyewall%20replacement%20cycle%20(ERC).">eyewall replacement</a>), it likely won’t be huge when it makes landfall &nbsp;—&nbsp;again, speaking in terms of diameter. “That is all-around good news,” he said. Smaller storms tend to produce less surge, which describes a rise in sea level. Compared to Hurricane Helene, which was an enormous system, for example, forecasters expect Milton to produce less storm surge.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That doesn’t mean experts like McNoldy, a Florida resident, aren’t worried. As of Monday, Milton appears to be headed straight for the Tampa Bay area, the most densely populated region of the state’s west coast. This is the same region where a <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hurricane-helene-florida-storm-surge-0284042dade78e04e453ad821e6e15c3">dozen people</a> were killed by Hurricane Helene in recent days.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is a very ominous forecast,” McNoldy said. “It will still be an extremely strong hurricane.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 8, 8:45 am ET:</strong> This story has been updated with new information about Hurricane Milton’s forecast.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Keren Landman, MD</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This popular sex trend is far more dangerous than you think]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/376472/sexual-choking-strangulation-brain-injury-herbenick" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=376472</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T14:14:29Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When did sexual choking become almost as mainstream as the missionary position?&#160; Nobody knows for sure, says Debby Herbenick, a leading sexuality researcher at Indiana University and author of Yes, Your Kid: What Parents Need to Know About Today&#8217;s Teens and Sex. But judging by the way&#160;it’s turning up in music, TV, and social media, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A footed glass dish of vanilla ice cream with a cherry on top is surrounded by a coil of barbed wire against a blue background." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Paige Vickers/Vox; Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/IceCream_Final_KerenLandman_Vox.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When did sexual choking become almost as mainstream as the missionary position?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nobody knows for sure, says <a href="https://news.iu.edu/live/profiles/771-debby-herbenick">Debby Herbenick</a>, a leading sexuality researcher at Indiana University and author of <em><a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/yes-your-kid-what-parents-need-to-know-about-today-s-teens-and-sex-debby-herbenick/19774485">Yes, Your Kid: What Parents Need to Know About Today&#8217;s Teens and Sex</a></em>. But judging by the way&nbsp;it’s turning up in music, TV, and social media, being strangled for sexual gratification is now far from taboo. (Although losing your breath due to external airway blockage is technically strangulation, experts commonly use the term “choking” to describe the practice in sexual contexts.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That tracks with a growing body of research — much of it led by Herbenick — suggesting that a truly astonishing number of young people are choking each other during sex. In surveys she and her team have conducted over the past four years, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39327226/">about half</a> of American college students acknowledge being choked during sex, despite the fact that the practice poses <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9333342/">significant health risks</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like so much of what contemporary humans do in bed, sexual choking initially wormed its way into modern sexual repertoires via <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34696638/">pornography</a>. Now, it’s everywhere, says Herbenick — but often as a symbol of sexual edginess and without the context acknowledging the true risks of the practice.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Judging by the way&nbsp;it’s turning up in music, TV, and social media, being strangled for sexual gratification is now far from taboo</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Young people deserve to have exciting sex lives; “We just want you to live so you can enjoy that exciting sex life,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I talked to Herbenick about why so many people are engaging in sexual choking, what makes it so risky, and how to talk about it. Our conversation has been edited for length and clarity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How common is sexual choking?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a long time, the media narrative on sexual choking has been that it’s rare — but it’s not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In college student surveys we’ve done over the past four years, we consistently find that around 65 percent of young adult women and around 45 percent of transgender and gender non-binary have been choked during sexual activity of some kind. In sex between women and men, it&#8217;s almost always the women being choked and the men doing the choking.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around 25 to 30 percent of male college students also say they’ve been choked during sex. When men get choked during sex, it&#8217;s usually within the context of sex with another man, although though some men do explore being occasionally choked with female partners, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There definitely seem to be some norms where masculinity goes with choking and femininity goes with being choked. There are also some norms around sexual orientation — one queer guy I interviewed said, “My heterosexual fraternity-types of friends, they don&#8217;t get why I want to be choked, whereas, my queer friends get it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These numbers track with the US population at large. It’s not just college students, but other young adults as well. Interestingly, almost nobody over 50 reports having ever engaged in choking.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Where are people getting the idea to choke or be choked during sex?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A lot of young men will talk about pornography as the place where they learned about it, but they also talk about friends and partners, and sometimes about media directed at young men, like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YqQ0JGm7vtY"><em>Family Guy</em></a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For young women and gender-diverse folks, fanfiction comes up a lot. If you go back 10 to 15 years, there&#8217;s a <em>lot</em> of very graphic One Direction fanfiction where people were imagining Harry Styles and his bandmates choking each other and being super kinky together.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sexual choking is also all over social media, especially on TikTok and in memes. We published a paper called <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36526942/">#ChokeMeDaddy</a> where we analyzed more than 300 memes that we found within a minute of searching. And it’s referenced in so many mainstream media shows: <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23762279/the-idol-hbo-review-sex-scenes-lily-rose-depp-boring"><em>The Idol</em></a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/6/23/18701226/euphoria-premiere-pilot-episode-1-recap-zendaya-hbo"><em>Euphoria</em></a><em>, </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/361755/love-island-usa-season-6-finale"><em>Love Island</em></a><em>, </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/368371/love-is-blind-uk-review-couples-spoilers"><em>Love Is Blind</em></a><em>, </em><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/1/8/16853922/lovesick-netflix-review"><em>Lovesick</em></a><em>.</em> The No. 1 song in the country for six non-consecutive weeks was Jack Harlow’s “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Iq8h3GEe22o">Lovin’ on Me</a>,” which talks about choking as vanilla.<br><br>If you are a teenager or a young adult growing up in these media spaces, you&#8217;re going to get the idea that sexual choking is very common, super-normative, possibly even romantic, or expected of you and your partners.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Is it safe?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no risk-free way to engage in choking or strangulation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you have external pressure to the neck that reduces blood flow and or airflow, it is technically strangulation, and there&#8217;s actually a massive, longstanding literature on the health risks of being strangled. In rare cases, people die; there are other cases in which people have a stroke days or weeks or even months later and may not connect it to being strangled.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes, after I give talks on this topic around the country, health care workers stay afterward and tell me about young people they cared for who had strokes and who turned out to have been choked during sex.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>There is no risk-free way to engage in choking or strangulation</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People can have cardiac arrest in rare cases and can also develop thyroid problems or airway collapse, but the much more common scenario is probably a very invisible <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37459254/">cumulative brain injury</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s really good research on strangulation in the context of partner violence that shows people who have been strangled and who have experienced alterations in consciousness — maybe they passed out, felt like they might pass out, or felt disoriented, had tunnel vision, or saw stars. These people are significantly more likely to have <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34596011/">poor mental health</a> and to struggle with <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39304396/">neurocognitive issues</a> over the long term.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Between 19 percent and 30 percent of our students have experienced these alterations while being choked, and a subset specifically <em>want </em>that. Quite a lot of people who engage in sexual choking report losing consciousness, around <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9333342/">3 percent to 5 percent</a>. It seems small, but it’s actually pretty substantial. So we really are concerned there is a sizable portion of the population of young adults who may not realize choking is likely to cause lasting damage to their brain. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of us [researchers] are aware of a reporting mechanism for this. That is something that I&nbsp; would love for the federal government to think about is a systematic way to collect injury and fatality data on sexual choking or strangulation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The best health-related medical advice is, don&#8217;t do it. Don&#8217;t choke other people, and tell your partners you don&#8217;t want to be choked. Find other ways to have sex.&nbsp;It can help people to remember that the sexual menu is vast, and if they like being submissive or they like being dominant or if they like to role play, there are ways to do those things that don&#8217;t risk injury and death.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What advice would you give to people who might feel pressured to engage in sexual choking?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can say early on, in either a relationship or an encounter, “By the way, please don&#8217;t choke me because I&#8217;m not into it.” Or, “Don&#8217;t ask me to choke you because it&#8217;s too risky for me and I&#8217;m not going to do it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If somebody tells you there&#8217;s a safe way to do it, you can respond, “Actually, there&#8217;s really not —&nbsp;so I&#8217;m not going to do it. That&#8217;s my line. Thanks for respecting it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People aren’t getting accurate messages about the risks of sexual choking from online sources. When most of my students hear about the health risks of choking, they generally say no one ever told them that before. And most of them say they’re going to find safer ways to have the kind of sex they want. And then I have a smaller subset of students who say, “I&#8217;m okay with these risks — can you tell me some ways to make it less risky?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What’s your advice for those people? Consent seems particularly tricky in these scenarios.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Choking is different from other kinds of sex in that it involves experiences in which people lose the ability to communicate, which also means the person being choked may lose the ability to withdraw consent. This can get you into really tricky situations — you can be liable for assault if you are having sex with somebody who has lost consciousness, even briefly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For people who choose to engage in it regardless of the risks, really clear consent is key, preferably before you ever engage in choking, outside of a sexual situation. We have heard of too many situations where somebody just chokes their partner without asking, or they get consent by putting their hand on their partner&#8217;s throat and then gauging their reaction — reading the vibe or the energy, when the partner&nbsp;might not feel like they can freely consent in a meaningful way. So there’s a worry there about pressure or coercion.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Really clear consent is key, preferably before you ever engage in choking, outside of a sexual situation</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People who are really more into kink will tell you: Have this conversation when you&#8217;re hanging out, having tea, and planning your sexual event. Don&#8217;t spring it on somebody during sex.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Are there other ways to take a “harm reduction” approach to sexual choking?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stay away from using other items, like belts and cords, or using arms and legs for choking — they’re associated with higher risks than hands. Avoid pressing on the windpipe, but also, avoid pressing on the sides of the neck. Although there’s misinformation out there saying the sides of the neck are safer, they’re not — you’re still risking brain injury and stroke and other harms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Go very, very light. We&#8217;ve had some folks in interviews who say that they didn&#8217;t feel comfortable choking a partner or being choked, so they switched from the neck to the collarbone.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">About 40 percent of our students tell us they&#8217;ve had experiences where they couldn&#8217;t breathe while being choked. If you’re going to engage in choking one way or another, you could tell your partner, “I do like to be choked, but not hard — only at the absolute lightest pressures.” You could also say, “Don&#8217;t ‘choke me out.’”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p> If they’ve seen pornography, if they listen to Jack Harlow, if they watch <em>The Idol</em>, they’ve probably heard about choking</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In our student surveys, about 4 percent of the people who have been choked report noticing neck swelling, which increases the risk for an airway collapse or another complication. If you have neck swelling, you should be observed in an emergency room setting for up to 36 hours in case you suddenly start to struggle with breathing. So for people who engage in sexual choking, it’s worth knowing that if they or their partner has some neck swelling, they should reach out to a nurse or doctor or go to an emergency room and be evaluated.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How should parents be talking to their kids about this?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parents sometimes fear bringing this up because they don&#8217;t want to plant ideas in their kids’ heads. But if they’ve seen pornography, if they listen to Jack Harlow, if they watch <em>The Idol</em>, they’ve probably heard about choking.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if it scares us or worries us, we want to come to these conversations without shaming and judging kids. We can ask them what they&#8217;ve seen, what they&#8217;ve heard — something like, “I&#8217;ve heard that there&#8217;s this trend about sexual choking. Have you or your friends talked about this or heard about it? What do people say about it? What&#8217;s your sense of it?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then, “I want to share some facts with you about it because I have some worries that maybe people your age aren&#8217;t getting factual information about it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are hard conversations. Role-playing it with a best friend or a co-parent or spouse can help parents prepare for them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Is there anything educators can do to talk about it?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ten to 20 years ago, many school systems were faced with the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/mm5901a1.htm">choking game challenge</a>, where kids were seeing how long they could hold their breath or choking each other to pass out. Some kids died, and the CDC issued a warning to parents and to pediatricians. It resurfaced a few years ago as a TikTok challenge and again, kids died.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point is, schools can approach this from a brain health perspective — not as a sexualized thing, but more like, “People should always be able to breathe; the brain needs blood flow to provide it with glucose and oxygen, which are food for the brain. It’s not safe to stop blood flow or oxygen flow to the brain.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At some schools, they can talk about sexual choking in the context of consent; in the rare schools where they can teach pornography literacy, they can talk about this in the context of the bad information a lot of young people get from it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During the first wave of the choking game trend, the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/mm5706a1.htm">CDC issued a warning</a> to parents and to pediatricians. I wish they’d issue official guidance around sexual choking. This is a major public health issue.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, October 8, 10 am ET: </strong>A previous version of this story misstated the level of impairment that 3 percent to 5 percent of students experience as a consequence of being choked; this proportion reports losing consciousness.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[This awkward fish works harder than you]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/375178/parrotfish-algae-coral-reef-climate-change" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=375178</id>
			<updated>2024-10-07T22:16:42Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ocean is full of strange creatures. The parrotfish is no exception. Its teeth are fused into a sharp beak, giving it a birdlike appearance. It’s hermaphroditic, changing sex partway through its life. And to sleep, some parrotfish engulf themselves in a mucus cocoon. Odd and awkward-looking as it may be, this creature is a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A rainbow parrotfish swims in the shallow waters of Bonaire, a small Dutch island in the south Caribbean." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-1411.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A rainbow parrotfish swims in the shallow waters of Bonaire, a small Dutch island in the south Caribbean.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The ocean is full of strange creatures. The parrotfish is no exception. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Its teeth are fused into a sharp beak, giving it a birdlike appearance. It’s hermaphroditic, changing sex partway through its life. And to sleep, some parrotfish engulf themselves in a mucus cocoon.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Odd and awkward-looking as it may be, this creature is a true hero of the ocean.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rising global temperatures, various diseases, and coastal development have been <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24137250/coral-reefs-bleaching-climate-change">killing off the world’s coral reefs</a>, iconic ecosystems that support as much as a quarter of all marine life. By <a href="https://www.cell.com/one-earth/fulltext/S2590-3322(21)00474-7">some estimates</a>, the live area of coral globally has declined by half since the 1950s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the situation would almost certainly be worse if it weren’t for parrotfish.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-9130.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-1443.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-caption wp-element-caption">A stoplight (left) and queen (right) parrotfish on a coral reef in Bonaire. There are dozens of parrotfish species worldwide.</figcaption></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parrotfish are essentially janitors who are very good at their jobs. While cruising around the reef, these animals — which live in oceans&nbsp;all over the world — scrape colonies of bacteria and algae off rocks using their beaks. If left unchecked, that algae can grow out of control, smothering reefs and preventing new corals from growing. And that makes it hard for reefs to recover after a bout of, say, extreme ocean warming kills off a bunch of coral.&nbsp;So where you find hungry parrotfish, coral has more room to grow.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem is that, on many reefs, the number of parrotfish — and especially large ones in the Caribbean — has plummeted. Other algae grazers like sea urchins, meanwhile, have vanished, too. Some scientists say that’s why Caribbean reefs have failed to recover following climate-related impacts like bleaching and superstorms; there’s simply too much algae for coral to regrow.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-4893.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A small queen parrotfish cruises over the crest of a reef in Bonaire." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">On the flip side, these dynamics offer a bit of hope for an ecosystem that seems all but doomed: By protecting parrotfish, alongside efforts to rein in climate-warming emissions, countries might have a better shot at saving reefs.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Reefs are turning green</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there’s one thing people know about coral reefs it’s that they’re colorful — an intricate mosaic of blues, reds, pinks, and oranges.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But more and more, just one color is starting to dominate: green.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-4727-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Dead and dying coral covered with algae." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In step with the decline of coral is the rise of algae, or seaweed. When corals die, this green, plant-like organism grows quickly on top of their skeletons. And as it spreads, that seaweed can prevent corals from regrowing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Baby corals, which start their lives swimming in the ocean, need a bit of bare rock to grow on and harden into adults. When the seafloor is covered in algae, larval coral has nowhere to develop. Seaweed can also release chemicals that harm coral and, when it grows abundantly, shade out reefs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The biggest enemy of corals is really seaweed,” said <a href="https://ocean.si.edu/contributors/nancy-knowlton">Nancy Knowlton</a>, a marine scientist and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Citizens-Sea-Wondrous-Creatures-Census/dp/1426206437?ref_=ast_author_mpb">author</a>, formerly with the Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History. “It goes without saying that reefs will recover better if they don&#8217;t have to deal with lots of seaweed.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://gcrmn.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/GCRMN_Souter_et_al_2021_Status_of_Coral_Reefs_of_the_World_2020_V1.pdf">Research shows</a> that in the last 50 years or so, algae has proliferated in coral reefs worldwide, and especially in the Caribbean.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Algae thrives on human waste, such as sewage, and runoff from farmland. This water pollution is full of nutrients like nitrogen and phosphorus that algae need to grow. So as it runs into the ocean, algae booms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plus, one of the most voracious algae-eaters, the long-spined black sea urchin, began dying in the Caribbean in the 1980s, likely from a waterborne pathogen. Caribbean reefs lost, on average, <a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/docserver/fulltext/marine/8/1/annurev-marine-122414-033857.pdf?expires=1727879230&amp;id=id&amp;accname=guest&amp;checksum=2DB6DBB6E4DADFC68FD0EF5871149AC4">more than 90 percent</a> of their urchins in a matter of weeks, and those populations have yet to recover.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-1433.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="A parrotfish with its mouth against a rock." title="A parrotfish with its mouth against a rock." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Parrotfish teeth are fused together and form a beak-like mouth. It’s the perfect structure to allow them to scape bacteria and algae off of rocks. " data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the important job of constricting algae — of giving corals a better shot at growing and recovering from die-offs — has fallen to certain vegetarian fish, including the parrotfish. In some parts of the Caribbean, parrotfish may be the only thing standing between a relatively healthy reef and one shrouded in green noxious gunk.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Parrotfish to the rescue</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The life of a parrotfish mostly consists of munching on rocks and dead corals, grinding it into sand, and releasing it through their rear ends. Some of the world’s beaches are <a href="https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/sand.html#:~:text=The%20famous%20white%2Dsand%20beaches,then%20excrete%20it%20as%20sand.">largely made of parrotfish poop</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not totally clear what parrotfish are actually eating. <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00338-023-02404-5">Research suggests</a> that their main source of food is colonies of bacteria including cyanobacteria and other microbes that live on rock surfaces, often alongside more visible clumps of seaweed. Parrotfish likely don’t seek out the seaweed itself — the stuff known to be harmful to coral growth and recovery. But when they’re grazing on microbes, they still end up removing it from rock surfaces, according to Andrew Shantz, who studies parrotfish at the University of Hawai’i at Mānoa.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-1499.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="An adult queen parrotfish." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“Irrespective of what they&#8217;re targeting, they end up removing algae from the reef,” Shantz told Vox. “That gives room for corals to come in and settle or grow and occupy that space.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s kind of like how you might weed a garden before planting seeds to give your seedings room to develop.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was produced in collaboration with the Pulitzer Center</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">This is the third story in an ongoing series on the future of coral reefs as they face threats from climate change and disease. It was supported by the&nbsp;<a href="https://bandfdn.org/about/">BAND Foundation</a>&nbsp;and a grant from the&nbsp;<a href="https://pulitzercenter.org/">Pulitzer Center</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Read the first two stories here:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">This coral reef has given scientists hope for years. Now they’re worried.</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/368728/disease-coral-reefs-caribbean-bonaire-solution">These beloved sea creatures are dying. Can human medicine save them?</a></p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms11833">number</a> of <a href="https://esajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ecm.1403">studies</a> have shown that when you exclude large fish including parrotfish from a reef, it gets covered in more algae, and that appears to limit the growth of some corals. <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/278014153_Experiment_mimics_fishing_on_parrotfish_Insights_on_coral_reef_recovery_and_alternative_attractors">One study</a> in Belize, for example, documented less algae and more baby corals when large parrotfish were around. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms14160">2017 study</a> in <em>Nature Communications </em>linked parrotfish to reef growth in Panama by examining historical records of fish teeth and coral fragments. The study relied on reef sediment cores: tubes of material extracted from the seafloor that contain layers of coral, sea shells, and animal remains. Those cores allowed researchers to see how fast the reef was growing and —&nbsp;by looking at the number and shape of teeth — how many parrotfish were on the reef.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-4752.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Danielle de Kool, an ecologist for an environmental group in Bonaire, surveys the reef." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Studies like this support the simple idea that parrotfish help coral reefs, yet the relationship between fish and coral is complex and somewhat controversial in marine biology. Smaller parrotfish, for example, don’t seem to limit the amount of seaweed, even if there are a lot of them. <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Justin-Rizzari/publication/281378099_The_parrotfish-coral_relationship_refuting_the_ubiquity_of_a_prevailing_paradigm/links/603efe7c299bf1e078512fd2/The-parrotfish-coral-relationship-refuting-the-ubiquity-of-a-prevailing-paradigm.pdf">Some studies</a><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00227-015-2728-3"> have also</a> failed to find links between fishing restrictions — which typically lead to <em>more</em> parrotfish — and the amount of algae and live coral. Parrotfish also snack on live coral to an extent, though scientists don’t suspect this causes much damage to reefs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The effect of parrotfish on reef dynamics is not always clear,” said Joshua Manning, a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Colorado Boulder who studies parrotfish. “It’s still safe to say that parrotfish are good for the reef.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What a reef full of parrotfish looks like</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People have been eating parrotfish for centuries in the tropics, and it’s <a href="https://openknowledge.fao.org/server/api/core/bitstreams/e52092a6-3ced-40cb-b965-48e0993f4cdc/content">still common today</a> in many coastal communities throughout the world. (They taste like sweet shellfish, according to a quick Google search). While global population data is sparse, it’s clear that overfishing has caused parrotfish —&nbsp;and especially large parrotfish, which are favored by fishermen —&nbsp;to decline in some of these regions, like <a href="https://ocean.si.edu/ocean-life/fish/despair-repair-protecting-parrotfish-can-help-bring-back-caribbean-coral-reefs">Jamaica</a> and <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00338-022-02315-x">Micronesia</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These declines have almost certainly contributed to the rise of algae.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are also places that have protected parrotfish for decades, where these animals are still abundant and apparently doing their job well. The Dutch island of Bonaire, for example, has banned spearfishing — a common method for catching parrotfish —&nbsp;since the early 1970s. The island, which is just east of Curacao in the south Caribbean, also outlawed the harvest of parrotfish altogether in 2010. While some of Bonaire’s large parrotfish have still declined, it has at least double the number of parrotfish compared to most other Caribbean reefs, <a href="https://www.dcnanature.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/BioNews-StatusOfTheReefs.pdf">according to</a> a 2018 report by the Dutch Caribbean Nature Alliance, a nonprofit.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-2 is-cropped wp-block-gallery-2 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"><img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-0951.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />

<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-7235.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" /><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-caption wp-element-caption">Scenes underwater in Bonaire, home to what some scientists consider the healthiest coral reef in the Caribbean.</figcaption></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All those parrotfish help limit the growth of algae on Bonaire’s reef, according to <a href="https://umaine.edu/marine/people/robert-steneck/">Robert Steneck</a>, professor emeritus at the University of Maine, who’s been studying Bonaire’s reef for more than 20 years. That in turn has helped the coral here survive, he said. Indeed, while much of the Caribbean’s coral has died off in recent decades from bleaching and disease, the reef in Bonaire is still intact; parts of it are <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/366763/bonaire-coral-reef-caribbean-climate-change">still thriving</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s more, Bonaire’s reef has been able to bounce back from large-scale die-offs in the past, <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/marine-science/articles/10.3389/fmars.2019.00265/full">according to</a> Steneck’s research. Parrotfish essentially make this ecosystem more resilient, he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The reality is more complicated. There are a number of reasons, beyond the abundance of parrotfish, why Bonaire’s reef is healthier than other parts of the Caribbean. The island lies below the path of most Atlantic hurricanes, for example.&nbsp;Bonaire’s coral is also not nearly as healthy as it once was. Bleaching has been harming the reef for years. And in the spring of 2023, a wildlife disease <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/368728/disease-coral-reefs-caribbean-bonaire-solution">started sweeping through</a> and killing off hundreds of corals, some of which were centuries old. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Against these mounting threats, parrotfish can do very little. When coral die-offs are unrelenting and pollution continues to flow into the ocean, reefs get overcome by seaweed. Once that happens, parrotfish can’t do much to bring them back to life, Manning said. “At some point, with the intensity and frequency of these disturbances, the parrotfish grazing is not going to be able to keep pace,” he said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/adler_final-5771.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.752607989199,100,78.494784021602" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The author, Benji Jones, swims over a field of staghorn coral in Bonaire." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Nonetheless, reefs are still better off with more of them. Saving coral reefs depends, above all, on policies and corporate efforts to slash carbon emissions, but that doesn’t mean effective fishing regulations don’t also help.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What parrotfish reveal is that individual components of an ecosystem matter.  Take one piece out and the system starts to fail. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We need to protect them, even if only to give reefs a chance,” Manning said. “As long as we have parrotfish, we might have a chance at least prolonging the potential for reefs to come back.”&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nick Bowlin</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaked recordings detail a major environmental agency quietly gutting its workforce]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/376321/usfs-forest-service-seasonal-hiring-freeze" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=376321</id>
			<updated>2024-10-07T20:45:05Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story was published in collaboration with High Country News. Americans visit hiking and camping areas managed by the US Forest Service more than 150 million times each year.&#160; If you have climbed a peak or hiked in a golden aspen forest, paddled a protected river or visited a cultural site on any of the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A group of seasonal workers plant seedlings as part of a US Forest Service reforestation effort. " data-caption="Temporary workers for the US Forest Service work in areas like timber, wildlife, watershed, botany, recreation, and visitor services. Facing budget woes, the agency has confirmed it has put a hiring freeze on all seasonal positions until further notice. | US Forest Service via Flickr" data-portal-copyright="US Forest Service via Flickr" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/50825428786_1435abdff0_k.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Temporary workers for the US Forest Service work in areas like timber, wildlife, watershed, botany, recreation, and visitor services. Facing budget woes, the agency has confirmed it has put a hiring freeze on all seasonal positions until further notice. | US Forest Service via Flickr</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was published in collaboration with High Country News. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Americans visit hiking and camping areas managed by the US Forest Service <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/sites/default/files/2019-09/5082018_national_summary_report_070219.pdf">more than 150 million times</a> each year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you have climbed a peak or hiked in a golden aspen forest, paddled a protected river or visited a cultural site on any of the hundreds of millions of acres of public national forest land, there’s a good chance any federal workers you encountered were not full-time employees.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The agency relies on a large, often underappreciated army of seasonal or temporary workers who clean bathrooms and campgrounds, empty trash cans, maintain trails, welcome people at visitor centers, and do critical research work on the environment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These employees help monitor the health of the public waters and forests the agency oversees, clearing brush and trees that pose wildfire danger and monitoring the health of Alaska’s sockeye salmon. The Forest Service-managed portions of the Appalachian Trail that were damaged by Hurricane Helene will likely be repaired by temporary workers. (Hikers are currently advised to stay off over <a href="https://appalachiantrail.org/news/hurricane-helenes-impacts-on-the-appalachian-trail-and-nearby-communities/">800</a> miles of the Appalachian Trail.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Next summer, however, most of these tasks will be performed by other staff — or not done at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to a looming budget cut, the agency will not be hiring seasonal staff for the next fiscal year, leaving thousands of people out of work and putting essential conservation and biodiversity work at risk.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.cpr.org/2024/09/25/congress-passes-funding-bill-avoids-government-shutdown/">spending bill recently passed</a> by the House <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/inside-fs/delivering-mission/excel/september-2024-chiefs-all-employee-call-hiring-update">gave the agency</a><strong> </strong>around half a billion dollars less than it requested, meaning that the Forest Service, within the Department of Agriculture, faces a large budget cut. Most other environmental and science-based federal agencies also face large cuts. Meanwhile, the money the agency received from <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/8/8/23296951/inflation-reduction-act-biden-democrats-climate-change">the Inflation Reduction Act</a>, the Biden administration’s signature climate law, has already been spent. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this, combined with recent cost-of-living increases for staff, means the agency is feeling strapped for cash. The next year “will not likely be a very robust budget environment,” said Forest Service Budget Director Mark Lichtenstein during <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/inside-fs/delivering-mission/excel/september-2024-chiefs-all-employee-call-hiring-update">an all-staff call in mid-September</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This decision does not apply to the more than 11,000 temporary firefighting positions that the Forest Service hires every year. An agency spokesperson said the Forest Service hired more than 2,500 non-fire temporary employees in fiscal year 2024.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the all-staff call, Forest Service Chief Randy Moore acknowledged that the agency will be forced to struggle without its seasonal workforce.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know that this decision will affect your ability to get some of the critical work done,” he said. “It’ll also be felt deeply by managers and units all across the agency.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the days before the call, news of the hiring freeze spread rapidly through the ranks of temporary seasonal employees. Some heard about it directly from their supervisors. Others found out <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Wildfire/comments/1ffgayw/r6_temp_and_pse_fy25_info/">on Reddit</a>, where a letter announcing the hiring freeze from the Forest Service’s Pacific Northwest region had been posted. Temporary workers who feared for their futures filled the comment sections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was really banking on (seasonal work next summer),” said one temporary employee in an interview, asking that her name not be used, since she is still employed by the agency. “I was also banking on seasonal winter Forest Service positions to get me through the off season, and all of a sudden, all of that was completely nixed.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Temporary employees often face this sort of precarity, piecing together work for the winter when they lose their jobs and health care benefits and then returning to seasonal work for the summer. In many cases, they depend on the agency not only for paychecks, but for housing, living in buildings owned or subsidized by the Forest Service.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The budget cut’s impact on hiring extends beyond seasonal workers. The agency also announced that, with very few exceptions, it won’t be hiring external candidates for any position within the agency, meaning that open positions will have to be filled by current employees. And since seasonal work is a common stepping stone to a permanent role, many temporary workers who hoped for a career in public land management now find themselves at a loss.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">News of the hiring freeze left longtime seasonal and permanent workers shocked and angry. In a recording of a mid-September staff meeting shared by an employee and reviewed by Vox and High Country News<em>,</em> staff at the Gifford Pinchot National Forest in southern Washington stressed the importance of seasonal labor. One man, who identified himself as Trevor, said his “entire program” relies on a “large seasonal crew” and wondered how he would be able to do his job in the future. Another employee referenced years of insufficient funding from Congress that have diminished agency morale. She added the loss of temporary workers would have “agency-wide” negative impacts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We cannot operate without our seasonal staff,” she said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/52941146468_954f2c0ba4_k.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.723395278369,100,78.553209443262" alt="A worker uses a drip canister to light a controlled fire on a hillside surrounded by trees." title="A worker uses a drip canister to light a controlled fire on a hillside surrounded by trees." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="An employee uses a drip canister to light a prescribed fire. Seasonal workers take on important reforestation and wildfire risk mitigation efforts conducted by the US Forest Service." data-portal-copyright="" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Seasonal workers symbolize the backbone of the </strong>Forest Service’s labor force</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They might be “temporary” in name, but the Forest Service’s seasonal employees are a vital source of institutional and local ecological knowledge for the agency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many return season after season, often to the same forests, despite the low pay — often around $15/hour for an entry-level position. Several workers interviewed for this story said they stay on in hopes of snagging a permanent role. These workers are especially vital for field operations, said Jamie Tommins, who worked for several years as a trails and wilderness lead for offices in Wyoming, New Hampshire, and Washington.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It takes most people many years of seasonal work to land a permanent job, and those higher-grade seasonals are where you find all the most knowledgeable field workers,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Permanent employees may be as highly trained, probably from being seasonals themselves first,” Tommins said, “but they’re usually busy under their own administrative load and aren’t always available to get out in the field or train the newer folks.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From building and maintaining trails to planting trees and removing dangerously flammable invasive species like cheatgrass, seasonal employees shoulder much of the work of maintaining the national forests.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I just can’t fathom all the skill and know-how the Forest Service is about to lose,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In practice, temporary employees often wind up doing work far above their pay grade. James Bardo, a biological science technician who works with plants, said this summer in Oregon’s Fremont-Winema National Forest, due to understaffing, he found himself doing rare plant work that would be better suited to an agency botanist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’d never been to southern Oregon,” he said. “I never worked in southern Oregon or anywhere near there. And I was the authority for taxonomy there, and it was just like, I really shouldn&#8217;t be.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bardo worries what cutbacks to the agency’s already paper-thin workforce will mean for important ecological work like preserving threatened species.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It can be problematic when you&#8217;re going to be working in the forest, cutting down trees,” he said. “Do you know that this rare plant species is actually there? Or is it easily confused with something else? … It&#8217;s very concerning as a conservation botanist.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Next summer, this loss of expertise will be felt in countless ways. During the all-staff call, Moore said the agency would scale back services rather than demand more of its reduced workforce.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We just can’t get the same amount of work done with fewer employees,” he said. “So, in other words, we’re going to do what we can with what we have. We’re not going to try to do everything that’s expected of us with less people.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there are some tasks that can’t be set aside easily. A temporary employee, who asked that her name not be used, works in the visitor center at the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument. She described basic chores like emptying trash, weed whacking around buildings to reduce fire risk, and directing overflow parking at the popular site. All these tasks, if left undone, could cause chaos next summer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She estimates two permanent employees will be left to do the work of five people, once the seasonal positions are cut. She imagined the possible consequences: locked gates and closed recreation access, and trails or camping sites left inaccessible. She called it a “disservice to the public” as well as to the employees who will have to deal with the fallout.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You always get people coming in complaining about things,” she said, “but if we’re shutting things down, and there’s trash everywhere, that&#8217;s just going to increase, and it’s very unfair to the workforce that will remain.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/31265633634_abfe7d82f9_k.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.723395278369,100,78.553209443262" alt="A woman in a US Forest Service shirt and hat with a large blue hiking backpack on her back writes on a small notebook attached to a trailhead sign in a forest. " title="A woman in a US Forest Service shirt and hat with a large blue hiking backpack on her back writes on a small notebook attached to a trailhead sign in a forest. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="An employee signs a logbook at a popular wilderness trailhead in Mount Baker Snoqulamie National Forest. | US Forest Service via Flickr" data-portal-copyright="US Forest Service via Flickr" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Important work will grind to a halt</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent years, the Forest Service has attempted to reduce its reliance on seasonal employees, converting approximately 1,400 temporary workers to permanent status. But even those newly permanent employees will feel the budget cutbacks.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of these new positions are known as “permanent seasonal” roles. In a recent <a href="https://www.jamietommins.com/p/seasonal-depression">Substack</a> post about the agency’s hiring woes, Tommins compared the job to that of a public school teacher: “a permanent employee with a long” break, although that break is during the winter, not the summer.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In normal years, employees can extend their terms, adding hours or taking on new work for some extra money. But in its announcement of the hiring freeze, the Forest Service made it clear that permanent seasonal workers will not be able to extend their terms in the coming fiscal year. Meanwhile, many promised promotions are on hold, and some external hiring offers will have to be rescinded.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scott Schell, the executive director at the Northwest Avalanche Center, worries what the cutbacks will mean for his organization, a public-private partnership that works with the Forest Service to provide weather and avalanche data in Oregon and Washington. In addition to vital avalanche data for backcountry skiers and ski resorts, the NWAC also contributes to climate research and weather forecasts for Interstate 90, one of the nation’s major transcontinental highways, which crosses the Cascade Mountains in Washington.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Schell said his office had received an allowance from the federal government to bring on a handful of seasonal employees to do avalanche forecasting, but fewer than in years past.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’re basically going through a kind of triaging matrix,” he said. “There is no way we can do the work we did last year.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why absolutely everyone is obsessed with Moo Deng]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/science/376476/moo-deng-pesto-nibi-viral-animals" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=376476</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T14:41:12Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T10:45:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moo Deng. Pesto. Nibi.  The three are a pygmy hippo, king penguin, and beaver, respectively, and they’re some of the latest celebrities to captivate the internet.&#160; Moo Deng — a 2-month-old pygmy hippo known for her sass and moistness — is perhaps the most viral of the trio, and has attracted upwards of 33 million [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Moo Deng, a pygmy hippo, bites her keeper’s knee." data-caption="Two-month-old pygmy hippo Moo Deng tries to bite her keeper’s knee at Khao Kheow Open Zoo. The cute little hippo has become an internet sensation in Thailand and other Asian countries because of its funny faces. The number of visitors to the zoo has doubled since its birth in July. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Carola Frentzen/dpa/&lt;/span&gt;Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Carola Frentzen/dpa/&lt;/span&gt;Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2172117668.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Two-month-old pygmy hippo Moo Deng tries to bite her keeper’s knee at Khao Kheow Open Zoo. The cute little hippo has become an internet sensation in Thailand and other Asian countries because of its funny faces. The number of visitors to the zoo has doubled since its birth in July. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Carola Frentzen/dpa/&lt;/span&gt;Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/24/style/moo-deng-baby-pygmy-hippo-thailand.html">Moo Deng</a>. <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp3w4nld5e3o">Pesto</a>. <a href="https://apnews.com/article/nibi-beaver-release-massachusetts-governor-d4d96214a18b1c41b8945e2c9d813f98">Nibi</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The three are a pygmy hippo, king penguin, and beaver, respectively, and they’re some of the latest celebrities to captivate the internet.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moo Deng — a 2-month-old pygmy hippo known for her sass and moistness — is perhaps the most viral of the trio, and has attracted <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/asia/southeast-asia/moo-deng-livestream-baby-pygmy-hippo-viral-memes-b2620832.html">upwards of 33 million views</a> across platforms like TikTok and Instagram. Based in Khao Kheow Open Zoo in Thailand, Moo Deng is often seen playfully biting her zookeeper with an exasperated expression, spawning hundreds of memes and a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/danidiplacido/2024/09/30/the-backlash-to-the-snl-chappell-roanmoo-deng-skit-explained/"><em>Saturday Night Live</em> segment</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Viral videos show Moo Deng biting her zookeepers, but that’s nothing new for the global sensation <a href="https://t.co/e8pALAoyZg">https://t.co/e8pALAoyZg</a></p>&mdash; USA TODAY (@USATODAY) <a href="https://twitter.com/USATODAY/status/1841693427286589529?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pesto, meanwhile, is a fluffy king penguin chick who’s risen to fame for just how large he is. He lives at the Sea Life Melbourne Aquarium in Australia and is already twice his parents’ size despite only being 9 months old. He’s been the subject of numerous social media posts and developed a dedicated fan <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/pesto-the-penguin-meet-australias-nearly-50-pound-baby-penguin-capturing-hearts-worldwide-with-its-hefty-fluff/#:~:text=Videos%20the%20aquarium%20has%20posted,to%20one%20of%20Perry's%20songs.">following of millions</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Move over Moo Deng — Pesto is the fat penguin stealing hearts: ‘Chonky king’ <a href="https://t.co/O9wkko50ko">https://t.co/O9wkko50ko</a> <a href="https://t.co/nNe8TScmyG">pic.twitter.com/nNe8TScmyG</a></p>&mdash; New York Post (@nypost) <a href="https://twitter.com/nypost/status/1839714562863517949?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 27, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Nibi is an adorable and vivacious 2-year-old beaver who was rescued as a baby — and is the subject of a recent Massachusetts court battle. At issue was whether Nibi, who resides at Newhouse Wildlife Rescue, had to be returned to the wild. According to Newhouse, Nibi would die if they released her, because she doesn’t yet have the skills to survive. <a href="https://www.change.org/p/protect-nibi-the-beaver-from-unnecessary-removal-from-newhouse-wildlife-do-not-donate-here?source_location=search">Roughly 29,000 people</a> signed a petition calling for Nibi to remain at the rescue, and Massachusetts Gov. Maura Healey has since issued a permit allowing her to do so. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Following public outcry and involvement from Massachusetts’ highest office, Nibi, an orphaned 2-year-old beaver, will not be sent back into the wild and be allowed to become an educational beaver.<a href="https://t.co/WEfSEEnbVj">https://t.co/WEfSEEnbVj</a> <a href="https://t.co/PI6Ao3AmpA">pic.twitter.com/PI6Ao3AmpA</a></p>&mdash; Boston 25 News (@boston25) <a href="https://twitter.com/boston25/status/1841961832191344898?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are a lot of cute animals out there, and humans tend to be attracted to them because of something scientists call “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/neuroscience/baby-schema">baby schema</a>,” the idea that humans generally feel warmly toward creatures that resemble babies because of how protective they are of infants.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Mammals are favorably inclined toward individuals that have infant-like traits: large heads, big eyes relative to those heads, rounded features, and typically an awkward gait,” <a href="https://psych.uw.edu/people/2800">David Barash</a>, a psychology professor emeritus at the University of Washington, told Vox. “These traits are characteristic of human babies and toddlers, so it’s adaptive for us to treat them favorably, to see them as especially cute.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Baby schema alone can’t explain why Moo Deng, Pesto, and Nibi have become so popular, however. While they benefit from their infant-like appearances, they also likely garnered a sizable degree of attention because they have unique personalities that reflect essential parts of the human experience, from frustration at things outside our control to delight in small pleasures. Exposure to animal content, in general, has also been found to provide stress relief, comfort, and escapism at a time when <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/642704/americans-sleeping-less-stressed.aspx">Americans in particular are more stressed than ever</a>. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why so many people are drawn to these animals</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The cuteness factor has always been a big reason that people are drawn to animals — but the internet’s latest faves seem to have achieved a rare type of animal celebrity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And a big part of that could be tied to each animal’s strong personality. <a href="https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20210211-why-escapism-benefits-from-a-dose-of-pandemic-reality?utm_source=html&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=daily_post&amp;utm_content=bbc-grizzard-reality">Researchers have found that people are attracted</a> to content and characters that validate their own experiences, and that reflect their own beliefs or feelings.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We do like to see characters that are going through the same thing we’re going through,” Matthew Grizzard, a communications professor at The Ohio State University, previously <a href="https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20210211-why-escapism-benefits-from-a-dose-of-pandemic-reality?utm_source=html&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=daily_post&amp;utm_content=bbc-grizzard-reality">told the BBC</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When it comes to Moo Deng, for example, her expression of apparent frustration — which commonly takes the form of open-mouthed yelling — embodies the stress and annoyance that many of her fans are experiencing amid ongoing uncertainty in the world. “I love that Moo Deng is fucking annoyed all the time. I can relate,” as <a href="https://x.com/esjesjesj/status/1837347574040158538">one online Moo Deng fan wrote</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nibi, too, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ced0x96lew2o">has been described as a “diva”</a> for her mischievous behavior and playful facial expressions, both of which have resonated with supporters, because they show off <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/04/nx-s1-5140582/nibi-beaver-massachusetts-govern-newhouse-wildlife">a certain aspirational swagger</a>. In one TikTok post, <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kashmeredanny/video/7421965843233262878">comedian Danny Murphy compared</a> her to that of other “2024 icons” like Chappell Roan and Sabrina Carpenter. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Pesto, in addition to his unique identity as a “<a href="https://www.instagram.com/brutamerica/reel/DAlptZPu-7s/?hl=en">chonky king</a>,” — a title some fans have given him — has also become known for <a href="https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pesto-the-penguin-is-big-hungry-and-famous-but-his-size-might-not-last/pbkswg1qq">how much he enjoys food</a>. According to his keepers, Pesto consumes roughly 25 to 32 fish a day, prompting internet observers to share their <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/t/ZTFftCYoo/">similar love of fish and sushi</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you can assign this sort of unexpected emotion to an animal, it’s effective,” Roger Dooley, a consumer marketing expert, previously <a href="https://www.csmonitor.com/Science/2015/0730/Why-do-we-love-grumpy-animal-memes-Science-explains">told the Christian Science Monitor</a>, about the appeal of memes like Grumpy Cat, a feline known for his dour facial expression. “I think we don’t expect our animals to be grumpy, so as a result you have that novelty factor at work too.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Broadly, animal content has also been found to have a soothing effect on people that can help relieve stress by providing distraction or comfort. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/09/27/us/watching-cute-animals-study-scn-trnd/index.html">A 2019 University of Leeds Study</a>, for example, found that showing college students preparing for finals a 30-minute montage of cute animal content helped reduce anxiety, blood pressure, and heart rates. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There&#8217;s no doubt that people turn to all sorts of escapist options when they&#8217;re anxious,” Barash told Vox, noting that pet adoptions and purchases also spiked during the Covid-19 pandemic when more people had heightened stress levels and were looking for support.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like other viral animals that have come before them, Moo Deng, Pesto, and Nibi have gained a following both because their cuteness can be pleasing, and because they’re appearing to convey emotions that reflect how many people are feeling at the moment.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s push for child care failed. What lessons are there for Kamala Harris?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/375488/child-care-paid-leave-build-back-better-harris-ctc-preschool-biden-families" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=375488</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T13:00:55Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Child Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Caregiving policies are having a moment in the 2024 election. Back in June, before President Joe Biden exited the race, the first presidential debate moderator asked both candidates how they’d help families better afford child care, noting that prices averaged over $11,000 per child in 2023. (Both Biden and former President Donald Trump dodged the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A pink banner is hanging on a fence in Washington, DC, and reads “Fund Childcare Now.”" data-caption="Activist group Community Change Action displays a banner supporting child care funding near the Capitol, in December 2023 in Washington, DC. | Brian Stukes/Getty Images for Community Change Action" data-portal-copyright="Brian Stukes/Getty Images for Community Change Action" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1829350627.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Activist group Community Change Action displays a banner supporting child care funding near the Capitol, in December 2023 in Washington, DC. | Brian Stukes/Getty Images for Community Change Action</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Caregiving policies are having a moment in the 2024 election. Back in June, before President Joe Biden exited the race, the first presidential debate moderator asked both candidates <a href="https://www.c-span.org/classroom/document/?22809">how they’d help families</a> better afford child care, noting that prices averaged over $11,000 per child in 2023. (Both Biden and former President Donald Trump dodged the question.) New care policy proposals then surfaced on the campaign trail over the summer, as vice presidential candidate Sen. JD Vance <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jd-vance-child-tax-credit-5000-what-to-know/">endorsed an expanded child tax credit</a> (CTC), followed by Vice President Kamala Harris endorsing her own expanded credit on top of <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/kamala-harris-child-tax-credit-6000-dnc-what-to-know/">a new CTC</a> for families with newborns. <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-09-16/trump-harris-campaigns-struggle-to-tackle-child-care-costs?sref=qYiz2hd0">Both</a> campaigns <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/07/24/kamala-harris-care-economy-biden/">have said</a> they’d fight for paid family leave and Harris recently said she’d <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/18/politics/child-care-harris-7-percent-cap/index.html">cap child care costs at 7 percent</a> of a family’s income.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If some of these ideas sound familiar, it’s because the push for &#8220;care economy&#8221; policies — ranging from paid family leave and an expanded CTC to affordable child care, universal preschool, elder care, and higher wages for care workers — was a central focus for advocates and Democrats during the 2021 <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/10/28/22748554/biden-budget-build-back-better-democrats-child-care-taxes">Build Back Better Act negotiations</a>. However, those <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/12/19/22844969/manchin-build-back-better-setback-biden-social-spending-bill">talks fell apart</a> after Democratic leadership failed to reach a deal with Sen. Joe Manchin of West Virginia, who had concerns over the size and scope of the package. The following year, care policies were ultimately excluded from the <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23293725/kyrsten-sinema-inflation-reduction-act-climate-taxes">$740 billion Inflation Reduction Act</a> Democrats passed into law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Advocates are now pressing politicians to redouble their commitment to care legislation — <a href="https://www.ffyf.org/2024/05/16/new-polling-on-child-care-and-the-2024-election/">citing</a> <a href="https://bpcaction.org/wp-content/uploads/2024-Caregiving-Poll-Results.pdf">polling</a> that suggests such investments are not just good policy but smart politics. Care organizations are particularly pinning hopes on Harris winning in November, as a Democratic victory increases the chances for significant new federal spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But should Harris actually win and advocates get another opportunity to push for federal policy, what, if anything, would they do? How, if at all, are they reflecting on their last failed push, and preparing for the future, especially given the strong chance that Republicans <a href="https://today.yougov.com/politics/articles/50573-republicans-favored-win-senate-democrats-win-yougov-model-mrp-polls">win the Senate</a>? The odds of a Democratic trifecta are low.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the past several months Vox has been speaking with lawmakers, strategists, philanthropic funders, congressional aides, think tank experts, and leaders of care advocacy groups to gauge the future of federal care policy. The interviews revealed a simmering debate over whether advocates should narrow their focus to one or two agenda items in a future legislative push or whether compromise represents premature capitulation, a sign of adopting a limiting &#8220;scarcity mentality.&#8221; Beyond the tactical debate, deeper tensions have surfaced over whether future efforts should focus on the most vulnerable families or build out new programs for more people, and broader&nbsp;questions have emerged about who sets the agenda in Democratic policymaking, and whether there’s room in the party for real dissent.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Should Democrats have prioritized more?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the summer and fall of 2021, as congressional negotiations for Build Back Better were heating up, activists saw a major opportunity to push new investments in paid family leave, child care, elder care, universal preschool and an expanded CTC. How exactly to describe this sweeping legislation wasn’t clear. “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/09/06/us/politics/democrats-biden-social-safety-net.html">Cradle-to-grave</a>” social welfare? A jobs and climate package? <a href="https://whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Build-Back-Better-Economic-Growth-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Human infrastructure</a>?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Sen. Manchin had signaled <a href="https://npr.org/2021/10/13/1044543025/united-against-higher-spending-centrist-democrats-dont-agree-on-what-to-cut-or-k">he opposed spending as much</a> as the White House and House Democrats were prepared to invest ($3.5 trillion over 10 years) and that he disapproved of budget tricks including temporary programs he suspected leaders would try to make permanent later on, advocates were optimistic that with enough pressure, Manchin would come around on most things. Manchin had also emphasized that he opposed expanding the CTC <a href="https://www.axios.com/2021/10/17/scoop-manchins-red-lines">in a way that eliminated its connection to work,</a> but activists believed he’d ultimately cave on that as well, given emerging research that showed how a CTC without work requirements successfully <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/01/27/1075299510/the-expanded-child-tax-credit-briefly-slashed-child-poverty-heres-what-else-it-d">reduced child poverty by 30 percent</a> during the pandemic. Both the White House and Senate Democrats were staking out political capital in declaring an extension of the pandemic CTC to be their top priority, too.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1359569124.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.72626853884,100,78.54746292232" alt="Manchin walks in a Capitol hallway flanked by masked reporters and aides on December 17, 2021." title="Manchin walks in a Capitol hallway flanked by masked reporters and aides on December 17, 2021." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sen. Joe Manchin is followed by reporters as he leaves a caucus meeting with Senate Democrats at the  Capitol on December 17, 2021, in Washington, DC. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">So when negotiations for Build Back Better ultimately collapsed in late December 2021, care advocates, White House officials, and Senate Democrats insisted there was ultimately nothing else they could have done, that Manchin had been disingenuous and never intended to strike a deal in the first place. (Manchin had expressed openness to <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2021/12/20/manchin-biden-child-tax-credit/">policies like a permanent expansion of preschool</a> and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/dc-md-va/2021/10/24/west-virginia-manchin-child-tax-credit/">a larger CTC</a> with a work requirement.) By the time January rolled around, care advocates were loath to adopt any new strategy, insisting they just needed to keep fighting and that eventually Manchin would come to his senses. <a href="https://www.vox.com/22996474/inflation-federal-reserve-nairu-ngdp-powell">Inflation was soaring</a> by that point.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Anyone who challenged this strategic consensus faced consequences. In February 2022, Patrick Gaspard, the president of the liberal Center for American Progress think tank, acknowledged <a href="https://www.americanprogressaction.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2022/02/The-Path-Forward-on-BBB-Gaspard-FINAL.pdf">in a memo</a> that the House’s version of the Build Back Better Act had no path in the Senate, and urged lawmakers to focus on lowering health care costs, addressing the climate crisis, and reducing child care expenses through initiatives like universal pre-K. Shortly after, a coalition of care advocates voted to expel CAP from their group for throwing its weight behind a proposal that didn’t include an expanded CTC.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also in February 2022, representatives <a href="https://www.ececonsortium.org/">from an umbrella group</a> representing large, private child care providers spoke with Manchin about possibly moving forward on expanding the Child Care and Development Block Grant (CCDBG) — a longstanding federal program aimed at reducing child care costs for low-income families. Other care economy advocates grew furious, and accused the group of sabotaging their larger, more progressive agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">(While CCDBG has <a href="https://www.scott.senate.gov/media-center/press-releases/scott-burr-introduce-bill-to-expand-families-child-care-options-build-on-existing-bipartisan-program">bipartisan support</a> in Congress and <a href="https://www.ffyf.org/2022-state-fact-sheets/">is massively underfunded</a>, many liberal child care advocates oppose its work requirement and want to see policymakers increase public subsidies to all or most families, not just poor households.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That was probably one of the ugliest negotiations I’ve seen in terms of stifling folks,” said one child care advocate who requested anonymity to describe their private coalition calls. People who held very senior positions in the Obama administration on child care were saying the same things about moving forward on CCDBG, the advocate added, “and were being met as some sort of public enemy #1.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Democratic Senate aide, speaking anonymously to describe their own private conversations, recalled hearing through the congressional grapevine in the winter of 2022 that Manchin might be open to a deal on expanding CCDBG. This sounded encouraging to the aide, who had already accepted that the window for some sort of investment on the scale of the House’s version of Build Back Better had passed. But when this aide broached the idea of a new path forward with care advocacy groups, they too were met with backlash.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We had some really tough conversations with outside advocates when we tried to change course and got some very bad reactions,” the aide told Vox. “The idea to expand and pump out CCDBG, I think, fell really short of what they were trying to do.” The aide had hoped that, given their boss’s record on championing care policies, advocates would have been more understanding about a strategic pivot, and see it more as an effort to be nimble and respond to an evolving situation, and not about throwing groups under the bus. “Honestly those were very bad conversations and I look back at that time with a lot of sadness,” the aide said. “These things can get kind of intense and personal.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, after more than five months of resisting a new plan, and more than three months after Manchin expressed openness to reviewing a proposal on expanding CCDBG, Sens. Patty Murray and Tim Kaine <a href="https://www.help.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Revised%20Child%20Care%20and%20Preschool%20Reconciliation%20Proposal%20One%20Pager_%20FINAL.pdf">released a proposal</a> to expand CCDBG aid <a href="https://www.clasp.org/publications/fact-sheet/child-care-early-education-reconciliation-proposal-could-reach-1-million-children/">for more than a million</a> new children. But most political observers felt it was too little, too late, and that the door for reaching a deal had closed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I mean, it was like a Hail Mary, you could see the window was closing and that’s finally when [advocates] came to try and find some compromise,” said one leader who supported pivoting much earlier. “There was this mentality that if you show your willingness to compromise early it’s going to kill your chances, and I think it was ultimately their unwillingness to compromise earlier that killed it.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When does perfect become the enemy of good?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The last few years seem to have revealed that within the Democratic Party, there’s not much space for debating competing care policy ideas.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the fall of 2021, as advocates began circling the wagon to get their policies through congressional negotiations, Matt Bruenig, the founder of the left-wing People’s Policy Project, came out with a number of critiques about the package — for instance, that the Senate’s paid leave bill would <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2020/03/08/family-act-would-deny-benefits-to-one-third-of-new-parents/">exclude at least 30 percent</a> of new parents, that <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2021/09/09/the-house-paid-leave-proposal-is-awful/">the House’s version</a> was full of giveaways to insurance companies, that the proposed child care bill could lead to <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2021/10/20/democratic-child-care-plan-will-spike-prices-for-the-middle-class-by-13000/">massive hikes in cost</a> for middle-class families, and that pre-K and child care bills were crafted in ways that <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/2021/11/22/build-back-better-does-not-implement-the-child-care-and-pre-k-plans/">made adoption by Republican states unlikely</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democratic lawmakers and care advocates “mov[ed] quickly to dull a dagger,” as <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/10/21/democrats-defend-child-care-plan-516568">Politico put it at the time</a>. Child care proponents publicly dismissed Bruenig, arguing he wasn’t closely reading the legislation and was spreading “<a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2021/10/21/democrats-defend-child-care-plan-516568">a viral set of misinformation</a>.” Paid leave advocates <a href="https://prospect.org/health/paid-leave-advocates-wont-push-back-on-payouts-to-private-insurance/">similarly declined</a> to raise any concerns. “I trust the judgment of the Ways and Means Committee and of politicians who need to square the fact that there are lots of different interests at play,” one national paid leave advocate told the American Prospect when questioned about the insurance giveaways. Another said they were <a href="https://prospect.org/health/paid-leave-advocates-wont-push-back-on-payouts-to-private-insurance/">not “choosing fights”</a> as negotiations progressed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bruenig wasn’t the only person to notice weaknesses in the bills. When another think tank analyst raised issues, they <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/rigorous-accurate-policy-analysis">were similarly told to keep quiet</a>. Anyone raising concerns at this vulnerable negotiating stage was <a href="https://x.com/JulieKashen/status/1465707544643395595">letting perfect</a> be <a href="https://www.vox.com/22744837/house-senate-democrats-build-back-better-child-care">the enemy of good</a>, or not grasping that this was the best possible version lawmakers could pass at this time, and that modifications could always be made later.<br><br>Except a few weeks after Bruenig&#8217;s critique about rising child care costs for unsubsidized families, Senate Democrats quietly revised their bill, significantly raising the income threshold to address that concern.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similar dynamics emerged the next year when attempts to strike a new deal with Manchin were met with fierce outcry. The incentives to keep one’s head down and go along with the coalition were real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bruenig has called this policymaking apparatus both dysfunctional and undemocratic. “If this nightmarish process actually generated good policy that was put into law, maybe you could forgive people for engaging in it,” he wrote <a href="https://jacobin.com/2022/05/democrats-policymaking-apparatus-is-wildly-dysfunctional-and-undemocratic">in May of 2022</a>. “But in reality, it keeps generating extremely broken policies that mostly don’t pass anyway and that fail to live up to expectations even when they do.”<br><br>Even if some believe it’s unwise to debate legislative details during ongoing negotiations, since the passage of the Inflation Reduction Act, there’s been little space or energy to explore alternative ideas. “Now is allegedly supposed to be the time when people are to say, ‘Okay, let’s hash it out,’ but it still doesn’t happen,” Bruenig told Vox.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Care advocates think they deserve more credit for coming close</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As it became even clearer over the summer of 2022 that child care investments were not going to be part of what ultimately became the Inflation Reduction Act, child care advocates began ramping up threats of economic calamity. A <a href="https://www.ffyf.org/2022/07/18/joint-statement-senate-must-make-good-on-promise-to-solve-child-care-crisis/">letter sent that July</a> from 26 national organizations warned lawmakers that omitting child care aid from the reconciliation package would push the early childhood sector “closer to a catastrophic funding cliff that will affect America’s entire economy” and “preven[t] countless moms from pursuing economic security — let alone economic success.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These warnings continued to escalate over the next two years. The following summer, <a href="https://tcf.org/content/report/child-care-cliff/">advocates warned</a> that if Congress failed to renew expiring Covid-19 child care funding, then 70,000 child care programs would likely close, resulting in 3.2 million children losing access to care, and mothers in particular would be forced to quit their jobs or work part-time. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This “child care cliff” idea originated with the left-wing Century Foundation and was echoed by Democratic and union leadership like Sen. Murray and AFL-CIO President Liz Shuler. It was repeated in more than a dozen national news outlets, including <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/21/upshot/child-care-daycare-disruptions.html">the New York Times</a>, the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/08/27/child-care-funding-crisis/">Washington Post</a>, <a href="https://www.axios.com/2023/09/20/child-care-cliff">Axios</a>, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-09-06/child-care-funding-expiration-risks-disrupting-women-s-work-force-gains?embedded-checkout=true&amp;sref=qYiz2hd0">Bloomberg</a>, the <a href="https://www.wsj.com/us-news/education/as-pandemic-funds-expire-child-care-centers-struggle-to-survive-6cefdf5b">Wall Street Journal</a>, and <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/biden-child-care-cliff-us-economy-rcna103631">MSNBC</a>. As I reported at the time, leading experts quietly disagreed with the scope of the projected closures, but <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/23892133/child-care-daycare-pandemic-emergency-providers">were staying quiet</a> so as to not upset others in their child care coalition. And indeed, industry-wide collapse never followed, while more moms with <a href="https://www.hamiltonproject.org/publication/post/prime-age-women-are-going-above-and-beyond-in-the-labor-market-recovery/">preschool and school-age children</a><strong> </strong>subsequently joined the labor force. Jobs in the child care sector continued <a href="https://cscce.berkeley.edu/publications/brief/child-care-sector-jobs-bls-analysis/">to grow, too</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Looking back, White House aides maintain they did all they could have done to reach a deal with Manchin on care policies, as evidenced by the fact that they were ultimately able <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23955967/joe-manchin-climate-change-senate-biden-inflation">to negotiate successfully with him</a> on climate change.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Leading care advocates also deny any missteps. They say that, upon reflection, they are proud of all they have accomplished over the last four years, despite losing the bruising reconciliation fight. They point to wins like the new Biden <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2024/02/29/biden-harris-administration-announces-new-rule-reduce-costs-more-than-100000-families-receiving-child-care-subsidies.html">administration rule</a> to lower child care costs, a <a href="https://19thnews.org/2023/04/pump-act-what-it-does-lactating-workplace/">new law protecting nursing parents</a>, and that care agenda policies have remained a top priority lawmakers regularly highlight.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In the Build Back Better fight, the care community was able to get care policies out of the US House, even though that was not assured for quite a long time, and we lost by just one vote in the US Senate,” said <a href="https://www.momsrising.org/blog/users/kristin">Kristin Rowe-Finkbeiner</a>, the executive director of MomsRising, a national advocacy group. “As a community we were punching above our weight. We did get care through the administrative level and through the House so what that means is we have to double down now.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a post-mortem of the Build Back Better fight published by the progressive think tank New America, care leaders interviewed similarly praised the coalition for being small and mighty. “While the outcome of the Biden administration’s Build Back Better (BBB) social agenda is widely known, much of the progress care advocates made given their minuscule financial resources is a big success story that deserves more attention,” <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/better-life-lab/reports/a-playbook-to-transform-how-america-cares/key-findings">the report said</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though some have argued advocates erred in refusing to pick one or two policies to focus on, activists publicly maintain that they are ultimately stronger if they push multiple programs all together.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In their <a href="https://tcf.org/content/commentary/the-top-six-lessons-from-arpas-care-economy-investments/">own post-mortem</a> of the American Rescue Plan, the Century Foundation pointed to historic levels of funding for child care and home care as evidence that “a holistic framework across care movements and strategies is impactful.” The liberal think tank argued that trying to silo aspects of the care agenda from one another “creates a scarcity myth and a fight for resources and helps maintain unfair power structures.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What care advocates see in the climate movement</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://elliothaspel.com/">Elliot Haspel</a>, the author of <em>Crawling Behind: America&#8217;s Child Care Crisis and How to Fix It</em>, says part of the challenge of figuring out strategy is that child care advocacy does not have a single leader or single organization. “In some ways [this] means more voices can be heard, more small-d democratic, but it also can create challenges,” he told Vox, contrasting this with the 1990s, when the Children Defense Fund, and specifically its leaders Marian Wright Edelman and Helen Blank, “were basically the child care points of contact.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Past legislative battles may offer insight: following the <a href="https://www.healthaffairs.org/doi/10.1377/hlthaff.14.1.66">defeat of universal health care</a> under President Bill Clinton and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/03/26/science/earth/26climate.html">cap-and-trade for carbon emissions</a> under President Barack Obama, advocates for health care reform and climate went through years of painful reflection and recalibration of their tactics and goals. To get legislation through the legislative process, leaders agreed, they’d have to change course.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Health care proponents had to figure out how to bypass a strong suspicion of socialized medicine. So, with the past failed health care push top of mind, lawmakers drafted the Affordable Care Act to allow for a market-based approach with industry buy-in. Meanwhile, climate advocates realized that they had <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/biden-pass-climate-legislation-1140934/">overestimated the power of businesses</a> in the GOP coalition &nbsp;An <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2013/01/16/why-has-climate-legislation-failed-an-interview-with-theda-skocpol/">influential 2013 report</a> by a Harvard scholar helped push the climate movement in its next decade to embrace grassroots activism, while practical experience led climate groups to negotiate more concertedly with Manchin in 2022 to get the IRA over the finish line.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The care movement has had no comparable recalibration, at least yet. If anything, top care leaders point to the climate movement not as a coalition that had to make tough strategic compromises but as an example of the power of big political spending and a commitment to fighting over many years. “What’s the difference between the climate change movement and the care movement?” Rowe-Finkbeiner, of MomsRising, asked <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/better-life-lab/reports/a-playbook-to-transform-how-america-cares/key-findings/">in the New America report</a>. “Tens of million dollars and several decades [of concerted organizing].”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The report noted that the top three environmental lobbying groups outspent care lobbying groups in 2021 and 2022 about three to one. In addition to investing more political dollars, the New America review recommended building a bigger coalition including more faith leaders and businesses, working with Hollywood to feature more diverse characters and storylines about caregiving, and getting serious about publicly battling the opposition, such as large industry groups that fight corporate tax increases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An aide for Sen. Murray also pushed back on the idea that there’s not enough room to update ideas, noting their boss’s Child Care for Working Families Act, which <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/senate-bill/1354">has 42 co-sponsors</a>, has evolved based on feedback, with <a href="https://www.murray.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/The-Child-Care-for-Working-Families-Act-Summary.pdf">newer changes including</a> the expansion of eligibility and increased grants to providers.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1247642689.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.198952879581,100,75.602094240838" alt="Sena. Patty Murray speaks outside to a crowd in front of a rally sign that says “Care Can’t Wait.”" title="Sena. Patty Murray speaks outside to a crowd in front of a rally sign that says “Care Can’t Wait.”" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sen. Patty Murray (D-WA) speaks on stage as activists gather in DC to advocate for federal care legislation in 2023. | Paul Morigi/Getty Images for Caring Across Generations" data-portal-copyright="Paul Morigi/Getty Images for Caring Across Generations" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“This was the product of countless discussions with other Senate offices, unions, policy experts, and other stakeholders,” the aide said. “Murray wanted to write a bill that could win the most possible support to actually get passed into law.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where things might go after the election</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In interviews with advocates, aides and policy experts, I’ve tried to glean a clearer sense of what might happen with care policies should Harris win in November. Some activists declined to discuss hypothetical scenarios at all, saying they would not “negotiate against themselves” by publicly signaling what they might compromise on, but others were willing to get more specific.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Assuming Harris wins but lacks a Washington trifecta, the two most commonly cited ideas I heard were an expansion of the CCDBG program for low-income families — as that’s something Republicans generally support — and an expansion of the child tax credit, as that bipartisan program is also set to expire next December, so Congress will likely plan to reauthorize it in some form.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One area of tension will likely be over whether to expand the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC), which helps parents offset the cost of child care. Supporters of expanding the credit say it will make any deeper investments in the CCDBG go further, by making child care both more affordable and more accessible. Rates for CDCTC <a href="https://www.ffyf.org/resources/2024/09/understanding-the-difference-between-the-child-tax-credit-and-the-child-care-tax-credit/">were last set in 2001</a>, so they have not kept up with inflation and other increases in care costs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a monumental opportunity that should not be squandered,” said <a href="https://www.ececonsortium.org/bio/radha-mohan/">Radha Mohan</a>, the executive director of the Early Care and Education Consortium, which is lobbying for the expansion of the CDCTC. Other progressive child care groups have opposed it, as they see it as further entrenching a child care financing system they want to ultimately move away from. The White House declined to endorse expanding the CDCTC in its latest budget, favoring a new child care entitlement instead, though Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-child-tax-credit-awareness-day-and-releases-guidance-for-unprecedented-american-rescue-plan-investments-to-support-parents-and-healthy-child-dev/">did support increasing the tax credit</a> in the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Aides say there is a real sense within the Democratic caucuses that lawmakers need to do <em>something</em> on care, since it was so clearly left on the cutting room floor in 2022. Some child care advocates worry that lawmakers might try to frame existing proposals to expand the CTC as sufficient. The National Women’s Law Center <a href="https://nwlc.org/resource/the-child-tax-credit-is-great-but-it-wont-solve-the-child-care-crisis/">put out a brief</a> last week on this concern, arguing that the CTC and child care should not be seen as interchangeable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">(There’s no doubt that many of these policies and acronyms can be confusing. In the first presidential debate, Biden mistakenly referred to the CTC, which can be used for any costs associated with raising kids,&nbsp; as <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tax-credit-update-biden-wants-make-new-savings-permanent-1926151">a “child care tax credit”</a> — causing stress among child care advocates that the two will continue to be conflated.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other care advocates are looking at the expiration of the Tax Cuts and Jobs Act next year as a fresh opportunity for advancing their own priorities, since Republicans likely will agree to new social spending in exchange for renewing their business tax breaks. The real question is how much money will exist to support care policies given other commitments. Harris, for her part, has already pledged to bring back the pandemic-era CTC and create a new CTC for newborns, two items that could cost <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/research/all/federal/kamala-harris-tax-plan-2024/">up to $1.6 trillion</a> over 10 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some experts say lawmakers should not be afraid to go back to the drawing board. There is a tendency for groups to become “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Path_dependence">path dependent</a>” on old ideas, even if there are better, more effectively designed policies out there.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bruenig, for example, <a href="https://www.peoplespolicyproject.org/projects/family-fun-pack/">advocates for</a> universal free child care along with home care allowances for those who don’t want to send their kids to day care. He believes these policies would&nbsp;be easier and fairer to implement than&nbsp; Democratic proposals aimed at <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2024-09-26/the-problem-with-harris-plan-to-cap-child-care-costs?sref=qYiz2hd0">capping costs at 7 percent</a> of a family’s income. He also says <a href="https://jacobin.com/2023/05/minnesota-paid-parental-leave-income-benefit-exclusion">there’s no reason</a> all the Democratic paid leave bills have to exclude nearly a third of new parents. In<strong> </strong>the next session of the Maryland state legislature, Democratic Del. Vaughn Stewart, with Bruenig’s help, will be introducing a bill to close that loophole in Maryland’s paid leave law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A divided government may force advocates to embrace more bipartisan solutions, and there are some signs that such work has already started. A new bipartisan working group of 30 child care experts and analysts convened throughout 2023 <a href="https://convergencepolicy.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/Convergence-Collaborative-on-Supports-for-Working-Families-Blueprint-for-Action.pdf">to try and find common ground</a>, and new bipartisan working groups <a href="https://thehill.com/opinion/congress-blog/3771742-regardless-of-party-moms-in-congress-agree-its-time-for-paid-family-leave/">in the House</a> and <a href="https://www.hassan.senate.gov/news/press-releases/gillibrand-cassidy-houlahan-bice-lead-bipartisan-bicameral-paid-leave-working-group-to-request-input-on-paid-leave-proposal">Senate</a> also launched last year to focus on paid leave.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether advocates would push for some or all of their care priorities together remains an open question. Rowe-Finkbeiner stressed that it’s important “the policies move together,” saying&nbsp;it’ll take a combination of them to&nbsp; help families the most.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sen. Murray is optimistic that if Democrats win the Senate, it will be a Democratic majority that’s “markedly different” from the last time, and one that’s ready to make serious, long-term investments in child care. But if they don’t win the Senate, Murray told me, Democrats will still act. “I will always talk to anyone and everyone to make progress on child care in every single way possible,” she said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This work was supported by a grant from the Bainum Family Foundation. Vox Media had full discretion over the content of this reporting.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The strategy that might decide Pennsylvania — and the election]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/375904/pennsylvania-kamala-harris-donald-trumplose-by-less-rural-black-suburb-voters" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=375904</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T14:50:55Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-08T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[PENNSYLVANIA — Ahead of November, both political parties have made a similar bet: that they can boost their odds of winning key swing states by going on offense in places they don’t normally compete. For Republicans, that means building on the 2020 trends that saw their candidates, led by Donald Trump, make inroads among a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at a rally in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania, on September 13. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Dominic Gwinn/Middle East Images/AFP&lt;/span&gt; via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Dominic Gwinn/Middle East Images/AFP&lt;/span&gt; via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2171015241.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris speaks at a rally in Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania, on September 13. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Dominic Gwinn/Middle East Images/AFP&lt;/span&gt; via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">PENNSYLVANIA — Ahead of November, both political parties have made a similar bet: that they can boost their odds of winning key swing states by going on offense in places they don’t normally compete.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Republicans, that means building on the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23770342/latino-voters-democrats-2022-2024-election-new-reality">2020 trends</a> that saw their candidates, led by Donald Trump, make inroads among a swath of working-class voters of color, especially in urban centers. For Democrats, that looks like holding down GOP margins of victory in rural regions and accelerating changes in suburbs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With just a few weeks left until Election Day, the key to making these strategies work may be the ground operations each side has built up to make the case to new, undecided, or persuadable voters. To get a better picture of what this looks like, <a href="https://megaphone.link/VMP1489740388">I teamed up with <em>Today, Explained</em> producer Miles Bryan</a> to examine the ground game and the pitches Republicans are using to win over Black and Latino voters in Philadelphia, and that Democrats are using to turn out low-propensity or undecided Democratic and independent voters in rural and suburban areas like Lancaster County.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The side best able to do this may end up reaping the biggest prize of 2024: Pennsylvania’s 19 electoral votes and the presidency.</p>

<iframe frameBorder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1489740388" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Republicans have a clear message, but a shambolic operation</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Early in September, Miles and I drove up to North Philadelphia. We had received word that a “Black Voters for Trump” <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/race-politics/4864000-black-conservative-federation-bus-tour/">bus tour</a> would be making a few stops in the city as part of a five-state <a href="https://www.wypr.org/wypr-news/2024-09-13/tiny-baltimore-crowd-gathers-for-final-stop-of-black-voters-for-trump-tour">swing</a> to motivate and mobilize Black Republican voters. The first stop of the day would be at a cheesesteak takeout in Nicetown, a predominantly Black neighborhood.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Organized by the Black Conservative Federation, one of the main Republican-aligned groups campaigning with Black voters on Trump’s behalf, the tour was meant to drill down on the central kitchen-table pitches Republicans have been using to take advantage of trends in election polling and political surveys: namely, that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373535/3-theories-gop-donald-trump-nonwhite-voters-hispanic-black-latino-asian">Democrats’ hold on Black voters seems to be weakening</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2024/08/22/black-voters-support-harris-over-trump-and-kennedy-by-a-wide-margin/">National polls</a> still <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/race-and-ethnicity/2024/05/20/an-early-look-at-black-voters-views-on-biden-trump-and-election-2024/">show</a> Democrats winning the lion’s share of this segment of the electorate, but also find Trump increasing his level of support from 2020. Black Republican party identification has also been increasing among the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/04/09/age-generational-cohorts-and-party-identification/">youngest segment</a> of this electorate, and though Vice President Kamala Harris appears to have <a href="https://x.com/admcrlsn/status/1838038449703567570">reconsolidated</a> support from Black voters compared to President Joe Biden’s now-defunct reelection campaign, she’s still <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/16D9GSxqF5LFIRTcoVJlvWWefU_h-ZMzlomghgbvYRaM/edit?gid=1863533280#gid=1863533280">not hitting his 2020 margins</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Nicetown, Florida Rep. Byron Donalds, one of Trump’s key Black surrogates, told us he thinks this disaffection is being driven by economic nostalgia and frustration with immigration and crime.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Black people are sick and tired of being sick and tired, man,” Donalds said. “I&#8217;ve been in North Carolina, been in Wisconsin, been in California, here in Philadelphia, obviously in Florida, Texas — it doesn&#8217;t matter. The story remains the same.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Plenty of Black and Latino voters, he said, don’t trust Democrats to handle the nation’s economy, to lower prices, or to improve daily life —&nbsp;and when they compare their finances today to life before the pandemic, they can’t help but wish for a change. It’s a pitch <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373535/3-theories-gop-donald-trump-nonwhite-voters-hispanic-black-latino-asian">I’ve explained previously for Vox</a>, and it sounds like a compelling message —&nbsp;but it’s hard to persuade people if no one shows up.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the tour bus pulled up in front of Max’s Steaks, it arrived at a nearly empty scene. There were no crowds, a few local reporters, and just a solitary Trump sign, nestled on a chair near the shop’s entrance. Plenty of passersby heckled the BCF staffers and volunteers that began to talk to customers, but eventually Donalds and other surrogates did meet some receptive ears, like Sharita White, a Black woman living in Kensington — a <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2024/02/20/1232496906/addiction-opioid-overdose-kensington-philadelphia-zombie-tranq">rougher part of Philadelphia</a> hit hard by heroin addiction and the fentanyl crisis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I&#8217;m in a neighborhood that I don&#8217;t want to be in, but if Trump gets in his chair that can change. I might [be able to] move,” White told us. “I need to survive. And these streets of Philadelphia, it seems like they’re turning into New York now. Everything is high here. People can’t even afford a water. I don&#8217;t know too much about politics, but the only thing I know, my income’s changed. And if I need that man to get into the chair to fix my income, I’m all down.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">White is the kind of voter Trump and Republicans are hoping will turn out in big cities like Philadelphia, Pittsburgh, Atlanta, Phoenix, Detroit, and Milwaukee, which net Democrats the big leads they need to win swing states like Pennsylvania, Georgia, Arizona, Michigan, and Wisconsin. In Philadelphia, at least, there are signs that these more diverse working-class neighborhoods are <a href="https://www.inquirer.com/politics/election/inq2/philadelphia-working-class-voters-republican-20241001.html">becoming more competitive</a>. But receptive voters don’t mean much if you don’t have a way of activating them on Election Day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We noticed that no one took down White’s information or checked her registration status, or logged her in any system to try to follow up with her and get her to vote. The same dynamic unfolded at the second stop of the tour, a soul food restaurant in the middle-class Germantown neighborhood.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2174706569.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A booth highlights efforts to sign up voters at the Bayfront Convention Center before a campaign rally for former President Donald Trump on September 29, 2024, in Erie, Pennsylvania. | Jeff Swensen/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright=" Jeff Swensen/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This disconnect between potentially gettable voters and the organizing work needed to turn them out is a recurring <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/14/us/politics/trump-voter-outreach-super-pacs.html">problem</a> with the GOP’s ground game. Grassroots and local work is primarily being run by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/10/us/politics/2024-election-gop-black-men-voters.html">outside groups</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/14/us/politics/trump-voter-outreach-super-pacs.html">PACs</a> like the Black Conservative Federation, not the Republican Party. These groups are hiring canvassers, doorknockers, and staffers who <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/trump-allies-launch-20-million-effort-to-reach-young-men-e65aeb31">register</a> people to vote at Trump rallies, but in many cases rally attendees are from out of state. This <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/sep/09/trump-campaign-rnc-ground-game-pacs">reliance</a> on outside groups has <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/republican-activists-say-little-sign-of-door-knocking-for-trump-in-swing-states">raised flags</a> among <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/30/republicans-alarm-trump-ground-game-00181577">longtime</a> Republican operatives, who warn that outreach and resource distribution by outside groups may be inefficient, and that local volunteers and longtime activists often know their neighborhoods and how to persuade voters better than paid staff do.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Democrats’ renewed ground game aims to lose by less</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats’ 2024 ground game stands in stark contrast to the GOP’s shortcomings, and could allow them to reverse a trend that has locked the party into close races in cycle after cycle.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, Democratic support in rural communities has collapsed in recent decades, in some cases allowing Republicans to overcome the big leads Democrats rack up in cities and their surrounding suburbs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1996, for example, Bill Clinton won 1,100 rural counties. By 2008, Barack Obama won 455. And in 2020, Joe Biden won just 194, leading to a rural Republican romp that put Donald Trump within striking distance of victory yet again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So ahead of 2024, Democrats set out to stem this bleeding. Biden and his cabinet spent much of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/biden-administration-releases-rural-playbook-launches-building-a-better-america-rural-infrastructure-tour-to-highlight-impact-of-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-on-rural-america/">2022</a>, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-biden-touts-new-economic-opportunity-in-rural-america-during-minnesota-visit">2023</a>, and early <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/02/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-investing-in-rural-america-regional-event-series-to-highlight-how-the-president-is-delivering-for-rural-communities/">2024</a> visiting rural communities to talk up the massive investments being made through the Inflation Reduction Act and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. While he was still the presumed Democratic nominee, Biden and his campaign began to set up field offices in, organize, and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/north-carolina-trump-biden-rural-voters-e368243f700ba46afe9a498ef876d687">visit</a> rural counties that Trump had won, and when the time came for Harris to take the reins in late July, the party had built up extensive ground operations in the kinds of rural places they need to lose by less.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That dynamic holds true in North Carolina, where Harris’s campaign has <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-lede/how-kamala-harris-hopes-to-take-north-carolina-back-for-the-democrats?utm_content=308662786&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;hss_channel=tw-752608758476468224">invested heavily</a>, and in Georgia, where Harris went on a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/28/us/politics/harris-walz-georgia-bus-tour.html">rural bus tour</a> shortly after becoming the Democratic nominee. And it’s true in <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/24/harris-trump-voters-rural-pennsylvania">rural Pennsylvania</a>, parts of which Harris and Walz <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4904898-kamala-harris-tim-walz-bus-tour-pennsylvania/">toured last week</a>. The Biden and Harris campaigns have opened 50 coordinated Democratic campaign offices across the state and deployed 350 staffers — including 16 offices in rural counties that Trump won by double digits in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Miles and I drove out to Lancaster County in southern Pennsylvania to visit the county Democratic headquarters in Lancaster City&nbsp;and see this operation in action.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The county has historically been a Republican stronghold, but that’s quickly changing, Stella Sexton, the vice chair of the Lancaster County Democrats, told us.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People move here for jobs for a bunch of reasons,” she said. “But the other piece of the story, and one that I think gets overlooked, is that our college-educated population is growing and it’s not just younger folks moving in with college degrees. It’s also retirees.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump won the county in 2020 by more than 44,000 votes, but in the 2022 midterms, Gov. Josh Shapiro, a Democrat then running for his first term, got close to flipping the county, losing by just 4,000 votes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The bottom line is the reason the Harris campaign —&nbsp;Biden and now Harris campaign —&nbsp;made this investment here is not necessarily because we&#8217;re going to flip it this cycle. It may take one more cycle to outright flip the county, but … the pickup in margin that they can get here is very important to winning the state,” Sexton said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2170953302.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Harris smiling in a crowded coffee shop." title="Harris smiling in a crowded coffee shop." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kamala Harris greets guests at Classic Elements, a coffee shop and bookstore, on September 13, 2024, in Johnstown in west central Pennsylvania. | Andrew Harnik / Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Harnik / Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">And the key to this margin-narrowing strategy is the field operation Democrats have built, both to encourage rural Democrats that may feel alone or forgotten by past campaigns and to contact persuadable or undecided voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There were always Democrats around, but I don&#8217;t know that in our suburban or rural areas that the Democrats realized there were other Democrats as their neighbors,” Sexton said. “What I&#8217;m noticing is that folks aren&#8217;t embarrassed or hiding it. People are proud to be Democrats, and they&#8217;re proud to represent that to their neighbors.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That vibe was there earlier on, according to Sexton, even before Biden dropped out, but it’s only accelerated since Harris became the nominee. Since then, more volunteers have begun to get involved in canvassing. The switch created “excitement and urgency among people who might have sat back and waited until October to get involved,” Sexton said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We joined a canvasser going out to various suburban and working-class neighborhoods to see the Democratic pitch in action. Democrats we encountered were excited about Harris, anxious about Election Day, and happy to be reminded to vote. But undecided voters and independents were still not sure. One, a middle-aged union electrician named Ziggy, told us he didn’t have strong feelings about Harris, but was still upset that both parties had put up “somebody that&#8217;s over the retirement age” and showed “signs of slipping.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We watched as the Democratic canvasser, a nurse named Laura, cycled through a few policy issues and topics to see if she could find a way to persuade Ziggy. Talking about January 6, family-friendly policies like the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/1/16/24035922/child-tax-credit-wyden-smith-deal">Child Tax Credit</a>, and climate change didn’t really land, but when they got to reproductive rights and abortion bans, Ziggy seemed ready to listen—&nbsp;particularly about how certain anti-abortion policies could impact care for other pregnancy-related medical issues.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the end of the conversation, he remained undecided about Harris, but did not seem like he’d back Trump, Laura told us. “And we <em>will</em> circle back to him,” she said, while marking him down in the party’s vote-canvassing app.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The whole exchange demonstrated the newfound hope that Democrats feel about competing in places that usually go red, and the advantage of having a highly organized in-house operation for turning out your own voters and persuading undecided voters. Democratic organizing efforts are also boosted by Harris’s improving favorability ratings, a <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/369878/kamala-harris-fundraising-transfer-state-legislature-abortion">significant</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364964/harris-trump-fundraising-donations-campaign-2024">cash advantage</a>, and <a href="http://www.sca.isr.umich.edu/">improving</a> economic vibes nationally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite that edge, Pennsylvania remains a dead heat in <a href="https://split-ticket.org/2024-presidential-polling-averages/">polling</a> <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/pennsylvania/">averages</a> and <a href="https://split-ticket.org/2024-presidential-ratings/">election</a> <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/2024-election-forecast/pennsylvania/">forecasts</a>. The presidential election may end up coming down to a few thousand votes in the state. And if that happens, the difference may well be the strategies each campaign is now pursuing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Miles Bryan contributed reporting to this article.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Rachel M. Cohen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Florida criminalized homelessness. Then came hurricanes Helene and Milton.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/375765/florida-homelessness-hurricane-helene-encampment-disaster-fema-housing-crisis-storm" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=375765</id>
			<updated>2024-10-08T14:49:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-07T21:40:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Homelessness" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Housing" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the wake of Hurricane Helene, a devastating Category 4 storm that has ravaged the Southeast, leaders rushed to restore homes, infrastructure, and power for millions of people. And now, another life-threatening storm, Hurricane Milton, a Category 5, approaches the Florida coast. Amid the overwhelming destruction and the mounting chaos expected from these back-to-back storms, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A sign in Florida that reads “Hurricane Warning” in capital orange letters alongside a road ahead of Hurricane Helene." data-caption="A sign displays a hurricane warning along a roadside as preparations are made for the arrival of Hurricane Helene, in Cedar Key, Florida, on September 25, 2024. | Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2173616056.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A sign displays a hurricane warning along a roadside as preparations are made for the arrival of Hurricane Helene, in Cedar Key, Florida, on September 25, 2024. | Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/374867/hurricane-helene">Hurricane Helene</a>, a devastating Category 4 storm that has ravaged the Southeast, leaders rushed <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/weather/live-blog/helene-deadly-storm-live-updates-rcna173203">to restore homes, infrastructure</a>, and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hurricane-helene-power-outages-32958ff95f6e51e8c69e56e587de46d2">power for millions</a> of people. And now, another life-threatening storm, Hurricane Milton, a Category 5, approaches the Florida coast. Amid the overwhelming destruction and the mounting chaos expected from these back-to-back storms, and a death toll of at least <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hurricane-helene-death-toll-asheville-north-carolina-34d1226bb31f79dfb2ff6827e40587fc">227 people across six states</a>, one group risks being overlooked in the scramble: the homeless population, those already vulnerable before the storm.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Disaster relief for people who were homeless prior to a hurricane has always been lacking, as FEMA, the main federal agency tasked with providing aid, has a policy that <a href="https://www.fema.gov/sites/default/files/documents/fema_iappg-1.1.pdf">explicitly excludes</a> those unhoused people from most forms of help, including housing and direct assistance. In recent years, the federal Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) has stepped up to try to plug some of those gaps in social safety, but a <a href="https://www.congress.gov/118/bills/hr1605/BILLS-118hr1605ih.pdf">new bill moving</a> through Congress <a href="https://nlihc.org/sites/default/files/HR_1605_Sign_on_Letter_Final.pdf">threatens these efforts</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These dynamics have grown more pressing as major hurricanes <a href="https://www.vox.com/natural-disaster/374366/hurricane-helene-florida-big-bend-beryl-storms-climate">increase in frequency</a> and the number of unsheltered Americans <a href="https://www.huduser.gov/portal/datasets/ahar/2023-ahar-part-1-pit-estimates-of-homelessness-in-the-us.html">continues to grow</a>. In June the US Supreme Court <a href="https://www.vox.com/homelessness/357861/homelessness-encampment-grants-pass-supreme-court-housing">issued a landmark decision</a> in <em>Grants Pass </em>v. <em>Johnson</em>, greenlighting local governments’ legal authority to clear out <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/3/8/23618237/homelessness-tent-encampments-housing-affordable">homeless tent encampments</a> even if a city lacks any available housing or shelter for the unhoused person to stay in.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since then, more jurisdictions have passed laws criminalizing homelessness, part of a broader effort to crack down on those sleeping outside. Just this month <a href="https://www.flgov.com/2024/03/20/governor-desantis-signs-legislation-to-address-homelessness-and-protect-the-public-and-quality-of-life-for-floridians/">a new law</a> in Florida —&nbsp;that bans sleeping on public property anywhere in the state — took effect. While the law <a href="https://www.flsenate.gov/Session/Bill/2024/1365/?Tab=BillText">includes exceptions</a> during emergencies like major storms, those protections end when the hurricane order is no longer in place.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In practical terms, this means that when Republican Gov. Ron DeSantis or a county official lifts Florida’s emergency hurricane order, Floridians who were homeless before Helene and Milton — <a href="https://fchonline.org/the-issue/">roughly 31,000</a> people —&nbsp;could face new criminal penalties. Local homeless advocates say there are countless questions and rumors circulating about how the new law will be interpreted and enforced in the wake of climate disasters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most people experiencing homelessness were aware the new anti-camping law was set to take effect, according to Martha Are, the executive director at the Homeless Services Network of Central Florida. “Some people are already trying to relocate their encampments to harder-to-find areas,” she told me in mid-September, about a week before Helene <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/373874/hurricane-helene-florida-forecast-warm-ocean-water">made landfall</a> in Florida’s Big Bend region.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><br>Leaders like Are have little idea yet what to expect, and she hears unofficially that most jurisdictions are in wait-and-see mode, watching to see which city gets sued first and what the judge who reviews that lawsuit decides. (Under the new Florida law, any citizen or business can sue beginning in January if they feel the anti-camping ban is not being properly enforced.)&nbsp;<br><br>“It’s going to be a challenge for how leaders actually enforce these [anti-camping] laws, like if I’ve lost my house from a hurricane and I’ve lived in that town for a decade, will I be found in violation of the law and are they going to arrest me?” asked Noah Patton, the manager of disaster recovery at the National Low Income Housing Coalition. “These laws create significant complications, will really make aid more difficult to sort out, and what I have been saying is it makes a community less resilient to disasters.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Moving homeless people to safety when a hurricane hits is difficult — and the anti-camping laws make that harder</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s always a stressful scramble to try and reach homeless people when a hurricane is coming. “A lot of people have phones but they don’t have data, they aren’t getting texts,” said Kelly Young, the CEO of the Coalition for the Homeless of Houston and Harris County.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Typically, homeless outreach workers will try and go out to spread the word, and existing homeless shelters will work to make extra room, sometimes allowing people to sleep in places like the kitchen and hallways. Unhoused individuals can usually seek refuge in convention centers and public schools, or at newly-erected Red Cross emergency shelters. Some governments and nonprofits arrange transport for unhoused people to get indoors, while others leave it on the individual to figure out their own travel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We had up to 13,000 people at George R. Brown Convention Center <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/8/28/16211392/100-500-year-flood-meaning">after [Hurricane] Harvey</a> and there was no distinguishing between the homeless versus people who had just lost their homes and needed a place to be,” said Larry Satterwhite, who leads the Houston Mayor’s Office of Public Safety and Homeland Security.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not everyone experiencing homelessness gets the information they need, and not everyone living outside <a href="https://www.huduser.gov/portal/sites/default/files/pdf/Understanding-Encampments.pdf">feels comfortable going to a shelter</a>, said Eric Camarillo, the executive director of SALT Outreach, which works with unsheltered homeless people in Orlando and central Florida. Some people fear losing their personal belongings, while others may have had traumatic prior experiences at shelters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The face of homelessness is not the same as it was 50 years ago,” Camarillo added. “These are single moms who can’t afford day care, these are seniors in their 70s and 80s on fixed incomes who can’t afford their rent increases, and youth and young adults.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The new anti-camping laws are intensifying the already tumultuous disaster response situation, as many homeless people living outside now try to become less visible to avoid jail time. The punitive laws are also expected to increase distrust between local government and homeless individuals, making it even more difficult for people to accept help if they are found.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These laws exist, in my opinion, to push people away and out of sight which makes our job tougher,” said Eric Samuels, the president of the Texas Homeless Network. (Texas passed its statewide camping ban in 2021.) “And if people are badly hurt and they’re miles from public view because they don’t want to get a ticket, then emergency crews might not be able to get out to help.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Disaster aid for those already experiencing homelessness faces an uncertain future</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">FEMA has the primary responsibility of providing disaster relief and works with states and local communities to manage emergency shelters, <a href="https://maps.redcross.org/website/maps/ARC_Shelters.html">which are mostly run by</a> the Red Cross. FEMA prohibits housing assistance from going to those who were already homeless — “because the need for housing was not caused by the disaster,” as their policy states — though homeless individuals may qualify for temporary transportation, funeral, child care, and medical aid.<br><br>FEMA policy does permit those who lived, pre-disaster, in “non-traditional forms of housing” like “tents, certain types of huts, and lean-to structures” to apply for a few months of rental assistance. But to receive this FEMA money, applicants must obtain verification of their pre-storm situation from “a credible or official source” which, according to Patton, makes accessing the aid virtually impossible.<br><br>“People do not apply,” he said. “It’s an exceptionally burdensome and administratively difficult process.”<br><br>Recently, in light of this, and after years of advocacy by housing organizations, HUD stepped up to establish the <a href="https://www.hudexchange.info/news/rapid-unsheltered-survivor-housing-rush-notice/">Rapid Unsheltered Survivor Housing</a> (RUSH) program, using unspent funds from <a href="https://www.hud.gov/program_offices/comm_planning/esg">another emergency grant program</a>. RUSH aims to help those who were homeless prior to a storm or other climate disaster, and the first grants <a href="https://www.nhlp.org/resources/nlihc-and-nhlp-release-report-on-huds-rapid-unsheltered-survivor-housing-rush-program/">were deployed</a> in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/23389508/hurricane-ian-death-toll-storm-florida-landfall-climate">wake of Hurricane Ian</a> in 2022.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We were very pleased to have the ability to launch the program because we see that people who are doubled up or experiencing homelessness during the disaster often don’t access FEMA funds or receive support from FEMA for long,” said Marion McFadden, HUD’s principal deputy assistant secretary for community planning and development. “By providing funds specifically for these situations, we’re filling in gaps.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><br>The other way HUD comes in is through its <a href="https://www.hud.gov/program_offices/comm_planning/cdbg-dr">Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery</a> program (CDBG-DR), which is a highly flexible, long-term disaster aid program that can be used to provide months of rental assistance and build new affordable housing well after FEMA is gone. However the program is not permanently authorized — meaning it relies on periodic appropriations from Congress, which are often delayed and insufficient. The Biden administration has called for Congress to permanently authorize CDBG-DR, and a bipartisan bill in Congress <a href="https://www.naco.org/news/bipartisan-bills-introduced-support-counties-disaster-recovery-process">has called for the same</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/118th-congress/house-bill/1605">a separate bill</a> currently moving through Congress seeks to move much of this longer-term disaster recovery work back over to FEMA, something low-income housing advocates believe will threaten those who are homeless before a hurricane.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We are concerned that the bill, as written, may lead to the misuse of scarce federal recovery funds and prevent critically needed long-term recovery assistance from reaching low-income disaster survivors,” more than 35 national<strong> </strong>housing advocacy groups wrote in <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1U15ZfvjLRefLildANBu3ij7zRXRGjL_51893RBYPTaE/edit">a congressional letter</a> in late September. &nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">McFadden, of HUD, said there’s “a real role” for her agency to play in supporting communities after disasters. “We are making billions of dollars in grants every year and we understand the unique needs of low-income people and of low-income housing,” she told Vox.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">FEMA was noncommittal when I inquired about the agency’s plans for unhoused individuals during a disaster if Congress granted them new authority, or whether they’d reconsider their stance on aiding the pre-disaster homeless.<br><br>“If additional or new authority is passed by Congress and signed into law, FEMA would then develop guidance necessary to implement the new authority,” an agency spokesperson said. “FEMA would focus on supporting communities’ recovery in addressing needs resulting from a disaster and adhering to the intent of Congress in approving any new authority.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As climate change escalates, communities across the US face increasing threats not only from hurricanes but also from heat waves, floods, and wildfires. Advocates <a href="https://www.biologicaldiversity.org/programs/energy-justice/pdfs/EMBARGOED_FEMA-Petition-on-Heat-and-Wildfire-Smoke.pdf">have been petitioning</a> FEMA over the last year to expand its criteria for disaster aid to include heat and smoke, emphasizing the need for more adaptable responses to these challenges. The nation’s severe shortage of affordable housing worsens the struggles of both the newly displaced and the long-unsheltered, and addressing these intertwined crises of climate resilience and housing stability has never been more urgent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 7, 5:40 pm ET: </strong>This story was originally published on October 3 and <em>has been updated with the current death toll of Hurricane Helene and new information as Hurricane Milton approaches the Florida coast.</em></em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Staff</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Vox podcasts tackle the Israel-Hamas war]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/podcasts/23948960/israel-hamas-palestine-podcasts" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/podcasts/23948960/israel-hamas-palestine-podcasts</id>
			<updated>2024-10-07T21:05:09Z</updated>
			<published>2024-10-07T21:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Editor’s note, October 7, 5 pm: While our podcasts will continue to cover the conflict in the Middle East, this page will no longer be updated with new episodes. You can listen to our shows wherever you find podcasts.  The Israel-Palestine conflict goes back decades, but this latest war has taken an unprecedented toll in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Israeli forces’ flares light up the night sky in Gaza City on November 6, 2023. | Abed Khaled/AP" data-portal-copyright="Abed Khaled/AP" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/25069266/AP23310764413057.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Israeli forces’ flares light up the night sky in Gaza City on November 6, 2023. | Abed Khaled/AP</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Editor’s note, October 7, 5 pm: </strong>While our podcasts will continue to cover the conflict in the Middle East, this page will no longer be updated with new episodes. You can listen to our shows wherever you find podcasts. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Israel-Palestine conflict goes back decades, but this <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/7/23907683/israel-hamas-war-news-updates-october-2023">latest war</a> has taken <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-hamas-war-news-11-6-2023-51286d15dddd77ae0dd7ea76ee52bc71">an unprecedented toll in terms of the number of people killed</a>, and represents a significant step back from any hopes of securing a two-state solution and a permanent peace. <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/podcasts">Vox podcasts</a> have spent the past year covering the conflict in depth, offering our listeners context and clarity about the history of the conflict, a deeper understanding of the players in Israel and Palestine and on the world stage, and the toll of Hamas’s attack and Israel’s retaliation on the people in the region.</p>

<p><a href="https://vox.com/todayexplained"><em>Today, Explained</em></a>,<strong> </strong>Vox’s daily news explainer podcast, has been covering the conflict since it began,<strong> </strong>with an episode posted right after Hamas’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/10/7/23907683/israel-hamas-war-news-updates-october-2023" data-source="encore">October 7 attack on Israel</a> that took the lives of around 1,200 people and resulted in the kidnapping of an estimated 240 hostages. The show has since continued to cover many threads in this story, from<strong> </strong>where Hamas comes from to<strong> </strong>how false information about the conflict has spread on social media and how information warfare is used in the Middle East. Vox podcasts <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-weeds"><em>The Weeds</em></a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area"><em>The Gray Area</em></a> have also been covering the unfolding crisis, its stakes, and its impact.</p>

<p>You can find those and all our other episodes on the topic below.</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-css-opacity" />

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The future of Gaza</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/yJ7G_BiN?sid=site">October 7, 2024</a> | It’s been one year since Hamas attacked Israel and started a war in Gaza. Israelis and Palestinians look back, and Vox’s Joshua Keating says Israel’s occupation is looking permanent.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9127022290" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">War in Lebanon?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/1OvjPtjK?sid=site">September 24, 2024</a> | It looks a lot like all-out war between Israel and Hezbollah. Semafor’s Sarah Dadouch has the latest from Beirut and CNN’s Nick Paton Walsh explains Israel’s strategy.</p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1778297298" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Israel vs. Hezbollah</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX829">August 29, 2024</a> | The two are on the brink of starting a regional war. An analyst and a negotiator say that without a ceasefire in Gaza, the Middle East could spin out of control.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4289052329" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">It’s not Islamophobic, it’s anti-Palestinian</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX625">June 25, 2024</a> | Islamophobic and antisemitic incidents are on the rise. Author Moustafa Bayoumi and Vox’s Abdallah Fayyad tell us about another kind of invisible discrimination: anti-Palestinian racism.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4148829716" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Was that antisemitic?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX611">June 11, 2024</a> | Since October 7 there has been a lot of debate over what is and isn’t antisemitic. Rabbi Jill Jacobs and Harvard law professor Noah Feldman explain why the definition is so important.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP5770834334" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The Hamas org chart</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX528">May 28, 2024</a> | Seven months in, Israel has not “eliminated” Hamas leadership. Newsweek’s Tom O’Connor introduces them, and Mairav Zonszein from International Crisis Group explains what it means for the war.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7294550951" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden’s breaking point on Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0508">May 9, 2024</a> | President Joe Biden says the US won’t supply further weapons if Israel is going to use them in Rafah. Axios reporter Barak Ravid explains what that means for the war.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8718689187" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel, Gaza, and Eurovision</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0507">May 7, 2024</a> | The pop music competition is facing boycott calls over Israel’s participation. Switched on Pop’s Charlie Harding and historian Tess Megginson explain why the apolitical event keeps getting political.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3223606607" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is divesting from Israel possible?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX0506">May 6, 2024</a> | Yes, but it’s hard. Inside Higher Ed’s Josh Moody and UC Merced’s Charlie Eaton explain.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3557683503" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Columbia’s free-speech fight</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX424">April 24, 2024</a> | Daily Spectator news editor Sarah Huddleston reports on the protests at her university. AAUP President Irene Mulvey explains the stakes for campus free speech.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4660296382" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Iran attacked Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXApril15">April 15, 2024</a> | The Economist’s Gregg Carlstrom explains. Jerusalem-based journalist Noga Tarnopolsky explores whether the unprecedented attack hurts or helps Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1751931241" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel’s attack on World Central Kitchen</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXApril4">April 4, 2024</a> | The Wall Street Journal’s Stephen Kalin explains what happened, and Refugees International president Jeremy Konyndyk lays out what this means for Gazans.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8483025580" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Israel is upending Democratic races</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/XkhCpuXi">March 5, 2024</a> | Super Tuesday is the biggest day of the presidential primary campaign, but the biggest race in the biggest state isn’t about Biden or Trump. Instead, the leading candidates for California’s open Senate seat — three Democrats and a Republican — are finding themselves talking a lot about Israel, Palestine, and the war in Gaza.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7327599366" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The protest vote against Biden</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/SFSTGt27">February 27, 2024</a> | Michigan’s primary today will test President Biden’s viability with Muslim voters amid the war in Gaza. One Arab American leader says the community is abandoning Biden and looking for alternatives — Donald Trump might be one of them.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1472451344" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rafah, the last “safe” zone</h2>

<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/rafah-the-last-safe-zone/id1346207297?i=1000645493072">February 15, 2024</a> | Palestinians are trapped in Rafah, Gaza’s southernmost city, where about 1.5 million people have sought refuge. After Israel bombed Rafah this weekend, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu is threatening a ground invasion. Palestinian journalist Aseel Mousa takes us inside Rafah, and the Economist’s Anton La Guardia explains why diplomatic efforts to halt the fighting have stalled.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8017917831" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Iran and the Axis of Resistance</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/Tex131">January 31, 2024</a> | Iran-backed militias use drones, missiles, and even TikTok dances to antagonize the United States and Israel. The International Crisis Group’s Ali Vaez explains how the war in Gaza has energized the self-described Axis of Resistance.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9744025655" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel at the International Court of Justice</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/Tex129">January 29, 2024</a> | South Africa took Israel to court over claims of genocide. Courthouse News reporter Molly Quell and the International Crisis Group’s Robert Blecher explain what happened next.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4209187305" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How the war in Gaza ends</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXGaza118">January 18, 2024</a> | Israel’s war against Hamas has now been raging for over 100 days. According to Ian Lustick, professor emeritus at the University of Pennsylvania, history tells us what it will take to end it.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7914504391" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel’s next move</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/IsraelsNextMove">January 3, 2023</a> | Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu faces trouble at home and abroad. AP correspondent Tia Goldenberg and scholar Hussein Ibish explain the significance of a high-profile killing in Lebanon.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8484180035" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The fight over campus antisemitism</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCampusAntisemitism">December 12, 2023</a> | Three elite university presidents walk into Congress for a hearing on antisemitism. Only two still have their jobs. New York magazine reporter Nia Prater tells us what happened, and a Harvard professor of Jewish history explains why he thinks resignations won’t make campuses safer.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4405751236" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Palestine went global</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEX124">December 4, 2023</a> | People with no direct connection to the Middle East have taken to seeing the Palestinian cause as an anti-colonial struggle connected to their own experience. Columbia historian Rashid Khalidi explains why “decolonization” is resonating worldwide.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7675203676" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The American politics of Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXIsraelPolitics">November 29, 2023</a> | The Israel-Hamas war is dividing the previously united Democrats and uniting the recently fractured Republican Party. Semafor’s David Weigel explains what that means going into 2024.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1957625702" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The hostage deal (brought to you by Qatar)</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXHostageDeal">November 27, 2023</a> | After 50 days of the Israel-Hamas war, both sides took a breather to save lives. And it couldn’t have happened without Qatar.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6031095818" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Inside the occupied West Bank</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXWestBank">November 20, 2023</a> | With the world focused on Gaza, Israeli settlers and soldiers are increasing attacks on Palestinians in the West Bank. Writer Nathan Thrall and journalist Dalia Hatuqa explain the decades of tension that shape life in the West Bank.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8588452161" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A call from Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCallFromGaza">November 14, 2023</a> | People are desperately trying to escape Gaza as the siege on the strip continues. Mohammed Ghalaieny, a Palestinian British man, tells us why he is choosing to stay, even as other foreign nationals escape through the Rafah border crossing with Egypt.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6452223851" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A Jew and a Muslim get honest about Israel and Gaza</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/GrayArea1113">November 13, 2023</a> | <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/zack-beauchamp">Zack Beauchamp</a>, a Vox senior correspondent who writes about democracy and Israel, speaks with Shadi Hamid, a columnist at the Washington Post, research professor of Islamic studies at Fuller Seminary, and author of<em> The Problem of Democracy: America, the Middle East, and the Rise and Fall of an Idea</em>. They discuss the October 7 attack, the subsequent war in Gaza, what it means for Israelis and Palestinians, and how Jews and Muslims in the United States can find common ground amid their communities’ grief. This conversation was recorded on November 2, 2023.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP5837160411" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">BDS and the history of the boycott</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/WeedsBDS">November 8, 2023</a> | If you turn on the news or scroll through your social media feed of choice, there’s a good chance you’ll see the latest on the Israel-Hamas war — and the reaction to it. But there’s one call to action making its way down social media feeds that feels different from all these other responses. It’s called <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/23935054/boycott-movement-palestine-against-israel-bds">BDS, short for boycott, divest, and sanction</a>. And like just about everything related to this conflict, it’s complicated and controversial. <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-weeds"><em>The Weeds</em></a> host <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/jonquilyn-hill">Jonquilyn Hill</a> sits down with Vox senior reporter <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/whizy-kim">Whizy Kim</a> to explain the controversial movement, and with Cornell professor and author of <em>Buying Power: A History of Consumer Activism in America</em> Lawrence B. Glickman to discuss the history of boycotts and whether they even work.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP3708406014" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ceasefire?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXCeasefire">November 8, 2023</a> | Protesters, politicians, and the pope are <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/11/9/23953714/biden-campaign-alumni-want-gaza-ceasefire-state-department-dissent-memo">calling for a ceasefire in the Israel-Hamas war</a>, but the US and Israeli governments remain opposed. Vox’s Jonathan Guyer and Jon B. Alterman from the Center for Strategic and International Studies explain what happens next.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7707398742" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The view from Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXviewfromisrael">November 2, 2023</a> | Israelis overwhelmingly disapprove of their government’s handling of the October 7 attacks, but their desire for unity keeps Prime Minister <a href="https://www.vox.com/23910085/netanyahu-israel-right-hamas-gaza-war-history" data-source="encore">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> in power. Michael Koplow of the Israel Policy Forum explains what Israel’s government should do next, and professor Noah Efron of Bar-Ilan University describes the mood among Israelis.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP7944317880" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Gaza’s humanitarian crisis</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXgazacrisis">October 30, 2023</a> | Cut off from water and power and recovering from a communications blackout, Gaza is plunged deeper into crisis. It’s not just a humanitarian problem, says leading human rights attorney Kenneth Roth — it’s a violation of international law.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP2717258243" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why does the US always side with Israel?</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXisraellistenerQs">October 25, 2023</a> | This was the top question we got when we asked <em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast" data-source="encore">Today, Explained</a></em> listeners hat they wanted to know about this conflict. Joel Beinin, Middle East history professor emeritus at Stanford, has answers.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8490887695" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hearts, minds, and likes</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXheartsmindslikes">October 23, 2023</a> | False information about what is happening in Israel and Gaza is taking over social media faster than journalists like BBC Verify’s Shayan Sardarizadeh can check it. That’s exactly how digital propagandists want it, says professor and social media expert Marc Owen Jones.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6875482691" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Biden goes to Israel</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXbidenisrael">October 18, 2023</a> | It’s been 11 days since Hamas attacked Israel, killing civilians and taking hostages. Israel’s retaliation has killed hundreds of Palestinians and created a humanitarian crisis in Gaza. Senior fellow at the Carnegie Endowment Aaron David Miller and Middle East analyst Michael Wahid Hanna explain what role diplomacy will play in the coming days.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP1718190767" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Palestinians view Hamas</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXpalestiniansviewhamas">October 16, 2023</a> | The US, along with Israel and many of its allies, has long considered Hamas a terrorist group. Khaled Al-Hroub, a professor at Northwestern University in Qatar, explains how its reputation is a lot murkier among Palestinians, who elected the group to political power in 2006.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP6885524911" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Israel, Hamas, and how we got here</h2>

<p><a href="https://link.chtbl.com/TEXIsraelHamas">October 10, 2023</a> | This Israel-Hamas war is unlike the ones that came before it, says Haaretz’s Allison Kaplan Sommer. But it was years in the making, says Vox’s Zack Beauchamp.</p>

<iframe loading="lazy" frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8658633452" width="100%"></iframe>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
