<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-07-03T20:08:52Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Brian Stelter</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Did the media botch the Biden age story?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358877/biden-age-debate-media-coverage" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358877</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T20:08:52Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T20:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clueless or complicit. That’s Ted Cruz’s take on the media’s coverage of Joe Biden’s age and mental acuity, which came under scrutiny after the president publicly unraveled in last week’s debate. On Monday, the Republican senator from Texas tweeted to me: “There are only two options: (1) the Dems &#38; their media shills were so [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="ATLANTA, GEORGIA - JUNE 27: U.S. President Joe Biden walks off stage during the CNN Presidential Debate at the CNN Studios on June 27, 2024 in Atlanta, Georgia. President Biden and Republican presidential candidate, former U.S. President Donald Trump are facing off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 campaign. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-2159613364.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>ATLANTA, GEORGIA - JUNE 27: U.S. President Joe Biden walks off stage during the CNN Presidential Debate at the CNN Studios on June 27, 2024 in Atlanta, Georgia. President Biden and Republican presidential candidate, former U.S. President Donald Trump are facing off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 campaign. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Clueless or complicit.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s Ted Cruz’s take on the media’s coverage of Joe Biden’s age and mental acuity, which came under scrutiny after the president publicly unraveled in last week’s debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Monday, the Republican senator from Texas <a href="https://x.com/tedcruz/status/1807857345000886311">tweeted to me</a>: “There are only two options: (1) the Dems &amp; their media shills were so clueless that they had no idea that Biden is mentally incompetent, or (2) they KNEW &amp; they deliberately LIED about it. Both are damning. I vote #2.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cruz isn’t the only one taking aim at the media after the debate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right-wing commentators are imagining that news outlets covered up Biden’s frailty for years. Some on the left are asserting that the White House press corps should have probed Biden’s health more closely, which could have prompted a fuller primary process. Journalists (including the one writing this column) are doing some reassessing of their own, asking if the clearly aging 81-year-old president was given the benefit of the doubt too many times.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I’m sorry, Ted Cruz, there are more than two options.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And after talking to top reporters on the White House beat, what emerges is a far more nuanced picture.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The national media wasn’t dodging the story: The biggest newspapers in the country <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/09/us/politics/biden-age-democrats.html">published</a> <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/11/11/biden-age-2024-election/">lengthy</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/joe-biden-age-election-2024-8ee15246">stories</a> about Biden’s mental fitness. The public wasn’t in the dark about Biden’s age: Most voters (67 percent in a <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646547/age-issues-working-trump-advantage-pre-debate.aspx">June Gallup poll</a>) thought he was too old to be president even before the debate. But questions about Biden’s fitness for office were not emphasized as much as they should have been. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s the third option: The stories should have been tougher, the volume should have been louder.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The hard thing about ‘Biden is old’ as a story is that it had a dead-end quality to it,” said Charlotte Alter, senior correspondent for Time magazine. “Biden is old. We know. So now what? You can’t turn back time. You can’t make him younger.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the story is no longer a dead end. Key members of Biden’s party, spooked by the debate, are wondering whether he should remain in the race. Some are pushing for him to step aside. One of the correspondents I interviewed, who spoke on condition of anonymity because their employer prohibits outside interviews, said, “Sources are coming out of the woodwork now.” Journalists who were previously stymied by uncooperative aides are now probing whether the White House did, to some degree, cover up Biden’s condition.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Until now, the coverage has largely consisted of questions; hopefully soon there will be answers.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A brief history of a half-decade of Biden age coverage</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Some consider it taboo to ask whether a candidate is too old to serve as president. Not the press,” Politico’s acclaimed media critic Jack Shafer wrote in 2019. Shafer’s <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/08/02/joe-biden-age-media-227499/">column</a> — titled “Is Joe Biden Too Old?” — observed that nearly every major media outlet was zeroing in on the candidate’s age, then 76, making “his state of mental and physical fitness the primary lens through which it views his candidacy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The scrutiny never really subsided. The New York Times’s chief White House correspondent Peter Baker told me that his first Page One <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/09/us/politics/biden-age-democrats.html">story</a> about Biden’s age was published in July 2022. “The age question is catching up to Joe Biden,” a CNN columnist <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/07/11/politics/joe-biden-age-democrats/index.html">wrote</a> that same month. “Biden, turning 80, faces renewed age questions as he weighs reelection,” the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2022/11/11/biden-age-2024-election/">wrote</a> in November 2022.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This was critical coverage. Journalists aren’t doctors, and shouldn’t pretend to be. But they are observers, and Baker, like others on the Biden beat, reported what he observed over the years. Biden “often shuffles when he walks, and aides worry he will trip on a wire,” Baker wrote in 2022. “He stumbles over words during public events, and they hold their breath to see if he makes it to the end without a gaffe.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back then, it was unclear whether Biden would run for a second term. Baker quoted S. Jay Olshansky, a longevity specialist at the University of Illinois Chicago, saying it was fair to ask if Biden would still be fit for office in 2028, when he would be 86 years old. “You can’t sugarcoat aging,” Olshansky said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, despite the scrutiny, some reporters are looking back and wondering what they could have done differently, particularly after Biden’s April 2023 announcement of his reelection bid raised the stakes. “That’s when the coverage should have gotten a lot tougher,” one of the beat reporters remarked to me.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The White House waged war on age reporting</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To assess the quality of the media’s coverage of Biden’s age, it helps to understand what made it such a difficult story to begin with. Because it certainly is difficult.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It has been a challenge for the media to find the best way to tell this story,” Baker said. “It’s a hard topic, right? It’s subjective. It depends in part on people in the room with him telling you in a candid way what they see. And it’s certainly true that this White House is not a particularly transparent White House.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Baker’s sentiment on the White House is widely shared. In conversations about this topic with a dozen White House correspondents and other Washington reporters, I heard harsh criticism of the Biden administration for “gaslighting” and “bullying” people who pursued stories about the president’s health — and praise for the journalists who did so anyway.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They really hate us over these stories,” Baker said. The administration’s “pushback is pretty strong and their resentment of the coverage is pretty deep, to the point that they’ve complained to our editors.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s press aides were inordinately sensitive, you might say defensive, about the topic. “When reporters raise age questions, they lose their minds,” one reporter said. “They go ballistic,” a second reporter said. “Every time you write about Biden’s age, they gaslight you and tell you that you’ll be responsible for the downfall of the American republic,” a third reporter said, exaggerating just a touch.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Atlantic’s Mark Leibovich penned a <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2022/06/biden-run-for-reelection-2024/661297/">column</a> in June 2022 saying that Biden was “too old for the next election.” In a February 2023 <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2023/02/joe-biden-2024-election-democrat-candidates/673212/">follow-up</a>, he quipped that “the White House did not like that story.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some left-leaning readers didn’t like it, either.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reader response to age coverage was punishing</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In my talks with reporters, I also heard complaints about how stories on Biden’s age were received. Many Trump supporters treated it as a given that Biden was senile, and any report that didn’t outright agree was seen as part of the alleged media cover-up.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Biden supporters accused journalists of abetting Trump by “both-sidesing” an election that features an aspiring authoritarian who tried to steal the last presidential election.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prominent journalists who were outspoken about voters’ age concerns, like New York Times podcasters Ezra Klein and Astead Herndon, were pummeled by partisans in social media comment threads. (“Americans have said consistently that they wanted someone else to be the nominee,” Herndon pointed out again on CNN after the debate <a href="https://transcripts.cnn.com/show/ip/date/2024-06-28/segment/01">last week</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tensions are still palpable this week: Every time I appear on CNN (my old home) or the BBC to discuss the Democratic Party’s post-debate state of crisis, I get messages from liberal viewers who believe I’m helping hand the election to Trump. The former president looms over every story and TV segment about Biden, and some Washington reporters have privately griped that Biden got a bit of a free pass because Trump was so aberrant and so dishonest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the White House reporters I know weren’t slacking off or going soft on Biden because they wanted to help the Democratic Party defeat Trump. That’s just Infowars-style conspiracy thinking. Reporters live for scoops, and a scoop about Biden being debilitated would be a blockbuster. It’s just not that simple.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Witness the Wall Street Journal’s <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/joe-biden-age-election-2024-8ee15246">prescient story</a> in early June — “Behind Closed Doors, Biden Shows Signs of Slipping” — which was widely criticized for leaning too heavily on Republican sources with partisan agendas. The Biden press shop went into <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/05/biden-age-wall-street-journal-2024-election">attack mode</a> and the Journal reporters felt rather lonely as media commentators <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2024/06/09/wall-street-journal-biden-slipping-article/">derided</a> the story.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The reality was that the Journal had lots of solid reporting, but too many people gave the Biden White House the benefit of the doubt. I was part of the problem; I appeared on MSNBC and said that Biden’s age could decide the election “if the media obsesses over it and ignores Trump’s faults.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s fitness for office merited more “obsessing.” His relative lack of in-depth interviews and news conferences was, in hindsight, a tell. His decision to turn down a prime spot on CBS on Super Bowl Sunday, bucking with presidential tradition, probably should have been scrutinized even more emphatically.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The evidence on Biden’s cognitive decline was often muddled</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The awkward reality is that there are “two Joe Bidens,” as Baker and several New York Times colleagues put it in a Page One <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/04/us/politics/biden-president-age-2024.html">piece</a> about “America’s oldest president” in June 2023.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To borrow a meme, that article has aged well. The notion of Biden having good days and bad days has become conventional wisdom. Perhaps the debate was his worst day yet — although reporters don’t have enough access to Biden to confidently say so.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That was the worst I’ve ever seen him,” one White House correspondent told me afterward, a sentiment affirmed by three other Biden beat reporters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the other hand, down-the-middle media outlets may not have placed enough significance on the string of embarrassing video clips and other episodes. Several reporters told me that, in retrospect, apparent signs of Biden’s advancing age were treated as one-offs when they might have been something more. “Did we miss some chances to connect some dots? I think that’s a fair question,” a veteran correspondent told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On one memorable occasion, in September 2022, Biden scanned a crowd and looked for Rep. Jackie Walorski, Republican of Indiana, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/wheres-jackie-biden-seeks-lawmaker-walorski-who-died-august-2022-09-28/#:~:text=Biden%20thanked%20other%20conference%20organizers,two%20staffers%20in%20early%20August">asking</a>, “Jackie, are you here? Where’s Jackie?” Walorski had been killed in a car crash the previous month.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One “senior moment” after another led to frequent corrections of White House transcripts and thorough fact-checks by news outlets. I was particularly galled when Biden said, in remarks to service members and first responders on the anniversary of September 11, that he remembered “standing there the next day” and looking at Ground Zero. He <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/09/11/politics/fact-check-biden-ground-zero-next-day/index.html">didn’t visit</a> the site until nine days after the attack. I wish I had made more of that. At the time, I chalked it up to Biden being Biden.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s also how the White House tried to minimize special counsel Robert K. Hur’s embarrassing <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/08/us/biden-documents-special-counsel.html#:~:text=Hur%20portrayed%20him%20as%20unable,He%20cited%20Mr.">assessment</a> of Biden as a “sympathetic, well-meaning, elderly man with a poor memory.” When Biden delivered an angry rebuttal to Hur’s report, he <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/4457527-biden-mistakenly-calls-egyptian-leader-president-of-mexico/">mixed up</a> the presidents of Egypt and Mexico — yet another one of those dots that could have been connected more assertively. Several beat reporters told me they thought the White House largely succeeded in framing Hur as a Republican smear artist.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Biden had a “bad day” with Hur, he also had lots of “good days,” and members of the media dutifully described those, in quotes that have come under newfound scrutiny. MSNBC host Joe Scarborough, a personal friend of Biden’s, said in March that he’d recently “spent a couple of hours with Joe Biden” and found him to be “better than he’s ever been intellectually.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Anti-Biden media outlets have ridiculed Scarborough for praising Biden’s intellect, but the assessment is entirely in line with the experience many people have with elderly relatives: sharp one day, slow the next day.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, Biden biographer Evan Osnos <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/03/11/joe-biden-profile#:~:text=For%20better%20and%20worse%2C%20he,a%20name%20or%20a%20date.">wrote</a> in the New Yorker that when he last interviewed Biden, in January, “his mind seemed unchanged. He never bungled a name or a date.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Immediately after the debate, Osnos said Biden was clearly diminished. He told me, of the article he published in March, “The piece was about Biden’s defiant belief that he could and should win. His job was to persuade Americans to agree with him, and that has failed.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Until the debate, Biden’s highest-profile television appearance of the year was his State of the Union address in March. He won high marks for a commanding, even feisty speech; he was so high-energy that Fox types claimed he was “jacked up” on stimulants or illicit substances. But he was using a teleprompter and speaking in front of a crowd, two features that last week’s CNN debate lacked.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The triumphant nature of Biden’s State of the Union address enabled White House aides, and Biden-friendly media outlets, to dismiss his mental misfires and physical deterioration. For a long time, “they did an incredibly effective job of bubble wrapping him,” a DC anchor told me. It worked, sometimes, with some audiences.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not working anymore. The bubble wrap is off.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So did the media get this one wrong?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I know many readers would love an easy answer here, and I know many pundits are eager to provide one. But it’s just not that simple.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For starters, there’s no such thing as “the media” anymore. We live in a time of such complete and utter mass-media fragmentation that we each live in a media bubble of our own making. In mine, Biden might be a wise leader who is making America sane again after four years of Trump insanity; in yours, he might be a doddering old fool or a victim of “elder abuse,” as Fox hosts are now openly saying.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And even if you narrow the media-criticism conversation down to a handful of high-profile, down-the-middle national outlets, the record of how effectively Biden’s health was covered is complicated, just as aging is a complicated process. Baker, who co-bylined a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/02/us/politics/biden-lapses.html">new story</a> on Tuesday titled “Biden’s Lapses Are Said to Be Increasingly Common and Worrisome,” told me, “It’s very likely that things have progressed in recent weeks and months that make this a more acute story now.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout Biden’s years in office, reporters sought to avoid ageist stereotypes and respect the fact that Biden has a history of stuttering while also reporting on what they were observing. They also weighed his verbal gaffes and viral video blunders against his political victories. Baker and several other reporters wrote in the June 2023 “America’s Oldest President” story that Biden was, in truth, “somewhere between the partisan cartoon of an addled and easily manipulated fogy promoted by Republicans and the image spread by his staff of a president in aviator shades commanding the world stage and governing with vigor.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, about those Republicans. Fox News stars have been taking a victory lap this week, having spent years and countless segments portraying Biden as incompetent and incapacitated. They feel like they deserve credit for being early to the story that’s now consuming Washington.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Fox supplied precious little actual reporting on the subject of Biden’s health. Instead, hosts like Sean Hannity and Laura Ingraham queued up video clips of Biden looking helpless and played those clips on a loop, devoid of any context or balance. When Biden would deliver a forceful speech, as on State of the Union night, Fox’s commentators seemed caught off guard.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider the recent controversies over so-called “cheapfake” videos of Biden. He really has, at times, appeared to wander off and freeze up in front of cameras. But some of the videos hyped by Biden critics were misleading, even maliciously so.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Pro-Trump media outlets took a clip of Biden pausing before sitting down in a chair and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/fact-check-biden-invisible-chair-normandy-634944982428">claimed</a> that there was no chair there at all. Online meme makers <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/this-video-shows-joe-biden-did-notin-factpoop-himself-at-d-day-event">imagined</a> that he was defecating during a D-Day ceremony.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those types of lies caused at least a little bit of hesitation among good-faith reporters. As one said to me, “I didn’t want to feed into a bad-faith caricature.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the answer to bad-faith attacks can’t be a supine press, and journalists have a chance now to prove they’re up to the task of reporting this story. The public deserves to know more about Biden’s health, and it is owed more insight into how the president is functioning in the White House.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We live in the era of a gerontocracy. Were Trump to win, he’d be 82 at the end of his second term —&nbsp;older than Biden is now. “The Biden-is-old story is a small piece of a bigger story, which is that our entire government is really old, across all branches,” said Alter, who wrote the 2020 book <em><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/598359/the-ones-weve-been-waiting-for-by-charlotte-alter/">The Ones We’ve Been Waiting For: How a New Generation of Leaders Will Transform America</a>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That new generation is still waiting for its turn. So questions of age will come up over and over again. Reporters who push past hostile press offices and recalcitrant readers to get to the facts will have met the moment —&nbsp;and delivered to the public what it deserves.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop setting your thermostat at 72]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358898/best-thermostat-setting-save-energy-money-ac" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358898</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T20:00:10Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T20:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Micah Pollak had no idea the trouble he was getting himself into when he shared his preferred thermostat settings on social media. “I just discovered most of our friends set their AC at 68-73F during the summer,” Micah, who is an economist at Indiana University, posted on Threads in late June. “We keep ours at [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A smart thermostat shows 72 degrees on a red background" data-caption="By setting your thermostat one degree warmer, you can save 6 percent on energy costs, according to the EPA." data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-510630038.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>By setting your thermostat one degree warmer, you can save 6 percent on energy costs, according to the EPA.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Micah Pollak had no idea the trouble he was getting himself into when he shared his preferred thermostat settings on social media. “I just discovered most of our friends set their AC at 68-73F during the summer,” Micah, who is an economist at Indiana University, <a href="https://www.threads.net/@micah.pollak/post/C80c91XMRBp">posted on Threads</a> in late June. “We keep ours at 77-78F. Are we monsters!?” Nearly a thousand replies later, the consensus was that, yes, Micah’s family are monsters, probably some type of lizard.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although he didn’t realize it, Micah has been following a set of numbers from the Environmental Protection Agency that <a href="https://x.com/gorgeousbrains/status/1803936205559431535">tends to spark an internet freakout</a> every summer, often after a local news station <a href="https://www.cbs8.com/article/news/local/the-coolest-you-should-keep-your-house-is-78-degrees-federal-program-recommends/509-1f1bc1e1-e5ea-4f8a-8068-c8b7ba463dbc">does a segment</a> on how to reduce your energy consumption and lower your utility bills. The recommendations include keeping your thermostat at 78º when you’re at home during the day, 82º at night, and 85º when you’re away during the warm months. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To many people, sleeping in 82º heat is simply outrageous. (Not to mention <a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/what-is-the-ideal-sleeping-temperature-for-my-bedroom">terrible for your sleep</a>, according to experts.) But energy prices are crazy too, and they’re only expected to rise as utility companies <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-09/interest-rate-cuts-unlikely-to-lower-energy-costs-for-americans?embedded-checkout=true">spend more and more</a> to make the grid more resilient to the effects of climate change. Extreme weather events are becoming more common, and heat waves in particular <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23893057/power-electricity-grid-heat-wave-record-blackout-outage-climate">can strain the power grid</a>, especially when thousands of people are running their ACs at full tilt.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So maybe cranking up your thermostat isn’t such a bad deal. Typically, I’m inclined to set my AC to 72 on a really hot day. If I could get used to a balmy 78º inside, I’d not only save money, I’d be doing my part to keep the grid running smoothly so that everyone can enjoy a little bit of air conditioning, too. And the savings are real. The EPA says that for every degree warmer you set your AC, you can save 6 percent on your cooling costs, although you get diminishing returns as you go higher and higher. Put simply, if your cooling bill is usually $170, setting your thermostat a single digit higher will save you over $10 a month.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s one big problem, though. That 78º baseline isn’t a real federal government recommendation. The EPA’s Energy Star program does have a guide for programmable thermostat settings, but it doesn’t recommend a specific number to set your thermostat to in the summer. The numbers that show up in the news actually come from <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/sites/default/files/asset/document/HeatingCoolingGuide%20FINAL_9-4-09_0.pdf">a table in a 2009 document</a> that offered examples of what energy-saving settings could look like. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Your household temperatures are very much a personal choice, and ultimately people should do what makes them comfortable,” Leslie Jones, a public affairs specialist from Energy Star, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The agency’s official position <a href="https://www.energy.gov/energysaver/programmable-thermostats">is that you can save</a> “up to 10 percent on heating and cooling settings by simply turning your thermostat 7°-10°F for 8 hours a day from its normal setting.” In other words, if you keep it at 71 while you’re home, go ahead and set it to 78 if you leave for the day.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then again, setting your thermostat at 78√ at all times is not a monstrous idea. And setting it at 72º probably means you’re wasting some energy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nobody wants the government telling them to suffer more in the summer heat. A lot of our assumptions, though, about how air conditioning works, how to optimize the effectiveness of this century-old technology, and how to save energy in the process are just that: assumptions. To clear up the outrage over where we set out thermostats, I talked to experts in thermal comfort, HVAC technology, and the built environment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It turns out, some of the most effective ways to stay cool are both simple and cheap.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why we fight over the thermostat</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a time-honored American tradition to fight over the thermostat. Winter, summer, spring, and fall, any given home will be too hot or too cold for someone in the family.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is for good reason, too. Physiologically, we each have our own optimal thermal comfort level. It comes down to a few key factors, according to <a href="https://www.tno.nl/en/about-tno/our-people/boris-kingma/">Boris Kingma</a>, a human thermal performance researcher at the Netherlands Institute of Applied Technology (TNO). The environment, including temperature, humidity, wind, and solar radiation, is obviously the big one. If it’s hot outside, you’ll feel hot. But a person’s metabolic rate and general physiology, including age and overall health, also play a big role — as does the clothing you’re wearing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Metabolism is what’s at play when you talk to people who say they “run hot.” They might literally do that if they have a high metabolism, which causes your body to produce more heat. People with more muscle mass, for instance, tend to have higher metabolisms, retain heat, and prefer cooler temperatures. The opposite goes for people with lower metabolisms, who <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK541107/">lose heat</a> and might need to wear a sweater in their over-air-conditioned office. Our metabolisms decrease with age, which might be why you think your grandparents keep their house too warm.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is therefore difficult, if not impossible, to find a single thermostat setting that will make all of America happy. Heck, it’s hard enough to agree on anything in a single family. But the good news is that our bodies are very good at acclimating to new environments. Kingma told me that it only takes about 14 days for your body to adjust to a new baseline temperature. So if you’re used to New York City’s relatively mild summer average of 80°F and then move to Miami, where it’s closer to 90°, you’ll probably get used to it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The same holds for thermostat settings. If you do try and save some money by moving your thermostat one digit up, your body will adjust in a couple weeks, especially if you use a fan and wear lightweight clothing inside. Fans are especially effective, since they move air around your skin, helping sweat evaporate. Loose clothing has the same effect.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Many of the solutions to this particular problem don’t need to be high tech,” said Kingma. “Dealing with temperature is about as old as humans.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The role of evaporation cannot be overstated here. Sweating cools us down because the fluid on our skin evaporates and <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30454591/">helps us shed heat</a>. This explains why humidity is so miserable: The air is already so saturated with moisture that your sweat doesn’t evaporate effectively, which means you don’t cool down as easily. On windy days or in dry climates — a dry heat, if you will — sweat evaporates more readily, making it easier to stay cool. Fans can help in either scenario.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Focusing on reducing humidity is actually how we got air conditioning in the first place. In 1902, an engineer named Willis Carrier installed an “<a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US808897A/en">apparatus for treating air</a>” at a printing company in Brooklyn that was having problems with magazine pages wrinkling in the summer heat. The machine sent air through coils filled with cold water, which removed humidity from the air and cooled the room. It wasn’t until 1922 that the Carrier Air Conditioning Company of America introduced the first practical centrifugal refrigeration compressor that <a href="https://americanhistory.si.edu/collections/nmah_846092">would become the foundation</a> for modern air conditioners.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most AC units today do the job with three simple steps. They pull warm air out of the room, cool it down by running it over coils filled with refrigerants, and then pump the cold air back into the room while releasing the heat to the outside world by using a compressor, which is why your AC can sound like a starting car. Heat pumps, <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/heat-pumps-explained">which can heat and cool a home</a>, operate using the same principles when cooling — more on that in a minute.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Why heaters are the future of cooling" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PIulbHyK0bc?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Air conditioning is an energy-intensive process, and the refrigerants used in them present a few problems of their own. The most common refrigerants needed to make these machines work include chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) and hydrofluorocarbons (HCFCs), commonly known as “freon,” which are greenhouse gasses that deplete the ozone and contribute to climate change. The EPA has been banning many of these chemicals <a href="https://www.epa.gov/ods-phaseout/homeowners-and-consumers-frequently-asked-questions">in recent decades</a> to comply with <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22686105/future-of-life-ozone-hole-environmental-crisis-united-nations-cfcs">the Montreal Protocol on Substances Depleting the Ozone Layer</a>. However, many modern replacements that do not damage the ozone are still potent greenhouse gasses.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, air conditioning has historically been great for comfort but bad for the climate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not only do they require a lot of energy, which may or may not be supplied by fossil fuels, but most air conditioners also pump more greenhouse gasses into the atmosphere. ACs can keep us cool, but they’ll also warm the planet in the process. <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/23067049/heat-wave-air-conditioning-cooling-india-climate-change">It’s a real paradox</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Technologies like heat pumps promise a greener future for heating and cooling, but it will take years to update our HVAC infrastructure due to the cost and sheer scale of trading old, inefficient equipment with new systems. And for many, including renters and certain businesses, those upgrades may even be impossible. So for now, the fight over the thermostat continues.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The futile effort to make everyone comfortable</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no magical thermostat number to make everyone happy and maximize energy savings. For some, like Micah, the economist, 78º during the day is just fine. For others, 68º is perfect. There have been attempts to solve this problem on an institutional level. And if you’ve ever spent a hot summer day in a large office building, you know that some of those attempts have failed. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The big difference between setting a thermostat at work and at home, of course, is that you typically don’t have any control over the office thermostat. A look at how offices attempt to make everyone comfortable does, however, provide some insight into how we make decisions at home.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First formed as the American Society of Heating, Refrigeration, and Air-Conditioning Engineers, ASHRAE sets the industry standards for all things HVAC-related. One specific standard, ANSI/ASHRAE Standard 55, provides guidance on how to optimize thermal comfort in the built environment. That includes adapting temperature, humidity, air movement, and thermal radiation in an occupied space to the activity and clothing of the people occupying it. If you’re building a business and want to figure out how to make everyone inside the office comfortable, this is the guide.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">ASHRAE, unlike the EPA, specifies an ideal number to set a building’s thermostat to. It’s a range, actually: around 23°-26°C, or 73.4°-78.8°F, in the summer. <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/are-women-colder-than-men-the-science-behind-office-temperature-wars-11594373401">According to Bjarne Olesen</a>, a former ASHRAE president, “At least 80 percent of men and women are satisfied in that range.” Some might say that the upper end of that range is a bit too warm for good productivity. That assumption would line up with <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1438463921000225">a 2021 review</a> of scientific studies about temperature and work performance, which found the optimal temperature is between 22°-24°C, or 71.6°-75.2°F. But again, the number on the thermostat is not the only thing to consider.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even fancy office buildings are not immune to energy costs. While the EPA suggests that a single digit, or setpoint, higher on the thermostat can add up to 6 percent savings on your cooling bill, the savings are magnified if you scale them up to an entire building or even an entire city. A 2023 study of three decades of weather and energy cost data concluded that a single setpoint change coupled with behavioral changes <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1748-9326/ad0a56/pdf">could result in 20 percent energy savings</a>. Behavioral changes, which include everything from using fans in addition to AC and wearing lighter clothing, are especially essential in cities, which are designed to depend on air conditioning.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The technology of cool air allowed people to design buildings that would not normally be comfortable in our environment,” said Robert Bean, a fellow and lecturer at ASHRAE. “And as this environment changes, it puts us in a tough spot.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There have been some high-profile experiments in thermostat tweaks and energy savings. In 2005, Yuriko Koike, who was Japan’s environment minister at the time, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna8046182">launched an initiative called Cool Biz</a> that pushed government offices to turn their thermostats up to 82ºF from May to September to save energy and reduce greenhouse gas emissions. As an incentive of sorts, workers were allowed to ditch their formal office attire — suits and ties, for instance — in favor of lighter, more casual attire, like aloha shirts and linen pants. <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna8046182">There were fashion shows and everything</a>. Big corporations followed the government’s lead, and within a couple years, Cool Biz <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/SB118947740601523458">was a national pastime</a>. By 2023, some 86 percent of workplaces <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/09/24/business/japan-cool-biz.html">participated in the initiative</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When it comes to energy savings, turning the thermostat up works, too. Estimates vary, but Cool Biz reportedly saves Japan <a href="https://www.env.go.jp/en/press/2005/1028a.html">between 1</a> and <a href="http://www.demand.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/demand-insight-17-V3.pdf">3 million tons</a> of carbon dioxide emissions every year. The program became even more significant in the aftermath of the 2011 Fukushima nuclear disaster, when reactors across the country shut down and the government mandated further energy savings. They <a href="https://www.nebb.org/blog/cool-biz-energy-conservation-efforts-in-japan/">called it Super Cool Biz</a>. There’s even an initiative to turn thermostats down during the winter months. And yes, it is called Warm Biz.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s not rocket science,” said Kingma, the Dutch researcher. “As long as you have the ability to adapt, the problem may be solved by actually adapting.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not everybody in Japan loves this, of course. And there is research that shows productivity <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/19/sunday-review/air-conditioning-is-an-environmental-quandary.html">starts to dip</a> once the temperature rises to 77°F. But Japan’s example shows that an entire nation can adapt to different indoor temperatures for the greater good — and they can look good while they do it. Maybe the rest of the world can, too.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How to stay cool and save the planet</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let me make a confession: I like the thermostat set at 72. If it’s 72 or less outside, I’ll open a window and enjoy the breeze. If it’s warmer, I seal myself into my Brooklyn apartment, let the AC do the work, and wait for nightfall.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or at least, that’s what I used to do. I actually stopped setting my thermostat at 72 while reporting this story. After my conversations with thermal comfort researchers and HVAC professionals, I realized that cranking up the AC unnecessarily isn’t just a waste of energy, it’s not that comfortable either. It’s silly to get goosebumps inside in the middle of a July day because your cooling machine has cooled the room down too much. That’s why I started to heed the advice of the experts. And let me tell you, these experts are fans of fans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stefano Schiavon, a professor at the University of California Berkeley and a member of ASHRAE, told me his colleagues stick with a “fans first” strategy to cooling. “If you feel hot,” he said, “the first thing you turn on is a fan.” You can also use fans to supplement your AC, especially if you’re trying to stay comfortable at a high setpoint. Wearing loose clothing will only add to the cool enjoyment of it all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There&#8217;s been a movement — arguably driven by the air conditioning industry — to say the fan is a technology of the past, we don&#8217;t want them,” Schiavon explained. “But fans cost much less to manufacture, they use a small fraction of the energy, and they&#8217;re very intuitive to people so people know how to use them.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are also less obvious strategies to stay cool and save energy. Running your dishwasher and doing laundry at night cuts down on bringing excess heat into the home. You can also try spending time in the rooms of your house or apartment furthest from the sun, like on the northern side of the building or in a basement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maintenance also plays a big role in making sure everything is running at peak efficiency. That means cleaning your air conditioner vents and changing filters regularly. You should also be sure to keep cool air in and hot air out, so be careful about opening windows and doors unless you’re doing so to ventilate the space.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Smart thermostats are another promising solution, although they don’t <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/when-a-smart-thermostat-isnt-the-smart-choice/">necessarily</a> work in older homes with radiators or window units. If you have central AC, you can swap out the thermostat on your wall with an internet-connected thermostat that <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/appliances/thermostats/are-smart-thermostats-worth-it-a7822875275/">lets you control everything with an app</a>. You set the system up to automatically change settings at certain times of day or optimize their performance to save energy. Good ones cost <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/the-best-thermostat/">about $250</a>, but Amazon sells a basic one <a href="https://www.theverge.com/22791333/amazon-smart-thermostat-review-learning-geofencing-hunches">for $80</a>. If you have a window unit, you <a href="https://gizmodo.com.au/2023/01/smart-air-conditioner-guide/">can upgrade it with a smart AC controller</a> that adds connectivity. Your utility company may even <a href="https://www.coned.com/en/save-money/rebates-incentives-tax-credits/rebates-incentives-tax-credits-for-residential-customers/bring-your-thermostat-and-get-$85">help you pay for</a> one of these devices.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You also shouldn’t sleep on the heat pump trend. Again, heat pumps operate on the same principle as an air conditioner for cooling: They use electricity and refrigerants to pull humidity and heat out of the air. They tend to be <a href="https://www.architecturaldigest.com/reviews/hvac/heat-pump-vs-ac">as efficient as ACs</a>, too, so don’t expect your summer bills to drop if you make the switch. But by moving heat from one place to another rather than actually generating it, heat pumps are much more efficient when it comes to heating buildings. The Department of Energy says that heat pumps <a href="https://www.architecturaldigest.com/reviews/hvac/heat-pump-vs-ac">use up to 65 percent less electricity</a> than old fashioned furnaces or baseboard heaters. You <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/23498215/ev-tax-credit-2023-heat-pumps-solar">can also get a tax break</a> for installing one in your home.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There&#8217;s no wrong way to save energy,” said Jones from Energy Star. “It&#8217;s just a matter of figuring out what is appropriate and right for you given your situation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s possible that some magical new invention could come along and change the way we stay cool. One promising technology involves installing radiant panels filled with cold water that effectively <a href="https://engineering.princeton.edu/news/2020/09/09/multiple-benefits-world-without-air-conditioning">pull heat off of people as they pass by them</a> without actually cooling the air. Researchers at Princeton showed off a system like this in Singapore in 2019. They called it a Cold Tube, and people who walked through it reported feeling cool, even though the temperature of the air didn’t actually change. This type of technology is decades away from becoming mainstream, but it’s proof that a future without air conditioning is possible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But for the futuristic AC-free technology to work well, guess what’s required? Fans.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christophe Haubursin</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What should an electric car sound like?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/videos/358846/what-should-an-electric-car-sound-like" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358846</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T18:35:22Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T18:35:22Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Electric Vehicles" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Transportation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Video" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For over a century, the internal combustion engine has powered vehicles with an intricate combination of moving parts and tiny explosions. That combustion process inevitably made noise, and that noise came to define the background soundscape of our roads, cities, and day-to-day life. But as hybrids and EVs have become increasingly mainstream — and more [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For over a century, the internal combustion engine has powered vehicles with an intricate combination of moving parts and tiny explosions. That combustion process inevitably made noise, and that noise came to define the background soundscape of our roads, cities, and day-to-day life. But as hybrids and EVs have become increasingly mainstream — and more of their near-silent electric motors filled the streets — it’s clear that silent vehicles don’t fit in the ecosystem we’d built around cars.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After efforts spearheaded by associations of the blind and visually impaired, legislation eventually <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/24/business/electric-vehicle-noises-nhtsa.html">began to require</a> electric vehicles to emit an artificial engine noise from hidden external speakers. These hidden speaker systems, called “Acoustic Vehicle Alerting Systems” — or AVAS — had to meet certain sonic criteria. But they were also a blank slate for sound designers to decide how the cars of the future should sound.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Simone Biles is so back]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358882/simone-biles-olympic-trials-paris-floor-vault" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358882</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T18:32:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T18:35:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Champion gymnast Simone Biles turned in a powerhouse performance at the Olympic trials this week, securing her the top score and a key spot on the US team for the 2024 games in Paris this year.  Her floor routine and vault, in particular, drew top marks and standing ovations from the audience. It was a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA - JUNE 30: Simone Biles reacts after competing on the floor exercise on Day Four of the 2024 U.S. Olympic Team Gymnastics Trials at Target Center on June 30, 2024 in Minneapolis, Minnesota. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2160036162.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA - JUNE 30: Simone Biles reacts after competing on the floor exercise on Day Four of the 2024 U.S. Olympic Team Gymnastics Trials at Target Center on June 30, 2024 in Minneapolis, Minnesota. (Photo by Elsa/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Champion gymnast <a href="https://www.vox.com/22596341/simone-biles-withdrawal-osaka-olympics-mental-health">Simone Biles</a> turned in a powerhouse performance at the Olympic trials this week, securing her the top score and a key spot on the US team for the 2024 games in Paris this year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her floor routine and vault, in particular, drew top marks and standing ovations from the audience.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🚨 Stop what you’re doing and watch Simone Biles’ floor routine. 🚨 <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/USAGTrials24?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#USAGTrials24</a> <a href="https://t.co/eLBMtZuSEm">pic.twitter.com/eLBMtZuSEm</a></p>&mdash; NBC Olympics &amp; Paralympics (@NBCOlympics) <a href="https://twitter.com/NBCOlympics/status/1807593739805732914?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 1, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was a significant victory that follows Biles stepping away from the sport for <a href="https://www.womenshealthmag.com/health/a46341233/simone-biles-mental-health-therapy-anxiety-medication/">two years</a> after her early exit from the team competition in Tokyo, <a href="https://olympics.com/en/news/simone-biles-withdraws-from-women-s-all-around-final" data-type="link" data-id="https://olympics.com/en/news/simone-biles-withdraws-from-women-s-all-around-final">when she cited the need to “focus on her mental health.”</a> It’s a testament, too, to the work she’s done since that contest to strengthen her mental well-being and resume a grueling physical training regimen. At the trials, Biles used her win to highlight the immense pressure that elite athletes are under and the importance of being candid about these challenges.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’ve all been pretty open and honest [about] what we’re going through,” Biles, 27, said at a press conference following the meet. “But we’re always going to prioritize mental health and it’s really nice that Tokyo gave us that opportunity to open up that stage for that talk.”</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="U.S. Olympic Team Trials: Simone Biles Press Conference" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wAAWWmYkENY?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biles’s recent win marks the third time she’ll head to the Olympics and also makes her the oldest US woman gymnast to qualify for the Games since the 1950s. That Biles is resuming competition once more is a feat in and of itself. She’ll be one of a small group of gymnasts who’s ever participated in three consecutive Olympic Games. Her willingness to confront her mental health struggles also sends a compelling message, normalizing the decision to speak out and showing how athletes can be stronger for doing so.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Biles’s dominant performance at the Olympic trials, briefly explained </h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biles made her Olympic debut in Rio in 2016, where she won three individual gold medals and a team gold. Since then, she’s also won countless other competitions, including the US national championships <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/GMA/Culture/simone-biles-wins-9th-us-gymnastics-championship/story?id=110767892#:~:text=Simone%20Biles%20dominated%20at%20the,Paris%20Olympic%20Games%20this%20summer.&amp;text=The%2027%2Dyear%2Dold%20finished,%2C%20balance%20beam%2C%20and%20vault.">nine times</a>. Biles is widely regarded as the greatest gymnast of all time because of the heightened difficulty of the skills she performs and her ability to execute them. Her wins at the Olympics and numerous world championships <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/10/06/1204379375/simone-biles-most-decorated-gymnast-history">also make her the most decorated gymnast</a> ever.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Tokyo in 2021, Biles returned to the Olympics as a member of the US team. While there, she experienced what’s colloquially known as the “twisties,” a dangerous condition when gymnasts lose the sense of where they are in the air. Given the complexity and difficulty of gymnastic routines, the twisties are extremely hazardous and can result in serious injury. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After getting the “twisties” on a vault, Biles opted to withdraw from multiple competitions at the Olympics, including the team contest. Prior to that decision, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/simonebiles/p/CRxsq_kBZrP/?img_index=1" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.instagram.com/simonebiles/p/CRxsq_kBZrP/?img_index=1">she wrote in an Instagram post</a> that she felt like she had the “weight of the world on my shoulders at times,” later describing the challenges as the build-up of longstanding traumas that all came to a head.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s like compressing all of this shit for so many years. It just unfolded. You can’t compress trauma that much longer,” Biles said this year on the<em> </em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WHRCJwSds1U">podcast <em>Call Her Daddy</em></a><em>.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the years since Tokyo, Biles has said she was “petrified” to get back in the gym and revisit some of the skills she used to do. She’s described engaging in therapy as a major factor in helping her process and recover from the 2020 Olympics, and she’s also <a href="https://www.womenshealthmag.com/health/a46341233/simone-biles-mental-health-therapy-anxiety-medication/">talked about taking medication in order to combat anxiety.</a></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“[I’m] continuing to work on my body and my mind, just like I have the past year and a half, and it’s worked,” Biles said on <em>Call Her Daddy</em>. “I didn’t think therapy was going to work, and it’s working.” According to her coach Cecile Landi, Biles also now has a toolkit she’s built of techniques to combat stress during competitions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biles made a dominant return to this year’s Olympic trials, which consist of two days of competition, with each athlete doing all four gymnastics apparatuses — bars, beam, floor, and vault — on both days. The Olympic selection committee then considers the scores the athletes have received as well as other factors to determine who should make the team. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year, the decision was relatively straightforward: The committee went with the top-scoring athletes across the board, something they don’t always do because they also consider individual strengths on different apparatuses.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the end, Biles led <a href="https://thegymter.net/2024/06/30/2024-u-s-olympic-trials-results/">with 117.225 points</a> — five points ahead of the next competitor. She was followed by Olympic vets Suni Lee at 111.675, Jordan Chiles at 111.425, Jade Carey at 111.350, and newcomer Hezly Rivera at 111.150. The five of them are the team that’s heading to Paris, while Joscelyn Roberson and Leanne Wong will serve as traveling alternates. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biles secured her spot on the Olympic team with two days of stellar routines, particularly on floor and vault. On these two apparatuses, she’s long been known for having some of the highest difficulty scores of any gymnast competing, something that hasn’t changed in her return. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her floor exercise, for example, included a jaw-dropping move <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/olympics/2024/06/29/simone-biles-us-olympic-gymnastics-trials/74252515007/">dubbed the Biles II</a>, which involves three twists and two flips. And her vault, widely viewed <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/olympics/2023/09/29/simone-biles-vault-yurchenko-double-pike-difficulty/">as the toughest in women’s gymnastics</a> — featured what’s known as a Yurchenko double pike, something no other female gymnast has been able to do. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Biles’s focus on mental health sends an important message</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since her experience in Tokyo, Biles has been vocal about the need to care for her mental health and the need for professional athletes who’ve long dealt with intense scrutiny and stress to have outlets to discuss them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think now athletes are a little bit more in tune and we trust what our gut is saying, and just taking mental health a little bit more serious,” Biles said at this week’s press briefing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elite athletes are under incredible strain to perform, <a href="https://news.asu.edu/20231102-mental-health-and-pressure-perform">making them more prone to anxiety, depression</a>, and other mental health conditions. In the past, discussing mental health has also been stigmatized and viewed by some as a sign of weakness. Biles’s decision to speak out helps dispel some of that stigma and allows more people, including her teammates, to share their own concerns. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Suni [Lee] earlier, she came up to me and she was like ‘I’m not okay,’ and so we walk through it. We tell her, her why, why she’s doing it, and we just give her those reminders that she can do it, she’s done it before, so let’s go out there and get it,” Biles said at the press briefing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lee, too, has emphasized how important her mental health and staying positive has been as she’s navigated recovery from kidney disease in order to compete again this year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biles has also said she’s focused less on external judgment. In Tokyo, some viewers reacted negatively to Biles’s decision to pull out of competition, and if athletes — including her — make similar decisions in Paris, it’s possible it could engender that same response from certain observers. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I think it has to be for us, because it can’t be for anybody else because that’s not why we do it. We do it for ourselves, and the love for this sport, and the love for representing the US,” Biles said in the press briefing. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Forget four more years. Is Biden fit to serve now?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358818/should-biden-resign-trump-kamala-harris" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358818</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T17:30:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T17:30:30Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The controversy concerning President Joe Biden’s disastrous debate performance last week has largely focused on the electoral consequences of whether he stays in the presidential race or drops out. But it should also raise the question of whether he is fit to govern right now. During the debate, Biden — said by aides to be [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="ATLANTA, GEORGIA - JUNE 27: U.S. President Joe Biden walks off stage during the CNN Presidential Debate at the CNN Studios on June 27, 2024 in Atlanta, Georgia. President Biden and Republican presidential candidate, former U.S. President Donald Trump are facing off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 campaign. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/gettyimages-2159613249.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>ATLANTA, GEORGIA - JUNE 27: U.S. President Joe Biden walks off stage during the CNN Presidential Debate at the CNN Studios on June 27, 2024 in Atlanta, Georgia. President Biden and Republican presidential candidate, former U.S. President Donald Trump are facing off in the first presidential debate of the 2024 campaign. (Photo by Justin Sullivan/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The controversy concerning President Joe Biden’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358652/biden-drop-out-debate-harris-convention">disastrous debate performance</a> last week has largely focused on the electoral consequences of whether he stays in the presidential race or drops out. But it should also raise the question of whether he is fit to govern right now.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During the debate, Biden — said by aides to be <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4744889-joe-biden-has-a-cold-debate/">suffering from a cold</a> — seemed at times to be unable to string a sentence together, struggled to communicate Democrats’ message on some of the most important issues in the 2024 presidential election, and repeatedly failed to hold former President Donald Trump accountable for his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357776/biden-trump-debate-democracy-crisis-analysis-lies-facts">prolific lies</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The performance sparked days of debate about the 81-year-old’s ability to win the election, but there were concerns about the president’s age well before then. After Biden defeated Trump in 2020, those worries quieted and were <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/06/biden-age-wall-street-journal-morning-joe-1235959576/">dismissed when they began to percolate again</a> earlier this year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, though, there is no arguing with what everyone who watched the debate saw: a man who does not seem to possess the stamina or mental acuity needed to handle the notoriously demanding job of running the United States. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s team has <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/02/politics/white-house-biden-mental-fitness/index.html">forcefully rebutted</a> any claims that his performance at the debate mirrors how he is at work, even as reports to the contrary have begun to pile up. On <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/biden-age-concerns-world-leaders-democrats-6d753921">foreign trips</a>, in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/02/us/politics/biden-lapses.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">private meetings with current and former officials</a>, and at public events where he <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/4457527-biden-mistakenly-calls-egyptian-leader-president-of-mexico/">misspoke</a> or <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/joe-biden-freeze-video-juneteenth-event-white-house-questions-republicans-rnc-1911050">appeared to freeze up</a>, he’s said to be showing alarming signs of an inability to recall details or communicate clearly. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some <a href="https://x.com/AlexThomp/status/1808107417785217474">Biden allies have argued</a> that it doesn’t matter whether the president is capable of carrying out his duties because he is surrounded by competent people. But voters did not select those officials and advisers and don’t have a clear picture of just how much they are responsible for decisions coming from the White House.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s why the question should be not only whether he should step aside to make way for another Democratic nominee, but whether Vice President Kamala Harris should take the reins before Biden completes his first term.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats’ focus is on Biden’s ability to beat Trump and his competency in a second term. They worry that Biden’s lapses are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/02/us/politics/biden-lapses.html">only getting worse</a> and that he will surely deteriorate further in another four years. The firestorm around his age is now <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/03/democratic-rage-biden-debate-performance">jeopardizing down-ballot candidates</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, these concerns also present a strong argument against Biden staying in office. That’s a conversation that should be happening, but few are currently discussing it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This raises an urgent question of accountability and transparency: Who is running the country?&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">A cascade of reports suggests Biden is struggling to do his job</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reporting in recent days indicates that Biden might only be able to perform his presidential duties part of the time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some White House sources claim Biden is “dependably engaged” <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/29/two-bidens-trump-debate-2024-president">between 10 am and 4 pm</a>; otherwise and on foreign trips, he is “more likely to have verbal miscues and become fatigued,” Axios reported. Both Republican and Democratic members of Congress <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/joe-biden-age-election-2024-8ee15246">told the Wall Street Journal</a> that he’s shown his age in meetings with them, at times forgetting his own policies or speaking so quietly that he could not be heard. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At a G7 summit in mid-June, he was the only leader not to attend a less-scripted dinner. While diplomats said he was at times sharp, he also repeatedly struggled with his talking points, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/biden-age-concerns-world-leaders-democrats-6d753921">the Wall Street Journal also reported</a>. On the anniversary of D-Day in June, he also spoke so quietly that reporters covering his meeting with Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky strained to hear him, and he misspoke when describing what the $225 million that the US was sending to Ukraine would be used for. It was for munitions to protect the electric grid and other targets; he said it was to “reconstruct the electric grid.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the last year, multiple people close to Biden have gone to former White House chief of staff Ron Klain to <a href="https://x.com/yashar/status/1807936310998716721">express concern</a> that he was losing his train of thought and unable to pick up where he left off, much like he was on the debate stage, according to CNN political analyst Carl Bernstein. In the days since the debate, White House aides have expressed <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/02/biden-white-house-campaign-staff-freaking-out-debate">concern about the president’s mental fitness</a> and say they’re operating without leadership and direction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even former Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi, who defended the late California Senator Dianne Feinstein from calls for her resignation related to her difficulties with her duties, is now asking what <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/campaign/4751972-pelosi-biden-debate-performance/">she told MSNBC</a> is a “legitimate question.” Speaking about Biden’s debate performance, she asked, “Is this an episode, or is this a condition?&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an early June <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/poll-debate-should-biden-be-running-mental-abilities/">CBS/YouGov poll</a>, 65 percent said that he did not have the cognitive ability to be president; that number has since grown to 72 percent after the debate. The same share said he should not be running for president. By comparison, 49 percent said Trump did not have the cognitive ability to be president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All presidents rely upon a vast administration to carry out their policies, but these incidents heighten questions about whom he is relying on around him to get the job done. Recent reporting has suggested that there are only a few people that Biden really listens to. That includes <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/06/29/biden-debate-replace-advisers">first lady Jill Biden, his sister Valerie Biden Owens, Ted Kaufman</a> (his longtime friend and a former US senator from Delaware), Klain, and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/22/us/politics/klain-kaufman-biden-campaign-election.html">Mike Donilon</a>, who has closely advised him since the 1980s. Post-debate (and reportedly to the frustration of House Democrats), his son Hunter Biden, who was <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hunter-biden-gun-trial-federal-charges-delaware-5dd8a9380235c6360a1ddb691ef24a06">convicted of three felony gun charges</a> last month, has also been <a href="https://x.com/maxpcohen/status/1808219986491760815">sitting in on high-level meetings</a> with senior advisers. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden is surrounded by a plethora of other aides, but it’s not clear even to members of Biden’s party how much sway they have. As one House Democrat <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/07/03/democratic-rage-biden-debate-performance">told Axios</a>, “I don&#8217;t know who&#8217;s making decisions. Why the hell isn&#8217;t Biden on the phone with congressional leadership?”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, no president can be everything everywhere all at once — they must rely on their staff for counsel and to execute their vision. At issue is how much of the Biden administration’s policy is Biden’s vision and how much comes from other sources. And if his closest advisers have more sway over the country than perhaps is typical, they have a personal incentive to encourage Biden to stay in office and to seek a second term, regardless of his condition: They have the president’s ear; their power disappears when he leaves the White House.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What happens if Biden does leave office now?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this juncture, the only say voters have over whether Biden is president will come in November’s elections. Republicans are <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/4752735-biden-25th-amendment-divides-gop/">entertaining the idea</a> of pressuring Biden’s cabinet to invoke the 25th Amendment and remove him from office if he is unable to perform his duties, but their motivations are mostly political and it’s not clear that Biden stepping down would help them in November.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Biden is unwilling to step down on his own accord, Harris and a majority of the cabinet could declare him unfit to serve <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/2/9/14488980/25th-amendment-trump-pence">under the 25th Amendment</a>. That would require him to vacate his office, after which Harris would immediately assume the role of acting president. Harris could then nominate someone as vice president, who would have to be confirmed by a majority vote in both chambers of Congress. If Biden contests the assessment that he is unfit to serve, two-thirds of both chambers of Congress would have to find him fit to serve for him to be reinstated as president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, this would be a practically unthinkable last resort for Democrats. It’s much more likely that Biden would decide to step down without anyone having to force his hand. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That would require him to write a simple resignation letter addressed to the Secretary of State, just as <a href="https://www.archivesfoundation.org/documents/richard-nixon-resignation-letter-gerald-ford-pardon/">President Richard Nixon did in 1974</a>. Harris would automatically become president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris temporarily stepping up as president likely would mean she would become the Democratic nominee. This is the path of least resistance: Unlike other potential replacement nominees, she would have immediate access to Biden’s campaign funds, and the party doesn’t have much time to rally around a new nominee. It’s also probably the most democratic option since she has already been elected by voters nationally, unlike other potential candidates. But it would involve <a href="https://apnews.com/article/replacing-biden-nomination-options-dnc-democratic-convention-d23c02047b6a2c991737915972a2fa4c">unusual procedures</a> at the Democratic convention this August. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To dismiss any question of Biden resigning, however, is to ignore what is not just an electoral issue, but a governance issue at a time when the Supreme Court is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/01/us/politics/immunity-president-supreme-court.html">vastly expanding executive power</a>. The more powerful the person at the top, the more confidence voters deserve to have that they can perform the duties of their office and be held accountable for the promises they made — not just from 10 to 4. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Caribbean has a defense system against deadly hurricanes — but it’s vanishing]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/358329/down-to-earth-coral-reefs-hurricane-defense" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358329</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T14:16:52Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T14:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hurricane season has begun, and it’s off to a frightening start.&#160; On Wednesday morning, Beryl — a Category 4 storm and the first named hurricane of the year — was churning toward Jamaica, where it’s expected to make landfall later today and bring life-threatening wind and flooding. Earlier in the week, Beryl pummeled islands in the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/1000x1000.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Hurricane season has begun, and it’s off to a frightening start.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Wednesday morning, Beryl — a Category 4 storm and the first named hurricane of the year — was churning toward Jamaica, where it’s expected to make landfall later today and bring life-threatening wind and flooding. Earlier in the week, Beryl pummeled islands in the southeast Caribbean, including Grenada and St. Vincent and the Grenadines. It flattened buildings, wiped out electricity, and left at least four people dead. Heavy rainfall from the storm has also killed another three people in Venezuela.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hurricane Beryl is already record-breaking. On Tuesday, Beryl intensified into a Category 5 storm, before slowing back down Wednesday, making it the earliest Category 5 storm on record in the Atlantic. The storm, which is expected to reach the Cayman Islands by Thursday, also intensified at record speeds for a storm this early in the year, jumping from Category 1 to Category 4 in less than 24 hours.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Caribbean nations are particularly vulnerable to hurricanes, for the obvious reason that they&#8217;re often in the path of these storms. Hurricanes typically form in the Atlantic Ocean, west of northern Africa, and then travel west toward the Caribbean and Southeastern US.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Caribbean islands also have one of the world’s best defense systems against superstorms like Beryl. That system is hidden under the waves, it’s free, and it’s all-natural. It’s coral reefs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, most Caribbean nations are surrounded by a colorful patchwork of coral reefs, communities of living animals that function together as natural seawalls. These hard, rocklike creatures help dampen waves and reduce flooding. Research shows that coral reefs help dozens of countries avert billions of dollars in flood damage each year, in the Caribbean and globally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem, more pressing now than ever, is that these lifesaving ecosystems are vanishing —&nbsp;for the very same reason hurricanes are becoming more destructive.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">An all-natural hurricane defense system&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Each piece of coral on a reef is actually a colony of tiny animals, called polyps. Those polyps build skeletons out of calcium carbonate, not unlike a snail growing a shell, that form the structure of the reef.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s these coral skeletons that safeguard coastlines during a storm.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Simply put, waves lose energy when they ram into coral reefs. The bigger and taller the reef, the more wave energy it dissipates, for the same reason that coastal cities use breakwaters made of rocks to protect the shoreline. Remarkably, studies show that coral reefs can dissipate <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms4794">more than 90 percent</a> of wave energy. Waves with less energy are smaller and slower and don’t deal as much damage when they reach the shore.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even a small difference in a reef’s height can make a big difference in risk. Flood risk is often measured by what’s called the 100-year flood zone — an area in which the chance of a flood in a given year is 1 percent. If coral reefs in the US lose 1 meter of height, <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/pcmsc/value-us-coral-reefs-risk-reduction">a study</a> found, that zone in the US would grow by 104 square kilometers (or about 26,000 acres, nearly twice the size of Manhattan), putting about 51,000 more people at risk of flooding.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1491221549.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,15.041829306103,100,69.916341387793" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="St. Vincent and the Grenadines in the Caribbean." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This service —&nbsp;which coral reefs supply for free —&nbsp;is worth a lot.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Across the US, including Puerto Rico and other Caribbean islands, coral reefs help safeguard the homes of more than 18,000 people and avert $1.8 billion in flood damage each year, <a href="https://www.usgs.gov/centers/pcmsc/value-us-coral-reefs-risk-reduction">according</a> to a 2019 study by the US Geological Survey (USGS). Slightly <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5997709/">older research</a> found that, globally, this number is more than $4 billion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Without reefs, annual damages would more than double,” authors of the latter study, published in <em>Nature Communications, </em>wrote.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Caribbean nations are among those that benefit most from coral reefs and the damage they prevent. In the <em>Nature Communications </em>study, published in 2018, researchers ranked countries by how much flood damage coral reefs avert, relative to their GDP. Eight of the top 10 are Caribbean nations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No. 3 is Grenada,&nbsp;where Hurricane Beryl made landfall Monday.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Vanishing reefs</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All the financial and potentially life-saving benefits reefs provide make losing them that much scarier. And we are indeed losing them, especially in the Caribbean’s warm(ing) waters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The area of live hard corals on Caribbean reefs has fallen by about <a href="https://www.epa.gov/coral-reefs/us-coral-reefs">80 percent</a> in recent decades. In some regions, like the Florida Keys, the declines are <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23868423/florida-coral-reef-bleaching-heat-wave-climate-change">even steeper</a>.&nbsp;Compared to the 1970s, most Caribbean reefs are <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24137250/coral-reefs-bleaching-climate-change">almost unrecognizable today</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elkhorn coral — a species resembling moose antlers known for its wave-weakening abilities  —&nbsp;is especially endangered. In the 1970s, it grew across more than 30 percent of Caribbean reefs. By the 1980s, coverage of the coral had fallen to <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-37858-2">less than 2 percent</a>, a number that has likely only shrunk further in the years since.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A number of human behaviors have destroyed Caribbean coral, from coastal construction to fishing, as have some seemingly natural threats, like disease. The most enduring and existential problem, however, is climate change.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Warming ocean water disrupts the relationship between coral and a kind of symbiotic algae that lives inside the polyps. This disruption causes coral to turn white —&nbsp;or “bleach” —&nbsp;and starve. Bleached corals often have more trouble surviving other threats and die.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That means climate change is not only making tropical storms more severe, but it can also weaken our natural defenses against them.&nbsp;And this is an important, frightening point: A warming ocean makes storms more dangerous, not just because they’re intensifying faster or dropping more rain but because, in places like the Caribbean, we’re losing resilience that iconic ecosystems provide.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, July 3, 10:15 am ET:</em></strong><em><strong> </strong>This story was originally published on July 1 and has been updated multiple times with the latest information about Hurricane Beryl.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Oshan Jarow</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The world’s emotional status is actually pretty good, a new global report finds]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/358022/global-mental-health-happiness-measure-gdp" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358022</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T12:56:53Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Mental Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Psychology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Gallup Global Emotions Report for 2024, released last Tuesday, starts with a provocation. By trying to measure life’s intangibles, like feelings and emotions, the survey is seeking insights into the health of societies that, as the authors of the report themselves note, “traditional economic indicators such as GDP were never intended to capture.” Thankfully, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A series of five faces from smiling to frowning" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="MirageC/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-1531398464.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.gallup.com/analytics/349280/gallup-global-emotions-report.aspx">Gallup Global Emotions Report for 2024</a>, released last Tuesday, starts with a provocation. By trying to measure life’s intangibles, like feelings and emotions, the survey is seeking insights into the health of societies that<strong>, </strong>as the authors of the report themselves note, “traditional economic indicators such as GDP were never intended to capture.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thankfully, the report doesn’t offer yet another critique of why GDP <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/8131721/8131772/Stiglitz-Sen-Fitoussi-Commission-report.pdf">isn’t</a> a <a href="https://www.imf.org/external/pubs/ft/fandd/2017/03/pdf/coyle.pdf">perfect</a> indicator <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/05/16/magazine/16GDP-t.html">for progress</a>. Instead, it reports on the annual state of two indexes —&nbsp;one for positive emotions, the other for negative — that can complement GDP in trying to give us a quick sense of how society is actually doing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The results are surprisingly … fine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps you’ve felt that the <a href="https://cup.columbia.edu/book/social-acceleration/9780231148344">world is accelerating</a> into chaos; heard more chatter about the experts who think <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/1/10/24032987/ai-impacts-survey-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt-openai-existential-risk-superintelligence">AI will lead to human extinction</a>; or thought that even if it doesn’t, our continued failure to adequately deal with climate change <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/ng-interactive/2024/may/08/hopeless-and-broken-why-the-worlds-top-climate-scientists-are-in-despair">will get the job done anyway</a>. Or maybe you have children, and have been particularly attuned to how screwed we keep <a href="https://www.vox.com/24127431/smartphones-young-kids-children-parenting-social-media-teen-mental-health">hearing youth mental health is</a>.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Against doomerism</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Media is known to <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23596969/bad-news-negativity-bias-media">lean negative</a>. I could rewrite that doomer-esque paragraph about the world accelerating into gloomy chaos in its mirror image, rattling off incredibly exciting achievements, ideas, and success stories that fuel a sense of optimism. In fact, we did <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23632673/against-doomerism">a whole package like that here</a>.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, the topline results from the Gallup report look pretty good. Positive emotions reached a score of 71 out of 100 worldwide, the highest since the pandemic began. And negative emotions dropped for the first time since 2014. Among all age groups, young people were, by far, the best off. They experienced more positive emotions than anyone else and fewer negative ones. And in both directions, that’s been the case since measurement began in 2006.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/YoungPeople.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,14.411593607775,100,71.176812784451" alt="A set of three lines on a graph track happiness from 2006 to 2023, by age. The line for people ages 15-29 is noticeably higher than the two for older age groups." title="A set of three lines on a graph track happiness from 2006 to 2023, by age. The line for people ages 15-29 is noticeably higher than the two for older age groups." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="2024 Gallup Global Emotions report" data-portal-copyright="2024 Gallup Global Emotions report" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">And to make things even more interesting: While GDP does track nicely with <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/gdp-vs-happiness">some approximations of well-being</a>, not a single highly economically developed country is to be found in the top ranks of Gallup’s Positive Experiences Index. The list is dominated by Latin American and Southeast Asian countries. While comparing happiness levels across countries with different cultures can be fraught,<strong> </strong>this still raises questions about the emotional wealth of industrialized nations, but it also reflects the important challenges in figuring out how to measure something as <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24125481/consciousness-mental-health-language-science-ineffable-math">intangible and fuzzy</a> as how we actually feel.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Different methodologies deliver different pictures of well-being</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every measure of well-being is biased in its own way. The Gallup emotions survey, which polls about 1,000 respondents from each of the 142 included countries, focuses on two measures. The Positive Experience Index is an average across different questions:</p>

<ol>
<li>Did you feel well rested yesterday?</li>



<li>Were you treated with respect all day yesterday?</li>



<li>Did you smile or laugh a lot yesterday?</li>



<li>Did you learn or do something interesting yesterday?</li>



<li>Did you experience enjoyment during a lot of the day yesterday?</li>
</ol>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Higher scores mean positive feelings are more pervasive across a given country. The Negative Experience Index has a similar structure, asking whether respondents felt physical pain, worry, sadness, stress, or anger the day before.&nbsp;By this measure, the world’s happiest countries are places like Paraguay, Indonesia, and Thailand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But wait. Perhaps you’ve heard that Finland is actually the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/03/20/happiest-countries-world-happiness-report-2024.html#:~:text=Finland%20ranked%20as%20the%20happiest,to%20The%20World%20Happiness%20Report.&amp;text=For%20the%20seventh%20year%20in%20a%20row%2C%20Finland%20has%20landed,happiest%20countries%20in%20the%20world.">world’s happiest country</a>, and has been so for seven years in a row.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That ranking comes from the <a href="https://happiness-report.s3.amazonaws.com/2024/WHR+24.pdf">World Happiness Report</a>, which also uses data collected by Gallup, but on a different question. It focuses on life satisfaction, rather than daily experiences, by using a question known as the <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/122453/understanding-gallup-uses-cantril-scale.aspx">Cantril ladder</a>. It asks people to imagine a ladder with numbered steps from zero to 10, the top representing “the best possible life for you and the bottom of the ladder represents the worst possible life for you.” Then, they ask people to place themselves on the ladder.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you look at happiness that way, you get Scandinavian domination:</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/bsAv3-the-world-s-happiest-countries-in-2023-change-depending-on-what-you-measure-4.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,25.482830072286,100,49.034339855428" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you ask people to place themselves on a ladder of life satisfaction, you’ll get a different answer than if you ask the same group of people about the emotions they felt the day before. By conjuring the image of a societal ladder, the life satisfaction approach might actually be measuring something closer to <em>social status</em> than happiness, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24112787/world-happiness-report-country-rankings">my colleague Sigal Samuel argues</a>. “The poisonousness of social comparison can also help make sense of the observation that higher GDP doesn’t always correlate with increased happiness,” she writes. “The US has a high GDP, but it also has extremely high inequality. So a lot of Americans are comparing themselves to other, richer Americans — and becoming more miserable as a result.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Measuring daily emotional experiences could circumvent the concern of biasing results toward status. But it could also miss a bunch of other considerations associated with a happy life or, certainly, progress. Amartya Sen, the famous development economist, <a href="https://academic.oup.com/book/2148/chapter/142107672">argued</a> that reducing welfare to pleasurable mental conditions “can be very misleading, since it may fail to reflect a person’s real deprivation.” Humans are remarkably adaptive, and may still find and report pleasurable experiences while living in conditions of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/22/23884636/united-nations-sustainable-development-goals-extreme-poverty-hunger-climate-change-ukraine">extreme poverty</a>, limited opportunities for education and social mobility, or political oppression.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Interestingly, not a single country from the <a href="https://www.cfr.org/backgrounder/what-does-g7-do">G7</a> —&nbsp;an informal group of economic powerhouses that meet annually to coordinate on global governance —&nbsp;is to be found at the top of either list. If there were a G7 formed on the basis of happiness, rather than economic development, it would consist of countries like Paraguay and Indonesia, not the US or Germany. If we had a life satisfaction G7, it’d mostly just be Scandinavia.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The vibecession paradox in young people</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As revealed in Gallup’s report, young people have been more positive than anyone else for almost two decades, and were quickest to bounce back to pre-pandemic levels of feeling good. Even zooming in on the US, where youth anxiety and depression have <a href="https://www.pewtrusts.org/en/trend/archive/fall-2023/americas-mental-health-crisis">increased</a> over the past <a href="https://www.apa.org/monitor/2023/01/trends-improving-youth-mental-health">two decades</a>, the Gallup report says that whatever’s been going on, positive experiences are still more pervasive among the young than anyone else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of this discrepancy could boil down to methodology. The survey defines “young” as anyone between the ages of 15 and 30. The report contains no data on adolescents younger than 15, which is where a good deal of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/24127431/smartphones-young-kids-children-parenting-social-media-teen-mental-health">youth mental health crisis</a> (which seems mostly confined, curiously, <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/06/mental-health-crisis-anglosphere-depressed/678724/">to English-speaking countries</a>) is happening.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s still pretty interesting that young people between the ages of 15 and 30 show up as consistently more positive and resilient than any other group. Where is the <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23632673/against-doomerism">specter of doomerism</a> we keep hearing about?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2542519621002783">a 2021 global survey</a> of 10,000 young people aged 16-25 found that 75 percent think the “future is frightening,” 55 percent agree that “the things I most value will be destroyed,” and 56 percent agree that “humanity is doomed.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Stack these two surveys next to each other —&nbsp;positive emotions are pervasive among a majority of young people, but they also think that everything around them is going to shit — and you get a tension that looks oddly like <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/20/23964535/labor-market-employment-inflation-sentiment-economy-bad-polls">the vibecession</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beneath the headlines of the vibecession,&nbsp;describing the still <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/23/opinion/biden-trump-vibecession.html">ongoing</a> paradox of an economy that is <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/20/23964535/labor-market-employment-inflation-sentiment-economy-bad-polls">really good</a> on paper but <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/07/opinion/ezra-klein-podcast-annie-lowrey.html">really bad</a> according to the people living in it,&nbsp;something more nuanced seems to be going on. People are reporting that they’re personally doing fine. <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/newsletters/archive/2022/06/american-economy-negative-perception-inflation/661149/">It’s everything else</a> — the local economy, the national economy — that’s terrible.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The global emotions paradox seems similar. The prevailing mood looks something like: “I’m fine, but humanity is doomed.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The wealth of emotions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Projects that try to expand our repertoire of indicators that tell us <em>something</em> about how we’re doing as a civilization are worth celebrating. But we should also make sure we learn our lesson from the GDP days.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What makes a fixation on GDP <a href="https://www.happierlivesinstitute.org/key-ideas/">problematic</a> has little to do with an error or bias in the measure itself. It’s a very useful measure of economic activity (and really does track pretty well <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23862090/subjective-wellbeing-wealth-philanthropy-gdp-happiness-givewell">with life satisfaction</a>). But even the guy who created it, economist Simon Kuznets, <a href="https://fraser.stlouisfed.org/files/docs/publications/natincome_1934/19340104_nationalinc.pdf">warned in 1934</a> that “the welfare of a nation can &#8230; scarcely be inferred from a measurement of national income.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, GDP became shorthand for progress, warping it into something it was never meant to be. Similarly, surveys that try to keep track of the intangible aspects of societal health are wonderful complements to GDP. But the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24125481/consciousness-mental-health-language-science-ineffable-math">intangibles of the mind</a>, by their very definition, resist measurement. If I felt <a href="http://e">the most intense, pure, concentrated form of bliss</a> I’d ever known yesterday, could a survey question really capture that? Which is to say, we should hold these results lightly, and look at well-being from other perspectives, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even so, the emotions survey is already turning up a handful of mysteries to explore. Why are none of the most highly developed countries rich in positive emotions? Are young people doing a bit better than we thought? What lessons in governance for well-being might we learn from Paraguay, or Finland?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We could be coming out of a time when metrics like GDP fixated us on building societies that <a href="https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2010/07/26/a-big-little-idea-called-legibility/">look good on paper</a>. By turning intangible stuff into tractable data points, however imperfectly, maybe these kinds of surveys will help turn our attention toward judging and designing societies based on how it actually feels to be a part of them, scrutinizing the direct emotional experience of being enmeshed in their cities, people, technologies, and landscapes. Maybe then, we can all join the young in their apparently resilient and positive experiences of the world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story originally appeared in the&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect"><em><strong>Future Perfect</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup"><em><strong>Sign up here!</strong></em></a></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sucharita Tyagi</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Diljit Dosanjh is one of India’s biggest stars. Now he’s taking on America.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/music/358078/diljit-dosanjh-dil-luminati-tour-tonight-show" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358078</id>
			<updated>2024-07-03T13:29:08Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T12:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="India" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Music" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I first met Diljit Dosanjh in 2017, he was a rapidly rising star in India. His Hindi film debut, Udta Punjab, was all the rage, only a year after his Sardaar Ji became one of the top-grossing Punjabi films of all time. His single “Do You Know,” a slow jam-esque love song, was an [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA - APRIL 27: Diljit Dosanjh kicks off his Dil-Luminati Tour at BC Place on April 27, 2024 in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada. (Photo by Andrew Chin/Getty Images)" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Chin/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-2150511667.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When I first met Diljit Dosanjh in 2017, he was a rapidly rising star in India. His Hindi film debut, <em>Udta Punjab</em>, was all the rage, only a year after his <em>Sardaar Ji</em> became one of the top-grossing Punjabi films of all time. His single <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P-DhwN87JDY">“Do You Know,”</a> a slow jam-esque love song, was an enormous hit. He served as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rising_Star_(Indian_TV_series)">judge of a reality TV singing show</a> and had an <a href="https://indianexpress.com/photos/entertainment-gallery/diljit-dosanjh-begins-dream-tour-gets-houseful-response-on-his-first-gig-4645683/">international tour</a> in the works. “I have barely begun,” he told me then. “This is nothing.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, seven years later, the 40-year-old powerhouse is the first musical artist from India to perform on <em>The Tonight Show</em>, entering American homes like few artists from the country have before.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dosanjh breaks new ground in cinema and music on the regular, and at a breakneck pace — he’s collaborated with <a href="https://youtu.be/jADTdg-o8i0?si=U8VPJAVlUr6ryodG">Sia</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/3JABJHlY4Tw?si=Dqh8Br8rGy-dTkjv">Saweetie</a>, and more. Almost a year after his <a href="https://youtu.be/o0QGw1LZpxM?si=glAGRpD02-qSB_YJ">Coachella debut</a>, he <a href="https://ca.billboard.com/music/concerts/diljit-dosanjh-bc-place">sold out Vancouver’s BC Place this</a> April — with a 54,000-strong crowd. Dosanjh’s ongoing Dil-Luminati tour is packing venues all across the US.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dosanjh also stands out beyond entertainment. If you’re familiar with India’s current political climate, you’ll appreciate the boldness of his vehement support for the farmer protests. In an arena that has become <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/24160779/inside-indias-secret-campaign-to-threaten-and-harass-americans">increasingly hostile toward outspoken critics</a>, he’s boosted calls from farmers to <a href="https://x.com/diljitdosanjh/status/1333662799424196608?lang=en">repeal laws threatening their livelihoods</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Who is this man, who in one performance had <em>The Tonight Show</em> audience totally rapt and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8VsqKCs5E6/">Jimmy Fallon backstage speaking Punjabi</a>? And how, from among the scores of talented Indian artists, did he reach this level of success?&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">A boy from rural Punjab makes it big</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">India is a country of film and music dynasties, but Dosanjh hails from a small village without family connections to the entertainment scene.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At only 11 years old, Dosanjh was sent from his village of<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dosanjh_Kalan"> Dosanjh Kalan</a> to the Punjab city of Ludhiana. There he started his music career singing Sikh religious hymns called kirtans<em> </em>at local Gurdwaras, the Sikh place of worship. Although he left his village, his village never left him. Born Daljit Singh, Diljit adopted Dosanjh as a surname later in life, a sign of pride and a reminder of where his roots lie.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thanks to early collaborators who saw the spark of young talent, Dosanjh moved on to embrace Punjabi pop. Diljit remembers shooting his first music video titled “Ishq Da Uda Ada,” which roughly translates to “The ABCs of Love,” at age 17. The <a href="https://youtu.be/O7C-Yu-k6JE?si=gfJ0cU6-EMC4zSI7">video</a> showed Dosanjh learning to speak “pop star” as he appeared on-screen for the very first time. It’s hard to recognize that baby-faced man in the low-budget, early-2000s music video. In <a href="https://youtu.be/YOQDM3kXVCY?si=UBMxXAd-LzBw7Cs_">my latest interview with him</a>, which took place the day after his Fallon performance, Dosanjh said that kid doesn’t exist anymore.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2156475337_4d0459.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.430930326218,100,79.138139347563" alt="Diljit Donsanjh on a red carpet to promote his latest Punjabi film Jatt &amp; Juliet 3 in Mumbai last month with actresses Jasmin Bajwa and Neeru Bajwa." title="Diljit Donsanjh on a red carpet to promote his latest Punjabi film Jatt &amp; Juliet 3 in Mumbai last month with actresses Jasmin Bajwa and Neeru Bajwa." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Dosanjh promotes his latest Punjabi film &lt;em&gt;Jatt &amp; Juliet 3&lt;/em&gt; in Mumbai last month. | Sujit Jaiswal/AFP" data-portal-copyright="Sujit Jaiswal/AFP" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Eight years after that first album, Dosanjh starred in his debut film, <em>The Lion of Punjab</em>. In India, visible success in music often acts as a natural pipeline into movie roles where, with luck and talent, artists can find a wider audience and greater fame.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For those unfamiliar with the expansive cinematic landscape of India, you’ve likely heard of “Bollywood” — but that moniker applies only to Hindi-language cinema. In reality, there are as many film industries in India as there are languages. The Punjabi independent film industry is nearly 90 years old. Calling all Indian movies “Bollywood” is as blasphemous as saying “naan bread” (naan means bread) or using the words “chai tea latte” together in a sentence (chai means tea).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, Hindi cinema <em>does</em> command a huge audience, if not the largest, in India. In 2016, after 13 years as a successful musician, and five as a major Punjabi movie star, Dosanjh finally stepped into the Bollywood arena. In his first Hindi film, the star-studded <em>Udta Punjab</em> produced by some of the biggest names in Hindi cinema, Dosanjh played a police officer slowly coming to understand the extent of rampant drug use in the state.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Udta Punjab</em>’s director Abhishek Chaubey wanted to cast someone fresh and unexpected. “Diljit’s name came up in conversation and I jumped at it,” he told me. “He was very popular in Punjab and the Indian diaspora abroad and was up and coming into the mainstream consciousness of India as well.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dosanjh heard the film was going into production and thought to himself, “This is a film about Punjab. I should be starring in it.” A few days later, the call came, asking him to join. Things like this happen to him a lot, he says. He seems to be a master of manifestation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since <em>Udta Punjab</em>, Dosanjh’s popularity has grown in unpredictable and exhilarating ways. Chart-topping albums one after another, umpteen singles, countless leading roles in Punjabi and Hindi films, sold-out concerts in venues around the world, and a growing social media presence that includes a very active <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@diljitdosanjh">YouTube channel</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="KHUTTI | Official Music Video | Diljit Dosanjh x Saweetie" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3JABJHlY4Tw?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid all of this, Dosanjh has never lost connection with his music. His most iconic work is lively and soulful, driven by Punjab’s traditional Bhangra beat, born from the hollow of a round drum known as a “dhol.” His efforts to take Punjabi pop international shine through everything from his lyrics to his clothing. “The Punjabi attire is more important to me than the songs I pick for a performance,” Diljit stressed to me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last year, Dosanjh became the <a href="https://www.ndtv.com/offbeat/diljit-dosanjh-creates-history-becomes-first-punjabi-artist-to-perform-at-coachella-3952420">first Punjabi artist to perform at Coachella</a>. Fans back home couldn’t stop making Instagram reels about this achievement. The spectacle made one thing clear: If there is a stage in the world worth conquering, Dosanjh is working his way toward it.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How he uses his voice in a divided India</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike most celebrities in India, Dosanjh has been willing to comment on political issues. In today’s India, speaking out like this is considered a direct and vocal challenge to the <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/354424/india-election-results-2024-modi-congress-economy-democracy-liberalism">ruling government</a> of Indian Prime Minister Narendra&nbsp;Modi’s Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP). One only needs to look at replies on X to see the level of harassment that kind of criticism can engender.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020 and 2021, despite India’s strictly enforced Covid-19 lockdown, the nation witnessed the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2020%E2%80%932021_Indian_farmers%27_protest">largest-ever protests organized by farmers</a>, most of whom hailed from Haryana and Punjab, with many coming from a Sikh background like Dosanjh.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Among their demands, the farmers were asking for the revocation of recent Farm Laws passed by the Parliament of India. These laws in essence stand to turn their government-regulated market into an open market, subject to all the competition that implies, but are also an example of the government’s willingness to pass sweeping policies that affect people’s lives. Protests took place all over the country. The movement spread rapidly. <a href="https://x.com/rihanna/status/1356625889602199552?lang=en">Rihanna tweeted about it</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Few celebrity voices from within India had anything to say. But not Dosanjh. He amplified the demonstrations through <a href="https://x.com/diljitdosanjh/status/1333662799424196608?lang=en">social media</a>, visited the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fDcCHvE70XY">farmers</a>, and reportedly went as far as to <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/entertainment/hindi/bollywood/news/diljit-dosanjh-donated-rs-1-crore-to-buy-winter-wear-for-protesting-farmers-punjabi-singer-singga/articleshow/79582451.cms">support them monetarily</a>. This gained him fans and adversaries in equal measure. Most severely, he was labeled an anti-national separatist by Kangana Ranaut, a prominent <a href="https://www.zoomtventertainment.com/celebrity/article/kangana-ranaut-urges-diljit-dosanjh-to-admit-he-is-not-a-khalistani-after-latter-says-mai-tera-koi-jawab-ni-dena/715584">actor-turned-politician</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The welfare and representation of the Sikh community has always been important to Dosanjh. In an interview, while talking about his 2022 Netflix release <em>Jogi</em>, Dosanjh insisted the journalist refer to the infamous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1984_anti-Sikh_riots">Sikh Massacre</a> of 1984 as <a href="https://youtu.be/8Jz_dl_WNgY?si=cniFlwiAPDUa8ltB">genocide</a>. Not riots, genocide. Polite, but stern.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-1251867888.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.3931135206327,100,81.213772958735" alt="Fans watch Diljit Donsanjh&#039;s 2023 Coachella performance." title="Fans watch Diljit Donsanjh&#039;s 2023 Coachella performance." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The crowd at his 2023 Coachella performance. | Christina House/Los Angeles Times" data-portal-copyright="Christina House/Los Angeles Times" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">While Dosanjh is willing to get political in his comments, much of his music takes a less weighty tack. “Can’t sing political songs. They’ll send me to prison!” joked Dosanjh when I asked him why that was. On top of Punjabi hip-hop and Bhangra mash-ups, he&#8217;s known for easy rhymes with catchy hooks. In “<a href="https://youtu.be/mYWQ9dyBFlQ?si=6X2h6f4PQ5i6QWKJ">Magic</a>,” he sings about a woman with “eyes like Coca-Cola,” and in “<a href="https://youtu.be/mH_LFkWxpI0?si=O7wgh102QdhMwH7C">Lover</a>,” he insists, “<a href="https://www.lyricstranslation.in/2021/08/lover-lyrics-in-english-translation.html">I am your lover</a>, baby. I can’t recover now that I’ve taken one look at you.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of his newer music depicts a high-flying lifestyle, one more reflective of the American hip-hop scene than his rural Indian roots. He’s got songs with titles like “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/7xYQWvXu4QP9Zkmm864EIW?si=a0a7d240d8ca4291">Caviar</a>,” “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/6Zp8T8QuT8XK1gPPs68zRz?si=9fedc97480b44946">Lamborghini</a>,” “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/5dUpL1UYXkjXqf55FrBLgr?si=829b9c262aa24b19">High End</a>,” “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/46QbY78ha62aiu6gBgC7lS?si=e06df4d132bb4912">GOAT</a>,” and “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/4XxfOvudrnBRdlgzEaq1sd?si=70715485cb9a447a">Born to Shine</a>,” the latter two of which he performed on <em>The Tonight Show</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dosanjh even has a song dedicated to Rihanna titled “<a href="https://youtu.be/fMnbqjcAXkM?si=jtLcYA-Qljkm11Qy">Ri Ri</a>,” where he imagines the pop star decked out in a traditional Patiala suit worn by Punjabi women. He <a href="https://lyricsraag.com/riri-rihanna-song-diljit-dosanjh/">sings</a> about wanting to attend a concert of hers, dressed in traditional Punjabi clothes himself.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s worth digging a little deeper, though, to older songs in his repertoire, where you might be surprised to find a pious undertone. His 2013 album, simply titled “<a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/5fHd1bizqjiFFoW9HSD09T">Sikh</a>,” has eight tracks, each dedicated to spirituality and valor. He has also released other softer, more obviously <a href="https://youtu.be/MMUpUpZ-d2s?si=6sFeiQqv_4BWpIjm">devotional songs</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Diljit is a very, very mild-mannered person when you interact with him one-on-one,” Chaubey says. The sentiment is echoed by Imtiaz Ali, the latest Hindi filmmaker to have worked with Dosanjh, for the film <em>Amar Singh Chamkila</em>. The role of Chamkila fit Dosanjh perfectly: a Punjabi musician known for his catchy tunes, raucous lyrics, anti-establishment bent, and deep affection from his fans. Dosanjh “remains basic and simple in his approach,” Imtiaz observes. But don’t let the simplicity fool you, those still waters run way deep.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Bridging cultures through music — and a sense of humor</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite film and music industries that generate billions of streams on any given day, Indian culture has little foothold in America. If you’re not yet buying my argument, consider this. My in-laws — suburban, middle class, white New Jerseyites — may have heard of Shah Rukh Khan but couldn’t name <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23592808/pathaan-shah-rukh-khan-bollywood">one of his films</a>. They know <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytEP7D-e4e4">Priyanka Chopra as a Jonas</a>. Regardless of its seemingly enormous success in the West, none of them have either heard of <a href="https://www.vox.com/23220275/rrr-netflix-tollywood-hindutva-caste-system-oscars-2023"><em>RRR</em></a> or have one clue what a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/02/21/movies/rrr-song-naatu-naatu.html">“Naatu Naatu”</a> is. (If you need to click away from this article to Google now, please just go on, come back quickly, and don’t admit it to anyone).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the US is a new frontier that Dosanjh has set his sights on, fans in India need not worry. At every new venue, “Punjabi aa gaye” (“Punjabis have arrived”) is Dosanjh’s rallying cry. Dosanjh now serves as an ambassador of Punjabi, and Indian, culture.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2157512914.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Diljit Dosanjh and Jimmy Fallon on The Tonight Show stage." title="Diljit Dosanjh and Jimmy Fallon on The Tonight Show stage." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Dosanjh with Jimmy Fallon on &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show.&lt;/em&gt; | Rosalind O&#039;Connor/NBC" data-portal-copyright="Rosalind O&#039;Connor/NBC" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">His refrain is heard, too, across his social media. Some of the most popular posts on his page are mini-vlogs he shoots in his free time. One viral video features Dosanjh engaged in friendly <a href="https://youtu.be/gfXL-0CwdGM?si=cg2lpUEVgu1n46KS">banter with Alexa</a>, asking her to play his song, with the device repeatedly failing to understand his Punjabi accent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ever so playfully, the singer exposes how a certain kind of assimilative attitude is required of brown people when we go to America. By speaking naturally to no avail and then adopting the most comical, stereotypical American accent to get the job done, he flips the “outsider” narrative on its head. The virtual assistant tech, much like America, doesn’t know what it’s missing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I can confidently predict that Dosanjh — and a slew of other talent from India — will bring you an endless stream of vibrant, bass-heavy, dance-friendly, and uncompromisingly accented music and movies in years to come. Maybe you’ve already bought your ticket. But if not, as Dosanjh told me last week: “My answer remains the same. This is nothing. I have barely begun.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Paige Vega</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Our most meaningful solutions to the climate crisis are hidden in plain sight]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358669/climate-indigenous-solutions-extreme-weather" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358669</id>
			<updated>2024-07-02T21:26:31Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T11:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week alone, a massive Category 5 hurricane tore through the Caribbean, and major rainstorms in Switzerland, France, and Italy have caused flooding and landslides and have led to the deaths of at least seven people. Meanwhile, a severe heat wave forecasted to put many Californians through several consecutive days of triple-degree temperatures has gripped [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A florist rests in the shade as a heat wave begins to grip Los Angeles on July 1, 2024." data-caption="A florist rests in the shade as a heat wave begins to grip Los Angeles on July 1, 2024. " data-portal-copyright="Zoe Cranfill / The Los Angeles Times, via Getty" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-2159617282.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A florist rests in the shade as a heat wave begins to grip Los Angeles on July 1, 2024. </figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">This week alone, a massive <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358323/hurricane-beryl-rapid-intesification-caribbean-climate">Category 5 hurricane tore through the Caribbean</a>, and major rainstorms in <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20240701-seven-dead-after-storms-lash-france-switzerland-and-italy">Switzerland, France, and Italy</a> have caused flooding and landslides and have led to the deaths of at least seven people. Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/07/01/weather/heat-wave-california.html">a severe heat wave</a> forecasted to put many Californians through several consecutive days of triple-degree temperatures has gripped the West Coast. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These extreme weather events are notable for their ferocity and duration, and for how early in what climate scientists regard as “<a href="https://www.climatecentral.org/climate-matters/billion-dollar-disaster-seasons-2024">the disaster season</a>” they have come. But the surprise is that they are not at all surprising.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hurricane Beryl’s 165-mile winds this week marked the earliest point in the season on record that a tropical storm has reached this intensity. This is <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358323/hurricane-beryl-rapid-intesification-caribbean-climate">exactly in line</a> with what scientists have been predicting as climate change grows worse.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ocean surface temperatures serve as the engine for hurricanes and the last year provided some of the hottest underwater temperatures we’ve ever seen. Normally, by early July, the ocean wouldn’t be warm enough to power a major hurricane like Beryl. But the Atlantic Ocean absorbed a tremendous amount of heat in the past year as the planet heated up to the hottest average temperature on record.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As my colleague Umair Irfan <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358323/hurricane-beryl-rapid-intesification-caribbean-climate">wrote</a> yesterday: “The Atlantic Ocean has been gathering the raw materials for a raucous hurricane season for months and is now assembling them into major storms. Beryl is the Atlantic’s first big project for 2024.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And this is only the start of what’s poised to be an unprecedented season. In the coming months, more people are likely to be experiencing extreme conditions and climate disasters all around the world. The need for adaptations and solutions is more urgent than ever. And those solutions may very well come from a place that few would expect.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Some of our most effective solutions are the simplest</strong></h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent years, there’s <a href="https://www.un.org/en/academic-impact/we-are-indigenous-addressing-global-challenges-indigenous-knowledge">been</a> a <a href="https://www.nps.gov/subjects/tek/description.htm">growing</a> appreciation for <a href="https://insideclimatenews.org/news/14022024/to-save-the-planet-traditional-indigenous-knowledge-is-indispensable/">Indigenous</a> land stewardship and traditional knowledge. But what gets overlooked is that successfully managing those lands means that Indigenous people have already survived severe climate events and extreme weather.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Indigenous communities are leading the way in climate adaptations — from living alongside rapidly melting ice to building resilient coasts and community support networks.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indigenous knowledge does not mean going back to “traditional” methods; it means evolving, a characteristic that has always been a part of Indigenous life.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, we launched a new Vox Climate project, Changing With Our Climate, a limited series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future. Every month, we’ll be publishing one feature that centers an Indigenous community confronting extreme weather on the front lines. <a href="https://www.vox.com/e/358597">Our first story</a>, out today, by Aquinnah Wampanoag writer Joseph Lee, explains how Alaska Natives are responding to extreme heat in a place built on ice — one that is warming drastically faster than the rest of the world.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s no easy fix for the planet. But Indigenous people have simple solutions rooted in the depth of their knowledge. These stories will not mythologize Indigenous communities with bespoke, unapproachable, or mystic traditional practices and solutions. The series, instead, underscores humility as a throughline: Indigenous people realize we cannot bend the world to our human will. We’re far better and more resilient when we tune in and lean into changes when possible.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take Lee’s story on extreme heat, which we’ve excerpted below. For a landscape adapted to ice, “extreme” heat means a matter of just a few degrees. Alaska is <a href="https://nca2023.globalchange.gov/chapter/29/">warming</a> up to three times faster than the rest of the world, and the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-022-00498-3">Arctic</a> is warming nearly double that. Alaska’s North Slope saw an average annual temperature increase of <a href="https://www.climatehubs.usda.gov/hubs/northwest/topic/alaska-and-changing-climate#:~:text=Alaska%27s%20statewide%20annual%20average%20surface,to%20the%201981%E2%80%932010%20period">6 degrees since 1971</a>. Since 1970, the US as a whole has warmed by 2.6 degrees.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;(You can read the rest of the story <a href="https://www.vox.com/e/358597">here</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>In Bethel, Alaska, the Kuskokwim River is the heart of the community, providing food, transportation, employment, and community throughout the year.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The only way to get to Bethel is by plane, which can be very expensive — or by the river. In the winter, snow machines zip through town, heading up and down the frozen river to the dozens of villages that depend on Bethel for food, supplies, health care, and much more. In the summer, people travel by boat to spend days at their fish camps on the river, smoking salmon to eat throughout the rest of the year. In between, when the ice is forming or beginning to break up, the river can be dangerous: too frozen for boats, but too unstable for snow machines and cars.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Lately, those shoulder seasons have been shifting, extending, and becoming terrifyingly unpredictable.&nbsp;</em></p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/Vox_AlaskaHeat_80ede6.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Alexandra Bowman" data-portal-copyright="Alexandra Bowman" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Every year, flooding and erosion get worse, fish are dying, and the winter ice is becoming more dangerous. Kevin Whitworth, the executive director of the </em><a href="https://www.kuskosalmon.org/"><em>Kuskokwim River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission</em></a><em>, says </em><a href="https://arctic.noaa.gov/report-card/report-card-2023/divergent-responses-of-western-alaska-salmon-to-a-changing-climate/#:~:text=Changes%20in%20salmon%20abundance,2)."><em>declining salmon populations</em></a><em> are especially concerning. “It<em>’</em>s hard times,” he said. “Our people are subsistence-based people. They<em>’</em>re not economy-based people. They rely on the river as their grocery store. Their life is the river.”&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Fifty-six percent of the statewide subsistence harvest is made up of fish. Beyond its cultural and community importance, subsistence is crucial for Alaska Natives because of the high cost of groceries. In a study of 261 urban communities across the country, the </em><a href="https://centerrec.sharepoint.com/:w:/s/DataProducts/EZyflv55hWZHmRzJ4EilYj8BxJOMVaxLqkaZvl49l9C9Wg?rtime=cx0dTDeV3Eg"><em>Council for Community and Economic Research</em></a><em> found that the three most expensive places for groceries were Juneau, Fairbanks, and Anchorage. Prices in more remote communities like Bethel are often even higher.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Salmon’s drastic decline can be attributed to a number of causes, including warming waters and increased offshore trawling. Every year, ocean trawlers fishing primarily for pollock catch, kill, and discard about 141 million pounds of salmon, halibut, and other species, an extraordinarily wasteful practice that </em><a href="https://salmonstate.org/press-releases/ak-fishing-groups-tribes-applaud-rep-peltolas-bycatch-bills"><em>Indigenous people and other groups</em></a><em> in Alaska have been rallying against. Meanwhile, communities upriver are severely limited in the number of salmon they can take from the river. “Right now, the salmon are crashing and we&#8217;re seeing big changes with the climate,” Whitworth says.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>So, facing declining salmon populations and a dangerous river, Indigenous people in the region are shifting their norms, too. While chinook and chum salmon are restricted, sockeye salmon, a less traditionally popular and available fish, has become an increasingly viable alternative.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Traditional salmon fishing techniques make it hard to separate different species of salmon, so Whitworth and the Kuskokwim River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission have been encouraging local fishers to use dip nets, large circular nets that allow people to target sockeye.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>In the commission’s </em><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5afdc3d5e74940913f78773d/t/65382f244a92ca079706dd80/1698180924749/Kuskokwim_EOS+Summary_final_linked+copy.pdf"><em>2023 end of season report</em></a><em>, sockeye made up about 40 percent of the estimated total salmon harvest on the lower Kuskokwim, a number that Whitworth says is much higher than it used to be.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>These shifts may sound like tiny changes in the face of global climate trends, but these are the kinds of local adaptations that will help communities thrive in a warming world. Outside of Alaska, planting trees to create more shade in urban heat islands or hiring more </em><a href="https://gothamist.com/news/lifeguard-shortage-limits-reopening-of-nycs-grand-astoria-pool"><em>lifeguards</em></a><em> for public pools could have a similar impact.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>But these solutions are within reach and meaningful — they literally save lives.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Read more <a href="https://www.vox.com/e/358597">here</a>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today, Explained</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joseph Lee</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What 6 degrees of warming means for a community built on ice]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358597/climate-extreme-heat-alaska-indigenous-solutions" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358597</id>
			<updated>2024-07-02T21:16:35Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-03T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story is the first feature in a new Vox special project, Changing With Our Climate, a limited series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future.&#160; When Priscilla Frankson thinks about home, she thinks about ice — thick sea ice stretching out toward the horizon.&#160; Frankson, an Iñupiaq masters [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration shows a community of Alaska Native people engaging with a scene of water with melting ice sheets. They&#039;re fishing with nets, swimming, prepping the fish, exploring and taking notes. Mountains are in the background." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Alexandra Bowman for Vox" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/Vox_AlaskaHeat.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story is the first feature in a new Vox special project, </em>Changing With Our Climate<em>, a limited series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future.&nbsp;</em></p>

<p class="has-drop-cap has-text-align-none">When Priscilla Frankson thinks about home, she thinks about ice — thick sea ice stretching out toward the horizon.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Frankson, an Iñupiaq masters student in Tribal Leadership and Governance at Arizona State University, is from Point Hope (Tikiġaq), Alaska, a small city about 125 miles above the Arctic Circle and one of the northernmost communities in the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For us, the ice is a part of land, even though every single year it changes and it’s always different,” she said. “I think of the way that my boots kind of crackle over the ice, or the different sounds that it makes when there’s a very thin kind of sheet of snow on the top, and how it’s a little bit softer.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Point Hope, where summer temperatures rarely break 60 degrees, ice and cold are a part of life. Thick, reliable sea ice is essential for harvesting whales, a key part of the subsistence diets, a lifestyle built around harvesting wild foods for personal and community use, of Point Hope’s Iñupiaq residents.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Growing up, even when temperatures reached 40 below zero, Frankson would bundle up to go play outside in the snow or go hunting on the ice, while whales passed by. And on cold, cloudless nights, the northern lights would be spectacularly clear, flashing and dancing across the sky. It was a sight that Frankson said still seems too incredible to be real — even after years of observing it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But climate change is threatening all of this.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alaska is <a href="https://nca2023.globalchange.gov/chapter/29/">warming</a> up to three times faster than the rest of the world, and the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-022-00498-3">Arctic</a> is warming nearly double that. Alaska’s North Slope, where Point Hope is located, saw an average annual temperature increase of <a href="https://www.climatehubs.usda.gov/hubs/northwest/topic/alaska-and-changing-climate#:~:text=Alaska%27s%20statewide%20annual%20average%20surface,to%20the%201981%E2%80%932010%20period">6 degrees since 1971</a>. Since 1970, the US as a whole has warmed by 2.6 degrees.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although the difference between, say, a day that is 0 degrees and one that is 5 degrees may seem like no big deal, the impact of these rising averages is immense.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sea ice is forming later in the year than usual and is not as predictable as it used to be. As the permafrost thaws, siġlauqs — the traditional ice cellars carved into the land — are caving in or flooding. The animals that people rely on for food and goods — whales, fish, caribou — are also growing harder to find.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/GettyImages-161120331.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.671533564388,100,78.656932871224" alt="Point Hope, Aslaka." title="Point Hope, Aslaka." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Point Hope, Alaska. | Andy Cross/Denver Post via Getty Images." data-portal-copyright="Andy Cross/Denver Post via Getty Images." />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite the challenges, Frankson, who researches the social impact of declining caribou populations, says that Iñupiaq people are not going to change their entire way of life, but instead are making small adjustments to changing conditions. “We’re not scared enough to stop hunting, we’re not scared enough to stop going out on the ice, we’re not scared enough to do any of this,” she said. “We’re just learning how to adapt, as we always have.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To adapt to the warming climate, Indigenous people in Alaska are relying on their deep understanding and respect for the land, a kind of humility developed over countless generations. “You can’t really change the Arctic,” Frankson said. “You can only change with the Arctic.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, daily life in Alaska — with its northern lights, its dependence on ice and the movement of caribou — may feel unrelatable. But this way of living in tune with the environment and gracefully adapting to a changing climate is becoming increasingly essential for the rest of the country. The strategies that Indigenous people in Alaska are developing show that sometimes the best forms of climate adaptation are achievable, local solutions.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Generations of extreme conditions have equipped Alaska Natives with the willingness and ability to embrace this kind of adaptation. As the impacts of climate change grow increasingly severe in the rest of the country, we could all learn from that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Swimming may not seem like an adaptation to global warming. But in Alaska, it is.&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hundreds of miles south of Point Hope, in Bethel, Alaska, the Kuskokwim River is the heart of the community, providing food, transportation, employment, and community throughout the year.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The only way to get to Bethel is by plane, which can be very expensive, or by the river. In the winter, snow machines zip through town, heading up and down the frozen river to the dozens of villages that depend on Bethel for food, supplies, health care, and much more. In the summer, people travel by boat to spend days at their fish camps on the river, smoking salmon to eat throughout the rest of the year. In between, when the ice is forming or beginning to break up, the river can be dangerous: too frozen for boats, but too unstable for snow machines and cars.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“You can’t really change the Arctic. You can only change with the Arctic.”&nbsp;</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lately, those shoulder seasons have been shifting, extending, and becoming terrifyingly unpredictable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every year, flooding and erosion get worse, fish are dying, and the winter ice is becoming more dangerous. Kevin Whitworth, the executive director of the <a href="https://www.kuskosalmon.org/">Kuskokwim River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission</a>, says <a href="https://arctic.noaa.gov/report-card/report-card-2023/divergent-responses-of-western-alaska-salmon-to-a-changing-climate/#:~:text=Changes%20in%20salmon%20abundance,2).">declining salmon populations</a> are especially concerning. “It’s hard times,” he said. “Our people are subsistence-based people. They’re not economy-based people. They rely on the river as their grocery store. Their life is the river.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/subsistence/federal-subsistence-management-program">Federal Subsistence Management Program</a>, rural Alaskans harvest 295 pounds of wild food per person, more than the 255 pounds of domestic meat, fish, and poultry that the average American consumes per year. Fifty-six percent of the statewide subsistence harvest is made up of fish. Beyond its cultural and community importance, subsistence is crucial for Alaska Natives because of the high cost of groceries. In a study of 261 urban communities across the country, the <a href="https://centerrec.sharepoint.com/:w:/s/DataProducts/EZyflv55hWZHmRzJ4EilYj8BxJOMVaxLqkaZvl49l9C9Wg?rtime=cx0dTDeV3Eg">Council for Community and Economic Research</a> found that the three most expensive places for groceries were Juneau, Fairbanks, and Anchorage. Prices in more remote communities like Bethel are often even higher.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Salmon’s drastic decline can be attributed to a number of causes, including warming waters and increased offshore trawling. Every year, ocean trawlers fishing primarily for pollock catch, kill, and discard about 141 million pounds of salmon, halibut, and other species, an extraordinarily wasteful practice that <a href="https://salmonstate.org/press-releases/ak-fishing-groups-tribes-applaud-rep-peltolas-bycatch-bills">Indigenous people and other groups</a> in Alaska have been rallying against. Meanwhile, communities upriver are severely limited in the number of salmon they can take from the river. “Right now, the salmon are crashing and we’re seeing big changes with the climate,” Whitworth says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bethel Vice Mayor Sophie Swope, who also sits on the <a href="https://nativecouncil.org/">Orutsararmiut Native</a> tribal council, says that river conditions have become more dangerous for fishing and travel. “It used to be pretty dependable that you could just go drive out during the winter and it would be fine and safe,” Swope said. “Now, you have to keep an ear out for what the river conditions are.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whitworth, who is Athabascan from McGrath, says that because of salmon’s increasing scarcity, people are taking greater risks to get fish even though the river ice forms later in the season and is less reliable, leading to accidents and <a href="http://www.epi.alaska.gov/bulletins/docs/b2023_08.pdf?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=govdelivery">drownings</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So, facing declining salmon populations and a dangerous river, Indigenous people in the region are shifting their norms, too. While chinook and chum salmon are restricted, sockeye salmon, a less traditionally popular and available fish, has become an increasingly viable alternative.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Chinook has been a staple of Indigenous subsistence diets for generations, but people are doing what they must to use what is available now. Traditional salmon fishing techniques make it hard to separate different species of salmon, so Whitworth and the Kuskokwim River Inter-Tribal Fish Commission have been encouraging local fishers to use dip nets, large circular nets that allow people to target sockeye.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the commission’s <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5afdc3d5e74940913f78773d/t/65382f244a92ca079706dd80/1698180924749/Kuskokwim_EOS+Summary_final_linked+copy.pdf">2023 end-of-season report</a>, sockeye made up about 40 percent of the estimated total salmon harvest on the lower Kuskokwim, a number that Whitworth says is much higher than it used to be. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As warming continues to impact the river, the local community has also been taking steps to protect its people.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2014, Yup’ik elder Beverly Hoffman and others finally succeeded in a <a href="https://www.adn.com/rural-alaska/article/bethels-first-pool-testament-perseverance-engineering-and-state-money/2014/09/21/">decades-long effort</a> to build a community pool in Bethel, which is now a resource for people throughout the region to learn how to swim, preparing them for an increasingly unpredictable river. Hoffman and others recognize that they cannot control the river, but they can help prepare the community to survive its dangers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swimming lessons and dip nets might sound like tiny changes in the face of global climate trends, but these are the kinds of local adaptations that will help communities thrive in a warming world. Outside of Alaska, planting trees to create more shade in urban heat islands or hiring more <a href="https://gothamist.com/news/lifeguard-shortage-limits-reopening-of-nycs-grand-astoria-pool">lifeguards</a> for public pools could have a similar impact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But these solutions are within reach and meaningful; they literally save lives.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such approachable adaptations mean understanding that although we have a limited ability to change the climate, there are many more options to change our own behavior.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>“This is what Indigenous knowledge is</strong>”</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As temperatures continue to rise, Alaska Natives are turning to intergenerational knowledge and community observations to build a wealth of data that they hope will urge non-Indigenous decision-makers to listen to what they have to say.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Unalaska, the largest city in the Aleutian Chain, the Qawalangin Tribe is gathering community feedback on climate change and what the people are experiencing. The tribe will then use these observations to help develop its climate resilience plans, which include <a href="https://www.qawalangin.com/camp-q">culture camps</a> with traditional dances and classes on kayak making, traditional food nights, and water quality testing programs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vera Metcalf is the executive director of the <a href="https://eskimowalruscommission.org/">Eskimo Walrus Commission</a>, which represents 19 coastal communities. Metcalf says that Indigenous walrus hunters have adapted to climate change by participating in research projects led by agencies like the US Fish and Wildlife Service. “In the past, we were largely ignored in research occurring in our homeland and waters,” she said. “When you combine the two ways of thinking, it really becomes a rich resource of information.”&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Changing With Our Climate: A limited series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future</h3>



<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s no easy fix for the planet, but Indigenous people have simple solutions rooted in the depth of their knowledge. This story is the first installment of a new Vox series exploring frameworks for responding to extreme weather and the climate crisis. Every month through October, we’ll be publishing a new feature that centers an Indigenous community responding to various aspects of climate disasters, from major storms like hurricanes and typhoons, to extreme heat, rising seas, wildfires, and spreading aridity.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Roberta Tuurraq Glenn-Borade, Iñupiaq from Utqiaġvik, is the project coordinator and community liaison at the <a href="https://arctic-aok.org/">Alaska Arctic Observatory and Knowledge Hub</a>, where she works with observers from four communities in the Alaskan Arctic.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/30d30ab062ea4aadb39b3734dd7770ae">Community observers</a> share details like air temperature, wind speed, ice conditions, and animal observations, sometimes sending in photos of animals being harvested. Glenn-Borade and her team then take this data and share it with agencies like the US National Weather Service, which releases forecasts for the region. Glenn-Borade says that, historically, these forecasts prioritized larger ships offshore rather than Indigenous people living on the coast and hopes that using local observations will lead to better forecasts for Indigenous communities. “That kind of foresight of what the conditions will be can really make a difference between life or death,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Glenn-Borade also says this kind of local observation provides invaluable historical context about how the coast and the ice have changed over the years, what is within normal ranges, and what is unexpected.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That’s what Indigenous knowledge is,” she said. “It is constant tracking and understanding and monitoring what’s going on and being prepared to respond on the fly.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As the world warms, these examples from Alaska offer a warning that we can’t simply do everything the way we used to. Saudi Arabia, for example, can no longer ignore the deadly impacts heat is having on <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/356624/hajj-mecca-heat-saudi-arabia-pilgrims-climate-change-prophet">Hajj</a>. Places like the Pacific Northwest can no longer count on mild summers and will save <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/health/new-count-of-states-past-heat-wave-deaths-give-a-warning-to-the-pnw/">lives</a> by investing in cooling infrastructure. But they also offer hope that if we can shift away from trying to change the environment to suit us, instead of the other way around, there may be a chance of finding creative, unexpected ways of changing with our climate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I spoke with Glenn-Borade recently, she told me she and her people are proud “that we’re still here. We’re not going to die off. Our languages aren’t going to die off. We will adapt. We’ll continue to adapt our lifestyles as the environment changes.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
