<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-11-01T01:59:10+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How much should kids know about politics?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/381410/kids-teens-politics-election-misinformation" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381410</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T18:23:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T07:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the midst of a heated presidential election, political coverage and commentary can feel unavoidable. Kids are not immune — they might be picking up information about the race from the adults in their lives, at recess, or on social media. As much as parents may think their children are oblivious, research shows kids, including [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of a father casting a paper ballot in a box. He is holding his daughter’s hand. She holds a toy bear." data-caption="Children as young as 5 have shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1277323587.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Children as young as 5 have shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In the midst of a heated presidential election, political coverage and commentary can feel unavoidable. Kids are not immune — they might be picking up information about the race from the adults in their lives, at recess, or on social media. As much as parents may think their children are oblivious, research shows kids, including very young ones, are paying attention. One study found that nearly all of the surveyed kids between the ages of 5 and 11<a href="https://news.ku.edu/news/article/2019/08/06/researchers-find-youths-knowledgeable-about-politics-call-even-better-early-political"> could name the candidates</a> running for president in 2016.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Kids as young as kindergarten and first grade can name candidates when they see their pictures,” says <a href="https://www.whitman.edu/academics/majors-and-programs/psychology/faculty-and-staff/erin-pahlke">Erin Pahlke</a>, an associate professor of psychology at Whitman College and a co-author of the study, “and they have a sense of what the candidates believe.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don’t have to have an in-depth discussion with your child every time they encounter a political topic. When it comes to political conversations with kids, experts say you should answer their questions about the civic process and quell any fears they may have — but avoid telling them how to think.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">When kids are young, teach them about civic engagement</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since children as young as 5 are shown to already have a basic understanding of presidents and elections, you can use this early exposure to guide and inform their knowledge. Kids of all ages can learn about civic engagement through activities like mock elections in school or accompanying their parents to the polls on Election Day, says clinical psychologist <a href="https://melissagoldbergmintz.com/">Melissa Goldberg Mintz</a>, author of<em> </em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/dp/1462547494"><em>Has Your Child </em></a><em><a href="https://www.guilford.com/books/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/Melissa-Goldberg-Mintz/9781462547494?srsltid=AfmBOopzU8cgP9dUWxCAgcx6boSaYPYd55-fu1OnB0NLCoFBcjd1EPcy">Been</a></em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Has-Your-Child-Been-Traumatized/dp/1462547494"><em> Traumatized? How to Know and What to do to Promote Healing and Recovery</em></a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can use this experience to teach kids how elections work. Children as young as 5 can grasp that voters are choosing between two major candidates from opposite parties and for laws that affect where they live, Pahlke says. If an elementary school-aged child has particular interests — maybe they love trains and buses — you could explain how proposed legislation would impact transportation in your city or town, Goldberg Mintz says. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But don’t get too in the weeds or too prescriptive. “Something we would not want to do,” she says, “is talk about ‘With global climate change and increasing natural disasters, our city is doomed if we don&#8217;t have these protective flood measures.’”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Allow kids to lead the dialogue</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although children are exposed to more political information than their parents realize, their understanding or the conclusions they draw is sometimes incorrect, Pahlke says. Parents have a responsibility to clear up these misunderstandings, she continues, so ask your kids what they know about certain topics. Watching or reading the news together can be an effective way to start a conversation, says <a href="https://www.american.edu/cas/faculty/caporino.cfm">Nicole Caporino</a>, an associate professor of psychology at American University. If any stories trigger fear or confusion, you can discuss the likelihood that their fears will materialize, point out hopeful news stories, and assure them the family will cope with any potential challenges together, Caporino says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Caporino’s research has suggested that <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32100153/">most children and adolescents were worried</a> about political issues. Don’t downplay their concerns, Goldberg Mintz says. Do your best to give them an honest answer, but try not to give into fear or negativity, even if you are feeling scared. You might say, “I hear that you’re worried about that, and I have some concerns too. But we’ll figure out ways to get through it if that happens.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parents should open the door to these conversations, because chances are children might already be thinking about these topics, Pahlke says. However, you shouldn’t offer up too many details if your child isn’t interested. For example, if you ask your elementary-aged kid, “The presidential election is coming up. Have you heard anything?” and they don’t have a strong opinion or say they haven’t talked about it with their friends, you can leave it at that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We don&#8217;t ever want to volunteer bloody details or gory information that kids don&#8217;t already know about,” Goldberg Mintz says. “We want to be a trustworthy source for them. And if we don&#8217;t know the answer, we want to show them how to get to a trustworthy source.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens who are closer to voting age can handle discussions about specific policies, Pahlke says, and parents can explain various perspectives and potential outcomes. Parents can also talk with their teens about the importance of voting, Goldberg Mintz says.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Encourage them to fact-check what they see on social media</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html">increasingly turning to social media</a> to stay informed, with one 2022 survey finding that half of Gen Z adolescents <a href="https://deloitte.wsj.com/cmo/digital-social-media-power-gen-z-teens-news-consumption-01655136478">source their news from online platforms</a>. If your kid asks you a question about something they’ve seen on social media (or sounds as if it originated there), use this as an opportunity to fact-check those claims with them. Check sources like <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html">AP </a><a href="https://apnews.com/ap-fact-check">Fact</a><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/learning/teenagers-tell-us-about-their-relationship-with-news.html"> Check</a>, <a href="https://www.politifact.com/">Politifact</a>, and <a href="https://www.snopes.com/">Snopes</a> and show them where they can find trusted reporting. To <a href="https://newslit.org/educators/resources/is-it-legit/">determine a source’s credibility</a>, the News Literacy Project recommends quickly researching the source of your news, determining if the organization has ethical standards, and assessing the quality of the outlet’s other coverage. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“We don&#8217;t ever want to volunteer bloody details or gory information that kids don&#8217;t already know about.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If your teen doesn’t come to you directly with what they’ve been watching online, you might need to gently broach the conversation. In the case of viral disinformation campaigns, you can ask your child, “Did you see people talking about this on social media?” This way you can glean information about what your kid is seeing online and correct any inaccuracies.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Let them come to their own conclusions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">High schoolers will have more nuanced understandings about certain current events and policies and it’s appropriate to discuss these topics with them, Pahlke says. But rather than paint various candidates or points of view as “good” or “bad,” help them consider different perspectives. Explain why people with various experiences would have different opinions on a topic. It’s fine if they align with a particular candidate or policy, but they should also be able to see where the other side is coming from. Perspective-taking can help them in other relationships, too, Pahlke says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Teens may also have a clear understanding of their personal values and can reflect on how certain candidates or policies reflect these values and goals, Goldberg Mintz says. You can show your teen where to find <a href="https://newslit.org/educators/resources/is-it-legit/">credible information</a> from <a href="https://libguides.rutgers.edu/fake_news">trusted news sources</a> on specific candidates and policies and let them make up their minds. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Rather than trying to get in the weeds about ‘This is the candidate that our family can support, and it&#8217;s because XYZ’ is trying to define a kid&#8217;s beliefs for them,” Goldberg Mintz says. “We let our kids come to their own decisions.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[5 mysteries that might determine the 2024 election]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/381399/electorate-demographics-2024-election-women-republican-black-latino-voter" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381399</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T18:22:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T06:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 2024 election cycle has produced some stunning and sometimes counterintuitive narratives about how demographic subgroups might end up voting. We may just see a historic gulf in the way men and women vote — or not. Polls suggest we’re in for the greatest racial realignment since the Civil Rights Act was passed — or [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="People in a line in the back with a floor sign that reads early voting here" data-caption="Early voters line up at the polls in Stamford, Connecticut. | John Moore / Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="John Moore / Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2180058118.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Early voters line up at the polls in Stamford, Connecticut. | John Moore / Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The 2024 election cycle has produced some stunning and sometimes counterintuitive narratives about how demographic subgroups might end up voting. We may just see a historic gulf in the way men and women vote — or not. Polls suggest we’re in for the greatest racial realignment since the Civil Rights Act was passed — or it could be a mirage. Young people might sit out the election because they’re disillusioned and vote for a third party — or they could turn out in record numbers for Kamala Harris. The more diverse Sun Belt states might pave the way for a Donald Trump victory — but the predominantly older and whiter “Blue Wall” states might elect the first Black woman president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’ll know soon enough. Though Election Day is mere days away,<a href="https://election.lab.ufl.edu/early-vote/2024-early-voting/"> at least 60 million people have already voted</a>. Battleground states are hitting or exceeding their records for early voting. And with polls of likely voters still showing an evenly tied race, any combination of factors, events, or movements within the electorate could swing the outcome.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To that end, I’ve assembled a handful of questions we at Vox have been tracking for the last year. Their eventual answers could determine who wins the White House.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will there be late deciders? And what might change their minds?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The story of the closing weeks of the 2024 election has been a scramble for undecided voters, a shrinking number in poll after poll. That share includes two groups: voters who are undecided between either candidate and voters who might have a preference but are undecided about voting at all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t exactly know who these late deciders are, though. Could they be the same kind of working class and non-college educated (primarily white) voters who boosted Trump to victory in Rust Belt states in 2016 (thus scrambling the polls)? Or are they going to be the scores of new and young (primarily nonwhite) voters who could give Harris an edge in Sun Belt states?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And for all these subgroups — what kind of message or campaign development might get them to vote that hasn’t persuaded them already? Could Harris’s late-in-the-game revival of democracy and Trump’s authoritarian bend resonate with them? Is something like the racist and extreme rhetoric at <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378299/trump-military-threat-dancing-town-hall">Trump’s Madison Square Garden rally</a> a factor that could make up their minds? Or is something like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381150/biden-garbage-gaffe-republicans-trump-supporters">President Joe Biden’s “garbage” gaffe</a> this week something that could juice more Trump support?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless, these late-deciders will be pivotal. They’ve <a href="https://www.aei.org/op-eds/revenge-of-the-late-deciders/">broken for Trump</a> by massive margins in each of the last two elections he’s been a part of. But things might be different this third time.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will there be Republican crossover to Harris?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Along those lines, Harris’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/379686/trump-fascist-kamala-harris-campaigns-biden-democracy-familiar-closing-argument-campaign-2024">fate-of-democracy appeal</a> and juxtaposition of her “to-do” list against Trump’s “enemies” list are the clearest examples of how the Democrat’s campaign has zeroed in on Trump-skeptical Republicans as a key part of preventing a Trump win. But will these registered Republicans cross party lines, or simply repeat as reluctant Trump voters?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Somewhere between 15 and 20 percent of Republican primary voters <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/04/04/trump-uncommitted-protest-vote/">did not vote for Trump</a>, and even after she dropped out, large shares of these voters opted to vote for former South Carolina Gov. Nikki Haley. Many of them are women, which explains part of the focus <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/10/liz-cheney-kamala-harris-campaign/680367/">Harris has put on touting Republican endorsers</a> like former GOP Rep. Liz Cheney, her father and former vice president Dick Cheney, and scores of <a href="https://www.thebulwark.com/p/a-message-for-haley-voters-still">former Never-Trump Republican politicians</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Partisanship is one hell of a drug, however. Republicans, even if they dislike Trump personally, routinely stick with their party’s nominee. Harris keeps asking these Trump-wary Republicans to put “<a href="https://www.facebook.com/KamalaHarris/posts/country-over-party/1092139625605807/">country over party</a>.” But if they don’t and Harris’s argument about Trump’s threat to democracy is right, they may have to throw a “country <em>over</em>” party.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Arab American voters drift toward Republicans?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Gaza War, and Israel’s treatment of Palestinians, has been one of the defining issues of the last year, including in the electoral realm. Biden’s handling and response drove a significant amount of dissatisfaction from more progressive and left-leaning members of the Democratic coalition, and that antipathy seems to have stuck around, to a lesser degree, toward Harris. That includes a voting group influential in a pivotal swing state: Arab American voters in Michigan.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Polls specifically of Arab Americans suggest that these voters will not turn out for Harris to the same degree that they boosted Democratic candidates in the past: An Arab News-YouGov poll this week found <a href="https://www.arabnews.com/node/2576167/media">Trump leading Harris among Arab Americans</a> 45 to 43. That’s a stark reversal from 2020, when Biden led Trump by <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/the-arab-american-vote-2020">24 points</a>, and especially 2016, when Hillary Clinton led Trump by 34 points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this wasn’t always the case. <a href="https://unherd.com/newsroom/arab-americans-are-drifting-back-to-the-republicans/">Before 9/11, Arab American voters</a> leaned Republican. Only after the GOP’s <a href="https://researchblog.duke.edu/2024/10/07/emgage-educates-on-muslim-voter-dynamics-endorses-harris-for-2024/">anti-Muslim and anti-Arab</a> turn during the George W. Bush years did this voting segment swing toward Democrats, reaching a <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna6056602">high point in 2004</a>. And since that high point, these voters have been trending toward the GOP, with the share supporting John McCain, Mitt Romney, and Trump growing from 2008 to 2012 and into 2020 (support dipped slightly in 2016). The Gaza War may be accelerating a latent rightward shift that was already happening as the GOP changed its foreign policy priorities, championed conservative culture war issues, and talked up economic populism as Democrats became more culturally progressive, including on issues of gender and sexuality.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Trump’s gamble on younger Black men pay off?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For much of the last year, the Trump campaign has played up its targeted outreach to a specific segment of the electorate: <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373535/3-theories-gop-donald-trump-nonwhite-voters-hispanic-black-latino-asian">Black men</a>. With an avalanche of <a href="https://www.wsj.com/politics/elections/trump-allies-launch-20-million-effort-to-reach-young-men-e65aeb31">digital advertising aimed</a> at <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/10/us/politics/2024-election-gop-black-men-voters.html">younger Black men</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/375904/pennsylvania-kamala-harris-donald-trumplose-by-less-rural-black-suburb-voters">deployment</a> of surrogates and outside groups to reach young Black voters, the campaign has hoped to exploit two dynamics: Harris’s apparent weakness with Black men, and an overarching vulnerability Democrats have with younger Black Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Traditional polling suggests Harris has been facing a challenge in hitting the same margin of support that past Democratic candidates have enjoyed among Black voters, and specifically Black men. Both <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378521/democrats-black-men-support">social</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/23873568/biden-polling-black-latino-voters-2024-election-trump">economic</a> reasons explain this, including former <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/10/obama-harris-rally-pittsburgh/">President Barack Obama’s theory that a degree of misogyny</a> is keeping some Black men from supporting a Black woman.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there is also a larger Democratic weakness, based on surveys finding that younger Black voters specifically may have <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/04/09/age-generational-cohorts-and-party-identification/">weaker ties</a> to the party than <a href="https://x.com/jburnmurdoch/status/1767198806259470540">older cohorts</a> of Black voters, and may be <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/08/14/g-s1-16261/young-black-voters-generation-democrats-conservative-trump-harris-gen-z-millennials">more conservative</a> than their elders. And <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/23/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/genforward-poll-black-latino-voters-00185161">young Black men</a> appear more <a href="https://www.scholarsandstorytellers.com/2024election">likely</a> this year to support Trump, perhaps as a product of that weaker bond.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this is also among the cohort of voters least likely to vote and which, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/28/nx-s1-5169193/2024-election-kamala-harris-black-voters-donald-trump">some polling suggests</a>, is consolidating for Harris as they tune into the election. And with more outright racist remarks and prejudiced speech being deployed by Trump and his supporters in the final weeks of the campaign, it’s not clear that this investment will materialize large enough gains on Election Day to swing races in battleground states.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will Latino voters shift right in the states that matter?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether Latino voters are shifting toward the Republican Party since the start of the Trump years isn’t really contestable. Trump’s gains in 2020 stuck around for Republican candidates during the 2022 midterms, and polls suggest he will, at the very least, hang on to much of the support in a week. But because the election is decided by the Electoral College and not the popular vote, the more interesting question is whether those gains will stick around or grow in the states that matter.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, much of the political media was captivated by the massive inroads Trump made in South Florida and south Texas, places that had given Democrats an advantage in Latino support for years. But Trump’s Hispanic gains also happened across the country, in primarily immigrant communities, and in both Democratic and Republican strongholds that <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2024/10/trump-electoral-college-edge-shrinks-pennsylvania-wisconsin-polls.html">don’t necessarily impact</a> the results of the Electoral College map.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year, it appears that states that are already likely to <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/state-watch/4909335-florida-hispanic-trump-lead/">solidly</a><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/article/2024/aug/10/election-latino-voters-texas-trump"> back</a> Trump or <a href="https://www.latimes.com/politics/story/2024-10-10/california-voters-poll-harris-trump-presidential-race">Harris</a> might see their Latino populations continue shifting to the right (as is most obvious in Florida), even as Latino voters in <a href="https://whyy.org/articles/north-philadelphia-latino-voters-pennsylvania-elections-2024/">swing states</a> like <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/08/22/harris-trump-hispanic-voters-00175772">Arizona</a>, Nevada, and Pennsylvania, according to polling, buck that trend and move toward Democrats (or at least keep Democratic margins from 2020 intact).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That could result in Trump making larger national inroads among Latinos, but not enough in swing states to boost him in the presidential races that matter. It would make for more evidence of an ongoing racial realignment between parties, but one driven by Hispanic and Latino voters in California, New York, and Texas. That has real implications for control of Congress, but, unless the Latinos switching their party affiliations are in swing states, it won’t affect who wins the White House.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Abdallah Fayyad</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Punish Democrats or Stop Trump? Arab Americans are agonizing over their votes]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/policy/381550/arab-americans-protest-vote-harris-gaza-palestine-israel" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381550</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T21:59:10-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-01T06:30:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arab Americans are one voting bloc that’s used to being slighted by both major parties. In 1984, Walter Mondale, the Democratic candidate for president, returned donations made by Arab Americans; a campaign official at the time said it was the campaign’s policy to refuse contributions from that community. In 1988, Democratic candidate Michael Dukakis rejected [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A demonstrator holds an “Abandon Harris” sign outside the Israeli Consulate during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois. | &lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin&lt;/span&gt; / Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin&lt;/span&gt; / Bloomberg via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2166943399.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A demonstrator holds an “Abandon Harris” sign outside the Israeli Consulate during the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois. | &lt;span style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Emily Elconin&lt;/span&gt; / Bloomberg via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Arab Americans are one voting bloc that’s used to being slighted by both major parties. In 1984, Walter Mondale, the Democratic candidate for president, returned donations made by Arab Americans; a campaign official at the time <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1984/08/28/opinion/slighting-arab-americans.html">said it was the campaign’s policy</a> to refuse contributions from that community. In 1988, Democratic candidate Michael Dukakis <a href="https://www.csmonitor.com/2000/0404/p2s1.html">rejected an endorsement</a> by an Arab American group. And in 2016, Donald Trump campaigned on <a href="https://www.npr.org/2015/12/07/458836388/trump-calls-for-total-and-complete-shutdown-of-muslims-entering-u-s">banning Muslims</a> from the country and <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fact-checker/wp/2015/11/22/donald-trumps-outrageous-claim-that-thousands-of-new-jersey-muslims-celebrated-the-911-attacks/">claimed that Arabs</a> in New Jersey cheered as the World Trade Center collapsed on 9/11.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, Arab Americans feel deliberately ignored and disrespected yet again. The Biden administration’s unflinching political and financial support for Israel — despite the rising death tolls and humanitarian crisis that the war in Gaza has wrought — has roiled the community, and the general <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/10/27/biden-israel-palestine-muslim-americans-war/">lack of empathy</a> the administration has shown for Palestinians has left a bitter taste in people’s mouths.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When President Joe Biden dropped out and Vice President Kamala Harris became the party’s nominee, Democrats had a chance at a reset with a voting bloc that could very well tip the election. (Arab Americans make up <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/demographics">hundreds of thousands of voters</a> in key swing states.) But many feel the Harris campaign’s outreach to Arab Americans has been, to put it mildly, lackluster at best. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was like, ‘All right, you have a blank slate, let’s see what you’re going to do with that,’” said Rowan Imran, a Palestinian American who lives in Phoenix, Arizona. “That was very disappointing to see her dig her heels further in the ground and just uphold every single [Biden] policy … It was very clear that we’re just getting a different face with the same policies.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Harris rose to the top of the ticket, she had to find a delicate balance: distance herself enough from Biden to convince some voters that she wouldn&#8217;t be the same as him on Gaza while still representing the US government’s policies as the sitting vice president. It’s a balance she never quite struck. At times, she criticized Israel’s actions that <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn0lx2xgn55o">led to “far too many”</a> civilian deaths and acknowledged the human toll in Gaza, but she would always couple those kinds of remarks with justifications for the war. Recently, after being asked about the prospect of losing Arab and Muslim voters because of Israel’s conduct, Harris <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/harris-the-first-and-most-tragic-story-coming-out-of-gaza-is-oct-7-onslaught/">said</a>, “There are so many tragic stories coming from Gaza,” but that “the first and most tragic story is October 7.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The numbers reflect a dissatisfaction with Harris’s approach: A recent poll showed Harris <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/press-release-new-poll-arab-american-voters-evenly-divided-in-race-for-white-house-f989m">effectively tied</a> with Trump among Arab Americans, leaving her nearly 20 points behind Biden’s numbers in 2020. Another poll showed Trump <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/top-stories/latest/arab-american-muslim-voters-trump-harris-michigan-gaza-israel-rcna177647">with a slight lead</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump has been trying to take advantage of that. Earlier this week, for example, he <a href="https://x.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1851658527187550629" rel="nofollow">tweeted</a> that he would “stop the suffering and destruction in Lebanon,” referring to Israel’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/israel/373428/lebanon-hezbollah-israel-hamas-gaza">escalating attacks</a> in the region. He then directly appealed to Lebanese American voters by adding, “Your friends and family in Lebanon deserve to live in peace, prosperity, and harmony with their neighbors.” He also <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dcwpdPfQvJU">touted an endorsement</a> he received from Amer Ghalib, the mayor of Hamtramck, Michigan, a Muslim-majority city on the outskirts of Detroit.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given how close the election has been — with poll after poll showing a neck-and-neck race in swing states — it’s clear that Arab Americans, who make up a meaningful number of voters in must-win states like Michigan and Pennsylvania, can’t be taken for granted. And some liberals have been <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2024/10/revenge-voting-over-gaza-is-a-mistake/680446/">expressing frustration toward</a> Arab American voters who refuse to vote for Harris, saying that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/30/opinion/gaza-harris-trump.html">Trump is worse for them</a> because of policies like the Muslim ban. Harris echoed that frustration when she responded to pro-Palestinian protesters at <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2024/08/07/harris-to-protesters-if-you-want-donald-trump-to-win-then-say-that/74714086007/">a rally in August</a>, telling them, “You know what? If you want Donald Trump to win, then say that.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But many Arab Americans are well aware of who Trump is and do resent the prospect of another Trump presidency. What they feel is that they’ve been pushed between a rock and a hard place.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A difficult choice</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some have dismissed Arab Americans’ concerns and potential protest votes as irresponsible, but the reality is much more complicated. Israel has been <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/378913/israel-gaza-genocide-icj">credibly accused of genocide</a>, and if you’re a voter who genuinely believes that what’s happening in Gaza is a genocide, then the choice next week might not be so easy: On the one hand, your vote can be used to hold the Biden administration accountable. On the other hand, it can be used to stop Trump’s assault on American democracy. And if you choose the latter, does voting for Harris mean that you’re giving the Biden administration a pass for its handling of Gaza?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those are the kinds of questions haunting many liberal Arab Americans as they approach the voting booth. But democracy, the voters I spoke with argued, requires politicians to cater to the electorate, not the other way around.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Imran, a 35-year-old psychiatric nurse practitioner, had been a reliable Democratic voter. “I remember crying when Biden won and just feeling this sense of relief and, you know, someone that&#8217;s gonna reflect our values, be the voice of the people. And so that&#8217;s why a lot of this is so disappointing, because voting and supporting Kamala Harris, it should be a natural decision for me,” she said. “But because of the constant betrayal that we feel, the unconditional aid to Israel, the indifference to the lives of Palestinians, this has become the most complicated, impossible decision of my life.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Imran is now planning to vote third party. And part of the reason that it’s been a difficult decision for her is because she acknowledges the dangers of a second Trump presidency. “We do not support a Trump presidency. We understand the dangers, the harm,” she said. But “people again feel abandoned, they feel betrayed. We&#8217;re seeing our leaders prioritize foreign interests over the lives of people who look like us. And that&#8217;s not something we can overlook. You know, votes are not just a given, they need to be earned.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her view, it’s not her personal responsibility to stop Trump; it’s Harris’s and the Democrats’. And if Trump has another go at the presidency, then it’s only the Democrats to blame, not the voters who defected. Choosing to sit out or vote third party is a way to remind the major parties that they aren’t doing enough.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even those who might be voting for Harris have agonized over their decision, and some don’t even feel comfortable speaking about it because she was, after all, part of the administration that financed Israel’s war.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asma, a 50-year-old medical professional in North Carolina, has voted in every election since she was 18. (Asma asked that Vox use only her first name so she can speak more freely.) And though she usually votes early, this time she’s still holding out in the hopes that she hears some commitment from Harris that she’ll deviate from Biden’s Israel policy. “I’m just looking for validation. I’m looking for basically Harris to do anything, something to show that she has some compassion or some interest in the views that Muslims hold,” Asma told me.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Harris never seemed to deliver. “We just wonder, what would she lose by being a little more inclusive in her humanity or her compassion or her empathy toward the Palestinians or toward Muslims?” Asma said. “When asked about Gaza, she doesn’t always have to talk about the October 7 hostages. Yes, we understand how you feel about that — you’ve made that plain and clear. Maybe you need to say something about the Palestinians and their plight, exclusive of [the hostages’] situation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Asma said the election has divided many in her community, with many people judging others for how they’re voting, and some saying that a vote for Harris is essentially a vote for genocide. But a lot of people, Asma said, would still prefer voting for Harris over Trump because they believe Trump would make the situation in Gaza even worse. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, some voters feel a certain level of guilt holding them back. If Gaza isn’t their red line, then what would be?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s how Houston Brown, a 33-year-old Atlanta resident, is thinking of his vote. “The most inconceivable thing you can think of is genocide. It&#8217;s horrific,” Brown, whose mother is Palestinian, said. “And if there are no consequences for that, there will be no consequences for anything.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Brown was hopeful that Harris would distance herself from Biden on Gaza. And though he views her as more conservative than he’d prefer the Democratic candidate to be, he was still willing to vote for her, he said, because he doesn’t agree with any of Trump’s policies. “I would still vote for her regardless of that, regardless of my disagreements with her policies, if there was an arms embargo and a commitment to hold Israel accountable for what they&#8217;ve done,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris, of course, made no such commitment, and other moves by her campaign — such as <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/368411/dnc-palestinian-speaker-uncommitted-democratic-national-convention">refusing to give a speaking slot</a> to a Palestinian American at the Democratic National Convention —&nbsp;made Brown feel like the vice president was not taking Gaza seriously. Now, Brown is likely going to vote third party, and if that means Trump might be back in the White House, that’s a risk Brown accepts. “The repercussions are what they are, and we’ll cross that bridge when we get there,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I understand that it could be worse under Trump,” he added. “But 40,000 dead Palestinians isn’t any different than 40,000 dead Americans to me. And our policies have led to the murder of over 40,000 Palestinians.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Trump has tried to make appeals to disaffected Arab Americans, he’s also been saying he’d be even more supportive of Israel than Biden has been. Recently, <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/187332/trump-biden-tough-netanyahu">Trump said</a> that Benjamin Netanyahu was “doing a good job” and that Biden was, if anything, holding the Israeli prime minister back. Trump’s own record on Israel has also been bad for Palestinians. For example, he moved the Israeli embassy to Jerusalem — making the US <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/donald-trump/trump-recognizes-jerusalem-israel-s-capital-n827096">officially recognize</a> the city as Israel’s capital, despite the fact that East Jerusalem is still occupied Palestinian territory — and his State Department <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/11/18/politics/pompeo-west-bank-settlements-announcement/index.html">declared</a> that the United States would no longer deem settlements in the West Bank to be illegal under international law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But many voters who are sitting out or voting third party aren’t under the illusion that Trump is in any way a better alternative for Palestinians. For them, what’s happened in Gaza over the past year already constitutes the worst of outcomes: Israel has killed tens of thousands of innocent people, obliterated educational, religious, and health care infrastructure, created conditions for <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/369872/polio-gaza-who-vaccination-campaign-israel">preventable diseases to spread</a>, and targeted and killed journalists at an <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/10/25/1208019720/journalist-deaths-gaza-israel-hamas">unprecedented rate</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“In no way do I imagine Trump is better for Palestine,” Brown said. But “I can’t imagine it worse. I don’t think the Democrats are doing anything to stop it — they’re actively supporting it. So if there’s no real change for Palestine, why would I reward the people who are doing this now?”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Where the Harris campaign goes from here</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Arab Americans didn’t always lean toward Democrats. In 2000, Arab Americans <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2016/08/arab-american-muslim-vote-2016-trump-bush-dearborn-detroit-michigan-214134/">predominantly voted</a> for George W. Bush, and Republicans viewed them as a winnable demographic. But since the aftermath of 9/11 and the surveillance of Arabs and Muslims, the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, and Republicans’ xenophobic and Islamophobic overtures to white voters, Arabs have steadily moved toward Democrats. In 2020, Biden <a href="https://www.aaiusa.org/library/keystatespoll">won about 60 percent</a> of the Arab American vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats’ progress, however, seems to have all but evaporated. Now, there’s no question that there is a protest vote in the making among Arab Americans and others who, like Brown, feel like a vote for Harris is an endorsement of the status quo. Since the primaries, Democratic voters have organized around this issue, launching an “uncommitted” movement where hundreds of thousands of voters selected “uncommitted” instead of Biden during the Democratic primaries to register their discontent over his handling of Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question is whether the protest vote will be big enough to swing the election in Trump’s favor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a ‘punish’ sense, and you hear that a lot, right? ‘We&#8217;re, we&#8217;re going to punish the Dems. They don&#8217;t deserve to win after what they’ve done,’” said James Zogby, president of the Arab American Institute. “I think that&#8217;s a smaller number than one might be led to believe, but if it comes out to a tie as it is right now, those are a lot of votes Democrats will have left on the table … losing 60,000, 70,000 votes in Michigan — that&#8217;s a lot of votes to lose in the state that&#8217;s going to be close.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Recently, Harris did address Arab Americans specifically and spoke more candidly about the suffering in Gaza and Lebanon that’s happening as a result of Israel’s assaults.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know this year has been very difficult given the scale of death and destruction in Gaza, and given the civilian casualties and displacement in Lebanon. It is devastating,” she <a href="https://x.com/bintlabaratte/status/1847484011930853731?s=46">said</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At this point, it might seem too little too late for Harris to change people’s minds. And for many Arab Americans and other supporters of the Palestinian cause, actions speak louder than words. And the lack of willingness on the part of the Biden administration to use the levers at its disposal to restrain Israel now leaves voters with a choice: take a unique opportunity to show that there can be electoral consequences for an administration facilitating the kind of war Israel has waged on Palestinians or help end Trump’s political career. But they can’t have both — at least not at the ballot box.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[2024 election violence is already happening]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381520/2024-election-violence-trump-loses-extremism-civil-war" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381520</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T16:01:17-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T16:01:17-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Political violence has reached alarming levels in the US over the last few years.&#160; The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband, and multiple assassination attempts against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment.  Now, the 2024 election could [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A protester flying a Trump flag and an upside down American flag on the lawn far in front of the Capitol Building." data-caption="Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-1230734387.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-Trump protesters gather in front of the US Capitol Building on January 6, 2021, in Washington, DC. | &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;Segoe UI&quot;, Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, sans-serif;&quot;&gt;Brent Stirton/Getty Images&lt;/span&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Political violence has reached <a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigates/special-report/usa-politics-violence/">alarming levels </a>in the US over the last few years.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The January 6, 2021, insurrection at the US Capitol, the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/david-depape-nancy-pelosi-husband-paul-attacked-454cbde088fcae22a356f1f8dd0e9eba">attack on former Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s husband</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371981/trump-shooting-ryan-wesley-routh-golf-club">multiple assassination attempts</a> against former President Donald Trump are all examples of America’s increasingly polarized and perilous environment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, the 2024 election could cause another flare-up, especially if Trump loses. Discussion of violence among right-wing extremists has already <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">spiked online</a>, and unlike Vice President Kamala Harris, Trump has refused to say that he would concede.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The polls show a <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">tight race</a> between Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, suggesting that this time, as in 2020, the results may be decided by narrow margins in a few battleground states. Trump has been priming Republican voters to reject the results if he comes up short, making <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/10/29/politics/trump-voter-fraud-claims-pennsylvania/index.html">unsubstantiated claims about voter fraud in Pennsylvania</a> and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-noncitizen-voter-fraud-fact-check/">noncitizens voting on a widespread basis</a>. Billionaire Trump supporter Elon Musk has also set up a platform on his social media site X, formerly known as Twitter, for users to &#8220;<a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/31/nx-s1-5165523/voting-election-conspiracy-theories-social-media">share potential incidents of voter fraud or irregularities</a> you see while voting in the 2024 election.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those tactics seem to be working. If Trump loses, about a quarter of Republicans said they think he should do whatever it takes to ensure he becomes president anyway, according to a <a href="https://www.prri.org/research/one-leader-under-god-the-connection-between-authoritarianism-and-christian-nationalism-in-america/?preview=true">September PRRI poll</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That may include resorting to violence. Among Republicans who don’t believe Biden’s win in 2020 was legitimate, almost one-third said in an <a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2024/08/07/snf-agora-poll-july-2024/">August poll</a> by the SNF Agora Institute at Johns Hopkins University that they expected “a lot” or “a great deal” of political violence after the November election. More <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/10/30/voters-fear-violence-trump-loss/">recent polls</a> have found similar results, including an October <a href="https://apnorc.org/projects/many-voters-are-worried-about-the-electoral-process-and-transition-of-power/">AP-NORC poll</a> that found 27 percent of Republicans, and 42 percent of voters overall, “extremely” or “very” worried about post-election violence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this has put law enforcement and national security officials on high alert about political violence in the days before and after the election. Earlier this month, a joint Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and FBI intelligence <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/election-violence-domestic-extremists-fbi-dhs-bulletin/">bulletin</a> said that domestic extremists &#8220;pose a threat of violence to a range of targets directly and indirectly associated with elections through at least the presidential inauguration&#8221; on January 20.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What kind of political violence might break out?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some incidents of political violence have already been recorded in the runup to Election Day. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ballots in mailboxes and drop boxes in <a href="https://apnews.com/article/election-2020-marty-walsh-boston-elections-crime-3d9dd32292187df91d73cb153b9c0a73">Massachusetts,</a> <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballots-damaged-usps-mailbox-fire-phoenix-rcna177067">Arizona</a>, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/ballot-boxes-set-fire-portland-vancouver-rcna177611">Washington, and Oregon</a> have been damaged in suspected arson. DHS warned this might happen, based on its monitoring of comments made online in domestic violent extremist circles. In a series of <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">security bulletins</a> in the last few months, the agency noted, “Some threat actors may perceive ballot drop boxes as ‘soft targets’ because they are more accessible” and that some of these actors had discussed a variety of methods for damaging them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A man was also <a href="https://www.azcentral.com/story/news/local/tempe/2024/10/29/grand-jury-indicts-man-accused-of-shooting-at-democratic-party-office/75924391007/">indicted on terrorism and gun charges</a> for allegedly shooting at the Democratic National Committee’s offices in Phoenix on three occasions since September.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Things might only get worse from here. Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco has <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/u-s-news-decision-points/articles/2024-09-24/deputy-ag-u-s-faces-unprecedented-level-of-political-threats">warned</a> that the US is “facing an unprecedented level of, and increase in, threats of violence against public officials.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/national-security/4957125-domestic-violent-extremists-2024-election/">DHS bulletins</a>, there is a “heightened risk” that domestic violent extremists could “attempt to initiate civil war.” That kind of chatter has become increasingly common in online spaces <a href="https://globalextremism.org/post/online-chatter-election-contains-signs-for-violence/">frequented by right-wing extremist groups</a>. That said, the DHS noted that the prosecutions of those involved in the January 6 insurrection and hesitation about potential false flag operations designed to entrap them could serve as deterrents.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Law enforcement officials across the country are bracing for the possibility of escalation, particularly in Democratic population centers. For instance, Detroit’s election headquarters have reportedly been reinforced with bulletproof glass and will be protected by armed guards after Trump supporters tried to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/legal/michigan-still-counting-votes-angry-poll-watchers-barred-in-detroit-trump-sues-idUSKBN27K2AL/">interrupt ballot counting</a> by chanting “Stop the count” and banging on the windows in 2020. Philadelphia election staff will <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-swing-states-officials-brace-conspiracy-theories-violence-2024-10-30/?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;utm_medium=Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=Daily-Briefing&amp;utm_term=103024&amp;user_email=38572e447ae2b3a943d6423dd3d8ad89c2e154a588929a92468b7914f3f4e88f&amp;lctg=66464e6f30f1bc62c305003b">count ballots in a warehouse</a> encircled by a fence with barbed wire, miles from the downtown area where protesters gathered in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, however, these preparations might not be enough to quell domestic violent extremist activity when Republican leaders are encouraging skepticism about the integrity of the election and are reportedly <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/speaker-johnson-appears-to-confirm-a-secret-election-plan-with-trump">making secret plans</a> to assure a second Trump term. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Being aware of the potential for violence and damage to the institutions we rely upon is important,” retired Gen. Joseph Votel, an executive board member of the Center for Ethics and the Rule of Law at the University of Pennsylvania, said in a statement. “But it is insufficient in the face of legislative acts that are open to broad interpretation, strong political rhetoric that dominates the public information space, and imperfect individuals acting in accordance with their oaths.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dylan Scott</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Republicans are serious about cutting people’s health care]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/health-care/381484/2024-election-donald-trump-health-care-mike-johnson-obamacare" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381484</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T15:45:06-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T15:45:02-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re confused, it’s not an accident. Republicans are trying to have it both ways on health care during the 2024 campaign. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage. That two-step keeps getting them into [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Johnson stands behind and to the left of Trump as he speaks into a microphone." data-caption="House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2148449297.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>House Speaker Mike Johnson said Republicans would pursue “massive” health care reform if Donald Trump is elected president in 2024. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re confused, it’s not an accident.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans are trying to have it both ways on <a href="https://www.vox.com/health-care">health care</a> during the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">2024 campaign</a>. They boast that they want to deregulate insurance and massively cut government spending, yet they also claim that they would never do anything to endanger people’s coverage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That two-step keeps getting them into trouble. House Speaker Mike Johnson was recently <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/morning-joe/watch/house-speaker-mike-johnson-criticizes-obamacare-and-promises-massive-reform-if-trump-wins-223060037976">caught on a tape</a> promising to take “a blow torch to the regulatory state.” Donald Trump, Johnson said, would want to “go big” in his second term because he can’t run for a third one, the speaker told a group of Republican voters in Pennsylvania. And health care, Johnson said, would be “a big part” of the GOP’s agenda.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One attendee directly asked Johnson: No Obamacare? “No Obamacare,” Johnson said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The ACA is so deeply ingrained, we need massive reform to make this work. We’ve got a lot of ideas,” the House speaker added. He wasn’t more specific than that.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kamala Harris’s campaign quickly <a href="https://x.com/KamalaHQ/status/1851604970992263224">flagged</a> Johnson’s comments, and Republicans backtracked. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> campaign <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/trump-campaign-distances-house-speakers-plan-massive-reform/story?id=115313086">said</a> that was “not President Trump’s policy position” and Trump tried to distance himself further in a social media post.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Lyin’ Kamala is giving a News Conference now, saying that I want to end the Affordable Care Act. I never mentioned doing that, never even thought about such a thing. She also said I want to end Social Security. Likewise, never mentioned it, or thought of it. She is the one that…</p>&mdash; Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1852033066157441249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 31, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/no-promise-johnson-blasts-dem-accusations-he-vowed-end-obamacare-dishonest">insisted</a> he had not actually promised to repeal Obamacare by emphasizing his comment that the 2010 law was “ingrained” while ignoring his subsequent promise of “massive reform.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump himself has alluded to having only “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/opinion/trump-harris-concepts-obamacare.html">concepts of a plan</a>” for American health care. That has left other Republicans to fill in the gaps and the party’s specific proposals remain poorly defined. But if there are a lot of details still to be filled in, the theme of the GOP’s health care agenda is clear: cuts. Cutting regulations. Cutting spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson’s comments were not an isolated incident. Just last month, Trump’s vice presidential nominee, JD Vance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/372635/trump-health-care-plan-vance-preexisting-conditions">hinted</a> at “a deregulatory agenda so that people can pick a health care plan that fits them.” If you actually parse his words about health insurance risk pools, it would be a return to a world where people could be charged more for coverage if they have preexisting medical conditions, the world before Obamacare.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was the same promise Johnson was making. That is the reality: Should they win control of the White House and Congress this election, Republicans will attempt to cut people’s health care.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Republicans still want to make big health care cuts</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Obamacare repeal <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/7/31/16055960/why-obamacare-repeal-failed">died in 2017</a>, it might have been tempting to think that a chapter had come to a close. Instead, the fight over the future of US health care had entered a new era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Make no mistake: Republican leaders still want to slash health care spending and unwind health insurance regulations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And Trump, whatever he might say, has proven before to be malleable to conventional conservative health policy. His people continue to put health care in the crosshairs, sometimes in ways that may not be as obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Elon Musk, who sometimes appears to be campaigning to be <a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/politics/elon-musk-eyes-a-shadow-presidency/">shadow president</a> of the United States, has <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/10/29/elon-musk-2-trillion-budget-cuts-trump-election/">pledged</a> to cut $2 trillion from the federal government’s $6.8 trillion budget. He has <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/the-reidout/reidout-blog/elon-musk-trump-hardship-austerity-taxes-rcna177732">acknowledged</a> that the cuts would result in “temporary” hardship, but insisted they would be to the long-term benefit of the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.nationalpriorities.org/budget-basics/federal-budget-101/spending/">About $1 in every $5</a> in the federal budget goes to health care. Barring a severe cut to the US military (unlikely), such a plan would require massive cuts to the health care programs. Trump has often said he will protect Medicare, which covers seniors, but he has in the past endorsed enormous cuts to Medicaid, the program for low-income people that insures <a href="https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/medicaid-and-chip-monthly-enrollment/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">73 million Americans</a>, as part of the 2017 ACA repeal-and-replace bills.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The main Republican bill to repeal and replace the ACA that nearly passed in 2017 was in fact <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/9/15579654/medicaid-cuts-ahca">as much about making massive Medicaid cuts</a> by capping the program’s funding as it was about loosening health insurance regulations or repealing the individual mandate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans could try to pass another Obamacare repeal bill with a comprehensive Medicaid overhaul. Or they could chip away at health care in incremental ways, as we saw during the first Trump term after the Obamacare repeal bill failed. Trump <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/9/8/16268572/trump-obamacare-navigators">cut funding for enrollment outreach</a> for the ACA markets while <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/8/2/17639124/trump-obamacare-short-term-insurance-plans-36-months">rolling back rules</a> for noncomprehensive plans, which resulted in <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/6/30/21275498/trump-obamacare-repeal-short-term-health-care-insurance-scam">catastrophic results for some patients</a> who didn’t know what they were signing up for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over Trump’s four years in office, the number of people covered by the ACA <a href="https://www.kff.org/affordable-care-act/state-indicator/marketplace-enrollment/?activeTab=graph&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;startTimeframe=10&amp;selectedRows=%7B%22wrapups%22:%7B%22united-states%22:%7B%7D%7D%7D&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">fell</a> by more than 1 million, to 11.4 million. Since Joe Biden became president, and Democrats expanded the law’s insurance subsidies as part of the Inflation Reduction Act, the number of people covered by marketplace plans has nearly doubled to 21.4 million.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump takes office again, a repeat of that previous sabotage seems likely even if a bigger repeal effort fails to materialize. Republicans could cut outreach funding again. They could make subtler tweaks to the health insurance rules, such as increasing the premiums that older people can be charged compared to younger people or giving insurers more leniency in restricting benefits, networks, and other aspects of a person’s health coverage. They could make more targeted cuts to Medicaid or <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/5/12/23712447/medicaid-work-requirements-us-debt-ceiling">permit states to set up Medicaid work requirements again</a>, as they did in the first Trump term only to be <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/3/13/18263675/medicaid-work-requirements-lawsuit-donald-trump">obstructed by the courts</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Republicans can’t be honest about their health care plan</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The failure of Obamacare repeal is the reason Republicans keep insisting that their health care agenda is not what it plainly is whenever they accidentally reveal their intentions too clearly.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s easy to forget now, but Obamacare was a winning issue for Republicans at first. They <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/blogs/washington-whispers/2011/04/12/healthcare-vote-doomed-13-democrats-in-2010-elections">stormed to historic congressional wins in the 2010 midterms</a> by rallying voters against the new health care law. They then took <a href="https://time.com/4712725/ahca-house-repeal-votes-obamacare/">dozens of votes to repeal all or parts of it</a> while Barack Obama still held the veto pen. For most of its first decade, the ACA was deeply unpopular.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then Trump won the presidency and the Republicans had to deliver on their promises to repeal and replace the law. GOP leaders did get the new president on board with <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/3/15531494/american-health-care-act-explained">a pretty conservative plan</a>: It would have left the skeleton of the ACA, but pared back its rules and financial aid, while making those huge cuts to Medicaid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then something changed. As the repeal plan started to move through Congress, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2017/5/24/15685760/ahca-cbo-score-new">projections</a> of millions of Americans losing health insurance dominated news coverage, the politics of health care flipped. The law had quietly grown to cover a sizable chunk of people —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/issue-briefs/2016/may/americans-experiences-aca-marketplace-and-medicaid-coverage">more than 25 million</a> —&nbsp;and, as importantly, it had started to <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/4708/healthcare-system.aspx#:~:text=During%20most%20of%20the%20years,it%20shouldn't%20be).">change Americans’ minds about the government’s role in providing health care</a>. “Preexisting conditions” became a loaded term, and when people understood that the GOP wanted to unwind the ACA’s health insurance rules, they <a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/2017/5/3/15530008/health-care-preexisting-conditions-insurance">loudly objected</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Medicaid also flexed a political salience not seen before, with <a href="https://time.com/4831386/disability-advocate-protest-gop-health-care-bill/">disability advocates in particular</a> fearful of what cuts to that program would mean for them and drawing widespread coverage for their protests. Senate Republicans from states that expanded Medicaid through the health care law were ultimately responsible for stopping the repeal effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the 2018 midterms, Democrats were <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/11/7/18070152/midterm-elections-2018-results-trump-obamacare-repeal">hammering Republicans over health care</a> and scoring surprising electoral wins. Today, the ACA is <a href="https://www.kff.org/interactive/kff-health-tracking-poll-the-publics-views-on-the-aca/#?response=Favorable--Unfavorable&amp;aRange=twoYear">as popular as it’s ever been</a> and US voters say they <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/poll-finding/kff-health-tracking-poll-may-2024-voters-views-of-health-policy-issues-in-context-of-presidential-campaigns/">trust Democrats more on health care</a> than the GOP.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This series of events has left Republicans in a bind. The relative success of the ACA has expanded the welfare state and influenced Americans’ perceptions of the role of government in ways that are antithetical to conservative economic thinking. They want to claw back some of those progressive wins. But they also have to be mindful of the changed politics of health care.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once in a while, particularly in “safe” conservative spaces, they slip up, admit they want to unwind the ACA, and then have to backtrack. Mike Johnson’s only mistake was being candid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 3:45 pm ET:</strong> This story was originally published earlier on October 31 and has been updated to include Trump’s social media post about the ACA.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Andrew Prokop</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trump really could empower RFK Jr. to wreck public health]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/381470/trump-rfk-cabinet-hhs-vaccines-health" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381470</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T17:01:35-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T14:25:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the most part, Donald Trump has been mum on who he’d appoint to his administration if he wins. But he has made one pretty clear promise: Trump has said he’ll let conspiracy theorist and vaccine skeptic Robert F. Kennedy Jr. “go wild” on health, food, and drug regulation. That could have massive consequences for [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Trump stands and smiles onstage with his hand on Robert Kennedy’s shoulder." data-caption="Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2180628742_f78212.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, Donald Trump has been mum on who he’d appoint to his administration if he wins.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he has made one pretty clear promise: Trump has said he’ll let <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/07/13/1187272781/rfk-jr-kennedy-conspiracy-theories-social-media-presidential-campaign">conspiracy theorist</a> and <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/08/30/rfk-jr-trump-campaign-public-health-policy-issue/">vaccine skeptic</a> Robert F. Kennedy Jr. “<a href="https://www.politico.com/video/2024/10/28/trump-says-he-would-let-rfk-jr-go-wild-on-medicines-1466853">go wild</a>” on health, food, and drug regulation. That could have massive consequences for public health and vaccine policy in America. If Kennedy were to completely get his way and deter vaccination, vaccine-preventable diseases like <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-highlight/23438552/covid-vaccine-refusal-hesitancy-politics-polarization-pandemic-mandates">measles and polio could make a comeback</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kennedy, who ended his third-party presidential run to endorse Trump <a href="https://apnews.com/article/rfk-jr-trump-speech-arizona-a2638f89ddcb5de03edbe4574ca17d45">in August</a>, expects big things. He <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/10/30/2024-elections-live-coverage-updates-analysis/robert-f-kennedy-jr-trump-administration-00186227">told supporters</a> at a recent virtual event that Trump “promised” him “control of the public health agencies, which are HHS and its sub-agencies, CDC, FDA, NIH, and a few others,” as well as the Department of Agriculture. Kennedy has also <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">said</a> he’d be “deeply involved in helping to choose the people” heading those agencies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump transition co-chair Howard Lutnick <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/robert-f-kennedy-trump-transition-chair-vaccines-public-health.html">said Wednesday on CNN</a> that Kennedy is “not getting a job” at the Department of Health and Human Services, but Lutnick voiced complete sympathy with Kennedy’s beliefs that vaccines cause autism. “I spent two and a half hours this week with Bobby Kennedy Jr. and it was the most extraordinary thing,” Lutnick said, proceeding to say he believes in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/5/11/15508006/what-causes-autism-spectrum-disorder-vaccine-theory">debunked theory</a> that vaccines cause autism.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Trump has a <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter/366472/2024-election-donald-trump-vaccines-schools">muddled stance</a> on the Covid-19 vaccines his administration approved, he’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/9/17/9346685/republican-debate-trump-autism">long been a believer</a> that childhood vaccines cause autism. He reiterated that belief in a call seeking Kennedy’s endorsement this summer (which was recorded and posted publicly by Kennedy’s son): Trump complained that babies now get too many vaccines and then “change radically.” He added: “I’ve seen it too many times.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to make it clearer that Kennedy’s views would have deep sympathy at the top of Trump’s administration. In his first term, experts, scientists, and professionals remained in charge of such issues — hence the Covid vaccine development. But given the right-wing backlash against such experts that the pandemic brought, Trump’s second term could well be quite different. The risk that Kennedy would take a wrecking ball to public health regulation and especially vaccine policy is very real.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tucker Carlson, appearing at an event with Kennedy this week, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/23/health/video/the-lead-dr-paul-offit-trump-rfk-jr-vaccine-covid-government-medicine-regulations-jake-tapper">was positively gleeful</a> about that prospect. “Can you imagine if you’re at FDA or NIH and Bobby Kennedy all of a sudden” came in, Carlson said, breaking off in laughter. “I mean, they must be dying!”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">RFK probably couldn’t be confirmed by the Senate. He could exercise vast influence anyway.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Public health leaders, including some <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/10/18/rfk-jr-alarms-leaders-in-health-even-many-in-gop/">former GOP</a> and <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">Trump appointees</a>, have been quite alarmed at the prospect of giving Kennedy sway over public health policy. Jerome Adams, who was Trump’s surgeon general in his first term, <a href="https://x.com/SherylNYT/status/1850936124220514439?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1850936124220514439%7Ctwgr%5E7446672bcc944cad1d00fb27c5d865ea38ccea8d%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.motherjones.com%2Fpolitics%2F2024%2F10%2Ftrump-rfk-health-hhs-covid-vaccine-adams%2F">said Monday</a> this “could further erode people&#8217;s willingness to get up to date with recommended vaccines” and that he was “worried” about the impact on Americans’ health.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Others have reacted with skepticism to the prospect of Kennedy getting a top agency job, pointing out that a post like HHS secretary <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/10/30/2024/senate-republicans-could-block-trump-from-putting-rfk-jr-in-the-cabinet">requires Senate confirmation,</a> a prospect that would seem unlikely even if the GOP regains control of the chamber. Sens. Susan Collins (R-ME) and Lisa Murkowski (R-AK), the two most moderate Republican senators, serve on the committee that would consider that nomination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet there is a model for how Kennedy could serve in government and exercise vast influence despite not being Senate-confirmed. Call it the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/373479/stephen-miller-mass-deportation-camps-trump-agenda">Stephen Miller model</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Miller, an extreme anti-immigration ideologue, served as a White House senior adviser (a job that doesn’t require Senate confirmation). But he exercised vast influence at federal agencies that handled immigration policy so much that he was dubbed “<a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2018/08/29/stephen-miller-immigration-policy-white-house-trump-799199">the president of immigration</a>.” He <a href="https://www.politico.com/story/2019/08/02/stephen-miller-green-card-immigration-1630406">berated</a> agency officials to carry out his preferred policies and, when he felt some Trump appointees weren’t getting the job done, he <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/08/opinions/stephen-miller-immigration-white-house-purge-elliot-williams/index.html">engineered their ouster</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is entirely possible that Trump could appoint Kennedy to a similar role if he wanted one. It’s far from clear whether Kennedy would prove as effective a bureaucratic operator as Miller, but he certainly matches Miller in obsessive monomania over his particular issue, having argued <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/lifestyle/magazine/robert-kennedy-jrs-belief-in-autism-vaccine-connection-and-its-political-peril/2014/07/16/f21c01ee-f70b-11e3-a606-946fd632f9f1_story.html">for two decades</a> that vaccines cause autism, as a writer, an activist, and then as a political candidate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another reason Miller had such influence is that it was believed throughout the Trump administration that he was speaking for Trump, that they had a “mind-meld” on immigration. And Trump’s comments have long made it clear he agrees with Kennedy on childhood vaccinations. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if Kennedy does not officially join the government, he could still have a major impact on policy. If accurate, his claim that he’ll be “deeply involved” in Trump’s public health appointment decisions means he could choose like-minded allies to try and overhaul public health agencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The real question is whether Trump would stake political capital on what would surely be an intensely controversial overhaul of US vaccine policies. Despite his belief in the autism link, Trump simply didn’t choose to really do anything about it in his first term. If he were to win a second term, though, he would owe Kennedy for his support, and anti-vaccine sentiment has been rising on the right.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps the biggest mystery hanging over a potential Trump second term is just how out of control he has gotten since he left office. The Republican establishment would like to believe that, in practice, Trump will still heavily rely on them and appoint capable people rather than kooks to top posts. But perhaps Trump will feel less beholden to that establishment than ever and more willing to reward his extreme supporters. That’s certainly what Kennedy is betting on.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Google a bigger threat to democracy than Trump? A debate.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/380978/trump-google-democracy-big-tech-monopoly-lina-khan" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=380978</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T13:29:41-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T13:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Biden era has witnessed a revolution in the Democratic Party’s approach to policing large corporations. Under the leadership of chair Lina Khan, the Federal Trade Commission has grown markedly more aggressive in blocking mergers and cracking down on big business’s exploitative practices. This has earned Khan’s FTC plaudits from critics of corporate power. But [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A sign with the Google logo on it. " data-caption="Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/gettyimages-2180164057.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Signage at the the Google headquarters in Mountain View, California, on October 10, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden era has witnessed a revolution in the Democratic Party’s approach to policing large corporations. Under the leadership of chair Lina Khan, the Federal Trade Commission has grown markedly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-10-09/lina-khan-on-a-second-ftc-term-ai-price-gouging-data-privacy">more aggressive in blocking mergers</a> and <a href="https://www.economicliberties.us/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/FTC-Accomplishments.pdf">cracking down on big business’s exploitative practices</a>. This has earned Khan’s FTC <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/09/lina-khan-federal-trade-commission-antitrust-monopolies">plaudits</a> from critics of corporate power. But Khan’s policies have also attracted the indignation of the Democratic Party’s <a href="https://www.msnbc.com/opinion/msnbc-opinion/kamala-harris-linkedin-reid-hoffman-ftc-chair-lina-khan-rcna163897">supporters in Silicon Valley,</a> as well as concerns from <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/12/lina-khans-rough-year-running-the-federal-trade-commission.html">some longtime civil servants at the FTC</a>, who question the strategic and substantive wisdom of Khan’s approach to antitrust enforcement. Both these factions are now bitterly fighting for presidential nominee Kamala Harris’s favor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a cover story for Harper’s Magazine this month, Barry Lynn makes the case for the “<a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2024/10/the-antitrust-revolution-big-tech-barry-c-lynn/">antitrust revolution</a>.” Lynn is the intellectual godfather of the modern antimonopoly movement. Once a business reporter, he has spent the better part of two decades chronicling the evils of corporate concentration. His antimonopoly think tank, the <a href="https://www.openmarketsinstitute.org/">Open Markets Institute</a>, employed Khan as its legal director before she entered government.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In his Harper’s essay, Lynn frames the fight against Big Tech in apocalyptic terms. He argues that the power of Google and Amazon today is analogous to that of absolute monarchs in the 17th century — and that such corporate titans pose an even more pressing threat to American democracy than Donald Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I sympathize with many of Lynn’s concerns and think that Khan’s FTC has done a lot of good. But I also found parts of Lynn’s Harper’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/politics/379738/progressive-democrats-lina-khan-corporate-power-antimonopoly">piece hyperbolic and unconvincing</a>. So I spoke with him about my objections, the impact of Big Tech on journalism and publishing, the political power of small business, whether monopolies have made America more racist, and other topics. Our conversation has been edited for concision and clarity. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>In your Harper’s essay, you suggested t</strong><strong>hat Google, Facebook, Amazon, Microsoft, and Apple wield power analogous to that of absolute monarchs, and that together they constitute a greater threat to political liberty in the United States than Donald Trump.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there not a categorical difference between wielding a lot of influence over commerce and controlling a monopoly on the legitimate use of violence, as monarchs and, to an extent, presidents do? Google doesn’t have the power to selectively prosecute and imprison public officials it does not like. But an authoritarian president plausibly could. So why do you think Big Tech is ultimately the bigger threat?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think the clear point I was trying to make is that these are both really disturbing, terrifying concentrations of power. In the case of Trump, the White House, even after the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">recent decision in the Supreme Court,</a> there&#8217;s still an immense number of restraints on the presidency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What you&#8217;re talking about — we&#8217;re not there yet. And whatever Trump has said, it&#8217;s going to take him a few steps at least to get there. Whereas what we&#8217;re talking about right now with big tech is where we are now. This is not theoretical. This is the power they have <em>now</em>, so that&#8217;s a really key thing to keep in mind.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But would you agree that there are constraints on the power of these companies in the current context? I think even before the recent revival of aggressive enforcement at the FTC, the government </strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/24/apple-google-settle-antitrust-lawsuit-hiring-collusion"><strong>sussed out collusion in terms of hiring practices</strong></a><strong> among these big tech companies. So are there not limits that these companies need to operate within, just as the president currently does?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In that case, what you had is, some tens of thousands of employees who were being restricted in their ability to go from one company to another through no-poach agreements. Yes, they did win that case. But I think it was like a $5 million fine, and a little pretend slap on the wrist, don&#8217;t do it again. <em>[Editor’s note: The companies </em><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/tech-industry/apple-google-others-settle-anti-poaching-lawsuit-for-415-million/"><em>paid $415 million</em></a><em> to settle a civil suit over the no-poach agreements.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That was affecting the lives of a lot of people, and they got a little slap on the wrist. I don&#8217;t think that that case in itself had very much effect on their sense of the power of the government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When I&#8217;m talking about their power, it&#8217;s not just the power over their workers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I first got into this work, not through Google, but through Amazon. When I published my book, <em>Cornered</em>, it was 2010. And in the process of writing that book, I had really spent a lot of time talking to my editor, to my agent, and then, to other people who were writing books and to their editors. And I realized that American publishers with Amazon were facing a situation in which you had a company that controlled the gate to the marketplace — and was unconstrained by any traditional laws requiring them to keep the gate open equally for all comers. They had the ability to open and close the gate arbitrarily to the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were there any examples of them doing that in an egregious way that illustrates the danger of that kind of power?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh, yes. I spent a lot of time talking to CEOs and publishers back then, David Young at Hachette USA. I spoke to Drake McFeely at Norton. These are one-on-one meetings. And the basic thing was: When the door was open, they would say, “Amazon is our absolute best customer.” When the door was closed, they&#8217;d say “Amazon is a dictator that was entirely interfering in our business in arbitrary ways. We don&#8217;t have access to the marketplace. We don&#8217;t connect with the reader, the buyer, because Amazon&#8217;s determining how we&#8217;re connecting.” And that&#8217;s only gotten worse over the last 15 years. <em>[Editor’s note: </em><em>Young neither confirmed nor denied this account, saying he did not remember meeting Lynn, as it would have been more than 15 years ago. McFeely could not be reached for comment.]</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In February 2010, Amazon shut off the buy buttons for McMillan. McMillan was complaining <em>[that Amazon was devaluing its authors’ work by </em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2010/01/30/technology/30amazon.html"><em>charging only $9.99 for ebooks</em></a><em>]</em>. What Amazon did is they just said no more “buy” buttons. It&#8217;s like: You&#8217;re not selling on Amazon. Back then, Amazon was probably responsible for 40, 50 percent of their book sales in the United States. It&#8217;s now higher, much higher. But even if it&#8217;s only 40, 50 percent, you can&#8217;t stand to lose that much of your capacity for sales, so they gave up.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Were any of the conflicts between publishers and Amazon explicitly about the content of work, as opposed to terms of compensation for ebooks?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">About the content? There was some point at which, I think it was Tom Cotton or somebody who was on TV or Fox — a politician who was having a fit about how they&#8217;re being suppressed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But let&#8217;s just say there is no evidence of Amazon ever trying to suppress a particular viewpoint, right? But, there&#8217;s two things. One is, when you either suppress a particular publisher because they don&#8217;t have the money to pay you the extortionary rates of advertising, then you&#8217;re less likely to be found. You have less opportunity to make your way to the market. Two, when you promote one book, you suppress every other book in the marketplace.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s a two-way amplification of a book — amplification of a publisher — so that there&#8217;s de facto suppression of all the books, de facto suppression of all other publishers. You can have very large effects on what books are being published, how they&#8217;re being sold, what ideas people are connecting with. The effects can be a byproduct of a business model, a byproduct of unconscious decisions that were somewhat automated that have no political intent in and of themselves. But they have a political effect.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I imagine there’s an analogy there to your view of the role that algorithms on social media play, in terms of amplifying. Maybe it&#8217;s a completely neutral algorithm that is just amplifying whatever gets the most engagement. But that has implications for what content ultimately gets the most attention.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. But the thing is that as these middlemen — who are in between the people who are speaking and the people who are listening, in between the author and the readers, the author and the voter, in between the creator and the buyer, the seller and the buyer — as these masters in the middle gather more and more and more information about each individual person, and about each individual company, they use that information to manipulate both sides of the market.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More and more perfectly, they use it to push you as a reader: Oh, you liked a book about this battle in World War II. Well, you&#8217;re going to like another book about this battle in World War II, and you&#8217;re going to like this third book about this battle in World War II. And then, you know what, there’s this guy who&#8217;s used an analogy to that battle in World War II to talk about Trump politics, maybe you&#8217;ll like him too. So you can see how a couple of things happen when you have this kind of a system, which is that as they feed off their knowledge of you, they drag you more and more to what we used to call filter bubbles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I feel like there’s an argument that what you’re describing isn’t that different from organic processes of knowledge acquisition, which existed before the internet. Like, say you are a left wing-minded person, and you read a book by Tom Frank in the early 2000s or something. And that gets you interested in other books that he&#8217;s written, and authors that he cites, and you start subscribing to certain magazines, and that self-reinforcing kind of interest or ideology is a natural process that humans engage in when learning about the world, and developing interests, and that this isn&#8217;t necessarily such an insidious</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, absolutely. You&#8217;re absolutely right, and that&#8217;s a good thing. That&#8217;s how we educate ourselves. But, there&#8217;s a huge difference between when Tom Frank wrote <em>What&#8217;s the Matter With Kansas?</em> and then that leads you to a review of it in the Nation; I started reading the Nation. I had to take out a subscription to the Nation, maybe. I take out a subscription to Mother Jones. But maybe, I learned that there&#8217;s actually a left-wing bookstore in Chicago, and I go to that bookstore, and I find a whole bunch of other books. And so, then suddenly, it&#8217;s like I found a bunch of work, and a bunch of people that helped me answer the questions that I&#8217;ve been asking. And so, that&#8217;s fantastic, and I certainly live that life.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, when you have fewer and fewer, and fewer places that you&#8217;re interacting with, when you get down to one major place where you&#8217;re going to buy books online, when you get down to one major place or two major places — if you&#8217;re getting most of your news off of TikTok or you get it off of Facebook — you&#8217;re not going to read the New York Times, and that&#8217;s going to make it very hard for you to link out to the New York Times site. You&#8217;re getting most of your news off the platform.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At that point, exploration is not something you control. You have then actually lost your sovereignty. You&#8217;ve lost your ability to control your own destiny in this process, and you go where they take you. Now, you went to a really good college; you know how to protect yourself against some of this bullshit. But I bet that sometimes you find yourself getting suckered in on it. But a lot of folks don&#8217;t know how to protect themselves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To get to a separate claim in your Harper’s piece: You write that monopolists are a leading driver of &#8220;the surge in racism and homophobia&#8221; and &#8220;the attacks on reproductive choice&#8221; in the United States. I was wondering what you were thinking about specifically here. To me, it is not clear that there has even been a surge in racism and anti-gay bigotry in the United States; support for marriage for </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646202/sex-relations-marriage-supported.aspx#:~:text=Same%2DSex%20Marriage%20Support%20Near,recorded%20in%202022%20and%202023."><strong>same-sex</strong></a><strong> and </strong><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/354638/approval-interracial-marriage-new-high.aspx"><strong>interracial couples</strong></a><strong> remains near record highs in Gallup&#8217;s polling. And in any case, certainly America has grown more progressive on race and gender since 1981 — the year that you believe that antitrust policy changed for the worse.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what&#8217;s your timeline here? I mean, you gotta separate out the different things. Okay? It&#8217;s like, yeah, okay, in 1981, Reagan makes it easier for General Electric to roll up control over televisions, or he makes it easier for Walmart to roll up control over retail. So at that point, you&#8217;re not actually dealing with communications platforms. So there&#8217;s a revolutionary change in how we do competition policy, which is applied initially to industrial and retail firms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it didn&#8217;t happen all at once. Reagan starts the process. Clinton then extends it to banking, to the defense industrial base, to oil and gas, to telecommunications. And then what you have over time with telecommunications, you have a shift in business models, which takes place around 15 years ago — 10 to 15 years ago — from relatively unobtrusive forms of manipulation, to manipulation as the foundation of the business model. So to say that, well, between 1981 and 2011, racism and homophobia went down in the United States, and then even though it has increased radically in the years since, that my thesis is somehow wrong, I don&#8217;t follow.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I think it&#8217;s an open question to me whether they&#8217;ve increased radically since then versus becoming more visible because of the way these platforms amplify certain speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re taking parts of the thesis out and you&#8217;re saying, &#8220;Well, I&#8217;m not sure that it works.&#8221; So it&#8217;s like, if you take the thesis apart, then yeah, then maybe things start to fall apart. But the thesis is that the reason that these people have these abilities is because we fail to apply traditional anti-monopoly laws.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Yeah, I agree that that&#8217;s the overarching thesis.</strong><strong><br></strong><br>Yeah. Okay. So what&#8217;s the issue then?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>So I also wanted to touch on the claim about reproductive choice. I agree that large businesses are involved in </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/6/3/18632438/federalist-society-leonard-leo-brett-kavanaugh"><strong>the Federalist Society</strong></a><strong>, and the right’s project there is both to empower big business and to restrict abortion rights. At the same time, when I look at </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/google-inc/totals?id=D000022008"><strong>FEC filings</strong></a><strong>, the </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/apple-inc/totals?id=D000021754"><strong>large</strong></a><strong> tech </strong><a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/orgs/amazon-com/totals?id=D000023883"><strong>monopolists</strong></a><strong> of our age throughout the past 10 years have generally given a lot more money to the Democratic Party — the pro-choice party — then to the pro-life party. If their money determined these elections, then Dobbs wouldn&#8217;t have happened. And there&#8217;s lots of small businesses and regional businesses that fund the American right.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Eric, corporations are complicated things. They do a lot of different things at the same time. They curry favor on both sides. Look at Mr. Horowitz from Andreessen Horowitz, right? Two months ago, he was all in for Trump. Now it looks like his friend, Harris, may win. So suddenly, he&#8217;s like, &#8220;Oh, poor Harris.&#8221; Andreessen is still out there, totally 100% in. Crazy-ass Andreessen is still out there 100% in for Trump. Musk is leaping up and down like a maniac on the stage in Pennsylvania.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So really, you&#8217;re going to say because Google threw some money behind some Democrats — and even then, it&#8217;s like, was it Google or is it the individuals in the corporation? Corporations, they do with their money what makes sense for them politically.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Do you think that small- and regional-sized businesses are any different in that respect?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Small- and medium-sized business, they&#8217;re different because they&#8217;re less politically powerful.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But can&#8217;t small business interests pool together in the Chamber of Commerce, in various other systems to &#8230;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, of course, that&#8217;s their right. But it&#8217;s very different. A Chamber of Commerce is generally much less powerful as an organization than a large corporation. You got a whole bunch of different people who are working through an issue. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to agree on. There&#8217;s a lot of things they&#8217;re going to disagree on. So the things they disagree on, they tend not to take political positions. So it&#8217;s just a basic rule of democracy that dividing power is going to make it less likely that an actor is going to rise up and threaten the democratic system.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To play devil’s advocate, what do you make of the </strong><strong>idea that actually, small businesses — precisely because in this country, we have this deep-seated yeoman farmer ideal, and the small proprietor has cultural cache —&nbsp; that this actually gives them pretty significant power over politics.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god, you&#8217;re repeating to me ancient libertarian truisms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, but there are </strong><a href="https://genlawgroup.com/do-you-know-which-laws-dont-apply-to-small-businesses/#:~:text=Small%20businesses%20may%20be%20exempt,%2C%20national%20origin%2C%20and%20religion."><strong>lots of federal regulations</strong></a><strong> — labor regulations — that small businesses are exempt from while large businesses have to abide by them. And so there are these ways in which arguably, the government shows some degree of affection for small businesses that maybe is not extended to large corporations.</strong>&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I have no understanding of how you could actually come to that conclusion. I mean, it&#8217;s like the affection for small business is just some little crumbs that Congress tosses to the little people once every four years or once every two years. And almost any one of these, they&#8217;re recent. Go do your homework, go actually look at how the SBA operates. Look at how every one of these laws that&#8217;s designed for farming support, where that money goes to. Very little of it goes to the small actor. It&#8217;s just enough to shut them up. Other than, say, Vance and Hawley, and Warren and Klobuchar, who&#8217;s really making their business taking on big corporations? So where is this imaginary world in which the government is favoring small business over big business?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I guess I&#8217;m just referring specifically to both proposed legislation and actual laws that exempt companies with, say, less than 25 employees from this or that federal regulation. There seems to be a sensitivity</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Wait, wait, wait, listen. The point of this conversation is not to go in and re-litigate antiquated conversations that the libertarians put together in the 1970s. If you want to have this, you go read my book. You can read my first book, you can read my second book, you can read my third book. You can read all kinds of other work that&#8217;s out there. We don&#8217;t have to waste our time — while I&#8217;m driving down the highway — having these arguments. Go do some reading.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Well, I mean, I’m partially speaking for readers who haven&#8217;t necessarily done all that reading and would like to know what</strong>—</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No, no, this is your job. You can go read and you can explain it. Like I said, go read <em>Cornered</em>. Go read <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. Go read Sally Hubbard&#8217;s or Jasper T. Scott&#8217;s books. There&#8217;s a lot of books that get it just from different levels, different angles.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s all kinds of articles you can read up on. There&#8217;s been just a broad destruction of independent business across America over the last 40 years. If you want to learn some of the math, you can go get a copy of <em>Liberty From All Masters</em>. I do the math about Walmart.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Retail was designed in the old days to serve everybody. The business was regulated to ensure that any family with some wherewithal could get into it, go out and start a business, to start a grocery. And these weren&#8217;t little rinky-dink groceries. They&#8217;re family-owned supermarkets.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a long period of time, all of the great technological advances that were made in groceries were made by independent people trying to get ahead of their rival down the street. Now, if you are Walmart and your rival down the street is Walmart, and down the next town, the rival is Walmart, you don&#8217;t have to do a damn thing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Isn&#8217;t Walmart under competitive pressure from Amazon?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Oh my god. Yeah, of course, they&#8217;re under a little bit of competitive pressure from Amazon. And Google&#8217;s under a little bit of competitive pressure on certain lines of business from Apple. Right? But it doesn&#8217;t mean that this is an open and democratic system. It doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s a system that is designed to prevent fascism and the absolute concentration of power over. Again, Eric, you got to do your homework. If you wanted to have a conversation, you want to be the devil&#8217;s advocate, come at me with something that&#8217;s worthwhile.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. I will ask you a question that maybe you&#8217;ll like better. So, the other thing I wanted to ask about from your Harper&#8217;s piece: You discussed the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision in Moody versus NetChoice. A colleague of mine </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/2/26/24083652/supreme-court-netchoice-paxton-moody-texas-florida-first-amendment-social-media-facebook-youtube"><strong>wrote about it as well</strong></a><strong>. At issue in that case was whether the governments of Florida and Texas could prohibit social media platforms from taking down posts based on the viewpoint represented in the user&#8217;s expression or another person&#8217;s expression. Justice Elena Kagan argued that Texas’s proposed restrictions on content moderation would effectively compel Facebook to tolerate neo-Nazi and pro-teen suicide content on their platforms and this would constitute a violation of those firms’ rights of free speech.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You suggested that by making this ruling, the liberal justices mounted as “outriders for autocracy,” and you argued that giving social media platforms the right to moderate content at their own whim was as antithetical to democracy as giving the president criminal immunity from official acts. And so, what would you say to a liberal, like my colleague, Ian Millhiser, who believes that allowing major platforms to bar pro-anorexia and pro-genocide content is actually in the public interest, and that enabling right-wing state governments to dictate which points of view private companies must platform would itself put us on a slippery slope to authoritarianism?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you go read the decision, a corporation has First Amendment rights as a corporation. Publishers have First Amendment rights as publishers. The case that we are making and what many other people are making — and this can give you a misunderstanding — is that these are platforms, not publishers. Platforms are curators. And so platforms are places where people come together to communicate with each other, where publishers come to gather with readers to share information with each other. And if you allow the master in the middle, the middle man, to manipulate that, then you have grossly interfered with the rights of the 330 million people in America — I guess, some of them are babies, so they&#8217;re not necessarily using these platforms — but every American youth relies on these platforms to communicate with other Americans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I&#8217;d say that Kagan&#8217;s thinking is that she&#8217;s basically advocating for the suppression of the First Amendment rights of every citizen of the United States who relies on these platforms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the idea that Florida and Texas and Ohio are going to force these platforms to carry what the states want them to, no. It&#8217;s like there&#8217;s a missing part of this conversation, and it&#8217;s called the terms of service. All these people have a right to publish terms of service. And under terms of service, they can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to carry racist material.&#8221; We can say, “We&#8217;re not going to carry stuff that we believe is harmful to kids, that seems to promote eating disorders or suicide.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So then, once you publish your terms of service, you can say, &#8220;We&#8217;re not going to publish anything that seems to advocate violence.&#8221; And it&#8217;s like, as long as you apply the terms of service equally without favor to all of your users, then you can shut down whatever you want.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But is there any principle that binds what they can put into a terms of service? It seems to me that, by this logic, if the social media company establishes a politically biased term of service, then that could result in what you&#8217;re concerned about — and I&#8217;m concerned about as well — in terms of deplatforming legitimate points of view. So what legally binds a company from just crafting the terms of service so they can discriminate against whichever point of view they want to suppress?&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well, the thing is that at a certain point, the Essential Facilities Doctrine, traditional American communications doctrine, is once you get to a certain size, that would be discriminatory. Political discrimination is illegal.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I just want to clarify the principles here. It seems to me there&#8217;s no way to permit all political speech regardless of its perspective on social media platforms </strong><strong><em>and</em></strong><strong> prohibit racist speech from them (since there is a lot of racist, political speech). So I guess, how do you see resolving that? I took you as saying that basically: We should have a situation where you can express any viewpoint on these platforms — no matter how vile — if it isn&#8217;t direct harassment or a direct violent threat, but that the platform shouldn&#8217;t be amplifying that speech. Is that correct? Or what is your view?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People can go to the branded publications, right? If you wanted to hear a certain kind of speech — if your morning&#8217;s not going to be complete without a big plate of racism along with your eggs and your coffee — then you can have a racist publication. You can have a Nazi publication. And the people who need that, they can go sit on the website of the publication and get what they want. That&#8217;s the beauty of America, is that you don&#8217;t need the middleman to boost it. And you can still get it, you can still go find it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Great. Well, there are a few other questions I had, but you&#8217;re running close to time, right?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah. I appreciate you trying to be a devil&#8217;s advocate, but I just encourage you, as you&#8217;re working through this — because you&#8217;re smart, you&#8217;re clearly asking a lot of the right questions — is just continue to do your research. Don&#8217;t react. And whenever you&#8217;re starting to see stuff that is reacting against the kind of stuff that we&#8217;re doing, just question, “Who is paying for that?” Just question who it is. Because almost every single person who&#8217;s coming at us, someone is paying for that person to come at us.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Who came out looking the worst on Love Is Blind season 7]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/381017/love-is-blind-season-7-reunion-winners-losers-hannah-nick-ramses-leo" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381017</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T17:30:38-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T10:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Reality TV" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="TV" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another season of Love Is Blind has come and gone, and in its wake we were left with two marriages, five breakups, a villain who bullies, a gold-digging hero, and at least one secret father who never mentioned his children to his partner. Initially, season seven didn’t look like it was ever going to peak [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman holding a cup and a man face each other" data-caption="Hannah and Nick, one of Love Is Blind’s worst couples on season seven. Behold their absolute incompatibility. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E6_00_41_56_16R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Hannah and Nick, one of Love Is Blind’s worst couples on season seven. Behold their absolute incompatibility. | Courtesy of Netflix</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Another season of <em>Love Is Blind</em> has come and gone, and in its wake we were left with two marriages, five breakups, a villain who bullies, a gold-digging hero, and at least one secret father who never mentioned his children to his partner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Initially, season seven didn’t look like it was ever going to peak — a mini letdown since it was <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/375548/love-is-blind-dc-season-7-recap-review">shot in DC</a> and DC is notoriously one of the more annoying places to date. But it eventually ramped into one of the more memorable seasons of <em>Love Is Blind</em>. Mess, drama, dysfunction — this season had it all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This season&#8217;s slow build, the shenanigans that later ensued, and the attention and discourse it eventually generated bring up a question inherent to the existence of the show: What does it mean when we say <em>Love Is Blind</em> had a “good” season?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Contrary to the show’s mission, a good season doesn’t mean that couples found love, it means people found strangers to break up with. The more outrageous and awful the breakups, the more viewers watch and keep the show in conversations. <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/love-blind-tops-nielsen-streaming-193036816.html">Higher ratings for Netflix</a> are negatively correlated with marital bliss for anyone on the show. <em>Love Is Blind</em> has never really been about love being blind; it’s just a window for viewers to get a glimpse into some regrettable relationships. Now, in season seven, we’re getting pure chaos, the real, unfiltered stuff.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But while romantic success might not be on the table, it’s still possible to win the show, in a sense. And it’s certainly possible to lose. With that in mind, here’s who came out on top, who came out looking awful, who found love, and all those who didn’t on season seven of <em>Love Is Blind</em>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: For the 7th season running, the experiment to see if love is indeed blind</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since its inception, <em>Love Is Blind</em> has purported to be an “experiment” to see if true love is a real thing that can transcend the superficiality of physical attraction. Also since its inception, <em>Love Is Blind</em> has never really been about what it says it’s about. The show has <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23464762/love-is-blind-cole-zanab-season-3">always had an eye for mess</a>, and with each season, it has allowed more and more messiness to bloom.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E1_00_04_39_07R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="Women sitting on the Love Is Blind set listening to the two hosts standing on a platform in front of them." title="Women sitting on the Love Is Blind set listening to the two hosts standing on a platform in front of them." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="&lt;em&gt;Love Is Blind&lt;/em&gt; is not really about whether love is blind. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">In this seventh installment, several of the participants appear to have been chosen because of their potential for drama rather than their earnest desire to be loved. From men who claim to be insecure about having so much money, to women who talk about their relationships in corporate HR speak, to trophy wives and men who live in their parents’ basement, it seems as though the casting department went out of their way to find a group of people who would yield the most incompatible couples and messiest breakups possible. That’s fine — and it makes wonderful television — but we&#8217;re still rooting a little for the scientists.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: Netflix</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the season, there were two weddings. Both couples — Garrett and Taylor, Tyler and Ashley — got married. Going by the show’s body count of people getting rejected at the ceremony, that’s a successful end-of-season! No one was dumped in front of their family, and everyone seemed so happy at the end.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s unclear, however, is whether Ashley and Tyler will stay together. In the show, post-pods, Tyler finally told Ashley he donated his sperm to a same-sex couple. While the show was airing, <a href="https://pagesix.com/2024/10/20/entertainment/mother-of-love-is-blind-star-tyler-francis-3-kids-claims-they-had-unplanned-twins-naturally/">tabloids reported</a> that the relationship between Tyler, his children, and their mother was more involved than Tyler let on. In the reunion, which aired Wednesday on Netflix, the two said they were still together and that despite how it seemed on camera, Ashley was not blindsided but was aware of the situation. Ashley said she and Tyler were still together and would continue their marriage. &#8220;This is a once-in-a-lifetime kind of love, and it&#8217;s worth risking anything,&#8221; she said. &#8220;It&#8217;s worth it all.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the engine of the show is mess. Sure, there were two happy endings, but there were seven couples to begin with. That means five relationships went up in flames. That’s very good for Netflix! Here’s how they all ended:</p>

<ul>
<li>Stephen texted a random internet woman behind Monica’s back and tried to excuse it as being drunk at a sleep study</li>



<li>Ramses told Marissa he didn’t vibe with her energy after living with her for a couple of weeks</li>



<li>Hannah finally cut it off with Nick after berating him for weeks about being a child </li>



<li>Tim told Alex she was disrespectful to his parents because she was sleepy, even after he promised her dad, who has MS, that he would take care of his daughter</li>



<li>Brittany and Leo never even made it to Mexico!&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These love implosions are far more watchable than the happy endings, and they keep viewers interested in the show. Maybe they’re tuning in to see Hannah reckon with the person she was during the season or to figure out what really happened between Brittany and Leo, but everyone wants to know the gritty details of why things didn’t work out and what really happens to the show’s losers. And of course, that’s why Netflix has a reunion special (and has its participants <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@/video/7341121404177255723?_r=1&amp;_d=secCgYIASAHKAESPgo8JwJxy53D6YvZv5w%2FY3qnJ%2BxrfBI5jPF1eBBEMeP2hRHCA%2F%2BadLOOdWtxwkrBQhOR95qQf%2BmJnjCFUrpKGgA%3D&amp;u_code=dbffejkjeg2367&amp;share_item_id=7341121404177255723&amp;timestamp=1710108685&amp;utm_campaign=client_share&amp;utm_source=short_fallback&amp;share_app_id=1233">signed to contracts</a>).&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winners: Immature men</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear: Reality TV shows are heavily edited. There have been a few seasons of the show in which men (see: <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23464762/love-is-blind-cole-zanab-season-3">season five Cole</a>) are portrayed as innocent but good-hearted idiots and women as harsh shrews. Further, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/380186/toxic-men-love-is-blind-the-bachelorette">one of the long-running criticisms</a><em> </em>of <em>Love Is Blind </em>and other dating shows is that producers and editors are harsher on women than they are on men. Season seven, in all its turbulent glory, followed that pattern.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nick, Tim, and Stephen all were too immature to be in relationships. Whether it was the inability to talk about a problem, not telling your partner about <a href="https://www.today.com/popculture/tv/love-is-blind-season-7-tyler-francis-kids-rcna174614">the children you fathered</a>, or sending lewd texts to a random woman from the internet, the men this season were not a prize bunch. The bar for <em>Love Is Blind</em> men is subterranean<em>,</em> yet they managed to scoot under it.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E8_00_02_43_01R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A man and a woman hold up glass ornamentation made from pressed flowers." title="A man and a woman hold up glass ornamentation made from pressed flowers." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Stephen and Monica. Monica nagged Stephen for talking too much and not buying her flowers. Stephen responded by texting “kinky” things to a random woman and lying about being drunk at a sleep study. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there was also a lot of focus on how the women in their lives were extremely scoldy, if not bullies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hannah seemed to delight in being mean to Nick instead of dumping him. Alex, Tim’s partner, got into an off-camera fight with him in which she allegedly covered his mouth with her hand. Monica, Stephen’s partner, got mad at him for talking too much and brought up not buying her flowers (multiple times) that he had promised in the pod.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While only the two people in these relationships know the entire truth about the ups and downs of their courtship, it seemed as though the show spent more time portraying the women being harsher and more severe than the immature men they were with. A lot of that has to do with how easy it is to capture the women’s active confrontations and complaints on camera versus the passive, less-visible behavior from men — like being inattentive or lacking initiative. The takeaway is that it felt as though being an unserious goof was better than being an overly serious scold, with some of the men coming away from the show looking less culpable. Not Stephen or Tyler, though; those guys were still at fault.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Loser: Hannah</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Every season of <em>Love Is Blind </em>has a villain, and this series that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/LoveIsBlindNetflix/comments/1g7ixet/hannahs_comment_section_is_brutal/">title belongs to Hannah</a>. The 26-year-old quit her “dream” job as a medical device sales associate to be on the show, and it was worth it because she gave us a show. After rolling through the pods — where she strategically gave hints about how good-looking she was (e.g., telling men she was a cheerleader who dates athletes, that she didn’t want to be seen just as someone who was “hot,” etc.) — she paired up with Nick, a real estate agent and ex-football player. To be fair, he also embellished about his appearance (Nick claimed to look like a “less buff” Henry Cavill).&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Calling this coupling a disaster is an understatement and unfair to disasters. So why is Hannah the bad guy?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, Nick is an adult baby and shouldn’t be in a relationship. And at the reunion, a few cast members intimated that he told them off-camera he wasn’t attracted to Hannah — a crucial tidbit that may have changed the way he was portrayed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, watching Hannah scold him about everything, from 401(k)s to boiling water to phone bills, from ordering him to walk a dog that doesn’t belong to him to telling him that riding hotel pool furniture would give her the ick, was painful. After being icked one evening, Hannah leaves a cryptic, bulleted note of eight or so mantras for Nick to find, with each bullet representing one thing she hates about him. At one point, she tells him that she won’t address him as an equal because she doesn’t see him as an equal.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E4_00_52_33_19R_c3d471.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A smiling blonde woman." title="A smiling blonde woman." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="While the show tends to portray women as harsher partners than the men, Hannah seemed intent on bullying Nick at every opportunity. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">What Hannah was doing wasn’t like the one or two aforementioned instances in which some of the show’s women called out their partners for dropping the ball. It seemed like every segment that focused on the two featured Hannah haranguing Nick. Again, this could all be part of an edit, but Hannah sure gave them a lot of material.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The longer this season went on, the more I wondered why Hannah — who kept talking about how unhappy she was and reminding her partner that he was inadequate — didn’t call the whole thing off sooner.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The thing is, Nick has the opportunity to learn how to boil water and contribute 15 percent to his retirement. And it seems like he’d be able to learn that faster than Hannah could unlearn some of the unpleasant behavior she showed on TV.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winner: Brittany, the trophy wife</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On a show full of deceit (see: Tyler), it’s nice to know there are participants like Brittany who state, plainly and honestly, that they’re there for all the wrong reasons. When we first meet Brittany, we find out that she wants to be a trophy wife and that she has only dated high-profile, very successful wealthy men. Brittany does not care about finding love or meeting her soulmate. Brittany wants a man who will take care of her and let her live a life of leisure, shopping, and unlimited group fitness classes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Luckily for Brittany, she made a connection with Leo. Leo’s main storyline was that he felt insecure about inheriting tons and tons of money from his family’s art dealing business. In Brittany, he found someone who would listen to these concerns. He was so happy that someone would finally be supportive of the hardships in his life!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Granted, Brittany was probably trying to figure out just how rich Leo was, but she was very invested in each conversation. Even though the two eventually picked each other for marriage, producers said cameras would no longer be following the couple — a true loss for the show and viewers at home.&nbsp;</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Winners: That one argument Ramses and Marissa had over politics</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there was one moment of the show that felt genuine and important, it was the <a href="https://time.com/7071826/love-is-blind-season-7-marissa-ramses-military/">fight Marissa and Ramses had</a> over her military service. The gist: Ramses vocally condemned the actions of the American military, specifically in destabilizing less-powerful countries and inflicting violence on people living in said countries. Marissa served in the Navy and is proud of her service, even though she said there were moments that she regretted “pushing a button” (e.g., performing military acts that caused harm to civilians). He said he wouldn’t want his child to enlist, and she disagreed. She said she felt like he was judgmental of her military tenure, he said he empathized with her because she voiced her concerns about her participation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While Marissa and Ramses eventually moved forward with their relationship, the conflict seemed to simmer beneath the surface of all of their problems. Ramses, who said he didn’t vibe with Marissa’s energy after living with her for a couple of weeks, called off the relationship before the wedding.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/Love_Is_Blind_n_S7_E12_00_06_33_01R.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4383212962771,100,93.123357407446" alt="A man sits with his hand to his chin, speaking to a woman we see in profile." title="A man sits with his hand to his chin, speaking to a woman we see in profile." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Ramses did not like Marissa’s military service — a very real deal-breaker for many real-life couples. But Ramses also was very unserious when it came to other parts of their relationship. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Though they didn’t end up together, Marissa and Ramses thoughtfully articulated the politics of a serious and complicated topic.&nbsp;Their disagreement is the type of stuff <em>Love Is Blind </em>says it wants to be about — being able to fall in love or not with a person based on who they are, what they believe in, and shared values. And sometimes, just like in real life, there are some deal-breakers that you just can’t get past, no matter how much you love a person.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, October 31, 10 am ET: </strong>This article, originally published on October 30, has been updated with revelations from the </em>Love Is Blind<em> reunion.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Anna North</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Halloween less scary than it used to be?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/life/380705/halloween-scary-stories-kids-spooky" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=380705</id>
			<updated>2024-10-30T17:27:51-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T07:45:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Family" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story originally appeared in&#160;Kids Today, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&#160;Sign up here for future editions. I remember the first time I encountered Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark. It was second grade, and another kid had smuggled a copy of the Alvin Schwartz horror collection out to the playground during recess. We [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A person in a sheet, carrying a book, walking down a dark street lit with Halloween decorations." data-caption="A child wearing a costume goes trick or treating. | Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-1438023413_badcfe.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A child wearing a costume goes trick or treating. | Robert Nickelsberg/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/family/369020/kids-children-generation-alpha-gen-school" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Kids Today</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s newsletter about kids, for everyone.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/kids-today-newsletter-policy-childhood-policy-culture" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I remember the first time I encountered <em>Scary Stories to Tell in the Dark</em>. It was second grade, and another kid had smuggled a copy of the Alvin Schwartz horror collection out to the playground during recess. We gathered around, repulsed yet compelled by the ghoulish illustrations, unaware that what we read next would form the script of our nightmares for the next 30 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Scary Stories</em>, first released in 1981 but still ubiquitous at sleepovers and back-of-the-bus scare sessions throughout the ’90s, is famous among millennials for inducing utter terror.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The one that haunts me to this day is “<a href="https://scary-stories.fandom.com/wiki/The_Dead_Hand">The Dead Hand</a>,” about a devil-may-care young lad who goes walking in a swamp at night, only to be attacked by a disembodied arm that yanks the boy’s own hand off, leaving nothing but a bloody stump. The story, with its <a href="https://scary-stories.fandom.com/wiki/The_Dead_Hand?file=The_dead_hand.jpg">accompanying illustration</a> of a howling, gap-toothed corpse head rising from a bog, kept me awake for at least a week. I still remember huddling in my bed with eyes peeled, absolutely certain that an oozing hand was about to float through my bedroom door.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Halloween approached this year, I started wondering if <em>Scary Stories</em> was still popular, or if my children would have their own equivalent — a horror tale so powerful it could leave a mark on a generation’s subconscious. So I reached out to booksellers, librarians, and my older kid’s favorite horror author to find out what’s scaring kids these days and what role, if any, spooky stories play in their lives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I thought the children of Gen Alpha, obsessed with the frenetic doomsday fantasy <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/369953/skibidi-tweens-gen-alpha-brainrot-ipad-kids">Skibidi Toilet</a>, might be too jaded to be scared. In fact, experts told me the opposite — that popular titles today, like <a href="https://www.bookfair.org/series/s-michael-dahls-really-scary-stories/"><em>Michael Dahl’s Really Scary Stories</em></a> or the <a href="https://freddy-fazbears-pizza.fandom.com/wiki/Five_Nights_at_Freddy%27s_(Novel_Trilogy)"><em>Five Nights at Freddy’s</em> series</a> — are a little tamer than the ones I read as a kid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We had serious, gripping fear that kept you up at night,” Jean Darnell, the director of library science for the Philadelphia School District and a lifelong horror reader, told me. “The psychological fear was a little bit more in-depth.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s something to be said for a lighter touch in children’s horror. As much as I now consider <em>Scary Stories</em> part of my education as a writer and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/31/opinion/a-ghost-story-for-the-golden-state.html">horror fan</a>, I don’t actually want my kids to lie awake night after night, terrified of being attacked by a disembodied limb.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the differences between my kids’ horror landscape and my own have me thinking about what kids really get out of scary stories, and the value of such tales in a legitimately scary world.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The taming of scary stories&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I didn’t know it at the time, but I came of age during a <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">children’s horror boom</a>. <em>Scary Stories</em>, which eventually grew to&nbsp;three volumes, kicked off the trend, with authors Christopher Pike and R.L. Stine soon following suit, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">according to Mental Floss</a>. The latter wrote the iconic Goosebumps series, which, with its accompanying mid-’90s TV series, still looms large in the imagination of many millennials.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While some were silly or <a href="https://goosebumps.fandom.com/wiki/The_Horror_at_Camp_Jellyjam">bizarre</a>, many were legitimately terrifying. The one that sticks in my mind is <a href="https://goosebumps.fandom.com/wiki/Welcome_to_Camp_Nightmare"><em>Welcome to Camp Nightmare</em></a>, in which a boy arrives at sleepaway camp only to be menaced and gaslit by weird counselors and ultimately pressured to hunt his fellow campers with a tranquilizer gun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though wildly popular, the Goosebumps books became a victim of their own success, with a <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/childrens-literature-horror-boom-1990s">saturated market and declining sales</a>. By the 2000s, horror had taken a back seat to fantasy, most notably the Harry Potter series.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But like a zombie, the genre has risen from the grave in recent years, even as <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/childrens/childrens-book-news/article/93142-buzzy-middle-grade-genres-fall-2023.html">book sales for elementary- and middle-schoolers struggle</a> overall. Anna Hersh, co-owner of Wild Rumpus Bookstore, a children’s bookshop in Minneapolis, told me that horror books are selling well, enough to keep the store’s dedicated “Spooky Shed” stocked year-round.&nbsp;Popular titles include <a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/tales-from-cabin-23-the-boo-hag-flex-justina-ireland?variant=41096253177890"><em>Tales From Cabin 23</em></a>, an anthology series with each installment written by a different bestselling author, and <a href="https://mattmcmann.com/all-books/"><em>Monsterious</em></a><em>, </em>whose monster-of-the-week vibe makes it the most obvious contemporary successor to Goosebumps, Hersh said. These are aimed at 8- to 12-year-olds, but younger readers enjoy the <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/series/Creepy-Tales!">Creepy Tales picture books</a>, about everyday objects and foodstuffs (underwear, carrots) that come alive and stalk Jasper, an unsuspecting rabbit.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Also popular, according to Hersh, is <a href="https://www.flaviazdrago.com/gustavo-the-shy-ghost"><em>Gustavo the Shy Ghost</em></a>, a 2020 bestseller (and a favorite in my house) about a sweet ghost who struggles to connect with his fellow paranormal beings. <em>Gustavo</em> and <a href="https://www.flaviazdrago.com/books">its sequels</a> are more heartwarming than scary, but they take place in a world in which werewolves, calavera-style skeletons, and invisible girls with floating eyeglasses are simply the norm.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for the classics of my youth, Wild Rumpus still stocks some Goosebumps titles, but they’re mostly <a href="https://kids.scholastic.com/content/kids64/en/books/goosebumps/series/goosebumps-graphix.html">graphic novel adaptations</a> released in the 2010s. Some of the original Goosebumps plots feel dated today —&nbsp;Gen Alpha readers might wonder why some of the terrified protagonists didn’t just “use their cellphone and call their mom,” Hersh said. Today’s spooky stories are more likely to include heroes doing online research into the monsters and ghouls plaguing them, or they take place in fantasy worlds where such technology doesn’t exist, Hersh said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scary stories are also just less scary than they were in the ’80s and ’90s, said Darnell, the library science director, who added that the horror simply “feels watered down.” Grown-ups are more concerned about age-appropriate subject matter than they once were, and school organizations and psychologists would be up in arms if kids’ authors today delved too deep into psychological horror, Darnell said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Young readers today are also “sort of more conservative in many ways” than kids in decades past, said Max Brallier, author (under the pen name Jack Chabert) of the <a href="https://www.scholastic.com/site/branches/eerie-elementary.html">Eerie Elementary books</a> and several other spooky series. While ’90s kids were drawn in by the frightening <em>Scary Stories</em> covers, today’s young people might be more put off. In fact, a 2011 re-release of the books featured <a href="https://darkartandcraft.com/blogs/news/stephen-gammell-illustrations">much less disturbing art</a> (although fan backlash eventually led to a restoration of the original images).</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What spooky tales do for kids</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s nothing wrong with a little concern over children’s mental health and ability to sleep at night. After all, there’s always been a fine line between a fun scare and a traumatic memory. After Brallier saw <em>Jaws</em> as a child, he recalls, “The ocean and the lake and the swimming pool were ruined for me for, like, 15 years.” And as an author, he said, “You don&#8217;t want to really screw someone up.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some adult efforts to scare children do just feel sadistic in retrospect. I had a neighbor growing up who used to answer the door on Halloween wearing a very scary werewolf mask with glowing red eyes. I do not remember this with any fondness, and I think it’s fine that such costumes for adults seem less common during trick-or-treating today.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/brooding-halloween-scary-for-kids.html">Kathryn Jezer-Morton of the Cut</a> recalls a complex parental stunt from her youth, complete with a cemetery, a chainsaw, and a disembodied voice coming from beneath fallen leaves. “It was an <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/haunted-bars-nyc-fraunces-tavern-financial-district-ghosts.html">ecstatic moment of terror</a> alongside the delicious relief of safety,” Jezer-Morton writes, and she worries that kids today are missing “the feeling of a thinning veil between worlds that is hard to describe in words but vividly conjured in memories.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Darnell, meanwhile, scary stories are about learning to live in this world, with all its horrors. “When I&#8217;m reading a scary story, I&#8217;m looking at how that main character strategizes,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fear “forces you to problem-solve with the resources around you,” Darnell said. “I think that&#8217;s a skill that kids need.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t want my kids to be psychologically scarred by the books they read — after all, the realities of a <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/375996/extreme-heat-october-climate-change">warming planet</a> and widespread <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/12/15/23990986/trump-2024-democracy-consolidated-culture-campaign">democratic backsliding</a> are scary enough. What I want them to get from scary stories is a sense of a universe charged with mystery, the unknown always sneaking up behind us, its cold breath raising goosebumps on the backs of our necks.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or maybe that’s just what I got from scary stories. Today’s young readers will have their own relationships to horror and their own ways of seeking out what they want to feel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even in this post-Goosebumps era, Hersh says she still encounters readers who love to be scared. “It&#8217;ll be this kid who comes in who&#8217;s just like, in the cutest little outfit, and so well-mannered, and is like, ‘What is your scariest book?’” she said. “Some people just kind of have it in them.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What I’m reading</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Olympian Allyson Felix is partnering with the nonprofit Chamber of Mothers to <a href="https://19thnews.org/2024/10/child-care-while-you-vote/">cover the cost of child care</a> while parents vote (the program is available in North Carolina, New York, and Los Angeles).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One Las Vegas high school made the decision to <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/education/2024/10/28/teachers-swing-states-young-voters-election/75781988007/">give students the day off</a> on Election Day — and many will be volunteering at the polls.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Do kids need “<a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/boo-baskets-for-kids-trend-for-parents-couples.html">boo baskets?</a>” Probably <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/mom-not-doing-boo-baskets-halloween-2024-10">no</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">My older kid and I are reading <em><a href="https://flyingeyebooks.com/book/season-of-the-witch-a-spellbinding-history-of-witches-and-other-magical-folk/">Season of the Witch: A Spellbinding History of Witches and Other Magical Folk</a></em>, a library find. It is not scary, but it does include a lot of cool spells.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">From my inbox</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, I asked for your experiences with <a href="https://www.vox.com/life/379082/school-tracking-apps-grades-google-classroom-classdojo">apps that track kids’ grades</a> and assignments in school. “My sons all struggled with keeping track of assignments and turning them in,” one reader wrote. “For us, the ability to see which assignments had 0’s has been the major benefit of the grade-tracking apps. I check their grades daily and can tell them when they need to check their own grades. Then they can figure out how to rectify the omissions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For kids with better <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/articles/executive-function">executive functioning</a> issues, this might be a non-issue,” she wrote. “But my very bright kids would probably have ended up with a lot of failing grades if we weren’t checking the apps!”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Next Tuesday, as you, um, <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/379814/election-anxiety-stress-coping-strategies-control-community" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/even-better/379814/election-anxiety-stress-coping-strategies-control-community">may be aware</a>, is <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections">Election Day</a> in the US. Have you ever taken the kids in your life to vote with you? If so, what did they think of the experience? Also, if you’re a young person voting for the first time this year, please write in and tell me how it felt! You can get in touch at anna.north@vox.com.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Should you feel guilty about using AI?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/381158/should-you-feel-guilty-about-using-ai" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=381158</id>
			<updated>2024-10-31T10:56:45-04:00</updated>
			<published>2024-10-31T07:00:00-04:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Emerging Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls Apple Intelligence this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users who opt in. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/GettyImages-2172386617.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The Apple Store in New York City glows like the new Siri, powered by Apple Intelligence, ahead of the iPhone 16 launch in September. | Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple just put AI in millions of people’s pockets. The company is rolling out what it calls <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2024/10/apple-intelligence-is-available-today-on-iphone-ipad-and-mac/">Apple Intelligence</a> this week, bringing some basic text generation and image editing features to iPhone, iPad, and Mac users <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/121115#:~:text=To%20get%20started%20with%20Apple,though%20wait%20times%20can%20vary.">who opt in</a>. I’ve been testing these tools through the developer beta version of the software for a couple months now, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/370836/apple-intelligence-iphone-16-ios-update-siri">they’re pretty mediocre</a>. But this is only the beginning.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Generative AI, once a parlor trick for the tech-obsessed, is fast becoming the main event for major software releases. As Apple pushes its version of the technology, Google <a href="https://blog.google/products/android/google-ai-android-update-io-2024/">is building AI into its Android operating system</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/357247/why-are-ai-search-engines-so-bad">forcing everyone to look at AI Overviews</a> at the top of virtually every Google Search. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/25/24205701/openai-searchgpt-ai-search-engine-google-perplexity-rival">OpenAI</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/28/24282017/meta-ai-powered-search-engine-report">Meta</a> are building their own AI-powered search engines, while the startup <a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/">Perplexity</a> already has one. <a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2024/10/21/new-autonomous-agents-scale-your-team-like-never-before/">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/22/anthropic-announces-ai-agents-for-complex-tasks-racing-openai.html">Anthropic</a> recently announced new, super-powerful AI agents that can complete complex tasks much like humans would. (Disclosure: Vox Media is one of several publishers that has signed partnership agreements with OpenAI. Our reporting remains editorially independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While some companies have had generative AI products out in the wild for over a year, the arrival of Apple Intelligence marks an inflection point for the mainstreaming of the technology. Apple Intelligence is only available on the latest Apple devices, but over half the phones in the United States <a href="https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/dont-blame-apple-for-the-us-smartphone-market-blame-the-us-carriers">are iPhones</a>. As people upgrade, millions more can tap into the new technology.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re not already using AI, you probably will be soon — whether you like it or not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re getting AI, especially generative AI, shoved down our throats with little to no transparency, and honestly, the opt-out mechanisms are either nonexistent or complicated,” said Sasha Luccioni, AI researcher and climate lead at Hugging Face, a platform for sharing AI and machine learning tools.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If that fills you with dread, it’s understandable. Maybe you feel bad participating in the race <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/9/19/23879648/americans-artificial-general-intelligence-ai-policy-poll">to build a superintelligent AI</a> nobody asked for. You may feel complicit for using <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/23/technology/openai-copyright-law.html">AI models trained on copyrighted material</a> without paying the creators. You probably feel just plain bad about the flood of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/378855/ai-slop-fall-autumn-inspiration-vibes-pinterest">AI slop that’s ruining the internet</a> even if you did not personally create the slop. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the climate consequences of it all. AI, in its many shapes and forms, requires a lot of <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2024/3/28/24111721/climate-ai-tech-energy-demand-rising">energy and water to work</a>. A <em>lot</em>. That might make you feel downright guilty about using AI.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI’s big energy appetite</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a chance Apple Intelligence is more guilt-free than the other big AI options as far as energy is concerned. Apple says it keeps the processing for certain AI features, like GenMoji and Image Playground, entirely on your device. That means less reliance on energy-intensive data centers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t know exactly how much energy AI uses at these data centers. Using data from a recent Microsoft Research study, Shaolei Ren, an engineering professor at the University of California Riverside, came up with this: Asking ChatGPT to write two 200-word emails uses roughly the same amount of energy as a Tesla Model 3 would need to drive one mile. Because they generate so much heat, the processors that generated those emails would also require <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/09/18/energy-ai-use-electricity-water-data-centers/">about four half-liter bottles of water</a> to cool down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The consequences of such energy profligacy become clearer if you scale up. The amount of electricity used by data centers, where AI processing largely takes place, is <a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/AI-poised-to-drive-160-increase-in-power-demand">predicted to grow by 160 percent</a> by the end of the decade, and carbon dioxide emissions could more than double as a result, according to Goldman Sachs. Meanwhile, the amount of water needed will also spike, so much so that by 2027, AI’s thirst <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.03271">could be equal to half the annual water withdrawal of the United Kingdom</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are all estimates based on limited data because the tech companies building AI systems, including Apple, Google, Microsoft, and OpenAI, do not share exactly how much energy or water their models use.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We&#8217;re just looking at the black box because we have absolutely no idea of the energy consumption for interacting with the large language models,” Ren said. He compared the situation to searching for flights on Google and being able <a href="https://support.google.com/travel/answer/9671620?hl=en">to see the carbon emissions for each leg</a>. “But when it comes to these large language models, there&#8217;s absolutely none, zero, no information.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lack of transparency about AI’s energy demands also runs counter to these tech companies’ sustainability promises. There’s good reason to believe that AI is <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">leading directly to those promises being broken</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Due to increases in data center energy usage, Google saw its greenhouse gas emissions <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-02/google-s-emissions-shot-up-48-over-five-years-due-to-ai?sref=qYiz2hd0">increase by 48 percent</a> from 2019 to 2023, despite a pledge to cut emissions by 50 percent from its 2019 levels <a href="https://sustainability.google/operating-sustainably/net-zero-carbon/">by 2030</a>. The company <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-07-08/google-is-no-longer-claiming-to-be-carbon-neutral?sref=qYiz2hd0">no longer claims to be carbon neutral</a>. Microsoft similarly <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/browns-take-ai-threatens-tech-companies-climate-commitments-3c6c1883">saw a 29 percent jump in emissions</a> from 2020 to 2023. While Microsoft has promised to be carbon negative by 2030, it <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/microsoft-wrestles-with-rising-emissions-from-ai-ahead-of-its-2030-net-zero-goal-b53d4cf4">is now openly struggling</a> with ways to make that happen while keeping pace with AI innovation.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What the AI dealers aren’t telling us</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is what an arms race looks like. It’s worth pointing out here that all energy usages started to spike around the time that OpenAI knocked the world’s socks off with its <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/12/05/technology/chatgpt-ai-twitter.html">surprise release of ChatGPT</a> in November 2022. The chatbot <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/6/23948386/chatgpt-active-user-count-openai-developer-conference">became the fastest-growing app ever</a>, capturing 100 million users <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/chatgpt-sets-record-fastest-growing-user-base-analyst-note-2023-02-01/">in two months</a> and kick-starting the AI gold rush in Silicon Valley. Now, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/10/16/generative-ai-startups-get-40percent-of-all-vc-investment-in-cloud-accel.html#:~:text=Generative%20artificial%20intelligence%20startups%20are,the%20startup%20at%20$157%20billion.">40 percent of all venture capital money</a> in cloud computing goes to generative AI companies. OpenAI itself announced a $6.6 billion funding round in early October — the <a href="https://www.emarketer.com/content/openai-raises-record--6-6-billion-investors-back-its-ai-dominance">largest venture capital round of all time</a> — giving it a $157 billion valuation. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With such staggering amounts of money at play, it’s perhaps no surprise that energy efficiency takes a back seat to growth and innovation. Companies like OpenAI want the models that power their AI technology to get bigger so they can get better and outperform competitors. And the bigger the model, the greater the energy demand — at least for now. Over time, it’s likely that performance will get more efficient thanks to advances in chip technology, data center cooling, and engineering.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Because the innovation happened so quickly around when ChatGPT burst onto the scene, you would expect, initially, for the efficiency to be at its lowest point,” Josh Parker, head of sustainability at chipmaker Nvidia, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the most energy-intensive products are now what companies like OpenAI, Google, and Meta are pushing the hardest. Those include real-time chatbots, voice assistants, and search engines. These features <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24066646/ai-electricity-energy-watts-generative-consumption">enlist larger models and require more advanced chips</a> to work at the same time to reduce latency, or lag. Put simply, they have to do a lot of hard math problems all at once and very quickly. That’s why it takes as much electricity as it does to run a Tesla.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Apple, however, seems to present itself as an exception. As part of its promise to protect user privacy, the company says it handles as many Apple Intelligence tasks as it can on your device without sending queries to data centers. That means when you opt in to Apple Intelligence, you download a small generative AI model that can handle pretty simple tasks on your phone. Your iPhone battery, unlike a grid-connected cloud data center, has a limited amount of power, which forces Apple Intelligence to handle these tasks with some efficiency. Maybe on-device AI is the guilt-free version of the future after all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem, of course, is that we don’t know exactly how Apple Intelligence works. We don’t know which tasks are handled on the device, which are sent to energy-hungry Apple servers, or how much energy it all requires. I asked Apple about this, but the company did not provide specifics. Then again, not providing specifics is a bit of a theme when it comes to big tech companies explaining their AI offerings.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So again, if you’re feeling dread or guilt about AI in your life, that’s understandable. It is clear that this technology, in its current state, consumes vast and increasing amounts of energy, contributing to greenhouse gas emissions and worsening human-caused climate change. It is also true that you might not have a choice, as big tech companies make generative AI more foundational to their products. You can opt out of Apple Intelligence or never opt in. But you’ll find it’s more difficult, if not impossible, to opt out of AI products from Google, Meta, and Microsoft. (If you want to try, here’s <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/05/31/opt-out-ai-training-meta-chatgpt/">a helpful guide</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a reason to feel guilty,” Luccioni said. “But I do think there&#8217;s a reason — as with climate change in general — to ask for more information, to ask for accountability on behalf of the companies that are selling us this stuff.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If AI is supposed to solve all our problems or destroy us all <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/2024/3/3/24083523/artificial-intelligence-ai-doomsday-panic-extinction-climate-change-utopia-tech-bros-silicon-valley">or both</a>, it would be nice to know the details. We could ask ChatGPT, but that might be a huge waste of energy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
