<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-08T19:58:51Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know for breaking’s Olympic debut]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366017/breaking-olympic-sport-what-to-know" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366017</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T19:58:51Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T20:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[At last, the B-boys of summer — and B-girls — are here, and they’re bringing their unique blend of dancing, gymnastics, and hip-hop culture to Paris. On August 9, breaking — don’t call it breakdancing — makes its hotly anticipated Olympics debut in the sport’s highest-profile moment to date.&#160; The entrance of breaking into the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A young person dressed in white pants and shirt spins in the air with several other dancers looking on." data-caption="A breaker performs on stage during the Paris 2024 Cultural Olympiad at L’Olympia on July 22, 2024, in Paris, France. | Julien M. Hekimian/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Julien M. Hekimian/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2163086651.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A breaker performs on stage during the Paris 2024 Cultural Olympiad at L’Olympia on July 22, 2024, in Paris, France. | Julien M. Hekimian/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">At last, the B-boys of summer — and B-girls — are here, and they’re bringing their unique blend of dancing, gymnastics, and hip-hop culture to Paris. On August 9, breaking — don’t call it breakdancing — makes its hotly anticipated Olympics debut in the sport’s highest-profile moment to date.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The entrance of breaking into the Olympics is a huge milestone for a sport and a dance style that has fought long and hard for social acceptance. After all, you don’t get to be an Olympic athlete without approaching a mindblowing level of physical stamina and ability. And when you match that with the level of agility required of great dancers, plus the heady competitiveness of a sport that was honed through street battles, you have the recipe for a truly unique, groundbreaking Olympic sport — and the mainstreaming of this American-born street dance on a whole new global level.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What is breaking?</strong></h2>
<div class="video-container"><iframe src="https://volume.vox-cdn.com/embed/7acd1fab6?player_type=youtube&#038;loop=1&#038;placement=article&#038;tracking=article:rss" allowfullscreen frameborder="0" allow=""></iframe></div>
<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand breaking, you have to understand the roots of hip-hop culture. On the sidewalks and back yards of the Bronx, where hip-hop was born in the late ’60s and ’70s, there were <a href="https://www.vox.com/videos/2017/6/20/15836346/how-bronx-created-breaking-breakdancing">four main streams</a>, or elements, of hip-hop artistry: DJ-ing, emceeing, graffiti art, and breaking. All of them evolved into cornerstones of contemporary mainstream culture. DJing is everywhere, from your average wedding to the megastars who play clubs and arenas, and has evolved further into producers who develop beats and sounds. Emceeing became more commonly known as rapping, which has evolved further into a varied and rich poetic language. Graffiti influenced modern art and pop aesthetics for decades and influenced “guerilla” art and other subversive underground art movements. It’s now a regular installation in museums and galleries and a crucial element of public art in urban areas. And breaking, growing alongside other related but individual street dance styles, became one of the most famous and popular dance forms around. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the decades, breaking and other street dance styles have benefited from popular dance media like the <em>Step Up</em> franchise, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/2/16/16915672/what-is-kpop-history-explained">K-pop</a> and other popular Asian dance groups, and shows like <a href="https://www.vox.com/22630249/one-good-thing-street-dance-of-china-wang-yibo"><em>Street Dance of China</em></a>. Simultaneously, the rise of high-profile international street dance circuit competitions like Juste Debout and Red Bull’s annual <a href="https://www.redbull.com/us-en/event-series/bc-one">BC One challenge</a> have sent breaking and its associated culture on an ascendant trajectory that shows no signs of stopping.  </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Breaking is a unique blend of athleticism and artistry</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When a B-boy or B-girl wants to be taken seriously as a breaker, they have to show not only that they can do big athletic movements, but that they can also execute precise “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8rSr93kCt2U">toprock</a>,” the basic steps for opening and transitioning a dance into the more athletic movements — because the beat is still essential to the performance. In a toprock battle, like the one shown below, bigger movements don’t always win out over controlled musicality.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="NANOX vs ALLEF - toprock | stance x PINK CITY WORLD BATTLE 2022" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X8g8Pj9bUNo?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Outside of a special toprock competition like this one, the purpose of toprock is to help the dancer get smoothly to the floor, where the bigger, more gymnastic moves usually happen. But that wasn’t always the case; in a <a href="https://preciousgemsofknowledge79.blogspot.com/2020/01/interview-with-dj-ez-mike-grandmaster.html">2020 interview</a>, OG hip-hop pioneer DJ EZ Mike explained that breaking evolved over time into the big movements it’s known for today: </p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">The dance changed as the years went on. We didn’t do windmills on the floor because we didn’t dirty our clothes. We dressed very nice. So it had a lot to do with hand movements, facial gestures and footwork. I guess they call it Up-Rocking today.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As dancers got more comfortable getting down and dirty, the form of breaking expanded. In this classic breaking footage from 1984, the street dance crew Sidewalk Breakers demonstrate a variety of moves that show how complex footwork flows to complex floor work:</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="SIDEWALK BREAKERS PART 1 1984" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lTge51Sa4Ck?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s where the most well-known breaking moves come from — like the “Thomas Flair,” a famous gymnast move that evolved into an even more famous old-school breaking move where a dancer whirls around while balancing on one or two hands…</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-embed wp-block-embed-embed"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe src="//cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?maxheight=750&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fthebreaks.org%2Fimg%2Fflare.gif&#038;key=a95589c51263af39f0de8ef8737db4f3" allowfullscreen allow="encrypted-media *;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">…or the “Windmill,” which is essentially the same thing upside down, with the dancer balancing on their elbows and shoulders and occasionally just their head.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-embed wp-block-embed-embed"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe src="//cdn.iframe.ly/api/iframe?maxheight=750&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Fthebreaks.org%2Fimg%2Fwindmill.gif&#038;key=a95589c51263af39f0de8ef8737db4f3" allowfullscreen allow="encrypted-media *;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Obviously some of these big “power moves” are extremely dangerous, which is one reason why breaking has fought for decades to overcome what was initially a negative reputation. Part of this was due to the overall stigmatization of hip-hop culture by the mainstream, and the racist stereotype that it was inherently tied to gang participation. In fact, the four “elements” of hip-hop were <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/1468-2427.12087">first brought together</a> as a way for gangs in the Bronx to unify and interact peacefully in block parties and other collective forms of community-building. They gave rise to dance crews, which are still a staple of street dance culture. Street dance is inherently both collective and competitive, so you’re always strongest when you’re part of a strong team of dancers.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another reason for breaking’s negative public perception was due to the media-coined moniker “breakdancing” itself (which arose thanks to a flub from <a href="https://www.undertheradarmag.com/interviews/the_origins_of_breaking_with_its_biggest_namecrazylegs/">the manager</a> of the legendary Rock Steady crew during an interview), and the danger and risk of injury it implied. Within the culture, the name “breaking” actually came from participants responding to breaks in the music — that is, filling the parts we now think of as “dance breaks” with, what else? Dancing. Originally, breaking was purely for fun, improvised during block parties. This led to the “<a href="https://www.redbull.com/us-en/the-importance-of-the-cypher">cypher</a>,” or dance groups in which the participants form a circle — an informal stage — and take turns dancing for one another. Eventually, the cypher spawned a more structured form of competition — the “battle” — that still dominates street dance culture.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As we can see from the first video above, the battle format is usually pretty simple. Two competitors improvise, or “freestyle,” dance moves to songs chosen on the spot by the DJ and administered by an emcee. They usually compete in two rounds, after which the judges declare the winner. The judges are nearly always on stage or next to the stage with the competitors, and in most settings they vote in the most informal way possible — by deciding then and there, pointing at whoever won. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a case where the judges can’t decide, they’ll form an “X” with their hands, indicating that the dancers need to perform one more round. In some cases, “one more round” can turn into multiple rounds and become a test of stamina. This is a big deal for breakers, who are known less for their stamina over long battles than for their huge bursts of physical activity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are, of course, variants of one-on-one battles, like two-on-two battles, or team battles. The most famous team battle is probably the “7 to Smoke,” a ruthless battle format in which contestants who win one round keep battling other competitors in succession until they lose and the new winner takes over battling. This continues either until 25 minutes have elapsed overall, with the winner being the person who’s won the most rounds, or until one person has managed to win seven rounds.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are the basics of breaking. But of course, for the Olympics, things are a little more complicated.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What you can expect at the Olympics</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout the 2010s, an Olympics dance lobby known as the World DanceSport Federation <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/2021/02/09/break-dancing-olympic-sport-paris-2024/">worked hard</a> to raise awareness of breaking as a dance style and advocate for its entrance into the Olympics. (They adopted breaking as their main cause after failing to get ballroom dancing accepted into the games — a big pivot, but one that paid off.)&nbsp; In 2016, they scored big when breaking made its debut in the 2018 Youth Olympic Games. It was widely seen as a precursor to the Olympics stage, and the official Olympics website <a href="https://olympics.com/en/news/breakings-debut-at-the-buenos-aires-2018-yog">hailed</a> the games as showcasing breaking as “a truly global sport.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might expect the Olympics to completely change the way that breaking battles are conducted, but surprisingly, they’ve only <a href="https://www.nbcolympics.com/news/everything-you-need-know-about-breakings-olympic-debut">slightly tweaked</a> the basic battle concept. At Paris, we’ll see 16 men and 17 women go through essentially two major rounds of competition. (Because the women’s competition has an odd number of participants, the two lowest-seeded women contestants will first have their own one-off round to choose which will join the rest of the competition.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first round for both men and women will be an all-encompassing round robin battle with contestants randomly divided into four groups of four. Each competitor will then battle against the other three in a two-round battle. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After they’ve all battled against one another, each group’s two highest-scoring contestants will advance to the next three rounds of competition, where they’ll be weeded out in one-on-one battles of three rounds each. The last breaker standing — or windmilling — gets the gold.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The format is only slightly different from standard battles, and the most important element — improvisation — remains. No pre-rehearsed routines here; the breakers will still be showing off their ability to adapt to songs they haven’t prepared for in advance. The judging will necessarily be more formal. Judges will vote after each round based on six criteria. As with ice skating, some factors carry more weight than others, but surprisingly, it’s not a “technical/artistic” split: technique, performativity, and creativity comprise 60 percent of the score; personality, variety, and musicality comprise 40 percent. (“Performativity” in this context refers to how cleanly moves are executed.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Contestants to keep your eye on include Afghani IOC Refugee team member <a href="https://www.instagram.com/bgirl_talash/">Manizha Talash</a>, who won hearts with her <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/8/4/afghanistans-first-female-olympic-breakdancer-i-want-my-big">inspiring story</a> of discovering and then rediscovering breaking across two continents. At 42, veteran Japanese dancer <a href="https://www.instagram.com/ayumi.bodycarnival/">Fukushima Ayumi</a> faces a much younger crop of dancers, many of whom are still in their teens and just started dancing a few years ago. She could also face her own teammate, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gfc_ami/">Yuasa Ami</a>, with whom she’s had a fierce back-and-forth rivalry. She defeated Ami in the 2021 world championships; Ami then won the 2022 world prize, only for Ayumi to return with a vengeance in the 2024 Olympic Qualifier.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Ayumi vs Ami | FINAL WDSF World Breaking Championship 2021" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Yeo9KikdlP0?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the men’s side, Vancouver-based frontrunner Philip Kim, aka <a href="https://www.instagram.com/philkwizard/?hl=en">Phil Wizard</a>, has a knack for pulling off miracles — he <a href="https://www.redbull.com/us-en/theredbulletin/b-boy-phil-wizard-interview">decided</a> to enter a cypher competition in Los Angeles, vowing to quit college and pursue breaking full-time if he won. He did. His main competition? Probably Japan’s Nakarai Shigeyuki, aka <a href="https://www.instagram.com/bboyshigekix/">Shigekix</a>, known for big, crowd-thrilling dance moves. For a preview of how that showdown might play out, here they both are, facing off last year: </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Shigekix vs Phil Wizard [BBOY SEMI FINAL] / WDSF World Breaking Champs 2023" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9n8T14umU2g?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As exciting and fresh as all of this is, these games and these contestants still have a lot to prove to skeptics and Olympic officials alike. “Dance is not a sport. It’s an art, no matter what the International Olympic Committee or <em>So You Think You Can Dance</em> judges try to tell you,” <a href="https://dbknews.com/2020/12/10/breakdancing-2024-olympics-breaking-dance/">opined</a> one columnist in 2022. “Including dance seems like a desperate reach for more viewership.” As Fortune recently <a href="https://fortune.com/europe/2024/08/04/breaking-breakdancing-new-york-streets-paris-2024-olympics-debut-future/">noted</a>, breaking has yet to be approved for the 2028 Olympics in Los Angeles — despite the city being a hotbed of street dance culture and a regular stop on battle competition circuits. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there’s anything we know about breakers, however, it’s that they know how to put on big, dramatic shows. The Olympics may indeed be experimenting to bring in more viewers, but this year’s breakers will make the gamble worth it — and hopefully leave them with plenty to look forward to in four more years.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Amy Green</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Lisa Sorg</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The slow, wet, meandering destruction of Tropical Storm Debby]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/366041/climate-hurricane-debby-drenches-the-southeast" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366041</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T19:45:16Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T19:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story was originally published by Inside Climate News and is reproduced here as part of the Climate Desk collaboration. Tropical Storm Debby, a plodding, waterlogged system that has already saturated four southeastern states, bears many characteristics of a warming planet, climate scientists say. It’s reminiscent of other catastrophic tropical cyclones that have battered the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A man walks his dog on a street flooded with water. The water goes up to the man’s calf and the dog’s neck (the dog appears fine with it)." data-caption="A man and dog walk on a flooded street due to Tropical Storm Debby on August 6, 2024 in Charleston, South Carolina. | Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165120418.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A man and dog walk on a flooded street due to Tropical Storm Debby on August 6, 2024 in Charleston, South Carolina. | Miguel J. Rodriguez Carrillo/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story was originally published by </em><a href="https://insideclimatenews.org/news/08082024/debby-drenched-southeast-climate-change-wetter-storms/"><em>Inside Climate News</em></a><em> and is reproduced here as part of the <a href="https://www.climatedesk.org/">Climate Desk</a> collaboration. </em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tropical Storm Debby, a plodding, waterlogged system that has already saturated four southeastern states, bears many characteristics of a warming planet, climate scientists say. It’s reminiscent of other catastrophic tropical cyclones that have battered the United States over the past eight years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Wednesday afternoon, the storm was drifting at 5 mph near the South Carolina coast, about the pace of a monarch butterfly. It is expected to pick up speed today as it heads through North Carolina, where a foot or more of rain could fall in the southeastern part of the state and 6 to 8 inches are anticipated in the central Piedmont.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">North Carolina Gov. Roy Cooper declared a state of emergency this week, warning residents on Wednesday to “be prepared for a deluge.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A warmer atmosphere holds more water; likewise, warmer temperatures accelerate evaporation. “There’s a lot of water in this system that’s just ready to come out,” North Carolina’s state climatologist, Kathie Dello, said. “We’re pulling more of that moisture into the air and essentially supercharging the atmosphere. Or, as I like to say, get a cup of coffee and pour in a few shots of espresso.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tropical Storm Debby has arrived in what is on track to be one of the top 10 warmest years on record in North Carolina. As recently as late June, 99 of the state’s 100 counties were experiencing drought conditions ranging from abnormally dry to severe, according to the State Climate Office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That pattern reversed in July, when several cities reported their wettest July on record.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Swings between wet and dry are something that we’re expecting with climate change,” Dello said. “The extremes become more extreme.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tropical Storm Debby is reminiscent of two historic hurricanes that hit North Carolina — Matthew in 2016 and Florence in 2018. Although both were Category 1 storms by the time they landed in the US, they caused disproportionate damage because they stalled over land and dumped historic amounts of rain — as much as 3 feet — in eastern North Carolina. Thousands of people were left homeless and damages totaled in the billions of dollars.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tropical storms and hurricanes are producing heavier rain over the US, an indicator of climate change, <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1xbxm8pZKEHo3IHe5PsIf5mB1Yblrk63vhKnTQSJVQmI/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">according to a study</a> published last month in the <em>Journal of Climate</em>, a publication of the American Meteorological Society.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">John Uehling co-authored the paper with Carl Schreck III, both of whom are scientists at the North Carolina Institute for Climate Studies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Uehling told Inside Climate News that Tropical Storm Debby is “a classic case of what we’ve seen a lot in recent years,” including with Hurricanes Harvey and Florence, “where we have a stalling storm near the coastline that basically dumps rain over the same areas for an extended and prolonged period of time.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Using historical rainfall gauge data, Uehling and Schreck found that instances of heavy rain associated with tropical cyclones are becoming more frequent and extreme. Major hurricanes — those in categories 3 through 5 — show the largest increases in extreme rainfall.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The real impact that we’re seeing is where the worst events are getting significantly worse,” Uehling said, whereas, in general, “your more run-of-the-mill events are not increasing at nearly the same rate.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The study’s findings could help local governments, planners, and residents prepare for these weather disasters to occur more frequently, Uehling said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That includes inland areas in particular, where the study found the highest increases in rainfall: Alabama and Mississippi through southern Appalachia, including the mountains of North Carolina. Flooding in higher elevations presents different threats — including mudslides and more challenging evacuations — than coastal areas. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Places that have not been used to dealing with these kinds of threats are going to have to start dealing with them more often,” Uehling said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s important that people keep in mind that our climate is changing, that these sort of events are occurring with more and more frequency, and that the impacts seem to be getting greater,” he said. “We have a duty as a society not only to mitigate against these changes, but to do what we can to prevent them from getting worse.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Debby <a href="https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/archive/2024/al04/al042024.update.08051056.shtml?" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">made landfall</a> Monday morning near Steinhatchee, Florida, in the state’s sparsely populated Big Bend region, so named for the way the peninsula meets the panhandle. The Category 1 storm forged a path similar to that of last year’s Idalia, a Category 3 hurricane that was the <a href="https://tropical.colostate.edu/Forecast/2023-11-pressrelease.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">strongest</a> to strike this part of the state since 1896.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165383492.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.740836125969,100,78.518327748063" alt="A person walks through a flooded street caused by the rain and storm surge from Tropical Storm Debby on Monday in Cedar Key, Florida." title="A person walks through a flooded street caused by the rain and storm surge from Tropical Storm Debby on Monday in Cedar Key, Florida." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A person walks through a flooded street caused by the rain and storm surge from Tropical Storm Debby on August 5, 2024, in Cedar Key, Florida. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images via Inside Climate News" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images via Inside Climate News" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Hundreds of thousands of Floridians lost power and Gov. Ron DeSantis declared a state of emergency in 61 of the state’s 67 counties. More than 9,400 feet of what his administration characterized as flood protection devices were deployed at critical infrastructure sites such as schools, health care facilities, and roads and bridges. For the first time flood control barriers also were positioned around utility substations, to try to prevent more power outages, his <a href="https://www.flgov.com/2024/08/06/governor-desantis-issues-updates-on-debby-response-announces-activation-of-small-business-emergency-bridge-loan-to-support-local-impacted-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">administration said</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Florida officials feared more flooding later in the week, as water continued to flow south from the rain-soaked states of Georgia and the Carolinas. By Wednesday, the Florida Division of Emergency Management had pumped more than 104 million gallons of floodwater from communities across the state, the DeSantis administration said.</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“Places that have not been used to dealing with these kinds of threats are going to have to start dealing with them more often.” </p></blockquote></figure>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This could take anywhere from three to seven days,” said Kevin Guthrie, executive director of the Florida Division of Emergency Management, of the duration of the flooding in the state. “This is going to be about a weeklong event that we’re going to be monitoring.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of the worst flooding occurred about 200 miles from the Big Bend region in Sarasota, a beachy community south of Tampa. As much as 12 to 18 inches of rain pummeled the community as Debby’s outer bands swirled some 80 miles offshore. The totals constituted some of the highest rainfall amounts in the state, said Tony Hurt, a meteorologist at the National Weather Service in Ruskin, south of Tampa. Florida typically receives roughly 50 inches of rain annually.   </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At least 500 Sarasota residents were rescued from flooded houses, according to the <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sarasotapolicedept/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">police department</a>. To the north, in neighboring Manatee County, 186 residents were rescued, the <a href="https://www.mymanatee.org/news___events/what_s_new" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">local government</a> said. Officials characterized the rainfall as record-breaking.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Any kind of event like this you just try to be as prepared and stay as flexible as you can,” said Terry Chapman, minister at the South Trail Church of Christ in Sarasota. “We are thankful that it was not worse.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of the church’s parishioners had friends and family members who were affected by the flooding, and the congregation was considering the best ways to offer help. One area that was especially hard-hit was east of Interstate 75, well away from the Gulf Coast.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Those are newer houses,” Chapman said. “Those are houses that were built within the last 20 years.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Warm sea surface temperatures in the Gulf of Mexico powered a rapid intensification of Debby, a phenomenon that is becoming more common because of climate change. The warming climate also is leading to more water evaporation, producing more water vapor that can feed heavy downpours like those experienced with Debby, said James Marshall Shepherd, director of the Atmospheric Sciences Program at the University of Georgia.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“For Floridians, the intensity of the rainfall falling from the afternoon storms and hurricanes has likely increased,” he said. “The pump is primed, if you will. I like to say these hurricanes probably are a little juicier because of the additional water vapor capacity.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165384565.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.740836125969,100,78.518327748063" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="People look out onto a flooded street caused by the rain and storm surge from Stropical Storm Debby on August 5, 2024, in Cedar Key, Florida. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images via Inside Climate News" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images via Inside Climate News" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The atmosphere today holds about 10 percent more moisture, said Brian Soden, professor of atmospheric sciences at the Rosenstiel School of Marine, Atmospheric, and Earth Science at the University of Miami.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It just compounds the problems you get from hurricanes,” he said. “You have not just the wind but more intense rain events. You have storm surge and higher sea levels, and gradually the sea levels rise higher. That means it takes longer for the rainfall to run off into the ocean in coastal regions, and that further compounds the flooding problems you experience.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Debby was the second hurricane to menace the US this year, after Beryl offered an explosive start to the season as the earliest Category 5 hurricane recorded in the Atlantic Ocean, according to the <a href="https://www.climate.gov/news-features/event-tracker/category-5-hurricane-beryl-makes-explosive-start-2024-atlantic-season#:~:text=On%20July%202%2C%202024%2C%20Beryl,to%20the%20National%20Hurricane%20Center." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</a> (NOAA). Beryl lost strength before making landfall on July 8 as a Category 1 storm near Matagorda, Texas, between Corpus Christi and Galveston. The hurricane season begins June 1 and peaks in August and September before ending November 30.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">NOAA had predicted an extraordinarily active season with 17 to 25 named storms, the greatest number the federal agency had projected since the forecasts began in 1998. The agency expected eight to 13 hurricanes and four to seven major hurricanes of category 3, 4, or 5 strength, packing winds of 111 miles an hour or more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">NOAA based its <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/noaa-predicts-above-normal-2024-atlantic-hurricane-season" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">unprecedented forecast</a> on a confluence of factors, most notably unusually warm sea surface temperatures, which the agency said could power more storms. The forecasters also cited an anticipated quick transition to La Niña conditions, leading to a decrease in wind shear or atmospheric choppiness that can weaken or break apart storms. The average season features 14 named storms, including seven hurricanes and three major hurricanes.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Advertisers aren’t buying what X is selling. Is that a crime?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/business-and-finance/365892/elon-musk-x-lawsuit-advertisers-antitrust" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365892</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T18:49:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T18:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Business &amp; Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Elon Musk" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Influence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Social Media" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Twitter" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fellas, is it illegal for brands to refuse to advertise on my social media site? If you’re Elon Musk, the answer is yes. This week, Musk’s social media company X (formerly Twitter) filed an eyebrow-raising lawsuit against an advertising industry group and several major brands, including Unilever (maker of Dove soap), Mars Inc. (maker of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Elon Musk at the Cannes Lions International Festival Of Creativity 2024, with a finger on his chin and looking deep in thought." data-caption="Since Musk’s takeover in late 2022, X’s ad revenue has plunged." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2158243766.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Since Musk’s takeover in late 2022, X’s ad revenue has plunged.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Fellas, is it illegal for brands to refuse to advertise on my social media site? If you’re Elon Musk, the answer is yes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This week, Musk’s social media company X (formerly Twitter) filed an <a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/25033219/x-vs-advertisers.pdf">eyebrow-raising lawsuit</a> against an advertising industry group and several major brands, including Unilever (maker of Dove soap), Mars Inc. (maker of lots of candy), and CVS. It argues that the companies coordinated an advertising boycott against X that not only led to “massive economic harm,” but even violated antitrust law because they colluded to specifically target X, making it less competitive in selling digital ads.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/23423341/elon-musk-buy-twitter-deal-social-media">having to buy</a> the site for a painful $44 billion in 2022, Musk has tried to turn it into a haven of unmoderated speech. Critics have <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2023/05/elon-musk-ron-desantis-2024-twitter/674149/">argued</a> that the site, <a href="https://slate.com/technology/2023/08/elon-musk-blocks-x-twitter-explained.html">often</a> <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/infinite-scroll/twitter-is-already-a-hellscape">called a</a> <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/voices/elon-musk-and-twitter-buy-b2214325.html">“hellsite”</a> for how toxic it could be even before the Musk era, became an unusable cesspit of <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-64804007">vitriol</a> and <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/03/07/1235784919/twitter-x-bots-social-media-elon-musk">incoherent porn bots</a>. Advertisers fled, because businesses don’t want to risk their ads showing up next to objectionable or outright <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/musk-twitter-elon-child-abuse-material-rcna63621">illegal content</a>, like <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/tech/twitter-ads-child-pornography-sexual-abuse-promote-b2177842.html">child sexual abuse material</a>. This is very bad for X, since, like other social media companies, it would go belly up without ad money. X contends this cessation of business is a “naked restraint of trade” because advertisers collectively forced the site to adhere to their content standards. It even had to lower its ad prices, the filing alleges.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lawsuit places the bulk of the blame on the <a href="https://wfanet.org/leadership/garm/about-garm">Global Alliance for Responsible Media</a> (GARM), an initiative launched in 2019 to establish a standard for brand safety across ad platforms. GARM’s membership, which was listed on the site <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240806201617/https://wfanet.org/leadership/garm/members-governance">as of August 6</a>, includes consumer brands, ad agencies, and media companies where ads are served (such as Spotify and, up until recently, X), asking them to commit to a shared understanding of what counts as <a href="https://wfanet.org/knowledge/item/2022/06/17/GARM-Brand-Safety-Floor--Suitability-Framework-3">harmful or risky content</a> that shouldn’t be monetized by ads. Membership is voluntary, and GARM says that individual advertisers ultimately decide how and where they advertise. It did not reply to a request for comment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of this has stopped X from portraying its <a href="https://fortune.com/2023/12/12/elon-musks-x-is-seeing-ad-revenue-plunge-by-half-from-prior-years-and-is-expected-to-bring-in-just-2-5b-this-year/">plummeting ad revenue</a> as a matter of criminal injustice. X says in the lawsuit that at least 18 GARM members pulled all ads from X in late 2022, while many more reduced their spending significantly. In a <a href="https://x.com/lindayaX/status/1820838625245880634">video</a> posted on X, CEO Linda Yaccarino made a grave appeal to X users, arguing that advertisers, not X’s chaotic management, have threatened the financial future of an important platform. “That puts your global town square — the one place that you can express yourself freely and openly — at long-term risk,” she said, echoing the refrain that X is a champion of uncensored free expression despite the fact that it moderates content, even if some say its <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/02/06/inside-elon-musk-x-twitter-austin-content-moderation/">policies are unclear</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A Message to X Users <a href="https://t.co/6bZOYPhWVa">pic.twitter.com/6bZOYPhWVa</a></p>&mdash; Linda Yaccarino (@lindayaX) <a href="https://twitter.com/lindayaX/status/1820838625245880634?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 6, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">X’s lawsuit comes a month after a Republican-led <a href="https://dw-wp-production.imgix.net/2024/07/2024-07-10-GARMs-Harm-How-the-Worlds-Biggest-Brands-Seek-to-Control-Online-Speech.pdf">House Judiciary Committee report</a> and <a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/committee-activity/hearings/collusion-global-alliance-responsible-media">hearing</a> on GARM made similar antitrust accusations, saying the group financially starved platforms hosting content it doesn’t approve of. It’s a continuation of a longer debate around free speech and its consequences. You have the right to speak, but do you have the right to get rich from monetizing your speech? If X goes bankrupt because it turns off too many advertisers, is anyone but X to blame?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loyola University antitrust law professor Spencer Weber Waller, who <a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/republicans-judiciary.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/Waller%20Testimony.pdf">testified</a> at the GARM hearing, tells Vox that he’s skeptical of the lawsuit’s merits. “Just because you’re mad about something doesn’t mean it’s illegal,” he says.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Elon’s beef with advertisers, explained</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Musk has had a volatile relationship with X advertisers for years. Here’s a quick recap: Musk took over in October 2022 and started laying off thousands of employees. Some of the heaviest cuts were made to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/11/04/technology/elon-musk-twitter-layoffs.html">safety team</a>, including <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/elon-musk-twitter-layoffs-outsourced-content-moderators/">content moderators</a>, which signaled to advertisers that brand safety wouldn’t be a priority under Musk’s reign. Twitter’s old identity verification system, which gave a blue check mark to verified public figures and official brand accounts, was removed — which predictably led to a wave of trolls <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/verified-twitter-accounts-impersonating-lebron-james-george-w-bush-aroldis-chapman/">impersonating famous people</a> and companies. (Notably, pharma giant Eli Lilly’s stock tumbled when an impersonator tweeted that <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/11/14/twitter-fake-eli-lilly/">insulin would now be free</a>.) All of this scared advertisers, and many big brands announced they were pausing their X ads in late 2022. A <a href="https://www.mediamatters.org/elon-musk/less-month-elon-musk-has-driven-away-half-twitters-top-100-advertisers">Media Matters for America report</a> found that half of Twitter’s 100 biggest advertisers had paused spending in the first month of Musk’s takeover (only some of which are GARM members). Other <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/08/16/tech/x-ads-pro-nazi-account-brand-safety/index.html">controversies since then</a>, including ads being placed next to pro-Nazi content, have led to more advertisers shutting their pocketbooks. Data from the media intelligence firm Guideline shows there was a 65 percent decline in national ad spending on X between spring 2023 and 2024, according to <a href="https://www.theinformation.com/briefings/x-sues-ad-industry-group-some-top-advertisers?rc=eh9iin">The Information</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Musk seems to have taken this exodus as a personal affront. Last fall, at the annual business conference DealBook, he was outright hostile to the clients that make up the lifeblood of all social media companies. “If somebody is going to try to blackmail me with advertising, blackmail me with money, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/29/23981928/elon-musk-ad-boycott-go-fuck-yourself-destroy-x">go fuck yourself</a>,” he said during an interview with host Andrew Ross Sorkin. He later hedged the declaration at the Cannes Lions advertising awards, saying he <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/elon-musk-pitches-advertisers-on-a-return-to-x-months-after-telling-some-to-f-themselves-532d2745">didn’t mean all of them</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not uncommon for brands to pause ads when they fear reputational harm. Meta was the target of a brief but much-publicized anti-hate speech campaign called #StopHateForProfit in 2020, when <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/01/business/media/facebook-boycott.html">over 1,000 companies</a> temporarily pulled ads on Facebook. When the heat dies down and brands are reassured that they won’t be promoted next to a post that, say, praises Hitler, they often return. The <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/13/technology/x-elon-musk-linda-yaccarino.html">New York Times reported</a> in June that X was claiming over half of its errant advertisers had come back in 2024. In <a href="https://x.com/Safety/status/1807793931003768991">early July</a>, X announced it had “reinstated” its GARM membership. Now, the relationship appears to have soured again.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">When is a boycott illegal?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a consumer, if you want to <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/2023/4/12/23680135/bud-light-boycott-dylan-mulvaney-travis-tritt-trans">swear off Bud Lights</a> for the rest of your life — go wild. If it’s so successful (most consumer boycotts aren’t) that it leads to a company’s financial ruin, then too bad for them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It gets trickier when a bunch of companies boycott another company, which could be an illegal <a href="https://www.theantitrustattorney.com/antitrust-group-boycotts-competitors-conspiring/">group boycott</a>. Let’s say that you just opened a new lemon stall in town, but the neighborhood lemonade stand association tells you they made a pact not to buy your lemons unless you agree not to sell to one specific lemonade stand they hope will go out of business — you might want to complain to the Federal Trade Commission. For X to be the victim of an illegal boycott, first it has to establish there was an agreement between advertisers. X is arguing that GARM’s public statements amount to a coordinated boycott effort, mostly because of <a href="https://wfanet.org/knowledge/item/2022/10/31/GARM-calls-on-Twitter-to-uphold-existing-commitments-on-brand-safety-and-deepen-future-collaboration">an October 2022 letter</a> from GARM calling on the social media site to “uphold its previous commitments” to the alliance. It warned that it would watch the site’s content moderation efforts and that members would use GARM’s insights “as part of their own independent assessments.” X’s lawsuit claims the letter communicated “written plans for a conspiracy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But GARM members deny that there was any agreement or conspiracy. During the House Judiciary Committee’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vmUfdnECOpA">hearing</a> this summer, the president of Unilever USA testified that GARM had never required it to avoid advertising on any platform. A big hurdle of the lawsuit is that X has to prove not just that companies adopted GARM’s standards and definitions of harmful content to justify pulling ads, but that there was a binding agreement.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Antitrust law is concerned with actions that have major anticompetitive effects, often involving cartels. GARM doesn’t appear to be a cartel, a term that usually applies to competitors in a common industry making a commercially beneficial agreement with one another, like if egg producers banded together to limit the supply of eggs. The defendants will likely argue that they’re not competitors, nor is X a competitor — GARM is a vast coalition including ad groups, tech companies, car makers, consumer packaged goods brands, and more. At this point there’s no evidence that advertisers who left X were looking for a financial benefit by boycotting. Then there’s the First Amendment to consider: generally, political and social boycotts are protected even if the companies made an agreement that had an anticompetitive impact, says Waller. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Antitrust laws “generally don’t micromanage the decisions of corporations as they decide what’s best for them in the market,” Waller said during the hearing. Rep. Jerry Nadler (D-NY) called the hearing a part of a “sham investigation,” saying that it served to “intimidate the exercise of free speech.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s unclear how far X’s lawsuit will get. Musk is certainly no stranger to <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/elon-musk-revives-lawsuit-against-sam-altman-openai-nyt-reports-2024-08-05">both suing</a> and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-07/elon-musk-s-pile-of-lawsuits-span-autopilot-toxic-speech-ai?embedded-checkout=true">being sued</a>. Sometimes the fight has <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23585251/elon-musk-tesla-trial-verdict">unexpectedly gone his way</a>, while other times it hasn’t. Recently, a California court dismissed a lawsuit X filed last year against a <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/03/25/elon-musk-x-hate-speech-lawsuit">hate speech watchdog</a> that had documented the rise of hateful rhetoric on the site. With this latest legal volley, X is making the Hotel California argument: Advertisers can check out any time they like, but they can never leave.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Constance Grady</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why readers love — and love to hate — Colleen Hoover]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/365988/colleen-hoover-it-ends-with-us-explained" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365988</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T18:28:10Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T18:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Books" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This weekend, one of the most popular books of the decade is making its way to the big screen. Colleen Hoover’s It Ends With Us, a romantic tearjerker about breaking the cycle of abuse that became a social media sensation after it was published in 2016, is now a movie starring Blake Lively. The moment [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Colleen Hoover at the It Ends With Us New York Premiere at AMC Lincoln Square Theater on August 6, 2024, in New York City. | John Nacion/Variety via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-portal-copyright="John Nacion/Variety via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165136195.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Colleen Hoover at the It Ends With Us New York Premiere at AMC Lincoln Square Theater on August 6, 2024, in New York City. | John Nacion/Variety via Getty Images&lt;br&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">This weekend, one of the most popular books of the decade is making its way to the big screen. Colleen Hoover’s <em>It Ends With Us</em>, a romantic tearjerker about breaking the cycle of abuse that became a social media sensation after it was published in 2016, is now a movie starring Blake Lively. The moment means the mainstream coronation of Hoover herself, the former social worker from Texas turned queen of the New York Times bestseller list.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover sells books the way Danielle Steel used to sell books. She sells the way Stephen King still does. She sells the way new authors usually don’t. In 2022, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/09/books/colleen-hoover.html">she held six of the top 10 spots on the Times’s paperback bestseller list at once</a> and sold more books than the Bible. According to industry tracker Circana BookScan, Hoover has sold 28.9 million books in print, plus 7 million ebooks. <em>It Ends With Us</em>, probably her most popular novel, has sold 6.9 million print and ebooks combined. It has been on the New York Times bestseller list for 131 weeks, and it is currently at the top.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover began as a self-published indie author, releasing her first novel, <em>Slammed</em>, in January 2012 when she was 42. She had already found what would become her sweet spot of melodrama combined with taboo romance: The book featured an 18-year-old grieving the death of her father and in love with her poetry teacher. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Slammed</em> unexpectedly became <a href="https://www.maryse.net/books/contemporary-romance/book-review-slammed-by-colleen-hoover.html">a word-of-mouth hit among book bloggers</a>. By August, the book and its sequel, published a month later, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/10/09/books/colleen-hoover.html">were on the New York Times bestseller list</a>, and Hoover had a traditional publishing contract. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“Colleen Hoover superfan” and “Colleen Hoover hater” are both legible identities in a way that they are for few other authors </p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since then, Hoover has published 24 books, counting her novellas, typically releasing at least one book a year, more frequently two and sometimes up to three or four. She has always sold well, but her career shifted into another gear in 2020, when the pandemic left readers in need of a good cry and BookTok emerged as <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23644772/booktok-money-business-sponsored-videos">a hit-maker</a>. On BookTok, Hoover fans <a href="https://nypost.com/2022/12/06/how-crying-tiktoks-made-colleen-hoover-a-millionaire-author/">could film themselves weeping over her books</a>, tossing them across the room out of pure emotional overwhelm, sighing over her heroes. Her sales figures exploded in response.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Hoover hasn’t published a book since 2022. <a href="https://www.texasmonthly.com/arts-entertainment/why-did-colleen-hoover-stop-writing/">Asked why</a>, she says she’s become very aware of how vast her audience is.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover has a point: Her audience numbers in the millions. It’s also polarized. In the emotional landscape of BookTok, “Colleen Hoover superfan” and “Colleen Hoover hater” are both legible identities in a way that they are for few other authors. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@sancheetwthapa/video/7341771795659279623" data-video-id="7341771795659279623" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@sancheetwthapa" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@sancheetwthapa?refer=embed">@sancheetwthapa</a> <p>My chest still hurts when I remember blawing out because of this one💗 <a title="itendswithus" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/itendswithus?refer=embed">#itendswithus</a> <a title="booktok" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/booktok?refer=embed">#booktok</a> <a title="herecurls" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/herecurls?refer=embed">#herecurls</a> <a title="colleenhoover" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/colleenhoover?refer=embed">#colleenhoover</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ sonido original - 💜Takis morados 💜" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/sonido-original-7329226765698943750?refer=embed">♬ sonido original &#8211; 💜Takis morados 💜</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Hoover fans film themselves sobbing over her books, Hoover haters post about flipping her books around at bookstores so that the covers are backward. They create detailed video essays laying out all the things they think are wrong with Hoover’s books: her simple sentences, her melodramatic plots, her toxic love stories that they say romanticize abuse. Or <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@elisereadz/video/7286134473861696801?lang=en">they just point to a line of text</a> she’s written and say, “What the fuck?” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s something about these books that seems to inspire intense reactions in their readers, ranging from sublime catharsis to visceral disgust. Here are the reasons so many of Hoover’s readers have become such ardent, adoring fans — and so many others have become such ferocious haters.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hoover’s subject matter is heavy, but her writing style is bubbly and fun. The contrast is weird.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover’s romantic melodramas tend to deal with intense real-life issues that some of her readers have surely experienced. All her characters are traumatized; all their children are destined for untimely deaths; all their love stories are twisted and tragic. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Ugly Love</em> (2014) features a hero who, following the death of his newborn baby, has sworn he’ll never love again. <em>All Your Perfects</em> (2018) deals with a couple struggling with infertility. In <em>November 9</em> (2015), a woman badly scarred by a house fire falls in love with a man still grieving the death of his mother, who died by suicide.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of what sets Hoover apart from other writers of melodrama (think: Nicholas Sparks) is that despite the trauma her characters must face, she writes them with a breezy romantic comedy charm. They meet cute, they banter, and they trade inside jokes as their worlds collapse around them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The juxtaposition between Hoover’s bubbly prose style and the intensity of her subject matter creates a jarring contrast. Her books are almost magnetically readable: The sentences are easy and pleasant to read while the plots are shocking and intense. You can blaze through one in a day. You can, if you are so inclined, fall in love with her troubled alpha male heroes, her tormented and striving heroines.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>They meet cute, they banter, and they trade inside jokes as their worlds collapse around them</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Hoover’s fans, this effect is something they love about her books. She makes reading feel straightforward and easy, even if you’re not naturally inclined to be bookish.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Hoover’s haters, however, the contrast is one of the signs that there’s something dishonest, even perhaps morally wrong, about the way she writes. How, they ask, can she expect her audience to take her subject matter seriously when she handles it so lightly? These readers feel there is something crassly manipulative about the way Hoover dredges up tragedy to make her readers cry, and then tosses it aside when she doesn’t want to deal with any of the parts that might be trickier to write or read about.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a paragraph in <em>Ugly Love</em> that has become <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AreTheStraightsOK/comments/17b6vrv/im_not_sure_colleen_hoover_is_okay/">something of a meme among Hoover haters</a> that exemplifies how oddly her banter can read. It’s a conversation between Miles, one of the novel’s narrators, and his girlfriend Rachel after they’ve just had a baby:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">“Thank you for this baby,” she says from the back seat. “He’s beautiful.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">I laugh. “You’re responsible for the beautiful part, Rachel. The only thing he got from me was his balls.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">She laughs. She laughs hard. “Oh my God, I know,” she says. “They’re so big.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">We both laugh at our son’s big balls.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover haters love to roast her for everything about this paragraph: the idea of parents mocking their kid’s genitalia, the simplistic sentence structure, the non sequitur of the joke. The context around these lines, however, make the situation and dialogue perhaps even more off-putting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, the young parents in this novel are step-siblings who carried on their forbidden love affair in their parents’ house, a taboo plot twist that never pays off into any major revelations or insight into their characters. Second, the balls joke is followed immediately by tragedy: they get into a car crash, and the big-balled newborn baby dies. (I told you all the babies die.) For Hoover haters, the moment is an encapsulation of everything that makes her books bad: the cutesy romantic “joke” right up against the pointless and out-of-nowhere drama, all of it handled in the very worst of taste.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover’s defenders, meanwhile, say that she writes books that are fun to read and that bring awareness to important issues. In particular, <em>It Ends With Us</em> has <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27362503-it-ends-with-us">staunch fans</a> who describe it, echoing the blurb on the cover, as the kind of book “every person with a heartbeat should read.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even most of Hoover’s haters <a href="https://youtu.be/U8zP5R3kh3o?si=9J61fLCgbutyTQmj">will concede</a> that <em>It Ends With Us</em> is one of her more ambitious books. Inspired by the marriage of Hoover’s parents, it puts readers in the head of our protagonist, Lily, as she first falls in love with and then grows gradually more afraid of manipulative, controlling, violent Ryle Kincaid. Lily thinks of herself as the kind of person who knows better than to stay with an abuser, but when Ryle gets violent with her — first hitting, then choking — she finds herself making excuses for him. It’s only when he eventually throws her down a flight of stairs and then sexually assaults her (and another potential love interest presents himself) that Lily finally decides to leave Ryle.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/img3.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4613147178592,100,93.077370564282" alt="A man and a woman gaze intensely at each other, cupping each other’s faces with their hands, in a moodily-lit bar." title="A man and a woman gaze intensely at each other, cupping each other’s faces with their hands, in a moodily-lit bar." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Blake Lively and Justin Baldoni as Lily and Ryle in &lt;em&gt;It Ends With Us&lt;/em&gt;. | Sony Pictures" data-portal-copyright="Sony Pictures" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The result is a didactic novel clearly written to explain why a person in an abusive relationship might find it difficult to leave her abuser, and then show how she might find the strength to do so anyway. This is why <em>It Ends With Us</em> is deeply important to many Hoover fans. It’s the kind of novel, they say, that makes you cry for the terrible dilemma of its heroine, that has the power to change the way you see abused women.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet Hoover’s critics say <em>It Ends With Us</em> is just like the rest of the books in her oeuvre: crassly using big, complicated stories for cheap tears and easy money. Hoover’s male characters tend to be domineering, in a way that is often supposed to be part of their appeal. Ryle, they point out, isn’t the only Hoover hero to override his girlfriend’s “no” when he touches her —&nbsp;he’s just the only one labeled an abuser when he does so.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Haters cite Hoover’s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/RomanceBooks/comments/1b2y5c7/colleen_hoover_releases_a_nail_polish_kit_thats/"><em>It Ends With Us</em> nail polish line</a> and a planned-but-never-published <a href="https://www.cnn.com/style/article/colleen-hoover-coloring-book-cancellation-intl-scli/index.html"><em>It Ends With Us</em> coloring book</a> as evidence that domestic abuse, like the dead baby with large testicles, is just another thing that Hoover will take heavily when she wants to make you cry, and lightly when she wants to keep things easy.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The genre question</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Part of the reason readers have a hard time grappling with Hoover’s work is the question of what genre she’s writing in, and what expectations they should hold for her. It’s hard to know what you’re going to get when you open one of her books cold, which is part of why it’s hard to know in what spirit to take her writing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Hoover transitioned from indie author into traditional publishing in 2012, she was positioned as New Adult author, <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publishing-and-marketing/article/55164-new-adult-needless-marketing-speak-or-valued-subgenre.html">a buzzy new marketing category</a>. The millennial YA audience that had made books like <em>Twilight</em> and <em>The Hunger Games</em> such sensations would soon be aging out of their market, publishers feared. Surely they would need new books as they left high school and entered the real world: books that were just as fun and straightforward to read as the YA they’d left behind, but with the sexy darkness that had been trending up in YA made explicit. New Adult books would provide just such a thrill for readers 18 through 23. Hoover, with her grabby pacing, steamy sex scenes, melodramatic subject matter, and straightforwardly bouncy prose, was an ideal author for the new genre.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem was that New Adult never took off. Few bookstores ever installed New Adult shelves. The readers who wanted to keep reading YA-style books stuck to YA, which is now <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/apr/30/more-than-a-quarter-of-readers-of-ya-are-over-the-age-of-28-research-shows">primarily read by adults</a>. Those who wanted more adult books transitioned to other categories like romance or thrillers or literary fiction. The newly established New Adult writers were left at sea.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, Hoover’s books are generally sold as romance novels. For readers, that’s a label that comes with expectations. It means that the characters should strive towards a healthy and aspirational relationship, that they should finish the book happy together forever. That is not the kind of story Hoover is interested in writing.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/img4.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,3.4613147178592,100,93.077370564282" alt="A man and a woman singing karaoke stare at each other with flirty smiles." title="A man and a woman singing karaoke stare at each other with flirty smiles." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Are they or aren’t they in a romcom? Lively and Baldoni in &lt;em&gt;It Ends With Us&lt;/em&gt;. | Sony Pictures" data-portal-copyright="Sony Pictures" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Some romance readers say they’d be happy with Hoover’s novels if she would simply call them dark romance, a subgenre that comes with the presumption that there will be a fair amount of sexy toxicity. (If romance novels in the ’70s were all about wickedly brooding men kidnapping and ravishing innocent virgins, dark romance is where that formula lives on.) Hoover, obligingly, has a couple of her more twisted novels labeled as dark romance on her website. Still, she prefers not to follow the genre’s latest guidance for <a href="https://bookriot.com/dark-romance-books-2/">a page of “trigger warnings”</a> at the front of her novels. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’ve received quite a number of negative reviews in relation to the lack of a trigger warning for the subject matter…and for writing about such unhappy things,” <a href="https://writerunboxed.com/2016/08/19/writing-in-a-trigger-happy-world/">Hoover wrote in a now-deleted blog post in 2016</a>. “As a fellow reader with my fair share of past experiences, I understand that there are issues some people do not want to read about. But as a writer, there are many things I don’t want revealed in the blurbs of my books.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover’s fans defend her distaste for content warnings as a display of artistic integrity. Her tragedies rely on an element of surprise for their immediacy: The reader is shocked by sudden horror in the same way the characters are. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sometimes, that surprise is central to the intended effect of the book. <em>It Ends With Us</em> has a back cover blurb suggesting that Ryle’s fear of commitment will be the primary obstacle in the novel. The reveal that Ryle is not just opposed to marriage but is in fact violently abusive is part of how readers are brought to empathize with Lily when she finds herself making excuses for Ryle’s behavior, even though she thinks she knows better: We thought she was in a romance the same way she did. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Hoover detractors, though, Hoover’s distaste for content warnings is another tell that she thinks of the issues she’s writing about as plot devices, not as real problems that affect real people. Why, they ask, is she prioritizing the element of surprise over the possibility of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/RomanceBooks/comments/13uw71y/why_tf_doesnt_it_ends_with_us_have_a_trigger/">triggering trauma flashbacks in an unsuspecting reader</a>?</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@alexiadyslexia/video/7179006689721453867" data-video-id="7179006689721453867" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@alexiadyslexia" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@alexiadyslexia?refer=embed">@alexiadyslexia</a> <p>Hoover hater <a title="colleenhoover" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/colleenhoover?refer=embed">#colleenhoover</a> <a title="books" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/books?refer=embed">#books</a> <a title="booktok" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/booktok?refer=embed">#booktok</a> <a title="book" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/book?refer=embed">#book</a> <a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp?refer=embed">#fyp</a> <a title="trending" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/trending?refer=embed">#trending</a> <a title="itendswithus" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/itendswithus?refer=embed">#itendswithus</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬  -" href="https://www.tiktok.com/?refer=embed">♬  &#8211; </a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Either way, Hoover once again finds herself at odds with the genre in which she’s been tentatively placed: too sad for traditional romance, too traditional for dark romance, too popular for New Adult. Readers coming to her never quite have a sense of what she’s going to give them, and the traditional signposts of publishing don’t seem to serve her well.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hoover doesn’t necessarily seem to mind that she’s hard to pigeonhole. In an interview with Vulture in 2022, Hoover mused that her most popular books seem to be the inspirational <em>It Ends With Us</em> and the psychosexual <em>Rebecca</em>-inspired <em>Verity</em>. (<em>Verity</em>’s one of those books that merits the dark romance label.) “I like that my readers’ tastes land on opposite ends of a reading spectrum, and I especially love it when their two favorites are books that are nothing alike,” <a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/colleen-hoover-best-books-most-romantic-riskiest.html">Hoover said</a>. “It reinforces my decision not to stick to one genre.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s true that Hoover’s readership tends to land on opposite ends of a reading spectrum — both in the way they like her books and in the way they hate them. But regardless of how many and how vocal the Hoover haters are, her books keep selling. Her reign at the top of the New York Times bestseller list will last as long as she has books to sell — which, depending on how long her writer’s block lasts, may be a very long time or no time at all.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Amanda Lewellyn</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Victoria Chamberlin</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How the UK’s far right used a local tragedy to spur chaos]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/365953/riots-uk-stabbing-far-right-merseyside-southport" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365953</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T16:47:08Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T16:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Europe&#039;s Far-Right" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Riots and violence have erupted in the UK following the killing of three young girls in the quiet seaside town of Southport in northern England. Last week, while learning dance moves to their favorite Taylor Swift songs, a 17-year-old boy entered their classroom and went on a stabbing rampage that left three dead and critically [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A line of police with helmets and riot shields stand in front of a burning vehicle, while protesters yell in front of them." data-caption="Riot police hold back protesters near a burning police vehicle after disorder broke out on July 30, 2024, in Southport, England. | Christopher Furlong/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Christopher Furlong/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2164490156.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Riot police hold back protesters near a burning police vehicle after disorder broke out on July 30, 2024, in Southport, England. | Christopher Furlong/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Riots and violence have <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/article/2024/aug/01/southport-uk-stabbings-arrests-london-protests">erupted</a> in the UK following the killing of three young girls in the quiet seaside town of Southport in northern England. Last week, while learning dance moves to their favorite Taylor Swift songs, a 17-year-old boy entered their classroom and went on a stabbing rampage that left three dead and critically wounded several others. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Following the attack, a UK law prohibiting the public naming of suspects under the age of 18 created an information vacuum, and within hours, rumors about the suspect in custody, including an incorrect name, were circulating around the far-right media ecosystem. Police in Merseyside, the county that includes Southport, quickly confirmed the suspect was born in the UK, but <a href="https://apnews.com/article/uk-southport-stabbing-online-misinformation-1dcd23b803401416ac94ae458e5c9c06">misinformation</a> on social media claimed he was an immigrant.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nigel Farage, a British broadcaster, leader of the right-wing Reform UK party and member of Parliament, added to the chaos when he <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelfarageofficial/videos/my-response-to-the-attack-in-southport/3758410404434530/?_rdr">released a video</a> statement casting doubt on the official information released by Merseyside police. “I just wonder whether the truth is being withheld from us. I don&#8217;t know the answer to that, but I think it is a fair and legitimate question,” Farage said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Three days after the attack, a judge <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/crime/southport-stabbings-suspect-named-axel-rudakubana-b2589606.html">agreed to allow</a> the name of the suspect to be released but the damage had been done. While the town of Southport was still in mourning, far-right protesters took to the streets, chanting “We want our country back,” attacked a local mosque, and injured <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/07/31/southport-stabbing-riot-misinformation/">more than 50 police officers</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That riot, the day after the stabbing attack, was just the first of many violent demonstrations that flared up across Great Britain and in Northern Ireland’s capital, Belfast. On Sunday, around 750 people surrounded a hotel housing asylum seekers in northern England. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo/?fbid=912881000884274&amp;set=a.311353597703687">According to police</a>, rioters smashed windows in an attempt to gain access to hotel residents and lit a large trash bin on fire.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Robyn Vinter, a correspondent for the Guardian covering the north of England, has been covering the protests across the UK and shared her experience with Noel King on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/2NU5PAYNPoKgVQkHaLm8Tu?si=ca5968da78de42f3">an episode of <em>Today, Explained</em></a>. Their conversation below has been edited for length and clarity.  </p>

<iframe frameBorder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4172479184" width="100%"></iframe>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Robyn Vinter</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">[The Southport attack] had happened on a Tuesday night, and by the Friday, there was a list of places where demonstrations were going to be held. They were described as protests. Fliers were going around social media that said things like, “A protest is going to be held outside this mosque.” And then we saw large-scale pockets of far-right riots: a lot of violence in a lot of towns and cities across the UK.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A hotel in Rotherham that was housing asylum seekers was on the list. That one got out of hand very quickly, partly because it was under-policed: there’d been another protest organized in a city nearby, and they perhaps underestimated how many people would attend. In total, there were about 750 rioters. They were physically attacking police, smashing windows, burning things. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They managed to set fire, briefly, to the hotel with about 240 asylum seekers inside, which was obviously terrifying. The windows were smashed and the asylum seekers were appearing at the windows. They were all fairly young. The ones I saw — teenagers, early 20s — all looked very scared, very worried. I shouted through the window, “Are you okay?” and I was holding a thumbs up. A lot of them were replying, “Okay, okay.” A lot of them don&#8217;t have good English. And then one man shouted down, “I am not okay.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The police were wearing fireproof gear and helmets and had big riot shields, so they were safe from the fireworks. But there were quite a lot of times when I saw the police that had been relieved from their shifts on the front line of this battle against the rioters. They would go around the corner or down a side street, and they would just be sitting with their heads in their hands because it had been such a draining and exhausting day. A few police officers said to me that it had been by far the biggest riot that they’d ever [responded to]. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over time, it calmed down. As the evening went on, it tended to be younger rioters who clearly were teenagers. I spoke to a 16-year-old girl who was there, and she said she recognized a lot of them from school, and that some of them were even younger than she was.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And that was only one riot that happened. While I was in Rotherham, a colleague of mine was in Middlesbrough on the opposite English coast. It was different scenes in Middlesbrough because there was not really a specific target. The far right were running riot through the town. There weren’t enough police. Journalists were being targeted, because there’s a huge mistrust among the rioters and the general public of journalists. A number of journalists and photographers have been hurt or had equipment stolen. My friend, the colleague who was in Middlesbrough, went back to his car to find it had been completely smashed up, and the police had to drive him home. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’ve been 400 arrests, but the arrests keep coming because there are so many people involved. There are more demonstrations due to be held, and there’s a lot of likelihood that these are going to turn into riots as well. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Noel King&nbsp;</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Robyn, you and other news media are using two words. You’re using “riot” and you’re using “protest.” The people who are protesting: What do they say they want to come out of this? </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Robyn Vinter</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some of the protests are local to a situation, but there are broad themes. You hear the phrase “We want our country back.” A lot of it is about a kind of broader anti-immigration sentiment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Rotherham — where I was, where the rioters attacked the hotel housing asylum seekers — there was a feeling that asylum seekers were getting better treatment in the UK than British people were. People were saying, “Well, I have to pay my bills. I have to put a roof over my head. I have to work. And these people are coming here and they’re living in a hotel and they’re not working. Not doing anything. They don’t have to worry about paying bills.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There were also — which I found very sinister — rumors going around in certain communities that certain men had been following women home. Or, the rumor in Rotherham was that two women had been raped by asylum seekers and that the authorities had covered it up. Obviously, as a journalist, that would be a very good story if I could stand it up. But I’m just completely unable to find any evidence that that’s the case. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in a way, it doesn’t matter, because it goes around on social media. People hear it. Everybody has heard it from somebody else. Nobody’s the person that it’s happened to. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This all got started with a rumor that the boy who had stabbed these little girls was an immigrant. Have rumors continued to contribute to what’s going on? Either rumors or deliberate misinformation — sometimes called disinformation, I suppose.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Robyn Vinter</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Disinformation and misinformation have had a really pivotal role in the last seven days. There have been a lot of deliberate instigators on social media — a lot of people, actually, who wouldn’t perpetrate violence themselves, but will easily goad other people into doing so. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Something I haven&#8217;t mentioned so far, as well: there’s something that the far-right instigators on social media are calling “two-tier policing.” They believe that white British people are getting worse treatment — they’re getting more heavy-handed treatment — from the police than Muslims or other groups of people. I wouldn’t go as far as saying “conspiracy theory,” but it’s a huge talking point among the far right. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We even heard Elon Musk describe Prime Minister Keir Starmer as “Two-tier Keir,” obviously referencing this nonsensical and nonexistent idea of two-tier policing.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Keir Starmer is brand new in the office. This would be his first real crisis. How is he perceived to be handling this?&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Robyn Vinter</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Keir Starmer is a very interesting character. When we had some riots in urban areas in London and other cities in 2011, he was the director of public prosecutions — kind of like your chief prosecutor, essentially making decisions about how these rioters would be handled by the courts, how they’d be prosecuted. His method of prosecuting was bringing people in quickly and prosecuting them quickly. There were late-night courts and courts running over the weekend in order to process the large numbers of rioters. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far we’re seeing something very similar to back then. He’s very keen on clamping down immediately on the rioters, and you can see the method as well. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think when people start to see the large sentences that rioters will be getting for attacking police and setting fires, they’re going to be more likely to think twice before they get involved in future violence. </p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We are expecting more of this; more protests, potentially more rioting, potentially more injuries, potentially more clashes with police. What should we take from all of this? What does this tell us more broadly about what is happening in the UK right now?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Robyn Vinter</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The summer of 2024 is going to be defined as a summer of rioting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although the riots will [probably] start to die down in the next couple of weeks, the sentiment will not go away. It’s going to take as long as it took to build it up to dissipate it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t have any answers about what we can do to improve that sentiment. It’s something that I feel very worried about. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We in the UK rarely descend into any kind of real nationwide violence. People from abroad have been saying that “it&#8217;s going to end in a civil war.” That’s absurd. But we do have to worry about this. We have to worry about it because that sentiment exists in other countries as well, places that don’t have a long legacy of stability. This kind of thing could be a spark that lights a fire somewhere else.  </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Communications</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Angela Chen Joins Vox]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/press-room/365917/angela-chen-joins-vox-politics-policy-ideas" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365917</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T15:22:19Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T14:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vox Press Room" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vox editor-in-chief Swati Sharma and executive editor Elbert Ventura announced today that Angela Chen has joined the brand as a senior editor on the policy, politics, and ideas team. She begins her new role on August 19. “I’m thrilled to welcome Angela. One thing that sets Vox’s coverage of policy and politics apart is our [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Angela_Chen_credit-Sylvie-Roskoff-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Vox editor-in-chief <strong>Swati Sharma</strong> and executive editor <strong>Elbert Ventura</strong> announced today that <strong>Angela Chen</strong> has joined the brand as a senior editor on the policy, politics, and ideas team. She begins her new role on August 19.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m thrilled to welcome Angela. One thing that sets Vox’s coverage of policy and politics apart is our deep commitment to ideas and intellectual debate and our ability to clarify the stakes for everyone. We are an idea-driven newsroom, and Angela is a perfect match for our ethos. I’m looking forward to seeing the insight and curiosity she will bring to our coverage,” said Ventura.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In her role at Vox, Angela Chen will work with writers on a wide range of stories across many issue areas — poverty, reproductive rights, housing, the care economy, and guns, among others — unpacking the ideas, themes, and concepts that underpin our politics and policies. Angela was most recently a senior editor at Wired, running its Ideas section and publishing thought-provoking work on various topics. Before that, she worked at the Wall Street Journal, MIT Technology Review, and Vox Media’s editorial brand, The Verge.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Do celebrity endorsements matter?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365865/celebrity-endorsements-kamala-harris-megan-thee-stallion" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365865</id>
			<updated>2024-08-07T23:21:39Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[First, there was Charli XCX’s post declaring Vice President Kamala Harris “is brat” on X. Then there was Beyonce’s approval of her song, “Freedom,” for Harris’s campaign use. And most recently, there was Megan Thee Stallion’s appearance at a Harris rally in Atlanta, alongside fellow musician Quavo.  Since Harris became the likely Democratic nominee at [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Megan, in a bright blue cropped jacket, white shirt, and blue tie, raises her hand as she sings, a crowd with KAMALA posters behind her. " data-caption="Megan Thee Stallion performs onstage at a campaign rally for Democratic presidential candidate Vice President Kamala Harris on July 30, 2024, in Atlanta, Georgia. | Julia Beverly/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Julia Beverly/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2164533746.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Megan Thee Stallion performs onstage at a campaign rally for Democratic presidential candidate Vice President Kamala Harris on July 30, 2024, in Atlanta, Georgia. | Julia Beverly/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">First, there was Charli XCX’s post declaring <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362300/kamala-harris-meme-brat-summer">Vice President Kamala Harris “is brat” on X</a>. Then there was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/22/entertainment/beyonce-freedom-harris-campaign/index.html">Beyonce’s approval of her song</a>, “Freedom,” for Harris’s campaign use. And most recently, there was Megan Thee Stallion’s appearance at a Harris rally in Atlanta, alongside fellow musician Quavo. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">.<a href="https://twitter.com/theestallion?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@theestallion</a>: My ladies in the crowd, if you want to keep loving your body, you know who to vote for<br><br>🔥🔥🔥 <a href="https://t.co/RTnzxt0zLT">pic.twitter.com/RTnzxt0zLT</a></p>&mdash; Kamala HQ (@KamalaHQ) <a href="https://twitter.com/KamalaHQ/status/1818420877836361821?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Harris became the likely Democratic nominee at the end of July, celebrities have poured in to support and endorse her. Some have coordinated with the campaign, and others — like Charli XCX — expressed their backing on their own. Other notable names who’ve chimed in include billionaire Mark Cuban, rapper Cardi B, and actress Jane Fonda. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These endorsements have brought a new wave of star power to the presidential election, and could drive more attention, dollars and enthusiasm to the campaign. Whether they’ll persuade people who weren’t already open to Harris to consider her, however, <a href="https://wset.com/news/nation-world/fact-check-team-what-is-the-impact-of-celebrity-endorsements-on-political-campaigns" data-type="link" data-id="https://wset.com/news/nation-world/fact-check-team-what-is-the-impact-of-celebrity-endorsements-on-political-campaigns">is uncertain</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to political scientists, celebrity endorsements tend to have “modest effects” in winning over voters, says Bowling Green State University professor <a href="https://www.bgsu.edu/arts-and-sciences/political-science/faculty-and-staff-directory/David-Jackson.html">David J. Jackson</a>, who notes that they’re more likely to boost excitement for a candidate a voter may already be leaning toward, rather than sway someone to cross party lines. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How celebrities have gotten involved so far</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Politicians often use celebrities in an attempt to energize key voting groups — and people who may be less engaged. Harris’s appearance alongside Megan Thee Stallion and Quavo in Atlanta, for instance, appeared dedicated to reaching younger voters as well as Black voters, both important groups that are expected to account for a notable proportion of the electorate this fall. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Political candidates are heavily leaning on celebrities as a mechanism to attract the attention of this cycle’s youngest voting demographic: Generation Z,” says <a href="https://www.pace.edu/profile/melvin-williams">Melvin Williams</a>, a professor of communications and media studies at Pace University. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2020/09/23/gen-z-eligible-voters-reflect-the-growing-racial-and-ethnic-diversity-of-u-s-electorate/">According to a 2020 Pew study</a>, Gen Z comprised roughly 10 percent of eligible voters that year, and about 45 percent of those voters were nonwhite. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/11/18/the-2020-election-shows-gen-zs-voting-power-for-years-to-come.html">A major uptick in Gen Z turnout in 2020</a> was also critical to helping President Joe Biden secure the presidency, even though younger voters have historically turned out at lower rates than other age groups. And Black voters have historically been a significant proportion of Democrats’ base as well, with <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2021/06/30/behind-bidens-2020-victory/">92 percent</a> of Black voters supporting Biden in 2020.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond high-profile rallies, celebrities like actor <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/23/politics/george-clooney-kamala-harris-2024/index.html">George Clooney</a> have given interviews and written social media posts announcing their backing for Harris. And others, like comedians Tiffany Haddish, Whoopi Goldberg, and Nick Offerman, have hosted <a href="https://variety.com/2024/digital/news/comics-elders-kamala-harris-fundraiser-nick-offerman-jane-fonda-1236096484/">virtual fundraising gatherings</a>, like one dubbed Comics for Kamala, that took place this week. Such events highlight how celebrities can be key contributors to campaigns by driving donations and broader awareness. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Former President Donald Trump has seen some celebrities speak out on his behalf, too, including country singer Kid Rock and wrestler Hulk Hogan, both of whom appeared at the Republican National Convention. They respectively described him as a “badass,” “hero,” and “gladiator,” all seemingly in a bid to hype up his masculine credentials and energize the crowd ahead of Trump’s appearance at the event.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And model Amber Rose, who also spoke at the RNC, was among the participants booked with the apparent goal of expanding Trump’s appeal to Black voters, after he made marginal gains with the group in 2020. Trump doesn’t care if “you&#8217;re Black, white, gay, or straight, it’s all love,” she claimed. Like Harris, Trump has sought to cultivate ties with younger voters as well, appearing on podcasts with Gen Z influencers like Logan Paul and streamer Adin Ross — both of whom have young, male audiences. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The impact celebrity endorsements can have on presidential elections</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re one of the most famous, influential women in the world, you may be able to sway a presidential election a little. If not, the effect might be a bit more limited.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.kellogg.northwestern.edu/faculty/garthwaite/htm/celebrityendorsements_garthwaitemoore.pdf">Oprah Winfrey’s support of former President Barack Obama</a> in the 2008 Democratic primary is the rare example of a specific endorsement having a tangible, scientifically studied impact on candidate choice. <a href="https://www.kellogg.northwestern.edu/faculty/garthwaite/htm/celebrityendorsements_garthwaitemoore.pdf">According to a 2013 Northwestern University study</a>, her endorsement — one of just a few political statements of support she’s made — translated to an uptick in turnout, donations, and approximately a million votes in favor of Obama. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A key caveat of that study is that it centered on a Democratic primary, when voters were choosing from candidates with the same party affiliation, rather than a general election, when candidates tend to have major partisan differences. Additionally, experts note that endorsements could provide voters with more useful information in a primary when there may be a broader mix of new and familiar options. In a general election, if the candidates are more well-established, endorsements could be less likely to offer novel insights.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That was a different environment because that was a primary election between Democrats where Oprah weighed in to that contest,” University of Wisconsin political scientist <a href="https://polisci.wisc.edu/staff/barry-burden-2/">Barry Burden</a> previously told CBS 58, <a href="https://www.cbs58.com/news/do-celebrity-endorsements-matter#:~:text=Overall%20the%20research%20and%20history,all%20solution%2C%E2%80%9D%20Paleologes%20said.">a regional affiliate in Wisconsin</a>. “So everyone participating is essentially a Democrat or sympathetic to a Democrat and that’s where an endorsement could really matter.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That case study, though, shows how a prominent celebrity could wield their cachet. Less powerful celebrities, meanwhile, still have the potential to have a narrower impact. They might strengthen a candidate’s connection with a specific age group or demographic, they could help drive people to turn out, and they could get more people to contribute their money.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you suddenly see it in your social media feed or on TikTok or wherever, and see your favorite celebrity has done an interview or had a conversation with a politician, that politician is much more likely to get traction just by having that entry into people’s attention spans,” <a href="https://www.nulondon.ac.uk/faculty/josephine-harmon/">Josephine Harmon</a>, an assistant professor of political science at Northeastern University in London, previously told <a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2024/07/10/celebrity-election-endorsements/">Northeastern Global News</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A Megan Thee Stallion endorsement could bolster Harris’s credibility among her listeners and add to her appeal given the singer’s popularity and clout. A fan who was already leaning Democrat could also be motivated to register to vote, or attend a rally, because of her endorsement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That was likely the case with endorsements like those made by Taylor Swift in 2018 and 2020. In 2018, Swift <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/02/01/taylor-swift-endorsement-00139033">endorsed</a> Tennessee Democratic Senate candidate Phil Bredesen, and emphasized why she opposed then-Republican Senate candidate Marsha Blackburn due to her votes on the Violence Against Women Act and her stance against marriage equality. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/09/voter-registrations-skyrocket-after-taylor-swift-instagram-post.html">Following Swift’s 2018 post</a>, 65,000 people between the ages of 18 to 29 registered to vote, according to Vote.org, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/09/voter-registrations-skyrocket-after-taylor-swift-instagram-post.html">an uptick the nonprofit attributed to her post,</a> noting that it may have galvanized people to get involved who wouldn’t have otherwise.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Overall, celebrities would like to think they could influence voter behavior, but they are more valuable as fundraising tools and door-opening opportunities to their followers,” <a href="https://www.suffolk.edu/academics/faculty/d/a/david-paleologos">David Paleologos</a>, director of the Suffolk University Political Research Center, <a href="https://www.cbs58.com/news/do-celebrity-endorsements-matter#:~:text=Overall%20the%20research%20and%20history,all%20solution%2C%E2%80%9D%20Paleologes%20said.">told CBS 58</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a close election like this one — <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/president-general/2024/national/">538’s polling average</a> puts Harris less than 2 percentage points ahead of Trump nationally, as of Wednesday — celebrities, and such marginal gains, could nonetheless be important. “Even though the effects are generally thought of as modest, in elections that turn on a small number of votes in a handful of swing states, any effect could be significant,” Jackson told Vox.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[You need a budget. But do you really need to pay for one?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/365747/best-budgeting-app-mint-replacement-ynab" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365747</id>
			<updated>2024-08-08T14:40:42Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Personal Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s never a bad time to think about budgeting your money, but one could argue that the week of a stock market meltdown and renewed anxiety of a recession is the best time. That’s where we are this week. So let’s talk about budgeting. A few months ago, I stumbled across an app called YNAB. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="An illustration of a person patching an elephant-sized, cracked piggy bank. " data-caption="YNAB started out as a spreadsheet 20 years ago and now has a massive online fan base." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1440470720.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>YNAB started out as a spreadsheet 20 years ago and now has a massive online fan base.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s never a bad time to think about budgeting your money, but one could argue that the week of <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed">a stock market meltdown</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/06/business/economy/recession-markets-stocks.html">renewed anxiety of a recession</a> is the best time. That’s where we are this week. So let’s talk about budgeting.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A few months ago, I stumbled across an app called YNAB. The name stands for You Need a Budget, and <a href="https://qz.com/1710081/ynab-has-the-most-devoted-following-of-any-budgeting-app">it’s fiercely popular</a> with a certain set of personal finance enthusiasts on Reddit.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With over 190,000 members, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ynab">the YNAB subreddit</a> is in the top 1 percent of popular subreddits — it’s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/best/communities/11/#t5_2vqaa/">about as popular, for example, as the surfing subreddit</a>. It’s not just Reddit, either. YNAB has 581,000 followers <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ynabofficial?lang=en">on TikTok</a>, 208,000 followers <a href="https://www.instagram.com/youneedabudget/?hl=en">on Instagram</a>, and 141,000 subscribers <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@YNABofficial">on YouTube</a>. This is all for a budgeting <em>app</em>, mind you.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So I downloaded YNAB with high hopes. It took quite a while to get through the complicated setup, which involved linking my bank accounts to it, and start allocating sums of money for absolutely every expense in my life, from rent to diapers. Then I realized that, after a 34-day free trial, the app costs money.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Starting August 1, YNAB even raised its prices from $99 a year to $109 a year. Many of those hundreds of thousands of personal finance enthusiasts <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ynab/comments/1dtnhgg/megathread_discuss_the_price_increase_here/">are not happy about this change</a>, by the way. Some said they were going back to Excel, which is what I have been doing for years. Still, that’s a lot of people who are excited about personal finance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What a great place to be,” Scott Ward, senior vice president and wealth adviser for Compound Planning, told me. “We’ve gone from an environment where people were reticent to really even think about budgeting, to using spreadsheets, and now wanting to have an active interest in seeing their money work for them on a daily basis.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The concept of connecting your bank account to an app that will tell you how much you should spend and save has actually been around for a couple of decades. It went mainstream in the late aughts with the rise in popularity of Mint, a free budgeting website and app that was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/11/2/23943254/mint-intuit-shutting-down-credit-karma">shut down earlier this year</a> by its new owner Credit Karma. And when Mint shut down in March, millions of users scrambled to find a good replacement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even though YNAB isn’t free, it’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/your-money/mint-budgeting-app-alternatives.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">one of several apps</a> that are filling that void. All of them can track your spending, automate your savings, and generally make you feel better about your financial health. Most of them cost money, while you can make a spreadsheet in Google Drive for free.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Budgeting is inevitably a very personal thing. If you don’t have one at all, however, the best budget for you is any budget at all. Inflation has slowed but is not gone. The economy is feeling <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/us/us-recession-worries-surge-again-what-is-data-2024-08-06/">a little shaky</a> right now, although it <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2024/06/us-economy-excellent/678630/">technically remains quite strong</a>. And like I said before, there’s never a bad time to pay attention to your money.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>So, you need a budget</strong>.</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Behind many of these apps is usually a budgeting philosophy that’s been around for over 50 years. It’s <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/finance/zero-based-budgeting-explained">called zero-based budgeting</a>. Developed <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/meet-the-father-of-zero-based-budgeting-1427415074">by Peter Pyhrr</a> when he was a young accountant at Texas Instruments in the early 1970s, this method directs you to start your budget from scratch, or “zero base,” every month and assign a purpose to every dollar you <em>must </em>spend in your budget. That means accounting for recurring costs like rent and bills as well as essentials like housing and groceries. It also leaves room to budget for longer-term goals like savings and paying off debt.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The system is also designed to be dynamic since not every month of the year is the same. If you’ve heard of <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/envelope-budgeting-system-5208026">the “envelope system,”</a> when you set aside cash for each expense at the start of the month, this is the same idea. Other systems include <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/022916/what-502030-budget-rule.asp">the 50/30/20 rule</a>, which was popularized by the progressive Massachusetts Senator Elizabeth Warren, and <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/p/payyourselffirst.asp">the “pay yourself first” method</a>, which focuses on building a retirement or emergency fund. My own budgeting spreadsheet ended up being based on the zero-base budgeting strategy, although I didn’t even know what that strategy was when I built it for myself a few years ago. The method is just that intuitive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">YNAB started out as a spreadsheet, too. In 2004, an accounting grad student named Jesse Mecham <a href="https://www.ynab.com/blog/the-ynab-origin-story">built the first version of the spreadsheet</a> to track his family’s finances and, with the help of a developer, built a desktop app a couple years later, before launching the first YNAB mobile app in 2015.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mecham pushed these four rules from the start: give every dollar a job, embrace true expenses, roll with the punches, and age your money. The first three are fairly self-explanatory. The last one about aging your money, however, is designed to help you break out of the pay-check-to-pay-check lifestyle and delay the time when you receive your money to when you actually spend it. In other words, the longer you hold onto your money and avoid spending like it’s an emergency, the more likely you are to make smarter decisions. Keeping more money around will also give you a bit of a cushion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I want people to take the fear out of the money conversation,” YNAB CEO Todd Curtis said in an interview. “We all spend, and imagine if you could do it confidently. Imagine if you could do it without second-guessing. Imagine if you could talk about it with your partner without real dread about walking into that conversation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the years, people <a href="https://qz.com/1710081/ynab-has-the-most-devoted-following-of-any-budgeting-app">have become obsessed with this system</a>. But YNAB <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/your-money/mint-budgeting-app-alternatives.html?partner=slack&amp;smid=sl-share">isn’t the only app</a> pushing the zero-based budgeting approach. <a href="https://www.wsj.com/buyside/personal-finance/banking/monarch-money-review">Monarch Money is a popular option</a> that automatically categorizes your spending, tracks your investments, and gives family members access to the budget. (YNAB <a href="https://www.ynab.com/blog/introducing-ynab-together-for-your-shared-financial-journey">has its own version of family access</a>.) Monarch Money also costs $100 a year. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/banking/pocketguard-budgeting-app-review/">PocketGuard is a beginner-friendly app</a> that offers some zero-based budgeting features. There’s a free tier with limited functionality or a premium version for $75 a year. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/banking/copilot-budget-app-review/">Copilot uses artificial intelligence</a> to categorize expenses and creates adaptive budgets for you. So it’s kind of like a robotic zero-based budgeting system and costs $95 a year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re not convinced the zero-based budgeting method is for you, there are a variety of different approaches represented in these recommendations for more budget apps <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/11/your-money/mint-budgeting-app-alternatives.html">here</a>, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/buyside/personal-finance/financial-tips/best-budgeting-methods">here</a>, and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/banking/best-budgeting-apps/">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">But you don’t want to pay for a budget. Now what?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It costs money to manage your money with the help of a good app. That comes with some benefits. You’re paying for something that’s easier to use than a free Google Drive spreadsheet, and you’re paying for the convenience of having your bank accounts, including all of your transactions, synced with the app instead of needing to manually add every expense yourself. You’re also paying for security, so that hackers don’t get their hands on your financial info.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the way, if you use a free budgeting tool, there’s a chance the company making it <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/1/29/21111848/free-software-privacy-alternative-data">is selling your data to data brokers</a>. (Here’s <a href="https://money.usnews.com/money/personal-finance/articles/how-safe-are-budget-tracking-apps">a great rundown</a> of how privacy and security work in these apps, and what to look out for.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But sometimes the most compelling free option out there is the trusty spreadsheet. After all, if one of the leading budgeting apps started out as a spreadsheet, why not get back to basics?</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">One surprising thing:</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The internet is awash with budgeting apps of all kinds. If paying for a budgeting app isn’t for you, and you don’t want to give your personal financial data to a free app, you can always import a free budgeting spreadsheet. Jon Wittwer, founder of the Excel template library Vertex42, offers up this roadmap for starting from scratch. It’s surprisingly easy:</p>



<ol>
<li>Start by tracking your expenses with <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/income-and-expense-worksheet.html">this simple spreadsheet</a>.</li>



<li>Use <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/excel-checkbook.html">a check register</a> or <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/account-register.html#google_vignette">an account register</a> to keep track of transactions.</li>



<li>Build a spending plan with this <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/personal-budget-spreadsheet.html">personal budget spreadsheet</a>.</li>



<li>Try to make every dollar count with <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/personal-budget-spreadsheet.html">this zero-based budgeting worksheet</a>.</li>



<li>When you’re ready, put everything into <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/money-management-template.html">a master money management template</a>.</li>
</ol>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you DIY your budget, the bonus is a system that’s better tailored to your needs than even the best and priciest apps could ever be. The drawback is that it can become a huge time suck. Trust me. I’ve resorted to tracking everything on a Google Drive spreadsheet of my own making, and it’s practically turned into a hobby. My spreadsheet isn’t particularly complicated, but it’s highly customized to my particular situation. When my wife and I got married and combined finances, it got a big overhaul, and that happened once again when we had a baby.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But along the way, I’m paying close attention on a weekly if not daily basis. It’s almost like a problem that I can never solve, but the process of simply trying — adding transactions here, reallocating funds there — calms me down. The time I spend in my clunky spreadsheet relieves some of my anxiety about family finances. It’s still time I’m not doing other things.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The main downside to most budgeting and money management spreadsheets is that they do not automatically import transactions from bank accounts,” Jon Wittwer, founder of <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/budgets.html">Vertex42</a>, which offers a wide range of free spreadsheet templates. “Importing transactions is the number one reason why I still use an app for my own finances.” Wittwer added that he still uses a combination of apps and spreadsheets to manage his business.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You’re also not entirely alone if you do decide to create your own system. Much like its budgeting app counterpart, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/personalfinance/comments/boza0g/i_made_a_spreadsheet_for_people_who_dont_know_how/">the budgeting spreadsheet community is active</a> and always coming up <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/personalfinance/comments/z378v4/updated_2023_simple_budget_spreadsheet/">with innovations</a> on this tried and tested way of tracking your expenses.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Completely free options do exist, and they’re so ubiquitous that the only real challenge is finding one that fits your needs. <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1YlGTsomx1Y47jdc9HMdV4iVLP9vtZEcNJZQWHLTc1jk/edit?gid=0#gid=0">Google</a> and <a href="https://create.microsoft.com/en-us/templates/budgets">Microsoft</a> have their own libraries of free budget spreadsheets that are very simple but customizable. I’ve also used <a href="https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTemplates/budgets.html">free Excel templates from Vertex42</a> and would recommend them for their sophistication and price of $0. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like I said before, though, budgeting is such a highly personal endeavor. Spreadsheets can be a solitary affair, where you might not know who to ask if you’re looking for a better way to do something. Apps are great, as long as you’re willing to pay a fee, and they can offer some community.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Curtis, the YNAB CEO, told me, “With YNAB, you can turn around to that community and say, ‘Hey, this just happened to me. I’m at this moment. What can I do?’ And you’ve got millions of people there who can help you with that question, because they’ve been there before you.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story was also published in the Vox Technology newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/newsletters"><em><strong>Sign up here</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;so you don’t miss the next one!</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[“Trump is weird” will only get Kamala Harris so far]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365833/trump-harris-walz-weird-2024-election-voters-biden-poll-attack-messaging" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=365833</id>
			<updated>2024-08-07T23:27:38Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent weeks, national Democrats and surrogates for Vice President Kamala Harris have settled on a pretty simple strategy: calling former President Donald Trump, his running mate Sen. J.D. Vance, and MAGA-aligned Republicans “weird.” One of its original purveyors, Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz, used it again Tuesday evening, during his first appearance with Harris as [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Harris and Walz stand in front of a large crowd in a venue lit with blue and white stars and large blue signs that read “Harris-Walz.”" data-caption="Vice President Kamala Harris and Democratic vice presidential candidate Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz appear on stage together during a campaign event on August 6, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Harnik/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2165600543.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Vice President Kamala Harris and Democratic vice presidential candidate Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz appear on stage together during a campaign event on August 6, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. | Andrew Harnik/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent weeks, national Democrats and surrogates for Vice President Kamala Harris have settled on a pretty simple strategy: calling former President Donald Trump, his running mate Sen. J.D. Vance, and MAGA-aligned Republicans “<a href="https://apnews.com/article/kamala-harris-trump-vance-weird-c54d506d1f533ee7aa455f7b500322c5">weird</a>.” One of its original purveyors, Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz, used it again Tuesday evening, during his first appearance with Harris as her running mate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You know it. You feel it. These guys are creepy and, yes, just weird as hell!” Walz said, after telling a joke that played into a meme about <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/363230/jd-vance-couch-sex-hillbilly-elegy-rumor-false">Vance and couches</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Democrats have found plenty of fodder for the tactic, which they’ve used to describe Republican positions on abortion rights and IVF, on the role of parents and biological children, and on an array of other right-wing beliefs.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The attacks may be <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/04/politics/video/jd-vance-weird-polls-impact-enten-digvid">sticking</a> — hardening the preexisting views many Americans have toward Trump, Vance, and the national Republican brand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But they’re no substitute for a forward-looking, positive case in favor of Harris and Walz, according to <a href="https://blueprint2024.com/polling/harris-poll-positive-message-8-8/">new polling</a> conducted by the Democratic firm Blueprint and shared with Vox. What must come next is an effort to define Harris by reintroducing the electorate to her track record before becoming vice president and leaving behind the politics and acrimony of the Trump-Biden era.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://blueprint2024.com/polling/harris-poll-positive-message-8-8/">new report</a> reveals an interesting and slightly counterintuitive sentiment among American voters at this point in the race. Voters are relieved that there is a new option available for them to pick and feel a “breath of fresh air” — but they don’t really know Harris.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Specifically, beyond hearing attacks on Trump and Vance, they want to hear a positive, uplifting platform from Harris. They are ready for optimism, to hear why she wants to be president, and — even more fundamentally — just learn who she is. Plenty of voters have heard of the vice president, but many don’t know much about her past, her accomplishments, and her life experience, Blueprint’s chief pollster Evan Roth Smith told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“People really want to know who Kamala Harris is, and people are interested in finding out more about her. That is part of the atmospheric shift that’s taken place in this race,” Smith said. “There’s a lot more interest in hearing Kamala Harris and her campaign talk about Kamala Harris — more so than there is in hearing her talk about Donald Trump, or even Joe Biden.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Blueprint, a center-left firm, has been conducting these kinds of polling experiments for the last year, questioning conventional wisdom and digging deeper on the subgroups of voters and kinds of questions that other big national polls don’t frequently ask. They’ve zeroed in on young voters, on what Americans know about Cabinet members, and how voters view specific policies.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Smith and his team have some messaging recommendations for the Harris campaign, and a handful of specific life facts and career highlights from her biography that they found resonate particularly well with voters, but they all underscore one central theme: voter perceptions of Harris are a lot more fluid and changeable than they are of Trump, suggesting there’s not that much of an upside to dedicating time, energy, and messaging to attacking Trump, and especially not when compared to spending those resources talking herself up.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That dynamic suggests that there are limits to criticizing Trump and making fun of Vance. Most voters, including persuadable swing voters and independents, want to know about Harris’s background and are interested in a substantive, forward-looking pitch. And specifically when talking about immigration, independents are curious about how Harris would address their joint desires for border security and immigration reform.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Harris and Walz begin to barnstorm battleground states ahead of the Democratic National Convention later this month, she has a limited window to define herself and make a positive case to voters. And while her campaign has been riding high since its late-July launch, the Harris honeymoon likely won’t last forever.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris has the advantage of being unburdened by what has been</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are two sets of numbers in Blueprint’s poll that explain the opportunity Harris has right now: the share of voters who say that their minds are absolutely made up on the candidates, and the share who say they could be persuaded to change their opinions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Trump, 71 percent of registered voters say “there is absolutely nothing” that could change their opinions of him. Just 57 percent say the same about Harris. And when asked if they would be open to changing their mind or would want to learn more about a candidate, just 12 percent of respondents felt that way about Trump, compared to the 20 percent who said that about Harris.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though neither is particularly popular, Harris is still viewed more favorably than Trump: 46 percent have a favorable view of her compared to 43 percent for Trump. A larger share of respondents say they have an “extremely” favorable or unfavorable view of the former president (64 percent) than the share who have “extreme” opinions about Harris (53 percent).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Smith, that suggests there is more room for voters to change or form an opinion about Harris than Trump.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This difference in strong opinions about Harris may help explain another of the poll’s counterintuitive results: Many voters don’t blame Harris for the unpopular parts of the Biden presidency and trust her more than President Joe Biden on specific issues, like protecting abortion and reproductive rights.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Don’t tell people about the last four years. People have complicated, often unfavorable, views of Democratic governance over the last four years, and they do not yet tie her to some of the perceived failures of the Biden administration,” Smith said. There’s also a downside to talking about Trump and defending Biden: Doing so could remind people Harris was around during that time as well.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To investigate where Harris <em>should</em> be talking about the last four years, Smith and his team asked voters to identify whether Biden, Harris, or both of them were responsible for an array of specific policy issues. Those include increasing access to abortion, reducing crime, addressing past surges on the southern border, and providing aid to Israel and Ukraine. Biden, specifically, is seen as more responsible for politically damaging issues like the US withdrawal from Afghanistan and inflation, though he also receives credit for attempts at widespread student loan cancellation. Harris, meanwhile, was most credited for her work on abortion access, reducing border crossings, and helping to pass the codification of marriage equality.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“On these big, salient issues — the economy, inflation, and immigration — she should define herself outside of the last four years and very, very, very carefully cherry-pick items from the Biden years to be associated with,” Smith told me. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, Harris and her campaign would be smart to “lead with her personal background, who she is, where she’s from, and her role as prosecutor, as California’s attorney general, as someone who enforced the law, and put criminals, particularly criminals related to transnational crime, behind bars.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Harris has some weak spots on immigration and the economy</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Blueprint survey also tested a variety of Republican attacks on Harris and hypothetical Democratic defenses. It found that a combination of facts about Harris’s background and work on the issues were more convincing to voters than the default Democratic response of calling something a “Republican lie” or attacking Trump as an existential threat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This dynamic was particularly notable when looking at how to respond to the Republican attacks that resonate the most with voters, including Harris’s role in addressing immigration (think of the attacks calling her a failed “<a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/361635/kamala-harris-border-czar-immigration-mexico-guatemala-rnc">border czar</a>”) and the rise in inflation during the first few years of the Biden presidency. As tested in the poll, both GOP arguments were compelling to voters. More than half of voters said they found the “border czar” argument very or somewhat convincing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the best Democratic rebuttal Blueprint tested turned out to not be based on debunking the false claims, such as by pointing out that Harris was not a border czar or responsible for the border. Instead, saying that she could be both tough on the border — because of her background prosecuting transnational gangs and drug smugglers — and compassionate to migrants — because her parents’ immigration stories gave her hope for humane and sensible reforms to the immigration system — proved the most effective.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, criticisms about inflation, the price of goods, and the economy in general — that Biden and Harris “let government spending get out of control and let companies rip us off on everything from gas to groceries,” as the poll puts it —  were convincing to half of respondents, with 33 percent finding that “very convincing” and 17 percent finding it “somewhat” convincing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those attacks were best rebutted not by pointing out facts about the growing GDP, the laws passed in the last few years, or the low rate of unemployment, as had been Biden’s approach. Instead, talking up a populist economic message, of going after price gouging, capping drug prices, cutting junk fees, and taxing the rich was more convincing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those two lines of attack are significantly more effective than the path that Trump, Vance, and other Republicans seem to have taken in the last few weeks: calling Harris a DEI hire, criticizing her lack of biological children, or attacking her racial identity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Those test way at the bottom for Republicans. They are barking up the wrong tree,” Smith said. But the responses that work best to those attacks are the more traditional anti-Trump response: getting a bit personal, comparing Trump’s past affairs and divorces against Harris’s family, and calling Trump and Vance “weird” for caring so much about how she runs her family.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similarly, responding to the DEI and identity politics attacks with lines about how “Trump and the Republicans are desperate to distract voters from their extreme Project 2025 agenda” does better, but not <em>that</em> much better than essentially just calling Trump and Republicans racists.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What the voters want to hear instead</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Candidates only get so much time to get their message across in an election. That’s particularly true for the Harris campaign, with the vice president getting a historically late start to a presidential bid. And as the summer passes by, the fall stretch of the election will be especially valuable, as that’s when a lot of casual voters tune in for the first time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because of that time constraint, there’s an opportunity cost to any line of messaging: The investments Harris makes in promoting her own record come at the expense of making the case that Trump is unfit for office.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the polling suggests that the trade-off is worth it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond talking about Trump and Biden, registered voters seem to want to hear most about Harris’s career in California. In some experiments Blueprint ran, biographical facts about her time as a prosecutor, as attorney general of California, and as a US senator resonated with voters, as well as her experience growing up in a middle-class neighborhood.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So did telling voters about her work prosecuting sex traffickers and jailing abusers, securing a billion-dollar settlement for people scammed by for-profit colleges, and suing BP for the Deepwater Horizon oil spill. And they liked hearing a tangible platform: protecting Social Security and Medicare, lowering costs, protecting those with preexisting health conditions, and protecting abortion rights. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That tangible platform has yet to be fully articulated. Harris is just two weeks into a campaign that she had to assemble from the wreckage of Biden’s own reelection effort. And she has hinted at some priorities during her stump speeches, including protecting entitlement programs and reproductive rights, investing in the care economy, and fighting inflation. She still has time to define a more unified governing agenda — but her newest rallying cry is a good start: “We’re not going back.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is what people are the most excited about when they hear about [her]: a mix of ‘I was attorney general, and that allowed me to a) go after bad guys and b) go after bad guys who are coming over the border, and c) go after the big companies who are ripping you off’,” Smith said. “It avoids reminding people too much about the past four years, it avoids having to say the name Joe Biden too much, and now she can introduce herself to voters without strengthening that association.”All together, Blueprint’s findings offer a logical next step for the campaign as the thrill of the honeymoon period ends and as disengaged voters begin to tune into the election. Up until now, the 2024 election has seemed to be mostly about the vibes. But the vibes <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365148/kamala-harris-trump-polls-election-2024">won’t stay positive forever</a>. It might be smart to make the most of them now.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jishnu.Guha-Majumdar</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Vegans are radical. That’s why we need them.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362321/factory-farming-veganism-animal-rights-movement-meat" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=362321</id>
			<updated>2024-08-07T15:45:53Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-08T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Animal Welfare" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future of Meat" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Despite decades of advocacy, vegans and veganism remain deeply unpopular, even detested. Many influential animal activists are now debating a question that would have once seemed absurd: Is it worth the movement’s precious time and resources to keep advocating for meatless diets, an apparently lost cause? Although people define veganism in different ways, it fundamentally [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Mark Harris for Vox; Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/MarkHarris_Vox_Veganism.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite decades of advocacy, vegans and veganism remain deeply unpopular, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/11/2/18055532/vegans-vegetarian-research-uk">even detested</a>. Many influential animal activists are now debating a question that would have once seemed absurd: Is it worth the movement’s precious time and resources to keep advocating for meatless diets, an apparently lost cause?</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">One surprising thing</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">The share of Americans who are vegetarian or vegan is incredibly hard to measure accurately. But one thing is clear: It hasn’t changed much in recent decades, and <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/510038/identify-vegetarian-vegan.aspx">may have even decreased</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>This piece is part of </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/364288/how-factory-farming-ends-animal-rights-vegans-climate-ethics"><strong>How Factory Farming Ends</strong></a><strong>, a collection of stories on the past and future of the long fight against factory farming.</strong> This series is supported by Animal Charity Evaluators, which received a grant from Builders Initiative.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although people define veganism in <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s41055-020-00081-6">different ways</a>, it fundamentally entails avoiding all animal products to the greatest extent possible, including meat, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/352359/milk-dairy-schools">dairy</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23588340/egg-prices-expensive-bird-flu-shortage-price-gouging">eggs</a>, but also non-dietary products like <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24008053/wool-marketing-environment-sustainable-claims-sheep-animal-cruelty-fast-fashion">wool</a> and <a href="https://www.peta.org/issues/animals-used-for-clothing/leather-industry/">leather</a>. Whereas the more commonly practiced vegetarianism only rejects meat consumption, the vegan movement generally rejects the property status of animals and aims to fully divest from animal cruelty and exploitation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vegans are often considered <a href="https://www.ivu.org/history/vegan-from-1909.pdf">too extreme</a>, especially in a meat-obsessed country like the US — a perception that persists despite the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/company/press/plant-based-foods-market-to-hit-162-billion-in-next-decade-projects-bloomberg-intelligence/">growing popularity</a> of vegan products. The famed late chef Anthony Bourdain once <a href="https://openlibrary.org/books/OL19290065M/Kitchen_confidential">compared</a> vegans to Hezbollah, declaring them “the enemy of everything good and decent in the human spirit.” His aversion seems representative of the public’s feelings. One 2015 <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1368430215618253">study</a> found that, in the United States, negative attitudes toward vegans rivaled those toward atheists.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These social headwinds are making veganism unpopular even among influential voices in the animal movement. Matt Ball, who co-founded the advocacy group <a href="https://veganoutreach.org/">Vegan Outreach</a> in the 1990s but has since changed his tune on the strategic necessity of promoting animal-free diets, has <a href="https://www.mattball.org/2017/05/how-vegans-hurt-animals.html">argued</a> that the “‘vegan’ brand is damaged beyond repair.” Bruce Friedrich — founder of the Good Food Institute, a nonprofit that seeks to develop alternative proteins that do not require animal slaughter — has made a moderated version of a similar claim. In a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/03/12/technology/bruce-friedrich-animal-activist.html">2019 interview</a>, he lamented that “we’ve tried to convince the world to go vegan, and it has not worked.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The percentage of Americans who are vegan or vegetarian remains small, though it is a notoriously difficult figure to pin down. This minute figure, juxtaposed with the <a href="https://www.nationalchickencouncil.org/about-the-industry/statistics/per-capita-consumption-of-poultry-and-livestock-1965-to-estimated-2012-in-pounds/">clearly documented increase</a> in US per-capita meat consumption, suggests veganism seems to be failing. For Friedrich and others, this failure to affect dietary habits signals a need to shift animal advocacy’s emphasis toward larger-scale policy and technological innovations, like <a href="https://gfi.org/cultivated/">cell-cultivated (sometimes known as lab-grown) meat</a>, that can reduce the number of animals slaughtered for food in the absence of dietary change. It also requires that pro-animal advocates tone down their dogmatism, abandon the quest for purity, and compromise more with large corporations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I suspect that at least some aspects of this weariness resonate with large swathes of people who advocate for animal rights or are sympathetic to their plight: the warning against dogmatism and a call for nuance, a healthy skepticism toward individualism and consumerism, and the sense that <em>something </em>is better than nothing, even if that something is less radical than we’d like. Indeed, on its own, even the strictest veganism can feel like a minuscule choice against the onslaught of the factory farming death machine, which tortures and kills more than <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24079424/factory-farming-facts-meat-usda-agriculture-census">10 billion land animals</a> annually in the US alone. Why spend so much energy convincing people to undertake such a massive life change if it seems akin to using a bucket to bail water out of a sinking cruise liner?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While I sympathize with these sentiments, I worry that they miss the promise and radical force of veganism: It can be an act of <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/10455752.2020.1837895">solidarity</a> with <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/josp.12460">nonhuman animals</a>. Veganism takes the recognition that animals are sentient beings with lives of their own and infuses it into one’s body and everyday practice. In a world that relies on extracting the literal lifeblood of nonhuman animals, that depends on externalizing the costs of “progress” onto them and distributing the benefits to privileged humans, veganism refuses to pass the buck. It is a way of “saying” to nonhumans, non-verbally and without the promise that the message will be received: <em>The world has turned against you, depends on your flesh and bone. But we will not. We refuse.</em></p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/CoeVegansDefend.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,28.335439610038,100,43.329120779924" alt="black-and-white linocut drawing of a large crowd of people with linked arms, labeled “VEGANS,” standing in front of a cow and calf, while a man representing the meat industry stands in front of them holding a knife and money bag with blood dripping from it. " title="black-and-white linocut drawing of a large crowd of people with linked arms, labeled “VEGANS,” standing in front of a cow and calf, while a man representing the meat industry stands in front of them holding a knife and money bag with blood dripping from it. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="“Vegans Defend” (2016) by Sue Coe. | © 2016 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York" data-portal-copyright="© 2016 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This exhortation has profound implications for the animal movement’s future direction. Animal advocates have often been <a href="https://faunalytics.org/abolitionism-and-welfarism-two-animal-advocacy-perspectives/">mired in debate</a> over which tactics are the best use of our time, and which ones meaningfully help animals instead of creating a “<a href="https://www.vox.com/22838160/animal-welfare-labels-meat-dairy-eggs-humane-humanewashing">humanewashing</a>” smokescreen. Promoting veganism need not be the movement’s only or primary strategy, but it should remain its heartbeat. After all, if we’re not committed to fighting for a world free from animal exploitation, then what exactly is the movement fighting for? Veganism as solidarity provides a core commitment and standard that can help set movement priorities.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Society enlists us into war against animals</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The strategic case against veganism largely depends on the claim that the percentage of Americans who have gone vegetarian or vegan remains minute — perhaps <a href="https://animalcharityevaluators.org/blog/is-the-percentage-of-vegetarians-and-vegans-in-the-u-s-increasing/">as low as 2 percent</a> — and has not appreciably increased in decades. But there are more optimistic ways to read the data. Communications scholar Vasile Stanescu <a href="https://www.criticalanimal.com/2019/07/guest-post-response-to-claim-that-only.html">argued</a> in 2019 that rates of vegetarianism and veganism in the US <em>have</em> increased, to somewhere between 8 and 13 percent. Even if his figure proves an overestimate — no peer-reviewed work, to my knowledge, exists to settle the question — it seems unwise to throw away a pillar of animal rights when we aren’t even sure of the numbers. One must also consider the counterfactual: How high might meat consumption be if consumers faced a firehose of industry-sponsored, pro-meat messaging without a pro-vegan counterbalance?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, one might argue, it makes little sense to invest scarce resources on promoting veganism without evidence of a clear and measurable impact. This objection makes a lot of sense if we understand veganism as primarily a consequentialist, consumer-oriented approach, of “voting with your dollar.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But reframing veganism as solidarity encourages advocates to think beyond quantifiable market consequences (though these effects are still <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/7/31/9067651/eggs-chicken-effective-altruism">relevant</a>). Put differently, veganism matters not only because of its economic divestment from animal exploitation, but also because of its less quantifiable <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/josp.12460">political</a> effects. Going vegan builds political energy and connections with other humans invested in animal liberation and with the animals that vegans recognize as sentient and social creatures. It builds glimpses of a desired future in the present.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps most importantly, solidaristic veganism acknowledges that in today’s world, after centuries of humans’ intense exploitation of animals, it’s nearly impossible to have an ethical relationship with animals without addressing the most direct ways that most people benefit from the destruction of animal life. Animals are not simply mistreated beings. Rather, society is organized around slaughtering, torturing, and dominating animals, as a class, on a massive scale.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A brief look at the statistics evinces this claim: Globally, an additional <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/how-many-animals-are-factory-farmed#note-1">70 billion</a> land animals are killed for food on top of the US’s 10 billion. Factory-farmed fish, which are harder to count, may add more than 100 billion. Habitat destruction, primarily driven by <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22287498/meat-wildlife-biodiversity-species-plantbased">industrial animal farming</a>, is snowballing out of control. Tens of millions, maybe hundreds of millions, of animals are <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2022/12/11/23500157/neuralink-animal-testing-elon-musk-usda-probe">held captive and experimented on</a> in scientific labs. Even dogs and cats, perceived as the most pampered animals in America, are still <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2023/4/11/23673393/pets-dogs-cats-animal-welfare-boredom">legal property</a>, living largely at the whims of whoever happens to own them (not to mention the <a href="https://www.aspca.org/helping-people-pets/shelter-intake-and-surrender/pet-statistics">6 million in shelters</a>, nearly 1 million of whom are killed annually, partly due to the pet breeding industry).</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>To become politically vegan is to become a conscientious objector </p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another way of framing this dire state of affairs, as the social theorist Dinesh Wadiwel <a href="https://brill.com/display/title/32110?language=en">does</a>, is that the world acts as if it is at war with animals. Not all humans are equally to blame for the atrocities of this war, but living in and benefitting from a society that, as a rule, marks animals for torture and death, changes the nature of one’s responsibility. For Wadiwel, veganism offers a “truce” to animals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can extend this war framework a step further: To become politically vegan is to become a conscientious objector.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Think about those who became conscientious objectors in the face of being drafted for the Vietnam War. Those who refused conscription could claim conscientious objector status only if participating in the war conflicted with their deeply held beliefs, and not merely because they had a self-interest in not being killed. Depriving the military of one soldier was not going to change the course of the war, but conscientious objection had other effects: It made private opposition public, it broke the facade of a uniform pro-war consensus, and it <a href="https://engagedscholarship.csuohio.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=4078&amp;context=clevstlrev">provided a rallying point</a> for further political action. Objectors in the 1960s and ’70s became part of <a href="https://www.history.com/news/anti-war-movements-throughout-american-history">the largest anti-war movement</a> in US history.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/CoeMyMotherIWatchPigEscapeFromSlaughterhouse_159118.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,32.493455497382,100,35.013089005236" alt="Painting of a slaughterhouse filled with stressed-looking farm animals of various species and workers preparing to slaughter them. A woman and daughter stand near the entrance as a pig runs toward them attempting to flee. " title="Painting of a slaughterhouse filled with stressed-looking farm animals of various species and workers preparing to slaughter them. A woman and daughter stand near the entrance as a pig runs toward them attempting to flee. " data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="“My Mother and I Watch a Pig Escape from the Slaughterhouse” (2006) by Sue Coe. | © 2006 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York" data-portal-copyright="© 2006 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, imagine that you were talking to a conscientious objector and said: “The data is against you. Very few people want to become conscientious objectors. You are only alienating people, and your refusal to serve is just a drop in the bucket compared to the military’s power. Perhaps you should try more moderate steps first.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To say this would be to misunderstand the goal of conscientious objection. Anti-vegan critics have a similar misapprehension. The world “conscripts” us in its war against animals in the way it structures our choices when we buy clothes, food, and other necessities whose production depends on violence against animals. To become vegan is not only to try to prevent some animal death and exploitation, but to build political opposition to our forced participation in this war.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The false binary of purity vs. pragmatism</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Veganism is sometimes strawmanned as a kind of purity politics that only benefits sanctimonious activists. It’s true that being purely cruelty-free is impossible: <a href="https://extension.oregonstate.edu/news/heres-scoop-chemical-organic-fertilizers">organic fertilizers</a> use animal products, <a href="https://extension.arizona.edu/sites/extension.arizona.edu/files/pubs/az1481i.pdf">pesticides harm many animals</a>, and large-scale plant farming generally kills and displaces animals (<a href="https://sentientmedia.org/does-veganism-kill-more-animals/">though not anywhere near as many as animal agriculture</a>). Similarly, by analogy, becoming an anti-war conscientious objector does not wash one’s hands of all complicity; even paying taxes abets the war effort.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But framing veganism as an act of solidarity can shatter the false binary between purity and pragmatism. There are uses for the public rigor that solidarity demands that go beyond purity. It punctures the smooth surface of everyday life, putting its everyday violence in view.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider a scenario Friedrich presents in an older piece of writing, where a vegan dines with omnivorous companions at a restaurant with limited vegan options. <a href="https://mercyforanimals.org/essays-effective-advocacy/">For Friedrich</a>, if “you give the server the third degree about the ingredients or about how it was cooked, you are forgetting the essence of being vegan” because you make veganism seem more difficult to others at the table.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I certainly agree that one shouldn’t give underpaid servers a hard time, but not with the scenario’s underlying respectability politics. Yes, veganism may seem more difficult, but demonstrating this difficulty <a href="https://www.academia.edu/9132254/Vegan_Killjoys_at_the_Table_Contesting_Happiness_and_Negotiating_Relationships_with_Food_Practices">highlights the gap</a> between what the world is willing to provide and what justice demands. Perhaps your tablemates will be put off by this demonstration, but perhaps the situation provides the opportunity for a conversation that would not have occurred if you simply smoothed over the issue. Perhaps they will admire your willingness to stick to your principles even when it’s inconvenient. Perhaps they are more likely to pay attention when vegan options are available.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fundamental point is that politics is not only about calm, rational persuasion and consensus-building. It can also be purposefully oppositional, concerned with <a href="https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=33817&amp;bottom_ref=subject">dissensus and agonistic conflict</a>. The great non-violence movements of the 20th century were not primarily focused on easing their opponents to their side but on raising the costs of the status quo via boycotts, sit-ins, and disruptive<em> </em>marches.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From this perspective, if the numbers of vegans truly are small, that is not in itself a cause for worry. Popularity is not the only goal of a movement that seeks to disrupt the public’s “common sense.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How solidarity with animals can inform movement tactics (and it’s not just advocating for veganism) </h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This perspective on veganism’s politics affects the movement’s strategy in two ways. First, veganism should remain a core principle. That is not to say that it should be the only strategy: I agree with the need to experiment with different tactics and to focus beyond shifting individual people’s beliefs toward changing social and industrial infrastructures with innovations like “clean meat” and policies that limit animal mistreatment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But solidaristic acts like veganism serve as the “political fuel” necessary for broader changes to policy and cultural norms, philosophers Alasdair Cochrane and Mara-Daria Cojocaru <a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/solidarity-with-animals-9780198897941?cc=us&amp;lang=en&amp;">argue</a>. The political will for new vegan technologies and anti-cruelty policies does not come miraculously from the ether but requires building a critical mass of people committed to a world without animal exploitation.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Solidaristic acts like veganism serve as the “political fuel” necessary for broader changes to policy and cultural norms</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Second, veganism as solidarity provides a lens through which to evaluate tactics deployed by the movement, like farm animal welfare laws. For decades, animal advocates have <a href="https://digitalcommons.law.buffalo.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1355&amp;context=journal_articles#:~:text=Part%20I%20discusses%20the%20differences,the%20property%20status%20of%20animals.">argued</a> fiercely over the value of incremental reforms to the factory farm system like, say, banning the most extreme forms of cage confinement. Do these strategies help us end factory farming, or do they merely give a false humane sheen to the killing machine?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Veganism as solidarity provides a rubric by which to evaluate pro-animal reforms: Does the reform in question come out of a place of solidarity with animals, one that may ultimately lead toward abolishing their status as commodities, or does it ultimately enable conditions that undermine the potential for this solidarity?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We can borrow a helpful framework from the prison abolitionist movement: the idea of <a href="https://www.yalelawjournal.org/feature/non-reformist-reforms-and-struggles-over-life-death-and-democracy">non-reformist reforms</a>. Non-reformist reforms help create the conditions for meaningfully shifting the power structure, while reformist reforms may only reify it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, when major animal welfare organizations publicly <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CqbE9EbpTAr/?img_index=3">congratulate </a>(and give free advertising to) large meat producers for signing on to voluntary welfare standards, I question whether this action advances solidarity. True accountability is limited to the corporations themselves, and they get to walk away with a gold star that increases their credibility even as their fundamental business model remains the same. To extend the anti-war analogy, would it be solidarity with the victims of war if Lockheed Martin agreed to use slightly more “humane” methods of war and modern activists went out of their way to congratulate the company?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Further, when activists implore consumers to eat one type of animal rather than another — “<a href="https://www.vox.com/videos/2017/5/27/15701168/save-animal-lives-eat-beef-not-chicken">save animals by eating more beef and less chicken</a>” or “<a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/eating-chicken-instead-beef-will-drastically-reduce-your-carbon-footprint-180972392/">save the environment by eating less beef and more chickens</a>” — they betray that obligation to solidarity. Even work like that of the famed livestock scientist <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/04/14/magazine/temple-grandin-on-autism-death-celibacy-and-cows.html">Temple Grandin</a>, who has <a href="https://www.grandin.com/design/chute.ramp.race.design.html">designed</a> livestock handling systems that reduce animals’ fear and resistance as they walk down a chute to meet a bolt gun, only helps them acquiesce in their oppression and reduces the friction in the meat industry’s slaughter pipeline.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/07/CoeGassingHogs.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,16.985900160697,100,66.028199678607" alt="black-and-white drawing of anguished-looking pigs being gassed before slaughter in a gas chamber. Two slaughterhouse workers in the scene slaughter and hang pigs that have already been gassed" title="black-and-white drawing of anguished-looking pigs being gassed before slaughter in a gas chamber. Two slaughterhouse workers in the scene slaughter and hang pigs that have already been gassed" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="“Gassing Hogs” (2010) by Sue Coe. | © 2010 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York." data-portal-copyright="© 2010 Sue Coe/Courtesy Galerie St. Etienne, New York." />
<p class="has-text-align-none">I feel more sanguine about recent policy victories in which advocates have gotten numerous states, most recently, Nevada, to <a href="https://www.humanesociety.org/blog/breaking-nevada-becomes-9th-state-ban-cages-egg-laying-hens">ban battery cages</a> for chickens. Obviously, these bans don’t challenge the fundamental commodity status of chickens, and chickens deserve far more. But it does <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23588340/egg-prices-expensive-bird-flu-shortage-price-gouging">impose an external cost</a> on the smooth operation of chicken farming, one that the industry would not willingly adopt for itself.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From this standpoint, I am disheartened when I see animal advocates so publicly decry veganism’s supposed failures. Partly because doing so creates a self-fulfilling prophecy — discouraging individuals from going vegan by making it seem like a lost cause from the get-go, as Stanescu <a href="https://www.criticalanimal.com/2019/07/guest-post-response-to-claim-that-only.html">notes</a>. But more fundamentally, it inaccurately frames the present moment. It is not that “promoting veganism has failed, so it is time to move onto new strategies.” Rather: veganism <em>opens</em> <em>the way</em> for these new strategies. The acorn does not negate the value of the oak tree it came from.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Admittedly, solidarity doesn’t provide clean lines that can uncontroversially decide which reforms are or are not permissible. But it hopefully offers more useful criteria than reform for the sake of reform.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The joy of veganism</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I have so far emphasized that veganism has broader, political implications beyond individual behavior change. But the way that <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24131229/vegan-vegetarian-meatless-climate-solutions-recipes-connection">it shapes the lives</a> of individuals who become vegan can be <a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/matthew-c-halteman/hungry-beautiful-animals/9781541602052/?lens=basic-books">extremely powerful</a>, too. Political veganism can better attune advocates as they persuade individuals of the practice’s virtues.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Political scientists have <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2014/12/11/protests-shape-policy-by-shaping-protesters/">observed</a> that political protests change the character of those who protest, even if the protest doesn’t achieve its stated policy goal. If, for example, you attend a protest against a new oil pipeline, what was once an abstract issue on a computer screen becomes alive to you. You learn that you are not alone, and you might find sustenance in community with others who care about climate politics as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Veganism as solidarity can have a similar effect. Abstaining from animal products in a world that disavows animal suffering prevents the vegan from forgetting the character of this world; it puts them into constant confrontation with it every time they go to the grocery store, buy clothes, and commune with others. To rework Upton Sinclair’s famous <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/21810-it-is-difficult-to-get-a-man-to-understand-something">line</a>, it is hard to get a person to think clearly about animals when their everyday life depends on animal slaughter, degradation, and exploitation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9749860/#ref78">One </a><a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0160597616640308?journalCode=hasa">objection</a> to this individual-level view is that veganism privileges those without gastrointestinal or other disabilities and those who can financially afford these restrictions. You may have an image of a vegan eating organic vegetables and overpriced meat substitutes from Whole Foods. While I would note there is evidence suggesting that plant-based diets can <a href="https://theconversation.com/vegan-vegetarian-and-flexitarian-diets-could-save-you-money-new-research-171559">cut food costs</a> in industrialized countries and that survey results find that people with <a href="https://news.gallup.com/file/poll/510047/230824VegetarianVegan.pdf">lower incomes</a> are more likely to be vegan, framing veganism as solidarity offers an alternative way of considering this issue. Calling for solidarity with regard to any cause or campaign entails asking potential allies to undertake some sort of sacrifice, whether that be in terms of money, time, or power. Having the resources to undertake these sacrifices is by nature unequally distributed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The call for solidarity with animals goes out equally to every person, but fulfilling that call may look different for everyone. For those who do not face substantial financial or health barriers, the demands are quite high, in my view. For others, full veganism might be an aspiration, which they fulfill in the present by lowering their animal consumption where possible. This is not an iron-clad, all-or-nothing law. Accidentally consuming animal products, or eating an “emotional-support pastry” in an otherwise vegan diet, is less important in the long scheme of things, because solidarity is a call that can be answered anew each day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Answering this call is not about purist asceticism; it is affirmatively oriented toward building community. It builds new connections that wouldn’t have otherwise existed; it helps you see new ways of being in the world that weren’t there before. It opens you to the joy of being with nonhuman others, of refusing “species loneliness,” what botanist Robin Wall Kimmerer <a href="https://milkweed.org/book/braiding-sweetgrass">describes</a> as “a deep, unnamed sadness stemming from estrangement from the rest of Creation.” You see the world as more enchanted and alive when creatures around you appear as individuals and not interchangeable automatons.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Veganism, thought of in this way, is not the province of dour, dogmatic scolds; it is a practice of joy and creativity that sustains hope for coexistence between species. As Cochrane and Cojocaru <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/josp.12460">write</a>, this sort of solidarity recognizes that “the world in which we live is not the one we must live with forever.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a vision worth fighting for.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
