<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-09-13T18:32:51Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Laura Loomer, Trump’s new favorite conspiracy theorist, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371794/laura-loomer-trump-campaign-911-marjorie-taylor-greene" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371794</id>
			<updated>2024-09-13T18:32:51Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-13T18:10:05Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When Donald Trump flew to Pennsylvania for a 9/11 anniversary event this week, he brought an unusual companion: a 9/11 conspiracist named Laura Loomer.&#160; Loomer has been a quasi-journalist on the fringe right for about a decade, with a penchant for saying things that make even hardened MAGA types recoil. She is a self-described “proud [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman with red-streaked hair standing in front of a wall covered in fake ivy." data-caption="Laura Loomer in Vero Beach, Florida, in April 2024. | Jacob M. Langston/Washington Post/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jacob M. Langston/Washington Post/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2150515858.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Laura Loomer in Vero Beach, Florida, in April 2024. | Jacob M. Langston/Washington Post/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When Donald Trump flew to Pennsylvania for a 9/11 anniversary event this week, he brought an unusual companion: a <a href="https://x.com/LauraLoomer/status/1672642483958710274">9/11 conspiracist</a> named Laura Loomer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loomer has been <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/8/19/21375159/laura-loomer-congress-republican-florida-trump-explainer">a quasi-journalist on the fringe right</a> for about a decade, with a penchant for saying things that make even <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/13/trump-allies-far-right-activist-loomer">hardened MAGA types recoil</a>. She is a self-described “proud Islamophobe” who has cheered the deaths of migrants and called for Muslims to be banned from driving for ride-hail apps. She ran for Congress twice, in 2020 and 2022, and failed both times. <a href="https://www.thebulwark.com/p/laura-loomer-looms-over-trump-land?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;publication_id=87281&amp;post_id=148832055&amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;isFreemail=true&amp;r=7ttw&amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;utm_medium=email">More recently</a>, Loomer has called Kamala Harris a “drug-using prostitute” and warned that, if she wins, “the White House will <a href="https://x.com/Bakari_Sellers/status/1834639659005067510">smell like curry</a> &amp; White House speeches will be facilitated via a call center.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite all of this, Trump has long displayed a soft spot for Loomer. He endorsed her House bid in 2020 and, in 2023, tried to offer her a spot on his campaign — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/04/07/us/politics/trump-laura-loomer.html">only to back down after aides revolted</a>. Undeterred, he <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/aug/14/laura-loomer-trump-praise-white-supremacist">hosted her at Mar-a-Lago afterward</a>, repeatedly boosted her content on Truth Social, and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/12/us/politics/trump-laura-loomer.html">traveled with her on the 2024 campaign trail</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not clear what Trump gets out of this relationship. But his ties to Loomer have become a major controversy since the 9/11 event, with some of the former president’s closest allies speaking publicly against Loomer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The history of this person is just really toxic,” Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-SC) <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/laura-loomer-trump-graham_n_66e32519e4b0056e82917b22">told the HuffPost</a>. Rep. Majorie Taylor Greene (R-GA) —&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/22256258/marjorie-taylor-greene-jewish-space-laser-anti-semitism-conspiracy-theories">who claimed a Jewish family was using space lasers to start wildfires</a>!&nbsp;— thinks Loomer is a bridge too far, calling Loomer’s tweet about Harris and curry “appalling and extremely racist.” (Loomer responded by accusing Greene of sleeping with a “<a href="https://x.com/LauraLoomer/status/1834019296156033525">Zangief cosplayer</a>.”)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to take these condemnations all that seriously. Trump and his vice presidential pick have spent this week pushing a <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/371466/trump-haitians-dogs-cats-pets-springfield-alt-right">nasty conspiracy theory about Haitian immigrants</a> stealing and eating people’s pets that appears to have <a href="https://x.com/evanhill/status/1834247008409788689">inspired real-world hate crimes</a>. If you’re worried about racism and conspiracy theorizing, maybe take a look at the top of the ticket.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what makes Loomer different from Trump is that she has literally no filter. She says the quiet part out loud, <em>every single time</em>. The more time Trump spends with her, the harder it is to deny that his thinly veiled bigotry is anything but the genuine article. And that, for the Republican Party, is a very big problem indeed.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Who is Laura Loomer?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loomer isn’t a household name for most Americans, but she’s been a presence in the conservative media ecosystem for quite some time.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">She first attracted attention in 2015 when, as a college senior at Barry University in South Florida, she secretly filmed a meeting with administrators in which she attempted to <a href="https://www.nbcmiami.com/news/local/group-claims-barry-university-approved-pro-isis-club/111603/">form a campus club supporting ISIS</a>. The video was released by <a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/miami-dade/article16934699.html">Project Veritas</a>, the conservative group that specializes in (<a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2019/6/27/18760463/project-veritas-youtube-sting-james-okeefe">questionably edited</a>) sting videos.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loomer worked for Project Veritas during the 2016 presidential campaign and learned to build a career out of political stunts. She grabbed the national spotlight in June 2017 when she <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/behind-the-scenes-with-the-right-wing-activist-who-crashed-julius-caesar-laura-loomer">stormed the stage</a> at a performance of Shakespeare’s <em>Julius Caesar</em> in New York that dressed the Roman general like Donald Trump. The disruption <a href="https://www.mediaite.com/tv/julius-caesar-protestor-speaks-out-on-hannity-this-is-assassination-porn/">earned Loomer a booking on Sean Hannity’s show</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You were making a very strong point. I applaud you for what you’ve done,” Hannity told her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loomer parlayed the notoriety from the <em>Julius Caesar </em>incident into a kind of internet celebrity on the pro-Trump right. The problem with celebrity, though, is that it can give you too many opportunities to show yourself. And Loomer proved to be someone with truly out-there opinions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After an ISIS supporter killed eight people with <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-41837386">a truck in November 2017</a>, she went on an Islamophobic rant on Twitter, blaming popular ride-hailing apps for employing Muslim drivers. “Someone needs to create a non Islamic form of Uber or Lyft because I never want to support another Islamic immigrant driver,” she wrote. The two services subsequently <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/laura-loomer-banned-uber-lyft-after-anti-muslim-tweetstorm-n816911">banned her</a>, the first of many bans from high-profile tech platforms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2018, Loomer teamed up with the conspiracy theory site Infowars to cover the mass shooting at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida. She had <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/infowars-sends-professional-troll-laura-loomer-to-parkland">suggested in a tweet</a> that the students there speaking out against gun violence were plants: “it’s obvious these kids are reading a screen or notes someone else wrote for them.” In May 2018, after a school shooting in Santa Fe, Texas, Loomer went even further, suggesting in a tweet that the entire thing was staged.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The doctor speaking to media outside the hospital in Santa Fe, TX where victims of a school shooting were taken today said they just had a ‘mass casualty drill’ at the hospital around the same time of the school drill,” <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/laura-loomer-defends-journalism-credentials-1190798">she wrote</a>. “I’m sorry, but I can’t help but notice these ‘coincidences.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This particular cocktail of hate speech and conspiracy theory misinformation became the hallmark of Loomer’s political style, prompting bans from major social media platforms.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The straw that broke the camel’s back on Twitter, for example, came in November 2018 when Loomer tweeted that Rep. Ilhan Omar (D-MN) <a href="https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2018/11/22/laura-loomer-banned-from-twitter-after-criticizing-ilhan-omar/">supported female genital mutilation</a> because she is Muslim.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In response to the ban, which came a year after Twitter stripped her blue check mark (then something given to notable people rather than a badge to be purchased) as punishment for similar false and offensive claims, Loomer <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/29/18118529/far-right-activist-laura-loomer-twitter-protest-handcuff-nyc-hq">physically chained herself to Twitter’s headquarters</a> in New York while wearing a Nazi-style yellow star. It’s worth noting here that Loomer is Jewish but has long had tight links to the white nationalist movement. She is, for example, <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2023/04/laura-loomer-trump-racism-christchurch-islamophobia/">close with the avowed anti-Semite Nick Fuentes</a> who dined with Trump in 2022, and once broadly boasted that “I’m going to fight for white people.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-1321754141.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.858168327532,100,76.283663344937" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Laura Loomer is escorted out after interrupting Twitter’s Jack Dorsey as he spoke onstage at the Bitcoin 2021 Convention, a crypto-currency conference held at the Mana Convention Center in Wynwood on June 4, 2021, in Miami, Florida. | Joe Raedle/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Joe Raedle/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Presenting herself as a victim of Big Tech censorship, she found allies in <a href="https://www.thegatewaypundit.com/?s=laura+loomer&amp;__cf_chl_jschl_tk__=28e62dda4af33fa06ce44b38c575976afdc4fd4d-1597853257-0-AdxapSOpc5FeMpdDfKxbbZjdSLNuxzsX96c36J2rExNNmg7GqIJ3EyFULUGSzNijdirqAt3J4GF6sIG7HriLVH3FDfsjhb3_LC17Ncc62AGEqHEYo33eFbHaSsgNQF8TAHXIDlWI1RGDQR_9r48k1cQmVWHHDXKcbwBwzM_WBcF2AEkwJDeBGJuwM3emBwIRB0Vwa2zXQq6GbHHjsSpVVKFDNh8rtKe3FIg9dq2SPioZPJp8pGWMeiU016rgOrNZZj8sXBymKkk5kRIP_hrJglFDYQEzO3ehgP1BC0cEKjlZ">popular far-right publications</a> like <a href="https://www.breitbart.com/tag/laura-loomer/">Breitbart</a> as well as in Washington. In December 2019, then-President Trump retweeted a Loomer supporter <a href="https://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2019/12/president-trump-tweets-in-support-of-laura-loomers-candidacy/">calling for donations to her campaign</a>. In <a href="https://www.breitbart.com/tech/2020/05/09/paul-gosar-urges-ag-william-barr-to-investigate-facebooks-censorship-of-laura-loomer/">May 2020</a>, Rep. Paul Gosar (R-AZ) sent a letter to Attorney General Bill Barr calling on him to open an investigation into Loomer’s Facebook ban. She was reinstated on Twitter <a href="https://www.congress.gov/118/meeting/house/115561/documents/HHRG-118-IF16-20230328-SD036.pdf">after Elon Musk’s purchase</a> of the site.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://twitter.com/DrPaulGosar/status/1157778910957821952">Gosar</a>, along with Rep. Matt Gaetz (R-FL), endorsed Loomer during her 2020 House bid in Florida. Positioning her as a victim of Big Tech censorship — a major concern on the right today — worked to help normalize her and bring her into the mainstream of political debate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, she actually won the Republican primary, only to get trounced by a Democrat in the general election. In 2022, she ran in a different Florida district but lost narrowly in the Republican primary.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In theory, Donald Trump hates losers. But for some reason, he keeps coming back to Loomer — hosting her at Mar-a-Lago, posting praise of her on social media, and trying to bring her into his campaign. Why she began traveling with him recently is also a mystery; <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/13/trump-allies-far-right-activist-loomer">a report in Axios</a> ascribes it to an angry Trump becoming increasingly dismissive of his advisers’ advice as his poll numbers fade and more inclined to trust sycophants like Loomer.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this is just a theory. Trump <a href="https://x.com/ShelbyTalcott/status/1834657176721228193">has been vague</a> about his association with Loomer during the current dust-up, and the Trump campaign hasn’t been all that helpful either.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;Anyone who thinks they know what is going on — whether people on the outside or reporters — is full of shit,&#8221; Trump campaign spokesperson <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/09/13/trump-allies-far-right-activist-loomer">Steven Cheung told Axios</a>.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why Laura Loomer matters</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is a reason that Laura Loomer has even Marjorie Taylor Greene panicking, and it’s not just that the two <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/09/12/trump-presidential-campaign-laura-loomer/">reportedly have personal beef</a>. It’s that Laura Loomer makes the rest of the Republican Party look terrible.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For decades, right-wing flirtation with racism has taken place through dog whistles and coded messages. Ronald Reagan’s attacks on “welfare queens” didn’t involve actual racist slurs but conjured up a mental image for some white voters of a poor lazy Black woman exploiting taxpayer dollars to live comfortably. Liberals would call this rhetoric racism, conservatives would say liberals are just trying to shut down legitimate debate, and round-and-round we went.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In theory, Donald Trump should have changed the game. By calling Mexican immigrants “rapists” and proposing a ban on Muslim immigration, he did very little to hide the racial resentment at the core of his political appeal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But after capitulating to Trump, the GOP fell back into its old habits. No matter how outrageous Trump’s rhetoric and even his actions became — from the Muslim ban to family separation —&nbsp;liberal critiques were met with the same kinds of dismissals. Trump’s rhetoric about immigration and crime can’t be racist, they would say; he’s just speaking the language of forgotten Americans left behind by globalization. Liberals, they’d say, are making everything about race when it’s not.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, and his <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/370519/tucker-carlson-holocaust-nazi-churchill-darryl-cooper-martyrmade">top allies like Tucker Carlson</a>, were typically careful to do just enough to keep these defenses plausible. They would insist, over and over again, that they weren’t racists — no matter how much their language resembled what you heard from out-and-out bigots.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bigots like, for example, Laura Loomer.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By bringing her into his inner circle, Trump explodes the entire game. No one can say a woman who talks about the first Indian-American president making the White House smell like curry is merely a race-neutral populist. No one can say that a woman who calls herself a “proud Islamophobe” isn’t a bigot.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump endorses Loomer, as he has repeatedly, he’s implicitly saying that these kinds of views are part of his world. He is validating the liberal critique that his movement is animated by plain old bigotry and removes whatever thin veneer of plausible deniability his professed opposition to racism might have had. Every post he sends endorsing her, every second she travels with Trump, weakens his reputational shield.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s why this week’s firestorm matters. In bringing an open bigot who suggests 9/11 was an “inside job” to a 9/11 memorial, Trump showed that the lines separating him from the people who represented his unbridled id were evaporating. And that, Republicans know, is a recipe for political disaster.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This is an updated version of a piece on Loomer <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/8/19/21375159/laura-loomer-congress-republican-florida-trump-explainer">that originally appeared in 2020</a>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Can the world stop a massive oil spill in the middle of a war zone?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/371734/sounion-houthis-red-sea-tanker-oil-spill" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371734</id>
			<updated>2024-09-13T17:08:42Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-13T11:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since it was attacked by Houthi rebels in Yemen three weeks ago, a tanker carrying roughly 1 million barrels of crude oil has been immobilized and on fire in the Red Sea. The MV Sounion is still intact, but may not be for long, and should it sink it could lead to one of the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A bird’s eye view of an oil tanker with flames on the deck. " data-caption="A satellite image of the crude oil tanker Sounion, which is on fire after being attacked by the Houthis, on August 29, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2168336308.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A satellite image of the crude oil tanker Sounion, which is on fire after being attacked by the Houthis, on August 29, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Since it was attacked by Houthi rebels in Yemen three weeks ago, a tanker carrying roughly 1 million barrels of crude oil has been immobilized and on fire in the Red Sea. The <em>MV </em>Sounion is still intact, but may not be for long, and should it sink it could lead to one of the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/article/2024/aug/28/sounion-tanker-yemen-houthi-attack-fire-red-sea-oil-leak">largest oil spills in history</a>, nearly four times bigger than the Exxon Valdez disaster of 1989. This would have massive environmental and economic impacts on a region already beleaguered by war, and imperil the livelihoods and safe drinking water of millions of people. Efforts will likely soon be <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/risky-salvage-sounion-tanker-restart-red-sea-this-week-sources-say-2024-09-12/">underway</a> to salvage the vessel, but it’s a high-risk operation in an active conflict zone, and success is far from guaranteed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is a cataclysmic disaster waiting to happen, and I don’t think everybody involved fully understands either the challenge of it, or the implications if that challenge is not met,” Ian Ralby, CEO of the maritime security firm Consilium, told Vox. “We’re staring down the barrel of an intergenerational problem that is really more consequential than pretty much any other oil spill has been.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Greek-flagged tanker Sounion, which had been carrying crude oil from Iraq to Greece, was first attacked on August 21 by Yemeni Houthi rebels firing small arms and projectiles, as well as an unmanned surface vessel. The Houthis, who have been <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/24010092/houthis-red-sea-shipping-yemen-israel-gaza">attacking shipping</a> in the Red Sea since near the start of Israel’s war in Gaza, <a href="https://www.washingtoninstitute.org/policy-analysis/five-lessons-sounion-salvage-crisis-red-sea">claim they fired on</a> the ship because its owner, the Greek company Delta Tankers, “has ties” to Israel and has other vessels that have called at Israeli ports. Two other ships owned by Delta Tankers were attacked in August.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ship’s crew of 23 Filipinos and two Russians as well as four private security guards were <a href="https://apnews.com/article/red-sea-attack-sounion-eu-yemen-houthi-rebels-9248d3c71e637d771715da7a6a9bfcce">rescued </a>by a French destroyer the day after the attack, but the Sounion itself is immobilized, currently anchored between the coasts of Eritrea and Yemen. On August 27, Pentagon Spokesperson Maj. Gen. Pat Ryder <a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/Transcripts/Transcript/Article/3886761/pentagon-press-secretary-air-force-maj-gen-pat-ryder-holds-a-press-conference/">told reporters</a> that an initial attempt to salvage the ship had been abandoned after the salvagers were “warned away by the Houthis.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On August 29, the Houthis placed and detonated explosives on the deck of the ship, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/red-sea-attack-sounion-yemen-houthi-rebels-israel-hamas-war-76c68f18a984d18905ce7c84e5cabe0c">releasing a video</a> of themselves carrying out the operation. Shortly after that, the Houthis’ main international patron, Iran, said that the group would <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/houthis-said-to-okay-salvage-of-burning-tanker-after-setting-off-bombs-on-ship/">allow a salvage operation</a> to take place. One of the Houthi senior leaders, Mohammed al-Houthi, <a href="https://english.almasirah.net.ye/post/42220/">has said</a> that they would allow the rescue to take place in order to prevent environmental damage, but that the US and United Kingdom would be responsible for any oil that spilled due to their support for Israel. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The situation appeared to be on its way to a resolution in early September, when an operation involving tugboats protected by European naval vessels was launched to salvage the Sounion. But on September 3, Operation Aspides, the EU naval operation in the region, <a href="https://x.com/EUNAVFORASPIDES/status/1830964218297749785">said in a statement </a>that “the private companies responsible for the salvage operation have concluded that the conditions were not met to conduct the towing operation and that it was not safe to proceed. Alternative solutions are now being explored by the private companies.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In a statement provided to Vox, the tanker’s owner, Delta Tankers, said that it is “doing everything it can to move the vessel (and cargo). For security reasons, we are not in a position to comment further.” The EU’s Operation Aspides did not respond to a request for comment. As of now, the US military does not appear to be involved in efforts to rescue the ship, with Deputy Spokesperson Sabrina Singh telling reporters in a September 5 briefing, “The US Navy is standing by to assist, but right now I’m told that this is being done through private means.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The trade publication <a href="https://maritime-executive.com/article/talks-continue-over-tanker-burning-in-red-sea-as-u-s-releases-video">Maritime Executive<em> </em>has reported</a> that Greece — the ship’s flag state — has been in talks with Saudi Arabia over options, which could include towing it to a Saudi port or an effort to transfer oil to another ship before it sinks. On September 12, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/risky-salvage-sounion-tanker-restart-red-sea-this-week-sources-say-2024-09-12/">Reuters reported</a> that another salvage operation would begin soon. But there’s no guarantee the Houthis wouldn’t strike again, and experts say the sort of companies that specialize in these types of operations are unaccustomed to doing so in the middle of a war zone. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Even though the Houthis are giving a green light to tug this boat, they’re still attacking ships around it,” Mohammed al-Basha, a Yemeni security analyst with the consultancy Navanti Group, told Vox. “So insurance companies are not comfortable with it, salvage companies are not comfortable with it. There’s just no trust between the international community and the Houthis.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With the ship still burning, there may not be much time left. Like nearly all tankers built since the Exxon Valdez disaster, the Sounion is <a href="https://blog.response.restoration.noaa.gov/spills-never-happened-thanks-double-hulls">double-hulled</a> and will not leak easily, and its oil tanks still seem to be intact. But depending on the amount of damage it has already sustained, how much oxygen the oil cargo has been exposed to, and the intensity of the fire, it’s likely only a matter of time.   </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We don’t know how long that vessel has. If the fires aren’t put out, it will eventually sink,” said Ralby.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The Exxon Valdez<em> </em>—<em> </em>times four</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If the Sounion’s cargo spills, it could potentially rank among the world’s worst environmental disasters. Julien Jreissati, Greenpeace’s Middle East North Africa program director, told Vox that because the Red Sea is a mostly closed body of water — with the Suez Canal to the north and the Bab-el-Mandeb Strait to the south — it doesn’t have the same level of circulation and dilution as open ocean, making the oil more likely to stick in place. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You cannot clean an oil spill,” Jreissati said. “You can try to contain it and mitigate it, but you will have impact and remnants for decades.” The difficulties involved in such an operation would be exponentially greater in an active combat zone.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Red Sea is truly a natural treasure,” Jreissati said. “It has species of corals which are among the most resilient to <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24137250/coral-reefs-bleaching-climate-change">climate change and bleaching</a>, and therefore are particularly precious, because they could help provide the solution for corals all over the world.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the impact wouldn’t only be felt underwater. A major oil spill could devastate the region’s fisheries, a key component of economies on both sides of the sea. (Prior to the outbreak of civil war in 2015, fish were Yemen’s <a href="https://www.nrc.no/shorthand/stories/yemen---how-fishing-communities-are-fighting-back/index.html">second-largest export after oil and gas</a>.) An oil spill could also block access to ports for impoverished Yemen’s <a href="https://www.unicef.org/emergencies/yemen-crisis">much-need humanitarian aid</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It could also cause an even greater disruption to shipping through the Red Sea, which is already <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/367258/globalization-shipping-economy-houthis-russia-air-travel-internet">down nearly two-thirds</a> due to the Houthi attacks, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2024/01/16/shipping-houthi-attack-energy-prices/">raising the costs of shipping</a> and causing further reverberations throughout the global supply chain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much also depends on <em>when </em>a spill would take place. Currently, the surface current in the Red Sea is mainly flowing south toward the Indian Ocean. In October it will <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/0011747174900680#:~:text=During%20winter%20(October%E2%80%93May),into%20the%20Gulf%20of%20Aden.">switch and begin flowing</a> north, toward Saudi Arabia and Egypt. One major concern is that an oil spill could contaminate the <a href="https://www.greenpeace.org/static/planet4-mena-stateless/2022/01/0fc732ba-fso-safer-a-shipwreck-in-slow-motion.pdf">coastal desalination plants that tens of millions of people</a> in countries bordering the Red Sea, rely on for fresh water. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A cruel irony of this situation is that the Red Sea region only recently escaped a similar disaster. The FSO Safer, a 1970s-era tanker that had been converted by the Yemeni government into an offshore oil platform, is moored off the central Yemeni city of al-Hudaydah, <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/10/11/the-ship-that-became-a-bomb">unmaintained and rapidly</a> corroding. In its hold were over a million barrels of oil, roughly the same amount as at the Sounion. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Around 2021, it became clear that the ship was at risk of sinking or exploding. A <a href="https://www.acaps.org/fileadmin/Data_Product/Main_media/20210407_acaps_yemen_fso_safer_impact_assessment_april-june_2021.pdf">risk assessment at the time</a> estimated that it could affect up to 1.6 million people’s livelihoods, disrupt 50 percent of Yemen’s fisheries, and that the cleanup alone would cost more than $20 billion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After years of negotiations with the Houthis, a UN-organized operation was finally organized to transfer the oil off the ship. The operation was <a href="https://www.un.org/en/stopredseaspill/background#:~:text=The%20catastrophic%20costs%20of%20inaction,for%20fish%20stocks%20to%20recover.">completed in August 2023</a>, almost exactly a year before the Sounion crisis began. This time around, the international community has far less time to act. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Why more environmental disasters are coming to the Red Sea&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hopefully there is still time for the private companies and militaries in the region to organize a salvage mission — and for the Houthis to allow it to proceed — before the worst-case scenario takes place. But even if the Sounion itself doesn’t cause the cataclysm, it’s just one reminder of the knock-on risks posed by the nearly year-old conflict in Gaza. Two additional oil tankers <a href="https://news.usni.org/2024/09/03/houthis-strike-two-more-crude-tankers-in-the-red-sea-another-tanker-continues-to-burn">were attacked by the Houthis</a>, but not disabled, in early September, even as the Sounion continued to burn. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then there’s the Rubymar, the first ship sunk by a Houthi attack, back in March. Though carrying only a fraction of the oil of the Sounion, the Rubymar left an 18-mile oil slick in <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/02/23/politics/sinking-ship-houthi-missile-oil-slick/index.html">the Red Sea</a>. A much bigger concern is the <a href="https://news.mongabay.com/2024/09/six-months-after-first-houthi-ship-sinking-attacks-slick-red-sea-with-oil/">22,000 metric tons of fertilizer</a> still in the ship’s hold, which, if released underwater, could potentially cause massive algae blooms that would devastate local species and potentially <a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2017/8/3/16089296/gulf-of-mexico-dead-zone">create oxygen-free “dead zones.”</a> Experts believe the cargo will remain in the Rubymar’s<em> </em>holds for years, but not indefinitely, and the International Maritime Organization, a UN agency, has launched an <a href="https://english.aawsat.com/arab-world/5038071-un-launches-campaign-collect-funds-clean-pollution-caused-sinking-ship-red-sea">appeal for funding</a> for a cleanup. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Greenpeace’s Jreissati, the crisis is a reminder that even under the best of times, the global economy relies on “these big ships traveling across the world the whole time carrying very toxic material. It’s a ticking time bomb.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also a reminder that the longer the escalating conflict in the Middle East lasts, the greater and more unpredictable the risks grow.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicole Kidman’s exquisitely fun and silly murder mystery era is upon us]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/371473/nicole-kidman-the-perfect-couple-spoilers-review" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371473</id>
			<updated>2024-09-13T13:56:12Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-13T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please cover your eyes if you aren’t prepared to be spoiled: The eponymous, beautiful pair at the heart of Netflix’s The Perfect Couple isn’t perfect, nor is the show specifically about said couple.&#160; To be clear, the series largely exists because if you squint and only pay half attention to it while scrolling your phone, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Nicole Kidman in a blond wig and blue blouse with her arms crossed." data-caption="Nicole Kidman as Greer Winbury in Netflix’s The Perfect Couple. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/The_Perfect_Couple_n_S1_E6_00_11_01_05RC.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Nicole Kidman as Greer Winbury in Netflix’s The Perfect Couple. | Courtesy of Netflix</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Please cover your eyes if you aren’t prepared to be spoiled: The eponymous, beautiful pair at the heart of Netflix’s <em>The</em> <em>Perfect Couple</em> isn’t perfect, nor is the show specifically about said couple.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, the series largely exists because if you squint and only pay half attention to it while scrolling your phone, <em>The Perfect Couple </em>could be mistaken for two better shows: <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/7/19/20698027/big-little-lies-season-two-wrap-up"><em>Big Little Lies</em></a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23504949/white-lotus-season-two-finale-recap-deaths-explained"><em>White Lotus</em></a>. Just like those splashy HBO hits, <em>The Perfect Couple </em>centers around<em> </em>a dead body that shatters the lives of very wealthy Caucasian people. Similarly, the female characters on the show are married to human pieces of garbage who may or may not also be murderers. And at the heart of it all is a very frazzled, very rich woman on the verge of a complete meltdown.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, viewers are here for Oscar and Emmy winner Nicole Kidman, whose wigs are always full of secrets. This time, she’s playing a matriarch whose moniker is just three last names and is part of one of the wealthiest families in Nantucket. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The Perfect Couple </em>culminates in many final twists: a sex-work-related origin story; a barbiturate-laced drink and a drowning; an illegitimate baby; and the reveal of a convoluted trust fund situation. But more intriguing than any of the twists in this series is perhaps what it says about Nicole Kidman herself. In the last four years, Kidman has acted in six television series. Four of those series involve rich white women and some kind of death shrouded in suspicion, if not an out-and-out murder mystery.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was an <em>es-scort</em>!” Kidman’s Greer Garrison Winbury shiver-shouts in the final episode, explaining to her family that she was a sex worker and that their father and possible homicider Tag (Liev Schreiber) was a john.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/TPC_104_Unit_03620RC.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Nice Kidman sitting in a robe with her bare legs on the desk in front of her." title="Nice Kidman sitting in a robe with her bare legs on the desk in front of her." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Nicole Kidman acting out how writers sit when they’re writing at home. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“Three times! All right? And now I pay for <em>eve-r-ything</em>!” she hisses (Kidman’s accent jumps from Australia to Boston in three syllables), revealing that Greer Garrison Winbury has receipts.<strong> </strong>“I’m not cleaning everything up for you. I’m done with your ego. I’m done with your bullshit. I am done. Do you hear me? Done. I’m not taking care of everything for everyone anymore.” It’s all sudsy, over the top — much more deliriously delicious than the other adjacent-to-murder women Kidman has played in recent years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The aforementioned two seasons of <em>Big Little Lies </em>featured Kidman as Celeste Wright, a rich former lawyer and now Monterrey stay-at-home mom with an abusive, adulterous, and freshly dead husband that’s all based on a Liane Moriarty novel. In 2020’s <em>The Undoing</em>, also an adaptation, she plays Grace Fraser, a rich Manhattan psychologist with an adulterous, murdery husband. Hulu’s <em>Nine Perfect Strangers</em> (2021) is another Moriarty adaptation. In that one, Kidman plays chilling wellness coach Masha Dmitrichenko, who drugs guests with psilocybin at her retreat and was shot once (but not murdered). In <em>Expats</em>,<em> </em>adapted from a 2016 novel by Janice Y.K. Lee, which premiered on Amazon this year, Kidman plays Margaret Woo, a neglected wife mourning the kidnapping (and death) of her son while also investigating a recently deceased neighbor as the possible kidnapper-pedophile-murderer.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If there’s a story in which a frazzled rich white woman is slightly aloof yet extremely adjacent to nefarious hijinks, Nicole Kidman, her agent, and a streaming service aren’t far behind. Bonus points if it’s based on a book touted as a beach read and written by Moriarty.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kidman’s choices and work ethic have come under a little bit of scrutiny. She’s not making enough <em>serious</em> stuff and perhaps is in a little too much television for a <em>serious</em> actress, <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/features/commentary/nicole-kidman-too-much-tv-perfect-couple-lioness-1235044028/">the argument goes</a>. But that undercuts an actress who has already won top awards in both movies and television, and is also <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000173/">producing the shows</a> she’s starring in. She’s doing what she wants to do, and from the intense wiggery to the chewy monologues about how many exact times she charged her now-husband for sex, it seems like she’s having plenty of fun creating these fizzy melodramas. And <a href="https://variety.com/2024/film/news/nicole-kidman-defends-acting-hollywood-blockbusters-batman-1236119507/">Kidman has famously</a> admitted to taking roles for the fun of it!&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The more you watch Kidman’s various blonde lace fronts and accents, the more it feels like she’s in on the joke or committing to a bit, taking the morbidity and macabre out of <a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/tv/story/2020-06-09/reese-witherspoon-little-fires-everywhere-morning-show-big-little-lies">death by</a> stealing the spotlight with her routine portrayal of these soapy protagonists. Playing Greer Garrison Winbury is just her latest role in a story where death functions like a great equalizer, as it is the only thing the rich can’t use their millions of dollars to hide from (especially if a SOB husband happens to be a murderer).&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/TPC_101_Unit_05484RC.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Nicole Kidman in sunglasses and a sweater holding a phone to her ear while walking along a coastal inlet." title="Nicole Kidman in sunglasses and a sweater holding a phone to her ear while walking along a coastal inlet." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The way Nicole Kidman’s Greer Garrison Winbury is giving coastal grandma but with murder. | Courtesy of Netflix" data-portal-copyright="Courtesy of Netflix" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">What is it about murder mysteries and affluent women that speaks to Nicole Kidman? Does she like television more than movies? Is there some kind of fun playing wealthy women with awful, possibly murderous husbands? Does she just really want to be in a season of <em>White Lotus</em> but is simply too famous?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re free to come up with our own conclusions about the why for her, but that Kidman keeps giving us these six- to eight-episode seasons as breadcrumbs is part of the pleasure.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Constance Grady</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Republicans became the party of raunch]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/371632/raunch-republicans-sydney-sweeney-hawk-tuah-girl" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371632</id>
			<updated>2024-09-13T15:11:43Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-13T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="#MeToo" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Gender" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sexual harassment" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the Purity Chronicles, Vox looks back at the sexual and gendered mores of the late ’90s and 2000s, one pop culture phenomenon at a time. Read more here. In an election year full of unprecedented events and weirdness, there’s been another notable oddity: Whenever a new hot girl enters the zeitgeist — say, actor [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman’s butt in an American flag thong bikini with a Republican elephant stamp prominently displayed on one cheek." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/Efi-Chalikopoulou_Final_9-4.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>In the Purity Chronicles, Vox looks back at the sexual and gendered mores of the late ’90s and 2000s, one pop culture phenomenon at a time. Read more <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22452846/purity-chronicles">here</a>.</em></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an election year full of unprecedented events and <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/363230/jd-vance-couch-sex-hillbilly-elegy-rumor-false">weirdness</a>, there’s been another notable oddity: Whenever a new hot girl enters the zeitgeist — say, actor Sydney Sweeney hosting <em>SNL</em> this spring in a low-cut dress, or <a href="https://www.vox.com/internet-culture/357813/hawk-tuah-girl-meme-tiktok-explained">Hawk Tuah Girl</a> taking over the internet earlier this summer — conservatives fall all over themselves trying to claim the phenomenon as their own.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Wokeness is dead,” <a href="https://x.com/RichardHanania/status/1764348035432374659?lang=en">gloated right-wing commentator Richard Hanania on X back in March</a>, over a video clip of Sweeney in a black dress with a plunging neckline, her breasts at the center of the frame. Hanania’s logic was obscure, but it seemed to go something like this: Sweeney’s prominently displayed chest was somehow inextricably opposed to the progressive ethos currently fashionable in popular culture. That ethos, according to Hanania, was profoundly anti-boob, regardless of how the owner of the boobs felt about them herself. Sydney Sweeney, somehow, was the antidote to this problem.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hanania’s take soon echoed across conservative publications, including the Canadian <a href="https://nationalpost.com/opinion/amy-hamm-wokeness-is-no-match-for-sydney-sweeneys-undeniable-beauty">conservative-leaning National Post</a> and <a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/boobs-are-back-thank-you-sydney-sweeney/">the Spectator</a>, a British news magazine. In August, after Sweeney posted a series of photographs of herself in a small swimsuit to Instagram, <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/sydney-sweeney-posts-thirst-traps-on-instagram.html">more of the online right</a> rallied to her side. “It’s a bad week to be a militant blue-haired lesbian,” declared Joe Kinsey, an editor for conservative sports website the Outkick, <a href="https://x.com/JoeKinseyexp/status/1824529722686181675">in a post on X</a> over screencaps of Sweeney’s curves.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2049055675.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Sydney Sweeney hosts &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt; on March 2, 2024. " data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/internet-culture/357813/hawk-tuah-girl-meme-tiktok-explained">Meanwhile, Hawk Tuah Girl</a> — a young woman named Haliey Welch — shot to viral fame in June after she appeared in a TikTok “girl outside a bar” interview and gave an oral sex tip that was both graphic and pithy. “You gotta give ’em that ‘hawk tuah’ and spit on that thang. You get me?” she said. The clip zipped around and was lauded on the parts of the internet where straight men hang out. On his podcast, Joe Rogan <a href="https://www.vox.com/internet-culture/357813/hawk-tuah-girl-meme-tiktok-explained">called Welch</a> “the most famous person on the planet right now.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Welch, who has <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/hawk-tuah-girl-merch-viral-video-1235047145/">gamely worked her newfound viral fame</a> for what it’s worth, has expressed no particular political affiliation, and no one on the left seems particularly outraged by her moment. Nonetheless, in the months since the video took off, “hawk tuah” became something of&nbsp;a <a href="https://slate.com/life/2024/07/hawk-tuah-girl-video-what-is-haliey-welch-meaning.html">conservative slogan</a>, plastered across <a href="https://torontosun.com/news/world/maga-supporter-booted-from-flight-for-offensive-trump-shirt">hand-crafted Donald Trump merch</a> and <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/sport/golf/article-13560903/hawk-tuah-bryson-dechambeau-liv-golf.html">shouted ecstatically by MAGA fans</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Those observing these developments could be forgiven for their confusion. After all, the left is considered the sex-positive side of American politics, the home for politicians and activists who agitate for access to birth control and abortions, who support LGBTQ rights, who are generally more sexually progressive. It’s Republican politicians who actively campaign against <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/06/05/birth-control-access-abortion-ban/">contraception</a>, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/04/20/house-gop-bill-transgender-athletes-00093044">trans rights</a>, and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/sex-education-us-laws-kentucky-florida-mississippi-bd6fffcb3a9a25babc32a143001f4ae1">sex ed</a> in schools, while right-wing think tank the Heritage Foundation is openly musing on ways to <a href="https://x.com/Heritage/status/1662534135762624520">put an end to casual sex in America</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the same breath that the right is ostensibly embracing breasts and blow jobs, they are also maintaining their tradition of critiquing the sex lives of their political enemies. Republicans starting with Trump have repeatedly and baselessly <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-biden-harris-attacks-1963d49f48696dafe2f7558c2dc1cc9f">claimed</a> that Vice President Kamala Harris launched her career in politics thanks to her relationship with former San Francisco Mayor Willie Brown in the 1990s, and that Harris essentially slept her way to the top. “Kamala Harris — she&#8217;s the original hawk tuah girl,” <a href="https://cbsaustin.com/news/nation-world/conservative-author-calls-kamala-harris-original-hawk-tuah-girl-on-live-tv-2024-presidential-election-politics-democrats-republicans-liberals-conservatives-gop-sexual-allegations-favors-harsh-tough-haliey-welch">conservative author Alec Lace said on Fox Business in July</a>, repeating a talking point apparently developed by a slew of <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/09/08/2024/mysterious-influencer-network-pushed-sexual-smears-of-harris">anonymous conservative influencers</a> earlier that month.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So as far as Republicans are concerned, is sex for celebrating and flaunting? Or is it for regulating and decrying and shaming?&nbsp;</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a sexual ideology that holds all of these concepts together in a single place: the idea that you can celebrate Hawk Tuah Girl and use her catchphrase to degrade a female politician; the idea that a starlet in a low-cut dress is yours to objectify, while contraception and sexual education are dangerous and probably immoral and should be restricted.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It harks back to the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22452846/purity-chronicles">idea that was dominant in the Bush era</a>, a moment when our culture was capable of prizing <em>Girls Gone Wild </em>and purity balls in equal measure, when pop stars like Britney Spears were expected to serve their audiences sex on a platter while avowing their virginity at the same time. It’s the ideology that unites Republican raunch and purity culture, that makes them two sides of the same coin: one based on the idea that women’s sexuality should exist in the service of men. The right once again championing this brand of bawdiness while working relentlessly to restrict women’s autonomy and denigrating the women they don’t like isn’t a departure. It’s a return to form.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the 2000s, three decades after the second-wave feminist protests of the 1970s, 10 years after the advent of the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/3/20/16955588/feminism-waves-explained-first-second-third-fourth">riot grrl third wave of the ’90s</a>, reeling from both 9/11 and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22672346/monica-lewinsky-bill-clinton-impeachment-american-crime-story">Clinton-Lewinsky scandal</a>, America entered into a moment of profound conservative reaction. One of the ways that reaction manifested itself was the mainstreaming of what the essayist Ariel Levy called <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Female-Chauvinist-Pigs-Raunch-Culture/dp/0743284283">raunch culture</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Raunch culture was the teen girl uniform becoming low-rise jeans with thongs showing over the top, not just as a subcultural trend but as the default. Raunch culture was Howard Stern telling his female guests to undress in the studio so that he and his sidekicks could critique their bodies and tell them what plastic surgery to get. Raunch culture was <em>The Man Show</em>, an over-the-top leer-fest that ran from 1999 to 2004, that ended with a segment called “Girls on Trampolines,” during which —&nbsp;the titular girls on trampolines being not quite bouncy enough — a dance troupe entitled the Juggy Dance Squad would perform in the audience.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The joke was that it was funny when girls were sexy and it was sexy when girls were degraded —&nbsp;especially when they played along.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Only thirty years (my lifetime) ago, our mothers were ‘burning their bras’ and picketing Playboy, and suddenly we were getting implants and wearing the bunny logo as supposed symbols of our liberation,” marveled Levy in her 2005 book <em>Female Chauvinist Pigs: Women and the Rise of Raunch Culture</em>. “How had the culture shifted so drastically in such a short period of time?”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>The joke was that it was funny when girls were sexy and it was sexy when girls were degraded —&nbsp;especially when they played along</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Levy’s answer to that question is that women had learned to internalize the misogyny that was all around them, to adapt by reflexively becoming their own chauvinist pigs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This was the mainstream sexual ideology of the postfeminist and reactionary Bush era: the sense that the feminism of the 1970s was now strident, shrill, and unfashionable. Being up to the minute meant being cool with a little light objectification, meant participating in it yourself —&nbsp;being one of the guys, even if you were a girl.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Levy interviews one woman who demonstrates the extent to which women were expected to capitulate to men’s misogynistic demands: “I went out with my friend a couple weeks ago and some guy touched her ass and she flipped out at him,” she says. “I was just like, ‘Dude, he slapped your ass.’ To me that would be no big deal — if anything, I’d be flattered.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The end of the 2000s, though, saw the Bush era give way to the Obama era, when liberal politics and pop culture forged what looked for a while like a profoundly powerful alliance. All of a sudden, Beyoncé was performing in front of the giant word “FEMINIST” and remixing Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie’s feminist TED talk into her music. The rest of the culture followed rapidly after her.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-454281358.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.673995286123,100,78.652009427754" alt="Beyonce onstage in front of the word “feminist” writ large." title="Beyonce onstage in front of the word “feminist” writ large." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Beyoncé performs at the 2014 VMAs in front of the word “FEMINIST.” | Jason LaVeris/FilmMagic via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jason LaVeris/FilmMagic via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Magazines started asking the young stars they profiled whether they identified as feminists, and the stars stopped reflexively saying that no they weren’t, because after all, they shaved their legs. Girlbosses were trending. Disney started making princess movies where the damsels saved each other rather than relying on a prince’s kiss. Period underwear started a campaign about how the fact that it was <a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/3/14/14911228/thinx-miki-agrawal-health-care-branding">advertising about periods</a> was actually deeply feminist.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The mainstreaming of pop feminism throughout the 2010s was expected to culminate in the election of Hilary Clinton in 2016. Instead, it faced the election of Donald Trump, a man who publicly bragged about sexually assaulting women. Widespread horror and anger at this result developed into the Me Too movement, further altering the rules for how pop culture could acceptably treat women.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can see these massive cultural shifts by looking at Hollywood, where the stars who clung on from 2004 to 2024 had to reimagine their images when it came to women. Late-night host Jimmy Kimmel, who co-created <em>The Man Show</em> and served as co-host until 2003, hosted the Oscars in 2018, months after the explosion of the Me Too movement.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We can’t let bad behavior slide anymore,” Kimmel declared during his opening monologue. “The world is watching us. We need to set an example. If we can do that, women will only have to deal with harassment all the time at every other place they go.” I don’t say any of this to pick on Kimmel but to make it clear just how dramatically our culture shifted over the course of the 2010s —&nbsp;almost as dramatically as the shift Levy is so shocked over in <em>Female Chauvinist Pigs</em>. The raunch that was so inescapable as to feel compulsory in the 2000s came very quickly to be considered beyond the pale. Now, it would seem a little weird and retro in most circles <em>not</em> to yell at a man who gropes a stranger’s ass in public.</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">For some conservative commentators, the feminist mainstreaming of the 2010s is a bizarre aberration, a refusal to acknowledge such self-evident truths as the fact that everyone likes a cute blonde with an ample bosom and a small dress.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hanania, the right-wing writer who started as <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/richard-hanania-white-supremacist-pseudonym-richard-hoste_n_64c93928e4b021e2f295e817">a white supremacist troll</a> before becoming a so-called “<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/08/richard-hanania-racist-message.html">intellectual muse of the Silicon Valley right</a>,” has described the rise of pop feminism in the 2010s <a href="https://x.com/RichardHanania/status/1771720488705761626">as the left declaring “jihad against boobs.”</a> You can see how he — and the rest of the online right — reached this conclusion by reading <a href="https://www.richardhanania.com/p/yes-sydney-sweeneys-boobs-are-anti">his Substack post</a> where he elaborates on his original “woke is dead” tweet about Sweeney’s breasts.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The more attractive women around us are, whether in real life or fiction, the less one is able to maintain two important leftist delusions,” Hanania writes. “That the sexes are or can be made interchangeable, and that sexual selection either is or can be made to be an unimportant part of human affairs. If Sydney Sweeney’s boobs walk into a room, even Chris Hayes is going to experience a physiological transformation.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hanania’s take, if I’m deciphering it correctly, is that it is fundamental to human nature for men to publicly ogle women’s bodies and value women accordingly, and that when feminists object to the ogling, they are attempting to put some sort of vise around human nature. Sweeney’s star power, combined with her willingness to show off her curves, he argues, is proof that this vise has vanished and men can go back to the way things should be: sexualizing women pretty much whenever they feel like it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hanania is not alone in believing liberalism is some sort of prison for traditional femininity. The idea is fundamental to multiple figures on the online right. Just look at <a href="https://www.thecut.com/2023/09/tradwife-content-influencers-conservative-ideology.html">the tradwives who chafe against the cultural tide</a> that normalized going to work outside the home and splitting domestic labor more equitably, or the reactionary elements on TikTok who seem to believe feminists would love nothing more than to <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@lilykateshow/video/7311484836533865770">forbid women from wearing skirts and dresses</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this is a willful misreading of contemporary feminism. There’s a clear difference between Sweeney being proudly boob-forward — while still getting taken seriously as an award-winning actor with major star power —&nbsp;and other people getting rich by exploiting the breasts of beautiful underpaid women, as was the case with <em>Girls Gone Wild, The Man Show</em>, and, heck, even <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/360219/dcc-dallas-cowboys-cheerleaders-netflix-judi-kelli-victoria-kalina">today’s Dallas Cowboys Cheerleaders</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The radical idea of pop feminism in the 2010s was that you should be accorded basic human dignity regardless of what your body looks like and how you choose to display it, even if you are an entertainer in a visual medium. Raunch culture looks at this request and declares it regressive, prudish, delusional. Raunch must be compulsory or it is nothing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s the compulsion that is the point. If raunch is not compulsory, then it is not degrading, and part of the point of raunch is to humiliate.<strong> </strong>Now that <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23581859/me-too-backlash-susan-faludi-weinstein-roe-dobbs-depp-heard">the Me Too backlash has well and truly arrived</a>, now that Trump is once again grasping for the White House, now that <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is dead and contraception is in the crosshairs, this is the sexual ethos that the right wants to return to its rightful place.&nbsp;</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">The return of raunch is particularly dangerous for women in politics because, after all, politicians need to perform power.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is in part to humiliate Kamala Harris that Republicans keep pushing on the claim that Harris slept her way to the top, that they have <a href="https://x.com/AlecLace/status/1815854696114098613">dubbed her “the original Hawk Tuah girl.”</a>&nbsp; To be clear, <a href="https://www.factcheck.org/2024/08/posts-mislead-about-harris-romance-with-willie-brown/">there does not appear to have been any impropriety</a> in Harris’s relationship with California politician Willie Brown, who she dated for nearly two years in the mid-1990s. That doesn’t matter to Harris’s attackers, because in raunch culture, the claim <em>feels</em> true.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Harris’s status as a woman in power means that her ambition is held to be inappropriately sexual and immoral</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under this ideology, Harris’s status as a Black woman means that her body is held to be inherently sexualized, all her romantic relationships thus suspect and deviant. Her status as a woman in power means that her ambition is held to be inappropriately sexual and immoral. The way to keep her in place is to suggest that she would be more comfortable on her knees.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Raunch culture says that if a woman must pursue politics, her ideal avatar is probably Sarah Palin: a white woman, the wife to a macho dude who worked for an oil company, a fervently pro-life mother to five children, someone who looked great campaigning in a mini skirt. (Harris’s status as a stepmother, rather than a biological mother, has also come in for <a href="https://apnews.com/article/jd-vance-kamala-harris-childless-trump-0a37e991097b66c52bff5bf7ecf8de7b">criticism from the right</a>.) <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2008/oct/24/women-sarahpalin">Palin was equal parts idealized and humiliated</a> by her admirers on the right during her 2008 run for vice president. She was lauded as <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2008/09/sarah-palin-smart-scrappy-and-oh-yes-sexy">“smart, scrappy, and oh yes, sexy,”</a> but she was also the center of a novelty song titled “Red, White, and MILF,” turned into a blow-up sex doll, and made into the subject of a porn parody film.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Palin’s foil in the era was Hillary Clinton, a woman whose public image was so thoroughly desexed that the raunchy joke about her was that she was castrating (they used to sell <a href="https://www.nationalreview.com/media-blog/katie-hates-hillary-nutcrackers-tim-graham/">Hillary nutcrackers</a> at airports), that she could not satisfy her man, that “<a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2016/07/qa-with-two-women-buying-hillary-sucks-shirt.html">Hillary sucks but not like Monica</a>.” There was no safe distance a woman could take from raunch that would not allow it to come for her, too, engulfing, humiliating, and titillating the onlookers.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1235890978.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,18.790840502554,100,62.418318994893" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The Hillary Nutcracker &amp; Corkscrew Bill, available for sale in 2009. | Paul J. Richards/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright=" Paul J. Richards/AFP via Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">If raunch is considered to be humiliating to women, that’s because raunch is about women being of service to men. The right is comfortable celebrating Sydney Sweeney when she references her own boobs and Hawk Tuah Girl making jokes about blowjobs because the idea at the core of those jokes is about women performing sex for men, as an act of service.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet the idea that Harris is “the original Hawk Tuah girl” is a tell that Republicans aren’t suddenly more liberated and celebratory around women’s sexuality. They still think it’s filthy and degrading. They just also want to be in a position to take advantage of it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This basic fact is why raunch culture and purity culture co-exist so closely. It’s why the online right can think of themselves as being pro-sex and also be in favor of outlawing abortion and making it harder to access contraception. All of it is about men controlling women’s bodies: controlling how they look, how they have sex, and how they have children. The point is always that it’s not the woman who chooses.&nbsp;</p>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">What makes raunch culture Republican is not just the underlying conservative social politics, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/366601/the-rights-plan-to-fix-america-patriarchy-2-0">the misogyny,</a> the fact that it goes mainstream when the country is swinging rightward. What makes raunch culture Republican is that its logic is commercial.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The woman idealized by raunch culture is an easily identifiable archetype. You can buy most of her attributes, points out Levy in <em>Female Chauvinist Pigs</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If we were to acknowledge that sexuality is personal and unique, it would become unwieldy. Making sexiness into something simple, quantifiable, makes it easier to explain and to market,” Levy writes. “If you remove the human factor from sex and make it about stuff — big fake boobs, bleached blonde hair, long nails, poles, thongs — then you can sell it. Suddenly, sex requires shopping; you need plastic surgery, peroxide, a manicure, a mall.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the other side of all that is potential profit.&nbsp;Welch has a <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/hawk-tuah-girl-merch-viral-video-1235047145/">merch line</a>. When Sweeney hosted <em>SNL</em>, she joked in her monologue that her backup plan to launch her career <a href="https://youtu.be/E4fh7eBK4qE?t=125">was to show her boobs</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>The claim that sex belongs to Republicans should not be understood simply as a bizarre and self-deluding brag. It’s a threat. &nbsp;</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“With Sweeney, what it really comes down to is this: Sex sells. That has never changed,” <a href="https://nationalpost.com/opinion/amy-hamm-wokeness-is-no-match-for-sydney-sweeneys-undeniable-beauty">explained Amy Hamm in the National Post</a> as she celebrated Sweeney’s breasts as “harbingers of the death of woke.” Sex sells, and raunch codifies sex into especially saleable forms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sweeney and Welch, however, have been able to keep at least some of the profits they’ve amassed largely to themselves. The ideal under pure raunch culture would be for their profits to go to the men who exploit them. That’s what happens if raunch manages to kill woke: Women lose control of not just their bodies but also their money.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The irony here is that the resurgence of Republican raunch is arriving on the tail end of a widespread movement in the mainstream to reexamine and rethink the conventional sexual wisdom of the 2000s. At the very moment that, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22452846/purity-chronicles">in essay series like this</a> one, in documentaries like <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/22276585/framing-britney-spears-us-weekly-perez-hilton-daniel-ramos"><em>Framing Britney Spears</em></a> and podcasts like <a href="https://yourewrongabout.com/"><em>You’re Wrong About</em></a>, and more reevaluations of women who were mistreated in the 2000s than we can count, lots of people who grew up in the Bush era are beginning to process exactly how messed up the sexual politics of that decade were, people on the right are expressing a profound nostalgia for those politics. They are saying, “We’d like to go back, please,” to when it was fine to treat women as sexual objects and treat their sexuality as a commodity.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the claim that sex belongs to Republicans should not be understood simply as a bizarre and self-deluding brag. It’s a threat.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, September 13, 9 am:</strong> This story, published September 13, originally misspelled Haliey Welch’s first name.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Whizy Kim</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Crypto is betting it all on the 2024 elections]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/371597/crypto-politics-spending-2024-elections-trump" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371597</id>
			<updated>2024-09-12T22:57:14Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-13T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Business &amp; Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Crypto" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s probably been a minute since you saw Larry David, Tom Brady, or Matt Damon on TV extolling the benefits of crypto. That’s because the era of feverish crypto hype — interrupted by a cascade of highly publicized scandals — has largely passed since its heyday in 2021.  But there’s one critical place where the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Illustration of a man about to fall off a stack of bitcoin cryptocurrencies as a giant hand removes coins out of the stack." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1358554531.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s probably been a minute since you saw <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hWMnbJJpeZc">Larry David</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VPa-g33qL8s">Tom Brady</a>, or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dHv2FBMtlUc">Matt Damon</a> on TV extolling the benefits of crypto. That’s because the era of feverish crypto hype — interrupted by a cascade of <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/11/21/investing/binance-changpeng-zhao-treasury/index.html">highly publicized</a> <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23458837/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-sbf-downfall-explained">scandals</a> — has largely passed since its heyday in 2021.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"> But there’s one critical place where the industry is hotter than ever: Washington, DC.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crypto has spent a <a href="https://www.citizen.org/article/big-crypto-big-spending-2024/">record $119 million</a> in the 2024 federal elections, magnitudes more than it has ever spent before. This huge number means that crypto accounts for almost half of all corporate political contributions in this cycle. Its spending since 2010, totaling $129 million, puts the industry second only to fossil fuels, according to a <a href="https://www.citizen.org/article/big-crypto-big-spending-2024/">report</a> from the progressive consumer advocacy group Public Citizen.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="Tom Brady FTX Flamethrower" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VPa-g33qL8s?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s already 15 percent of all known corporate contributions since the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/7/1/22559318/supreme-court-americans-for-prosperity-bonta-citizens-united-john-roberts-donor-disclosure"><em>Citizens United</em> ruling</a>,” says Rick Claypool, a research director at Public Citizen who authored the report on crypto election spending, referring to the landmark 2010 Supreme Court decision that opened the floodgates for virtually unlimited corporate spending in elections through outside groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crypto’s ballooning political war chest and voracious appetite to dangle money in front of lawmakers speaks to the power it has amassed over the past decade and a half, even as it has struggled to gain any real traction with the public.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Three-quarters of Americans who’ve heard of crypto aren’t confident in its safety and reliability, a 2023 <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2023/04/10/majority-of-americans-arent-confident-in-the-safety-and-reliability-of-cryptocurrency/">Pew Research survey</a> found, and only 7 percent of Americans used crypto last year, according <a href="https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/stock-market-today-dow-jones-05-21-2024/card/americans-crypto-use-down-in-2023-fed-reports-fQwS4X6E4ptB8Ec03Ysk">to the Federal Reserve</a>. Crypto’s reputation suffered in particular from the controversy surrounding crypto companies in the last few years, especially the catastrophic meltdown of <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23458837/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-sbf-downfall-explained">FTX</a>. Though the first cryptocurrency was launched in 2009, it still hasn’t penetrated as a mainstream <a href="https://www.pymnts.com/cryptocurrency/2024/crypto-is-minting-millionaires-but-its-payment-utility-remain-uncertain/">payment method</a>, with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2022/04/18/the-amc-mobile-app-for-u-s-theaters-now-accepts-dogecoin-shiba-inu-and-other-cryptocurrencies/">very</a> <a href="https://www.tesla.com/support/dogecoin">few</a> <a href="https://promotions.newegg.com/nepro/16-6277/index.html">retailers</a> allowing customers to pay directly with cryptocurrency. It remains mostly a vehicle for <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2022/08/23/46-of-americans-who-have-invested-in-cryptocurrency-say-its-done-worse-than-expected/">speculative investment</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite that — or because of it — crypto companies have redoubled their efforts to help elect pro-crypto politicians and lobby for policies that would boost the sector’s growth. The industry wants the influx of money it’s spending to send the clear message that the crypto craze isn’t over — and in fact, isn’t a craze at all, but the <a href="https://fortune.com/longform/coinbase-bitcoin-brian-armstrong/">lasting future of finance</a>. “Crypto is here to stay,” Paul Grewal, Coinbase’s chief legal officer, recently wrote in <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/blog/we-need-clear-rules-for-crypto-to-protect-american-leadership-and-consumers">public comments</a> regarding regulation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The sector’s most strident champions want you to believe that it’s a key issue for voters in the upcoming election, right next to inflation and health care. The industry is shouting from the rooftops that politicians can’t ignore crypto — and trying its hardest to make sure we won’t be able to either.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Crypto wants to get regulators off its back&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After a rough few years of being walloped by scandals and government crackdowns, crypto is facing an existential crisis. There are already some patchwork regulations governing the world of digital currencies, but one key issue remains hotly debated: Which government agency should oversee them?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the US, securities like stocks and bonds have to be <a href="https://www.sec.gov/resources-for-investors/investor-alerts-bulletins/exercise-caution-crypto-asset-securities-investor-alert">registered</a> with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), which comes with a host of disclosure requirements and other rules to protect investors.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>The industry wants the influx of money it’s spending to send the clear message that the crypto craze isn’t over — and in fact, isn’t a craze at all</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As far as the SEC is concerned, the law already puts most cryptocurrencies squarely under its purview, and the agency has been aggressively pursuing enforcement against <a href="https://www.vox.com/business-and-finance/2023/3/29/23662146/binance-crypto-exchange-government">crypto exchanges like Coinbase and Binance</a>, alleging that they’re running unregistered securities exchanges. But the crypto industry doesn’t want to be regulated by the SEC — it wants to fall under the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) instead.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The CFTC is a much smaller agency with far fewer resources,” says Molly White, a crypto researcher and critic who has been <a href="https://www.followthecrypto.org/">tracking</a> the industry’s political spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Right now, there are several bills trying to clear up which cryptocurrencies count as commodities — often a physical good, like oil or wheat — and would be overseen by the CFTC, and which are securities, essentially a stake in a company that you’re hoping will net you a profit thanks to the business savvy of the firm’s leaders. One bill popular among the pro-crypto crowd is the Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act, or <a href="https://financialservices.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=409277">FIT21</a> for short. It gives much of the regulatory authority of crypto over to the CFTC, and it likely means a “much riskier situation” for investors than if the SEC had primary oversight, says Claypool.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the last several years, the industry’s efforts to be placed under the CFTC haven’t exactly borne fruit, as the SEC has continued to come after them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Cozying up to politicians hasn’t shielded crypto from being held accountable. The most powerful names in the industry have long professed to want to cooperate with Washington. Before the collapse of FTX, founder Sam<strong> </strong>Bankman-Fried met with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-12-29/bankman-fried-met-white-house-aides-in-pre-collapse-crypto-push?embedded-checkout=true">Biden administration officials</a> at least four times in 2022, and even had a <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2023/02/gary-gensler-on-meeting-with-sbf-and-his-crypto-crackdown.html">private meeting</a> with SEC Chair Gary Gensler. That didn’t stop Bankman-Fried from being convicted on multiple federal charges of fraud and given a 25-year prison sentence. Prosecutors revealed in their indictment that the former FTX head had channeled <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/bankman-fried-used-customer-funds-100-mln-us-political-donations-prosecutors-say-2023-08-14/">over $100 million</a> to political contributions in the 2022 midterms, much of it to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/10/20/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-allies-donated-millions-in-dark-money.html">dark money</a> groups that don’t have to disclose their donors. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, crypto sees the 2024 election as vital to its survival. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“A lot of people view the current administration, and potential future administrations, as extremely hostile,” says White. “Not only toward the cryptocurrency industry — the companies that are actually operating in the United States — but toward cryptocurrency as a concept.”&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Where crypto money has gone</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One major change this election cycle is how much more visible and vocal the Trump-supporting faction of crypto proponents has become. Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss, who founded the crypto exchange Gemini, tried to donate roughly <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-21/winklevoss-twins-refunded-after-trump-crypto-gift-exceeded-limit">$1 million worth of bitcoin</a> each directly to the Trump campaign, apparently unaware it would exceed the FEC contribution limit. Venture capitalists Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz have both affirmed that they’re <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/07/16/andreessen-horowitz-co-founders-explain-why-theyre-supporting-trump/">joining Team Trump</a> too. Other backers include Jesse Powell, co-founder of the crypto exchange Kraken, and Charles Hoskinson, co-founder of the ethereum blockchain.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s worth noting that when Bankman-Fried was still the biggest face of crypto, he was known as a Democratic megadonor. We only found out later <a href="https://time.com/6241262/sam-bankman-fried-political-donations/">that he’d contributed roughly the same amount</a> to Republicans through dark money groups.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, for his part, was a harsh <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/07/27/politics/donald-trump-bitcoin-cryptocurrency/index.html">crypto critic</a> in the past, but has recently done a 180, saying he would end Biden’s “<a href="https://x.com/BitcoinMagazine/status/1803182597062668299">war on crypto,</a>” and that he would fire Gensler, the SEC chair. He even recently announced a family crypto project, run by the Trump Organization, called The DeFiant Ones — a play on “<a href="https://www.forbes.com/advisor/investing/cryptocurrency/defi-decentralized-finance/">decentralized finance</a>” — <a href="https://x.com/DonaldJTrumpJr/status/1826598601897742600">that would</a>, according to Trump, help Americans who have been “squeezed by the big banks and financial elites.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But crypto’s partisan inclinations are more complicated than simply supporting Republicans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The industry’s spending is funneled mostly through the pro-crypto super PAC Fairshake, which has already <a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/political-action-committees-pacs/fairshake-pac/C00835959/summary/2024">spent $93.8 million this election cycle</a> and is the second best-funded super PAC in the election, after Trump-backing Make America Great Again Inc. Fairshake’s backers include Coinbase, which has contributed a total of <a href="https://www.citizen.org/article/big-crypto-big-spending-2024/">$50 million</a> to the 2024 elections so far, and Ripple, a blockchain payment network that spent $49 million. (Both Coinbase and Ripple have faced SEC lawsuits.) Venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz has also contributed <a href="https://a16zcrypto.com/posts/article/contributing-to-fairshake-pac/">$47 million to Fairshake</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fairshake largely focuses on House and Senate races, and has been largely nonpartisan, supporting and opposing politicians of both parties based on their crypto stance. According to <a href="https://www.followthecrypto.org/">Follow the Crypto</a>, a project White launched earlier this year that compiles crypto’s campaign contributions, the money spent to support pro-crypto candidates was roughly even between Democrats and Republicans up until recently.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, the sector ramped up support spending for <a href="https://www.followthecrypto.org/elections/OH-S">Republican Bernie Moreno in his</a> race for a US Senate seat in Ohio, where he’ll go head-to-head with crypto critic Sen. Sherrod Brown. “Now Republican spending is about double that of the Democrats,” says White. (A recent Politico piece reported that the strategy for the Ohio race in particular is <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/09/08/inside-cryptos-civil-war-00176227">causing a rift</a> within crypto circles.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fairshake has enjoyed a good track record of <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/06/26/crypto-pac-house-senate-elections.html">backing the winning candidate</a> and unseating opponents this year. It spent <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/08/us/politics/crypto-super-pac-senate-oh-mt.html">$10 million</a> against Rep. Katie Porter (D-CA), a vocal crypto critic who voted against FIT21, and was recently defeated in the primary race earlier this year. It also spent $2 million to help defeat Rep. Jamaal Bowman (D-NY), and $1.4 million against Rep. Cori Bush (D-MO), also both defeated.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>The strategy of “[trying] to discipline elected officials to just cater to this sector’s needs is very concerning,” says Claypool. “It’s incredibly threatening.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The willingness to spend truckloads on both Democratic and Republican candidates makes clear that the industry is using a carrot-and-stick strategy. If you show a willingness to be friendly to the industry’s interests, Fairshake is willing to spend money on your behalf. But if you don’t — it will just back your opponent. The strategy of “[trying] to discipline elected officials to just cater to this sector’s needs is very concerning,” says Claypool. “It’s incredibly threatening.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fairshake has not returned a request for comment.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Crypto is the center of the universe</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crypto proponents often claim that somewhere in the neighborhood of 50 million Americans own the asset. It’s a stat that Tyler Winklevoss promoted when writing on X that being anti-crypto was “<a href="https://x.com/tyler/status/1815497425127199075">political suicide</a>.” Brian Quintenz, head of policy at Andreessen Horowitz’s crypto arm, wrote a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/11/16/egulate-crypto-dont-kill-it/">letter to the editor</a> in response to a critical Washington Post editorial, insisting on crypto’s widespread adoption and its <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a4F9u8Z84YI">populist mission</a>, writing that “good regulation would ensure the future of the internet is not solely controlled by a handful of tech companies.” Anthony Scaramucci, founder of SkyBridge Capital and a former communications director in Trump’s White House, said in a recent <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/crypto-voters-cost-harris-us-election-warns-sky-bridge-founder">interview with Cointelegraph</a> that Democratic presidential nominee Kamala Harris could lose the election if she didn’t court the crypto vote.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their sense of injury at not being acknowledged by America’s foremost politicians, including <a href="https://decrypt.co/248550/kamala-harris-policy-positions-bitcoin-crypto-mia">Harris</a>, represents a “weird reality distortion field that happens with the crypto world, where they think they’re sort of the center of the universe,” says White.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For all the strenuous appeals to how important an issue crypto is for everyday Americans, there’s no evidence that this is actually true. Crypto appears nowhere in <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2024/09/09/issues-and-the-2024-election/">various</a> <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1362236/most-important-voter-issues-us/">surveys</a> <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/how-economic-concerns-are-shaping-the-youth-vote-in-2024/">measuring</a> voters’ top concerns. Another telling sign: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zQ9qn_x2efg">The</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q0sEwgmoAyY">TV</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pfBdCSqouh4">ads</a> that Fairshake paid for don’t even mention this supposedly vital issue, instead focusing on more general attacks. “Everybody has seen ads from various corporate sectors, whether it’s the oil industry saying that such-and-such politician is going to make the price of gas go up,” says Claypool. “That’s not what the crypto sector is doing. They’re funding attack ads, and it’s all about electing crypto-friendly lawmakers, but they don’t say anything about crypto.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fighting for industry-friendly regulation serves another purpose beyond avoiding the grip of the SEC. Regulation helps legitimize crypto. It’s no longer a scary, risky thing with a shadowy undertone. Having a regulatory framework gives the industry a broad rubber stamp to keep chugging along now that the rules are clearer and the few bad apples have been rooted out. One <a href="https://www.grayscale.com/elections">recent survey</a>, for example, suggests that the SEC’s decision to allow bitcoin to be included in ETFs — which are a bundle of stocks that can be traded on an exchange — increased Americans’ interest in investing in crypto.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crypto companies argue that the volatility — and the <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/crypto-scam-risk-bbb-report/">rampant fraud</a> — are just the growing pains of a small, still-young sector. Yet if all goes according to the hopes and ambitions of its advocates, crypto would in fact transform how people invest their money and store their wealth, especially as its acceptance leads to more stock portfolios and even <a href="https://news.bloomberglaw.com/daily-labor-report/bitcoin-funds-set-new-precedent-for-crypto-401k-ira-investing">retirement</a> <a href="https://www.wpr.org/news/wisconsin-pension-fund-bitcoin">funds</a> containing crypto.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They want to be enmeshed in our financial system as much as they possibly can,” says Claypool. “The 2008 financial crisis demonstrated that there are benefits to being too big to fail.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Crypto’s future is a real concern for ordinary Americans, just not in the way the industry would like people to believe. Like the predatory <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2013-08-16/the-dramatic-racial-bias-of-subprime-lending-during-the-housing-boom">subprime mortgages</a> that led to the collapse of big banks in 2008, crypto has been sold <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23599845/crypto-bitcoin-black-investors-ftx-freedmans-bank-civil-war">particularly enthusiastically to Black Americans</a> and other marginalized groups, presented as an alternative to the traditional banking system that discriminates against them. We know what happened in the aftermath of the mortgage crisis: Black Americans’ homeownership rates fell, and they <a href="https://www.urban.org/urban-wire/black-homeownership-increased-slightly-during-pandemic-high-interest-rates-threaten">still haven&#8217;t fully recovered</a>. We don’t know what will happen if crypto becomes a juggernaut of the US financial sector, but many amateur crypto traders have already been <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/jul/12/they-couldnt-even-scream-any-more-they-were-just-sobbing-the-amateur-investors-ruined-by-the-crypto-crash">burned by crashes</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What’s certain is that the industry’s backers are unloading an arsenal of money to ensure all of us become more entangled in crypto, whether we want it or not.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the SpaceX spacewalk is such a huge deal]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/science/371656/spacex-spacewalk-elon-musk-jared-isaacman-sarah-gillis-space" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371656</id>
			<updated>2024-09-13T18:22:06Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-12T20:21:20Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Billionaires" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Elon Musk" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Influence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Space" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="SpaceX" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Tesla" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Billionaire Jared Isaacman and SpaceX engineer Sarah Gillis completed the first privately funded spacewalk Thursday —&#160;a critical aspect of a risky, somewhat troubled mission designed to test new SpaceX technology, gather valuable data about high-altitude space travel, and generally push the limits of space exploration.&#160; The mission, called Polaris Dawn, was supposed to launch in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket with the Crew Dragon Resilience spacecraft lifts off from the Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral, Florida, on September 10, 2024." data-caption="The privately funded Polaris Dawn mission lifted off on September 10 from the Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral. | Gregg Newton/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Gregg Newton/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/gettyimages-2170463991.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>The privately funded Polaris Dawn mission lifted off on September 10 from the Kennedy Space Center in Cape Canaveral. | Gregg Newton/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Billionaire Jared Isaacman and SpaceX engineer Sarah Gillis completed the first privately funded spacewalk Thursday —&nbsp;a critical aspect of a risky, somewhat troubled mission designed to test new SpaceX technology, gather valuable data about high-altitude space travel, and generally push the limits of space exploration.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The mission, <a href="https://www.vox.com/science/369106/spacex-polaris-dawn-jared-isaacman-elon-musk-tesla-space-crew-dragon">called Polaris Dawn</a>, was supposed to launch in late August, but was grounded due to safety concerns. But on Tuesday, Isaacman and Gillis — along with two other crew members, former Air Force pilot Scott Poteet and SpaceX engineer Anna Menon — <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/09/10/science/polaris-dawn-mission-spacex-launch/index.html">finally took off</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since then, the astronauts have gone about 870 miles from Earth, which makes Polaris Dawn the farthest crewed space mission since <a href="https://www.space.com/17287-apollo-17-last-moon-landing.html">the Apollo 17 mission to the moon in 1972</a>. They came closer to Earth — away from the high radiation levels they faced at the furthest point of their journey — for Thursday’s spacewalk.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Back at home, we all have a lot of work to do, but from here, Earth sure looks like a perfect world,” <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/11/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-astronauts-spacewalk.html">Isaacman said</a>, observing the planet from outside his SpaceX Crew Dragon spacecraft Thursday.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the spacewalk is complete, the astronauts aren’t done. Their mission is set to last five days — much shorter than typical NASA missions which can last weeks or months — but still includes dozens of experiments, and, critically, safely reentering the Earth’s atmosphere. </p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP9173794066" width="100%"></iframe>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why is SpaceX’s Polaris Dawn mission so groundbreaking?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SpaceX’s current mission is supposed to be the first of three Polaris missions, all funded by Isaacman and SpaceX, Elon Musk’s aerospace company.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The goal of the Polaris mission series is to help SpaceX develop the skills and technology needed to achieve its longer term goals of sending humans to Mars. The company hoped this first mission would be a useful test of the spacecraft and its instruments’ ability to survive the extreme conditions of space, particularly as it passes through the <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/phenomena/radiation-belts">Van Allen</a> radiation belts, <a href="https://spacecenter.org/what-are-the-van-allen-radiation-belts/#:~:text=The%20Van%20Allen%20radiation%20belt,by%20that%20planet%E2%80%99s%20magnetic%20field.">regions in space that encircle the planet and are highly radioactive</a>. They were detected on the first US space mission in 1958, and their highly charged, energetic particles can damage spacecraft instruments.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The crew traveled through the Van Allen belts on their way to the furthest point in their journey, and, so far, the tech aboard the capsule — and the astronauts — seem to have withstood that radiation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The trip was also a test of SpaceX’s latest spacesuit designs, which were designed <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/19/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-jared-isaacman-spacewalk/index.html">in just two and a half years</a> — an astonishingly quick turnaround by space exploration standards — and are meant to be upgrades to the bulky suits NASA has made famous. Rather than having life support systems integrated into the suit, like in NASA’s, Space X’s new suits connect to a spacecraft via a tube — all of the Polaris Dawn astronauts used that functionality to breathe while Isaacman and Gillis performed their spacewalk.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s because though only Isaacman and Gillis exited the craft, all four astronauts were exposed to space (and that means, technically, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/12/g-s1-22253/watch-spacewalk-spacex-astronauts?refresh=true">all four astronauts completed a spacewalk</a>). To complete the spacewalk, Isaacman and Gillis had to open the Crew Dragon’s hatch to exit, exposing everyone inside to vacuum. Though that was once the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/09/11/science/spacex-polaris-dawn-astronauts-spacewalk.html">preferred way for astronauts to leave</a> their spacecraft, modern astronauts usually&nbsp;exit via an airlock mechanism, which has two doors separated by a chamber so that the vacuum of space doesn’t enter into the spacecraft.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Exiting through the hatch appeared to be a success, and could be something future missions emulate in order to avoid the need for airlocks. During the walk — which saw Isaacman and Gillis holding onto a specialized ladder leading out of the crew capsule rather than floating freely through space — the astronauts completed a series of tests meant to check the maneuverability and functionality of the suits.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The suits were a particular area of focus for this mission not just because they are new, but because SpaceX sees getting an inexpensive, reliable spacesuit design down pat as being key to its long-term mission of supporting mass human colonization of space.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Building a base on the Moon and a city on Mars will require millions of spacesuits; the development of this suit and the execution of the EVA will be important steps toward a scalable design for spacesuits on future long-duration missions,” <a href="https://polarisprogram.com/dawn/">the company wrote on its website</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In their final days in space, the astronauts will do other experiments meant to support that long-term goal, including some related to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/science/live-news/spacex-polaris-dawn-spacewalk-09-12-24#h_f4d7d60732a017a4a0fbbc25518bd78b">motion sickness</a> and some focused on communications tests <a href="https://www.cnn.com/science/live-news/spacex-polaris-dawn-spacewalk-09-12-24#h_82bc37750b5c7c4cc1e943caf5f8ea4b">involving SpaceX’s Starlink satellites</a>. On Earth, those are used to provide internet service, particularly to remote locations; the astronauts will do some initial tests to check the satellites’ usefulness in communicating from space.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After those are complete, all that will be left is reentry — historically one of the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/spacex-spacewalk-private-polaris-dawn-87d4c78853f0249baf29631bedfac749">most dangerous parts of spaceflight</a>. It was during <a href="https://www.space.com/19436-columbia-disaster.html">reentry that NASA’s Columbia space shuttle</a> was destroyed in 2003.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once back, the astronauts will have completed a historic mission full of firsts: the first private spacewalk, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/09/12/g-s1-22253/watch-spacewalk-spacex-astronauts?refresh=true">the most astronauts spacewalking at once</a>, and Menon and Gillis will be the only women ever to travel such a distance from Earth.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Celia Ford</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Science has a short-term memory problem]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/370681/science-research-grants-scientific-progress-academia-slow-funding" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=370681</id>
			<updated>2024-09-12T18:13:45Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-12T18:13:45Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Back in 2016, Vox asked 270 scientists to name the biggest problems facing science. Many of them agreed that the constant search for funding, brought on by the increasingly competitive grant system, serves as one of the biggest barriers to scientific progress. Even though we have more scientists throwing more time and resources at projects, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A biologist peers into a microscope." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/diane-serik-M3t3E7gzPKQ-unsplash.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A biologist peers into a microscope.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Back in 2016, Vox asked 270 scientists to name the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/14/12016710/science-challeges-research-funding-peer-review-process#1">biggest problems facing science</a>. Many of them agreed that the constant search for funding, brought on by the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/1/18/18183939/science-funding-grant-lotteries-research">increasingly competitive grant system</a>, serves as one of the biggest barriers to scientific progress.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even though we have more scientists throwing more time and resources at projects, we seem to be blocked on big questions — like how to help people live healthier for longer — and that has major real-world impacts.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">This story was first featured in the <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Future Perfect newsletter</a>.</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Sign up <a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">here</a> to explore the big, complicated problems the world faces and the most efficient ways to solve them. Sent twice a week.</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Grants are funds given to researchers by the government or private organizations, ranging from tens to hundreds of thousands of dollars earmarked for a specific project. Most grant applications are very competitive. <a href="https://report.nih.gov/nihdatabook/category/10">Only about 20 percent</a> of applications for research project grants at the National Institutes of Health (NIH), which funds the vast majority of biomedical research in the US, are successful.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you do get a grant, they usually <a href="https://www.nigms.nih.gov/Research/Application/Pages/ResearchProjGrantDuration.aspx">expire after a few years</a> — far less time than it normally takes to make groundbreaking discoveries. And most grants, even the most prestigious ones, don’t provide enough money to keep a lab running on their own.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Between the endless cycle of grant applications and the constant turnover of early-career researchers in labs, pushing science forward is slow at best and Sisyphean at worst.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, science has a short-term memory problem — but there are steps funding agencies can take to make it better.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Grants are too small, too short, and too restrictive</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Principal investigators — often tenure-track university professors — doing academic research in the US are responsible not only for running their own lab, but also for funding it. That includes the costs of running experiments, keeping the lights on, hiring other scientists, and often covering their own salary, too. In this way, investigators are <a href="https://academia.stackexchange.com/questions/188722/why-do-academics-have-to-get-their-own-grants">more like entrepreneurs than employees</a>, running their labs like a small-business owner.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the US, basic science research, studying how the world works for the sake of expanding knowledge, is <a href="https://sgp.fas.org/crs/misc/R44307.pdf">mostly funded by the federal government</a>. The NIH funds the vast majority of biomedical research, and the National Science Foundation (NSF) funds other sciences, like astrophysics, geology, and genetics. The <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23384446/future-perfect-50-renee-wegrzyn-arpa-h">Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health</a> (ARPA-H) also funds some biomedical research, and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) funds technology development for the military, some of which finds uses in the civilian world, <a href="https://www.darpa.mil/about-us/timeline/modern-internet">like the internet</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The grant application system worked well a few decades ago, when <a href="http://mbio.asm.org/content/7/2/e00422-16.full">over half of submitted grants were funded</a>. But today, we have more scientists — <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6294951/">especially young ones</a> — and <a href="https://drugmonkey.scientopia.org/2020/12/16/updating-the-erosion-of-the-purchase-power-of-the-modular-nih-r01/">less money, once inflation</a> is taken into account. Getting a grant is harder than ever, scientists I spoke with said. What ends up happening is that principal investigators are forced to spend more of their time writing grant applications — which often take dozens of hours each —&nbsp;than actually doing the science they were trained for. Because funding is so competitive, applicants increasingly have to <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/1745691616687745">twist their research proposals</a> to align with whoever will give them money. A lab interested in studying how cells communicate with each other, for example, may spin it as a study of cancer, heart disease, or depression to convince the NIH that its project is worth funding.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Federal agencies generally fund specific projects, and require scientists to provide regular progress updates. Some of the best science happens when experiments lead researchers in unexpected directions, but grantees generally need to stick with the specific aims listed in their application or risk having their funding taken away — even if the first few days of an experiment suggest things won’t go as planned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This system leaves principal investigators constantly scrambling to plug holes in their patchwork of funding. In her first year as a tenure-track professor, <a href="https://www.buckinstitute.org/lab/garrison-lab/">Jennifer Garrison</a>, now a reproductive longevity researcher at the <a href="https://www.buckinstitute.org/">Buck Institute</a>, applied for 45 grants to get her lab off the ground. “I’m so highly trained and specialized,” she told me. “The fact that I spend the majority of my time on administrative paperwork is ridiculous.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Relying on a transient, underpaid workforce makes science worse</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the most part, the principal investigators applying for grants aren’t doing science — their graduate students and postdoctoral fellows are. While professors are teaching, doing administrative paperwork, and managing students, their early-career trainees are the ones who conduct the&nbsp;experiments and analyze data.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since they do the bulk of the intellectual and physical labor, these younger scientists are usually the lead authors of their lab’s publications. In smaller research groups, a grad student may be the only one who fully understands their project.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In some ways, this system works for universities. With most annual stipends falling <a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/loans/student-loans/how-much-do-graduate-students-get-paid">short of $40,000</a>, “Young researchers are highly trained but relatively inexpensive sources of labor for faculty,” then-graduate researcher Laura Weingartner <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/14/12016710/science-challeges-research-funding-peer-review-process#1">told Vox in 2016</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Grad students and postdocs are cheap, but they’re also transient. It takes an average of <a href="https://www.usnews.com/education/best-graduate-schools/articles/2019-08-12/how-long-does-it-take-to-get-a-phd-degree-and-should-you-get-one">six years to earn a PhD</a>, with only about three to five of those years devoted to research in a specific lab. This time constraint forces trainees to choose projects that can be wrapped up by the time they graduate, but science, especially groundbreaking science, rarely fits into a three- to five-year window. CRISPR, for instance, was <a href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/what-broad/areas-focus/project-spotlight/crispr-timeline">first characterized in the ’90s</a> — 20 years before it was first used for gene editing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trainees generally try to publish their findings by the time they leave, or pass ownership along to someone they have trained to take the wheel. The pressure to squeeze exciting, publishable data from a single PhD thesis project forces many inexperienced scientists into roles they can’t realistically fulfill. Many people (admittedly, <a href="https://neuroscience.berkeley.edu/news/2023-qa-neuroscience-phd-program-graduates">myself included</a>, as a burnt-out UC Berkeley neuroscience graduate student) wind up leaving a trail of unfinished experiments behind when they leave academia — and have no formal obligation to complete them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the bulk of your workforce is <a href="https://www.aps.org/apsnews/2024/03/grad-students-postdocs-fair-wages">underpaid</a>, <a href="https://gradresources.org/dealing-with-emotional-fatigue/">burning out</a>, and constantly turning over, it creates a continuity problem. When one person leaves, they often take a bunch of institutional knowledge with them. Ideally, research groups would have at least one or two senior scientists — with as much training as a tenured professor — working in the lab to run experiments, mentor newer scientists, and serve as a stable source of expertise as other researchers come and go.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One major barrier here: Paying a highly trained scientist enough to compete with six-figure industry jobs costs far more than a single federal grant can provide. One $250,000/year NIH R01 — the primary grant awarded to scientists for research projects — barely funds one person’s salary and benefits. While the NIH has specialized funding that students, postdocs, junior faculty, and other trainees can apply for to pay their own wages, funding opportunities for senior scientists are limited. “It’s just not feasible to pay for a senior scientist role unless you have an insane amount of other support,” Garrison told me.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How can we help scientists do cooler, more ambitious research?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Funding scientists themselves, rather than the experiments they say they’ll do, helps — and we already have some evidence to prove it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://hhmi.org/our-approach">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</a> (HHMI) has a funding model worth replicating. It is driven by a “people, not projects” philosophy, granting scientists many years worth of money, without tying them down to specific projects. Grantees continue working at their home institution, but they — along with their postdocs — become employees of HHMI, which pays their salary and benefits.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">HHMI reportedly provides enough funding to operate a small- to medium-sized lab without requiring any extra grants. The idea is that if investigators are simply given enough money to do their jobs, they can redirect all their wasted grant application time toward actually doing science. It’s no coincidence that <a href="https://hhmi.org/about/nobel-laureates">over 30 HHMI-funded scientists</a> have won Nobel Prizes in the past 50 years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://arcinstitute.org/">Arc Institute</a>, a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2021/12/18/22838746/biomedicine-science-grants-arc-institute">new, independent nonprofit collaboration</a><strong> </strong>partnered with<strong> </strong>research giants Stanford, UC Berkeley, and UC San Francisco, also provides investigators and their labs with renewable eight-year “no-strings-attached” grants. Arc aims to give scientists the freedom and resources to do the slow, unsexy work of developing better research tools — something crucial to science but unappealing to scientific journals (and scientists who need to publish stuff to earn more funding).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Operating Arc is expensive, and the funding model currently <a href="https://arcinstitute.org/about">relies on donations</a> from philanthropists and tech billionaires. Arc supports eight labs so far, and hopes to expand to no more than 350 scientists someday — far short of the <a href="https://nexus.od.nih.gov/all/2024/02/21/fy-2023-by-the-numbers-extramural-grant-investments-in-research/">50,000-some biomedical researchers</a> applying for grants every year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For now, institutional experiments like Arc are just that: experiments. They’re betting that scientists who feel invigorated, creative, and unburdened will be better equipped to take the risks required to make big discoveries.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Building brand-new institutions isn’t the only way to break the cycle of short-term, short-sighted projects in biomedical research. Anything that makes it financially easier for investigators to keep their labs running will help. Universities could pay the salaries of their employees directly, rather than making investigators find money for their trainees themselves. Federal funding agencies could also make grants bigger to <a href="https://nexus.od.nih.gov/all/2022/06/29/inflation-and-nih-research-project-grants/">match the level of inflation</a> — but Congress is unlikely to approve that kind of spending.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Science might also benefit from having fewer, better-paid scientists in long-term positions, rather than relying on the labor of underpaid, under-equipped trainees. “I think it would be better to have fewer scientists doing real, deep work than what we have now,” Garrison said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not that scientists aren’t capable of creative, exciting, ambitious work — they’ve just been forced to bend to a grant system that favors short, risk-averse projects. And if the grant system changes, odds are science will too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Clarification, September 12, 2:15 pm ET:</strong> This story, published September 11, has been changed to make it clearer that Arc Institute is independent from its university partners.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Raygun earned her breaking world champ spot — fair and square]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/367059/raygun-olympic-controversy-breaking-corruption" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367059</id>
			<updated>2024-09-12T15:35:27Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-12T15:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October 2023, members of the World DanceSport Federation, or WDSF, learned breaking, the sport they’d been trying to make happen at the Olympics for years, would not be appearing at the 2028 Los Angeles Games. In response, the organization’s president, Shawn Tay, made a grand proclamation. “Ensuring the success of breaking’s Olympic debut at [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Raygun, in a dark teal shirt, cap and pants, performs a “kangaroo hop” move in front of a panel of white-shirted Olympics breaking judges against a purple backdrop reading Paris 2024." data-caption="B-girl Raygun of Team Australia competes during the b-girls’ round robin at the Olympic Games Paris 2024. | Ezra Shaw/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Ezra Shaw/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166052398.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>B-girl Raygun of Team Australia competes during the b-girls’ round robin at the Olympic Games Paris 2024. | Ezra Shaw/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In October 2023, members of the <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/">World DanceSport Federation</a>, or WDSF, learned breaking, the sport they’d been trying to make happen at the Olympics for years, would not be appearing at the 2028 Los Angeles Games.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In response, the organization’s president, Shawn Tay, made a grand proclamation. “Ensuring the success of breaking’s Olympic debut at Paris 2024 is therefore on the forefront of the WDSF agenda,” he <a href="https://www.insidethegames.biz/articles/1141612/breaking-world-dance-sport-los-angeles">said</a>. “Our performance in Paris will define the future of dance sport within the Olympic Movement.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">…Oops?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Going into the games, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366017/breaking-olympic-sport-what-to-know">breaking had a lot riding</a> on its shoulders. But no one counted on Raygun — the newly infamous, 36-year-old, last-place Australian b-girl (as breakers are called) whose <a href="https://twitter.com/jwdaddy80/status/1822828281617666084">performance</a> on the Paris stage included bizarre floor-writhing, awkward freezes, and “original” moves like kangaroo hops.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Raygun, real name Rachael Gunn, instantly became a viral sensation — notoriety that only skyrocketed when the public learned that Gunn, who won none of her Olympics battles, actually has a PhD specializing in breakdancing. <a href="https://researchers.mq.edu.au/en/persons/rachael-gunn">Yes, really</a>. Gunn’s performance has not only overshadowed the two actual breaking gold medalists, Japan’s <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gfc_ami/">Yuasa Ami</a> and Canada’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qXMkP2zTXY0">Phil Wizard</a> (plus 16-year-old Australian b-boy <a href="https://www.instagram.com/j__attack/?">Jeff Dunne</a>), it’s arguably become the defining moment of a Parisian Games <a href="https://www.vox.com/sports/364856/olympics-boxing-imane-khelif-angela-carini">marked</a> by <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/12/sport/jordan-chiles-bronze-olympics-controversy-explained/index.html">controversy</a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/2024-olympics-seine-river-illness-02d937f2d5f0fd20efafbf2250264aea">absurdity</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gunn shocked the world again in September when <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn47e3pgr01o">she was ranked the No. 1 breaker</a> in the world, based on the WDSF’s rules, which exclude Olympic events (including qualifiers) from its assessment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alongside widespread mockery of Gunn herself runs speculation that Gunn’s presence at the Games and at the top of the rankings has to be some sort of mistake, even corruption. How did Raygun wind up at the Olympics when, for example, a couple of b-girls in Melbourne can serve these moves? </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-instagram wp-block-embed-instagram"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"><div> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank"> <div> <div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div><div></div> <div></div><div> <div>View this post on Instagram</div></div><div></div> <div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></a><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">A post shared by Ayvee (@__ayvee__)</a></p></div></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To answer this question, we have to go on a bit of a deep dive — so let’s (sorry) hop on in.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Reports Raygun manipulated her way into the Olympics couldn’t be further from the truth…</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For decades, the WDSF was <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366017/breaking-olympic-sport-what-to-know">devoted to ballroom dancing</a>. The association started in the late ’90s with a focus on winning a place in the Olympics for ballroom dancing before its subsequent pivot, around 2017, toward breaking. A quizzical backstory, yes — but it doesn’t make the organization less legitimate. <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/Officials/Te-Hiiritanga-Robert-Wepiha-5ea90df8-2e8b-4bc4-adfe-ae66008749d0">Te Hiiritanga Wepiha</a>, a.k.a. Rush, one of the judges in the women’s breaking final for the Oceania championship Gunn won, posted a 90-minute livestreamed <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-nA98kS4lL/?igsh=eWJuNTltMXZseW40">Instagram commentary</a> on Tuesday in response to the controversy. He pointed out that the WDSF judging system, used in the Olympics and its breaking qualifiers, requires judges to be veterans in the breaking scene, both as competitors and as judges, as well as to pass multiple exams. “You have to be trained to be a judge,” he insisted.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This wasn’t Gunn’s first rodeo either. Prior to her Olympics appearance, she represented Australia at multiple World Championship competitions between 2021 and 2023. She <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--hnj1cNLL4">judged</a> Red Bull’s preeminent BC One breaking contest. She’s an established local champ.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet following Gunn’s appearance at the Olympics, a <a href="https://www.change.org/p/hold-raygun-rachel-gunn-anna-mears-accountable-for-unethical-conduct-olympic-selection">petition</a> circulated claiming, without sources, that Gunn and her husband, breaking coach Samuel Free, had manipulated the entire WDSF system in order to gain a spot at the Olympics. The petition falsely claimed Gunn had judged herself at the qualifying Oceania championship competition — despite the judges’ list for the event being <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/Competitions/Officials/Oceania-Championship-Sydney-Adult-Breaking-1vs1-B-Girls-60318">readily available</a> on the WDSF website.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other rumors further <a href="https://twitter.com/CLouvres/status/1823211157014085981">alleged</a>, again without any apparent sourcing, that Gunn and her husband were the masterminds behind the Australian Breaking Association, better known as <a href="https://ausbreak.org/">AUSBreaking</a> — another <a href="https://www.acnc.gov.au/charity/charities/582aa363-5afb-e911-a811-000d3ad1f29c/people">easily debunked</a> claim. An AUSBreaking spokesperson further confirmed to Vox in an email that Gunn and her husband did not found the organization. Gunn doesn’t appear to be directly responsible for managing, or funding, any breaking group, which likely also negates the petition’s claim that she denied travel funding to a marginalized dance crew from Australia’s Northern Territory.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>…But that doesn’t mean it’s easy to understand how she got there</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The subtext of this criticism — that Gunn benefited from her whiteness — has merit. Gunn was educated at one of Sydney’s most elite high schools; she had the opportunity to get a PhD in an obscure field, and the wealth to fund appearances at international breaking competitions. Her white privilege in a dance scene rife with cultural appropriation makes her an easy target for criticism. At the same time, some have tried to argue she represents exactly the opposite — a “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iudBeuoA2RA">diversity hire</a>” and Australian “<a href="https://twitter.com/ConceptualJames/status/1823012007324385763">wokeness</a>” gone wrong. “People have jumped on and used her as the new scapegoat to further their cause,” Wepiha observed in his livestream.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We never thought this would happen,” he told me. “She’s getting torn down by a lot of people.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, while the rest of the world has put Gunn through the ringer since her Paris appearance, the actual breaking community seems to have <a href="https://www.ktiv.com/2024/08/12/breaking-community-defends-b-girl-raygun-breaking-is-all-about-originality-bringing-something-new-table/">rallied</a> behind her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is what happens when people outside of our dance want to control the narrative but have absolutely no expertise of technical knowledge on our dance, particularly in an Oceania context,” Dujon Cullingford, a veteran New Zealand breaker who attended the Oceania qualifiers, told me. Cullingford <a href="https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=10160560771447967&amp;id=536182966&amp;mibextid=WC7FNe&amp;rdid=HzSLKjOFKIwxikNK">wrote a Facebook post</a> arguing against the idea Gunn benefited from any factor besides a small talent pool.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He emphasized that Oceania’s breaking community is tiny; one of Gunn’s own <a href="https://research-management.mq.edu.au/ws/portalfiles/portal/338493337/Publisher_version.pdf">articles</a> placed the number of Australian breakers at around 400, total, and Wepiha claimed the WDSF had to “get people out of retirement in order to make up the numbers” of competitors. One of the main criticisms being bandied about concerns a public <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MorhA98eK7M&amp;lc=Ugxxry-kM60vXoyI98V4AaABAg">perception</a> that the WDSF must not have been promoting their events among “real” breaking scenes, but rather elitist communities like universities. But both Cullingford and Wepiha rejected this idea. “It’s very easy to know if there’s a jam on because the scene is tiny,” Wepiha said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Down here, like other countries, we feel the squeeze of cost of living, and the breaking scene is small so it doesn&#8217;t produce a lot of people who have time to teach, lead crews, and mobilize the community in the same way,” Cullingford said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He noted that, further diminishing the small talent pool, many breakers chose not to compete in the Olympics qualifiers because they didn’t want to shell out the cash needed to travel to the competition in Sydney last November. Additionally, many breakers simply had no interest in participating due to the feeling that the efforts of the establishment to rope breaking into the rigid organizational structure of the Games was antithetical to street dance culture. According to Wepiha, many dancers felt informal jams are more expressive with less strict judging — the kind of breaking they want to do, as opposed to Olympic-level battling.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then there was Raygun. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She rocked up like everybody else,” Wepiha said in his livestream regarding Gunn’s Oceania qualifier. “She won fair and square.” He pointed out that of the 10 judges at the event, only one was white and none were Australian — a fact AUSBreaking also confirmed to Vox. “She won by majority decision, she battled like everyone else … it’s not that deep.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can judge for yourself: in the Oceania Championships Raygun won which secured her spot in the Olympics, she netted 51 overall points to 50 scored by her opponent Holy Molly (Molly Chapman). The crucial final points came in this battle when the pair faced off, with Raygun winning two of three rounds.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="RAYGUN VS MOLLY | FINAL BGIRL | WDSF OCEANIA BREAKING CHAMPIONSHIPS 2023" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MorhA98eK7M?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Gunn became a viral sensation, many people have watched this battle and claimed that Molly was the clear winner, but it’s not so simple. For one thing, these judges had seen their overall performances throughout the competition. If Molly was recycling moves from previous battles while Raygun kept things unique, the judges probably would have favored Raygun. Other factors to keep in mind include things like who was more on beat, which dancer spent more time on floor moves as opposed to the transitional dance moves called toprock, whose movements were stronger and more fluid, whose moves were crisper and more precise, and whose transitions were more interesting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prior to this, both Chapman and Gunn competed in the World Championships in Belgium in September 2023. While neither of them qualified then, out of 80 competitors, Gunn <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/culture/celebrity/the-inside-story-of-how-raygun-broke-into-the-olympics-20240812-p5k1mg.html">ranked</a> 64th — a full 15 slots ahead of Chapman, who came in next to last. Not only that, but thanks to <em>another</em> regional first-place win that Raygun scored in October 2023, she is currently at the top of the world rankings due to the way the WDSF <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/News/WDSF-Statement-Regarding-World-B-Girl-Ranking-List-3479">awards points</a> to non-qualifier competitions. That’s right — Raygun, for a hot minute, is the No. 1 ranked breaker in the world, fair and square, before the rankings are expected to reset in October. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this means, despite the viral narrative that’s attached to her, it isn’t as simple as writing Gunn’s Olympics entrance off as a hilarious fluke or a mark of privileged corruption. Indeed,&nbsp;according to Gunn, she intended to bring a style of movement to the Paris Games that was less about meeting expectations and more about making an indelible impact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What I wanted to do was come out here and do something new and different and creative — that’s my strength, my creativity,” Gunn <a href="https://www.espn.com/olympics/story/_/id/40798973/paris-2024-olympics-raygun-fails-fire-breakdancing-breaking-debut">told ESPN</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was never going to beat these girls on what they do best, the dynamic and the power moves, so I wanted to move differently, be artistic and creative because how many chances do you get … in a lifetime to do that.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Score by score, Raygun’s dancing isn’t actually that bad. Really.</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gunn has been reflecting on what her style is for some time. In one of her academic articles on breaking, she <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/305519064_Don't_Worry_it's_Just_a_Girl_Negotiating_and_Challenging_Gendered_Assumptions_in_Sydney's_Breakdancing_Scene">argues</a>, “Gender norms both articulate and limit my corporeal potential.” Gunn has also written about what she sees as the dance’s “normative construction” of masculinity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, the weirdness of Gunn’s dance … might be the whole point. Moreover, in more informal breaking venues, it’s not even that weird. “What Raygun showcased at the Olympics is that breaking is a spectrum,” Wepiha said in his livestream. He argued her style represents that more informal, self-expressive side of street dance. “She went up there and did what a lot of you complaining could never do. She was her authentic self.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You may well ask: But don’t we have to hold Olympians to a higher standard of excellence? Even if that excellence is forged from a masculinist construction of athleticism and dance?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well… do we? There’s every indication Gunn is currently the most famous b-girl in the world, and while most people are laughing at her, not with her, somewhere in the wide vast world of breaking, other b-girls may feel inspired rather than shamed and mortified.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, even by the Olympic standards, Gunn didn’t do that badly. If you look at the <a href="https://olympics.com/en/paris-2024/results/breaking/b-girls/gpb-000200--">judges’ scoring</a>, for example, of her battle with US breaker Logistx, you can see that while she nabbed zero rounds, a handful of judges had her beating Logistx in some subcategories, usually originality. Meanwhile, while Logistx won most categories, she typically<em> </em>only won by a few percentage points at best.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, Gunn arguably held her own at the Olympics under a once-in-a-lifetime amount of pressure, and she did it while trying out her own unique style.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Was it great? No. Was it bad? Evidently not as bad as we thought.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ambiguity leaves us with a mess; many (though certainly <a href="https://x.com/wrong_speak/status/1823002717905711398">not all</a>) of the people heaping criticism upon Gunn are people who barely knew what breaking was a fortnight ago, while many of the people rushing to defend her are breaking veterans. In between are the people who just want to meme. The situation has some Australian breakers <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/aug/14/raygun-breaking-paris-olympics-australian-dance-industry">worried</a> the backlash will drive away sponsors and support — which, Wepiha told me, was already a concern given the lack of government funding for breaking as an art form.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for Gunn, “Above all she’s a human being,” Wepiha said. “We first and foremost just hope that she’s all right.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet if there’s one thing we know about breaking, it’s that it takes a lot more than ridicule to, well, break it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Update, September 12, 11:15 am: </em></strong><em>This story was originally published on August 14 and has been updated to include Raygun’s No. 1 ranking.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Constance Grady</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Taylor Swift’s Kamala Harris endorsement actually matter?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/371396/taylor-swift-kamala-harris-endorsement-democrats-elon-musk" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371396</id>
			<updated>2024-09-12T14:42:20Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-12T14:42:18Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Kamala Harris" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taylor Swift, always noted for her flair for dramatic timing, finally endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris in the presidential race Tuesday night.&#160; Moments after the first debate between Harris and former President Donald Trump, Swift posted her endorsement to Instagram, with a picture of herself posing with her now almost-equally famous cat. Meanwhile, Harris walked [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Taylor Swift stands against a bright pink stage backdrop in a sparkly bodysuit, holding a microphone. She is twirling her hair in an exaggerated motion to suggest coyness." data-caption="Who’s afraid of little ol’ her? Taylor Swift in concert at the Eras tour in London, August 15, 2024. | Kate Green/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kate Green/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-2166913977.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Who’s afraid of little ol’ her? Taylor Swift in concert at the Eras tour in London, August 15, 2024. | Kate Green/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Taylor Swift, always noted for her flair for dramatic timing, finally endorsed Vice President Kamala Harris in the presidential race Tuesday night.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Moments after the first debate between Harris and former President Donald Trump, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/">Swift posted her endorsement to Instagram</a>, with a picture of herself posing with her now almost-equally famous cat. Meanwhile, Harris walked off the stage at her post-debate party with Swift’s feminist anthem “The Man” blaring. The entire endorsement was a carefully choreographed move coming after nearly a year of speculation, disappointment, and paranoia from political onlookers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m voting for @kamalaharris because she fights for the rights and causes I believe need a warrior to champion them,” Swift wrote, urging her followers to do their own research and make their own choices. She signed off with what appeared to be a jab at VP nominee Sen. <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/364369/trump-kamala-not-black-indian-vance-childless-cat-ladies">JD Vance’s infamous “cat lady”</a> sound bite: “Taylor Swift, Childless Cat Lady.”&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-instagram wp-block-embed-instagram"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"><div> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank"> <div> <div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div><div></div> <div></div><div> <div>View this post on Instagram</div></div><div></div> <div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></a><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_wtAOKOW1z/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">A post shared by Taylor Swift (@taylorswift)</a></p></div></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the post, Swift unambiguously states that she’s voting for Harris and her running mate Gov. Tim Walz because of their support for such feminist issues as “LGBTQ+ rights, IVF, and a woman’s right to her own body.” At the same time, she makes space for potentially millions of fans who might not feel the same way.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If you haven’t already, now is a great time to do your research on the issues at hand and the stances these candidates take on the topics that matter to you the most,” Swift writes. “As a voter, I make sure to watch and read everything I can about their proposed policies and plans for this country.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Her endorsement drew jubilation among some quarters, as well as vitriol in others. Elon Musk had perhaps the most bizarre and off-putting response. “Fine Taylor … you win … I will give you a child and guard your cats with my life,” <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1833728804579111268">Musk wrote on X</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Onlookers have been breathlessly speculating about whether and when Swift will weigh in on this election all year. In January, after Swift began her much-publicized <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2023/9/25/23889682/taylor-swift-travis-kelces-date-nfl-chiefs-game">romance with NFL star Travis Kelce</a>, conservatives theorized that Swift was a deep-state psyop. The idea was that her relationship with Kelce was a ploy to juice her popularity so that her eventual endorsement of Joe Biden, then the Democratic nominee, would be all the more impactful.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The same month, the New York Times reported that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/29/us/politics/biden-trump-election-taylor-swift.html">the Biden campaign was actively courting Swift’s endorsement</a>, and that she was their “biggest and most influential” target. “Fund-raising appeals from Ms. Swift could be worth millions of dollars for Mr. Biden,” the Times noted.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump, predictably, was incensed at the very idea. “There&#8217;s no way she could endorse Crooked Joe Biden, the worst and most corrupt President in the History of our Country, and be disloyal to the man who made her so much money,&#8221; <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/02/11/1230747538/donald-trump-taylor-swift-biden-endorsement-disloyal">he posted on Truth Social in February</a>, apparently referring to his role in signing the <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/10/11/17965690/music-modernization-act-copyright-law-licensing-streaming">Music Modernization Act</a>.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>Reading the tea leaves of a possible Swift endorsement became a fever-pitched and chaotic guessing game in the months following</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After Harris became the Democratic nominee in July, she received <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-news/kamala-harris-celebrity-endorsements-cardi-b-charli-xcx-barbra-streisand-1235065132/">a slew of celebrity endorsements</a> from the likes of Charli XCX, Megan Thee Stallion, and Cardi B. Even Beyoncé gave Harris permission to use her song “Freedom” in campaign ads, a de facto endorsement from one of the most powerfully elusive figures in pop culture. Reading the tea leaves of a possible Swift endorsement became a fever-pitched and chaotic guessing game in the months following.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In August, rumors flew over one of Swift’s Instagram posts, in which Swift was pictured on stage at one of her concerts next to the silhouette of a strong-shouldered woman. To some observers, it looked as though <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/general-news/taylor-swift-kamala-harris-silhouette-instagram-endorse-walz-election-1235968005/">Swift had photoshopped Harris’s</a> shadow into the frame as an easter egg to let the sharp-eyed know her endorsement would be forthcoming. She hadn’t: The woman was one of her backup dancers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some Swift fans cautioned patience. On the occasions when Swift has made political endorsements in the past, she’s usually done so relatively late in the race. In 2016, she didn’t endorse at all. In 2018, she got politically involved for the first time, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2018/10/07/taylor-swift-endorses-democrats-bredesen-cooper-in-instagram-post.html">endorsing Democrats</a> Phil Bredesen and Jim Cooper for Congress on October 7, two days before the voter registration deadline in Tennessee. In 2020, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2020-election/taylor-swift-endorses-joe-biden-president-n1242483">Swift similarly endorsed Joe Biden on October 7</a>. Expecting an endorsement in August, her fans said, was too early for her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, as the months wore on, there was a growing outcry among some of her fans. Trump shared <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/article/2024/aug/24/trump-taylor-swift-deepfakes-ai">a series of AI-generated images</a> falsely claiming Swift had endorsed him, but Swift said nothing. Her new friend Brittany Mahomes <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/369543/brittany-mahomes-likes-trump-instagram">went public with her support</a> of Trump, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/stephaniesoteriou/taylor-swift-embrace-trump-supporter-brittany-mahomes">but Swift publicly embraced her</a> at the highly photographed US Open shortly thereafter.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-instagram wp-block-embed-instagram"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qsMcbyHeT/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"><div> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qsMcbyHeT/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank"> <div> <div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div><div></div> <div></div><div> <div>View this post on Instagram</div></div><div></div> <div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></a><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C_qsMcbyHeT/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">A post shared by ExtraTV (@extratv)</a></p></div></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fervor with which people have speculated about what Swift would do is striking, considering that celebrity political endorsements appear to be a mixed bag with relatively narrow effects. <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/365865/celebrity-endorsements-kamala-harris-megan-thee-stallion">As Li Zhou has reported for Vox</a>, celebrities can be good at getting people to pay attention to a race, or at heightening excitement about a candidate that people are already interested in, but they’re not necessarily good at changing people’s minds across party lines.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might be more likely to tune into the DNC if you think <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/368466/dnc-beyonce-taylor-swift-rumors-reports">Swift or Beyoncé is going to show up</a>, but there’s little evidence that their presence could turn you from an undecided voter into a committed Harris supporter. At best, celebrity endorsements might convince some otherwise unenthusiastic people at the margins to turn out and vote.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At worst, there’s some evidence that the <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2016/11/election-celebrities-trump-clinton-endorsements-beyonce-springsteen-david-jackson-bowling-green/507383/">plethora of celebrity endorsements for Hillary Clinton</a> in 2016 hurt her rather than helped her, strengthening the sense that she was a candidate for the liberal elite. That’s the reason Swift said she <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/8/8/20791816/taylor-swift-hillary-clinton-2016-endorsement-vogue-september-issue">decided not to endorse Clinton</a>. “​Unfortunately in the 2016 election you had a political opponent who was weaponizing the idea of the celebrity endorsement,” <a href="https://www.vogue.com/article/taylor-swift-cover-september-2019">Swift told Vogue in 2019</a>. “He was going around saying, <em>I’m a man of the people. I’m for you. I care about you.</em> I just knew I wasn’t going to help.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift’s previous political actions have generally followed the pattern you would expect from the data: good for overall political engagement, less good for any one political candidate. She’s great at getting people to register to vote. Last year, a single Instagram story from her led to a <a href="https://www.npr.org/2023/09/22/1201183160/taylor-swift-instagram-voter-registration">23 percent increase in voter registration</a>. In 2018, a similar Instagram post <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/10/10/17957190/taylor-swift-voter-registration-october-spike">led to 65,000 new registrations </a>in 24 hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift seems to know her strength here. Tuesday’s Instagram post endorsing Harris included a reminder to her fans to make sure they’re registered to vote, and an Instagram story linked fans to vote.gov.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, even after Swift’s endorsement, <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/entertainment/music/2018/11/07/taylor-swift-bredesen-endorsement-tennessee-senate-race-political-post/1918440002/">Phil Bredesen handily lost his 2018 campaign</a> for the Senate in Tennessee. Swift may have moved the needle for him, but not enough to get a Democratic senator elected in a red state.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The 2024 presidential election is projected to be much closer. “Biden’s electoral vote majority was a function of fewer than 50,000 votes in three states four years ago,” <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/08/12/is-taylor-swift-finally-big-enough-affect-election/">pointed out the Washington Post in August</a>. “Getting a small segment of the massive Taylor Swift fan base to vote that otherwise wouldn’t? Hard to dismiss the idea that it could tip the balance.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, given the mixed track record, it’s fair to ask why people are so worked up about Swift’s political endorsements.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are basically two factors at play behind this fascination. The first is her image. The second is her stature.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift has played with pop feminism through much of her career. <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/taylor-swift-and-the-bran_b_11101662">In 2014 she declared that she identified as a feminist</a> and positioned her <em>1989</em> tour, girl squad and all, as a feminist act. When she was mocked at the Golden Globes, <a href="https://www.avclub.com/taylor-swift-golden-globes-tina-fey-joke-career-1851152564">she declared the jokes anti-feminist</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/21/21189239/taylor-swift-kanye-west-famous-leaked-phone-call-kanye-west-is-over-party">After her public downfall in 2016</a>, Swift rehabilitated her image in part by leaning into politics. Her 2020 documentary <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/1/28/21095321/miss-americana-taylor-swift-documentary-interview-lana-wilson-netflix-sundance"><em>Miss Americana</em></a> features a scene in which Swift weeps while begging her father and management team to get on board with her endorsing Democrats for Congress. “I need to be on the right side of history!” she cries. Shortly after that encounter, she released her song “<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/2/27/21155844/taylor-swift-the-man-video">The Man</a>,” in which she argues that she comes in for public criticism because of her gender.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That led many of Swift’s fans to expect her to walk the walk. The price of starting so many sentences with “As a woman in this industry,” they argue, is that you also have to say something when the known <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23696250/e-jean-carroll-trump-trial-sexual-misconduct-rape-allegations">sexual abuser</a> who ended <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is running for president against a woman who’s campaigning <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024-elections/368489/kamala-harris-dnc-speech-takeaways-analysis">on a platform of reproductive rights</a>. Swift’s continued silence, even after Trump used AI to speak for her, had those fans worried.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>With this new endorsement, Swift can assure her fans she’s still got her feminist cred, even as she’s phrased it carefully to give her more Trump-leaning fans room for plausible deniability</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Given … how much mileage Swift got in the past out of her decision to speak out on politics, the idea that she will remain silent would seem to make her past speaking out, at a more convenient moment, appear cynical,” <a href="https://variety.com/2024/music/opinion/taylor-swift-kamala-harris-1236138123/">wrote Daniel D’Addario for Variety earlier this week</a>. “It’d be regrettable if her engagement with the world of politics were just another of her eras, and one from which she were willing to move on.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With this new endorsement, Swift can assure her fans she’s still got her feminist cred, even as she’s phrased it carefully to give her more Trump-leaning fans room for plausible deniability. She’s successfully beaten back charges of hypocrisy and bandwagon feminism, and her star can continue to shine.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The bigger reason so many are so concerned with Swift’s endorsement, however, is her singular&nbsp;stature in the pop culture landscape. Taylor Swift has been a huge star for years, but with the success of the Eras tour, she’s ascended to <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23905279/taylor-swift-eras-concert-film-image-analysis">a new level of superstardom and cultural saturation</a>. Political onlookers seem to think Swift has become so powerful that there’s a chance her say-so might actually swing the needle in a meaningful direction.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swift probably won’t change the minds of many people, because no celebrity can do that. But celebrities are good at activating voters on the margins, and Swift’s reach is broad enough at this point that her impact there could make a real difference come November.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Just the possibility that she might seems to be threatening to some on the right: see Musk’s response offering to “give [Swift] a child.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He’s ostensibly responding to Swift calling herself a “childless cat lady.” But there’s a crude implied threat in his offer, too: <em>let me knock you up so you stop talking</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an election cycle <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/366601/the-rights-plan-to-fix-america-patriarchy-2-0">laced with misogynistic rhetoric</a>, Swift’s cautious, carefully phrased endorsement was enough to make her a target of threats from one of the richest men in the world. Musk’s post is a tell that even Swift’s most measured political speech can be a threat to a political movement arrayed against women having control of their bodies and voices — and Swift’s voice is much louder than most. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Correction, September 12, 10:45 am: </strong>This story, originally published September 11, incorrectly dated a Washington Post article; it was from August 2024</em>. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kelsey Piper</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Shrinking the economy won’t save the planet]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/371640/economic-growth-climate-change-degrowth-science-global-warming" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=371640</id>
			<updated>2024-09-12T18:33:48Z</updated>
			<published>2024-09-12T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Poverty" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Could we solve climate change if we just accepted being dramatically poorer, forever?&#160; As I’ve written before, the answer is 1) no, not really, and 2) we can also solve climate change without that, and that will be better for everyone — especially those who are already poor — so we should do that instead. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A crowd of protesters walking down a tree-lined city street carry a banner reading “Degrowth now.”" data-caption="Protesters hold a sign reading “Degrowth Now” after they blocked the A12 highway during an Extinction Rebellion protest on March 11, 2023, in The Hague, Netherlands. | &lt;p style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Michel Porro/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-portal-copyright="&lt;p style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Michel Porro/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/09/GettyImages-1248032807.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Protesters hold a sign reading “Degrowth Now” after they blocked the A12 highway during an Extinction Rebellion protest on March 11, 2023, in The Hague, Netherlands. | &lt;p style=&quot;caret-color: rgb(0, 0, 0); color: rgb(0, 0, 0); white-space: normal;&quot;&gt;Michel Porro/Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Could we solve climate change if we just accepted being dramatically poorer, forever?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As I’ve <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22408556/save-planet-shrink-economy-degrowth">written before</a>, the answer is 1) no, not really, and 2) we can also solve climate change without that, and that will be better for everyone — especially those who are already poor — so we should do that instead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this idea has stuck around in the form of the <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2022/06/what-is-degrowth-economics-climate-change/">“degrowth” movement</a>, which argues that “economic growth” as an objective <a href="https://degrowth.info/en/degrowth">inevitably leads</a> to environmental destruction and that we should focus away from economic growth and toward ways to improve quality of life without it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Degrowth has always been a bit of a moving target. Even mainstream economists will agree that GDP alone doesn’t measure whether a life is meaningful and fulfilling, but they will also point out that as <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/happiness-and-life-satisfaction">countries get richer, they also get healthier and happier</a>. Is degrowth just the uncontroversial claim that what really matters is people leading good lives, or is it the wildly controversial claim that people would lead equally good lives even if we were to systematically shrink GDP in rich countries to focus on sustainability? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think a lot of people find something appealing about the rhetoric of degrowthism: anti-consumerism, a simpler life, local food, etc. But widespread adoption of all of those things would do <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23132579/eat-local-csa-farmers-markets-locavore-slow-food">approximately nothing</a> about climate change or the other environmental issues the movement cares so much about. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And while degrowth positions itself as a policy platform, it’s <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/degrowth-movement-is-politically-impractical-by-alessio-terzi-2024-03">political poison</a>. As soon as you start getting into details, it’s hard to come up with anything that polls worse than a steadily shrinking economy and the end of the conveniences of modern life. That makes it a policy agenda without any proposals about how it would become a law, an agenda that would sink any politician who attached themselves to it. (Not that you’re likely to find one.) </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this combines to make the degrowth literature — which has by this point become an <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/08/books/review/shrink-the-economy-save-the-world.html">enormous body of work</a> — frustrating. Degrowthers understandably expect people who want to criticize their movement to engage with its literature. One of the <a href="https://x.com/jasonhickel/status/1423633532006674438?lang=en">most frequent responses</a> to criticism is that the critics have engaged with only a tiny fraction of the degrowth literature out there. That’s true, but at the same time, no one can seriously engage with hundreds of papers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact that there’s so much written about degrowth doesn’t mean there’s good answers hidden somewhere in the pile of papers. I’ve increasingly gotten the sense that the movement’s contributors are effectively in an academic echo chamber, publishing papers that only they read and that don’t address any of the reservations of their critics. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A new <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921800924002210">fiercely critical review of the degrowth literature</a>, published in the journal <em>Ecological Economics</em>, sums up everything that’s gone wrong. But it also offers the degrowth community the serious critical engagement it will need if it wants to move from idle speculation to a workable policy program.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s wrong with the degrowth literature?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The authors analyzed 561 papers about degrowth in an effort to describe where the field is at today. What they uncovered was profoundly discouraging. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Their major takeaways: Of the 561 studies, “the large majority (almost 90%) of studies are opinions rather than analysis … most studies offer ad hoc and subjective policy advice, lacking policy evaluation and integration with insights from the literature on environmental/climate policies … Data analysis is often superficial and incomplete … studies tend to not satisfy accepted standards for good research.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s rare to see a critique this stark of an entire field’s academic literature in a respected journal that is itself within that field (<em>Ecological Economics</em> publishes papers on degrowth). And, to be clear, these are some extremely damning critiques. They paint a picture of a field that’s unserious about the actual standards of academic work, one flooded with papers (many of them in reasonably respected journals) but conducted totally without reference to everything we actually know about how climate, development, and policy work. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reading this review, one comes away with the impression that the degrowth literature is fundamentally unserious. The authors of the review say, “[O]ne is inclined to infer that degrowth cannot (yet) be considered as a significant field of academic research.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The review describes paper after paper with meaninglessly tiny sample sizes: sociological interviews with 10 volunteers who make handicrafts for a charity in a town in Germany, 12 <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/14766825.2020.1832103">interviews with residents of a town near Barcelona about tourism</a>, eight <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0921800924002210#bb0145">interviews with environmental justice leaders in Croatia</a>. Even a healthy field will have the occasional paper with a tiny sample size or that’s methodologically shaky, but the popularity of these tiny sample-size qualitative interview-based studies is typical of a field in its infancy that hasn’t yet nailed down its core questions or methodologies. </p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Degrowthism isn’t ready</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this is a significant problem. If a policy proposal is intended to solve a problem like climate change, it needs to be put into effect worldwide within the next decade or two. That’s not the stage of policy maturity where you publish lots of interviews with volunteers at NGOs; it’s the stage of policy maturity where you are expected to have (and where the <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/syr/">mainstream climate policy literature</a> does have) specific by-country emissions targets, breakdowns of possible routes for that country’s energy demand to be met while those emissions targets are met, and analyses of the trajectory so far. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might expect that the field would have these struggles as it was new but would have higher-quality research as it matured. That does not appear to be the case with degrowthism, which has its <a href="https://degrowth.info/en/history">origins as far back</a> as the 1972 report “<a href="https://www.clubofrome.org/publication/the-limits-to-growth/">The Limits to Growth</a>” by the Club of Rome. As the review authors concluded: “There is also no indication that things are improving with time.” Recent work is just as far from meeting scientific standards as older work. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of this surprised me as someone who has tried in the past to wade through the degrowth literature for my reporting. But I am glad the review was comprehensively written up and published in a journal that people who believe in degrowth actually read. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you think that our world needs degrowth, then the horrendously poor quality of the degrowth literature isn’t just annoying, it’s a serious emergency. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The more important a problem is, the more important it is to do high-quality, comprehensive, well-justified work on it. If degrowth ideas have something to offer the world, it’s all the more important that they adhere to normal standards about how to do research.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story originally appeared in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect">Future Perfect</a>&nbsp;newsletter.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup">Sign up here!</a></em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
