<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-06-28T23:16:49Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Zack Beauchamp</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[You’re a liberal and you don’t even know it]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/356824/liberalism-way-of-life-lefebvre" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356824</id>
			<updated>2024-06-27T18:25:30Z</updated>
			<published>2024-07-01T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 1955, the philosopher Charles Frankel was troubled. A committed civil libertarian, he had come to believe that the prevailing winds of public life had turned against his beloved liberalism. He wrote a book, The Case for Modern Man, defending it from critics on the left and right alike. His concluding chapter, titled “The Revolution [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Pro-abortion activists rally for &quot;reproductive rights and emergency abortion care&quot; as anti-abortion activists also demonstrate, outside the US Supreme Court as it hears arguments in the Moyle v. United States case, in Washington, DC, on April 24, 2024. The case deals with whether an Idaho abortion law conflicts with the federal Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA). (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP) (Photo by SAUL LOEB/AFP via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2149408696.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pro-abortion activists rally for &quot;reproductive rights and emergency abortion care&quot; as anti-abortion activists also demonstrate, outside the US Supreme Court as it hears arguments in the Moyle v. United States case, in Washington, DC, on April 24, 2024. The case deals with whether an Idaho abortion law conflicts with the federal Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA). (Photo by SAUL LOEB / AFP) (Photo by SAUL LOEB/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1955, the philosopher Charles Frankel was troubled. A <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1979/05/11/archives/charles-frankel-resigned-a-post-under-johnson-he-left-state.html">committed civil libertarian</a>, he had come to believe that the prevailing winds of public life had turned against his beloved liberalism. He wrote a book, <a href="https://www.kirkusreviews.com/book-reviews/a/charles-frankel-2/the-case-for-modern-man/"><em>The Case for Modern Man</em></a>, defending it from critics on the left and right alike.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His concluding chapter, titled “The Revolution of Modernity,” argued that liberalism had succeeded on a more fundamental level than most appreciated. Liberal modernity has not only been the era of technological progress and rapid economic growth, but also “a moral revolution of extraordinary scope, a radical alteration in what the human imagination is prepared to envisage and demand.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One contemporary reviewer <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2022641">urged Frankel to expand on these concluding remarks at book length</a> — to explain how this moral revolution worked and how it would shape our world. But Frankel never did. In fairness, he was quite busy: He left his post at Columbia University to join the State Department, only to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1979/05/11/archives/charles-frankel-resigned-a-post-under-johnson-he-left-state.html">quit in 1967 in protest of the Vietnam War</a>. He spent the rest of his shortened life advocating for civil liberties and the humanities, murdered in 1979 during a robbery at his New York home.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Frankel lived just long enough to see his optimism vindicated by events. The rise of the civil rights movement, feminism, and LGBT activism proved that liberalism had indeed altered the kinds of moral equality that Americans were prepared to demand. Liberalism’s central idea, that society should allow all people to live their lives as free and equal citizens, had never come closer to reality in all of human history.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Our moment, like Frankel’s, is a seemingly dire time for liberalism: a moment where it faces an extinction-level threat from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reactionary-Spirit-Insidious-Political-Tradition/dp/154170441X/">the rise of authoritarian movements</a> inside its historical bastions. Intellectuals are once again <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/9/9/20750160/liberalism-trump-putin-socialism-reactionary">predicting liberalism’s imminent doom</a>. Is there any hope that they are as wrong as the obituaries penned during Frankel’s time?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The answer, I believe is yes. To understand why, we should turn to a new book that finally delivers on the promise of Frankel’s concluding chapter&nbsp;— and, in the process, helps us understand what a future liberal revival might look.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Our liberal soul</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Liberalism as a Way of Life</em>, by Canadian political theorist Alexandre Lefebvre, is an unusual work of philosophy — pairing exposition of John Rawls’ theory of moral psychology with analyses of <em>The Good Place</em> and headlines in <em>The Onion</em>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The goal is to illustrate something Lefebvre believes has been lost: the idea that liberalism is not merely a political philosophy, but rather a set of implicitly shared values and norms that define social life in advanced democratic societies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Written into our foundational institutions, and underlying so much of the culture we daily live and breathe, liberalism has seeped into our pores so as to profoundly and personally shape who we are,” Lefebvre writes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Think about what you believe about the world, on a really elementary level. Does it start with the idea that all people deserve to be treated equally? That no one person is fundamentally better than any other? That each person should be free to live life in the way that they want, and still be treated with kindness and respect?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These, Lefebvre argues, are liberal beliefs — ones that have spread only recently and to only some parts of the world. But in those parts, these liberal values are so widely and commonly accepted that most people consider them nothing more than common sense. We are liberals and we don’t even know it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of Lefebvre’s most vivid illustrations is his discussion of English-language swear words.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It used to be that the worst curses focused on hygiene, religion, and sexual morality. But words like “shit,” “fuck,” and “damn” have lost their sting, now considered more impolite than offensive. We print them in Vox without much pushback from either readers or editors. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The words that actually cause offense nowadays are slurs — especially ones that target minorities and marginalized groups. These are the words that truly shock people today, language that could blow up a dinner party or give cause for a hostile workplace lawsuit. I can’t imagine a circumstance in which I would publish an article with uncensored versions of them.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Lefebvre, this shift in linguistic norms reflects a deeper moral regime change.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Swear words derive their power from transgression, a kind of verbal shorthand that communicates disregard for prevailing social norms. The classic four-letter words transgressed against Victorian ideals of sexual morality and purity; their declining power represents the declining hold of those ideas on our collective morality. Slurs have taken their place because they transgress against liberalism — specifically, the liberal idea that all humans deserve equal respect regardless of their identity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“A slur is a missile aimed at self-respect. It diminishes a person’s value, dismisses their goals, and undermines their confidence,” he writes. “If you condemn slurs no matter who they are aimed at … and if you are provoked by them in a way no other word has the power to do, then you are liberal in at least this respect.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The slurs example, and many others, illustrate how liberalism has become more than a political doctrine about rights and democracy: It is, in liberal countries, the invisible source of many of our most basic ways of living. Liberal ideas shape the way we think about everything from government to religion to sports to friendship. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is, as Lefebvre writes, “the water in which we swim:” as omnipresent and taken-for-granted as the ocean is for its fish.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Liberalism versus “liberaldom”</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lefebvre’s analysis raises an obvious question. If liberal ideas about equality and freedom are so dominant in places like the United States, how come our country is so unequal and unfree?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To explain the gap, Lefebvre borrows a concept from the 19th-century Christian philosopher Søren Kierkegaard. For Kierkegaard, true Christianity was a radical moral doctrine that preached total devotion to others and the renunciation of worldly pleasures. This was, of course, at odds with the way nominally Christian societies — including their churches — <a href="https://academic.oup.com/book/10283/chapter-abstract/158011027?redirectedFrom=fulltext">operated at the time</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, Kierkegaard distinguished between Christianity, on the one hand, and “Christendom” on the other. In Christendom, church leaders said the right things and performed the right rituals, but flagrantly violated Christian ethics in their actual lives. In Christendom, Kierkegaard wrote, the pastor is “a royal office holder, advancing steadily, making a career—and now he dramatically plays at Christianity, in short, he is performing comedy.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today, Lefebvre argues, we are living in liberaldom — a liberalism as compromised, infected and diluted by other forces as Christianity was in Kierkegaard’s time. “Liberaldom, we could say, is the craven capitulation to unliberal values that threaten to destroy your and my spirit,” he writes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Lefebvre doesn’t offer a macro-solution to the problem of liberaldom. His task isn’t to theorize about politics traditionally conceived, like mass movements and elections. Instead, he aspires to write something like self-help: instructing liberals on how they can live a good life even when faced with the reality of liberaldom, detailing a list of “spiritual exercises” that can help us be more authentic liberals.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Liberaldom is not something ‘out there’ in the world but rather anchored in a pattern of wants, aspirations, and habits built up over a lifetime. Unlearning it takes work and effort,” he writes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a novel idea (most of Lefebvre’s ideas are). But it also can feel a bit unsatisfying at a moment of liberal crisis. The New Yorker’s Adam Gopnik, for example, <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2024/05/27/why-liberals-struggle-to-defend-liberalism">writes that Lefebvre’s idea of spiritual exercise</a> “seems scarcely more likely to get us through 2024 than smoking weed all day.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Surely that’s an unfair standard. But it’s also a misunderstanding of Lefebvre’s project. His aim is not merely to help liberals be happier or calmer, but to rescue them from liberaldom. His goal is for readers to think through where their values and lives conflict, and figure out how to bring them in line. It is to create ways for people to confront the contradictions inherent to their lives and, ultimately, to resolve them in favor of their values.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Toppling liberaldom</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The clearest pathway forward can be found in Lefebvre’s treatment of “reflective equilibrium,” a tool of moral reasoning developed by Lefebvre’s intellectual hero (and mine): John Rawls. The greatest liberal philosopher of the 20th century, Rawls is best known for his book <em>A Theory of Justice </em>— which almost single-handedly revived political philosophy in the Anglophone world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Reflective equilibrium” is one of Rawls’ less well-known concepts (at least outside of academic philosophy). It is a deliberate process where people start with a basic thing they believe to be true, draw out its implications, and see whether there are any contradictions that must be resolved. You repeat this process until you’re satisfied that everything is consistent — in equilibrium, so to speak.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take an example: thinking through the morality of killing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you start from the premise that killing is always wrong, you’re quickly led to the conclusion that killing in self-defense is also wrong. But most people don’t think that it seems like if someone is trying to murder you, you should be able to fight back. Therefore, upon reflection, you should probably modify the original principle: instead of saying that killing is always wrong, you probably want to say that killing is <em>almost</em> always wrong. You keep testing and probing, figuring out what conditions should count as exceptions to the “no killing” rule. When you think you’re done, and that all your beliefs about killing are consistent, you’ve arrived at reflective equilibrium.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Lefebvre, reflective equilibrium can be a means of testing whether our lives actually live up to our liberal values —&nbsp;and for refining our beliefs, and even everyday practices, to better fit with what we profess.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The person who achieves such an equilibrium will be less susceptible to hypocrisy,” he says. “They will have brought their ideas, feelings, principles, and desires into alignment. Fluency and candor, grace and self-command, will be theirs.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If he is right — and I believe he is — then the implications are not merely individual. If human beings are creatures who can reflect on our ideas and, when confronted with contradiction, believe that we need to change, then that creates a potential pathway for broader <em>social</em> change. Even in liberaldom, many people genuinely believe in liberal ideas; they get angry when they’re flouted by the state and its agents. Under such circumstances, identifying a gap between liberal belief and liberaldom’s reality can be a potentially radical act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the United States, this is the history of successful movements for social change. In his famous address “<a href="https://loveman.sdsu.edu/docs/1852FrederickDouglass.pdf">What to the Slave is the Fourth of July</a>,” abolitionist Frederick Douglass made the contradictions between the liberalism of America’s founding and the liberaldom of the slaveholding South a central theme.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Would you have me argue that man is entitled to liberty? That he is the rightful owner of his own body? You have already declared it,” Douglass said. “For revolting barbarity and shameless hypocrisy, America reigns without a rival.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But “notwithstanding the dark picture I have this day presented, I do not despair of this country,” he added. “There are forces in operation, which must inevitably work the downfall of slavery.” No modern society, in Douglass’ view, could long survive the ruinous tension between slavery and freedom. Eventually, something had to give —&nbsp;and Douglass was convinced that, given the “obvious tendencies of the age,” liberalism would win out over liberaldom.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, he was right: The rising popularity of the abolitionist cause led to Abraham Lincoln’s election. While the motivating power of America’s liberal ideas was hardly the <em>only</em> reason for slavery’s doom, it was a vital one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This holds true in the grand contest for liberalism today. In my own forthcoming book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reactionary-Spirit-Insidious-Political-Tradition-ebook/dp/B0CMQB8S94"><em>The Reactionary Spirit</em></a>, I argue that elected authoritarians —&nbsp;like Donald Trump and Viktor Orbán — are vulnerable precisely because they claim to stand for democracy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The contradiction between their stated beliefs and actions creates fertile ground for their opponents to appeal to the pro-democracy consensus in their societies. And indeed, there is <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/12/19/23453073/2022-year-democracy-russia-ukraine-china-iran-america-brazil">substantial evidence</a> from recent elections in the United States, Brazil, Poland, and India that this can be a winning tactic.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But this tactic is not merely useful in defending liberalism from its enemies. It has also proven effective in improving our liberal societies: enacting reforms that bring them closer to their stated ideals.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Take, for example, the pro-housing YIMBY movement. The very name, Yes in My Backyard, is a play on the older term NIMBY  — referring to the kind of faux-liberals who like the idea of wind power or affordable housing but won’t support such projects if they affect local property values. YIMBYs argue that, if you take the beliefs of liberal urban dwellers seriously, you must support building more and building faster to deal with America’s catastrophic housing crisis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And guess what? It’s working!&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I used to keep track of individual YIMBY policy wins, but at a certain point I stopped because there were just too many,” <a href="https://www.slowboring.com/p/yimbys-keep-winning">Matt Yglesias writes at Slow Boring</a>. “I have met actual human beings living in Arlington who read <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Color-Law-Forgotten-Government-Segregated/dp/1631492853">Richard Rothstein’s ‘The Color of Law,’</a> found that it genuinely changed their mind, and now are eager to fight the legacy of white supremacy by opening the door to expanding housing supply.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Back in 1955, Charles Frankel called on his comrades to “reconstruct the liberal tradition to make it applicable to an age of technical specialization, bureaucratized power, and mass movements.” Today, liberals like the YIMBYs are doing just that by acting on the insights embedded in Lefebvre’s book. Their successes should give us hope that contemporary liberaldom is no more inevitable than the liberaldoms of 1854 or 1954 — and that liberalism’s reigning status as dominant moral doctrine provides resources to beat back illiberal challenges.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Delete your dating apps and find romance offline]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/357937/delete-dating-apps-meet-people-irl-tinder-hinge-bumble-flirting-offline" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357937</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T21:33:20Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-30T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Dating" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ali Jackson had been single for about four years, and like so many women, felt burned out on dating apps. Swiping had become a monotonous routine, something to do when she was bored.&#160;So Jackson decided to delete the apps and try something novel: Meet people in person. In October, she made a commitment to attend [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Hand picking up red heart" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/Westend61" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-1835402235.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,26.390732138907,100,73.609267861093" />
	<figcaption>Hand picking up red heart</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Ali Jackson had been single for about four years, and like so many women, felt burned out on dating apps. Swiping had become a monotonous routine, something to do when she was bored.&nbsp;So Jackson decided to delete the apps and try something novel: Meet people in person.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In October, she made a commitment to attend two social events a month where she didn’t know many people. Initially, Jackson signed up for singles mixers and speed dating parties but found she had more fun at non-dating get-togethers, like adult summer camp and run club. It was at one of these social gatherings, hosted by a friend on the periphery of her friend circle, where Jackson met her now-boyfriend. Her only intention going into the event was simply to talk to people. Finding romance was a bonus.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I feel very strongly that one of the reasons that we clicked so well is because, at least on my end, I was just hanging,” says Jackson, <a href="https://findingmrheight.com/">a dating and relationship coach</a> who also hosts a popular dating advice podcast, <a href="https://findingmrheight.com/podcast/"><em>Finding Mr. Height</em></a>. “I wasn&#8217;t thinking about how I was coming across or trying to meet someone.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the last few years, many singles’ disillusionment with dating apps seems to have reached a breaking point. Some app users are tired of the lack of civility of online dating: According to a Pew Research Center Survey, over 85 percent of respondents ages 18 to 34 said <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2020/02/06/the-virtues-and-downsides-of-online-dating/">someone on a dating app continued to contact them</a> even after they said they weren’t interested. Others bemoan the jarring nature of going from strangers to romantic interests within days. A Forbes Health/OnePoll survey found <a href="https://www.forbes.com/health/dating/dating-app-fatigue/">79 percent of Gen Z respondents were burned out by dating apps</a>. On TikTok, videos with views in the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@foreverathlete/video/7134885994871950638?q=delete%20dating%20apps&amp;t=1719242714345">hundreds of thousands</a> urge <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@y0sher0se/video/7324290839801318688?q=dating%20apps&amp;t=1719242340116">viewers</a> to <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@wildflowerhairsuite/video/7359567019093527839?q=delete%20dating%20apps&amp;t=1719242714345">delete their apps</a>, while <a href="https://www.thecut.com/article/tiktok-videos-single-women-crying.html">tearful young women recount their dating disasters</a>, both on and off apps, wondering why it’s so hard to meet someone or make a genuine connection. The market value of Bumble and Match Group — which owns Tinder, Match.com, OkCupid, Hinge, and more — <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/12/business/dating-apps-tinder-bumble.html">has plummeted by over $40 billion since 2021</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although would-be lovers have, for nearly all of existence, found other ways to meet, some singles — especially ones whose only dating experience has been digitally mediated — may find their in-person flirting skills lacking. The key to connecting with someone in the flesh, experts say, is to focus on quality conversations with everyone you meet and not to take rejection personally.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Prioritize social events where you know you’ll meet new people</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the biggest challenges to in-person dating is not knowing where to meet people. There’s the clichés — bars, parties — and locations ripped from rom-com plots — elevators, bookstores. But the key is to find a place where there are people you don’t know. Think of an activity you like to do and find a club or gathering around that pursuit, says relationship expert <a href="https://susanwinter.net/">Susan Winter.</a> Try not to think of these social events as opportunities to meet a potential romantic partner, but as chances to learn more about something you’re genuinely interested in, Winter says. If you’re having fun, it takes the pressure off.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The best tips for IRL flirting</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Go to recurring social events — like a softball league — where you don’t know many people</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Uncross your arms, take off your headphones, and make eye contact</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Chat with three, four, or five strangers, regardless of whether you’re interested in them romantically</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">If the person you&#8217;re talking to is giving short, clipped answers and isn&#8217;t making eye contact, best to exit gracefully</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re into someone, ask them if they want to get together outside of the event</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Don’t beat yourself up if they don’t reciprocate your feelings</p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These can be one-offs, like a concert, or a routine event, like an amateur softball league. However, the more frequently the group meets, the less intimidating it is to approach people, since they’re already familiar with you. “My biggest tip for people that feel more introverted or like they&#8217;re scared to walk up to people,” Jackson says, “is to do that more recurring event so you can establish bonds with people until they&#8217;re not strangers and it doesn&#8217;t feel so scary.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re up for attending these events alone, go for it — it’ll push you to chat with more people. To signal that you’re open to being approached, <a href="https://williamsburgtherapygroup.com/meet-the-team/dr-ida-taghavi">Ida Taghavi</a>, licensed clinical psychologist at Williamsburg Therapy Group, suggests making eye contact with others, uncrossing your arms, and squaring your face and body toward people you want to talk to. Take off those headphones, too. (If you’re unsure whether someone is interested in being approached, look for these same signs in others.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Winter says there’s nothing wrong with asking a friend to tag along, ideally someone who is also open to talking to new people. Small groups of two or three are great, Jackson says. The larger the crew, the less likely a stranger will approach you. “If you&#8217;re in a group of eight people, [it’s] highly unlikely that somebody is going to approach that group,” she says. “That&#8217;s just super intimidating.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the few places where it’s not a good idea to meet a prospective partner: the workplace. Think twice about attempting to date a coworker. Sure, you may have a good read on their personality, but you risk making the office uncomfortable if the relationship doesn’t pan out. Plus, any power imbalance between you and your romantic interest may create an inappropriate relationship. If you do decide to pursue a colleague, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/02/23/1233443278/im-dating-my-coworker-help">review your company’s rules about dating coworkers</a> and let things develop slowly at social gatherings outside of work, Jackson says.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Take romance out of the equation</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dating apps take the ambiguity out of meeting people: The fact that a person is on the platform and has matched with you is a pretty good indicator that they’re open to dating you. IRL interactions are far murkier. While people are rightfully concerned not to come across as creepy when approaching others, experts say the best course of action is simply to chat with someone not because they’re a “prospect,” but because they are a person worth talking to.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Don’t focus on flirting and instead <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/24083942/master-small-talk-interesting-conversation-strangers">flex your conversational skills</a>. Try complimenting a stranger at the bus stop or asking if the person sitting next to you at the bar would recommend the book they’re reading. Listen carefully to their responses, Winter says, and ask follow-up questions based on what they’ve said. Soon you’ll find something you’re mutually interested in. “If you get boxed up, forget that they are a romantic prospect,” Winter says. “Actually tell yourself they are a human being and your task is to engage with this human being.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s completely fine to be nervous approaching someone you don’t know, says <a href="https://www.smartdatingacademy.com">Bela Gandhi</a>, dating coach and host of the <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/smart-dating-academy-the-podcast/id1583496218"><em>Smart Dating Academy</em></a> podcast. But the best way to overcome those jitters is to talk to more people, she says. Start in low-stakes environments, like the grocery store, and try chatting with the least intimidating person you encounter. “Have a couple of icebreakers in your back pocket that you can talk to people about,” Gandhi says. “It’s about doing the reps. Doing the reps builds confidence.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another way to get your conversational reps in, Gandhi says, is involving your friends. For instance, while at a volunteering event, challenge yourself and a pal to have conversations with three new people over a 30-minute period. Then, you can touch base after.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“You might need to be the conversational leader — that’s not desperation, it’s socializing”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s important to pay attention to the other person’s verbal and nonverbal cues to determine whether they’re enjoying the conversation. If they’re giving you short, clipped answers and aren’t making eye contact, they might not be interested, Winter says. You might consider gracefully exiting the conversation to avoid wading into creepy territory.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Most of us would love for an attractive stranger to approach us at a party, but “everybody wants someone else to do the approach,” Gandhi says. You might need to be the conversational leader — that’s not desperation, it’s socializing. Even if you don’t connect with someone romantically, they have the potential to be a new friend, a professional connection, or even someone who can set you up with one of their single friends.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Asking someone out doesn’t need to be awkward</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Maybe you’ve been chatting to someone for a while and the conversation is flowing: You’re laughing at each other’s jokes, there’s lots of eye contact, you’re both asking the other questions. All signs are pointing to mutual interest in getting to know each other better.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You don’t need to explicitly mention you’d like to go on a date with them, Jackson says, but keep it light by saying, “This was really fun. Maybe we could try that new [wine bar/restaurant/tennis court] you mentioned sometime,” or “We should totally exchange numbers and meet up at the [mutual favorite band] show next week.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You could take another approach for crushes you see at recurring events. If the object of your affection is, say, another student in your pottery class, try asking the entire group if anyone wants to grab food afterward, Jackson suggests.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ball is in their court now and you have to be open to any outcome, good or bad.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Be chill if you get rejected (and be chill when rejecting someone)</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People might have a multitude of reasons for turning down a date. They could be in a relationship already, they might be moving to a new city in a few months, or they may just not feel the romantic spark. It’s okay to take it personally, Winter says. If they were brash and unkind in their response, you dodged a bullet.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Try not to get stuck feeling like you’re not worthy of love or attractive enough, Gandhi says. Instead, put yourself in their shoes, Jackson suggests. Imagine a time when a perfectly fine person asked you out but you weren’t feeling the spark. Chances are you weren’t thinking the person was unworthy of romance. “I wouldn&#8217;t feel embarrassed for a guy if he came up to me and struck up a conversation and asked for my number, and I was like, ‘I actually have a boyfriend. I&#8217;m not interested,’” Jackson says.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>If they were brash and unkind in their response, you dodged a bullet&nbsp;</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As obvious as it may seem, do not insult the other person if they decline a date. “Respect the other person’s decision and simply move on,” Taghavi says. “The relationship that is for you is one where both you and your partner feel aligned on your intentions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you’re the one turning someone down, always be kind and direct. You might say, “I’m so flattered, but I’m seeing someone. I’m sorry,” or “I really enjoyed our conversation, but I’m not interested.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s always the risk that the other person might not take your rejection kindly. That’s their problem, Jackson says. Now you know for certain you made the right call. “If somebody reacts to your very clear, kind communication with that attitude,” she says, “that sucks for them. That&#8217;s really unfortunate that they move through the world with that lens and I feel bad for them.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Dating IRL can be an emotional minefield, but you can take the pressure off. So long as your expectations are to simply have a pleasant conversation with someone, the romance will soon follow.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Keren Landman, MD</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[There is no one weird health hack]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/357645/misinformation-debunking-health-tiktok-youtube-instagram-weird-health-trick-hack" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357645</id>
			<updated>2024-06-27T23:26:41Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-30T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been on the consumer health beat for a few months now. That means I stand directly in the path of a lot of strikingly bad “wellness” advice on social media. For example: Take potato juice instead of antibiotics for strep throat (what? no); douse yourself in beer for a better tan (ouch — use [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Collection collage elements. open mouth, teeth, lips and cut out text halftone style. Scream, hate, fake news concept. Punk y2k retro magazine clippings on yellow background. Vector illustration" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-1718248545.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Collection collage elements. open mouth, teeth, lips and cut out text halftone style. Scream, hate, fake news concept. Punk y2k retro magazine clippings on yellow background. Vector illustration</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">I’ve been on the consumer health beat for a few months now. That means I stand directly in the path of a lot of strikingly bad “wellness” advice on social media. For example: <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-11808007/Doctors-warn-against-dangerous-TikTok-trend-drinking-raw-potato-juice.html">Take potato juice</a> instead of antibiotics for strep throat (<a href="https://www.aafp.org/pubs/afp/issues/2009/0301/p383-s1.html">what? no</a>); <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health-news/tiktoks-beer-tanning-beauty-hack-can-increase-your-risk-of-sunburn-and-cancer">douse yourself in beer</a> for a better tan (ouch — <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/354203/sunscreen-sunblock-spf-sun-damage-skin-cancer-tiktok-confusion">use sunscreen or stay in the shade</a>); <a href="https://www.everydayhealth.com/fitness/dry-scooping-why-health-experts-warn-against-trying-the-viral-tiktok-trend/">scoop dry protein powder directly into your mouth</a> (<a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/dry-scooping-tiktok-trend#:~:text=If%20your%20first%20lift%20for,dangerous%20%E2%80%94%20and%20even%20potentially%20deadly.">bad idea!</a>).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It also means I think a lot about the consequences of the bullshit fire hose. People are <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/factcheck/2024/03/15/covid-misinformation-spreads-4-years-after-pandemic/72896725007/">getting hurt</a>, and experts, struck with horror at the spectacle, are sinking countless hours and dollars into attempts at a fix. A variety of scientists and health care providers are trying to flood the zone with debunking content. However, it’s <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1386505624001412#b0450">not at all clear that the content is reaching or changing many minds</a> among those most susceptible to health misinformation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As someone relatively new to doing debunking work, I hate it. It is boring, and it is endless. The “one weird hack” videos influencers barf up seem to come in multipacks of a thousand; before I’ve whack-a-moled even one of them, 10 more have cropped up. And because I’m not convinced that what’s written actually reaches the people most likely to believe the health bullshit they see online, the work often feels pointless.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s plenty of fault to go around for this bleak state of affairs. I blame the <a href="https://www.opb.org/article/2024/03/18/think-out-loud-uw-study-social-media-influencers-misinformation/#:~:text=Some%20of%20those%20influencers%20are,false%20information%20about%20COVID%20vaccines.">snake oil salespeople</a> who profit off others’ desperation and confusion, and the tech platforms that allow them to proliferate. I blame the regulators and legislators who <a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2023/11/21/hany-farid-to-limit-disinformation-we-must-regulate-internet-platforms/">drag their feet</a> on bringing these massive corporations into check. I blame the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/2023/11/18/what-house-republicans-want-do-public-education-funding/">underfunding</a> of <a href="https://www.sanders.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/06.24.24-Education-Privatization-Report.pdf">public education</a>, which would otherwise be teaching kids better critical thinking skills. I blame the government agencies whose best intentions still haven’t led to effective communication, and the politicians and other public figures who undermine those agencies for clout.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I have to admit that, in my heart of hearts, I also find myself wanting to shake the consumers who blindly follow the internet’s unvetted health “advice” without interrogating its source. Sorry, but you’re going to trust a rando shilling a “parasite cleanse” and telling you to <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/2023/7/29/23811639/tiktok-borax-challenge-dangerous-laundry-detergent">drink laundry detergent</a> — and not the government scientist who’s literally forbidden from monetizing engagement? I am occasionally guilty of wanting to give up on humanity.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is not a response I’m proud of. After all, the public is on the pointy end of some of the most <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6679162/">skilled</a> <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-44640959">attention</a> <a href="https://www.fairobserver.com/business/are-addiction-inducing-algorithms-in-social-media-lawful/#">manipulators</a> of all time. We know that the rising reach and power of health misinformation is directly tied to a very reasonable <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0747563223003436">distrust in systems</a>, including government, the health care industry, and scientific experts. Certain players in each of these institutions have <a href="https://retractionwatch.com/">serious</a> <a href="https://kffhealthnews.org/news/article/medical-debt-hospitals-sue-patients-threaten-credit-khn-investigation/">integrity</a> <a href="https://hls.harvard.edu/today/the-business-ethics-of-elon-musk-tesla-twitter-and-the-tech-industry/">problems</a>, and they may well have failed many people in very personal ways. I don’t question anyone’s right and reason to view these systems with healthy skepticism.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But friends, we simply cannot go on like this. You and I both know it: In a recent <a href="https://www.edelman.com/trust/2024/trust-barometer/special-report-health">survey</a> conducted by health communications firm Edelman, 63 percent of 18- to 34-year-olds were worried about health misinformation.(Notably, that’s the same demographic that, according to the Kaiser Family Foundation, is most likely to <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-misinformation-and-trust/poll-finding/kff-health-misinformation-tracking-poll-pilot/">go to social media</a> for health information or advice.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Furthermore, people are well aware of the harms of believing the bullshit, and have insight into how that bullshit has harmed them personally. Fifty-five percent of young adults in the Edelman survey <a href="https://www.edelman.com/trust/2024/trust-barometer/special-report-health">regret</a> a health decision they made based on misinformation they got from an ad, their family or friends, or a content creator online.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, the bullshit fire hose persists. It’s insidious — more often than not, misinformation finds people by oozing into their feeds uninvited. While it’s more likely to leave people <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-misinformation-and-trust/poll-finding/kff-health-misinformation-tracking-poll-pilot/">confused than convinced</a>, it plants a seed of lingering doubt that can have an impact when it comes to making health decisions further down the line.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, seeing a TikTok about <a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/putting-garlic-in-nose-to-clear-sinuses">shoving a garlic clove in your nose</a> might not send you running for the crisper drawer — but the next time you hear about it, you might react with a “huh” instead of a “hell no.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Try as they might, public health is having a hell of a time keeping up with all the nonsense out there, especially when so much of it is in video form. The <a href="https://nida.nih.gov/research-topics/parents-educators/lesson-plans/legit-accessing-valid-and-reliable-health-information">rules</a> of <a href="https://www.nia.nih.gov/health/healthy-aging/how-find-reliable-health-information-online">engagement</a> health experts have created to help consumers vet written health information don’t always apply to video, and simple tools to help people assess the quality of short videos about health are <a href="https://colab.ws/articles/10.1016%2Fj.ijmedinf.2024.105426">scarce</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So what’s a person on the internet to do next time social media serves up “one weird trick” that promises a jacked bod, a dewy complexion, immaculately balanced hormones, and a cancer-free eternity?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, let your bullshit meter guide you. If a wild health claim is too good to be true, it probably is. It’s also a red flag when the person making the claim is relying on language or visuals that elicit super-intense emotional reactions like fear and outrage, Cambridge University misinformation expert Sander van der Linden recently <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/03/16/well/health-misinformation.html">told</a> the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>So what’s a person on the internet to do next time social media serves up “one weird trick” that promises a jacked bod, a dewy complexion, immaculately balanced hormones, and a cancer-free eternity?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Is the person sharing the information trying to sell you something by making a health claim? If so, that’s a concerning sign, and you should be especially careful to further check the accuracy of what they’re saying.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When in doubt, Google anything that causes even a slight tingle of your spidey senses. Has the claim been verified by news sites that value accuracy? (Here’s some <a href="https://newslit.org/educators/resources/is-it-legit/">guidance</a> on determining whether a news site is trustworthy, and a <a href="https://libguides.ala.org/InformationEvaluation">list of news vetting resources</a> from the American Library Association.) You can also check specific assertions on one of many fact-checking websites, including <a href="http://factcheck.org">FactCheck.org</a>, and on the sites of medical institutions — the <a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/health-conditions">Cleveland Clinic</a> does some <a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/tiktok-health-trends">good work</a> in this space. You can also take an offline approach by asking your own health care provider, or enlisting a local or university library to help you fact-check certain claims.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course, all of the groups involved here should be doing a lot more to protect us — and if we’re obliged to do hand-to-hand combat with a ceaseless stream of health misinformation, we need to be doing a much more sophisticated job of it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Better education around news literacy that teaches young people to critically assess everything they read online — basically, <a href="https://www.apa.org/topics/journalism-facts/misinformation-interventions">pre-bunking</a> —<strong> </strong>is a good start. Government agencies and other health institutions could also get far better at communicating information to people in the ways they want and need to hear it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The problem is that my videos &#8230; are, like, an hour long, and they’re super boring,” Kristen Bibbins-Domingo, editor-in-chief of the Journal of the American Medical Association, a leading health research publication, said while speaking at <a href="https://youtu.be/PPO-8LN173U">Aspen Ideas: Health</a>. “And all of the other ones — they’re super interesting and engaging! I don’t need to be in the business of dumbing down ideas,” she said, but “consumers are consuming.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Good information can be engineered to seep into users’ feeds just as often as bad information does. But for that to happen, both government employees and health care providers need to be enabled to do this work far more effectively. That means respecting and compensating the debunking work scientists and providers do on social media and training them to make content that’s as likely to go viral as the worst nonsense in the fire hose.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s always the possibility that something will compel social media platforms to take some responsibility and actually do something to protect the public from misinformation. But in the meantime, please listen to that faint buzzing noise you now hear almost constantly. It’s your bullshit meter, it’s working harder than ever — and your health could depend on whether you’re paying attention. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What, if anything, is AI search good for?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/357247/why-are-ai-search-engines-so-bad" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357247</id>
			<updated>2024-06-27T19:35:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-29T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Apple" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Artificial Intelligence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Big Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Emerging Tech" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Google" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Innovation" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been a month since Google’s spectacular goof. Its new AI Overviews feature was supposed to “take the legwork out of searching,” offering up easy-to-read answers to our queries based on multiple search results. Instead, it told people to eat rocks and to glue cheese on pizza. You could ask Google what country in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A nerdy man hunches over an old Apple computer." data-caption="Goofy 1980s Computer Worker looking intently at a vintage computer screen.  Retro colored and styled image with wood panelling in the background." data-portal-copyright="sjharmon / Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-618210072.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Goofy 1980s Computer Worker looking intently at a vintage computer screen.  Retro colored and styled image with wood panelling in the background.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It has been a month since Google’s spectacular goof. Its new AI Overviews feature was supposed to “<a href="https://blog.google/products/search/generative-ai-google-search-may-2024/">take the legwork out of searching</a>,” offering up easy-to-read answers to our queries based on multiple search results. Instead, it told people to <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/google-explains-why-its-ai-overviews-told-users-to-eat-rocks-and-glue-pizzas#:~:text=One%20of%20the%20queries%20that,important%20for%20your%20body's%20health.%E2%80%9D">eat rocks</a> and to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/google-search-ai-overview-answers-pizza-glue-fix-2024-5">glue cheese on pizza</a>. You could ask Google what country in Africa starts with the letter “K”, and Google <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2023/11/google-generative-ai-search-featured-results/675899/">would say none of them</a>. In fact, you can still get these wrong answers because AI search is a disaster. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This spring looked like a turning point for AI search, thanks to a couple of big announcements from major players in the space. One was that Google AI Overview update, and the other came from Perplexity, an AI search startup that’s already been labeled <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/01/technology/perplexity-search-ai-google.html">as a worthy alternative to Google</a>. At the end of May, Perplexity launched a new feature called Pages that can create custom web pages full of information on one specific topic, like a smart friend who does your homework for you. Then <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/randalllane/2024/06/11/why-perplexitys-cynical-theft-represents-everything-that-could-go-wrong-with-ai/">Perplexity got caught plagiarizing</a>. For AI search to work well, it seems, it has to cheat a little.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a lot of ill will over AI search’s mistakes and missteps and critics are mobilizing en masse. A group of online publishers and creators <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/06/26/google-ai-overviews-congress-web-publishers-raptive/">took to Capitol Hill on Wednesday</a> to lobby lawmakers to look into Google’s AI Overviews feature and other AI tech that pulls content from independent creators. This is just a couple days after the Recording Industry Association of America (RIAA) and a group of major record labels <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/24/24184710/riaa-ai-lawsuit-suno-udio-copyright-umg-sony-warner">sued two AI companies</a> that generate music from text for copyright infringement. And let’s not forget that <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/30/business/media/newspapers-sued-microsoft-openai.html">several newspapers</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/27/business/media/new-york-times-open-ai-microsoft-lawsuit.html">including the New York Times</a>, have sued OpenAI and Microsoft for copyright infringement for scraping their content in order to train the same AI models that power their search tools. (Vox Media, the company that owns this publication, meanwhile, <a href="https://www.vox.com/technology/352849/openai-chatgpt-google-meta-artificial-intelligence-vox-media-chatbots">has a licensing deal with OpenAI</a> that allows our content to be used to train its models and by ChatGPT. Our journalism and editorial decisions remain independent.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Generative AI technology is supposed to transform the way we search the web. At least, <a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2023/3/4/23624033/openai-bing-bard-microsoft-generative-ai-explained">that’s the line</a> we’ve been fed since ChatGPT exploded on the scene near the end of 2022, and now every tech giant is pushing its own brand of AI technology: Microsoft has Copilot, Google has Gemini, Apple has Apple Intelligence, and so forth. While these tools can do more than help you find things online, dethroning Google Search still seems to be the holy grail of AI. Even OpenAI, maker of ChatGPT, is reportedly <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/openai-plans-announce-google-search-competitor-monday-sources-say-2024-05-09/">building a search engine</a> to compete directly with Google.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But despite many companies’ very public efforts, AI search won’t make finding answers online effortless any time soon, according to experts I spoke to.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s not just that AI search isn’t ready for primetime due to some flaws, it’s that those flaws are so deeply integrated into how AI search works that it’s now unclear if it can ever get good enough to replace Google.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s a good addition, and there are times when it&#8217;s really great,” Chirag Shah, a professor of information science at the University of Washington, told me. “But I think we&#8217;re still going to need the traditional search around.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rather than going into all of AI search’s flaws here, let me highlight the two that were on display with the recent Google and Perplexity kerfuffles. The Google pizza glue incident shows just how stubborn generative AI’s hallucination problem is. Just a few days after Google launched AI Overview, some users noticed that if you asked Google how to keep cheese from falling off of pizza, Google <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/5/23/24162896/google-ai-overview-hallucinations-glue-in-pizza">would suggest adding some glue</a>. This particular answer appeared to come from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Pizza/comments/1a19s0/my_cheese_slides_off_the_pizza_too_easily/">an old Reddit thread</a> that, for some reason, Google’s AI thought was an authoritative source even though a human would quickly realize that the Redditors are joking about eating glue. Weeks later, The Verge’s Elizabeth Lopatto reported that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/11/24176490/mm-delicious-glue">Google’s AI Overview feature was still recommending pizza glue</a>. Google <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/01/technology/google-ai-overviews-rollback.html">rolled back its AI Overview feature</a> in May following the viral failures, so it’s difficult to access AI Overview at all.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The problem isn’t just that the large language models that power generative AI tools can hallucinate, or make up information in certain situations. They also can’t tell good information from bad&nbsp;— at least not right now.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ll ever be at a stage where we can guarantee that hallucinations won&#8217;t exist,” said Yoon Kim, an assistant professor at MIT who researches large language models. “But I think there&#8217;s been a lot of advancements in reducing these hallucinations, and I think we&#8217;ll get to a point where they&#8217;ll become good enough to use.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The recent Perplexity drama <a href="https://www.platformer.news/how-to-stop-perplexity-oreilly-ai-publishing/">highlights a different problem with AI search</a>: It accesses and republishes content that it’s not supposed to. Perplexity, whose investors include Jeff Bezos and Nvidia, made a name for itself by providing deeper answers to search queries and showing its sources. You can give it a question and it will come back with a conversational answer, complete with citations from around the web, which you can refine by asking more questions. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When Perplexity launched its Pages feature, however, it became clear that its AI had an uncanny ability to rip off journalism. Perplexity even makes Pages it generated <a href="https://www.perplexity.ai/discover">look like a news section of its website</a>. One such Page it published included <a href="https://x.com/JohnPaczkowski/status/1799135156051255799">summaries of some Forbes’s exclusive, paywalled investigative reporting</a> on Eric Schmidt’s drone project. Forbes <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/randalllane/2024/06/11/why-perplexitys-cynical-theft-represents-everything-that-could-go-wrong-with-ai/">accused Perplexity of stealing its content</a>, and Wired <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/perplexity-is-a-bullshit-machine/">later reported</a> that Perplexity was scraping content from websites that have blocked the type of crawlers that do such scraping. The AI-powered search engine would even construct incorrect answers to queries based on details in URLs or metadata. (In an interview with Fast Company last week, Perplexity CEO Aravind Srinivas <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91144894/perplexity-ai-ceo-aravind-srinivas-on-plagiarism-accusations?partner=rss&amp;utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=rss+fastcompany&amp;utm_content=rss">denied some of the findings</a> of the Wired investigation and said, “I think there is a basic misunderstanding of the way this works.”)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The reasons why AI-powered search stinks at sourcing are both technical and simple, Shah explained. The technical explanation involves <a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/what-is-retrieval-augmented-generation/">something called retrieval-augmented generation</a> (RAG), which works a bit like a professor recruiting research assistants to go find out more information about a specific topic when the professor’s personal library isn’t enough. RAG does solve a couple of problems with how the current generation of large language models generate content, including the frequency of hallucinations, but it also creates a new problem: It can’t distinguish good sources from bad. In its current state, AI lacks good judgment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When you or I do a Google search, we know that the long list of blue links will include high-quality links, like newspaper articles, and low-quality or unverified stuff, like old Reddit threads or SEO farm garbage. We can distinguish between the good or bad in a split second, thanks to years of <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/why-ai-search-blew-up-in-googles-face.html">experience perfecting our own Googling skills</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then there’s some common sense that AI doesn’t have, like knowing whether or not it’s okay to eat rocks and glue. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“AI-powered search doesn’t have that ability just yet,” Shah said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of this is to say that you should turn and run the next time you see an AI Overview. But instead of thinking about it as an easy way to get an answer, you should think of it as a starting point. Kind of like Wikipedia. It’s hard to know how that answer ended up at the top of the Google search, so you might want to check the sources. After all, you’re smarter than the AI.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What Kenya’s deadly protests are really about]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/357857/kenya-protest-tax-ruto-loans-china-imf" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357857</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T19:44:52Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-29T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Poverty" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kenya, one of east Africa’s more economically developed and democratically stable countries, has been rocked this week by a political crisis that reveals the deep cracks in both sides of that stability. Massive protests broke out earlier this week after parliament passed a bill increasing taxes — including on a bevy of everyday essentials like [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Protesters try to advance towards the police during a demonstration in Nairobi, on June 25, 2024. Kenyan police fired tear gas at crowds of young protesters in the capital Nairobi on Tuesday, as demonstrators rallied across the country against the government&#039;s proposed tax increases. The demonstrations, led mainly by Generation Z, which began last week, took President William Ruto&#039;s government by surprise, and he said over the weekend that he was ready to talk to the protesters, according to AFP reporters. (Photo by SIMON MAINA / AFP) (Photo by SIMON MAINA/AFP via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158662516.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Protesters try to advance towards the police during a demonstration in Nairobi, on June 25, 2024. Kenyan police fired tear gas at crowds of young protesters in the capital Nairobi on Tuesday, as demonstrators rallied across the country against the government&#039;s proposed tax increases. The demonstrations, led mainly by Generation Z, which began last week, took President William Ruto&#039;s government by surprise, and he said over the weekend that he was ready to talk to the protesters, according to AFP reporters. (Photo by SIMON MAINA / AFP) (Photo by SIMON MAINA/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Kenya, one of east Africa’s more economically developed and democratically stable countries, has been rocked this week by a political crisis that reveals the deep cracks in both sides of that stability.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Massive protests broke out earlier this week after parliament passed a bill increasing taxes — including on a bevy of everyday essentials like cooking oil, diapers, and bread — on a population already suffering from inflation and high rates of unemployment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As protests increased in size and intensity, even breaching parliament’s chambers, they were met with violent repression. Nearly <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/world/africa/kenya-protests-taxes-president-ruto.html">two dozen people were killed Tuesday</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After initial recalcitrance, President William Ruto said Wednesday he would not sign the controversial bill. His decision was a victory for the protesters, but the saga leaves the country’s future more uncertain than ever, both economically and politically. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ruto requested the bill to cover Kenya’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/26/business/kenya-tax-protests-debt.html">approximately $80 billion</a> in domestic and external debt. Around $35 million of that debt is owned by foreign creditors, primarily China and powerful international groups like the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund (IMF). If Kenya doesn’t pay it, the possibility of borrowing in the future will become more difficult in the short term; over time, it could mean more unemployment, more poverty, and <a href="https://www.opensocietyfoundations.org/explainers/what-happens-when-a-country-goes-broke">overall worse outcomes for Kenyans</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kenya’s troubles are a distillation of the problems facing several dozen developing nations, crushed under debt: “More than 3 billion people across the world live in countries that are spending more on servicing their debt than public spending on education or health,” Binaifer Nowrojee, the president of the Open Society Foundations, <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/06/28/kenya-protests-ruto-imf-taxes-poverty-broke-social-contract/">wrote in Foreign Policy</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Complicating matters are Kenya’s other economic problems. Corruption, cronyism, financial mismanagement, and the vestiges of colonialism have hobbled Kenya’s <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/african-lions-tapping-the-potential-of-kenyas-economic-growth/">once-impressive</a> economic development and exacerbated class and ethnic inequalities.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of that has led to a long-simmering political crisis: Ruto was elected on a promise that he would improve the lot of Kenya’s youth and lower classes, presenting himself as a break from the old, corrupt, politically incestuous elite. But he’s been unable to deliver, despite the country’s wealth in resources and economic boom in the early 2000s — and that has left large swaths of the population displeased with him, and his government, leading to the rancorous protests of recent days.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Ruto has backed off from the taxation bill, Kenyans, especially young people, are mobilized against the government and the status quo — and they aren’t backing down. <a href="https://apnews.com/article/kenya-protests-finance-bill-taxes-43fef18b87cd6f7c1cfd002709fd8a20">Protests continued Thursday</a> in Nairobi and other cities despite military patrols. After the bill and the violent repression, some protesters are now <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/27/world/africa/kenya-protests-taxes-president-ruto.html">calling for Ruto to resign</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid serious distrust of his administration, Ruto now must find a way to manage the East African country’s debt load and avoid default without further harming the economy or inflaming people’s very real anger. It’s unlikely he’ll be able to do all of these things. But inaction could drive Kenya further into economic disaster.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What happened at Kenya’s protests, and how Kenya’s economic situation got this bad</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kenya’s Finance Bill of 2024 was supposed to increase government revenue through taxes, satisfying a condition of the IMF loan. But Kenyans already struggling with high inflation and organizing on social media <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/kenya-braces-fresh-protests-despite-presidents-tax-climbdown-2024-06-27/">came out in cities</a> including Nairobi, Mombasa, Homa Bay, and Kisumu to condemn the bill after it passed in parliament. Protesters <a href="https://www.economist.com/middle-east-and-africa/2024/06/27/a-new-breed-of-protest-has-left-kenyas-president-tottering">breached the parliament</a> on Tuesday, setting fire to part of the building and sending lawmakers fleeing. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The seeds of the recent protests, however, have been sown for years, as Kenyans see an <a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/06/27/microfinance-kenya-predatory-lending-international-development/">economic and financial system stacked against them</a>. They started to come to a head in earnest during last summer’s anti-tax protests, but they’ve taken on a slightly different character this year; so far, the movement seems to be composed of young people, leaderless and coordinated online. That’s no surprise, <a href="https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/staff/profiles/gov/cheeseman-nic">Nic Cheeseman</a>, professor of democracy and international development at the University of Birmingham, told Vox. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Young people were the first to get sacked during Covid, had higher unemployment, are less likely to be registered to vote, and are under-represented in parliament,” he said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">During his campaign, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/09/world/africa/kenya-elections-william-ruto.html">Ruto made his pitch to these young people</a>, dubbing them the “hustler nation” and emphasizing his own rags-to-riches story. But his promises for “bottom-up” economic reform have rung hollow as Kenyans still suffer from <a href="https://www.oxfam.org/en/kenya-extreme-inequality-numbers">severe economic inequality</a> and lack of educational and job opportunities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Kenya’s economic woes didn’t start recently; the nation’s immense debt stems from an economic boom in the early 2000s, when the government borrowed money from a variety of international creditors to <a href="https://apnews.com/article/kenya-china-beijing-loans-train-55dd517978a020b255a461f8ad372546">fund public infrastructure projects</a>, supporting agriculture and small and medium businesses and <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-01-19/kenya-gets-210-million-loan-as-eurobond-maturity-looms?sref=qYiz2hd0">external debt servicing</a> but failed to invest those loans in ways that could grow the economy. Add to that a series of costly natural disasters (including floods and Covid-19), ineffective taxation strategy, and the long-term pattern of politicians overspending to make good on campaign promises, and Kenya was poised for crisis. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The drivers of [the] debt crisis are predominantly political, in other words, and can only be solved by political solutions,” Cheeseman said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By that he means a deeper problem needs to be solved: Ultimately, Kenyans don’t trust their government, and understandably so; high levels of government waste and corruption, as well as a patronage system that relies heavily on favors, nepotism, and quid-pro-quo relationships with roots in Kenya’s British colonial period, mean the government isn’t responsive to the Kenyan people. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though Ruto positioned himself as an alternative to this system, promising voters that he was a break from the political dynasties of the past, that’s simply not true. Ruto has been in the government in some form <a href="https://www.president.go.ke/administration/office-of-the-president/">since 1997</a>, and he was part of the system that brought this crisis about. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, protesters have stormed the parliament and called for his resignation —&nbsp;and say they won’t stop until he is gone.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What happens to Kenya now?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The question of what’s next — both politically and financially —is murky at best. For now, Ruto has refused to sign the tax bill, but the government will have to enact austerity measures to both save money and comply with a <a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Countries/KEN/kenya-qandas">2021 loan agreement</a> with <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-27/protest-deaths-in-kenya-echo-decades-of-angst-over-imf-orthodoxy?sref=qYiz2hd0">the IMF</a>, which requires Kenya to increase taxes and cut government spending while also protecting and strengthening the social safety net. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That agreement is likely to cause Ruto more political headaches, if other countries in similar situations are any indication.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It happens again and again,” W. Gyude Moore, a fellow at the Center for Global Development and former public works minister of Liberia. “Countries go to the IMF, get recommendations, and do everything they can to remain on the good side of the IMF. And in the process of doing that, people end up hurt.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the meantime, Ruto has said that he will <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-06-28/kenya-prepares-spending-cuts-after-scrapping-2-3-billion-taxes?srnd=homepage-africa&amp;sref=qYiz2hd0">introduce austerity measures</a> aimed at cutting government spending to align with the IMF’s guidelines, starting with slashing his own office’s budget. Those austerity measures don’t seem to be cutting into public programs like infrastructure, health care, and education yet — but such cuts could still come. The central government could decrease cash transfers to Kenya’s counties, further fueling the inequality that plagues Kenyan society, and could cut into critical programs like <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/eadf0d8a-730c-4934-8c10-8edd075982ff?shareType=nongift">meals for school-age children</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kenya spends about 60 percent of its revenue <a href="https://www.theeastafrican.co.ke/tea/business/why-kenya-is-still-debt-distressed-despite-eurobond-repayment--4533300">on debt payments</a>; a third of that revenue <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/kenyas-double-digit-debt-costs-sign-tough-times-2024-02-13/">goes toward interest</a>. While continuing to service its debt plays well for creditors, it negatively affects the population, because that money isn’t being spent on programs and services for them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kenya doesn’t have many options when it comes to dealing with its debt burden. It could default on its payments — simply not pay the loan back, in other words. While this could ease some of the burden on Kenya’s population in the short term, it would tank the country’s credit rating, impacting the country’s ability to borrow in the future. Should it need fast cash for another Covid-level crisis after defaulting, it could find itself out of luck. It could also have even more trouble accessing foreign currency and struggle to pay for imports, leading to higher inflation as <a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/asia/sri-lankas-economic-crisis-debt-restructuring-efforts-2024-04-16/#:~:text=At%20the%20start%20of%202022,%2478%20million%20bond%20coupon%20payment.">Sri Lanka</a> experienced in 2022 — which resulted in ended in mass civil upheaval and the ouster of the country’s president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Renegotiating the terms of its loans is another option. That could help lower the amount that the country pays to external creditors so Kenya isn’t paying more than half of government revenue to service its debts. That would likely still mean implementing some austerity measures and increased taxes, though perhaps not as extreme as the shelved tax bill.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Finally, Kenya could keep its present course. But again, that means little to no money would be left for stoking internal economic development, and scant resources for the sorts of services citizens expect from their governments. Ruto has proposed a two-week period to <a href="https://www.president.go.ke/president-ruto-declines-to-sign-finance-bill-calls-for-its-withdrawal/">discuss options for a new economic plan</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All that means Kenya does need to find some money from somewhere. Any increase in taxes, Cheeseman said, would have to be targeted at Kenya’s ultra-wealthy, to demonstrate a sensitivity to the plight of ordinary Kenyans, if Ruto hopes to regain some of their support. However, that’s unlikely to be popular among Kenya’s powerful elite.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ultimately, even raising capital is a short-term financial fix to the long-term political problems of corruption, waste, and mismanagement. Efforts to undo those patterns are likely to anger the ultra-wealthy, whose businesses depend on corrupt relationships with the government to thrive.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether or not the Ruto administration finds a way to manage its debt payments, the problem is that Kenyans don’t feel that their government is looking out for their best interests. That has played out in protests over the economy, but those circumstances are a product of Kenya’s political culture and international financial institutions that have failed developing countries.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Hady Mawajdeh</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How the UFC explains the USA]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/sports/357984/ufc-303-fight-trump-maga-periera-prochazka" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357984</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T20:06:18Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-29T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fans of the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) have had Saturday blocked off on their calendars for months. They were all anticipating the long-awaited return of former UFC featherweight and lightweight champion Conor McGregor in UFC 303. But a broken toe ruined those plans just two weeks before fight night.&#160; Instead, viewers are tuning in for [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Opponents Alex Pereira of Brazil and Jiri Prochazka of the Czech Republic face off during the UFC 303 press conference at T-Mobile Arena on June 27, 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada. " data-portal-copyright="Photo by Chris Unger/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-2159595481.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Opponents Alex Pereira of Brazil and Jiri Prochazka of the Czech Republic face off during the UFC 303 press conference at T-Mobile Arena on June 27, 2024 in Las Vegas, Nevada. </figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Fans of the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) have had Saturday blocked off on their calendars for months. They were all anticipating the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2024/apr/14/conor-mcgregor-to-make-long-awaited-ufc-return-against-michael-chandler#:~:text=Conor%20McGregor%20will%20make%20his,president%2C%20Dana%20White%2C%20said.">long-awaited return</a> of former UFC featherweight and lightweight champion <a href="https://www.espn.com/mma/fighter/_/id/3022677/conor-mcgregor">Conor McGregor</a> in <a href="https://www.espn.com/mma/fightcenter/_/id/600043173/league/ufc">UFC 303</a>. But a <a href="https://bleacherreport.com/articles/10125598-conor-mcgregor-posts-photo-of-injured-toe-after-ufc-303-fight-vs-chandler-canceled">broken toe</a> ruined those plans just two weeks before fight night.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, viewers are tuning in for what ultimately might be a much better contest between light heavyweight champion <a href="https://www.espn.com/mma/fighter/_/id/4705658/alex-pereira">Alex Pereira</a> and former champ <a href="https://www.espn.com/mma/fighter/_/id/3156612/jiri-prochazka">Jiří Procházka</a>. The fight will be a rematch between the two brawlers, who <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UHGomATiHvU">last met in November 2023</a>. That first fight was a back-and-forth bout, with each fighter landing big blows and takedowns. Pereira won via TKO after a devastating hook allowed him to take Procházka to the ground for an old-fashioned pounding, landing punches and elbows before the referee stopped the fight.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This time around, the two will meet in front of more than 20,000 fans at a sold-out T-Mobile Arena in Las Vegas — with <a href="https://www.ufc.com/news/ufc-300-pereira-vs-hill-numbers-behind-record-breaking-success?language_content_entity=en">an estimated more than 2 million viewers watching from home</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">UFC 303 is expected to bring in <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/trentreinsmith/2024/05/13/dana-whiteufc-303-mcgregor-vs-chandler-will-top-20-million-gate/?sh=1ae37eaec848">a record-breaking gate of $20 million</a>, which is a feather in the cap for <a href="https://www.forbes.com/forbes/2008/0505/080.html">the most dominant league in the world of mixed martial arts (MMA)</a>. The UFC was recently valued at an eye-popping <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/justinteitelbaum/2024/04/18/the-most-valuable-combat-sports-promotions-2024/#:~:text=The%20two%20brands%20each%20had,Forbes'%20Highest%20Paid%20Athletes%20List.">$11.3 billion</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the UFC is more than just a sports sensation that lures fight fans and uninitiated looky-loos toward pricey pay-per-view events promising violence and excitement. The league is a cultural phenomenon. It’s turned fighters into celebrities; it’s created new expectations for what fighting looks like in movies and media; and it’s even intersected with national politics. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In fact, how UFC got this big says a lot about America today — and where American politics could be headed next.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How the UFC got so huge</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The UFC hasn’t always been a behemoth. In its earliest days, it was unpolished; one of the company’s taglines was “<a href="https://30for30podcasts.com/episodes/no-rules-birth-ufc/">there are no rules</a>.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Its no-rules violence led Sen. John McCain to call the UFC “<a href="https://slate.com/culture/2018/08/john-mccain-ufc-how-he-grew-to-tolerate-mma-the-sport-he-considered-human-cockfighting.html">human cockfighting</a>.” The lifelong boxing fan wrote letters to governors in every state asking them to ban the organization’s events saying, “I’ve seen people repeatedly getting smashed in the face with a guy sitting on top of them. That’s not sport!”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That really sent [the UFC] to a pretty terrible place. It got kicked off of Pay-Per-View. A lot of states didn&#8217;t even want anything to do with it, they would shut down [fights] at the last minute,” Luke Thomas, a combat sports analyst for CBS Sports, <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297?i=1000659810536">told the <em>Today, Explained</em> podcast</a>. “And in January 2001, the guys who originally founded the UFC, they threw in the towel. They sold it for $2 million to Dana White, [and] Lorenzo and Frank Fertitta.”<br><br>UFC’s new owners struggled too. Then Donald Trump called, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WsMpZtyU0-Q">White said on a podcast</a>, and said, “Come to my place. We’ll have you here at the Taj Mahal.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump’s invite helped the UFC’s new owners in the short term, but it was really when they seized upon a new trend — America’s love of reality television in the early 2000s — and created the reality TV series <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U6fw68fUEsY"><em>The Ultimate Fighter</em> on Spike TV</a> that the league’s fortunes turned around.<br><br>“For the casual audience who had maybe heard of UFC this put a brand new face on it,” says Thomas. “The world got to see really unique people doing a really crazy thing at the height of the reality TV show boom. And it worked!”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the success of the first season led to more seasons. It led to deals with ESPN. The UFC was eventually valued as a billion-dollar sports organization. And it’s only improved its value and stature in culture since. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-1861372857.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.72920025005,100,78.541599499901" alt="Men fight in a ring as Donald Trump and Kid Rock look on from the crowd." title="Men fight in a ring as Donald Trump and Kid Rock look on from the crowd." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Former President Donald Trump and Kid Rock attend the UFC 296 event at T-Mobile Arena on December 16, 2023, in Las Vegas, Nevada. | Jeff Bottari/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Jeff Bottari/Zuffa LLC via Getty Images" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How MMA turned MAGA</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Journalist <a href="https://x.com/sam_eagan?lang=en">Sam Eagan</a> has been a longtime fan of combat sports. He writes and podcasts pretty often about UFC, MMA, and domestic extremism. And he says that he began to see the topics overlap after reporting on the growth of <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/n7evgw/neo-nazi-fight-clubs-robert-rundo-fat-shaming-white-nationalism">neo-Nazi fight clubs</a> in the US.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I would say fighting is in no way inherently a conservative sport, but it presents as being about the individual. It’s one person competing against one person in a very violent, dominant fashion,” Eagan <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297?i=1000659810536">told the <em>Today, Explained </em>podcast</a>. “So there’s these themes of domination and violence — and in the case of the really, really far right … they’re very easily paralleled in MMA.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s not on the extremes where Eagan sees an overlap. He pointed to the 2016 Republican National Convention where Dana White became one of the first people to publicly endorse Trump.<br><br>“For over 15 years, Donald Trump has been a loyal and supportive friend,” White said.“And I know that if I needed Donald, he would be there for me, just like he was when I first met him.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Soon after that Trump was elected president. But in 2019 he was pretty unpopular. He was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uQjd9GPG3LA">booed at the World Series</a> in Washington, DC. “And so, he makes an appearance at a UFC event shortly after. And, you know, it gets the full treatment, the cameras panned to him, and fighters are cheering his name and talking about him in their post-fight interviews,” Eagan says. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Trump continues to appear at events periodically for the next few years. But then in 2023, it really takes off, Eagan says. “By my count, he appeared at three separate events in that year alone. [And] as I was watching these events, I would notice this feels like a captive campaign stop for Trump.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I&#8217;m sure there will be many more in the lead-up to the election.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s not just Dana White showing love for the former president. Former title contender <a href="https://www.espn.com/mma/fighter/_/id/3088810/colby-covington">Colby Covington</a> has built <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ul2Wq77cSCc">a whole persona</a> around being a Trump fan. He <a href="https://a57.foxnews.com/static.foxnews.com/foxnews.com/content/uploads/2023/12/1200/675/colby-1.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1">wears MAGA hats</a> all the time; in post-fight interviews, he makes shoutouts to first responders, members of the military, and to Trump himself; and throws around phrases like “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WA-2yXPxmeA">fake news</a>” regularly. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Jorge Masvidal, a Cuban American fighter from Florida, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/10/29/mma-trump-election-433529">held a series of pro-Trump rallies</a> called Fighters Against Socialism. “We either re-elect President Trump and keep America great,” Masvidal said at one rally. “Or we let Joe Biden destroy the greatest country the world has ever seen.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite the rising popularity of the UFC, and its owner’s and fighters’ embrace of conservative politics, Eagan says, “I do not think that the UFC will sway the election [for Trump].” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he does believe that Trump’s embrace of UFC and combat sports has created a sort of blueprint for appealing to young men who “may be vaguely conservative but are generally sort of apolitical.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the sports data site <a href="https://www.imgarena.com/about/">IMG Arena</a> 75 percent of <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17430437.2022.2033218#:~:text=The%20UFC%20has%20over%20300%20million%20fans,and%20stratification%20(MacDonald%2C%20Lamont%2C%20and%20Jenkins%202019).">UFC’s fans</a> are men and 88 percent of those men are between the ages of 18 and 44. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A demographic any candidate would be happy to tap into.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Costner, the American Western, and the American ego]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/358108/kevin-costner-horizon-american-saga-review-history" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358108</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T23:16:49Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-29T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Reviews" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[What becomes of the mighty when they don’t merely fall from glory, but leap headlong while crowing about their own greatness? In this case, the mighty is Kevin Costner, and he hath not only fallen but hurtled over the edge with Horizon: An American Saga — Chapter One. The new three-hour behemoth, released Friday, is [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Kevin Costner as a gunman in Horizon." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/costner.avif?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">What becomes of the mighty when they don’t merely fall from glory, but leap headlong while crowing about their own greatness?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In this case, the mighty is Kevin Costner, and he hath not only fallen but hurtled over the edge with <em>Horizon: An American Saga — Chapter One</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The new three-hour behemoth, released Friday, is the first of a four-film epic Western that Costner <a href="https://deadline.com/2023/05/francis-ford-coppola-kevin-costner-interview-megalopolis-horizon-1235359148/">says</a> he’s wanted to make since 1988. Directed, co-written, and self-financed by Costner, <em>Horizon</em> features an all-star ensemble cast, has a $100 million budget, and will be, when all four films wrap, approximately 12 hours long. It’s a bizarre work about the settling of a small Western town that critics are accurately calling “<a href="https://nypost.com/2024/06/26/entertainment/horizon-an-american-saga-chapter-1-review-kevin-costner-quit-yellowstone-for-this/">an embarrassing</a>, poorly told mess,” “<a href="https://ew.com/movie-reviews-horizon-an-american-saga-chapter-1-three-hours-stable-clearing-8669810">dull as dirt</a>,” “<a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/movies/story/2024-06-27/horizon-american-saga-chapter-1-review-kevin-costner-western">overindulged tedium</a>,” and “<a href="https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20240520-horizon-an-american-saga-review-kevin-costners-western-is-a-numbingly-long-incoherent-disas-ter">a numbingly long</a>, incoherent disaster.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also, despite its best efforts at creating sympathy for Indigenous Americans, borderline offensive, with an intense, violent depiction of a nominally unprovoked Apache raid that takes up nearly the first third of the film. The sequence does its very best to make settlers seem like the innocent victims in all this. While the rest of the film tries to undo the initial impression that the Apache are the true aggressors, it’s the only thing that lands. That isn’t surprising when you consider that Costner can be an excellent director, creating a gripping action sequence but failing to deliver on the quieter parts of the film, but it is surprising when you consider that he’s generally been far more sympathetic to Indigenous concerns than <em>Horizon</em>’s first chapter shakes out to be. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That leads us to the inevitable question: What happened here?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand how we reached this baffling point, we have to understand just how big Costner was at the peak of his stardom — and how quizzical his career has been ever since.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>In the early 1990s, there was no bigger star than Costner</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard to overstate just how successful Kevin Costner was at the height of his career. Somewhat unusually for an actor of his caliber, Costner, who was born in 1955, didn’t start working in the field until his mid-20s, and didn’t break through until he was 30. He did so, however, with a string of iconic film roles — as wayward outlaw Jake in <em>Silverado</em> (1985), federal agent Eliot Ness in <em>The Untouchables</em> (1987), heartthrob baseballer Crash Davis in <em>Bull Durham</em> (1988), and Ray Kinsella, the builder (and dreamer) of <em>Field of Dreams</em>’ titular field in 1989. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These early roles identified Costner with both mythologized Americana and iconoclastic heroes. Then, in 1990, Costner doubled down on this persona and elevated his stature to a whole new level by directing himself in one of the most influential films of the decade: <em>Dances With Wolves</em>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Dances With Wolves</em> typically gets credited with revitalizing and reinventing the epic Hollywood western for modern audiences — a craze that kicked off with <em>Wolves</em>, by 1991, grossing over $175 million and winning seven Oscars, including Best Picture and Best Director. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Faithfully adapted by Michael Blake from his own bestselling novel, <em>Dances With Wolves</em> depicts the journey of a lone soldier (Costner) assigned to a wayward Western outpost during the Civil War. There, he interacts primarily with Lakota and Pawnee, sympathizing with them and their concerns until he ultimately stands with them against an encroaching Union army encampment. The film has a <a href="https://crookedmarquee.com/the-complicated-legacy-of-dances-with-wolves/">complicated cultural legacy</a>, as it both galvanized important cultural conversations about Indigenous rights and <a href="https://filmschoolrejects.com/dances-with-wolves-native-lens/">typified</a> the “<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23832310/michael-oher-blind-side-adoption-tuohy-white-savior">white savior</a>” narratives that until recently dominated Hollywood’s treatment of marginalized communities. Still, it’s a true cinematic achievement with grand cinematography, stunning landscapes, and a soaring depiction of a troubled time in the country’s history. It still earns accolades as a true American epic. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-159824459.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,12.02928192313,100,75.941436153741" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kevin Costner holding an American flag in &lt;em&gt;Dances With Wolves&lt;/em&gt;. | Tig Productions/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Tig Productions/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">For a heady few years after <em>Wolves</em>, Costner was unstoppable: He became the A-lister’s A-lister, hopping from blockbuster to blockbuster in quick succession. <em>Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves </em>was a fun anachronistic romp with an all-star ensemble that <a href="https://screenrant.com/robin-hood-prince-of-thieves-90s-classic-still-holds-up-relevant/">still slaps</a>, as well as one of the <a href="https://www.billboard.com/music/music-news/the-biggest-summer-songs-of-all-time-bryan-adams-everything-i-do-i-do-6634483/">bestselling theme songs</a> in history. <em>The Bodyguard</em> saw Costner star opposite Whitney Houston as a hardened security guard in what was considered a groundbreaking interracial romance between two titans at their peaks. Its cultural legacy has <a href="https://pitchfork.com/thepitch/the-paranoid-prescience-of-the-bodyguard-whitney-houston/">been kinder</a> than critics were at the time, but its $400 million box office and <a href="https://www.grammy.com/news/bodyguard-soundtrack-25-years-after-whitney-houstons-masterpiece">the biggest soundtrack of all time</a> are hard to argue with. Even pivoting away from type and toward weirder fare, Costner still did numbers, with Oliver Stone’s conspiratorial <em>JFK</em> grossing $<a href="https://www.boxofficemojo.com/title/tt0102138/">70 million</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s important to remember the chronology here. Costner enjoyed phenomenal career success after an astonishingly short time as an actor; just five years out from his first major role, he directed a film that swept the Oscars. Then he quickly followed that feat up with a truly incredible run of films.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because he did so many important and successful films after it, most people probably catalog <em>Dances With Wolves</em> as coming early, toward the start of his incredible run of success, until the infamous back-to-back cringe flops of <em>Waterworld</em> and <em>The Postman</em> torpedoed his trajectory for years. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But <em>Wolves</em> was instead arguably his pinnacle — the peak of both his creative achievements and his cultural impact. That’s significant as a predictor of what <em>Horizon</em> eventually became, both because of its Western theme and because of its outsized ambition.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Costner personified red-blooded rugged individualism onscreen — and Hollywood divadom offscreen</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The idea of a prestige movie this immense being released by a major studio now is absurd,” Will Leitch <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/130346/dances-wolves-best-picture-25-years-later">argued</a> of <em>Dances With Wolves</em> in the New Republic in 2016. “This was the last time a movie star had so much clout that he could do something so patently crazy and expensive, and get a major studio to finance it—and thus the last time it could pay off.”  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, even though it was an important film in many ways, <em>Dances With Wolves</em> was effectively the last of its kind — as Costner would soon learn. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Alongside the runaway success Costner enjoyed between the late ’80s and the mid-90s, he was gaining a reputation within Hollywood as an egomaniac — “either exacting to a fault or an unjustified pain in the ass,” as Puck’s Matthew Belloni <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2023/02/22/when-hasnt-kevin-costner-been-a-pain-in-the-you-know-what/">summarized</a> last year. By 1994, the sands had begun to shift. That year, <em>Wyatt Earp</em> flopped, even with Costner heading another all-star ensemble and once again proving his chops as a leading man in a Western. But then came <em>Waterworld</em>, an infamously expensive post-apocalyptic film. Costner was reportedly so difficult and demanding during its creation that director Kevin Reynolds <a href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/movies/a33443888/why-waterworld-is-actually-good-25th-anniversary-essay/">walked out of the editing process</a>, leaving the actor to wrap things up. “In the future Costner should only appear in pictures he directs himself,” Reynolds <a href="https://ew.com/article/2012/05/18/kevin-costner-and-kevin-reynolds-speaking-feuds/">reportedly told</a> <em>EW</em> after the split. “That way he can always be working with his favorite actor and his favorite director.” (Though that quote seems prescient, the pair would go on to make up and work together again on 2012’s History channel series <em>Hatfields &amp; McCoys</em>. )</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Waterworld</em>, about a waterlogged society, became perhaps the most notorious of Hollywood “flops.” Even though it ultimately grossed over $250 million worldwide, its bloated $175 million production budget was the most expensive in Hollywood history at the time; the film’s marginal profits were <a href="https://screenrant.com/how-much-money-waterworld-lost-box-office-bomb/">swallowed</a> in marketing and production costs. Reynolds commented in a <a href="https://edcaesar.co.uk/2008/09/14/kevin-costner-sunday-times/">2008 interview</a> that the pressure was intense: “The press were after us from early on, willing us to fail.” It didn’t help that Costner displayed diva behavior on set, making finicky demands of production and <a href="https://www.sheknows.com/entertainment/articles/2895997/kevin-costner-difficult-reputation-waterworld/">reportedly</a> lounging in an “$1800-a-day oceanfront villa” while the crew <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150729011111/http://moviepilot.com/web/20150729011111/http://moviepilot.com/posts/3402322">reportedly</a> languished in shoddier quarters. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/Waterworld-Kevin-Costner-4K-UHD-Blu-ray-Review-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,1.463186382376,100,97.073627235248" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kevin Costner in &lt;em&gt;Waterworld&lt;/em&gt;. | Arrow Video" data-portal-copyright="Arrow Video" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, <em>Waterworld</em>, which has since enjoyed a <a href="https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20200916-waterworld-at-25-reappraising-cinemas-biggest-flop">markedly</a> warmer <a href="https://www.esquire.com/entertainment/movies/a33443888/why-waterworld-is-actually-good-25th-anniversary-essay/">critical reception</a>, didn’t fully sink Costner’s career; it took a second post-apocalyptic flop, even stranger than the first, to do that. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The Postman</em>,<em> </em>directed by Costner, is a true oddity. Considered a post-apocalyptic Western a la <em>The Road</em>, it clocks in at three hours and boasts a screenplay by absolute GOAT Brian Helgeland, writer of a range of bangers from <em>Mystic River</em> to <em>A Knight’s Tale</em>. Fun fact: Helgeland won the Oscar for <em>L.A. Confidential</em> and a Razzie for <em>Postman</em> in the same weekend. <a href="https://ew.com/gallery/oscar-winners-who-have-razzies/">The Razzies</a> took delight in perpetually nominating Costner and all his projects throughout the ’90s; <em>The Postman</em> was like Christmas come early for the infamous “worst-of” awards, which gave the film the prize in five different categories and later nominated it for Worst Picture of the Decade. (It lost to <em>Showgirls</em>). </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unlike <em>Waterworld</em>, <em>Postman</em>’s reception has stayed flaccid over time, largely thanks to the bleakly authoritarian, pseudo-fascist ideology that undergirds its story of a lonely troubadour who tells people false stories of a new US government springing up to replace the one that no longer exists, spreading the myth until it sparks a real movement. Helgeland said in a <a href="https://guru.bafta.org/brian-helgeland-screenwriters-lecture">2012 interview</a> that he wrote Costner’s unnamed character as a con man, spinning a darkly satirical fantasy of American greatness, but Costner wanted the character to be more “sympathetic” and “sincere.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Helgeland noted this is where the film “went wrong” — but for Costner, the vision he committed to film was clearly the vision he wanted: an essentially hopeful, essentially kind, but fundamentally conservative vision of American greatness. And he’s continued to build that narrative, more or less, ever since.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Costner’s directorial and ideological oeuvre has stayed consistent since </strong><strong><em>Wolves</em></strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although <em>The Postman</em> flopped so badly it essentially paused Costner’s career for half a decade, he began a self-made revival with 2003’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rd1tXbsOGxs"><em>Open Range</em></a>, which revived: 1) Costner in the lead 2) directing himself 3) in a panoramic western 4) as a lone hero standing up to injustice, armed only with a bunch of guns and a Personal Code. <em>Open Range </em>met a warm critical and audience reception, and Costner’s career meandered back on track through the 2000s and early 2010s with a wide range of films. He took smaller roles in ensemble movies like <em>The Company Men</em> (2010) and romantic leads in rom-coms like 2005’s eyebrow-raising flop <em>Rumor Has It</em> (where he sleeps with three generations of women in one family). </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His most mainstream hit in this period, <em>Hidden Figures</em> (2016), saw him once again in a white savior role, albeit a historical one, facilitating structural change at NASA.  The film’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hNK8FCFpmm4">most famous scene</a> has him taking out his frustration at systemic inequality by physically destroying a segregated bathroom sign. It was on the heels of that renewed success that <em>Yellowstone</em> creator Taylor Sheridan came calling in 2017. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The rest, as viewers of that juggernaut know, is history: Costner’s cantankerous relationship with Sheridan notwithstanding, he propelled the show, about an iconoclastic family of maverick ranchers, to becoming <a href="https://www.vox.com/22759551/yellowstone-kevin-costner-paramount-peacock-tv">TV’s biggest hit</a> since <em>Game of Thrones</em>. And despite rumors swirling about why he left after five seasons, leaving the show to flounder to complete a sixth without him, he <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/kevin-costner-disappointed-rumors-yellowstone-exit-1235927434/">claims</a> he still loves that world and would even come back to it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s easy to see why Costner loves <em>Yellowstone</em>: Sheridan’s universe of morally off-center individuals playing by their own rules fully aligns with all of Costner’s major works to date; in 2018, he <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/08/arts/television/kevin-costner-interview.html">called</a> his character, John Dutton, equivalent to “a modern-day CEO.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Costner’s conservatism isn’t that of the extreme far right; recall that he <a href="https://www.politico.com/blogs/click/2012/05/kevin-costner-waiting-on-obamas-call-124733">supported</a> Obama in both terms, <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/kevin-costner-blasts-american-politics-140038203.html">thinks</a> Michelle Obama would make a good candidate, and faced major backlash among his <em>Yellowstone</em> faithful when he publicly supported Liz Cheney’s failed 2022 bid for reelection after her stand against the January 6 insurrection. In <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/entertainment/tv/2022/11/10/yellowstone-kevin-costner-john-dutton-season-5-preview/8296024001/">an interview</a> where he touted Cheney’s “brave, clear-headed stance,” he also said he wished politicians “had a bigger vision and more of a morality about how they see the country evolving.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Costner, that morality seems to boil down to a kind of broad populism. “I feel I’ve made a movie for the people, period,” he recently <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/05/kevin-costner-horizon-an-american-saga-yellowstone-controversy-1235907679/">told Deadline</a> about <em>Horizon</em>. “This isn’t a movie from me. I felt like it was my turn in my career to tell a story. This is the one I choose to tell. It’s just my turn.”  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The story he seems to be telling in <em>Horizon</em> is one of settler communities facing and overcoming hardships, embracing the call of the West in the 1850s and ’60s, and battling Indigenous Americans, who are themselves trying to assert their identity and maintain their way of life amid encroaching colonization. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or, at least, that’s the story he may be telling. Eventually. The story onscreen in <em>Horizon</em>’s first chapter is an incongruous muddle with a bizarre, difficult-to-parse script that often vibes like Thornton Wilder writing dialogue for the Shire. Subplots that never connect play out amid sweeping vistas and a constantly bombastic soundtrack, as though someone ran John Ford and Sergio Leone through ChatGPT and got an enthusiastic community theater troupe to fully commit to the bit. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid all of it, there&#8217;s that horrific Apache raid — conveying what, exactly? Unfortunately, it’s too early to tell; its settler apologetics coast on a thin layer of empathy for a small group of pacifist Apache characters who disappear halfway through the movie, presumably to return in later films. Where any of this is going, or if any of it will even carry over to the second film, is unclear. A final hasty montage appears unprompted at the end of the film — a long, confusing barrage of disjointed clips that could be an attempt to wrap up the current plot, preview the next movie, or just quickly use up all the footage they ran out of time to squeeze into this one. Who knows?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What is clear is the sense of gravitas, of a man with a strong mission carrying it out at long last. Costner’s ego fills every frame; we can sense from the outset how desperately he wants this film sequence to restore to him the industry’s <em>Wolves</em>-era respect for his artistry and talent as a director. As it stands, however, there’s too much that’s baffling and unchecked about this project to make that likely. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If, however, Costner means what he says about making a film for “the people,” he might have better luck. Currently, despite its muddled, messy state, the audience score for <em>Horizon</em> on Rotten Tomatoes currently <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/horizon_an_american_saga_chapter_1">hovers</a> around 70 percent. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Will it be enough to make up for Costner <a href="https://nypost.com/2023/06/02/kevin-costner-risked-home-to-fund-100m-30-year-film-series/">mortgaging</a> his beachfront Santa Barbara mansion in order to create the ultimate American cinema?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Probably not, but it wouldn’t be an American dream if it weren’t giant, over the top, and fueled less by reason than by sentiment. All in all, that’s the essence of Costner himself — and why <em>Horizon</em> might surprise us in the end.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Abdallah Fayyad</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[LBJ and Truman knew when to quit. Will Biden?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/358084/biden-drop-out-lbj-harry-truman" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=358084</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T22:52:39Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-29T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since becoming president, Joe Biden has faced calls to step aside and not run for reelection out of concern that he’s too old for the job. And since his disastrous debate performance, those calls have only grown louder.&#160; What might be making him press ahead? Some have suggested that the president feels an overwhelming sense [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Man reads newspaper with the headline &quot;LBJ: Won&#039;t Run&quot;" data-caption="A man reads the news in the April 1, 1968 Chicago Tribune announcing President Lyndon B. Johnson&#039;s decision not to run for reelection." data-portal-copyright="Corbis via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-615297800.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A man reads the news in the April 1, 1968 Chicago Tribune announcing President Lyndon B. Johnson&#039;s decision not to run for reelection.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Since becoming president, Joe Biden has faced calls to step aside and not run for reelection out of concern that he’s too old for the job. And since his disastrous debate performance, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">those</a> calls <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/28/opinion/joe-biden-tom-friedman.html">have</a> only grown <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/27/biden-democrats-replacement-00165672">louder</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What might be making him press ahead? Some <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/10/25/biden-run-president-again-2024/">have suggested</a> that the president feels an overwhelming sense of duty to serve his country and believes that stepping aside would be a cop-out. Others have theorized that he remains in the race because he thinks he’s one of the few people — <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/3973460-biden-on-beating-trump-i-may-not-be-the-only-one/">if not the only one</a> — who can beat Donald Trump. As <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2023/12/06/biden-democrat-trump-2024-elections-00130403">Biden told supporters</a>, “If Trump wasn’t running, I’m not sure I’d be running.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In this case, it’s also hard to ignore the obvious: Power is an extraordinarily difficult thing to walk away from. Take it from a former president who voluntarily chose not to run for reelection.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There is a lure in power,” <a href="https://www.trumanlibrary.gov/library/truman-papers/longhand-notes-presidential-file-1944-1953/april-16-1950?documentid=NA&amp;pagenumber=1">Harry Truman wrote</a> in 1950, two years before he publicly announced that he would not seek another term. “It can get into a man&#8217;s blood just as gambling and lust for money have been known to do.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Power can distort someone’s view of reality, making them believe they’re invincible or somehow not bound by the basic rules of biology. But while that makes power all the more seductive, it’s not impossible to break its spell. After all, for well over a century before there were term limits, American presidents tended to know when to call it quits: If they weren’t killed or voted out, they voluntarily bowed out after serving two terms — that is, until Franklin Delano Roosevelt was elected in 1932 and won four consecutive terms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Notably, two more recent presidents, Harry Truman and Lyndon B. Johnson, chose to walk away from the job. Here’s what we can learn from them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Harry S. Truman and Lyndon B. Johnson didn’t run for reelection</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Biden were to drop out of the race, he wouldn’t be the first incumbent president to know when it’s time to go.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Truman, a Democrat, was the last president who could have run for as many terms as he would have liked;&nbsp;the 22nd Amendment, which put in place the presidential term limits we still have today, applied only to presidents who would go on to serve after him. Truman won only a single full term in office in 1948, but he had also served almost the entirety of FDR’s fourth term after Roosevelt’s death.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Truman had had his fill. “In my opinion eight years as President is enough and sometimes too much for any man to serve in that capacity,” <a href="https://www.trumanlibrary.gov/library/truman-papers/longhand-notes-presidential-file-1944-1953/april-16-1950?documentid=NA&amp;pagenumber=1">he wrote</a>. “When we forget the examples of such men as Washington, Jefferson and Andrew Jackson, all of whom could have had a continuation in the office, then will we start down the road to dictatorship and ruin.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I know I could be elected again and continue to break the old precedent as it was broken by F.D.R.,” he continued. “It should not be done. That precedent should continue — not by a Constitutional amendment but by custom based on the honor of the man in the office.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After facing several setbacks, including declining popularity and losing the New Hampshire primary, Truman announced in March 1952 that he wouldn’t seek reelection. The Democrats held a brokered convention later that year and ultimately picked Adlai Stevenson, then governor of Illinois, to be their presidential nominee. (Stevenson also happened to be Truman’s preferred candidate.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 1968, President Lyndon B. Johnson also chose not to seek reelection. Johnson’s administration had been mired in the Vietnam War, and he was quickly losing domestic political support. He was facing serious challengers in the Democratic primaries and realized that his road to reelection would be rocky. The Democratic Party also seemed split, with many preferring someone like Robert F. Kennedy to move the country forward. He also had concerns about his health, uncertain that he could live out another term in office.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So Johnson pivoted, focusing the remainder of his presidency on salvaging his legacy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“With America&#8217;s sons in the fields far away, with America&#8217;s future under challenge right here at home, with our hopes and the world&#8217;s hopes for peace in the balance every day, I do not believe that I should devote an hour or a day of my time to any personal partisan causes or to any duties other than the awesome duties of this office — the presidency of this country,&#8221; <a href="https://www.npr.org/2018/03/25/596805375/president-johnson-made-a-bombshell-announcement-50-years-ago">Johnson said</a> on March 31, 1968, when he announced he wouldn’t seek reelection. The party went on to nominate his vice president, Hubert Humphrey, as the next Democratic candidate for president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Neither Johnson nor Truman can be considered wildly brave for their decisions. <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/statistics/data/lyndon-b-johnson-public-approval">Both</a> had <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/statistics/data/harry-s-truman-public-approval">tanking approval ratings</a>, and for anyone watching, the writing was on the wall: Reelection was highly unlikely.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The outcomes of their decisions can be viewed in many different ways. Both Democratic presidents saw their party suffer crushing defeats after they withdrew from their race. Then again, who’s to say the elections would have been different if they’d stayed in?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the fact that they knew when to quit was itself notable and worth commending. And as it turned out, both men saw <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/statistics/data/harry-s-truman-public-approval">a bounce</a> in <a href="https://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/statistics/data/lyndon-b-johnson-public-approval">their approvals</a> after withdrawing from the race.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>So, what should Biden do?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden could well be thinking: If Johnson and Truman dropping out didn’t save the party’s chances, then should he follow in their footsteps? More than that, the <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2018/09/the-complicated-legacy-of-lyndon-johnson/569068/">post-presidency for Johnson</a> led him <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/lbjs-last-interview">to agony, depression, and self-pity</a> — yet another personal reason Biden might want to plow through.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s more to Truman’s and Johnson’s stories, however, than the political outcomes that followed. The fact that they were able to walk away from the most powerful office in the country rather than being forced out was itself an admirable display of humility: a willingness to realize that there’s more to life than politics or their legacy.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-515284950.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.737627430915,100,78.52474513817" alt="Harry Truman sitting at a desk holding a corded phone receiver to his ear." title="Harry Truman sitting at a desk holding a corded phone receiver to his ear." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no question that it’s not easy to leave the presidency behind. One of Johnson’s daughters told the former president’s biographer, historian Robert Dallek, that her father’s career was essentially his whole identity. “My daddy committed political suicide for that war in Vietnam,” she said. “And since politics was his life, it was like committing actual suicide.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Johnson might have been angry on his way out of the White House, but he also looked forward to life on his Texas ranch without the burden of the presidency. “By God I’m going to do what I want to do,” he <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/387971.Flawed_Giant">said</a>. “If I want to drink a glass of whiskey, I’m going to drink a glass of whiskey. And if I want to have some bad manners, I’m going to have bad manners. I’ve got some freedom to do what I want to do.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Truman likewise stepped into the post-presidency by looking forward. In his farewell address to the nation, he reflected on his years in politics with pride and appeared sure in his decision to step down. “So, as I empty the drawers of this desk, and as Mrs. Truman and I leave the White House, we have no regret,” he told the nation in January of 1953. “We feel we have done our best in the public service.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At 81 years old, Biden has a lot to gain in his personal life from walking away. Past the average life expectancy of the average American man, he has the option to spend the rest of his time with friends and family, especially after a five-decade career in national politics.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like any president, however, his chief concern seems to be his legacy, and he likely believes that sending his party to a loss in the fall could ruin it, whether he’s on the ticket or not.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2015/01/12/opinion/zelizer-lbj-vietnam-disaster/index.html">Johnson</a> and <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/7741/gallup-brain-americans-korean-war.aspx">Truman</a>, Biden has lost political support because of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/12/19/us/politics/biden-israel-gaza-poll.html">his involvement in a foreign war</a>. But he’s also struggled with voters simply because of his age. After all, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/27/biden-democrats-replacement-00165672">more panic set in</a> among Democrats after Biden’s poor debate performance this week than during the campus protests on Gaza or the <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/detroit/news/uncommitted-movement-over-the-israel-hamas-war-spreads-from-michigan-to-other-states/">protest “uncommitted” campaigns</a> during the Democratic primaries.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though the polls at press time suggest that <a href="https://www.natesilver.net/p/the-presidential-election-isnt-a">Biden is on track to lose</a> in November, it’s certainly within the realm of possibility that Biden could eke out a victory because he’s running against a weak candidate with extraordinarily heavy baggage. It’s also possible that if Biden drops out,&nbsp;the Democratic candidate who replaces him will lose.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if Trump defeats Biden, the postmortems will likely say that the writing was on the wall before the campaign even began and that Biden handed democracy to a would-be autocrat simply because he had too much pride to drop out.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Short of winning, there’s only one thing Biden can do to prevent his legacy from being defined by his ego: He could give someone else a chance.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Flawed as their tenures may have been, Johnson and Truman understood that the presidency isn’t theirs to keep, and that power, however alluring, is fleeting. Biden would be wise to remember that.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Eric Levitz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Democrats got here]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357955/biden-age-democrats-nominee-kamala-harris" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357955</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T19:30:42Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-28T19:30:42Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A viciously xenophobic demagogue — who fomented an insurrection against the US government less than four years ago — is on track to win the White House this fall. And the only remotely viable alternative to him, for now, is a massively unpopular, geriatric Democrat who just advertised his inability to speak in complete sentences [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="ATLANTA, GEORGIA, UNITED STATES - JUNE 27: President of the United States Joe Biden and Former President Donald Trump participate in the first Presidential Debate at CNN Studios in Atlanta, Georgia, United States on June 27, 2024. (Photo by Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Anadolu via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158937191.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>ATLANTA, GEORGIA, UNITED STATES - JUNE 27: President of the United States Joe Biden and Former President Donald Trump participate in the first Presidential Debate at CNN Studios in Atlanta, Georgia, United States on June 27, 2024. (Photo by Kyle Mazza/Anadolu via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">A viciously xenophobic demagogue — who fomented an insurrection against the US government less than four years ago — is on <a href="https://www.economist.com/interactive/us-2024-election/prediction-model/president">track to win the White House this fall</a>. And the only remotely viable alternative to him, for now, is a massively unpopular, geriatric Democrat who just <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">advertised his inability to speak</a> in complete sentences on national television.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is the reality that confronts us in the wake of Joe Biden’s catastrophic performance at <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357788/biden-trump-debate-winners-losers">Thursday night’s presidential debate</a>. A comprehensive account of how we arrived at this grim moment would require a multi-volume history. But one cause of our current predicament is worth highlighting: Democratic presidential candidates repeatedly failed to select running mates with an eye to their party’s long-term best interests.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vice presidents do not always go on to become presidential nominees. But they very often do. In partisan primaries, few résumé items are more advantageous than a tenure as a beloved president’s heir apparent. Given this reality, a presidential nominee should aim to pick a running mate whom they consider <em>highly</em> electable.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Unfortunately, the last two Democratic presidents did not prioritize political chops when selecting their veeps.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Barack Obama didn’t choose Joe Biden because he thought that the then-Delaware senator would make a great Democratic nominee in 2016. To the contrary, by most accounts, Obama thought that Biden would be a totally nonviable candidate by the time his own hypothetical presidency ended. And he reportedly selected Biden precisely for that reason.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to senior Democrats who spoke with <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2019/05/joe-biden-and-barack-obamas-one-sided-embrace.html">New York magazine’s Gabriel Debenedetti</a> in 2019, Obama had assumed that Biden would be too old to run for president by 2016. And he reasoned that this fact would render Biden an especially loyal second-in-command: Bereft of political aspirations of his own, Biden would have no compunction about putting Obama’s interests and goals above all else.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As it happened, Obama misjudged his running mate in more ways than one. In hindsight, it appears likely that Biden would have been a stronger nominee in 2016 than Hillary Clinton — Obama’s hand-picked successor — proved to be. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, Obama was certainly correct that — even eight years ago — Biden, then 71, was much older than an ideal presidential candidate. Instead of making the Delaware senator his running-mate, or putting his thumb on the scales for Clinton, Obama should have found a veep who was in his or her political prime and boasted a demonstrable capacity to compete in a swing state. Instead, he put his own campaign and future administration’s interests over the long-term best interests of the Democratic Party, likely damaging his own legacy in the process.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Biden’s choice of Kamala Harris in 2020 was even more misguided. When he made that choice in August 2020, there was little basis for believing that Harris was one of the most politically formidable Democrats in the country.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harris had just mounted an exceptionally lackluster bid for the presidency. Then a California senator, Harris had entered the race for the Democratic nomination with <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/kamala-harris-more-billionaire-donors-than-any-other-democratic-candidate-2019-11">strong donor support</a> and an <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2019/02/09/politics/kamala-harris-first-good-month-poll-of-the-week/index.html">early surge in the polls</a>. Despite these early advantages, Harris failed to maintain — let alone build out — her coalition over the ensuing months, and her campaign collapsed before the primary’s first ballots were cast.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Nor was Harris’s electoral track record before 2020 especially encouraging. She had never won an election in a swing state or competitive district. And in her first statewide race in deep blue California in 2010, Harris defeated her Republican rival by less than 1 percentage point. Two years earlier, Barack Obama had won that state by more than 23 points.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given that Biden was 77 in August 2020, the likelihood that his running-mate would one day become his party’s standard-bearer was unusually high. It was entirely plausible that health problems would force him to retire before the end of his first term, let alone his second. And were Harris to become an incumbent president, no other Democrat would stand a chance of defeating her in a contested primary. For these reasons, Biden’s primary consideration in choosing a running-mate should have been his or her electability.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, he put enormous weight on demographic considerations. “I think he came to the conclusion that he should pick a Black woman,” former Democratic Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/13/us/politics/biden-harris.html#:~:text=In%20the%20end%2C%20Mr.%20Biden,might%20be%20expected%20to%20govern.">told the New York Times</a> in the summer of 2020. “They are our most loyal voters and I think that the Black women of America deserved a Black vice-presidential candidate.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without question, it is desirable for a vice presidential candidate to energize the Democratic Party’s most loyal constituencies. That is one dimension of electability. But it is not obvious that Harris actually possessed that capability; after all, her 2020 campaign resonated so little with Black voters in South Carolina that she was forced to withdraw before that state’s primary.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any case, the ability to appeal to swing voters is much more electorally valuable than a penchant for pleasing loyal Democrats. Turning out a Democratic voter who would otherwise stay home increases your margin by 1 point; flipping a Republican voter into your column increases it by 2. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The desire to give historically marginalized groups representation at the apex of American power is a righteous one. Such representation does have the potential to shift cultural perceptions about race and gender in a progressive direction (although, as Obama’s presidency showed, it also <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2018/11/5/18052390/trump-2018-2016-identity-politics-democrats-immigration-race">has the potential to catalyze a reactionary backlash</a>). But such diffuse cultural shifts are ultimately of less consequence than public policy, above all for the most vulnerable in American society. Working-class Black women have more to lose from a Congress that <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2017/05/biggest-outrage-of-trumpcare-continues-to-be-medicaid-cuts.html">guts Medicaid</a> and a civil rights division that prioritizes <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/01/trump-reverse-racism-civil-rights">anti-white discrimination</a> than they have to gain from seeing someone of their race and gender squander a national election. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, there were plenty of non-white-male Democrats with a proven record of appealing to swing voters for Biden to choose from. Amy Klobuchar had repeatedly won landslide victories in light blue Minnesota. Tammy Duckworth had unseated a Republican incumbent in a purple Illinois House district before subsequently winning election to the Senate. Michigan Gov. Gretchen Whitmer had demonstrated her appeal to Rust Belt independents. Tammy Baldwin had repeatedly won Senate races in Wisconsin. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead, Biden opted for a running mate who few in the party considered to be an optimal general election candidate, despite the fact that — were Biden to win — there was a high probability that Harris would be her party’s standard-bearer at some point in the near future.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Over the past two years, Harris’s <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/polls/approval/kamala-harris/">poor poll numbers</a> — and Democratic <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2023/01/30/harris-democrats-worry/">insiders’ lack of confidence in her political acumen</a> — reduced pressure on Biden to step down, and allow his party to run a less aged and unpopular nominee. Many party leaders seemed to reason that Biden was a safer bet than his vice president.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After Thursday night, it looks like this view was mistaken. For all her liabilities, Harris’s approval rating is somewhat <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/357746/biden-trump-debate-democrats-replace-dnc">better than Biden’s</a> at this point. The vice president has some gifts as an orator and no shortage of vitality. Given the immense difficulty of coordinating behind a non-Biden candidate at this late date, there’s a plausible case that she is now the Democratic Party’s best option. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Considering the importance of keeping Trump out of power, however, we deserve a better option. And if Obama and Biden had prioritized their party’s long-term best interests when choosing their running mates, we would likely have one.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the Supreme Court just ruled in favor of over 300 January 6 insurrectionists]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/357973/supreme-court-fischer-united-states-january-6-insurrection" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=357973</id>
			<updated>2024-06-28T19:26:25Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-28T19:25:37Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Friday, the Supreme Court ruled that a federal law, providing that anyone who “obstructs, influences, or impedes any official proceeding, or attempts to do so” commits a very serious federal crime, does not actually apply to everyone who obstructs, influences, or impedes an official proceeding.&#160; Worse, the Court does so in a case involving [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="WASHINGTON, DC - JUNE 28: Demonstrators rally in front of the U.S. Supreme Court on June 28, 2024 in Washington, DC. In a series of 6-3 rulings -- with the court’s conservative bloc in lock-step -- justices upheld Oregon’s law preventing homeless people from sleeping and camping outside, reduced the power of federal agencies to interpret ambiguous statutes and ruled that prosecutors overstepped when charging members of the January 6, 2021 mob that attacked the U.S. Capitol with obstruction. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2159699954.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>WASHINGTON, DC - JUNE 28: Demonstrators rally in front of the U.S. Supreme Court on June 28, 2024 in Washington, DC. In a series of 6-3 rulings -- with the court’s conservative bloc in lock-step -- justices upheld Oregon’s law preventing homeless people from sleeping and camping outside, reduced the power of federal agencies to interpret ambiguous statutes and ruled that prosecutors overstepped when charging members of the January 6, 2021 mob that attacked the U.S. Capitol with obstruction. (Photo by Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">On Friday, the Supreme Court ruled that a federal law, providing that anyone who “<a href="https://casetext.com/case/united-states-v-fischer-64">obstructs, influences, or impedes any official proceeding, or attempts to do so</a>” commits a very serious federal crime, does not actually apply to everyone who obstructs, influences, or impedes an official proceeding.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Worse, the Court does so in a case involving a January 6 insurrectionist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Approximately <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/3/25/24108640/supreme-court-january-6-insurrection-fischer-united-states-obstruct">330 people</a> who allegedly participated in that insurrection are charged with violating the statute at issue in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-5572_l6hn.pdf"><em>Fischer v. United States</em></a>, including Donald Trump. So Friday’s decision could potentially undermine much of the Justice Department’s ability to prosecute hundreds of people who attacked the US Capitol.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the surface, in other words, the <em>Fischer</em> decision could not play more into the growing narrative that the Supreme Court is a partisan institution that protects the interests of the Republican Party, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/4/22/24133424/supreme-court-donald-trump-immunity-january-6-president">and of Trump in particular</a>. How else can one explain the Court’s decision that the anti-obstruction law does not do what it says it does?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The full story of <em>Fischer</em>, however, is slightly more nuanced. For one thing, while five of the justices in the majority are Republicans, Biden-appointed Justice Kentanji Brown Jackson joined these five in the majority. Trump-appointed Justice Amy Coney Barrett wrote the dissent, which was joined by the Court’s two remaining Democrats.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And, while Chief Justice John Roberts’s majority opinion does not read the obstruction law according to its plain text, it does rely on rules governing statutory interpretation that the Court has, at least, <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2024/3/25/24108640/supreme-court-january-6-insurrection-fischer-united-states-obstruct">applied in less politically charged cases</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Fischer</em>, in other words, is less a case about justices tying themselves into knots in order to help out January 6 defendants than it is a case about how easy it is for judges to read a seemingly unambiguous law in multiple ways. The rules governing statutory interpretation are not clear, and it is not even certain when judges should apply one of those rules as opposed to a different one.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And that means each of the justices could have chosen either outcome in the <em>Fischer</em> case.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">So what did <em>Fischer</em> actually hold?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Fischer </em>case involves a <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/18/1512">federal law with two separate subsections</a>. Subsection (1) applies to anyone who “corruptly &#8230; alters, destroys, mutilates, or conceals a record, document, or other object, or attempts to do so, with the intent to impair the object’s integrity or availability for use in an official proceeding.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, subsection (2), the provision many January 6 defendants are accused of violating, applies to someone who “otherwise obstructs, influences, or impedes any official proceeding, or attempts to do so.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Barrett writes in dissent, the most natural reading of this statute is that anyone who broke into the US Capitol to disrupt certification of the 2020 election “can be tried for ‘obstructing, influencing, or impeding an official proceeding.’” Subsection (2) of this law “is a very broad provision.” The case that it applies to January 6 defendants “seems open and shut.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, the overwhelming majority of lower court judges who heard similar cases reached the same result as Barrett.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Roberts’s reading of the statute is, to put it mildly, less intuitive. He claims that subsection (2)’s broad language is “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-5572_l6hn.pdf">linked to its ‘surrounding words</a>.’” So subsection (2)’s broad language is “limited by the preceding list of criminal violations” in subsection (1).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Therefore, under Roberts’s reading, subsection (2) must be read to only capture activities similar to the ones described in subsection (1) — that is, activity like altering, destroying, mutilating, or concealing a record or document. The way that plays out, according to Roberts, is that January 6 defendants can only be charged under this statute if they created false evidence or otherwise impaired “the availability or integrity of other things used in an official proceeding beyond the ‘record[s], document[s], or other object[s]’ enumerated in (c)(1), such as witness testimony or intangible information.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let’s stipulate that Roberts’s interpretation of the statute is super confusing and that it does not comport with the way most English speakers would read this law. The oddest thing about <em>Fischer</em> is that there are actually some Supreme Court precedents that support Roberts’s decision.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar_case?case=3213681007315665467&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=6&amp;as_vis=1&amp;oi=scholarr"><em>Yates v. United States</em></a> (2015), which involved a very similar dispute in a much less politically charged case. The law in <em>Yates</em> targeted anyone who “knowingly alters, destroys, mutilates, conceals, covers up, falsifies, or makes a false entry in any record, document, or tangible object” with the intent to obstruct a federal investigation or proceeding.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The defendant was a commercial fisherman who caught undersized red groupers, then ordered a crew member to toss these fish overboard “to prevent federal authorities from confirming that he had harvested undersized fish.” <em>Yates</em> asked whether these undersized fish are a “tangible object” within the meaning of the federal statute.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Remarkably, a majority of the justices concluded that they are not. Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg’s plurality opinion concluded that a court should “avoid ascribing to one word a meaning so broad that it is inconsistent with its accompanying words,” and thus the term “tangible object” should be read “to refer, not to any tangible object, but specifically to the subset of tangible objects involving records and documents.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ginsburg’s opinion only garnered four votes, but Justice Samuel Alito wrote a concurring opinion saying that the question in <em>Yates</em> is “close,” but that largely agreed with Ginsburg’s reasoning.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given that <em>Yates</em> exists, Roberts’s <em>Fischer</em> opinion isn’t entirely ridiculous. The uncomfortable reality about <em>Fischer</em> is that a judge who wants to crack down on January 6 defendants can read the law according to its plain text, as Barrett did, while justices who wish to reach a different result can rely on <em>Yates</em>, as Roberts did.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What actually happened in this case is that five of the Court’s Republicans read the law in a way that minimizes the law’s impact on a particularly lawless band of Trump supporters, and they were joined by the Court’s sole former public defender. Read into that what you will.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The point is simply that previously established rules governing statutory interpretation give judges a great deal of leeway to reach a variety of results in many cases.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
