<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-06-25T13:35:01Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/05/vox-favicon.jpeg?w=32</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, you should prepare your kids for climate disasters]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/356532/prepare-kids-family-climate-disasters-emotions-logistics-tornado-hurricane-wildfire-heat" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356532</id>
			<updated>2024-06-25T13:35:01Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T13:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Advice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Family" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s a disconcerting but unmistakable fact that in an age of climate change-related natural disasters, parents may now find themselves fielding more questions from their children about wildfires, tornadoes, extreme heat, and hurricanes — and facing the prospect of guiding their kids through an emergency.&#160; Given all the stressors families face on a daily basis, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Familie, Eltern, Kinder, Haus, Eigenheim, geborgen, Zukunft, sicher, Schutz, Bausparvertrag, Immobilie, Generationen, Mutter, Vater, Tochter, Sohn, Geschwister, Mann, Frau, Mädchen, Junge, Bruder, Schwester, Patchworkfamilie, Schneekugel, Biotop, Gruppe, Vereinigung, abgeschlossen, ausgrenzen, einschließen, Figuren, Symbol, Konzept, Gemeinschaft, gemeinsam, Team, miteinander, zusammen, sonnig, gelb, orange, 3D Rendering" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/Westend61" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-564951375.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,15.25859375,100,84.74140625" />
	<figcaption>Familie, Eltern, Kinder, Haus, Eigenheim, geborgen, Zukunft, sicher, Schutz, Bausparvertrag, Immobilie, Generationen, Mutter, Vater, Tochter, Sohn, Geschwister, Mann, Frau, Mädchen, Junge, Bruder, Schwester, Patchworkfamilie, Schneekugel, Biotop, Gruppe, Vereinigung, abgeschlossen, ausgrenzen, einschließen, Figuren, Symbol, Konzept, Gemeinschaft, gemeinsam, Team, miteinander, zusammen, sonnig, gelb, orange, 3D Rendering</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s a disconcerting but unmistakable fact that in an age of <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2021/09/1098662">climate change-related natural disasters</a>, parents may now find themselves fielding more questions from their children about wildfires, tornadoes, extreme heat, and hurricanes — and facing the prospect of guiding their kids through an emergency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Given all the stressors families face on a daily basis, discussing and planning for such extreme events often falls by the wayside. “We know by the data that many Americans live in the moment, and there’s so much on family’s plates that it&#8217;s hard to remember to think about something in the future,” says <a href="https://newsroom.ucla.edu/experts/preview/531dadeb299b506ab20001b5/">Melissa Brymer</a>, the director of terrorism and disaster programs for the UCLA-Duke University National Center for Child Traumatic Stress. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thinking about the possibility of a natural disaster impacting your family can be overwhelming, so it makes sense that you would want to avoid it. But having a plan in place that keeps your kids’ needs in mind in case an extreme weather event does occur is crucial. Even if you don’t live in a part of the country prone to these events, climate-related disasters are striking everywhere and with greater frequency. Preparedness — logistically, physically, and emotionally — is more important than ever.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Broaching the topic doesn’t need to be distressing, experts say. Rather, it’s possible to talk honestly about the potential of a climate event while still allaying kids’ anxieties and giving them space to discuss their emotions. Despite how stressful it can seem, there are also strategies to help your kids cope if your family is affected by a natural disaster.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Emphasize preparation before a natural disaster</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parents understandably want to protect their children from unpleasant emotions, but try not to minimize the likelihood of a natural disaster, says <a href="https://www.caroline-hickman.com/index">Caroline Hickman</a>, a climate-aware psychotherapist who focuses on eco-anxiety in children and young people. You don’t want to frighten your child, but you do want them to be prepared in case there is an emergency.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consider the chance of certain extreme weather events where you live and give them age-appropriate guidance on how your family would stay safe, says American Academy of Pediatrics spokesperson <a href="https://www.chla.org/profile/david-schonfeld-md">David Schonfeld</a>, the director of the National Center for School Crisis and Bereavement. Younger kids respond well to storytelling, Hickman says, while older kids might roll their eyes and resist. “But you have to be very firm with them and say, ‘Look, I get it. I’m annoying. You don’t want to talk about it right now, but we are going to talk about it sometime this week,’” she says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might say to a younger child, “We’re entering into a season where we could get storms that bring a lot of rain and wind. But we will listen to the weather forecast and go to a place where the rain and wind aren’t as strong if we need to so we can stay safe.” You could also take this opportunity to explain the concept of a go bag — a backpack with essentials in the event you need to evacuate — and ask them what they might pack in it, like a favorite toy. The US Department of Homeland Security offers <a href="https://www.ready.gov/kids/prepare-pedro">free extreme weather preparedness resources</a> for children and families.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I don’t think the goal is just to let them know bad things can happen because that’s just frightening. It isn’t helpful,” Schonfeld says. “It is helpful if you can give them practical information about what they can do to decrease the risks and keep themselves and those they care about safe.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It can be helpful to ask kids, especially those in grade school, what they know about extreme weather events that occur where you live and how they feel about it, Hickman says. “Chances are, they know as much as you do, if not more,” she says, “and children love teaching their parents things.” This can give you an opportunity to correct them on any misinformation they may have read online or heard from friends.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“Feelings come later when you’re safe.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let them know if they ever feel scared, anxious, or have any questions about natural disasters, you’re here for them, says clinical psychologist <a href="https://www.longislandbehavioral.com/">Regine Galanti</a>, author of <a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/parenting-anxious-kids-understanding-anxiety-in-children-by-age-and-stage-regine-galanti/19865768?ean=9781728273020"><em>Parenting Anxious Kids: Understanding Anxiety in Children by Age and Stage</em>.</a> You’ll want to validate your childrens’ emotions without bringing in your own. Avoid statements like “I’m freaking out about this too,” or “You don’t have to be scared.” Instead try, “It’s gotten too hot in our house so we have to go somewhere else to cool off. I know it’s last minute and I’m not happy about it either. We’ll talk about it more in the car.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That’s actually super invalidating when you tell a kid not to feel their feelings,” Galanti says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reassure your children that they don’t need to take on the responsibility of keeping the family safe. Remind them that they can relax knowing that you will tell them when it’s time to take action, says <a href="https://childtrauma.ucsf.edu/our-team">Chandra Ghosh Ippen</a>, the associate director of the Child Trauma Research Program at the University of California, San Francisco and author of the <a href="https://piploproductions.com/stories/trinka-and-sam/">Trinka and Sam book series</a> developed to help families with young children cope after natural disasters.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reassure your kids and give them a task in case of evacuation</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If a natural disaster is imminent, explain to your kids any precautions you are currently taking, Schonfeld says. You might say, “There’s a bad storm coming and we’re going to go to the basement for a little while because it’s safer there,” or, “We’re tracking this fire. It might hit our area but because we have a plan, we’ll be safe since we are going to stay at grandma’s if it does.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You’ll want to model effective emotional coping even if you’re feeling anxious, says Schonfeld. That means sharing that you do have some unpleasant feelings and outlining what you’re doing to cope with them. You could mention, for instance, how the flooding made you nervous, but you remembered all of the steps your family has taken to stay safe and how you feel more prepared.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Avoid watching constant news or media coverage on TV or online, both for your own mental health and for your child’s peace of mind. Choose quality sources of news and only read or watch as much as you need to be informed about what steps to take next. Kids are observant and will pick up on their parents’ anxieties, even if they don’t understand exactly why they are upset, Ghosh Ippen says. If you need to take a moment to break down, do so in private. “Because for us to provide that support for our children,” Ghosh Ippen says, “we need to have a place where we can metabolize.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the event of an evacuation, tell your kids you are going to a place where you are absolutely certain you will be safe, Ghosh Ippen says. It can be helpful to give children a task, says Hickman, such as grabbing their go bag and a book or putting their shoes on. You might also mention that your family’s role is to get out of the way so emergency responders can do their jobs. Don’t feel like you must unpack any of your kid’s emotions during the height of an emergency, Hickman says: “Feelings come later when you’re safe.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Should you shelter in place, explain why you’re doing so, Brymer says. You could say, “The weather is dangerous so you can’t play outside and we need to sit in the basement until the storm passes,” or, “It’s too hot to go to the park today so we’re going to do some arts and crafts inside where it’s cool.” Distracting your kids from the ongoing extreme weather event can help pass the time, especially if you’ve lost power, Schonfeld says. Try singing songs, playing games, building a pillow fort, or reading books. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Avoid the impulse to pretend it never happened</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the aftermath of a natural disaster, it’s important parents don’t pretend it didn’t happen, experts say. You can praise your children for being mature and playing their part, Hickman says. Be truthful with your children if you are unable to return home right away and if there are disruptions to school. You could say, “We need to stay here longer than we thought because our house was damaged in the storm, but you’re safe here. We’re going to continue to stay together as a family.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Parents should try to facilitate conversations with their kids to discuss how they feel about the disaster. Kids can mask how they’re feeling, Hickman says. “You need to repeatedly ask those questions, because if you just do it once, and think we’re done — big mistake,” Hickman says. “You need to come back to it.” On the surface, children may appear calm, but are struggling to cope with the event. Acknowledge that it might have been scary and ask them how they’re feeling now. Chances are that if your family was directly impacted by the extreme weather event, your kids might know another family that has been, too. “We get a secondary trauma or a vicarious trauma,” Hickman says, which makes having repeated conversations necessary. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“You need to repeatedly ask those questions, because if you just do it once, and think we’re done — big mistake.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Children are more likely to be upset over the loss of their routines, Hickman says, and parents should acknowledge their child’s emotions. You can lead the conversation by mentioning, “I feel sad we’re dealing with all of this. I’m wondering how you feel about it?” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“You show them how to deal with the emotion,” Hickman says. “You’re not collapsed on the floor in a mess.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Acknowledge any damage to property, too. Resist the urge to tell your kids that you can buy more toys, Schonfeld says, and instead affirm that you know how important they were to them. Try to reframe a child’s sadness over losing their backyard tree house, for instance, as a sign of how much love they had for it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If school is canceled, you can facilitate ways for kids to connect with their friends, Brymer says, whether through coordinating a playdate, FaceTiming with the other child’s parents, or making artwork your kid can give to their friends when they see each other again.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Common <a href="https://www.schoolcrisiscenter.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Providing-psychosocial-support-to-children-and-families.pdf">reactions children might have after a natural disaster</a> include sleep problems, difficulty concentrating, and developmental regression, like bedwetting or thumb-sucking. Give your child grace to self-soothe in the service of healing, Schonfeld says, but encourage them to move forward. “Your goal is to get them back to normal as quickly as you can,” Galanti says. “So what extra supports do I need to give my kid to get them back to their normal?” You should seek out a mental health professional if your child is harming themselves or others or if behavioral problems persist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Continue to acknowledge how you feel in the aftermath so your kids know it’s okay to discuss their emotions, Brymer says. However, your child could feel confident and secure that you’ve kept them safe and may not be affected by the natural disaster, Ghosh Ippen says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Regardless of the extreme weather event or the extent of disruption to your family, experts stress the importance of acknowledgment: that the event occurred, that your child might be scared, that they might have lost a routine. Keep the lines of communication open and let kids know that they’re allowed to feel any range of emotions. </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The whole time? The Boys has been making fun of Trumpers the whole time?!]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/356474/boys-season-4-trump-woke-review" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356474</id>
			<updated>2024-06-24T23:18:50Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Comic Books" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="TV" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Television shows getting terrible reviews isn’t anything new.&#160;But there’s something fascinating happening with the fourth season of The Boys. It’s not just that people have suddenly turned on Amazon’s hit superhero satire, it’s who those people are and why they’ve changed their tune that’s so interesting.&#160; Since premiering to critical praise on June 13, alleged [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Amazon Studios" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-24-at-2.26.49 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Television shows getting terrible reviews isn’t anything new.&nbsp;But there’s something fascinating happening with the fourth season of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/The-Boys-Season-1/dp/B0875L45GK"><em>The Boys</em></a>. It’s not just that people have suddenly turned on Amazon’s hit superhero satire, it’s who those people are and why they’ve changed their tune that’s so interesting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since premiering to <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/tv/the_boys_2019/s04">critical praise</a> on June 13, alleged fans have been review-bombing the show’s latest season on sites like Rotten Tomatoes and IMDB. The most vocal and eye-catching of these takedowns pronounce that the show has gone “<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TheBoys/comments/1df475c/s4_seems_a_bit_woke/">woke</a>” or is so obviously “<a href="https://gizmodo.com/eric-kripke-the-boys-anti-woke-fans-trump-prime-video-1851546943">anti-Donald Trump</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They’re not wrong, but they’re excruciatingly late to this observation.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since the show’s inception in 2019,<em> The Boys</em> has been a superhero allegory about Trump, dangerous authoritarianism, political fanaticism, Nazis, and America’s sway toward fascism. Its showrunner, Eric Kripke, has said as much <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/boys-penis-homelander-trump-billy-joel-season-3-1369258/">interview</a> after <a href="https://x.com/therealKripke/status/1328006661408055296">interview</a>: This is a show explicitly about the allure of Trump and a critique of corporate America. The only thing that’s seemingly different in this fourth season is that it skates so close to what’s happening in the US now: Homelander (Antony Starr), a Superman-like sociopath who functions as the Trump stand-in, is facing a criminal trial and is fanning the flames of a January 6-like insurrection. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These angry public admissions from conservatives that they&#8217;ve spent the previous seasons cheering on this horrible character — only to now realize they&#8217;re the butt of the joke — have become bigger than the show itself. It’s a testament to our culture’s ever-diminishing <a href="https://www.vox.com/conversations/2017/5/8/15440292/donald-trump-politics-culture-neil-postman-television-media">media literacy</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t the first time in pop culture that a superhero satire has served as a warning about fascism and its biggest fans have whiffed on the point. That it keeps happening is a testament to how difficult it may be for all of us to not be lost in the allure of powerful people.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s happening on this season of <em>The Boys&nbsp;</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the heart of <em>The Boys</em> is a brash deconstruction of the superhero fantasy, taking apart the traditional comic book superhero arc where super-powered beings save the day and defend those who can’t defend themselves.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <em>The Boys</em>, however, every character, every line, every shot, and every scene paints a larger portrait of how extremely screwed we would all be if superheroes existed in real life. <em>The Boys</em>’s<em> </em>cynical counter to the fantasy is a worldview that humans — even super ones — are morally flawed beings and that power always compromises morality. No matter how good we could be or think we could be, our selfishness, biases, envy, and everything in between will always get the better of us.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People aren’t meant to be superheroes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These human failings take the form of heroes like the terminally narcissistic Homelander or any of his coworkers, known as The Seven (a parallel to DC Comics’s Justice League or Marvel’s Avengers). Homelander and his pals rape and kill and lie but their powers and, more importantly, their celebrity status keep them from facing any semblance of justice. The Seven are all propped up by Vought International, an ultra-powerful pharma-entertainment-military defense corporation originated by a Nazi who invented a serum that gave normal people superpowers.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vought has its tentacles wrapped around every sphere of human life, whether its politics or sports or television and movies or law enforcement. There is no escaping Vought and the heroes it uses to make the world bend to its will.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-24-at-2.25.49 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.440818997756,100,79.118362004488" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Just like former President Donald Trump, Homelander faces a criminal trial in the fourth season of &lt;em&gt;The Boys&lt;/em&gt;. | © Amazon Content Services LLC" data-portal-copyright="© Amazon Content Services LLC" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This season builds on the idea that Homelander has built a following so large and loyal that Vought can’t control him. He’s always been invincible and able to shoot laser beams from his eyes, but it’s his acolytes that have made going against him impossible. The monster Vought created has become the master, and he’s now pulling the strings and attempting to manipulate the world around him.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the season opener, Homelander is facing trial for the killing of a protester, a fan of former Seven member Starlight (Erin Moriarty). Starlight, who has the ability to manipulate electricity and energy, was the rare “good” hero and didn’t last long in Homelander’s tribe. She’s now part of an anti-Vought, anti-Homelander political movement, which is the short version of why Homelander killed her supporter. That, and Homelander is also a pathetically fragile sociopath. Yet, everyone including Homelander knows that he won’t be found guilty. Even if he was, it wouldn’t matter because he’s too politically significant to face any real consequences. It’s only a matter of time before Homelander plans a coup, a January 6-like insurrection and takeover of the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A celebrity turned powerful political figure and authoritarian who is facing trial and stirring up a fascist insurrection should sound very familiar to anyone paying the slightest bit of attention to American politics over the last eight years. Kripke, the showrunner, <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-features/boys-penis-homelander-trump-billy-joel-season-3-1369258/">said as much in 2022</a>, asserting that Homelander has “always been a Trump analogue” and that the parallel should have been crystal clear in the show’s third season in 2022. Kripke’s fourth season is even more urgent and obvious.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, despite <em>The Boys</em>’s purposefully unsubtle treatment of the dangerous creep of authoritarianism over the past three seasons and the showrunner plainly stating that the villain of his show is Trump, some of <em>The Boys</em>’s viewers are just now crying foul and expressing shock over the show’s politics.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>The Boys</em>’s audience score is the lowest in the show’s existence&nbsp;</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On Rotten Tomatoes, the show’s <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/tv/the_boys_2019/s04">audience score</a> is at 50 percent, despite boasting a 95 percent critical score. That’s the lowest score The Boys has ever had. The divide between critics and viewers, with viewers submitting a lower score, doesn’t usually happen. Outlets like <a href="https://screenrant.com/the-boys-season-4-rotten-audience-score-explained/">Screenrant</a>, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/conormurray/2024/06/18/anti-woke-critics-of-the-boys-mocked-on-social-media-as-creators-say-the-series-was-always-a-satirical-right-wing-critique/">Forbes</a>, and <a href="https://www.nme.com/news/tv/the-boys-season-four-being-review-bombed-3766932">NME</a> pointed out that the divide seems to be driven by viewers claiming the show has gone “woke.” They also explain that the show is being <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/5/23/18637464/rotten-tomatoes-audience-verified-score-trolls-brigading-review-bombing">review-bombed</a>, a practice in which users — whether or not they’ve seen the shows — flood aggregators like Rotten Tomatoes and IMDB with bad reviews to drive the audience/word of mouth score down. Television series and movies that are seen as progressive (e.g., shows that center characters of color, LGBTQ characters, and women) are sometimes <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/2/26/18241840/rotten-tomatoes-review-bomb-captain-marvel-star-wars-the-last-jedi">review-bombed</a> by those who don’t agree with that progress.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The blowback to this season mirrors the backlash that happened at the end of 2022’s season three — the season in which Kripke said the satire was extremely clear and the line between Homelander and Trump extremely thin. Certain Homelander-loving fans had <a href="https://slate.com/culture/2022/06/homelander-fans-herogasm-boys-amazon-trump.html">a meltdown</a> upon realizing that their hero was actually a villain.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That it took four seasons of the show for right-wing and conservative-leaning viewers to realize the characters they were championing were liberal spoofs of them is a dynamic that’s ripe for jokes about how media literacy is fighting for its life. How long would you let someone make fun of you for? What if it took roughly four years for you to figure it out? Wouldn’t you keep something like that private?&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-24-at-2.33.12 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,11.136610005305,100,77.72677998939" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A character named Stormfront (Aya Cash) who likes men with Aryan features and drumming up online chaos turned out to be ... a NAZI! | © Amazon Content Services LLC" data-portal-copyright="© Amazon Content Services LLC" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if fans forgive <em>The Boys</em>’s superheroes for committing reprehensible acts like the aforementioned rape, killing, and violence, there were still moments that should have made the intent quite clear. In season two, an honest-to-God Nazi named<strong> </strong><a href="https://ew.com/tv/the-boys-season-2-stormfront-reveal/">Stormfront</a><strong> </strong>(which is literally the name of a <a href="https://www.splcenter.org/fighting-hate/extremist-files/group/stormfront">Neo-Nazi internet forum</a>) emerged on the scene and became Homelander’s ally and love interest. Her name and characterization (violence, really into social media, complimenting Homelander for Aryan features) couldn’t have been more obvious. But certain fans didn’t pick up on it, some even tied themselves in knots trying to exonerate Homelander’s fixation with her. Take for example this Reddit thread about whether <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CharacterRant/comments/vlghop/homelander_isnt_a_nazi/">Homelander was a Nazi</a> because of his relationship with Stormfront, including the distinction that Homelander wasn’t a Nazi but a racist who has sex with Nazis.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fact that so many erroneous interpretations of <em>The Boys</em> exist — despite its creator explicitly talking about <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-features/the-boys-showrunner-erik-kripke-interview-trumpism-1235914642/">how mistaken they are</a> — indicates there may be something at work with how viewers filter the media they consume. Perhaps media bubbles have reached a point where all of us expect the things we watch to reinforce our ideals. We’ve gotten so good at watching things that fit with our political leanings, and being served things that fit with our politics, that we can’t even identify when something is built to challenge those beliefs. What if it’s hard for conservative and alt-right viewers to comprehend that <em>The Boys </em>wasn’t made <em>for </em>them because they’re so used to everything in their sphere being <em>for</em> them?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The show has skewered some liberal ideologies as well. <em>The Boys</em> includes multiple moments where Vought International’s PR team strategically focus-groups race and sexuality when it comes to their celebrity heroes. Each person of color or LGBTQ person joining The Seven is seen by corporate HQ as a token, a tool to push their agenda more effectively. It’s a blistering critique of the shallowness of corporate diversity, equality, and inclusion and how effective appearances are at winning liberals over.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And in season two, the show introduces Victoria Neuman (Claudia Doumit). Enigmatic and for the people, Neuman seems to be a stand-in for one Rep. <a href="https://slate.com/culture/2020/10/boys-season-2-finale-victoria-neuman-aoc-head-exploder-twist.html">Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez</a>.&nbsp; Slowly viewers came to understand that she has her own nefarious motives and at least one mind-blowing super-powered secret. That you can’t trust even the most progressive lawmakers because all lawmakers sell a little part of themselves to the highest bidders sure feels like a leftist critique.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kripke has no qualms about the bluntness of his series.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I’m certainly not going to pull any punches or apologize for what we’re doing,” Kripke told <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-features/the-boys-showrunner-erik-kripke-interview-trumpism-1235914642/">the Hollywood Reporter</a>. “Some people who watch it think Homelander is the hero. What do you say to that? The show’s many things. Subtle isn’t one of them. So if that’s the message you’re getting from it, I just throw up my hands.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>The Boys</em> isn’t the first superhero critique where people didn’t see the critique</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>The Boys</em> isn’t the first superhero satire that seems to have gone over the heads of much of its devoted audience. Writer Alan Moore and artist Dave Gibbons’s <em>Watchmen</em> was both a critique of the genre and a warning about how superhero comics glamorize authoritarianism and fascism while doing double duty in infantilizing their audience.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, so many fans, some very prominent, gush over <em>Watchmen</em> and how it portrayed gritty, damaged men, all but ignoring Moore’s warnings. <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2015/7/29/9060251/ted-cruz-rorschach-watchmen">Texas Sen. Ted Cruz</a> famously named Rorschach, an extremist vigilante who sees violence and torture (<a href="https://www.cbr.com/watchmen-worst-things-rorschach-has-done-ranked/">e.g., breaking people’s fingers</a>) as part of his job, one of his favorite superheroes. Similarly, director Zack Snyder’s 2009 adaptation <a href="https://www.avclub.com/the-watchmen-movie-proves-you-can-be-faithful-to-a-comi-1830312684">reveled in the gloom and doom</a> of its bloodied heroes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to Moore, those were exactly the wrong things to take out of his work.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The creation of Rorschach — I was thinking, well, everybody will understand that this is satirical. I’m making this guy a mumbling psychopath who clearly smells, who lives on cold baked beans, who has no friends because of his abhorrent personality. I hadn’t realized that so many people in the audience would find such a figure admirable,” <a href="https://www.gq.com/story/alan-moore-interview">Moore told GQ in 2022</a>, voicing his frustrations. He added, about <em>Watchmen </em>and<em> </em>his other graphic novel<em> V for Vendetta&nbsp;</em>:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>They were trying to show that any attempt to realize these figures in any kind of realistic context will always be grotesque and nightmarish. But that doesn’t seem to be the message that people took from this. They seemed to think, uh, yeah, dark, depressing superheroes are, like, cool.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">I think I understand fascism … But if this stuff can be so fundamentally misunderstood, it does make you wonder what the point of doing it was.</p>
</blockquote>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While <em>Watchmen</em> and <em>The Boys</em> touch upon the same themes, they’re drastically different in style. The latter leans into raunch and slapstick to highlight the hilariously bleak absurdity of just how close its creator thinks we are to a fascist dictator — while the former relies on plain old bleak absurdity.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/Screenshot-2024-06-24-at-2.26.18 PM.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.9316166257079,100,80.136766748584" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Homelander (left) is supposed to be a Trump analogue. Victoria Neuman (right) seems to be a stand-in for AOC. What if the message of the show is that you can&#039;t trust anyone with power? | © Amazon Content Services LLC" data-portal-copyright="© Amazon Content Services LLC" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, both want to raise a mirror to their audiences, using superheroes to warn us about the perils of believing in the goodness of the most powerful people, from professional athletes to politicians to pop stars. Political affiliation doesn’t matter, power is power and shouldn’t be adulated. At the end of the day, no one is going to save us, especially not corporate-backed, focus-grouped capitalist heroes. That viewers keep tripping on this point only proves how alluring this fantasy is.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Anna North</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Pregnancy in America is starting to feel like a crime]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/health/356512/pregnancy-america-crime-dobbs-justice" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356512</id>
			<updated>2024-06-24T22:25:15Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T11:15:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine you’re eight months pregnant, and you wake up in the middle of the night to a bolt of pain across your belly.&#160; Terrified you might be losing your pregnancy, you rush to the emergency room — only to be told that no one there will care for you, because they’re worried they could be [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A pregnant person cradles their belly." data-caption="Pregnant people are struggling to get care in the wake of the Dobbs ruling, experts say." data-portal-copyright="Jose Luis Pelaez Inc via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/GettyImages-91497758.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Pregnant people are struggling to get care in the wake of the Dobbs ruling, experts say.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Imagine you’re eight months pregnant, and you wake up in the middle of the night to a bolt of pain across your belly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Terrified you might be losing your pregnancy, you rush to the emergency room — only to be told that <a href="https://apnews.com/article/pregnancy-emergency-care-abortion-supreme-court-roe-9ce6c87c8fc653c840654de1ae5f7a1c">no one there will care for you</a>, because they’re worried they could be accused of participating in an abortion. The staff tells you to drive to another hospital, but that will take hours, by which time, it might be too late.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such frightening experiences are growing more common in the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/24/23181720/supreme-court-dobbs-jackson-womens-health-samuel-alito-roe-wade-abortion-marriage-contraception">the Supreme Court’s 2022 <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health</em> decision</a>, as doctors and other medical staff, fearful of the far-reaching effects of state abortion bans, are simply refusing to treat pregnant people at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s part of what some reproductive health activists see as a disturbing progression from bans on abortion to a climate of suspicion around all pregnant patients. “People are increasingly scared even to be pregnant,” said Elizabeth Ling, senior helpline counsel at the reproductive justice legal group If/When/How.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fall of <em>Roe</em> has led to an ever-widening net of criminalization that can ensnare doctors, nurses, and pregnant people alike, leading to devastating consequences for patients’ health, experts say. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Complaints of pregnant women turned away from emergency rooms doubled in the months after <em>Dobbs</em>, the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/pregnancy-emergency-care-abortion-supreme-court-roe-9ce6c87c8fc653c840654de1ae5f7a1c">Associated Press reported</a> earlier this year. Concerns about such treatment, combined with stories of people like <a href="https://time.com/6960387/kate-cox-abortion-rights-interview/">Kate Cox</a>, who was denied an abortion despite the risks her pregnancy posed to her health, have made some Americans afraid of conceiving: In <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2023/09/13/dobbs-pregnancy-maternal-health-00115561">one recent poll</a>, 34 percent of women 18 to 39 said they or someone they knew had “decided not to get pregnant due to concerns about managing pregnancy-related medical emergencies.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Such surveys, along with ER records and calls to helplines, reveal a sense that in a post-<em>Dobbs</em> America, any pregnancy can be dangerous — to patients, to doctors, or both. “The fact that people are viewing the condition of pregnancy as something that makes them vulnerable to state violence is just so heartbreaking,” Ling said.</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Americans are facing prosecution after miscarriage</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Dobbs</em> decision has created an environment in which people experiencing miscarriage are treated as criminals or crimes waiting to happen, advocates say — or sometimes both.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In October 2023, an Ohio woman named Brittany Watts <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/03/us/brittany-watts-ohio-miscarriage-abortion.html">visited a hospital</a>, 21 weeks pregnant and bleeding. Doctors determined that her water had broken early and her fetus would not survive, but since her pregnancy was approaching the point at which <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ohio-miscarriage-prosecution-brittany-watts-b8090abfb5994b8a23457b80cf3f27ce">Ohio bans abortions</a>, a hospital ethics panel kept her waiting for eight hours while they debated what to do. She eventually returned home, miscarried, tried to dispose of the fetal remains herself, and was charged with felony abuse of a corpse.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The charges were <a href="https://apnews.com/article/miscarriage-prosecution-ohio-brittany-watts-68145b3044b3cc61017b71a97f7cc036">ultimately dropped</a>, but experts say her case is part of a larger pattern. “There has become this hypersurveillance, hyperpolicing, hyperinterrogation” of pregnant people in America, said <a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/michele-goodwin/">Michele Goodwin</a>, a professor of constitutional law and global health policy at Georgetown and the author of <em>Policing the Womb: Invisible Women and the Criminalization of Motherhood</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That surveillance isn’t entirely new, advocates and scholars say. Black pregnant women, especially, have been targets of suspicion for generations, stereotyped as drug users or <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/154404/myth-welfare-queen">“welfare queens”</a> and even arrested when they tried to seek maternity care, said Goodwin. “There are cases of Black women having been dragged out of hospitals, literally in shackles and chains,” Goodwin said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Black women and other women and girls of color have also been disproportionately targeted for arrest or investigation following miscarriages or stillbirths. In 1999, Regina McKnight, a 22-year-old Black woman in South Carolina, became the first person prosecuted for homicide after experiencing a stillbirth, <a href="https://capitalbnews.org/miscarriage-criminalization-ohio/">according to Capital B</a>. She was convicted and sentenced to 12 years in prison for endangering her pregnancy through drug use, but her conviction was eventually overturned.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But now, the atmosphere of criminalization around pregnancy is “spreading into wider and wider groups of people,” said Karen Thompson, legal director of the group Pregnancy Justice, which tracks the criminalization of pregnant people.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Black advocates have long cautioned that while the criminalization of pregnancy might affect Black and brown women today, “tomorrow it’s everybody,” Goodwin said. “<em>Dobbs</em> brought us into the tomorrow.”</p>

<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Dobbs</em> is making doctors scared to treat pregnant patients</h3>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the tomorrow of post-<em>Dobbs</em> America, doctors and hospital staff now fear criminal charges if they are found to have performed an abortion in violation of their state’s bans. These bans have <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/article/2022/12/focusing-exceptions-misses-true-harm-abortion-bans">exceptions</a> for saving the life, or sometimes the health, of the pregnant person, but the exceptions are often extremely narrow or <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/07/20/us/abortion-save-mothers-life.html">unclear</a>, forcing medical professionals to choose between refusing to treat a severely ill patient and losing their license or going to jail.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The way the states write their statutes, there’s no deference to the medical judgment of the doctor,” said <a href="https://publichealth.gwu.edu/departments/health-policy-and-management/sara-rosenbaum">Sara Rosenbaum</a>, an emerita professor of health law and policy at George Washington University. “It has had a profound chilling effect on any care in emergency departments, because physicians and hospitals are in a panic.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That chilling effect is leading some doctors to refuse not just to perform abortions, but also to provide any care for pregnant people in crisis, lest their care draw scrutiny in a restrictive and uncertain legal environment. A week after the <em>Dobbs</em> ruling, a woman arrived at Falls Community Hospital in Marlin, Texas, nine months pregnant and having contractions, according to a federal investigation of ER visits. The doctor on duty refused to treat her, instead sending her to another hospital in Waco, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/pregnancy-emergency-care-abortion-supreme-court-roe-9ce6c87c8fc653c840654de1ae5f7a1c">the AP reported</a>. The outcome of her pregnancy — and the impact on her health of delayed maternal care — are unknown.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In another case, a pregnant woman arrived at a North Carolina hospital complaining of stomach pain. Staff told her they could not perform an ultrasound, and she eventually gave birth in a car on the way to another facility 45 minutes away, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/pregnancy-emergency-care-abortion-supreme-court-roe-9ce6c87c8fc653c840654de1ae5f7a1c">the AP reported</a>. The baby did not survive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’re talking a level of outlandishness that is up there with <em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em>,” Rosenbaum said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA) requires all hospitals that accept Medicare to stabilize the medical condition of anyone who arrives at an emergency room, including pregnant people. But the medical interventions allowed under new state abortion laws are often less than what EMTALA requires, Rosenbaum said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, the Supreme Court in the coming days will decide <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/12/4/23984674/supreme-court-abortion-emtala-emergency-medically-necessary-idaho">a case that could gut EMTALA</a>, giving hospitals even more leeway to turn away pregnant patients.<em> </em>“I don’t think it’s an understatement to say that the loss of EMTALA, or even just weakening of EMTALA, puts pregnant people’s lives at risk,” Ling said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even people who are not yet pregnant feel the widening effects of <em>Dobbs</em>. The If/When/How helpline has received calls from people who want to become pregnant, but are terrified that “they might experience an unexpected loss like a miscarriage, and still somehow be punished for experiencing that loss,” Ling said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent months, she has heard herself say the words, “it is not a crime to be pregnant,” she told Vox. And yet, more and more, it feels like it is.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story originally appeared in&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Today, Explained</a></em></strong><em>, Vox’s flagship daily newsletter.&nbsp;</em><strong><em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/today-explained-newsletter-signup" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sign up here for future editions</a></em></strong><em>.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Benji Jones</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The frogs of Puerto Rico have a warning for us]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/356465/down-to-earth-puerto-rico-coqui-bioacoustic-science" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356465</id>
			<updated>2024-06-25T03:03:32Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In much of the world, nature sounds like birds or maybe insects — the cheerful, rhythmic cheeps of a robin, say, or the buzz of a cicada.&#160; In Puerto Rico, it sounds like frogs. Lots and lots of frogs. If you walk into pretty much any forest on the island you’ll hear a loud, almost [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9I5A9446.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In much of the world, nature sounds like birds or maybe insects — the cheerful, rhythmic cheeps of a robin, say, or the buzz of a cicada.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In Puerto Rico, it sounds like frogs. Lots and lots of frogs. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If you walk into pretty much any forest on the island you’ll hear a loud, almost deafening chorus of amphibians.&nbsp;The lead singer is the common coqui, a tannish treefrog with big, sticky toes. They are Puerto Rican icons no larger than a ping-pong ball that call — <em>CO-KEE, CO-KEE</em> — to attract mates and mark their territory.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Puerto Rico, a Caribbean island and US territory, is home to more than 15 native species of frogs. And these animals have a lot to say. The number and diversity of frogs,&nbsp;and their collective voice, can indicate the health of an ecosystem. Frogs, like other amphibians, tend to be sensitive to subtle changes in climate and water quality, making them reliable environmental sensors, according to Marconi Campos-Cerqueira, an ecologist.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/re-edit-frog.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A common coqui. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">When lots of frogs are singing, it’s a sign that the forest is healthy. A quiet forest is cause for concern.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Scientists are increasingly listening to their calls. In the last two decades, a large number of researchers have turned to bioacoustics, the study of all kinds of animal sounds, to monitor the health of the environment. It’s pretty simple: They place a few mics in the forest to gather sound, and then run the data they retrieve through computer software. That software reveals what animal species are there, and when.  </p>

<iframe frameborder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP4689141263" width="100%"></iframe>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For years now, scientists in Puerto Rico have been using bioacoustics to monitor environmental changes. By listening to the sounds of frogs, they’re figuring out how climate change — and the storms and heat waves that come with it — is altering life on the island.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A frog paradise</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On a cloudy morning earlier this year, I drove into the mountains of central Puerto Rico with Kris Harmon, a scientist at WildMon, a nonprofit that monitors ecosystem health in Puerto Rico and elsewhere. Parts of the road were crumbling, likely eroded from excessive rain. Climate change has been making hurricanes&nbsp;more destructive —&nbsp;<a href="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2019GL082077" data-type="link" data-id="https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2019GL082077">including Hurricane Maria</a>, which struck Puerto Rico in 2017 — in part by loading them up with more moisture.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Harmon parked above the clouds at the edge of a lush forest. Before I even opened the door I could hear frogs singing. <em>CO-KEE! CO-KEE! </em>There was also the more occasional <em>KI-KI-KI-KI-KI</em> from a red-eyed coqui, a small tree frog with rust-colored eyes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The frogs are omnipresent,” Harmon said.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/re-edit.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kris Harmon peers into a bromeliad plant in search of frogs. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">We walked into the woods down a steep, overgrown path flanked by ferns, palms, and bromeliads (plants that look like the tops of pineapples). Harmon soon spotted what he was looking for: a microphone strapped to the trunk of a large tree.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This mic, housed in a simple black box, records forest sounds. It’s part of a long-term project, initiated a few years ago by Rainforest Connection, another environmental group, to monitor wildlife in Puerto Rico. There are some 29 other mics just like it in different habitats around the island that have been running for years. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9I5A8508.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,32.547993019197,100,34.904013961606" alt="A square black box is screwed to the bark of a mottled tree." title="A square black box is screwed to the bark of a mottled tree." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A Rainforest Connection microphone that records sounds in the forest. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The hardware is simple. The mic is attached to a circuit board and a battery that records one minute of sound every five minutes to a built-in memory card. Every few months, those cards are collected and the recordings are uploaded online and converted into spectrograms, which show sound data in visual form. Then, the software essentially scans the spectrograms for matches within an existing library of animal noises. The data can tell researchers which species are present at each recording site and, more broadly, how the range of sounds in one habitat differs from another. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The mic Harmon showed me, in a site called Toro Negro, has picked up the mutterings of a number of different animals in the last few years. These include those two noisy frogs, of course — the common and red-eyed coquis — as well as several other frogs, including melodius and grass coquis, that have their own distinct song. It has also detected a variety of birds, such the Puerto Rican tody, an emerald green species with bright red throats. (The software that analyzes sounds for this project only detects about 40 species of interest, Harmon said, including those that are threatened with extinction.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The data isn’t perfect. Some animals, such as snakes, don&#8217;t call at all. Plus, sound alone can’t tell you much about abundance — i.e, how many of a certain species are found in a particular place. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;Discerning whether 100 detected calls are from one bird in mating season or dozens of less active individuals remains challenging,&#8221; said Ben Gottesman, a bioacoustics expert at Cornell University. &#8220;Estimating population density through bioacoustics is still quite complex.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But if your goal is to figure out what species live or travel through a particular area, Harmon says, bioacoustics technology is “pretty hard to beat.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What these recorders have taught us</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On a basic level, microphones reveal what does and does not live in a place, without having to spend a lot of time doing field work. This helps scientists easily create maps of biodiversity. Local authorities and nonprofits use these sorts of charts to establish new wildlife reserves.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But these sounds can also help researchers understand how ecosystems are changing. In a <a href="https://peerj.com/articles/4059/#aff-1">pair</a> of <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1002/ece3.3520">studies</a> based on bioacoustics, Campos-Cerqueira, the chief scientific officer at WildMon, who works with Harmon, found that a number of frog and bird species appear to be moving to higher elevations, where it’s cooler, likely due to rising temperatures. In lowland areas of the Luquillo Mountains, a rainforest in eastern Puerto Rico, for example, recording devices no longer detect a handful of frog species that once lived there. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Many bird and frog species are changing their distribution on the island,” Campos-Cerqueira told me. “A lot of species are going up [higher] into the mountains to track more favorable temperature and humidity conditions.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This movement of frogs and birds makes existing protected areas less useful —&nbsp;because unlike the animals they safeguard, they’re stuck in place. By mid-century, much of the habitat that’s cool and wet enough for frogs will likely fall outside of wildlife reserves, <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10531-021-02258-9">according to a 2021</a> study led by Campos-Cerqueira.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9I5A9449.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A red-eyed coqui. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Other research has used mics to understand how superstorms affect wildlife on the island. In <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1470160X21003009">another 2021 study</a>, led by Gottesman, scientists compared communities of birds and insects before and after Hurricane Maria using bioacoustics. Maria was the second most powerful storm to hit Puerto Rico in recorded history, killing nearly 3,000 people and damaging or flattening millions of trees. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though not all that surprising, the authors found that sounds made by birds and insects (at least those that produce low and medium frequency noises) dropped by about 50 percent following the hurricane. It took one to two months for the sounds of insects to return to pre-storm levels, the authors found. The variety of bird calls took even longer to bounce back.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the analysis, audio recorders detected a drop in bird calls two days before the storm hit, adding evidence that some animals — from <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2014/12/141218131413.htm">warblers</a> to <a href="https://www.vox.com/down-to-earth/23852549/hurricane-idalia-sharks">sharks</a> — may be able to detect incoming storms days in advance and flee the area. “In this time of rapid environmental change,” Gottesman and his coauthors wrote, “soundscapes can signal the ways in which altered disturbance regimes are transforming ecosystems.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A new era of wildlife monitoring</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tropical ecosystems are complicated. There are literally thousands of species of plants, animals, and fungi that all influence each other, like a complex machine that no one fully understands.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In just a few days in Puerto Rico this year, I saw boa constrictors and lizards and waterbirds, lots of weird bugs, and so many frogs. They all play a role,&nbsp;including species that we’re <a href="https://oakland.edu/oumagazine/news/cas/2022/ou-professor-helps-discover-describe-new-species-of-gecko-in-puerto-rico#:~:text=The%20karst%20gecko%20(Sphaerodactylus%20verdeluzicola,Biological%20Sciences%20at%20Oakland%20University.">only just</a> discovering.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9I5A8626_8c31eb.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="A small slimy green slug-like creature sits on a green leaf." title="A small slimy green slug-like creature sits on a green leaf." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="A “semi-slug,” a mollusk with a tiny, almost imperceptible shell. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">This complexity makes figuring out how ecosystems are changing — really,&nbsp;how <em>we are </em>changing them — extremely difficult. And that in turn makes it hard to hold those who are responsible for that change accountable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">More and more, major financial firms, <a href="https://www.responsible-investor.com/investors-turn-to-acoustics-in-search-for-biodiversity-measurement-solution/">including Fidelity International</a>, increasingly want to know the impact of their investments on the environment, and how declining ecosystems put those investments at risk. How, for example, are insect pollinators faring and what impact might that have on agricultural commodities and producers?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Advances in bioacoustics are making it much easier to answer these sorts of questions. When paired with other tools that are now similarly mainstream — including motion-sensing cameras, satellite imagery, and eDNA analysis, where scientists analyze the bits of DNA in a habitat —&nbsp;audio recordings and the software to analyze them are ushering in a new era of wildlife monitoring.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t just about pointing out problems, such as&nbsp;the destruction of a food web. It’s also about helping monitor progress in restoring nature. A study <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-41693-w">published last year</a> in <em>Nature Communications, </em>for example,<em> </em>showed that bioacoustics can be used to measure the recovery of wildlife in tropical forests that were previously cleared for farming and ranching.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The researchers analyzed audio from forests in northwestern Ecuador, finding significant changes in the community of noise-making animals in forests at different stages of recovery. “Clearly the regenerating forests are recovering species that are only really found in old growth forests, which is a really good sign,” Zuzana Buřivalová, a coauthor on the study, told my colleague Byrd Pinkerton earlier this year for an <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/a-stethoscope-for-the-rainforest/id1554578197?i=1000641144211">episode of the podcast <em>Unexplainable</em></a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9I5A8673.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Tiny pearl-like eggs bubble together in a cluster inside the curved inner rim of a thick green bromeliad leaf." title="Tiny pearl-like eggs bubble together in a cluster inside the curved inner rim of a thick green bromeliad leaf." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="The eggs of a common coqui inside a bromeliad plant. | Benji Jones/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Benji Jones/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">As I spent more time in Puerto Rico, my ears became more discerning. Instead of just recognizing “a frog,” I was able to identify different species of coqui, even when I couldn’t see them. (They were nearly impossible to find, even when they seemed to be calling from just inches away.) In those subtle musical differences I was starting to detect — in that variety of frog croaks — are secrets to the health of these forests. To unlock them we just have to listen.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why this year’s Hajj was so deadly]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/356624/hajj-mecca-heat-saudi-arabia-pilgrims-climate-change-prophet" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356624</id>
			<updated>2024-06-24T23:26:38Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Religion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 1,300 people have died in Saudi Arabia during this year’s Hajj, the annual pilgrimage to some of Islam’s holiest sites, succumbing to the brutal temperatures in the Gulf region.  The kingdom of Saudi Arabia has always had hot summers, but temperatures reached 125 degrees Fahrenheit during this year’s pilgrimage, conditions that may become [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="TOPSHOT - Rescuers carry away a man, affected by the scorching heat, on a stretcher as Muslim pilgrims arrive to perform the symbolic &#039;stoning of the devil&#039; ritual as part of the hajj pilgrimage in Mina on June 16, 2024. Friends and family searched for missing hajj pilgrims on June 19 as the death toll at the annual rituals, which were carried out in scorching heat, surged past 900. (Photo by FADEL SENNA / AFP) (Photo by FADEL SENNA/AFP via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2157800659.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>TOPSHOT - Rescuers carry away a man, affected by the scorching heat, on a stretcher as Muslim pilgrims arrive to perform the symbolic &#039;stoning of the devil&#039; ritual as part of the hajj pilgrimage in Mina on June 16, 2024. Friends and family searched for missing hajj pilgrims on June 19 as the death toll at the annual rituals, which were carried out in scorching heat, surged past 900. (Photo by FADEL SENNA / AFP) (Photo by FADEL SENNA/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">More than 1,300 people have died in Saudi Arabia during this year’s Hajj, the annual pilgrimage to some of Islam’s holiest sites, succumbing to the brutal temperatures in the Gulf region. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The kingdom of Saudi Arabia has always had hot summers, but temperatures reached 125 degrees Fahrenheit during this year’s pilgrimage, conditions that may become routine for the country as the world struggles with the effects of climate change. That reality raises the question of how the kingdom can better mitigate extreme heat to limit Hajj deaths in future — and likely hotter — years. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year’s tragic deaths were caused by the heat, but were exacerbated by a visa system many attempt to circumvent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Muslims, Hajj is one of the five most sacred professions of faith and many adherents view making the journey to Mecca, the birthplace of the Prophet Muhammad, as a requirement for all believers able to do so. To control the flow of Muslims wishing to complete the journey, Saudi Arabia limits the number of Hajj visas it offers per year. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To get around that requirement, some companies provide would-be pilgrims with tourist visas to Saudi Arabia that do not include permission to make Hajj — or accommodations at the holy sites where people can shelter from the heat. Left without any official government aid or oversight, many of these unauthorized pilgrims suffered from exposure — and it is they who make up the largest proportion of the dead, according to Saudi authorities.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">How Saudi Arabia will manage these pilgrims, and the coming extreme temperatures, in the future isn’t clear; though if the government does not, people are likely to continue to die in large numbers.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is Hajj?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hajj consists of visits to multiple holy sites in Mecca, Saudi Arabia, where the Prophet Muhammad was born. During Hajj, Muslims visit the Kaaba, a shrine within the Great Mosque which they are to walk around seven times. Over the five days, they also visit other sites outside Mecca, including Mount Ararat, the site of Muhammad’s last sermon according to tradition. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This journey is very expensive, running anywhere between <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-06-24/hajj-heat-deaths-saudi-arabia-s-soaring-temperatures-endanger-pilgrims?sref=qYiz2hd0">$3,000 and $17,000</a> depending on the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-06-24/hajj-heat-deaths-saudi-arabia-s-soaring-temperatures-endanger-pilgrims?sref=qYiz2hd0">package they choose and their country of origin</a> (some countries, like Indonesia, subsidize parts of Hajj travel). It requires a special visa that’s obtained ahead of time through<a href="https://hajj.nusuk.sa/"> a government portal</a> — where people can also choose their Hajj packages, including accommodations, transportation, and even add-ons like SIM cards and additional tours. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s estimated that <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/06/23/hajj-heat-saudi-arabia-pilgrims/">hundreds of thousands of pilgrims</a> unable to access the official visas complete Hajj through alternative methods each year. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why was it so deadly this year?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many pilgrims come to the kingdom under tourist visas, which technically don’t allow access to Hajj sites. Though these pilgrims are allowed in Saudi Arabia and visit the Hajj sites without official paperwork, those sites are not set up to accommodate them. That means they don’t have air-conditioned transportation to and from the sites, or government reserved air-conditioned lodging where they can rest or escape the heat. According to government officials, <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8000dgk9gzo">141,000 of these unauthorized pilgrims</a> were treated for heatstroke. Many more are <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/06/23/hajj-heat-saudi-arabia-pilgrims/">believed to have suffered</a> without treatment. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Muslims from poor countries are likeliest to come without the necessary accommodations — and likeliest to suffer from heat-related injury and death, especially as the journey becomes increasingly costly. &#8220;It&#8217;s beyond the reach of so many pilgrims from Egypt, Bangladesh and Morocco and other countries, even though they save for a lifetime to come once,” Madawi al-Rasheed, a visiting professor at the London School of Economics Middle East Centre, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2024-06-24/hajj-heat-deaths-saudi-arabia-s-soaring-temperatures-endanger-pilgrims?sref=qYiz2hd0">told Bloomberg</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All told, the government says it treated <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8000dgk9gzo">roughly half a million</a> of the 1.8 million people who made Hajj this year for heat-related conditions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year’s Hajj is not the deadliest on record. A 2015 stampede killed approximately 2,400 people though the Saudi government put that number much lower, at 769. The royal family, as <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2016/09/06/world/middleeast/2015-hajj-stampede.html">the New York Times</a> reported in the aftermath, had been accused of negligence and mismanagement in its oversight of the Hajj — primarily by regional rival Iran, which lost hundreds of citizens in the stampede — but has implemented huge infrastructure projects over the years meant to help make the Hajj less perilous. And there have been other mass casualties due to heat as well, like in 1985 when 1,012 people died in temperatures reaching 129 degrees, Bloomberg reported. And from 2002 to 2015, more than 90,000 pilgrims died on Hajj or Umrah, another pilgrimage to Mecca that does not need to be performed during the time of Hajj.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Islam operates according to the lunar calendar, so the timing of holy periods like Hajj shift from year to year. Next year, for instance, it will come earlier in June — which still may mean high heat. But often the Hajj doesn’t take place in the sweltering summer, so over the next several years travelers may not be subject to these dangerous conditions. However, that also means that by the next Hajj period, temperatures could be even higher than this year.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Is anything being done to make these events safer?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus far, many governments are putting much of the blame on travel brokers who got pilgrims into Saudi Arabia without the correct travel provisions and visas to actually complete the Hajj safely. Egyptian brokers have come under particular scrutiny: Of the 650 Egyptians who reportedly died during the Hajj, 638 were so-called unregistered pilgrims. The Egyptian government has already <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20240622-egypt-to-prosecute-travel-agents-over-hajj-fraud-government">sanctioned 16 travel brokers</a>, stripping them of their licenses and recommending them for prosecution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Figuring out how to prevent such unauthorized visits will be important for Saudi Arabia in the long term, especially as it continues its ongoing tourism push; <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-03-13/saudi-arabia-gets-13-billion-in-investment-in-tourism-boost?sref=qYiz2hd0">according to Bloomberg</a>, the tourism industry plans to add up to 200,000 new hotel rooms in the kingdom over the next two years, and hopes to have 150 million tourists by the year 2030. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But another significant concern is climate change — and the Gulf countries, including Saudi Arabia, are at particular risk. Regional temperatures are already significantly higher than global averages, and the majority of the population of the Gulf countries will be exposed to extreme heat by 2070 — even if global temperatures rise by only 1.5 degrees Celsius per global climate targets. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The government has tried to to mitigate some of the risks of conducting Hajj in such weather, including sending texts to pilgrims asking them not to go outdoors during the hottest parts of the day; misting and fanning walkways; and providing free water, in addition to training medical responders to deal with heat-induced illnesses. But that’s just not enough; improved medical infrastructure, flexible or staggered schedules for conducting different ceremonies; and more shading or pavilions for worshipers are just some of the simple ways the kingdom could address the problem.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The most effective ways to ensure reduced heat deaths, however, will have to come from policy changes. Though the government said it turned away 155,000 people who did not have the proper Hajj visas this year, nearly that number managed to subvert the system and suffered some form of heat injury. The kingdom will need a better system to reduce the number of unauthorized pilgrims — which could include helping subsidize the journey or encouraging other governments to do so, or <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/articles/it-is-time-to-reform-the-management-of-the-hajj/">changing the Hajj calendar and otherwise improving infrastructure</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And though Saudi Arabia has pledged to try to attack the root of the problem by releasing net zero carbon emissions by 2050, it remains one of the world’s largest producers of oil. And although the kingdom is diversifying its economy, it is still heavily dependent on oil and seems to be intent <a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/saudi-arabia-focuses-on-emissions-from-wind-and-solar-over-oil/">on staying that way in the future</a>. And that — along with the <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/23648274/climate-change-report-ipcc-ar6-warming-overshoot">relative inaction of other large polluting countries</a> — suggests it will have to reckon with extreme heat, and find ways to avoid unnecessary deaths, in future years.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Li Zhou</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[A contentious New York primary spotlights Democratic fault lines on Israel]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/356515/jamaal-bowman-george-latimer-new-york-primary" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356515</id>
			<updated>2024-06-25T13:04:25Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-25T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Congress" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rep. Jamaal Bowman, a progressive lawmaker who’s been vocal in his calls for a ceasefire in Gaza, is the latest member of the Squad to face an aggressive primary challenge — one that highlights Democrats’ larger divide over the US’s approach to Israel. Bowman, a two-term lawmaker, is known for backing progressive policies, including Medicare-for-All [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="NEW YORK, NEW YORK - JUNE 22: U.S. Rep. Jamaal Bowman (D-NY) greets supporters during a rally at St. Mary&#039;s Park on June 22, 2024 in the Bronx borough of New York City. Supporters gathered three days before New York&#039;s primary elections as incumbent Rep. Bowman (D-NY) attempts to retain his seat in a heated primary race. (Photo by David Dee Delgado/Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158192984.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>NEW YORK, NEW YORK - JUNE 22: U.S. Rep. Jamaal Bowman (D-NY) greets supporters during a rally at St. Mary&#039;s Park on June 22, 2024 in the Bronx borough of New York City. Supporters gathered three days before New York&#039;s primary elections as incumbent Rep. Bowman (D-NY) attempts to retain his seat in a heated primary race. (Photo by David Dee Delgado/Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Rep. Jamaal Bowman, a progressive lawmaker who’s been vocal in his calls for a ceasefire in Gaza, is the latest member of the Squad to face an aggressive primary challenge — one that highlights Democrats’ larger divide over the US’s approach to Israel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman, a two-term lawmaker, is known for backing progressive policies, including Medicare-for-All<em> </em>and the Green New Deal. Since Hamas’s brutal October 7 attacks and Israel’s devastating military offensive in Gaza, he’s also become one of the country’s staunchest critics on Capitol Hill. Bowman <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2024/6/21/whats-behind-the-historic-pro-israel-spending-in-a-new-york-house-primary#:~:text=Bowman%20was%20among%20the%20first,Biden%20to%20stop%20the%20war.">was among the first to urge a ceasefire</a>, has <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/which-house-democrats-republicans-vote-against-israel-gaza-aid-2024-4">voted against military aid to Israel</a>, and has <a href="https://sg.news.yahoo.com/not-just-aipac-jamaal-bowman-175437360.html">described its invasion in Gaza as genocide</a>. In <a href="https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2024/03/26/congress/bowman-house-israel-october-7-sexual-assault-hamas-00148426">one set of controversial remarks,</a> Bowman also questioned whether Hamas had committed sexual assault during its operation inside Israel, a statement he eventually walked back. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These positions have become central to his race, which has underscored Democratic differences on the subject.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman’s stance has made him a top target for pro-Israel advocacy groups like the American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC), lost him the endorsement of left-leaning Jewish organizations like <a href="https://forward.com/fast-forward/577654/j-street-jamaal-bowman-israel-hamas-war/">J Street</a>, and led to some of Bowman’s constituency calling for a primary challenge, for example.&nbsp;It’s also spurred groups including AIPAC to spend a staggering amount to bolster his opponent, making this the most expensive House primary ever.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman’s challenge comes from Westchester County Executive George Latimer, who’s been in state and local politics for decades and framed himself as a moderate alternative. Latimer has seized on their differences on policy toward Israel. Unlike Bowman, <a href="https://www.aol.com/latimers-call-military-pause-gaza-080054134.html">Latimer was much slower to endorse a temporary ceasefire</a>, though both he and Bowman say they <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/jamaal-bowman-primary-latimer-aipac-collective-liberation-1235044908/">support a two-state solution</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are several other factors influencing this race, namely the negative attention that Bowman received for pulling a fire alarm in Congress, and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/01/30/politics/jamaal-bowman-9-11-blog-post/index.html">past blog posts</a> he’s written entertaining conspiracy theories about September 11. (Bowman has expressed regret about the posts and said that he does not believe them.) For his part, Latimer has also been accused of outright racism by Bowman and his allies due to <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/12/new-york-house-primary-charges-racism-00163099">statements he’s made</a> and his approach to <a href="https://jacobin.com/2024/06/george-latimer-bowman-segregation-westchester">desegregation policies in Westchester County</a>. On the whole, however, this race is being closely watched because of the war in Gaza.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If Bowman wins, it might be interpreted by some as an indicator of where the Democratic Party broadly is headed on support for Israel — which is away from it,” says Daniel DiSalvo, a political scientist at City College of New York. “If Latimer wins, it might be interpreted as the other way, which is that there is still stronger support for Israel inside the Democratic Party.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, the race is just one of dozens of primaries taking place this year and shouldn’t be read as an exact analogy of others still expected to play out given key differences specific to each contest. Instead, it’s one data point of many that offers some indication of where the Democratic party stands, and that points to just how fractured it has become on this issue. </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Bowman’s primary, briefly explained</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman — a former middle school principal and the first Black Congressman to represent New York’s 16th district — was first elected in 2020, after mounting a successful progressive primary challenge to then-incumbent Rep. Eliot Engel. Spanning parts of the Bronx, Yonkers, and suburbs of Westchester County, <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/06/12/new-york-house-primary-charges-racism-00163099">the district has a majority Black and Latino voter base</a>, as well as a sizable contingent of Jewish voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While in Congress, he’s become a member of the Squad, a group of progressive lawmakers that includes Reps. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez (D-NY) and Ilhan Omar (D-MN). The group has urged Democrats to pursue more ambitious social policies and has grown in size since 2018. In 2022, Bowman won his House primary by double digits.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This year’s race, according to limited polling, appears more closely contested. In one independent early June poll of likely voters conducted by <a href="https://emersoncollegepolling.com/ny16-poll-george-latimer-leads-jamaal-bowman-48-to-31/">Emerson University</a>, Latimer led Bowman by 17 points. Bowman claims his internal polls are far closer, however, and that the methodology of the Emerson one led to a skewed result. Given the dearth of polling in the race, it is difficult to tell how much or little the Emerson results are likely to mirror the final result.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We’re looking at a contest that, as of now, is essentially a coin flip,” says <a href="https://polisci.columbia.edu/content/jonathan-e-collins">Jonathan Collins</a>, a Columbia political science professor.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The tightly fought race has attracted a lot of outside attention, largely because of how central Israel policy has become, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/06/24/bowman-latimer-primary-israel-race/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/06/24/bowman-latimer-primary-israel-race/">and it’s broken spending records</a>. AIPAC, and its affiliates, which have reportedly vowed to spend $100 million to unseat candidates they view as not supportive enough of the country, have spent upwards of $14 million to back Latimer. In total, outside groups have spent more than $18 million to boost Latimer, and just over $2 million to bolster Bowman — a dynamic that’s led the incumbent to attack the outsize spending in the contest. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This race against AIPAC is a really good litmus test as it relates to that, because [they’re] a big-money lobby [that’s] spending more money in this race than has ever been spent in primary history,” Bowman <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/jamaal-bowman-primary-latimer-aipac-collective-liberation-1235044908/">previously told Rolling Stone</a>. “They’re doing that because they do not want a progressive agenda to move forward.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman’s positions on Israel have grown more progressive over time: In 2021, he previously supported military aid and funding for the Iron Dome, a defense system that the country relies on. Following a trip to the West Bank later that year, however, Bowman <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2024/06/21/jamaal-bowman-israel-trip-reelection-00163788">told Politico</a> his perspective shifted due to the inequality he witnessed. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Latimer, who has previously served as a state representative and state senator — in addition to stressing his ideological contrast with Bowman — has touted local tax cuts and infrastructure investments that he’s overseen in his current role as examples of how he’s delivered for the region.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">His campaign has also been plagued by accusations of racism by Bowman, <a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/182933/george-latimer-jamaal-bowman-ethnic-benefit-race">and others</a>, for comments he’s made. Among them, Latimer said that Bowman has an “ethnic benefit,” and that his constituency is “Dearborn, Michigan,” which has a higher Arab American population than many US cities. Bowman has said that Latimer has leveraged the “angry Black man” trope in his campaign attacks, and diminished those supporting him. <a href="https://jacobin.com/2024/06/george-latimer-bowman-segregation-westchester">The Westchester official</a> has been criticized, too, for implementing desegregation policies too slowly in the region. Latimer has denied accusations of racism.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Democrats are divided on Israel</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Bowman and Latimer primary highlights an enduring Democratic divide as Israel’s offensive in Gaza — and the humanitarian crisis it’s caused — deepens. <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/06/22/middleeast/israel-gaza-central-strikes-dozens-killed-intl/index.html">According to the Gaza Health Ministry</a>, more than 37,000 people have been killed in the region, while over 85,000 have been injured. Palestinians in Gaza are also facing the risks of famine and disease as food, water, and medical supplies all run devastatingly low. And tens of thousands of Gazans have been displaced due to the Israeli military’s airstrikes and lack of safe zones.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">President Joe Biden has long taken a much more supportive position in favor of military aid to Israel, prompting an outcry from progressives — and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/democratic-lawmakers-tell-biden-evidence-shows-israel-is-restricting-gaza-aid-2024-05-03/">a growing number of</a> Democratic lawmakers — who’ve called for more restrictions or accountability regarding how these funds are dispersed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Bowman’s race, which is taking place in a solidly blue district, underscores these differences and could indicate where loyal Democratic voters stand on this issue. Additionally, it could reveal how resilient progressive members who’ve entered Congress by unseating longstanding establishment incumbents, continue to be.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Progressives, including members of the Squad, have been far more aggressive about both pushing for a ceasefire in Gaza and curbing US aid to Israel than most of their colleagues. There are some indications that the Democratic base is in alignment with these progressives: For instance, 83 percent of Democrats <a href="https://www.dataforprogress.org/blog/2024/5/8/support-for-a-permanent-ceasefire-in-gaza-increases-across-party-lines">in a May 2024 Data for Progress poll</a> said they were supportive of a ceasefire, and a Gallup poll also found that most Americans disapprove of Israel’s actions. <a href="https://thehill.com/policy/international/4629597-americans-israel-hamas-gaza-student-protests-poll/">When asked specifically about the conflict,</a> more Americans support Israel over the militant group, however.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The outcome of the Bowman-Latimer face-off could provide another signal regarding where Democrats stand on this issue.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are some suggestions that Democrats in blue districts want leaders who are to the left of Biden on Israel. Earlier this year, Rep. Summer Lee fended off a primary challenge in Pennsylvania’s 12th district after she was attacked for her positions on Israel. Similarly, in California, state Sen. Dave Min, a candidate who has criticized Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, won a primary in Katie Porter’s former district, despite AIPAC efforts to back his opponent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And it could also be a harbinger for races to come. Other progressives are poised to soon see similar challenges, including Rep. Cori Bush, who has seen AIPAC pour money into her race, and Rep. Ilhan Omar, who also faces off against a more centrist challenger later this year.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel isn’t ending the war in Gaza — just turning its attention to Hezbollah]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/356578/israel-gaza-war-hezbollah-netanyahu-biden-ceasefire" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356578</id>
			<updated>2024-06-24T22:02:36Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-24T22:05:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Defense &amp; Security" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Israel" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Palestine" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israel seems like it might be winding down the intensity of its war in Gaza — just as another fight it’s waging is winding up. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu indicated in a television interview on Sunday that he intends to move some of the country’s forces to the northern border to fight the Lebanon-based [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="A woman looks for salvageable items following Israeli bombardment at al-Shati refugee camp in Gaza City on June 22, 2024, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian militant group Hamas. (Photo by Omar AL-QATTAA / AFP) (Photo by OMAR AL-QATTAA/AFP via Getty Images)" data-portal-copyright="AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-2158149997.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A woman looks for salvageable items following Israeli bombardment at al-Shati refugee camp in Gaza City on June 22, 2024, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian militant group Hamas. (Photo by Omar AL-QATTAA / AFP) (Photo by OMAR AL-QATTAA/AFP via Getty Images)</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel seems like it might be winding down the intensity of its war in Gaza — just as another fight it’s waging is winding up.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cpvvvkxpxwno">indicated in a television interview on Sunday</a> that he intends to move some of the country’s forces to the northern border to fight the Lebanon-based military group Hezbollah. Were it not for the war in Gaza, that conflict might have <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/24153755/hezbollah-israel-lebanon">already been capturing the world’s attention</a>. Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Gallant is also visiting Washington this week in part to discuss the implications of that escalation with US officials.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But as part of that same interview and another that followed Monday, Netanyahu, in typical fashion, delivered conflicting statements about his intentions regarding the future of the war in Gaza.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the first interview on Sunday, Netanyahu appeared to rule out a permanent ceasefire in Gaza, which is a requirement of the proposed deal that President Joe Biden laid out last month that would return the remaining Israeli hostages. But the Israeli leader also said that the military would be winding down its activities in Gaza imminently.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The intense phase of the war will come to an end very soon … But that does not mean that the war will be over,” Netanyahu said. “I am willing to make a partial deal, which will bring some of the people back to us. That is no secret. But we’re committed to continuing the war after the truce.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, on Monday, Netanyahu appeared to walk back those remarks somewhat.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We are committed to the Israeli proposal for a hostage deal that President Biden welcomed, our position has not changed. The second thing, which does not contradict the first, we will not end the war until we eliminate Hamas,” he <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/netanyahu-says-committed-truce-proposal-army-cites-advances-rafah-2024-06-24/#:~:text=%22We%20are%20committed%20to%20the,in%20a%20speech%20to%20parliament.">said in a speech to the Israeli parliament</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Holding both positions is impossible, and leaves little clarity as to where Netanyahu stands.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One thing that has become increasingly clear, however, is that Israel’s war is moving into a new phase, dictated largely by increasing tensions along Israel’s northern border with Lebanon.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Will there be a ceasefire in Gaza soon?</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu may publicly say that he favors a ceasefire deal. But Mairav Zonszein, senior Israel analyst at the International Crisis Group, said that the international community should take any of Netanyahu’s remarks with a “grain of salt” and that his actions may be more instructive in terms of deciphering his intentions in Gaza.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We can look at how he&#8217;s approached the situation from the get-go, which is that he&#8217;s not interested in a strategy in this war that has some kind of endgame, that has some kind of exit strategy, that prioritizes the hostages,” she said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu’s actions so far are consistent with the <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/gallant-says-after-hamas-vanquished-israel-will-seek-new-security-regime-in-gaza/">three-phase plan</a> for Gaza he and his advisors laid out at the beginning of the war: First, wiping out Hamas’s military and governing capabilities in Gaza (a goal that many security experts, including in Israel, <a href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/352059/why-israel-cant-destroy-hamas">believe to be impossible</a>); second, “eliminat[ing] pockets of resistance” in Gaza through lower-intensity fighting; and third, “the creation of a new security regime” in Gaza that will remove Israel’s “responsibility for day-to-day life” there.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Israel has not yet achieved even its first objective. In that sense, Netanyahu may have no intention of signing a ceasefire deal anytime soon, even if Israel might scale back its operations in Gaza somewhat. That’s because he relies on a right-wing religious nationalist coalition that wants the war to continue. That coalition is keeping him in power amid widespread calls in Israel for <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/poll-71-think-netanyahu-should-resign-either-immediately-or-right-after-war/">early elections and his resignation after the war</a>, as well as shielding him from an <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/12/04/world/netanyahu-corruption-trial-resumes/index.html">ongoing corruption trial</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But his public statements have at times signaled that he is willing to entertain a permanent ceasefire. That may be an attempt to placate the families of remaining Israeli hostages and the US, Israel’s closest ally whose military and political support it relies on. Hostage families have recently stepped up their pressure on Netanyahu to accept a ceasefire deal that would bring their captive loved ones home. Biden has also thrown his weight behind a ceasefire proposal and wants to see the war end, ideally before the November US elections.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu is “trying to at once signal to Biden and to the world that he’s willing to go for a deal, but still pander to his base and to his own political interests by not agreeing to the deal,” Zonszein said. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this suggests a ceasefire may not be imminent. But for every day that Israel delays a ceasefire, the threat on its northern border with Lebanon grows.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Regional war is looming</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For months, Israel has been trading fire with <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/2023/10/28/23935157/hezbollah-lebanon-israel-hamas-palestine-gaza-iran-militia-group">Hezbollah</a>, an Iranian-backed Islamist militant organization and Lebanese political party.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hezbollah, which is designated as a terrorist organization by many countries, initially launched its campaign saying it was in “solidarity with the victorious Palestinian resistance.” The group has said that it will not let up its attacks on Israel’s northern border until a ceasefire in Gaza is reached. But it is <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/06/23/israel-hamas-war-news-gaza-palestine/">growing impatient</a> with ceasefire negotiations in which Hamas and Israel do not seem to be converging on an agreement, eight months into the war in Gaza. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far, <a href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/24153755/hezbollah-israel-lebanon">as my colleague Joshua Keating laid out</a>, the human casualties and displacement in Israel and Lebanon caused by this northern fight have been significantly lower than the horrific toll in the south. But it “could have been — and may yet be — far worse than it has been, given the military strength on both sides.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Netanyahu did not seem to indicate a ground invasion of Lebanon was imminent. But intense escalation with Hezbollah could be disastrous, as Israel’s previous wars with Hezbollah in 1996 and 2006 would indicate. <a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2023/10/17/beyond-hezbollah-the-history-of-tensions-between-lebanon-and-israel">Both of those conflicts</a> involved heavy civilian casualties in Lebanon, leaving more than 1,200 dead.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It would also be a black mark on the US, which has supported Israel since the beginning of the war and played a leading role in the ceasefire negotiations with the objective of maintaining stability in the Middle East. Throughout the last eight months, US officials like National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/administration/4281908-sullivan-on-israel-hamas-war-escalating-into-regional-conflict-risk-is-real/">have repeatedly emphasized</a> that one of the US’s key goals is “to try to keep this conflict that is currently in Israel and Gaza from spinning out into a regional conflict.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The US should take seriously Israeli declarations and actions — and take actions of its own to restrain Israel’s recklessness,” said Thanassis Cambanis, director of the progressive think tank Century International. “The US government is more and more deeply implicated in Israel’s [alleged] war crimes, and in what has proven to be a humanitarian disaster and in addition an epic strategic blunder.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Now, both Israel and Hezbollah are preparing for the possibility that the so-far contained hostilities on the border could escalate into a full-out war, one that could engulf the entire Middle East. Recently, Hezbollah released <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2024/06/19/israel-hezbollah-drones-iron-dome/">drone footage</a> of an Israeli military base, suggesting that there are gaps in the country’s air defense system that the group could exploit. Israel, meanwhile, is planning to move troops currently deployed in Gaza to its northern border.  </p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Allie Volpe</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What to do (and avoid) in extreme heat]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23800261/tips-extreme-heat-heatwave" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/even-better/23800261/tips-extreme-heat-heatwave</id>
			<updated>2024-06-24T20:09:14Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-24T20:00:02Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Earth has never been so hot. The year 2023 was the globe’s warmest year on record. Millions of people in the mid-Atlantic, Midwest, and South are currently under heat alerts. It’s not just the US: More than 1,300 people died in Saudi Arabia during this year’s Hajj pilgrimage. Over 1,000 temperature records were broken worldwide in June. Extreme heat is [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman in a bathing suit lies in a kiddie pool in the shade. A hose is looped on the green grass beside the pool." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images/fStop" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/uploads/chorus_asset/file/24796958/GettyImages_1158241872.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The Earth has never been so hot. The year 2023 was the <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news/2023-was-worlds-warmest-year-on-record-by-far" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">globe’s warmest year on record</a>. Millions of people in the mid-Atlantic, Midwest, and South are <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/06/22/g-s1-5772/heat-wave-storms-midwest-east-coast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">currently under heat alerts</a>. It’s not just the US: <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hajj-heat-deaths-mecca-saudi-arabia-pilgrimage-9f97aae1032b14ada29bbea7108195d3" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">More than 1,300 people died in Saudi Arabia</a> during this year’s Hajj pilgrimage. <a href="https://www.semafor.com/article/06/23/2024/world-breaks-1400-temperature-records-heat-waves-sweep-globe" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Over 1,000 temperature records were broken</a> worldwide in June.</p>

<p>Extreme heat is extremely dangerous, and can <a href="https://www.vox.com/22560815/heat-wave-worker-extreme-climate-change-osha-workplace-farm-restaurant">even be deadly</a>. Heat is the <a href="https://www.epa.gov/climate-indicators/climate-change-indicators-heat-related-deaths">leading weather-related cause of death</a> in the United States. Prolonged exposure to hot temperatures can result in <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/disasters/extremeheat/warning.html">heat exhaustion, heat stroke, heat cramps, sunburn, and heat rash</a>. Infants and young children, adults over the age of 65, people who are overweight, and people who are on certain medications — like <a href="https://www.jeffersonhealth.org/your-health/living-well/is-your-medication-putting-you-at-increased-risk-for-heat-stroke">amphetamines and antidepressants</a> — are <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/disasters/extremeheat/faq.html">most at risk</a> for heat-related illness. <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/16425-heat-illness">People who work outside</a> and are exposed to the sun and heat also are at greater risk.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfiStGSlsWDBmglim7Dh1Y9Hy386rkeKGpfwF6BCjmgnZdqfQ/viewform"><strong>Do you have a question or idea for Even Better?</strong></a></h2>



<p>Submit it by filling out this&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/k4KXm1PcNQiP92LN7">form</a>.</p>
</div>

<p>Children <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18347699/">produce more body heat and sweat less than adults</a>, and tend to not stay as hydrated, making them more sensitive to the heat. “Their skin is also vulnerable,” says <a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/profiles/details/joanna-cohen-1">Joanna Cohen</a>, a pediatric emergency medicine physician at Johns Hopkins Children’s Center. “They can get sunburned more easily and sunburns actually increase your body temperature and can contribute to overheating and dehydration as well.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Like children, older adults don’t have as rapid or efficient a thermoregulatory response as other adults, explains <a href="https://www.emergencymedicine.columbia.edu/profile/raleigh-w-todman-md">Raleigh Todman</a>, an emergency medicine physician at Columbia University Medical Center. The body doesn’t cool down as quickly as the rest of the population, she says.</p>

<p>However, everyone should take precautions to stay cool and hydrated during extreme heat. When humidity exceeds 75 percent, the body’s ability to cool off by sweating is not as effective, Todman says, making heat safety all the more important. Here’s what to keep in mind.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Keep your home and your body as cool as possible</h2>

<p>One of the most effective ways to fend off heat-related illness is to <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/features/extremeheat/index.html">stay in an air-conditioned building</a> (even though air conditioning is a <a href="https://www.vox.com/22638093/air-conditioning-worsens-climate-change-ac">contributor to climate change</a>). According to the <a href="https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=52558">2020 Residential Energy Consumption Survey</a>, 88 percent of US households use air conditioning. The survey also found that half of households in the Northeast use individual AC units, like window and wall units, mini-splits, and portable units.&nbsp;</p>

<p>You can lower the temperature in your home by <a href="https://www.realsimple.com/home-organizing/how-to-cool-down-a-room-without-ac">closing your shades</a> to prevent the sunlight from heating up the house and <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/features/extremeheat/index.html">avoiding the use of your stove and oven</a>. Electric fans may feel nice, but will <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/disasters/extremeheat/faq.html">not prevent heat-related illness</a>. If you have individual air-conditioning units, try to contain the cold air to one area by keeping the doors closed to one room.</p>

<p>Other <a href="https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/326235#causes-of-feeling-hot">at-home ways of cooling down</a> include avoiding exercise or strenuous activities, taking a cool bath or shower, placing wet cloths or ice on your wrists, neck, and temples, and wearing light-colored, loose-fitting fabrics like cotton and linen — and dressing your children in loose, light clothes as well.</p>

<p>If your home does not have air conditioning or if you still feel hot, find a cooling center — an air-conditioned indoor location where the public can stay safe from the heat — in your area by calling 211 and asking for information about local cooling centers. Some states have <a href="https://nchh.org/information-and-evidence/learn-about-healthy-housing/emergencies/extreme-heat/cooling-centers-by-state/">lists of cooling centers online</a>. Museums, libraries, movie theaters, cafes, malls, and stores can offer respites from the heat as well. Parents should remember to never leave children and pets unattended in the car. Cohen suggests placing your purse or phone next to your child or pet in the backseat as a double reminder to take them all with you.</p>

<p>Children may want to take advantage of sunny days outdoors with trips to the park, beach, or pool. Outdoor activities can be safe for children so long as there’s shade and water available, Cohen says, like a pool, beach, or backyard or park with sprinklers. “If they’re going to be doing exercise, like playing soccer outside, they should take frequent breaks and go into the shade,” Cohen says. “If they do start to get overheated, get inside in air conditioning, if you can.”&nbsp;</p>

<p>Everyone, regardless of age, should take <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/16425-heat-illness">plenty of rest breaks in the shade</a> and <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23699060/sunscreen-questions-answered-spf-uv-rays-supergoop-la-roche-posay">wear sunscreen</a> and a hat if you’re spending time outdoors, though Todman suggests avoiding going outside between noon and 4 pm. “If you need to do something and you have your elderly parents and your baby and you need to go get groceries,” Todman says, “if you can possibly do it in the morning before noon, or in the afternoon after 4, that’s your best bet for avoiding the most direct sun and the hottest part of the day.”</p>

<p>Aside from avoiding the heat in a cool location, staying hydrated is another crucial aspect of hot weather safety because it helps <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/food-nutrition/why-is-water-important#body-temperature">regulate your body temperature</a>. On hot days, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/disasters/extremeheat/faq.html">you need to increase your water intake</a>, even if you don’t feel thirsty or aren’t physically exerting yourself. <a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/16425-heat-illness">Avoid alcoholic or caffeinated beverages</a>, which can contribute to dehydration. Try to consistently sip water all day and encourage kids to always have a water bottle with them, Cohen says. If your kids are resistant to drinking water, Todman suggests giving them sports drinks or drinks with electrolytes, like Pedialyte, coconut water, and Gatorade, and even milk, which will help replenish the electrolytes lost in sweat. You’ll know if you’re properly hydrated if you <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/07/01/how-to-properly-hydrate-in-hot-weather-experts.html">use the bathroom every two to three hours and your urine is light yellow</a>; if it’s dark yellow or gold, drink more water. One way to determine if children are dehydrated is by gently pinching their skin. If they’re hydrated, the skin should bounce back, Todman says, if they’re dehydrated, the skin will stay pinched.</p>

<p>Ideally, everyone should drink 32 ounces of water a day, Todman says, although “I know it’s not easy to convince elderly people or small children to drink that much water.” People who work outside should drink one cup of water <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/mining/userfiles/works/pdfs/2017-126.pdf">every 15 to 20 minutes </a>(and <a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/23699060/sunscreen-questions-answered-spf-uv-rays-supergoop-la-roche-posay">ensure you’re wearing sunscreen</a>). Cold treats and foods with a high water content, like ice cream and watermelon, can keep you hydrated and cool, Todman says.</p>

<p>Treat your pets the same way you would a baby, Todman says: Don’t leave them outdoors, keep them in the air conditioning, and always keep their water bowl filled.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recognize the signs of heat exhaustion and heat stroke</h2>

<p>If you, a family member, or a neighbor start to exhibit signs of heat exhaustion or heat stroke, it’s important to r<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/disasters/extremeheat/warning.html">ecognize the symptoms and react swiftly</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p>According to the CDC, symptoms of heat exhaustion include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Heavy sweating</li>



<li>Cold, pale, clammy skin</li>



<li>Fast, weak pulse</li>



<li>Nausea or vomiting</li>



<li>Muscle cramps</li>



<li>Tiredness or weakness</li>



<li>Dizziness</li>



<li>Headache&nbsp;</li>



<li>Fainting</li>
</ul>

<p>Here’s what to do if you or someone else is experiencing heat exhaustion:</p>

<ul>
<li>Move to a cool place</li>



<li>Loosen clothes</li>



<li>Put cool, wet cloths on your body or take a cool bath</li>



<li>Get medical help if you or someone else is vomiting, or the symptoms get worse or persist for more than an hour</li>
</ul>

<p>According to the CDC, symptoms of heat stroke include:</p>

<ul>
<li>Body temperature of 103 degrees Fahrenheit or higher</li>



<li>Hot, red, dry, or damp skin</li>



<li>Fast, strong pulse</li>



<li>Headache</li>



<li>Dizziness</li>



<li>Nausea</li>



<li>Confusion</li>



<li>Fainting</li>
</ul>

<p>Here’s what to do if you or someone else is experiencing heat stroke:</p>

<ul>
<li>Call 911</li>



<li>Move the person to a cooler place</li>



<li>Put cool, wet cloths on their body or place them in a cool bath</li>



<li>Do not give the person anything to drink&nbsp;</li>
</ul>

<p>The signs of heat exhaustion and heat stroke are the same for both adults and children, Cohen says, but a baby or younger kid may not be able to vocalize how they’re feeling. Ensure children are consistently drinking, urinating frequently, and that they look alert.</p>

<p>Best practices for dealing with extreme heat are to stay hydrated, avoid strenuous or prolonged activities outdoors, keep your environment as cool as possible, and ensure members of the community are doing the same. Keep in touch with elderly neighbors or folks with young children or pets who may not have access to an air-conditioned location.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This sort of neighborly mindfulness,” Todman says, “is something, if possible, to keep in mind.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, June 24, 4 pm ET: </strong>This story was originally published in June 2023 and has been updated with information about 2024&#8217;s spate of extreme heat.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What two years without Roe looks like, in 8 charts]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/explainers/356314/abortion-laws-roe-wade-dobbs-decision-mifepristone-supreme-court" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356314</id>
			<updated>2024-06-21T22:20:54Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-24T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Congress" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Joe Biden" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Parenting" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="US Federal Courts" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For 49 years after Roe v. Wade, Americans had the right to obtain an abortion if they became pregnant. Then, two years ago, with Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, the Supreme Court put an end to it. The Biden administration and some blue states — supported by a network of nonprofits focused on reproductive [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="illustration showing the united states shape and roe v wade text in the background" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Joan Wong, Paige Vickers/Vox; Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/FactsOnTheGround_Final_01.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">For 49 years after <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, Americans had the right to obtain an abortion if they became pregnant. Then, two years ago, with <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/24/23181720/supreme-court-dobbs-jackson-womens-health-samuel-alito-roe-wade-abortion-marriage-contraception"><em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em></a>, the Supreme Court put an end to it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration and some blue states — supported by a network of nonprofits focused on reproductive care — aggressively sought to compensate, while many red states enacted near-total bans on abortion.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But <em>Dobbs</em> has nevertheless had a devastating effect on pregnant people in huge swaths of the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the number of abortions across the country <a href="https://www.vox.com/2024/3/20/24106109/dobbs-roe-abortion-reproductive-rights">actually increased last year</a> — thanks in large part to increasingly cheap and accessible medication abortion — that has not changed the fundamental realities of post-<em>Dobbs </em>America. Large reproductive care deserts have emerged in which there are no abortion providers for hundreds of miles. Pregnant people are being denied necessary medical care as their doctors fear the legal repercussions of providing it. All of this has exacerbated long-standing inequities.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Both <a href="https://19thnews.org/2024/04/women-abortion-access-beliefs-legality/">abortion bans</a> and attacks on <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/646025/americans-back-ivf-divide-morality-destroying-embryos.aspx">reproductive</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/02/26/us/politics/republicans-birth-control-ivf.html">rights</a> are broadly unpopular, and elections in the years since <em>Dobbs</em> showed that abortion rights were a potent motivating issue for voters. But in this year’s matchup between President Joe Biden and former President Donald Trump — both of whom have been reluctant messengers of their party’s stance on abortion — there’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24101209/abortion-reproductive-freedom-biden-2024-election">a question</a> as to whether the issue will continue to motivate American voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is not too late for their votes to make a difference for reproductive access. It may seem like the worst has already come to pass for the abortion rights movement: though once protected by the constitution nationally, access now increasingly depends on where you live or whether you can afford to travel for the care you need. But Republicans have also made clear that they have no intention of stopping there.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How the legal landscape has changed</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of <em>Dobbs</em>, 13 states immediately implemented <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/article/2022/06/13-states-have-abortion-trigger-bans-heres-what-happens-when-roe-overturned">“trigger” bans</a> on abortion, while others sought to enforce abortion restrictions that were on the books before <em>Roe v. Wade</em> was even decided in 1973 or quickly moved to pass new bans on abortion. A new patchwork of abortion laws was established in the US within months. A total of 14 states have <a href="https://www.guttmacher.org/2023/12/state-policy-trends-2023-first-full-year-roe-fell-tumultuous-year-abortion-and-other">enacted near-total bans on abortion</a>.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/0c5Kg-the-state-of-us-abortion-laws-in-2024-1.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,25.919337548744,100,48.161324902512" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of these bans involved narrow medical exceptions in which abortions could be performed when the health or life of the mother was at risk. But those exceptions have proved exceptionally difficult — in some states, nigh impossible — to qualify for.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kate Cox, a Texas woman, was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/03/06/politics/kate-cox-texas-abortion/index.html">notably denied</a> an abortion even though her fetus was diagnosed with a rare and terminal genetic condition and forced to travel out of state to obtain one. Other women have been <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/05/02/health/florida-abortion-term-pregnancy/index.html">forced to carry to term</a> fetuses doctors know will die shortly upon birth, or been <a href="https://link.vox.com/click/35616768.71438/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZGFsbGFzbmV3cy5jb20vbmV3cy9wdWJsaWMtaGVhbHRoLzIwMjQvMDYvMDQvaG93LWEtY291cGxlLWZvdW5kLXRoZW1zZWx2ZXMtdGFuZ2xlZC1pbi10ZXhhcy1zdHJpY3QtYWJvcnRpb24tbGF3cy1hZnRlci1taXNjYXJyaWFnZS8_dWVpZD03MmRmM2EwM2IzMzFmNDQyZDllZjQ2M2VhMGVhYzE2OQ/60917b99ac7e007ef63c6b67Bd5b18d70">denied abortion care even after experiencing a miscarriage</a> that leaves them in medical distress. The Texas Supreme Court also ruled against a group of 20 women who claimed that they had been <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/2024/05/31/texas-supreme-court-zurawski-abortion/#:~:text=The%20court%20ruled%20against%2020,the%20law%20were%20broad%20enough.">denied medically necessary abortions</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans aren’t stopping now that they have overturned <em>Roe</em>. They have continued to advocate for a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/05/10/speaker-mike-johnson-national-abortion-ban/">national abortion ban</a>, even though Trump has indicated that he would not sign it, and opened up new attacks on <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/supreme-court/thomas-wants-supreme-court-overturn-landmark-rulings-legalized-contrac-rcna35228">contraception</a> and <a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/senate/4720506-senate-republicans-block-ivf-legislation/">in vitro fertilization</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If Trump wins the election, he could also order the FDA to rescind its approval of the abortion drug mifepristone after the Supreme Court <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/355175/supreme-court-mifepristone-abortion-alliiance-hippocratic-medicine-fda">left open that possibility</a> in a recent ruling upholding access to the drug for now.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In short: The dust has still yet to settle post-<em>Dobbs</em>, but it’s clear that abortion was only Republicans’ first target in a larger war on reproductive freedom.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What that has meant for people seeking abortions</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite the new restrictions on abortion in many parts of the country, the number of abortions performed nationally has actually gone up slightly since <em>Dobbs</em>. But it would be a mistake to see that statistic and say that everyone has improved access to abortion equally across the US.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“While the numbers have gone up a bit nationally, in some states, there are virtually no abortions happening,” at least in a formal health care setting, said Usha Ranji, associate director for women’s health policy at KFF, a health policy research and news organization.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/BvZAB-abortions-have-increased-nationally-post-i-roe-i-.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=8.1032258064516,0,83.793548387097,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">The use of medication abortion, which can end a pregnancy during the first trimester, has <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/12/27/24015092/abortion-pills-mifepristone-roe-reproductive-misoprostol">gone up in particular</a>. Though it was already the most common method of obtaining an abortion pre-<em>Dobbs</em>, it is now cheaper and easier to obtain quickly, especially via telemedicine. That’s because, amid the pandemic, the FDA suspended the requirement that mifepristone be dispensed in person, resulting in an explosion of telemedicine abortion services.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">However, <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/medication-abortion-telemedicine-innovations-and-barriers-during-the-covid-19-emergency/#:~:text=These%20new%20restrictions%20are%20in,physically%20present%20with%20the%20patient.">19 states</a> have banned telemedicine abortion: Five do so explicitly, and the other 14 require that a prescribing clinician be physically present with the patient. Some states also require counseling or an ultrasound prior to administering an abortion, which can rule out obtaining medication abortion via telemedicine.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That has caused some patients to turn to community networks or websites that sell abortion pills without interacting with a clinician or pharmacy.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/EjPtQ-most-us-abortions-are-now-medication-abortions.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,19.026018144758,100,61.947963710483" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this is a reflection of the monumental effort in states without bans to scale up care, as well as the <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/01/23/abortion-fund-warning-demand-up-donations-down/">flood of donations</a> to abortion funds post-<em>Dobbs</em>. New Mexico, for instance, <a href="https://www.axios.com/local/houston/2023/03/23/abortion-clinic-new-mexico">dedicated $10 million</a> to building a new abortion clinic that opened last year on its border with Texas, which has banned abortion with limited exceptions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the question is whether this patchwork solution is sustainable in the long run, especially given that those funds are <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2024/01/23/abortion-fund-warning-demand-up-donations-down/">drying up</a>. And it doesn’t entirely mitigate the impact of abortion bans, which have created maternal care deserts across large tracts of the southern US and Midwest.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There are still people who are not getting abortions that they would want in part because not everybody can travel,” Ranji said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/ezgif.com-optimize.gif?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,22.208276554543,100,55.583446890913" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Nicole Narea/Vox" data-portal-copyright="Nicole Narea/Vox" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Travel might be difficult for both logistical and financial reasons. And poor women are disproportionately affected: Those women (defined as those who live under 200 percent of the poverty line, which was $46,060 for a family of three in 2022) are <a href="https://www.kff.org/womens-health-policy/issue-brief/what-are-the-implications-of-the-dobbs-ruling-for-racial-disparities/">concentrated</a> in the 14 states that have banned abortion and the 11 states that have passed strict gestational limits on abortion. Though they may be candidates for medication abortion, they are less likely to know about it as an option — a messaging challenge that abortion <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/2023/12/27/24015092/abortion-pills-mifepristone-roe-reproductive-misoprostol">activists are struggling to overcome</a>. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/9SC3x-abortion-bans-disproportionately-hit-poor-women_4e16e8.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,19.662866369819,100,60.674267260361" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><br>There is also growing evidence that the <em>Dobbs</em> decision has had an adverse effect on maternal health outcomes, including maternal mortality. However, only two years have passed since <em>Dobbs</em> and the number of annual maternal deaths is too small (even if maternal mortality is <a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/publications/issue-briefs/2024/jun/insights-us-maternal-mortality-crisis-international-comparison">higher in the US</a> than in any other high-income nation) to determine any trends that have emerged just yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So for now, the best information is based on statistical modeling. Researchers at the University of Colorado Boulder <a href="https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/7g29k">projected</a> based on 2020 data on maternal outcomes that, if no abortions were performed nationally, there would be an overall 24 percent increase in maternal deaths after a year.&nbsp;Black mothers would see the biggest increase in mortality.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These communities that have historically been harmed will continue to bear the brunt of this abortion care crisis that we’re in,” said Candace Gibson, state policy director at Guttmacher, a nonprofit that researches abortion policy.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/nxmMJ-abortion-bans-are-likely-to-hurt-maternal-health-nbsp-.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,21.575540293964,100,56.848919412072" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Anecdotally, physicians have also reported concerns about their ability to provide adequate reproductive care since the <em>Dobbs</em> decision came down. A <a href="https://www.kff.org/womens-health-policy/report/a-national-survey-of-obgyns-experiences-after-dobbs/">KFF national survey</a> of OBGYNs found that significant shares of respondents were concerned about their ability to administer a level of care consistent with the medical profession’s standards, their potential legal liability in states where abortion is banned, and health outcomes for their patients. In states where abortion is banned or restricted, for example, six in 10 OBGYNs say their decision-making autonomy has become worse since the <em>Dobbs</em> ruling.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“They’re in this place where they have to really contemplate whether they continue to provide care within that state, or whether they leave the state so that they can actually practice medicine in a way that complies with the standards of care,” Gibson said.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/OCvma-what-doctors-say-about-the-end-of-i-roe-i-.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,13.69045527484,100,72.61908945032" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">What that has meant for American politics</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Republicans’ opposition to abortion rights has proved a thorn in their side electorally ever since <em>Dobbs</em> came down.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, Democrats running on abortion rights <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23444732/2022-midterm-elections-results-abortion-rights-nebraska-north-carolina">nearly swept the table</a>. Every ballot initiative aimed at restricting abortion <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23451074/abortion-ballot-measure-midterms-kentucky-montana-michigan">lost</a>, including those in <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Kansas_No_State_Constitutional_Right_to_Abortion_and_Legislative_Power_to_Regulate_Abortion_Amendment_(August_2022)">Kansas</a>, <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Kentucky_No_Right_to_Abortion_in_Constitution_Amendment_(2022)">Kentucky</a>, and <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Montana_LR-131,_Medical_Care_Requirements_for_Born-Alive_Infants_Measure_(2022)">Montana</a>. Meanwhile, ballot initiatives strengthening abortion rights prevailed in states including <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2022/11/09/michigan-abortion-amendment-results-2022-00064778">Michigan</a>, <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Vermont_Proposal_5,_Right_to_Personal_Reproductive_Autonomy_Amendment_(2022)">Vermont</a>, and <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/California_Proposition_1,_Right_to_Reproductive_Freedom_Amendment_(2022)">California</a> and even outperformed Democratic candidates in some cases.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2023, <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Ohio_Issue_1,_Right_to_Make_Reproductive_Decisions_Including_Abortion_Initiative_(2023)">Ohio</a> also passed a ballot measure enshrining abortion rights in its state constitution. And Democrats were able to flip the Virginia House of Delegates and maintain control of the state senate after Republican Gov. Glen Youngkin <a href="https://19thnews.org/2023/11/virginia-voters-reject-republican-campaign-abortion-ban/">committed to a 15-week abortion ban</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Abortion has proved a key motivating issue in these off-cycle years. The question is whether it can continue to be the same force in a presidential election year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That may be the case in a handful of states, especially when it comes to the <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Colorado_Right_to_Abortion_and_Health_Insurance_Coverage_Initiative_(2024)">four</a> <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Maryland_Right_to_Reproductive_Freedom_Amendment_(2024)">upcoming</a> <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/South_Dakota_Constitutional_Amendment_G,_Right_to_Abortion_Initiative_(2024)">ballot</a> <a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Florida_Amendment_4,_Right_to_Abortion_Initiative_(2024)">measures</a> aimed at expanding abortion rights. In Florida, a six-week abortion ban that recently went into effect could be overridden by a ballot measure seeking to protect abortion until fetal viability, which is estimated around 24 weeks of pregnancy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But at the top of the ticket, the potential impact of abortion is less clear at a moment when other issues, including the economy and immigration, are dominating the national conversation. Critically, <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/24101209/abortion-reproductive-freedom-biden-2024-election">low-propensity voters</a> — those who Biden is struggling with and who could decide this election either because they stay home or lean toward Trump —&nbsp;don’t rank abortion rights among the top issues they care about, even though they are broadly pro-abortion rights.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/e19GC-abortion-can-t-compete-with-other-top-issues-on-voters-minds-in-2024-1.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,19.606055258152,100,60.787889483695" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">But turnout in this election is projected to be lower than in 2020 due to voter apathy over a rematch between Biden and Trump. Some <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/biden-needs-disengaged-unhappy-voters-to-stay-home.html">commentators argue</a> that low turnout <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/06/15/upshot/election-democrats-republicans-turnout-trump.html">might actually help Democrats</a>, in a turnabout for recent American politics. But abortion could help boost turnout in a way that helps Biden, said Tom Bonier, a Democratic political strategist and the senior adviser to TargetSmart, a data and polling firm.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But first, he has to overcome a clear messaging problem: 17 percent of voters overall and 12 percent of Democrats blame President Biden for the end of <em>Roe</em>, according to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/05/15/upshot/abortion-biden-trump-blame.html">New York Times/Siena College polls and a Times/Philadelphia Inquirer/Siena poll</a> in battleground states. Some less-engaged voters inaccurately associate the overturn with Biden because he was president when the conservative-controlled Supreme Court issued the decision.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it also shows that Biden — who as a Catholic has been at times an uncomfortable messenger of his party’s pro-abortion rights stance — has room to persuade voters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“One of the jobs in front of Democratic campaigns, including the president’s campaign, is [to] spend time communicating with these voters and make sure that they understand the reality,” Bonier said. “I don’t think that most voters are aware of what Republicans are doing, unless they’re in the states where it’s happening. But I do think those issues will have a substantial impact on the election as that is communicated to more voters.”</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Christian Paz</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What the rise of queer Republicans tells us about America]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/politics/356033/gay-republican-lgbtq-pride-month-history-voter-election-2024" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=356033</id>
			<updated>2024-06-21T16:53:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-06-24T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="LGBTQ" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Pride Month, the rainbow flags come out, parades march on, and, if it’s an election year, Democratic candidates make their appeal to a growing part of the electorate: LGBTQ voters. But it’s easy to forget how modern of a development this is. That LGBTQ voters and the Democratic Party would become so closely intertwined [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="GRAND JUNCTION, CO - OCTOBER 18: Supporters hold up a gay pride flag for Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on October 18, 2016 in Grand Junction Colorado. Trump is on his way to Las Vegas for the third and final presidential debate against Democratic rival Hillary Clinton. (Photo by George Frey/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/06/gettyimages-615526928.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>GRAND JUNCTION, CO - OCTOBER 18: Supporters hold up a gay pride flag for Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump on October 18, 2016 in Grand Junction Colorado. Trump is on his way to Las Vegas for the third and final presidential debate against Democratic rival Hillary Clinton. (Photo by George Frey/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Every Pride Month, the rainbow flags come out, parades march on, and, if it’s an election year, Democratic candidates make their appeal to a growing part of the electorate: LGBTQ voters.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But it’s easy to forget how modern of a development this is. That LGBTQ voters and the Democratic Party would become so closely intertwined was never a given — and as far back as the 1950s, when LGBTQ Americans were first beginning to organize, it wasn’t at all clear which political party was a natural home.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, starting in the 1940s and into the 1960s, politicians of both parties enabled and empowered the so-called Lavender Scare — part of a wave of anti-Communist sentiment to drive out LGBTQ people from working in the federal government.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, the Reagan era saw the creation of the religious right and union of social conservatives with the GOP. But then it was a Democratic president who enacted the “Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell” policy to prohibit LGBTQ servicemembers from being out in the military in the 1990s — Bill Clinton. It was also Clinton who signed the Defense of Marriage Act, which defined marriage in heterosexual terms and banned federal recognition of same-sex marriages. It would remain the law of the land until the Supreme Court recognized the right to marriage for same-sex couples in 2015.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Political realities have changed rapidly since. The Republican Party has generally oscillated between outright aggression and disgruntled passivity toward the LGBTQ community. But the Democratic Party has moved rapidly in the last two decades from mere tolerance to active advocacy and inclusion.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the more distant past provides important context: It explains why gay and queer people exist in both parties and across the political spectrum today, how conservative and Republican LGBT people played influential roles both in efforts to gain protections and in shaping the modern Republican Party, and why this subset of the LGBTQ community is often overlooked.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And this part of the electorate won’t be going anywhere, Neil J. Young, a writer and historian who recently assembled a definitive history of the gay right, told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“If anything, the proliferation of more people who identify as LGBTQ will mean a growth of people who identify as gay Republicans, because there will probably be a lot more people who are comfortable to be out and to be recognized as gay Republicans in a way that they weren&#8217;t in the past,” Young, the author of <a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/C/bo212887554.html"><em>Coming Out Republican: A History of the Gay Right</em></a><em>,</em> told me.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So while the mainstream picture of LGBTQ Americans is one of progressive and liberal activism, the overlooked history of conservative and right-wing queer organizing provides additional color of the past and clues for what a future America might look like: As LGBTQ Americans grow in numbers and change the nation, the country — and our politics — may be changing the community too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Our conversation has been edited for length and clarity:</em></p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz </h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As you write, LGBTQ conservatives and Republicans have always existed. But is there a common misconception that came up while working on this book, or that you have heard since?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The biggest misconception is that there aren’t that many of them. The overwhelming idea is that all LGBTQ people are Democrats, or have politics that align them with the left. Both contemporary data shows us — and also this history I’ve delved into — this is a much bigger phenomenon than even I anticipated, and certainly [than] the average person, and even the media, talks about.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s one thing to talk about how many LGBTQ people vote for a Republican candidate in any election — and again, those numbers are higher than most people think — but it’s another to think about how conservatism and right-of-center politics incorporates a much larger swath of LGBTQ people than people appreciate.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You focus your book on specific activists and players within Republican politics going back to the 1950s, and they serve as stand-ins for their greater community. Is there a throughline that ties them all together? What does gay or queer conservative ideology look like compared to how straight conservatives or Republicans think?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Ideologically, there are a couple of things that really connect most of these actors across time and at any given moment. Typically there’s what they would describe as some sort of politics of fiscal conservatism: that means lower taxes, less government regulation, constrained federal power to regulate business.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s also generally been an emphasis on the military and national security politics — that’s manifested in different ways in different historical eras.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the last thing is a politics and discourse of individual rights. That varies a lot over time, because political language can shift across decades, but this is a sense of individualism that is part of a broader conservative politics [and] it’s a consistent characteristic of the LGBTQ Right.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Beyond ideology, the big consistency is that this is mostly a story of white gay men, especially at the activist level that my book is focusing on.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Connected to that, I find it really interesting how LGBTQ identity is both a discrete part of individual identity and also interconnected with education, class, gender, and race. I’m wondering —&nbsp;for these gay white men, does LGBTQ identity not play a central factor in how they think of themselves or their politics? Do they prioritize class, for example, in their concern for fiscal conservatism? Does that make them different from how a progressive or left-leaning LGBTQ person might be able to think of themselves?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This has been a long-running debate within the people and groups I was looking at, especially like the Log Cabin Republicans [the major right-wing national LGBTQ advocacy group]. I even have a chapter that’s titled after an essay in one of the Log Cabin Republicans’ magazines, which was something like “Are You a Gay Republican or a Republican Gay?” It was never resolved. In some ways that debate was about identity: “Am I a gay Republican?” meaning, “I am someone for whom that is a coherent identity, and that’s the identity I am seeking for the party to accept and acknowledge.” And also, does that mean that my work here is to not only increase our visibility, but also advocate for gay rights within the GOP?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Or “Am I a Republican gay?” meaning, as they would often say, a Republican who happens to be gay. Those folks are really aligned with what you ask — they really don’t have any sort of patience or interest in identity politics, and, actually, they think of themselves as conservatives, as “I don’t engage in identity politics at all.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But all of this, I think, is predicated on almost all of these folks being white, gay men, and so their whiteness and maleness are obviously powerful markers of identity that allow them to operate within the Republican Party in a lot of ways.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And also those are things that by the nature of how American society is set up that they get to sort of negate that they are engaged with or benefitting from any sort of identity politics.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So they get to say something like “I’m an American first.”</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah for a lot of these folks, they didn’t believe this part of their identity was something that needed to be a big deal. That wasn’t their primary identity in the world. They would say, “I’m an American first. I’m a conservative first. I’m a Christian who just happens to be gay.” And that’s ongoing.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Does that change as coming out becomes more acceptable in society? There’s some academic research to suggest that coming out, be it a political act in and of itself or not, can be key to radicalizing or reforming someone’s political ideology.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It really matters what time period we’re talking about. My opening chapters are about closeted gay men who were important in the <a href="https://guides.loc.gov/lgbtq-studies/before-stonewall">homophile movement</a> [the earliest activism demanding equality regardless of sexual orientation] or the conservative movement. Then you have folks in the 1970s who come out and essentially found the first chapters of what becomes the Log Cabin Republicans. … Their work is tied to their politics, but it’s tied to the sense that they are already the best representatives of the Republican Party’s libertarian traditions of “leave us alone, stay out of our bedroom, stay out of our wallets, don’t police us.” <em>That</em> coming out is an extension of their politics, as opposed to a moment that politicizes them. It’s a moment which makes them more politically active. Those are two different things.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But in the ’90s and after, you have guys who are coming out in a completely different context, one of increasing public acceptance of homosexuality and support for a broad array of gay rights. Those attitudes start to shift within the Republican Party. So in more recent decades, their coming out is almost unpolitical for them. Society has shifted so much, and for these folks, it’s more of a nonpolitical act, and it’s an act that they think should have little political bearing.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That dynamic actually reminds me of a broader electoral question: I’m wondering if as society changes, as issue priorities change for LGBTQ people, as the coming out experience becomes less tense, does that lead to an LGBTQ community that centers that part of their identity less? And if so, am I just describing gay Republicans?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Absolutely, and that manifests itself in a few ways. Historically these folks would be more in line with what some of the LGBTQ polls for 2024 show: that these folks have always ranked other things as their political priorities. It was almost always the economy first, national security and military issues were preeminent, and lower down was any sort of gay rights. And even their notions of gay rights were very constrained compared to what activists on the left in any given moment were envisioning. If they believed in gay rights at all.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Tell me more about that. A cleavage over gay rights, among the Gay Right?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was an ongoing conversation: For the folks who said yes, it typically meant, <em>we just want the government to get rid of discriminatory language or regulations</em>. They were for anti-discrimination that made sexuality a protected category. There was a big debate over gay marriage, and whether to support that. They generally came around to that. But these were always low-ranking priorities to other things. That is in keeping with them being a primarily white, professional, entrepreneurial, male group.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And you’re seeing a lot of this happening on the right today. There is a real separation of LGBTQ identity. Log Cabin Republicans continues to call itself an LGBT Republican organization, but they don’t use the “Q,” and there’s been a lot of internal fighting about whether to get rid of the “T,” and just be LGB.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When [LGBT Republicans] talk about themselves individually, when I interviewed them, they had to correct me, they would say, “I’m gay. I’m not LGBTQ. I’m not queer.” They would say “we’re gay, we’re lesbian, we’re bisexual.” They really argue that LGBTQ has become a political identity rather than a sexual identity.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You say some of those cleavages are old, but it feels like a lot of this is amplified or worsened by social media and our modern right-wing politics. Is that fair?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re seeing it ramp up, and depending on where you look, yes, it is more inflamed, especially on social media. You can go down an ugly rabbit hole if you look at #LGBnotT or #LGBnotQueer. Log Cabin Republicans isn’t engaging that part of internet culture right now, but you see it on Fox News and other media of gay men decrying the trans movement or attacking what they call “radical gender ideology.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think we’re in the opening stage of that, of more bigoted and impassioned turns, and it’s not temporary. It’s predicated on the calculation that gay rights are secure, meaning that we have marriage, for the most part [have] employment protection, and even some would say trans rights — that the Supreme Court has established some basic trans rights for adults, and that’s sort of case closed. But in general, it’s predicated on large public acceptance, including on the right, of gay persons. And there is a calculation that this is a strategy that is going to work to keep them in the fold of conservatism and conservative media.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I ask some of these contemporary actors, “Do you have any concerns about where that might be headed down the line?” And they don’t at all. Time will tell. But to the extent that these gay Republican activists have facilitated a lot of this anti-LGBTQ turn is noteworthy.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But how will that gel with what feels is like the constant growth of younger generations into political society, these younger LGBTQ Americans who seem more progressive and feel comfortable coming out. Wouldn’t that eventual turnover lead to some kind of end of this conservative queer identity? Will there be gay/LGBT/LGBTQ/LGB conservatives and Republicans 15 years from now?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If anything, it felt like there was a dip during the early Trump years at first. You look at Trump’s results with LGBTQ voters and it’s 14 percent, tied for the lowest recorded vote in 1992. [In 2020] he grew that vote. I think that there’s some indication that he wants to build on that. But whatever happens with Trump, this is not a movement that’s diminishing. If anything, the proliferation of more people who identify as LGBTQ actually will mean a growth of people who identify as gay Republicans because there will probably be a lot more people who are comfortable to be out and recognized as gay Republicans in a way that they weren’t in the past.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But also, this proliferation of identity and the sort of enhancement of identity politics also works to sort of elevate these anti-identity arguments that resonate with certain, again, white, gay men. There’s lots of ways in which we can imagine gay Republicans and LGBTQ Republicans growing in the years ahead, as this general LGBTQ demographic expands.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Christian Paz</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As you say that, the thing that I keep going back to is this meme, this question, of “how can you be a gay Republican? How can you be part of the Leopards Eating Faces Party and then get shocked when the leopards eat your face?” And I guess what I mean is, if you are speaking to a liberal American, how do you justify that this is a movement to be thinking about, to be worried about, or take seriously?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Neil J. Young</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is a phenomenon that’s much bigger than people have ever really known. And gay Republicans and gay conservatives have been really fundamental to some of the most important rights that we have, especially marriage and the end of “Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell.” And also, gay Republicans and gay conservatives, even if they&#8217;ve been marginalized by the party and demonized by the party, they’ve actually also been fundamental to the development of modern conservatism and the Republican Party that we have today. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And also I would say that this is not just about the Republicans. The larger history I engage with is to show that none of these historical developments, none of these breakthroughs and real legislative accomplishments are secure. Everything is up for grabs. Everything can be overturned. And this is really urgent.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So it’s important to understand that gay Republicans have and gay conservatives have been central actors in the development of many of the things that we think of as progressive change, and they’ve also accommodated a party that is seeking to overturn those very things. We should all be vigilant, whatever our politics are, about how much of this progress is under threat, and that nothing in history is a given.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
