<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-11-30T19:44:50+00:00</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joshua Keating</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[He thought he would die in Putin’s gulag. Now he has a message for the world.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world-politics/388169/kara-murza-putin-russia" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388169</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:47:20-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-12-01T07:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Democracy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Russia-Ukraine war" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On April 11, 2022, just weeks after Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the writer and activist Vladimir Kara-Murza was arrested outside his home in Moscow. He was charged with “spreading deliberately false information,” Kremlin-speak for criticizing the war in Ukraine. A year later, he was sentenced to 25 years in prison before later being transferred [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A white man with a receding hairline and beard smiles in a crowd of people." data-caption="Russian opposition politician Vladimir Kara-Murza attends a demonstration against Moscow’s Ukraine invasion in Berlin on November 17, 2024. | Ralf Hirschberger/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Ralf Hirschberger/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2184589196.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Russian opposition politician Vladimir Kara-Murza attends a demonstration against Moscow’s Ukraine invasion in Berlin on November 17, 2024. | Ralf Hirschberger/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">On April 11, 2022, just weeks after Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the writer and activist Vladimir Kara-Murza was <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2022/06/07/vladimir-karamurza-dont-forget-russia-political-prisoners-putin-ukraine-war/">arrested outside his home</a> in Moscow. He was charged with “spreading deliberately false information,” Kremlin-speak for criticizing the war in Ukraine. A year later, he was <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2023/04/anti-war-political-activist-and-prisoner-of-conscience-vladimir-kara-murza-sentenced-to-25-in-jail/">sentenced to 25 years in prison</a> before later being transferred to a remote Siberian penal colony where <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/russian-dissident-kara-murza-transferred-punishment-cell-new-prison-media-cites-2024-01-30/">he was held in an isolation cell</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Kara-Murza, who had already survived two earlier poisonings that had been <a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/uk-and-europe/2021/02/11/vladimir-kara-murza-tailed-by-members-of-fsb-squad-prior-to-suspected-poisonings/">linked</a> to Russia’s security services, continued writing in prison, including regular columns for the Washington Post, for which he was awarded the <a href="https://www.pulitzer.org/winners/vladimir-kara-murza-contributor-washington-post">Pulitzer Prize for commentary</a>. He expected to die in prison, as his fellow dissident Alexei Navalny did earlier this year.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Then, in August of 2024, Kara-Murza —  a dual Russian-British citizen — found himself suddenly released and expelled from Russia as part of the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/01/world/who-are-detainees-russia-us-prisoner-swap-intl/index.html">massive international prisoner</a> exchange that also freed the American journalist Evan Gershkovich. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, Kara-Murza sat down with Vox for an extended interview on the sidelines of the <a href="https://halifaxtheforum.org/">Halifax International Security Forum</a>, where he had just received the event’s John McCain Prize for Leadership. (The award was particularly meaningful for Kara-Murza, who was a friend of the late Arizona senator and a pallbearer at his funeral.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an interview with Vox, which has been edited for length and clarity, Kara-Murza talked about the “surreal” experience of sudden freedom, the lessons of history for the war in Ukraine, and why Putin’s regime might not be as stable as it seems.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>When this conference was happening a year ago, you were still in prison. Is the experience of being out still strange for you?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It is completely surreal. For the last three months, I’ve felt as if I&#8217;m watching some kind of a film. Frankly, it&#8217;s a very good film, but it does not feel real. I was absolutely convinced that I was going to die in that Siberian prison. And what happened on August 1, I can only describe it as a miracle, because the last time that there was an international prisoner exchange that actually freed <em>Russian</em> political prisoners — not just Western citizens held in Russian jails, but Russian political prisoners — was in October 1986. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It was a miracle, but in many ways, a human-made miracle, because this exchange was made possible by the relentless efforts of so many good people in democratic nations who never stopped advocating and speaking and shouting about this growing crisis with political prisoners in Russia. We have more political prisoners in Russia today than there were in the whole of the Soviet Union in the mid-1980s. This is the situation in Russia under Putin.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And so yes, it still feels totally surreal. I haven&#8217;t really had any transition. That&#8217;s another problem. I went from solitary confinement in a maximum security prison in Siberia to being in four or five different countries every week. And that&#8217;s not really the way it should be done after the prison experience, but I just feel I have no choice. Because, you know, while people are prepared to listen, I have to speak, because I do feel that responsibility now that I&#8217;ve been rescued from that hell.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Given what’s happened to a number of prominent critics of the Russian government abroad, do you still feel like there’s some threat to your safety, even outside of Russia?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When our plane was landing in Ankara on the day of the exchange, one of the FSB [Russia’s state security service] officers who was accompanying us turned to Ilya Yashin [another Russian opposition activist freed as part of the exchange] and to me, and said, “Don&#8217;t think that you guys will be safe over there. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vadim_Krasikov">Krasikov</a> can come for you too.” [Vadim Krasikov is the Russian security service hitman, released as part of the prisoner exchange, who had been serving a life sentence in Germany for the assassination of a former Chechen rebel in Berlin.] He didn’t mean literally Krasikov, of course. They have a whole desk of Krasikovs. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;ve been in Russian opposition politics for 25 years. We all know what can happen to people who publicly oppose the Putin regime. My closest friend, my mentor, the godfather to my younger daughter, Boris Nemtsov [the former Russian Deputy Prime Minister turned opposition leader, killed in 2015], was <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-31669061">gunned down, literally in front of the Kremlin</a>, on Putin&#8217;s direct orders. Other people have been poisoned, including myself, and we know that these attacks have happened not just on Russian soil, but abroad.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And so look, we all know the risks. We all know what it involves, but frankly, I just don&#8217;t think about it, because, well, I don&#8217;t want to become paranoid, and it&#8217;s not possible just to live every day with that thought in your mind. I know that what I&#8217;m doing is the right thing to do, and I&#8217;m going to carry on anyway.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what&#8217;s even more important is that I&#8217;m not just a politician. I&#8217;m a historian by education. And we know that the arc of history may not bend as fast as we&#8217;d like, but it does bend towards liberty, and we know that the future belongs to democracies and not to one-man, personalistic, archaic dictatorships, like the dictatorship led by Putin. And so the bottom line is, even if Vladimir Putin gets rid of all of us who are the current leaders, the current faces of the Russian opposition, all it means is that others will come in our place.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-1231428118.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.740836125969,100,78.518327748063" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Kara-Murza laying flowers on a bridge." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Looking at the </strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-ukraine-losses-putin-1988034"><strong>number of Russian casualties</strong></a><strong> that are coming back from Ukraine, why doesn’t this seem to have more of an impact on Russian society? And how long can this situation be sustainable for the Russian government? </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We do not know whether or not it is having an impact, because it&#8217;s not possible to objectively assess the state of public opinion in a country that imprisons you for expressing it. And that&#8217;s the problem with authoritarian and totalitarian regimes. They seem stable and strong and secure, and then suddenly they collapse.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“That’s the problem with authoritarian and totalitarian regimes. They seem stable and strong and secure, and then suddenly they collapse. ”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Both the czarist regime and the communist regime in Russia went down in a matter of days, literally, and nobody saw it coming. There&#8217;s a book by the Berkeley anthropologist Alexei Yurchak about the later years of the Soviet Union — I have not read it because it came out while I was in prison, but I love the title: <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/paperback/9780691121178/everything-was-forever-until-it-was-no-more?srsltid=AfmBOopj6_1RyQawtvpnnpDWPVDVzYTd1MJO8OKTcUES1ppbqPBZxU7R"><em>Everything Was Forever, Until It Was No More</em></a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And this is exactly how it happened in Russia, and this is exactly how it&#8217;s going to happen next time. In these repressive, tyrannical regimes, you don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s happening beneath the surface. [Czech dissident and later President] Václav Havel writes about this in <a href="https://hac.bard.edu/amor-mundi/the-power-of-the-powerless-vaclav-havel-2011-12-23"><em>The Power of the Powerless</em></a>, that there may be problems developing for the regime, but nobody&#8217;s aware of them until they come out of the open and suddenly everything collapses. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So the honest answer is, we don&#8217;t know what the real impact of the war is on Russian society. What we do know for certain is that there are a lot of people in Russia who are against this war. We don’t know it from opinion polls. Those are useless. But you have to look at what I call little glimpses of reality. One of the most vivid ones came in February in the middle of our so-called presidential election campaign, which you’ll remember was just Putin and a couple of handpicked clowns. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there was one guy, a lawyer and former member of parliament named Boris Nadezhdin, who announced that he was <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/01/27/world/europe/russia-putin-election-boris-nadezhdin.html">running as a presidential candidate on an anti-war platform</a>. And the public response in Russia was just unbelievable. All across the country, in large cities and small towns, you had these long, massive, hours-long lines of people who were waiting at his campaign headquarters to sign petitions to get him on the ballot.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And of course, he was not allowed to. He was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/02/08/europe/russia-nadezhdin-election-candidate-disqualified-intl/index.html">barred from running</a> as an opposition candidate in Putin’s Russia. But that was almost beside the point, because suddenly everyone saw through this lie pushed by Putin&#8217;s propaganda that everybody in Russia backs this regime, that everybody in Russia supports this war. You can fake election results. You can rig the opinion poll numbers, but you cannot hide the sight of hundreds of thousands of people all over the country literally voting with their feet for the anti-war candidate. And I got a lot of letters in prison, and in February, almost all my letters were about these lines all over the country.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;ll never forget, there was one woman, one young woman, who wrote to me from Novorossiysk, which is a town on the Black Sea coast in the south of Russia. And she was describing how she waited in that long, long line of like-minded, mostly young people, to sign [Nadezhdin’s] ballot access petition. And then she wrote, “I never realized how many of us there are.” It&#8217;s these glimpses of reality that really matter for sort of trying to assess what the actual situation is.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>But do you think the government is really feeling insecure? It’s certainly not reflected in the economic numbers, </strong><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-68823399"><strong>which show Russia is still rapidly growing</strong></a><strong>. Last month, we saw Putin host half a dozen world leaders at the BRICS summit in Kazan. This doesn’t seem like an isolated leader who’s feeling the pressure.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a lot of pressure. The economists tell us that this sort of formal growth that the Russian statistics are producing is all, in a major sense, artificial. This is all just fueled by the war machine. And as soon as this is over, economists are forecasting some very hard times ahead, because this is not a real economy. This is not a consumer economy or a free-market economy in the full sense of this term. Everything is geared towards the military-industrial machinery.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And in terms of how the regime is feeling, I would say that the best way to gauge that is to actually look at their own behavior. Because you know, on the one hand, that propaganda says that, you know, Putin is very popular, his regime is stable and secure. But to me, actions are always more important than words. If that were really the case, why would they need to arrest somebody for a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/01/29/europe/russian-teen-social-media-ukraine-war-intl-cmd/index.html">social media post</a> and send them for seven years to prison? Why would they be so afraid of allowing, for example, that anti-war candidate on the ballot, if that position is as unpopular as they claim? Why not just let him on the ballot and let him get his 1 percent?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>When this war ends, what do you think it will take to repair the anger and distrust between Russian and Ukrainian societies?&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First of all, I can tell you that I&#8217;ve had very good contacts, very good dialogue with my Ukrainian friends and colleagues over these last few months that I&#8217;ve been out of prison. I also got letters from Ukrainians while I was in prison. So you know, let&#8217;s not also pretend that it&#8217;s total. Reasonable people can distinguish between a dictatorial regime and its society, and they don&#8217;t blame all 140 million Russians. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But of course, there is a lot of pain, there is a lot of grief, there&#8217;s a lot of emotion on the Ukrainian side, and it could not have been otherwise when every day people are hearing bombs falling on their towns, and every day children are dying and civilians are dying.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Not only do I totally understand this — this is why I could not stay silent in the first place. Russians will have a very long and very difficult road ahead of us once this is all over and once, of course, there&#8217;s a different political situation in Russia. It will be a long and difficult path to reconciliation, to finding a way to speak to each other again, to look into each other&#8217;s eyes again. It&#8217;s going to be long, it&#8217;s going to be difficult, but I fully believe that it&#8217;s going to be possible.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And what gives me this hope is, again, my background is as a historian, because we know that this has happened in history before. Just a couple of months ago in September, I was in Strasbourg in France for the autumn session of the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe. They invited me to give a speech at the plenary session. The easiest way to get to Strasbourg is to fly to Frankfurt and just get a rental car and drive for a couple of hours.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I’m a historian. I know what Alsace-Lorraine [a much fought-over border region, now part of France] is. I know how much blood was spilled over that piece of land between the Germans and the French. I know how many thousands of people are buried in that land because they fought over it in the Franco-Prussian War, in the First World War, in the Second World War. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It must have seemed like this hatred would be eternal, that it would never be possible to overcome it. But when I was driving from Frankfurt to Strasbourg, I wasn&#8217;t even sure if I was still in Germany or already in France, because there&#8217;s an open border. There&#8217;s a single currency. People are living in peace and friendship with each other, even when there are still people alive today who fought in the Second World War. So this all happened within the life of a single generation. The French and the Germans were able to find that way to reconcile, and I have no doubt, Russians and Ukrainians will.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You’ve referred to your training as a historian. Are there moments from history that you think can help us better understand this current moment we’re in, both the war and the political situation in Russia?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So first, I&#8217;ll answer the negative side of your question, and this links to your question about the next US administration and this talk we hear about possibly <a href="https://www.chathamhouse.org/2024/11/can-trump-do-deal-putin-ukraine">cutting a deal with Putin </a>over Ukraine. I think one lesson from history that we must never forget is that the appeasement of dictators never brings peace. It always leads to more aggression, more suffering, more wars, because dictators do not see compromise as an invitation to compromise back. They see it as a sign of weakness, and they become more aggressive. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We know this from the history of the 1930s. We know this also from the history of the past 25 years of Western dealings with Putin because for a lot of that time, Western leaders on both sides of the Atlantic basically engaged in the policy of appeasement, and this is where it led us. And so I think that it&#8217;s very important that whatever agreement, whatever settlement is made to to end this war, that settlement has to take into account the interests of Ukraine, and that settlement cannot be done in such a way as to allow Vladimir Putin to present himself as being the victor, who&#8217;s being triumphant, because if that happens, that would be a disaster for everybody.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the more positive side, I mentioned how quickly political changes happen in Russia. I remember 1991. I was 10 at the time, I was a child, but you know, when the revolution is happening in front of your eyes, it&#8217;s not something you can forget. And I remember those days in Moscow — the very smell of the air, the freedom. And to me, this was, in many ways, a life-defining lesson of those three days in August of democratic revolution. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Because, as you know, of course, that began as an attempted hardline coup d&#8217;état led by the leadership of the Soviet Communist part of the KGB, the military. And it seemed that everything was on the side of those coup plotters, right? They had everything to themselves. They had the whole machinery, the whole apparatus of the Soviet state. They had the whole propaganda apparatus. They had the police, the military, and of course, they had the KGB, the world&#8217;s most powerful machine of repression. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And the people who opposed that coup, who wanted to stand up for Russian democracy, they were not armed with anything except their dignity and their determination to defend their own freedom, but they went into the streets in hundreds of thousands — my dad was among those people — and they literally stood there on the streets of Moscow in front of the tanks, and then the tanks stopped and turned away. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The lesson here is that however strong, however stable, however secure a dictatorial regime may seem, if enough people are willing to stand up to it, they succeed.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“Russia can change unexpectedly, and we have to be ready for it.” </p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Russia can change unexpectedly, and we have to be ready for it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>How can we get ready for it?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What happened in the 1990s was that the Soviet system collapsed so suddenly that people were not prepared, and people made mistakes, both on the Russian domestic side and on the international side. And we have to learn from those mistakes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On the domestic side, we know that any country that wants to overcome the trauma of totalitarianism and successfully transition to democracy has to undergo some sort of a process of public reckoning, a public reflection of the crimes that are being committed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We saw this in South Africa after apartheid. We saw this in Argentina after its military dictatorship. We saw this in Central and Eastern Europe after the fall of communism. Of course, we saw this in Germany after ’45, and then again, after ’89 in the eastern parts. This is a process where society is made aware of all the horrendous crimes that have been committed in its name by the previous regime. So the archives are opened and these crimes are made public. The people responsible for these crimes are made accountable. The institutions that have been committing these crimes, like the secret services, are dismantled, and so on. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">None of this happened in Russia in the ’90s. And we know that when evil is not publicly reflected on and publicly condemned, it’s going to come back. And this is exactly what we saw with a former KGB officer coming to power in Russia. We must never make this mistake again. So this is our homework for the Russian opposition, for the Russian democratic forces. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there&#8217;s also an important international aspect, and that is that, you know, for many of the countries of the former Eastern Bloc, the former Warsaw Pact in the 1990s, the promise of Euro-Atlantic integration, served as the most powerful incentive to successfully complete their reforms. When Václav Havel <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/politics/1990/02/22/text-of-havels-speech-to-congress/df98e177-778e-4c26-bd96-980089c4fcb2/">addressed the US Congress </a>in February of 1990, he termed the entire process of post-communist transformation in Czechoslovakia as, I quote, “returning to Europe.”And that light at the end of the tunnel is very important for these countries to continue their reforms and successfully complete them. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Russia never really got the promise of the 1990s. It was sort of kept to the doorstep. When President Boris Yeltsin in December of 1991 wrote to Manfred Wörner, the then-Secretary General of NATO, for the first time <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1991/12/21/world/soviet-disarray-yeltsin-says-russia-seeks-to-join-nato.html">officially and publicly raising the question of future Russian membership in NATO</a>, he did not even receive a response. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We have to be ready the next time this happens, because what happens in Russia affects everyone.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>To go back to the question of Ukrainians and Russians, it seems like what you’re proposing will require the West to take a leap of faith on Russia after the war. Here at this conference, we’ve heard a lot of slogans like “Make Russia Small Again,” and it’s not unusual to hear people talk about Russia needing to be demilitarized or carved up.&nbsp;</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All this talk that you just referenced, that&#8217;s an amazing gift to Putin&#8217;s propaganda, because all he needs to do is just amplify those voices and tell people, ‘all these people in the West, they’re so Russophobic. They hate all Russians. Their quarrel is not with me, with Putin, they hate all of you. And frankly, it is really damaging, really shortsighted and really counterproductive to hear.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>So there’s now been years of discussions, analysis, and legal proceedings regarding the relationship between Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin. As this new American administration comes in, what do you think are kind of the best- and worst-case scenarios? What are your expectations for how this administration will handle Russia?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think a character trait that we definitely know about Mr. Trump is that he&#8217;s famously unpredictable, so I think that it’s anybody&#8217;s guess what the actual policy will be. To be honest, I was really heartened by the selection of the secretary of state. I&#8217;ve known Senator Marco Rubio for many years. I know he cares about the issues of democracy and human rights, and standing up to dictatorial regimes. He&#8217;s spent a lot of his Senate career on these issues. He has advocated on behalf of political prisoners in Russia, in Belarus, of course, in Venezuela and Cuba.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“I’m an optimist about Russia, and I’m certainly an optimist about the United States.” </p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Something that’s very close to my heart: After Boris Nemtsov was assassinated, we launched this international initiative to commemorate him with street designations around the world. And the first city that did this was Washington, DC. And today, if you go to the Russian embassy, you’ll see that it stands on <a href="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B22-0646">Boris Nemtsov Plaza</a>. The original sponsor of the Senate bill that did that was Marco Rubio.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>A lot of Americans are worried now about the future of their own democracy. Polls show that was top of mind for a large number of voters. As someone who’s seen authoritarianism firsthand, do you think it’s reasonable for people in the US or other democracies to be worried about their countries remaining democracies? </strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well, first of all, I do think it&#8217;s right to never be complacent about this, to never take things for granted. I think it was President Reagan who said that freedom is never more than one generation away from extinction. That is unfortunately, absolutely true, and we all have to be vigilant about this. But you know, I&#8217;m an optimist about Russia, and I’m certainly an optimist about the United States.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;ve had two-and-a-half centuries of democratic institutions and democratic traditions. That&#8217;s not going to suddenly be undone because of any single person in the space of four years. So I don&#8217;t share these alarmist sorts of views and predictions. But it&#8217;s right that people are concerned because we always have to stand guard and make sure that we protect these democratic institutions.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Noah Gordon</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Daevan Mangalmurti</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[A surprise solar boom reveals a fatal flaw in our climate change projections]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/388506/solar-energy-power-projections-climate-change-pakistan" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388506</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T19:37:08-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-12-01T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[When the satellites zoomed in, you could see the panels gleaming from space. Pairing images taken miles above the Earth with Chinese customs records, BloombergNEF solar analyst Jenny Chase and her team discovered this year that the rooftops of homes and factories across Pakistan are blanketed with solar panels. Catching their own government by surprise, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Solar power panels in Pakistan." data-caption="Solar panels installed on the roof of buildings at Skardu in Pakistan’s Gilgit-Baltistan region." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-2155733321.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Solar panels installed on the roof of buildings at Skardu in Pakistan’s Gilgit-Baltistan region.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">When the satellites zoomed in, you could see the panels gleaming from space. Pairing images taken miles above the Earth with Chinese customs records, BloombergNEF solar analyst Jenny Chase and her team <a href="https://mastodon.green/@solar_chase/112920169220291471">discovered</a> this year that the rooftops of homes and factories across Pakistan are blanketed with solar panels. Catching their own government by <a href="https://uploads.renewablesfirst.org/The_Great_Solar_Rush_in_Pakistan_38157451a3.pdf">surprise</a>, Pakistanis have been <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-22/surprise-solar-boom-in-pakistan-helps-millions-but-harms-grid?cmpid=BBD112224_GREENDAILY&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_term=241122&amp;utm_campaign=greendaily">installing a massive amount of solar power</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the process, Pakistan has gone from an inconsequential solar market to the <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-08-09/pakistan-sees-solar-boom-as-chinese-imports-surge-bnef-says?sref=wOrDP8KX&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email">sixth-largest</a> in the world. The country of <a href="https://www.pbs.gov.pk/sites/default/files/population/2023/Press%20Release.pdf">242 million</a> has a power grid with a peak capacity of <a href="https://nepra.org.pk/publications/State%20of%20Industry%20Reports/State%20of%20Industry%20Report%202023.pdf">46 gigawatts</a> — that’s less than 4 percent of the <a href="https://www.eia.gov/energyexplained/electricity/electricity-in-the-us-generation-capacity-and-sales.php">US power supply</a> for a country with more than two-thirds as many people. In the last three years, Pakistanis have imported <a href="https://www.dertaskforce.com/p/pakistans-distributed-solar-boom">more than 25 gigawatts</a> of solar panels from China. This disorganized, bottom-up boom has increased Pakistan&#8217;s power supply by 50 percent.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The solar surge is driven by high local electricity costs. At 16.6 cents per kilowatt-hour, Pakistan’s electricity rate for businesses is <a href="https://www.thenews.com.pk/print/1245129-pakistan-s-power-costs-among-highest-in-s-asia-for-industry-commerce">37 percent higher</a> than its neighbor India, and more than double the average rate in Asia. Agreements made in the <a href="https://www.brecorder.com/news/40327485/termination-of-contracts-with-ipps">1990s</a> have kept the state stuck in expensive contracts with independent power producers, and power plants burn <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/energy/pakistan-plans-quadruple-domestic-coal-fired-power-move-away-gas-2023-02-13/">lots</a> of liquefied natural gas, which became costlier after Russia invaded Ukraine in 2022. That same year, Pakistan fell into a <a href="https://www.cnbctv18.com/world/pakistan-economic-crisis-how-pakistani-banks-pulled-off-a-usd-2-38-billion-heist-that-still-haunts-the-govt-19481519.htm">foreign exchange crisis</a> as the country’s dollar reserves plunged, which made everything more expensive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this opened an <a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2024/11/04/dealing-with-pakistans-solar-panel-glut/">opportunity</a> for businesses and better-off Pakistanis to begin importing solar panels from China, which can pay for themselves in as little as <a href="https://ieefa.org/resources/future-net-metered-solar-power-pakistan#:~:text=The%20current%20government%20offers%20attractive,to%20lower%20per%20kW%20costs.">two years</a> and free their users from the expensive, <a href="https://aptma.org.pk/seasonal-grid-instability-challenges-in-pakistan-ii/">unreliable</a> grid. The <a href="https://www.dawn.com/news/1845916">middle class</a> has started to do the same. The state has come under pressure to <a href="https://ieefa.org/resources/future-net-metered-solar-power-pakistan#:~:text=The%20current%20government%20offers%20attractive,to%20lower%20per%20kW%20costs.">raise rates</a> for the conventional grid to satisfy its contracts with power producers — which the increasingly shrinking, poorer customer base struggles even more to afford. Consumers who have made the switch to solar panels, like the owner of a factory that makes soccer balls in Sialkot, <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/69e4cb33-3615-4424-996d-5aee9d1afe19">told</a> the Financial Times, “Allah has given us this gift to get out of this mess.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But there’s a bigger story here, beyond one nation’s problems with its power grid. What’s happening in Pakistan is the latest sign that energy authorities are underestimating how much clean power the world demands — and that energy models can suffer from the same biases as their makers. Those failures in number-crunching are not merely abstract. Failing to grasp how much energy is wanted, and the things people in places like Pakistan might be willing to do to get it, leaves the world unprepared to build, fund, and plan for a cleaner future.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why our energy demand projections are always wrong</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">History has shown that cheap energy creates its own <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7471716/">demand</a>. When steam engines got more efficient in 19th century Britain, <a href="https://energyhistory.yale.edu/w-stanley-jevons-the-coal-question-1865/">coal consumption</a> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/science/environment/energy-efficiency-carbon-emissions-climate-struggles-9b10e037">grew</a>. When oil got cheap and plentiful after World War II, humans didn’t enjoy the savings. They built more cars. More recently, in 2000, when estimating an industrializing China’s electricity demand for 2005, the Energy Information Administration’s projections were off by <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/43861125?seq=34">25 percent</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Modelers try to project how much energy will be demanded years into the future. But those projects often fail to distinguish between how much energy is needed and how much is <em>wanted</em>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In part, this is about the particular<a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-investment-2024/overview-and-key-findings"> outperformance</a> of solar, whose growth the International Energy Agency (IEA), an intergovernmental organization that oversees the global energy sector, has drastically <a href="https://x.com/AukeHoekstra/status/1730992987021226002">underestimated</a> every year <a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2018/11/20/iea-versus-solar-pv-reality/">since 2006</a> — as have <a href="https://x.com/CleanPowerDave/status/1856288117583495332">countries’ own renewable energy targets</a>. The IEA’s <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/net-zero-by-2050">Net Zero by 2050</a> report, a plan for how to eliminate net greenhouse gas emissions by the mid-21st century, was seen as ambitious when it came out in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/18/climate/climate-change-emissions-IEA.html">2021</a>. It called for the world to add 630 gigawatts of solar power annually by 2030. This is actually proving a very easy target: The world is already on track to add nearly <a href="https://ember-climate.org/insights/in-brief/solar-power-continues-to-surge-in-2024/">600 gigawatts</a> in 2024 — 334 gigawatts in China, 53 gigawatts in the US, and, stunningly, at least <a href="https://www.dertaskforce.com/p/pakistans-distributed-solar-boom">16 gigawatts</a> in Pakistan. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The pattern is that Western energy forecasters are continually surprised by how much energy people in developing countries will consume. As countries like Pakistan grow wealthier, their people are going to demand the same energy-dependent conveniences that people in wealthy countries already do —&nbsp;and our energy forecasts must reflect that reality or we’re going to keep getting it wrong.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One recent projection illustrates the problem. Working with Pakistan’s energy authorities, the <a href="https://ens.dk/sites/ens.dk/files/Globalcooperation/publication_-_pakistans_power_sector_towards_2045.pdf">Danish Energy Agency examined in 2023</a> how Pakistan’s electricity sector might develop to align with the IEA’s net-zero-by-2050 pathway. It expected Pakistani electricity generation to reach about 350,000 gigawatt-hours (a unit of energy use over time) in 2045, doubling its 2022 capacity of <a href="https://www.iea.org/countries/pakistan/electricity">173,000 gigawatt-hours</a>. But that would still leave the hundreds of millions of people living in future Pakistan to get by with much less power than <a href="https://www.eia.gov/electricity/state/texas/">Texas generates today</a>, with a fraction of Pakistan’s population.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But that estimate fails to account for Pakistan’s middle class, which is almost <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/middle-class-voters-deal-historic-defeat-to-pakistani-military-regime-by-adeel-malik-2024-02#:~:text=According%20to%20economist%20Durr%2De,like%20motorcycles%20and%20TVs%20has">100 million</a> strong with millions more on the cusp of exiting poverty and joining its ranks. As people get richer, they ask for — and use — more electricity. Today, only <a href="https://www.clasp.ngo/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Cooling-Needs-Assessment-2022.pdf">11 percent</a> of Pakistani households have air-conditioning. In six days this June, when temperatures in southern parts of the country hit 120 degrees Fahrenheit, at least <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn05rz3w4x1o">568</a> people died. In a 3 degrees Celsius  scenario, which is what we are on track for by <a href="https://www.unep.org/news-and-stories/statements/emissions-gap-report-2024-press-statement">2100</a>, South Asia’s major cities will face multiple heat waves every year that last an average of <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/climate-change-effects-cities-15-vs-3-degrees-C">23 days — nearly twice as long as they do today</a>. Even if air conditioners grow increasingly <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-solutions/interactive/2024/air-conditioning-humidity-hotter-summers-solutions/">efficient</a>, in a scenario in which power production merely doubled between now and 2045, a large share of the population would lack protection from the deadly temperatures of the 2040s. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Either the rising middle class of Pakistan will continue to endure heat waves like this year’s without using technology to ease their suffering — or they are going to end up using a lot more power than prominent forecasts for energy consumption assume. That would have precedent: global demand for energy to power air-conditioning and other cooling measures grew from 300 terawatt-hours in the 1990s to 800 terawatt-hours in 2023, which is one <a href="https://climateanalytics.org/comment/new-gas-and-oil-has-prevented-co2-global-emissions-from-peaking">reason</a> why worldwide carbon emissions still haven’t peaked. In Pakistan, a recent <a href="https://journals.iub.edu.pk/index.php/pjes/article/view/2134">study</a> found that higher temperatures will help drive electricity demand to grow twice as fast (6 to 8 percent annually) as current estimates. The IEA itself has once again<a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-outlook-2024?utm_content=buffer9942a&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer"> revised</a> its forecasts for electricity demand growth upward by <a href="https://www.iea.org/reports/world-energy-outlook-2024/executive-summary">6 percent</a>, adding that demand for air-condition is a key <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/de175bfd-aaf1-4adc-b4b5-3e9973aed522">uncertainty</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Models of energy and climate systems are full of assumptions that often don’t filter through to those reading the headline findings: some scholars call it “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211467X21000225">status quo bias</a>.” When an energy agency in Paris or Copenhagen posits that the world can reach net-zero with millions of Pakistanis having just enough power to spin ceiling fans, they are postulating certain limits on how much power could be installed in Pakistan, and how much Europeans could cut emissions to leave Pakistan space for growth. When seemingly apolitical integrated assessment models, which evaluate the economic results of climate change, tell policymakers which temperature targets are possible or desirable, they are also revealing political assumptions that are often mistaken. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Accepting his Nobel Prize in 2018, William Nordhaus, the godfather of <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/qa-how-integrated-assessment-models-are-used-to-study-climate-change/">integrated assessment models</a>, <a href="https://www.nobelprize.org/uploads/2018/10/nordhaus-lecture.pdf">asserted</a> that the “cost-benefit optimum [for warming] rises to 3C in 2100.” In other words, the most cost-effective outcome of climate change — in terms of how much we spend to stop it and how much damage it inflicts — is a global average temperature increase of 3 degrees Celsius, twice the warming target set in the 2015 Paris climate agreement (a target the world is well on its way to missing). But whose cost, and whose optimum? Models like Nordhaus’ assume economic development can protect people from the climate change that the same economic activity causes. This line of thinking assumes there is a limit to how much the world’s wealthy countries can slow down (or green) their energy consumption to arrest climate change — and that therefore there is a limit on how much new energy can be allocated for poorer countries with their rapidly developing economies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The world’s growing middle class isn’t waiting for permission to buy air conditioners. The task now is to make sure that the energy that powers them is clean — and that means having more than enough solar panels for Lahore as well as Copenhagen.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sam Delgado</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How did Elphaba become wicked? There’s a hidden message people keep missing.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/388499/wicked-elphaba-animal-rights-dillamond" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388499</id>
			<updated>2024-11-30T14:44:50-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-30T07:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Animal Welfare" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone wants to hold space for “Defying Gravity,” the powerhouse anthem from Wicked, the Broadway musical-turned-movie blockbuster. But behind the in-your-face themes of female rivalry and friendship, unrequited love, and the unfortunate circumstance of being green, there’s a deeper undercurrent: the alienation that comes when you stand behind what you believe in. The story — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Elphaba, wearing her signature black hat and gown, holds her broomstick and looks out into the horizon" data-caption="Cynthia Erivo as Elphaba in Wicked. | Universal Pictures/Wicked" data-portal-copyright="Universal Pictures/Wicked" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/2551_TP_00125.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Cynthia Erivo as Elphaba in Wicked. | Universal Pictures/Wicked</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Everyone wants to <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/387545/ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-wicked-dont-worry-darling-it-ends-with-us">hold space</a> for “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qeqj5GnoFUY">Defying Gravity</a>,” the powerhouse anthem from <em>Wicked</em>, the Broadway musical-turned-movie blockbuster. But behind the in-your-face themes of female <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DAvOfEweyJo">rivalry</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aCTmVliv4XM">friendship</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CeUragIeYXg">unrequited love</a>, and the unfortunate circumstance of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VDMiHYgQKLE">being green</a>, there’s a deeper undercurrent: the alienation that comes when you stand behind what you believe in.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The story — a reimagining of L. Frank Baum’s 1900 <em>The Wizard of Oz </em>— explains how the notorious Wicked Witch of the West came to be. Like the musical, the movie takes place in the Land of Oz and follows Elphaba Thropp (Cynthia Erivo), a kind but hardened young woman who has been ostracized her whole life for her green skin, as she enters Shiz University to cultivate her strong magical powers. It’s here where she meets, rooms with, and eventually befriends Galinda Upland (Ariana Grande), an aspiring sorcerer who&#8217;s been beloved and popular her whole life.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But what seems to get ignored is the root of Elphaba’s supposed wickedness: her horror at the mistreatment of animals and her determination to free them. In the Land of Oz, animals are regular members of society, living and working alongside other Ozians — until they’re silenced and forced out of the public eye.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, <em>Wicked</em> is a fantasy tale, but if one focuses just a bit longer on Elphaba’s origin story, it’s hard not to see the parallels between the movie and the real-world state of animal welfare. The reality of animal oppression is not only stranger than the fiction in <em>Wicked</em>, but unfortunately much more cruel. And those who seek to expose this abuse and create change are ridiculed, jailed, and, much like Elphaba, ostracized for their stance and deemed wicked.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How the animal rights message in Wicked connects to real life</h2>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/10/spoilers_below.webp?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=39.551567944251,0,20.896864111498,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">From the very beginning of her life, the movie shows that Elphaba has felt a connection to animals, at least partially because of the prejudice she’s faced in her own life. When Elphaba is born and it’s revealed she has green skin, her father rejects her. She’s raised mostly by Dulcibear, her nanny who happens to be a brown bear and who empathizes with Elphaba and sees the good in her, while her father berates and chastises her for being different.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Years later, when Elphaba enrolls at Shiz University after showing her magical powers, she’s ostracized by much of the student population for her skin. She finds solace in her studies, particularly her class with Doctor Dillamond, a goat who teaches history. It’s in his class where the disenfranchisement of animals becomes clear to Elphaba: Dillamond tells the students he is one of the few animal professors left, after animals were blamed for a widespread drought in Oz years before. Later in the class, Dillamond finds that someone has written “Animals should be seen and not heard” on the other side of his chalkboard.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/Animals-should-be-seen-and-not-heard.png?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=9.0290923196276,0,81.941815360745,100" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="Universal Pictures International/Wicked trailer" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Elphaba learns more about the oppression of animals after eavesdropping on a conversation with Dillamond and other fellow creatures about stories of animals losing the ability to speak, being forced out from their jobs, and leaving Oz entirely. This becomes Dillamond’s own fate, when he’s violently removed from his classroom and replaced by a new human instructor who shows his latest invention to keep animals from learning how to speak: a cage, with a scared lion cub inside. “Can you imagine a world where animals are kept in cages and they never learn to speak?” Elphaba asks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the real world, animals don’t speak (at least, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/354478/elephants-call-name-study-nature-personhood-rights">not in languages we can understand</a>). But caging animals? That’s a reality that most of the world widely accepts in exchange for food and entertainment — though few understand what it really looks like.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Humans raise about <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22890292/food-waste-meat-dairy-eggs-milk-animal-welfare">75 billion animals</a> for food annually, and while caging animals is not a new practice, modern factory farming has taken the confinement and exploitation of animals to new extremes. For example, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/353393/farm-bill-republicans-prop-12-gestation-crates-pork">female breeding pigs are held in “gestation crates,”</a> small cages barely bigger than their own bodies where they’re essentially immobilized, forcefully and artificially inseminated, and made to go through repeated cycles of pregnancy and birth. Chickens, whose eggs are often sold with misleading claims like “<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/384740/foster-farms-usda-humane-story">humanely raised</a>,” are also stuffed in cages so small <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2019/1/30/18197688/organic-cage-free-wild-caught-certified-humane">they can’t fully spread their wings</a> (and even “cage-free” eggs could mean that thousands of chickens are all together in a space too small for them all, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/21437054/chickens-factory-farming-animal-cruelty-welfare">effectively living on top of each other</a>.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And when disaster strikes, these trapped animals have nowhere to go. A fire at a pig farm in August <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/371921/farm-animals-barn-fire-north-carolina-pigs-deaths">left more than 1,000 pigs to die in flames</a> (a <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23683141/texas-farm-fire-explosion-dimmitt-cows-factory-dairy">routine occurrence</a> on factory farms), after the pork industry lobbied against fire code updates that would require them to install sprinklers in barns. When Hurricane Helene hit Georgia, the country’s top chicken-producing state, it’s likely that <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/374940/hurricane-helene-georgia-chicken-poultry-farms">millions of chickens were killed</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Inhumane confinement is the tip of the iceberg. Multiple investigations have exposed the stomach-churning reality of factory farms. On one pig farm, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23817808/pig-farm-investigation-feedback-immunity-feces-intestines">an undercover investigation</a> showed piglets gasping for air after being poisoned with carbon monoxide, while others were fed a mixture of pig parts and feces. One years-long investigation at livestock auctions across multiple states showed animals like cows and goats <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/379527/livestock-auctions-animal-abuse-investigation-cow-sheep-goats">violently abused</a> by being kicked, dragged, and thrown. While these particular findings are just snapshots, these forms of cruelty are ubiquitous, consistently reflected in investigations into the meat industry.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Though farmed animals may face the worst and largest-scale abuse, they are not the only animals to be confined. Zoos, where animals are whisked away from their natural habitat and forced to live in much smaller spaces, are largely forms of entertainment for the public. While zoos do contribute to conservation work, they also <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23914885/zoo-animals-conservation-endangered-threatened-species-sanctuaries">come at a cost</a> for the very beings withheld in these facilities, like “<a href="https://slate.com/technology/2014/06/animal-madness-zoochosis-stereotypic-behavior-and-problems-with-zoos.html">zoochosis</a>.” Animals confined in zoos have been recorded engaging in repetitive behaviors like pacing around and self-harming.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Elphaba, the animal rights activist</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the end of the movie, Elphaba meets the Wizard of Oz and is given the chance to work under him. While there, she tells the Wizard that her heart’s desire is to help the animals, which the Wizard seemingly agrees to.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But after tricking her into casting a spell that painfully sprouted wings on the Wizard’s monkey servants’ backs (the origin story of the <a href="https://screenrant.com/wicked-elphaba-flying-monkeys-creation-wizard-of-oz/">famous flying monkeys</a>), the Wizard reveals he can now use them to spy on other animals. Realizing it’s the Wizard behind the subjugation and villainization of animals in order to hold onto power, Elphaba refuses to use her magic to help him any further and flees — but not before being labeled a wicked witch and a threat to all of Oz by Madame Morrible, her sorcery instructor.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Vegetarians, vegans, and animal rights activists can probably relate — especially the ones who put their freedom on the line. In recent years, a string of activists have been <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23647682/factory-farming-dxe-criminal-trial-rescue">criminally prosecuted</a> for rescuing sick and injured animals from factory farms. In November 2023, the lawyer and animal rights activist <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23952627/wayne-hsiung-conviction-direct-action-everywhere-dxe-rescue-sonoma-county-chickens">Wayne Hsiung was convicted</a> for his role in helping Direct Action Everywhere members remove 70 chickens and ducks from two factory farms in Sonoma County, California. He faced up to 3 1/2 years in prison, but was released after 38 days in jail, much of it spent in conditions that experts have said are <a href="https://www.pressdemocrat.com/article/news/constant-lockdown-sonoma-county-jail-detainees-confined-to-cells-23-hour/">tantamount to solitary confinement</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And even non-activists who simply point out the <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23738600/un-fao-meat-dairy-livestock-emissions-methane-climate-change">climate</a>, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/362271/factory-farming-climate-movement-public-health-pandemics">public health</a>, and <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/363550/factory-farming-human-progress-sustainable-food-movement">moral ills</a> of factory farming and animal abuse are accused of being radical, or wanting to take people’s burgers away. Just as Elphaba is made fun of after she stands up for Doctor Dillamond when he mispronounces Galinda’s name, those who question the cruelty of animals and its consequences are often ridiculed and socially alienated for speaking out against the status quo.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like Doctor Dillamond, Dulcibear, and the flying monkeys in <em>Wicked, </em>animals in real life are <a href="https://sentientmedia.org/what-do-animals-and-insects-feel/">sentient beings</a>, according to a growing body of research. Like humans, studies show that <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/animals/article/animals-science-medical-pain">animals feel pain</a> and they experience <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/magazine/article/what-are-animals-thinking-feature">joy</a>. And in <em>Wicked</em>, most of Elphaba’s classmates seem to ignore the treatment of animals in Ozian society, even Galinda who (often superficially) seeks to do good. It’s not too different from how our real world interacts with animal welfare — largely, our society accepts the subjugation of animals, even if it involves large-scale cruelty. Perhaps this helps explain part of why the animal rights activism portions of the film so often get left out of the conversation: Animals being confined and stripped of autonomy is considered normal in our reality.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The second installment of <em>Wicked </em>is scheduled to hit theaters in 2025. While the first part gave <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/386247/wicked-2024-movie-novel-ending-explained-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo">more attention to Elphaba’s radicalization</a> through animal rights than did the Broadway musical, it still treats it with a lighter touch than did Maguire’s <em>Wicked</em> novel, allowing all the (very) catchy songs and sweet depictions of unexpected friendship to hit viewers harder than the animal rights message. How much of <em>Wicked: Part Two</em> will focus on animal rights is not entirely clear — but it certainly would be much more interesting to see the movie attempt to better grapple with animal rights than its predecessor.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Mandy Nguyen</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Should we put pig organs in humans? We asked an ethicist.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/388544/pig-organ-transplants-xenotransplantation-ethics-consent" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388544</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:47:12-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-30T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Animal Welfare" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Unexplainable" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2022, surgeons transplanted the first genetically engineered pig heart into a human. Fifty-seven-year-old  David Bennett, a patient with heart failure, survived almost two months with a pig heart beating in his chest, one of five people who have received pig organs as a part of an experimental procedure called xenotransplantation — the transplanting of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="Cloned piglets created by the company PPL Therapeutics for use in organ transplants. | PPL Therapeutics via BWP Media/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="PPL Therapeutics via BWP Media/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-689546.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Cloned piglets created by the company PPL Therapeutics for use in organ transplants. | PPL Therapeutics via BWP Media/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2022, surgeons <a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/01/10/1071906223/doctors-transplant-genetically-modified-pig-heart">transplanted</a> the first genetically engineered pig heart into a human. Fifty-seven-year-old  David Bennett, a patient with heart failure, survived almost two months with a pig heart beating in his chest, one of five people who have received pig organs as a part of an experimental procedure called <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24117935/pig-kidney-transplant-mass-general-donation" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/24117935/pig-kidney-transplant-mass-general-donation">xenotransplantation</a> — the transplanting of living cells, tissues, or organs from one species to another.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Some scientists view these <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22738680/pig-kidney-human-transplant" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/22738680/pig-kidney-human-transplant">pig organs transplants</a> as potentially lifesaving for many like Bennett.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the US alone, more than 100,000 people are waiting for an organ transplant, and almost 20 people die every day because they can’t get one in time. But a major challenge remains in making xenotransplantation work: scientists haven’t figured out how to get a human body to accept a pig organ for very long. None of the five patients who received these pig organs have survived beyond two months, though researchers believe they’re making progress toward overcoming rejection and eventually moving to clinical trials.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This push to make pig organs viable for humans also comes with enormous ethical implications — from concerns surrounding the use of humans in an experimental procedure that they’re highly unlikely to survive, to the impacts on animals who are supplying the organs themselves. At first glance, the pursuit can feel like hubris. I wanted to better understand these questions, so I spoke with bioethicist <a href="https://www.upstate.edu/bioethics/faculty-staff/fac_johnson.php">L. Syd Johnson</a>, author of a <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/cambridge-quarterly-of-healthcare-ethics/article/abs/existing-ethical-tensions-in-xenotransplantation/1639750599DBE6E0D4A8E435FED06BC7">2022 paper</a> on the ethics of xenotransplantation, for <a href="https://www.vox.com/unexplainable"><em>Unexplainable</em></a>, a Vox podcast that explores unanswered scientific questions. A portion of our conversation, edited for clarity, is included below. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-spotify wp-block-embed-spotify"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><iframe title="My animal heart" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/episode/0Bsebd2q2npWSsK26LSjNA?utm_source=oembed" width="720" height="152" allowfullscreen allow="clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture;"></iframe></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Mandy Nguyen:</strong><strong> Before you started doing this research, what were your general impressions of xenotransplantation?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>L. Syd Johnson:</strong> My initial impressions of it were, ”Boy, this doesn&#8217;t really sound like something that&#8217;s going to work.” It&#8217;s something that in theory might be possible, but there have actually been experiments in xenotransplantation going back to the 1960s, and some of the first experiments involved hearts from chimpanzees.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the reasons why doctors were looking to get organs from other animals was because there wasn&#8217;t a supply of [human] organs at the time. Transplantation was sort of just starting out and they were just starting to have success with figuring out how to do it, but there was no legal mechanism at that time to obtain organs from humans who had died. So they were looking at animals, which they could kill and take their organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think the first time I ever heard of xenotransplantation involved a case in the 1980s, which was a pretty famous case involving an infant named Baby Fae, who received a baboon heart. She was born with hypoplastic left heart syndrome, which is a fatal condition, and then, as now, it was very difficult to obtain organs that were the right size for an infant.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That was a really famous case where the doctor involved was actually sort of notorious and was criticized for what he had done. And of course, baby Fae also died.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>From those initial experiments that failed, how did we suddenly get to this being done in living people today? What was that jump?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The leap was that we have this relatively new genetic editing technology, CRISPR Cas9, and it has enabled scientists and investigators to perform lots of gene edits on an animal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several decades ago, the US Public Health Service essentially told investigators that it was too dangerous to try to transplant organs from monkeys, baboons, chimpanzees [into humans], because they were so similar to humans and had a lot of viruses that could be transmitted to a human patient through an organ. That took organs from non-human primates off the table.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The effort to use pigs comes about because of the ability to genetically modify those pigs. We are not nearly as closely related to pigs as we are to the nonhuman primates, so the development of CRISPR, the ability to do lots of gene edits on an animal, is what has led to the current optimism on the part of scientists about the possibility that xenotransplantation using organs from pigs might be able to work.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Right. And now to temper that optimism — what do you see are the biggest ethical concerns or potential harms when it comes to the people who get the transplant?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The biggest concern is that we haven&#8217;t figured out how to make this work. It&#8217;s very possible that xenotransplantation will never work, that no animal&#8217;s organs could be made to support life in a human being, that the risk of xeno-zoonotic transmission of viruses from pigs to humans is still a live possibility.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That for me is a major concern. We&#8217;re in the middle of a zoonotic pandemic right now, the Covid pandemic. We are still dealing with another zoonotic pandemic in AIDS, which is a worldwide problem. There is a concern that putting an organ from an animal that has a virus into a human, and that human is immunosuppressed [as organ transplant recipients are], will result in the mutation of a virus that might plausibly be transmitted to other humans, and who knows what the results of that could be.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Right. So in my mind, there are two big buckets of potential harm to people. One is the infectious disease aspect, and one is the danger to the patients themselves and the ethics around informed consent. I&#8217;d love to hear a little bit more about that. What are the concerns there?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The living patients that they have attempted these organ transplants in have been individuals who are quite sick, who are in organ failure, and who are not able to get an organ from a human. So those are all patients who have few good options. Some of them are facing almost certain death if they don&#8217;t get a transplant of some kind. So the worry is that we are making these patients an offer they just can&#8217;t refuse because their alternative is that they are going to die.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You have to be concerned about whether or not they&#8217;re truly providing voluntary informed consent under those circumstances, whether they really understand the risks of xenotransplantation — which so far has never worked and has never actually saved a human life in all the decades of experimentation — and whether or not those patients understand the difference between being part of an experiment and receiving therapeutic treatment. This is something called the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22942217/">therapeutic misconception</a>, where patients believe that being part of an experiment, that experiment is actually intended to benefit them. And we can&#8217;t say that at this point about xenotransplants.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But unfortunately, the patients who have agreed to these transplants have all said in media interviews that it was their last chance at survival, that they really had to do this because they had no other options. And that suggests that they did truly believe that these transplants would save their lives, and that is, unfortunately, a misconception. And unfortunately, all of these patients so far have died.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I&#8217;ve spoken to scientists and ethicists who are working with scientists to try to make sure informed consent is really tight and transparent. Do you think that&#8217;s a possible solution?Is it possible to get informed consent from someone who&#8217;s put in this position?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Of course it&#8217;s possible, and someone might go into this thinking, well, it&#8217;s never worked before and it&#8217;s really a long shot and It&#8217;s probably not going to work for me, but a one in a million chance is better than a zero in a million chance, so I&#8217;m going to take it. We can provide patients with all of the information that they need in order to make an informed choice.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s been lots of research showing that <em>d</em>espite our best efforts, lots of people who are enrolled in clinical trials or enrolled in experimental therapies do still misunderstand what might happen and that the purpose of the experiment is not to benefit them, but to benefit others, to, to acquire more scientific knowledge that will be a benefit to patients in the future.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But I think people are complex and they can understand both of those things at the same time, and still have this hope that this might work for them.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You&#8217;ve done a lot here on animal research and the use of animals as models for humans. How are you thinking about xenotransplantation here?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So two things. One is, there are questions about what&#8217;s happening to the pigs, and the welfare of these pigs. And the other is that we are actually still doing research transplanting monkeys with these pig organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So far the longest that monkeys have been kept alive with a pig organ is two years. There&#8217;s not a lot of information about what happened to that monkey, what that monkey had to undergo in order to get it to survive for that long. Any time we&#8217;re talking about experimenting on animals, there are welfare concerns about what happens to those animals and how we&#8217;re using them. But there&#8217;s also the fact that having a monkey living in a laboratory in a cage where we can do just about anything we want to that monkey is very different from the circumstances in which human patients exist.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A human patient doesn&#8217;t want to spend the rest of their life in a hospital bed. They want to be able to go home and, and go on with their lives. So we&#8217;re not replicating the conditions of a human life or a human existence in a laboratory animal. So I have concerns that what we&#8217;re doing with those monkeys actually isn&#8217;t really telling us anything very useful about whether or not this will work in humans and whether it will provide the kinds of benefits that we&#8217;re hoping it would provide to humans.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So one question is whether what we are doing with other animals is telling us anything useful about long-term survival for humans with pig organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the pigs themselves, there are a few concerns here. One is what the effects of the genetic modifications are on those pigs, on their health, on their survival, and on their wellbeing. Of course, those pigs are not actually created to survive. We are creating them to produce organs so that they can be killed and those organs can be used in humans.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">With gene editing, we&#8217;re trying to sand off the edges of pig organs to force it to fit into a human and to work in a human. So what are we doing to the pigs under those circumstances? What are the conditions under which they are bred or cloned and raised? Much of it requires them to stay in unnatural environments in isolation, with multiple invasive medical procedures and tests, and that&#8217;s before they&#8217;re killed for their organs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are animals who would not exist at all, except for our human intervention. And I think we&#8217;re treating them just for the purpose of taking them apart to provide spare parts for humans. They don&#8217;t see the sky. They&#8217;re not going to touch grass. And we are attempting to undo 80 million years of evolutionary divergence&nbsp; in this way that involves the radical exploitation of an animal that we&#8217;ve created and built for a purpose. I think we really do need to reflect on what we&#8217;re doing there and on the harms that we&#8217;re causing to living, conscious, intelligent creatures, in part so that a handful of biotech companies can profit from their existence.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>I was recently reading how <a href="https://apnews.com/article/meat-allergy-lone-star-tick-pig-alphagal-edf82b6c1928450da1373ea61e6a3a44">GalSafe pigs</a>, a kind of pig being used for xenotransplantation research, were recently <a href="https://apnews.com/article/meat-allergy-lone-star-tick-pig-alphagal-edf82b6c1928450da1373ea61e6a3a44">FDA-approved</a> for both consumption and therapeutic uses. I think there&#8217;s something really strange about the idea that someone could get a pig heart from this pig and also be eating the same pig. It&#8217;s very bizarre.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That does raise some weird issues. That I am now part pig, I have this heart that I got from a pig and it saved my life, so that I could go eat parts of that pig&#8217;s relatives.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Say we get into a future where xenotransplantation works, it becomes common. Is there a concern that we&#8217;re just replicating some of the environmental harm of, say, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/364288/how-factory-farming-ends-animal-rights-vegans-climate-ethics">factory farming</a>?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This would absolutely be factory farming. These would be animals grown and bred and raised in a facility. And you presumably have a fairly resource-intensive facility, even perhaps beyond what we see currently with pig farms.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These are pigs that are being grown and created and controlled by these private biotech companies with this hope that we might actually have on-demand organs for everyone who needs one at some point in the future. But we are talking about expanding the footprint of factory farming — expanding the use of resources to grow these animals. And we would be talking about growing perhaps millions of these animals rather than however many we are currently growing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>It has been really interesting to learn how much funding is coming from these biotech companies into all this research. Are there any other concerns around that that you have?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is sort of what biotech companies do. They spend a lot of money and invest it in products that are speculative, that may or may not work, that may or may not improve human life for people in general. And part of my concern is that they are currently in control of what is being done experimentally.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">They create the pigs, they create the organs, and they are paying investigators at academic research hospitals to do these experiments on their patients. You can&#8217;t just find patients on the street —&nbsp; you have to access them through doctors who have patients who are in dire straits and who don&#8217;t have good options So what we have now is this kind of private enterprise with lots of hype around it, but not enough attention, I think, to the profit motive behind this and how much that is driving research in xenotransplantation.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Do you think we&#8217;re moving too fast here? What needs to be done to be able to get to a point when it feels safe to do clinical trials? Or do you think that&#8217;s not really possible?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I think we&#8217;re not close to that yet. But I also think it&#8217;s important for us to think about what else we might be doing as an alternative to xenotransplantation. In some sense, xenotransplantation seems like the least likely technology to be used out of the gate as the solution to this problem.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We have other options that people are also working on, things like being able to grow a human organ from the cells of the actual recipient, which would be an organ that is made from that person’s own cells where they wouldn&#8217;t face problems of rejection. There is potential for therapeutics that would actually help address organ failure so that the patient doesn&#8217;t get to the point where they need an organ transplant.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are opportunity costs in terms of the time and the effort and the resources that are being put into xenotransplantation, which, if it doesn&#8217;t work, is a lot of money and a lot of time and effort down the drain. There are other possibilities that we could be pouring more resources into that don&#8217;t require us to overcome 80 million years of evolutionary divergence between humans and pigs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">A really important option, one of the least glamorous ones, is what else could we be doing to prevent organ failure in the first place — because an organ transplant, whether that organ comes from an animal or comes from another human, is not a quick, easy fix. You&#8217;re looking at a patient who has a lifetime of immunosuppressive therapy ahead of them. There&#8217;s always going to be the potential for the rejection or the failure of that transplant for that individual where they may need another transplant somewhere down the line. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the major causes of kidney failure is diabetes, and another one is hypertension. And those are both illnesses that we have treatments for if we provided them to the people who actually need them. And so instead of pouring however many billions of dollars are being poured into xenotransplantation research, what if we put that money somewhere else where we might actually be able to prevent organ failure in the first place? That would truly benefit lots and lots of patients.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Wicked hits Instagram and TikTok, with more than a little help from fans ]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/388703/wicked-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-tiktok-instagram" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388703</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:47:02-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-29T07:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a code of conduct for the multiplex experience, deliberately broadcast right before a movie: When the lights start to dim, we turn off our phones and end any side discussions. However, if dispatches of Wicked screenings around the country are any indication, this code isn’t being followed.&#160; In the few days since the highly [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Cast members of the Wicked movie stand onstage at a screening." data-caption="John M. Chu, Cynthia Erivo, Ariana Grande, Kristin Chenoweth, and Marc E. Platt at a cast and filmmakers screening of Wicked on October 28, 2024. | Kevin Mazur/Getty Images for Universal Pictures" data-portal-copyright="Kevin Mazur/Getty Images for Universal Pictures" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-2181644613.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>John M. Chu, Cynthia Erivo, Ariana Grande, Kristin Chenoweth, and Marc E. Platt at a cast and filmmakers screening of Wicked on October 28, 2024. | Kevin Mazur/Getty Images for Universal Pictures</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a code of conduct for the multiplex experience, deliberately broadcast right before a movie: When the lights start to dim, we turn off our phones and end any side discussions. However, if dispatches of <em>Wicked</em> screenings around the country are any indication, this code isn’t being followed.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the few days since the highly anticipated musical movie <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/386247/wicked-2024-movie-novel-ending-explained-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo"><em>Wicked</em></a> arrived in theaters, it’s been difficult to scroll through social media without seeing photos — if not entire scenes —&nbsp;of the film taken from patrons’ phones. In-theater recordings of <em>Wicked</em>’s signature number “Defying Gravity” are all over TikTok. <a href="https://x.com/nat_dwbua_/status/1860541618060943677">One X<em> </em>user</a> went viral for asking fans to post photos they had snapped during the movie. This immediately ignited a conversation among film critics and cinephiles about a lack of theater etiquette in the general public. But is it totally their fault?&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s safe to say that the film marketing tactics of the past few years have taught people how to show up to movies — ready to whip out their phones. That’s not to mention the advent of streaming, plus the years spent mostly inside during the pandemic, that have certainly played a role in a lack of movie-going etiquette.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23789864/barbenheimer-barbieheimer-barbie-oppenheimer-release-memes-double-feature">Barbenheimer</a>, movies aren’t just meant to be shared with a room full of people but with others on social media. The endless merch and product tie-ins that come with IP films, as well as more organic efforts to dress up for screenings, have made the extremely mundane experience of sitting in a dark room for a couple of hours &#8220;content.&#8221; But what happens to moviegoing when it becomes all about sharing?&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Moviegoing for the ’gram</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In an effort to recoup losses from the pandemic, there have been more and more incentives for people to get off their couches and back into movie theaters. These innovations certainly enhanced the moviegoing experience beyond snacking on popcorn, ultimately making it a lot more shareable and post-worthy online. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since 2019, when AMC offered <a href="https://www.marketingbrew.com/stories/2024/11/22/how-the-specialty-popcorn-bucket-is-helping-build-out-the-theater-experience">specially designed R2-D2 popcorn buckets</a> to coincide with the release of <em>Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker</em>, novelty items have made a huge comeback. Now, they’re an expected bonus when buying tickets for the year’s biggest releases. Over the past few years, AMC has sold uniquely designed buckets and cups for buzzy movies like <em>The Mario Bros. Movie</em>, <em>Renaissance: A Film By Beyoncé</em>, and <em>Dune: Part Two</em>. The last film’s elaborately designed bucket — with an opening resembling the mouth of a sandworm — was so attention-grabbing that it got its own parody song on an episode of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rl_Xhvgkxrk"><em>Saturday Night Live</em></a>.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The popcorn bucket for ‘DUNE 2’.<br><br>(via: <a href="https://twitter.com/3CFilmss?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@3CFilmss</a>) <a href="https://t.co/FzNZjGJiTC">pic.twitter.com/FzNZjGJiTC</a></p>&mdash; DiscussingFilm (@DiscussingFilm) <a href="https://twitter.com/DiscussingFilm/status/1750669926816182408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 26, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/362928/how-to-see-twisters-4dx-perfect-way-imax-rpx-explained">4Dx experience</a> is another in-theater development that patrons can’t stop posting about. The immersive format, involving motion seats and practical effects, gained a lot of word-of-mouth popularity this year for movies like <em>Madame Web</em>, <em>Twisters</em>, and <em>Deadpool and Wolverine. </em>Much of this word-of-mouth, though, has occurred online, particularly on TikTok where <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@sharmedlife/video/7393729832238042398?q=4dx%20&amp;t=1732734281770">influencers</a> and <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@allyb1226/video/7400158266266815774?q=4dx%20&amp;t=1732734281770">regular</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@yourboymoyo/video/7238331364293102874?q=4dx%20&amp;t=1732734281770">customers</a> film themselves being thrust around and sprayed with water while the movie’s playing.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Outside of theaters, studios are <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/movie-marketing-spends-summer-films-1235142253/">investing more and more money</a> into elaborate marketing campaigns for their buzziest movies, the most notable cases being the 2023 hit <em>Barbie</em> and this year’s <em>Wicked.</em> This advertising has largely manifested in endless brand collaborations, from <a href="https://pressroom.lexus.com/drive-the-magic-lexus-unveils-a-wicked-pair-of-rides/">luxury cars</a> to <a href="https://www.crocs.com/c/cast-of-characters/wicked?gclid=Cj0KCQiAgJa6BhCOARIsAMiL7V9r16y4M6AfvJSTaWB0mYsiMwfQ2-GipciKFAxbgly9P16pZr-9VrQaAoE-EALw_wcB&amp;adid=ppc_google_us_brand_wicked_searchgooglebrandcollections_x_x_x&amp;ef_id=Cj0KCQiAgJa6BhCOARIsAMiL7V9r16y4M6AfvJSTaWB0mYsiMwfQ2-GipciKFAxbgly9P16pZr-9VrQaAoE-EALw_wcB:G:s&amp;s_kwcid=AL!4035!3!717308216836!e!!g!!wicked%20crocs&amp;gad_source=1">Crocs</a>, all designed to&nbsp;be collected and shared on social media with the movie’s hashtag. The ubiquity of the marketing suggests that if you aren’t seeing these movies in theaters, you’re missing out on a huge monocultural moment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Studios have also turned to influencers to provide <a href="https://www.thewrap.com/film-critics-social-media-influencers-screenings-publicity/">early reactions to movies</a>. Sometimes, these popular X and TikTok users are invited to advance screenings alongside journalists. In more and more cases —&nbsp;like with <em>Gladiator II</em> and <em>Wicked — </em>they’re given earlier access to these movies than some critics.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid all of these orchestrated marketing movies, it seems as though customers are finding unique ways to enhance the moviegoing experience for themselves. For example, the trend of “themed dressing” feels like an earnest expression of movie fan culture with organic roots. In the past, this trend has been reserved for movies associated with “nerd culture,&#8221; like <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Harry Potter</em>. But <a href="https://www.gq.com/gallery/barbie-oppenheimer-street-style-photos">“Barbenheimer”</a><em> </em>made this activity more of an instinctual habit for the average moviegoer. Without the instruction of a studio, everyone got the memo to wear pink to their screenings of <em>Barbie</em> and, on a lesser scale, black to see <em>Oppenheimer</em>. Since then, marketers have clearly taken notice. This seemed evident in a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/itendswithusmovie/reel/C-dIFmsPeWH/?hl=en">promotional video</a> Blake Lively filmed earlier this year for the domestic abuse movie <em><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366523/blake-lively-drama-justin-baldoni-it-ends-with-us-hoover-movie-feud">It Ends With Us</a></em>, where she urged ticket-buyers to “wear their florals” in theme with the movie’s florist protagonist. The same phenomenon is occurring at <em>Wicked</em> showings, where fans are arriving in pink or green clothes, and even full-on green face paint to imitate the main character Elphaba.&nbsp;If fans weren’t planning on dressing up themselves, the pink-and-green marketing certainly implied that it was a crucial part of the theater experience.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What happens to a communal space when it’s all about content?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since <em>Wicked</em>’s premiere, moviegoers have been posting their reactions to the film — along with their themed outfits —  on TikTok and X, often directly from the theater. One <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@fredasquith/video/7440889417750809888?q=me%20before%20wicked&amp;t=1732646647387">trend</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@bacobell_/video/7440845864546929951?q=me%20before%20wicked&amp;t=1732646647387">that’s</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@yourstrulybusie/video/7440330399710072094?q=me%20before%20wicked&amp;t=1732646647387">proved</a> <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@gia.mariano/video/7440953771108076846?q=me%20before%20wicked&amp;t=1732646647387">popular</a> is a format where a user posts themselves before the movie starts with a hard cut to their emotional reaction during the credits or outside of the theater. In other cases, people have <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@imogenhorton/video/7441177027815738656?q=reactions%20during%20wicked&amp;t=1732730139853">filmed themselves</a> or the <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@songsbyralph/video/7441433639751077175?q=reactions%20to%20wicked&amp;t=1732730084783">person next to them</a> reacting to the movie while they’re watching it. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of these emotional responses are genuine. But the urge to self-broadcast in the middle of a film speaks to a misunderstanding or, in some cases,&nbsp;complete disregard for the sanctity of movie theaters. In its worst interpretation, it shows a lack of respect for other people’s in-theater experiences.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-tiktok wp-block-embed-tiktok"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="tiktok-embed" cite="https://www.tiktok.com/@imogenhorton/video/7441177027815738656" data-video-id="7441177027815738656" data-embed-from="oembed"> <section> <a target="_blank" title="@imogenhorton" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@imogenhorton?refer=embed">@imogenhorton</a> <p>When I tell you my whole seat was shaking I was sobbing THAT much 😭😭😭😭😭😭😭😭 (I did already pre warn the couple sitting next to me at the beginning that I would cry A LOT) 😂😂😂 genuinely the best thing I’ve ever watched in my life, I don’t even know where to begin. From the cast, the vocals, the choreography, the cinematography, the connections on screen, every single member of the ensemble and chorus, the effects, the acting, the nuances, the EVERYTHING. I am blown away, I can’t stop crying just thinking about it and I’m not even ashamed to say that. Elphaba is such an incredible character than I think so many of us could actually benefit from just absorbing even an inch of her strength, her moral compass, her kindness and the fact she doesn’t care about fitting in, she does what she thinks is RIGHT. I’m an emotional deep person and I don’t care if anyone else doesn’t like it, I LOVE IT 🙌🏽❤️<a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp?refer=embed">#fyp</a> <a title="wicked" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/wicked?refer=embed">#wicked</a> </p> <a target="_blank" title="♬ original sound - Imogen Horton" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/original-sound-7441177117520022305?refer=embed">♬ original sound &#8211; Imogen Horton</a> </section> </blockquote> 
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This phenomenon has become a problem outside of the theater, too. In the case of <em>Wicked</em>, many users have posted photos of the film, including spoilers or pivotal scenes.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Undoubtedly, studios’ recent embrace of <a href="https://www.screendaily.com/features/how-social-media-influencers-are-transforming-film-marketing/5187462.article">influencers as marketers</a> has something to do with this. In an article for <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/movie-marketing-spends-summer-films-1235142253/">the Hollywood Reporter</a>, writer Pamela McClintock said that, as “advertising on TV is more complicated and expensive,” studios have had to explore different promotional routes including “TikTok, Snapchat, Instagram, YouTube and other platforms.” Likewise, influencers are now&nbsp;appearing at press junkets, activations, and other events, implying that moviegoing is also about engagement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Entertainment reporter Raven Brunner says that screenings have contributed to the movie-posting problem, given that influencers and even critics are encouraged to take photos and post them. “When you go to an early screening, they have that customized banner before the movie starts that you&#8217;re supposed to take photos of,” she says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s hard not to draw a line from the posts that circulate after an advanced screening — whether it’s from a film account or a <a href="https://people.com/ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-transform-kim-kardashian-home-wicked-magical-screening-party-8732640">celebrity</a> — to the average moviegoer snapping photos during <em>Wicked</em>. Comedian and writer Josh Gondelman thinks this problem exposes a tendency for moviegoers to view themselves as “creators” first. As a result, they end up prioritizing what they share with others over their own personal consumption.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There are so many ways to be like, ‘hey, check me out. I&#8217;m a person in the world engaging with culture,’ which I think is pleasant,” he says. “But you can do it without making everyone else&#8217;s experience in the theater secondary to your followers&#8217; later.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, he doesn’t think all movie-posting comes from a shallow, attention-seeking place.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I always try to be understanding and appreciative of people who want to do, like, a long vlog response to something and just want to share their thoughts on art,” he says.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, there are basic rules of behaving in public that people, particularly in a younger, more online generation, are <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23835782/concert-attack-cardi-b-pink-ashes-movie-theater">struggling with</a>. The past few years since the pandemic spent largely inside watching movies on streamers presumably haven’t helped.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At a bare minimum, these inescapable spoilers and leaked scenes show an enthusiasm around movies (or at least certain titles). Maybe there’s hope that, in a world where young people have been influenced to see movies again, they can also be influenced into turning off their phones.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Lavanya Ramanathan</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Izzie Ramirez</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Friday is a trap]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/money/388152/black-friday-sales-bad-consumer-behavior-retailers-tariffs" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388152</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T22:46:46-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-29T06:45:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Consumerism" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the 1980s, Black Friday has signified the kickoff to the holiday shopping season. Stores offered almost-impossible “doorbuster” deals on TVs and hand blenders, shoppers rose before dawn to wait in line to get them, violence ensued, and the tinsel-covered period when retailers finally operated “in the black” began in earnest.  It’s probably for the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Black Friday sale at a Macy’s store advertising 50 percent off original price" data-caption="A customer visits the store during early morning Black Friday sales in 2023 at Macy’s Herald Square in New York. | Kena Betancur/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Kena Betancur/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-1800559734-1.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A customer visits the store during early morning Black Friday sales in 2023 at Macy’s Herald Square in New York. | Kena Betancur/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Since <a href="https://wwd.com/feature/why-is-it-called-black-friday-history-1235941382/">the 1980s</a>, Black Friday has signified the kickoff to the holiday shopping season. Stores offered almost-impossible “doorbuster” deals on TVs and hand blenders, shoppers rose before dawn to wait in line to get them, <a href="https://nypost.com/article/black-fridays-most-gruesome-injuries-and-deaths-through-the-years/">violence ensued</a>, and the tinsel-covered period when retailers finally operated “in the black” began in earnest. <br><br>It’s probably for the best, then, that <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/walmarts-black-friday-crowds-chaos-over-employees-couldnt-be-happier-2023-11">Black Friday is not what it was even 20 years ago</a>. A movement to recognize its toll on retail workers eventually <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2021/11/29/22808238/black-friday-2021-pandemic-shopping">convinced several stores to close on Thanksgiving</a> so workers could be with their families, instead of stocking for the busy day ahead. Holiday shopping <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2023/11/22/online-shopping-has-grown-rapidly-in-u-s-but-most-sales-are-still-in-stores/">has continued to move online</a>. And the thrill of a deep, one-day discount has morphed into a numbing, month-long thrum of flash sales, Cyber Monday specials, and member appreciation events.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect">Future Perfect</a> deputy editor Izzie Ramirez has reported extensively on the state of American consumerism, from our habit of <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/370626/consumerism-circular-economy-single-use-recycling-landfill-garbage">buying, using, and throwing away literal tons of stuff</a> each year, to how the <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23529587/consumer-goods-quality-fast-fashion-technology">quality of the things we’re purchasing — from appliances to undergarments — is progressively getting worse</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I caught up with her to talk about why Americans’ shopping habits have transformed, what the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-tariffs-canada-mexico-china-59239afe12033ca99c65c7a2be0e4f0d">threat of high tariffs</a> might mean for big-ticket goods, and how sales bonanzas like Black Friday are part of a larger effort by retailers to keep us shopping, to our own detriment, and the planet’s. This conversation has been edited for clarity and length.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Lavanya Ramanathan: So, the quality of our stuff is worse now. Tell me a bit about that, as we stare down a period when Americans will be buying a ton. </strong><br><br><strong>Izzie Ramirez: </strong>I would like to preface this by saying everyone thinks that I&#8217;m anti-shopping, and it&#8217;s not that I&#8217;m anti-shopping; I actually love shopping. Materials are fun, materialism is fun, except for when it&#8217;s not. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I started <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/23529587/consumer-goods-quality-fast-fashion-technology">writing about it </a> because I came across a problem, and the problem was that my brand-new bra absolutely sucked. Shouldn&#8217;t new things be better? Isn&#8217;t this, like, the whole promise of capitalism, in a way? </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I really wanted to get a mass-production understanding of what&#8217;s going on, and talk a little bit about the decline of repairability, and what we can do about it. Because I do think that people want to buy things that make them happy, that last and fit into their lives. And it sucks when you invest your money and you don&#8217;t get your money&#8217;s investment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It&#8217;s less that companies want to be making worse-quality goods. In the case of my bra, it&#8217;s more that for the cost of producing something like my bra, you can&#8217;t do the same thing for the same amount of money. Something has to give, and it&#8217;s going to either be labor or the quality of the material, and it&#8217;s usually a little bit of both. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Knowing all of that, what is a good way to approach something like Black Friday? There are all sorts of deals, like TVs for $50. With some of these, is it just throwing good money after bad? Is there actually a way for the consumer to be a winner?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m going to be a hypocrite with this. I usually think Black Friday is bad, <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy/386042/trump-tariffs-economy-global-trade">but if Trump does enact tariffs</a>, then maybe Black Friday might be good for larger purchases, such as washing machines, dishwashers, and other major appliances, because tariffs would create conditions for those globalized objects, where you need parts from a billion different places, to become way, way, way more expensive. And if they don&#8217;t become more expensive, those are going to be the very objects that become way worse, very, very rapidly.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><br>That’s bad advice for most circumstances. There is a lot of science and psychology behind buying things. On Black Friday, you feel like you don&#8217;t have time. It is entirely a lie, because they run the same sales regularly. If you know anything about Black Friday, they do the same sales every year. It&#8217;s not like that sale is never going to happen again. Or the Sephora sale. It really grinds my gears when I see people posting Sephora hauls, like they&#8217;re never gonna do the members sale again. They do, two or three times a year. It&#8217;s the scarcity mindset.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/GettyImages-1801104722.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,8.1888422166698,100,83.62231556666" alt="Shoppers inside a busy mall on Black Friday" title="Shoppers inside a busy mall on Black Friday" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Shoppers flooded the Polaris Fashion Place mall in Columbus, Ohio, on Black Friday in 2023." data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You have also written about hauls. We </strong><strong><em>are</em></strong><strong> shopping differently now. We shop online. It&#8217;s become that much easier to get things from all over the world. If I had to guess, I’d say there are a lot more brands, too — direct-to-consumer sellers of things like jewelry. What is happening to shopping itself?</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/even-better/2023/11/14/23955673/fast-fashion-shein-hauls-environment-human-rights-violations">Hauls</a> are when people buy 10 or 15 or 20 different items in one go, and usually parade them around on social media. They&#8217;re buying things from places like Amazon, Temu, Shein, Abercrombie &amp; Fitch. The thing about haul culture is that it also creates that mindset around scarcity, like, “Oh, you need this.” It normalizes mass consumption, and buying a lot all at once and regularly, and that it is a regular practice to spend that much money.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"> And if you&#8217;re not spending that much money, then you&#8217;re going to be spending at places like Shein that have $1 T-shirts, and that normalizes a dangerously low price for workers and the planet.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>A lot of the things that you&#8217;re describing feel like new behaviors. There&#8217;s also a thing happening in our shopping ecosystem, and in our consumer culture, around demand for the new — for newness at all times.</strong></p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yeah, and I think so much of that is driven by that normalization of excitement around buying — dopamine shopping, wanting to feel something. So much of it is social media, and so much of it is the scale of globalization and all of these new players that are in the market. It’s just a whole other level of consumer deception, too — this false sense of urgency from companies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes, there is the demand, but it is also companies knowing that they could take advantage of us like this. It’s like ouroboros, the snake that’s eating itself. It&#8217;s never going to end if we don&#8217;t make a conscious choice of saying no.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Miranda Kennedy</name>
			</author>
			
			<author>
				<name>Noel King</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The author of the seminal book about loneliness explains what we’re getting wrong]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/today-explained-podcast/388069/robert-putnam-bowling-alone-loneliness-epidemic" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388069</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:44:14-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-29T06:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Family" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Friendship" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Mental Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Podcasts" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Relationships" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained podcast" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the holiday season upon us, it’s important to grapple with the loneliness many Americans face every day. It’s often more intensely felt in the times when you are expected to be surrounded by the warm embrace of family and friends. And, increasingly, that warm embrace isn’t happening. Americans spend more time at home — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Two men in suits face each other and smile in front of a gold curtain and an American flag; the man on the right grips the other’s arm." data-caption="Political scientist and professor Robert Putnam is awarded the 2012 National Humanities Medal by President Barack Obama during a ceremony in the East Room of the White House on July 10, 2013, in Washington, DC. | Pete Marovich/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Pete Marovich/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-173232773.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Political scientist and professor Robert Putnam is awarded the 2012 National Humanities Medal by President Barack Obama during a ceremony in the East Room of the White House on July 10, 2013, in Washington, DC. | Pete Marovich/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">With the holiday season upon us, it’s important to grapple with the loneliness many Americans face every day. It’s often more intensely felt in the times when you are expected to be surrounded by the warm embrace of family and friends. And, increasingly, that warm embrace isn’t happening. Americans spend more time at home — alone — than they did 20 years ago, according to a <a href="https://sociologicalscience.com/articles-v11-20-553/">recent analysis </a>of federal data. The numbers went up dramatically during the pandemic and never came back down.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Across the board, Americans have fallen away from activities that involve or require community. Religious service attendance is down dramatically. Two decades ago, over 40 percent of US adults attended religious services every week or nearly every week. Now, just 30 percent of Americans say the same, <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/642548/church-attendance-declined-religious-groups.aspx">according to Gallup polling</a>. Other metrics of civic engagement have dropped off too: According to <a href="https://americorps.gov/about/our-impact/volunteering-civic-life">one AmeriCorps study</a>, just 20 percent of Gen Z volunteer their time to help others, compared to almost 30 percent of Gen X.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Loneliness has been on the steady march for many decades, and one man has been watching its advance: <a href="https://www.hks.harvard.edu/faculty/robert-d-putnam">Robert Putnam</a>, a public policy professor at Harvard University and the author of 15 books, including the 2001 bestseller <a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/Bowling-Alone-Revised-and-Updated/Robert-D-Putnam/9780743219037"><em>Bowling Alone: The Collapse and Revival of American Community</em></a>. The book was based on a simple premise: Once, Americans joined bowling leagues. Now, they are going bowling by themselves. In the book, Putnam extends the metaphor to speak to all our social connections, saying that their drop-off speaks to the decline of our democracy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This half-century of civic decline is charted in a documentary about Putnam’s life that came out in 2023, called <a href="https://www.joinordiefilm.com/"><em>Join or Die</em></a>. We wanted to hear more about the importance of a culture that embraces community activities, so we reached out to the man who inspired a thousand clubs himself.&nbsp;Noel King spoke with Putnam — though he prefers to be called Bob — for <em>Today, Explained</em> to discuss if “bowling alone” has grown even more acute, the role technology plays, and how to reverse the trend. Below is an excerpt of their conversation, edited for length and clarity. There’s much more in the full podcast, so listen to <em>Today, Explained</em> on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/today-explained/id1346207297">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3pXx5SXzXwJxnf4A5pWN2A">Spotify</a>, or <a href="https://www.iheart.com/podcast/1319-today-explained-87205166/">wherever you get podcasts</a>.</p>

<iframe frameBorder="0" height="200" src="https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=VMP8778198437" width="100%"></iframe>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Volunteering is good for the person who is doing the volunteering, right? Is that a reason to volunteer?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There&#8217;s a lot of evidence that if you&#8217;re volunteering to help somebody else, you&#8217;re probably getting more benefits out of it than they are, because there are all sorts of physiological changes. People after volunteering are happier than if you hadn&#8217;t volunteered. It&#8217;s one reason to volunteer. You don&#8217;t have to choose between the reasons. In writing the book <em>Bowling Alone</em>, I talked about the consequences of our connections with other people, both our actual in-person connections and our connections through political organizations. And that, as a community in which people are more connected with one another, the whole community functions better, not just the two people involved in a given exchange.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Let me give an example from education. If I, as a parent, get involved in my child&#8217;s school, I join the PTA or I volunteer in the classroom, that turns out to be good for my child. But the astonishing thing is my getting involved has even more effect on the success and the happiness of other kids in the school. In the book <em>Bowling Alone</em>, which was written [about] 25 years ago, I talked about the decline in these connections, decline in what I called social capital. And I said, “Gosh, if this continues, it&#8217;s going to be bad for American democracy. You know, we&#8217;re going to have more polarized politics,” and so on. And the reason that there&#8217;s now a little bit of a new wave of interest in my work is that I turned out to be right. Even more right than I thought. If you&#8217;ve not noticed, American politics is in a pickle right now, and the fundamental reason for that is because for the last 30 or 40 years, we as a country have become less and less connected with one another — in my jargon, with less and less social capital.&nbsp;</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Does the data bear it out? Because it feels like we&#8217;re more isolated now, and it felt that way when you wrote <em>Bowling Alone</em> 25 years ago. Is it true?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yes. Once upon a time there was a debate, there was a thought that maybe we don&#8217;t actually have to be in somebody&#8217;s presence. That we could see them on Zoom or social media would be just as good as actual social connections. For quite a while, the evidence has been that Facebook is not as good as bowling leagues. That is, you don&#8217;t get the same benefit from connecting with people via social media as you do from actually connecting with them face to face. That&#8217;s what <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0747563203000402">the evidence has shown</a>. I can tell you when public opinion on that changed. It was just about November 25th of 2020, at the height of the pandemic, and everybody in America realized that hugging Grandma was not the same thing as actually seeing Grandma over Zoom. And it isn&#8217;t.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People who might otherwise not leave the house very much join Reddit communities; people have WhatsApp chat groups with their relatives in other countries. I text my 14-year-old niece, who I don&#8217;t get to see very often. I hear you saying the technology has not been good for us and I want to make sure that we’re sure about that.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I&#8217;m not saying that electronic connections are of no use to us. I&#8217;ve got lots of grandchildren and I&#8217;m texting with them or emailing with them literally every day. I&#8217;m not saying that social media or other forms of electronic connection are literally no good, I am saying they&#8217;re not as good as face-to-face ties.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So if, currently, we’re at a low point for social connection, what brought us here?</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the beginning of the 20th century, around about 1900, America was very polarized politically. Our politics were tribal. We were very unequal. There was economically a big gap between the rich, who were living on the Upper East Side of New York, and the huddled masses, the poor immigrants on the Lower East Side of Manhattan. We were very socially disconnected. We&#8217;d had connections back on the farm, where we knew other people, whether the farm was in Iowa or in southern Italy, but we&#8217;d all moved. There had been a huge movement from the rural areas to the cities, and we did not know our new neighbors, and so we were very socially isolated. And actually, we were culturally very self-centered. We were an “I society” rather than a “we society.” We didn&#8217;t think of ourselves as having a lot in common. And then beginning about 1910 — none of these things are super exact — but about 1910, all of those things began to change and they moved in a different, better direction for a half-century or more. So from roughly 1910 to roughly 1965 or 1970, every year we became less polarized politically, less socially isolated, less unequal, or more equal, and more of a “we” society.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So we went from being an “I” society around 1900 to being a “we” society around, roughly speaking, 1965. The movements of the 1960s — which you no doubt you don&#8217;t remember, [but] I do remember that period — that was the culmination of a half-century long increase in political participation, increase in connecting with other people, increase in cooperation across party lines, increase in equality. And I have to say, this is just about the time when I personally began to vote. So you may think I personally brought these problems on America in the middle ’60s. All those lines turned and for the next half-century, up to now, every year we got more socially isolated, more politically disconnected, more unequal. We lost it all.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Could it work to sell joining clubs, volunteering, in-person engagement as, “This will make you feel good, I promise”? And the side effect is that it&#8217;s good for society, it’s good for democracy — but if you&#8217;re going to do it, do it for yourself? Think of it as a kind of self-care.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The danger to your life expectancy from social isolation is <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-social-connection-advisory.pdf">as big a risk factor for premature death </a>as smoking. If you did smoke and you had a choice, should you smoke? Or should you join a club? By all means, join the club! There are huge personal benefits from connecting with other people, including joining. The most important reason is actually that you should connect with other people. You will add years to your life expectancy.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Noel King</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You&#8217;re going to live longer. And also you&#8217;re going to save American society.</p>

<h4 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Robert Putnam</h4>

<p class="has-text-align-none">By the way, you&#8217;re also going to save American democracy. That&#8217;s right.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[A new JonBenét doc posits the Ramseys didn’t do it. But what about the ransom note?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/388794/jon-benet-ransom-note-full-text-theories" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388794</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:44:09-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-28T08:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="True crime" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to a new Netflix docuseries from true crime mainstay Joe Berlinger, audiences across the nation are asking a question true crime fans never really let go of. The new series, Cold Case: Who Killed JonBenét Ramsey, doesn’t actually spend all that many of its three hour-long episodes speculating about its title question. Instead, it [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Patsy Ramsey holding up a reward sign as John Ramsey hits next to her with his head turned toward her" data-caption="Patsy Ramsey holds up a reward sign on May 1, 1997, for information leading to the arrest of their daughter’s murderer. Their 6-year-old, JonBenét, was found dead on Christmas night 1996. | Helen H. Richardson/The Denver Post via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Helen H. Richardson/The Denver Post via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-186118411.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Patsy Ramsey holds up a reward sign on May 1, 1997, for information leading to the arrest of their daughter’s murderer. Their 6-year-old, JonBenét, was found dead on Christmas night 1996. | Helen H. Richardson/The Denver Post via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Thanks to a new Netflix docuseries from true crime mainstay <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/2/5/18210945/ted-bundy-extremely-wicked-shockingly-evil-vile-review-netflix">Joe Berlinger</a>, audiences across the nation are asking a question true crime fans never really let go of.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The new series, <em>Cold Case: Who Killed JonBenét Ramsey</em>, doesn’t actually spend all that many of its three hour-long episodes speculating about its title question. Instead, it spends most of them arguing a hot take that’s less hot than you might think — that JonBenét’s own parents <em>didn’t </em>do it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"> Following JonBenét’s violent death — which occurred sometime during the early morning hours of December 25 and 26, 1996, in her family’s massive home in Boulder, Colorado — that was a very popular theory. During the ensuing media frenzy, many members of the public looked at John Ramsey and his wife Patsy (who died in 2006) and assumed the case was open and shut. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The victim was an <a href="https://www.bustle.com/articles/184273-how-the-jonbenet-ramsey-case-affected-me-as-a-kid">eerily</a> <a href="https://www.academia.edu/6086362/_Necrophilia_Pedophilia_or_Both_The_Sexualized_Rhetoric_of_the_JonBenet_Ramsey_Murder_Case_">sexualized</a> 6-year-old pageant queen; her face graced the tabloid magazine covers at every checkout line in America. In 1997, no single news story was bigger than this one; by 1998, the Los Angeles Times labeled her “<a href="https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1998-sep-28-ca-27182-story.html">the nation’s most famous murdered child since the Lindbergh baby</a>.” And although a <a href="https://realnewjournalism.com/2016/09/17/jonbenet-ramsey-a-judicial-analysis/">2003 federal ruling</a> supported the Ramseys’ innocence, and they were formally <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/id/wbna25608543">exonerated in 2008</a>, many people remain convinced that one or both of JonBenét’s parents were the culprits and suggest they did it to cover up a horrible accident committed by their 9-year-old son. A hugely influential <a href="https://www.today.com/popculture/burke-ramsey-now-rcna181229">2016 CBS series</a> about the case confidently made that argument. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet in recent years, many experts, including several featured in Berlinger’s documentary, have argued that an intruder committed the crime — a theory that the original police investigation never really seemed to take seriously, and which led to deep divisions among Boulder police, the district attorney, and the FBI. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Much of the confusion stems from the problem that the original investigation was botched from the beginning, with police allowing the crime scene to be completely contaminated, evidence to be moved around and tampered with, rooms to be cleaned, and a string of visitors to traipse throughout the house for hours after the Ramseys called 911. This negligence torpedoed the integrity and reliability of nearly every piece of evidence in the case. As a result, even decades later, every detail remains up for debate. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for a list of potential suspects, while there are several primary contenders, including the Ramseys, it’s often difficult to have an even-handed discussion about them. That’s likely all because of a single piece of evidence, one of the most infamous in true crime history: the ransom note. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For most people who look into the JonBenét case, how they view the ransom note determines how they view the rest of the case, including who did it. That’s because the ransom note itself is so inexplicable that it immediately, and perhaps permanently, biased and derailed the entire investigation.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>The strangest ransom note ever</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The first weird thing about the ransom note is where Patsy claims to have found it — lying unobtrusively on the floor of a back spiral stairwell in the early-morning hours of December 26. She gave conflicting stories about the sequence of events: In one version, she checked JonBenét’s room first and noticed she was missing, and then found the ransom note; in the more frequently repeated version, she found the note first, then ran upstairs to check on JonBenét, only to discover her missing.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The next weird thing about the ransom note is&#8230; well&#8230; everything about it. Here is the text in full:</p>

<blockquote class="wp-block-quote has-text-align-none is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-none">Mr. Ramsey,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Listen carefully! We are a group of individuals that represent a small foreign faction. We [the word “do” has been scribbled out] respect your bussiness [sic] but not the country that it serves. At this time we have your daughter in our posession [sic]. She is safe and unharmed and if you want her to see 1997, you must follow our instructions to the letter.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">You will withdraw $118,000.00 from your account. $100,000 will be in $100 bills and the remaining $18,000 in $20 bills. Make sure that you bring an adequate size attache [sic] to the bank. When you get home you will put the money in a brown paper bag. I will call you between 8 and 10 am tomorrow to instruct you on delivery. The delivery will be exhausting so I advise you to be rested. If we monitor you getting the money early, we might call you early to arrange an earlier delivery of the money and hence a [sic] earlier [“delivery” is scribbled out] pick-up of your daughter.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Any deviation of my instructions will result in the immediate execution of your daughter. You will also be denied her remains for proper burial. The two gentlemen watching over your daughter do not [“not” has been inserted between words] particularly like you so I advise you not to provoke them. Speaking to anyone about your situation, such as Police, F.B.I., etc., will result in your daughter being beheaded. If we catch you talking to a stray dog, she dies. If you alert bank authorities, she dies. If the money is in any way marked or tampered with, she dies. You will be scanned for electronic devices and if any are found, she dies. You can try to deceive us but be warned that we are familiar with Law enforcement countermeasures and tactics. You stand a 99% chance of killing your daughter if you try to out smart [sic] us. Follow our instructions and you stand a 100% chance of getting her back.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">You and your family are under constant scrutiny as well as the authorities. Don&#8217;t try to grow a brain John. You are not the only fat cat around so don&#8217;t think that killing will be difficult. Don&#8217;t underestimate us John. Use that good southern common sense of yours. It is up to you now John!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Victory!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none">S.B.T.C</p>
</blockquote>

<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity" />

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a lot to unpack here: The strange ransom amount — $118,000 — corresponded to John’s year-end bonus that year from the lucrative tech company he ran. The note’s over-the-top language seems to be referencing well-known quotes from movies that feature abductions and ransoms, including <em>Dirty Harry</em>, <em>Ransom</em>, <em>Ruthless People</em>, and <em>Speed</em>. The “foreign faction” is very obviously not real, and “S.B.T.C.” has never been linked to any existing group.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The final oddity about the note is where it came from — a notepad belonging to Patsy. The note’s author not only used the notepad, they wrote a draft version of the note originally addressed to “Mr. &amp; Mrs.” before directing the note just to John. They even used a Sharpie from the house that they then helpfully returned to the correct pen holder. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Patsy participated in a string of handwriting analysis sessions, over which multiple analysts concluded it was probable, but not definitive, that she wrote the note. However, the modern understanding of handwriting analysis generally holds that it’s a shaky forensic arena prone to <a href="https://www.criminallegalnews.org/news/2023/jan/15/debunking-forensic-science-decade-increased-scrutiny-reveals-forensic-processes-prone-bias-and-error/">significant cognitive bias</a>, and that less experienced analysts are <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2119944119">more likely</a> not only to be wrong, but to be more confidently wrong than their peers. Other handwriting analysts have since <a href="https://www.the-sun.com/news/9797920/jonbenet-ramsey-update-ransom-note-handwriting-gary-oliva/">offered</a> totally different opinions about who wrote it. Behavioral analysts, too, tried to analyze the note with dubious results. To give you an idea of the kind of hysteria that surrounded this case, one official psychological profile <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/19990224122955/http://www.seraph.net/jonbenet.html">claimed</a> that “SBTC” could have meant “Saved by the cross,” and argued that Patsy was a “delusional sociopath” who committed the murder as part of an arcane religious ritual.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ransom note is so strange that for many people it’s impossible to get around the sheer improbability of anyone writing it at all. After all, what purpose could it serve an intruder to linger in the house after the crime, taking their time to write multiple drafts of a note, for a kidnapping that had not taken place?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One argument against this is that the intruder could have written the note <em>before</em> the crime. The Ramseys were away for hours at a Christmas party that evening, which gave a potential predator hours to enter the house, familiarize themselves with the home’s layout, and play around with creative writing exercises while waiting for the family to return and settle in for the night.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But the question of motive — why?  — seems to lead, for most people, away from an intruder and straight back to a Ramsey: The note is so fantastical that the most glaringly obvious conclusion is that it was written by someone who was desperate to divert attention away from the home and away from the family. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For a while, if that was the motivation, it worked: Boulder police assembled at the house but then left without securing it as a crime scene, leaving only one officer there throughout the day until JonBenét’s body was ultimately found by her father in the basement. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet if this was really a cover-up by the family, the question of motive still remains: Why would the family leave (or place) JonBenét’s body in the basement if they wanted the police to think she’d been abducted? Why write such an elaborate ransom note or ask for such a specifically incriminating amount? Either way you look at it, the ransom note just doesn’t make sense. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For most people, there’s only one way to read the ransom note: Patsy wrote it. What else could it be?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One alternate way for us to think about this ransom note comes to us via <a href="https://www.truecrimeconsult.com/"><em>The Consult</em></a>, a recent podcast hosted by former members of the FBI’s Behavioral Analysis Unit, of <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2017/10/14/16474370/mindhunter-review-netflix-fincher"><em>Mindhunter</em></a> fame. We know <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2018/11/12/18044688/criminal-profilers-mindhunter-hannibal-criminal-minds">criminal profiling is as pseudoscientific</a> as every other cool-but-actually-junk forensic tool, so we have to take this analysis with many grains of salt. But in their <a href="https://www.truecrimeconsult.com/jonbenet-ramsey-the-ransom-note-part-1/">two-part</a> <a href="https://www.truecrimeconsult.com/jonbenet-ramsey-the-ransom-note-part-2/">series</a> studying the ransom note earlier this year, host Julia Cowley and her guest Robert Drew made interesting observations about the mindset of the letter writer — by honing in on the fact that they were really into movies about abduction. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That sounds like an obvious point, but the profilers used it to make a salient point about the kind of person who could commit this crime. Every film referenced in the note involves a villain who, at the moment he’s making ransom demands, fully has the upper hand over the hero. He’s not only calling the shots, but doing so gleefully and maliciously, exactly as the letter writer may be attempting to do with John. The former FBI profilers argue that the letter is a fantasy of having control over someone rich and powerful — that it’s not an anomaly, but rather an extension of a crime scene created by a sadistic child abuser.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This isn’t the only way to read the note, of course, but it’s a reasonable way to think about how the note fits into an intruder scenario. And given the resurgence of interest in the case, maybe this truly bizarre piece of evidence will finally start making some sense.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[No, FBI checks aren’t required for Trump’s nominees. Yes, it’s concerning.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/trump-administration/388627/fbi-background-checks-trump-gaetz-hegseth-nominees-senate-congress-transition" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=388627</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T17:44:30-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-28T07:00:00-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="2024 Elections" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Donald Trump" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Trump Administration" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[President-elect Donald Trump and his transition team have yet to sign the customary documents allowing the Federal Bureau of Investigation to conduct background checks on his nominees for important government posts, and it’s unclear whether those nominees will receive FBI background checks at all.&#160; The background checks flag any serious concerns about the nominees — [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Donald Trump puts his hand on Robert Kennedy Jr.’s shoulder." data-caption="Former US President Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally at the Gas South Arena on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2180628742.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Former US President Donald Trump welcomes Robert F. Kennedy Jr. to the stage at a Turning Point Action campaign rally at the Gas South Arena on October 23, 2024, in Duluth, Georgia. | Anna Moneymaker/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">President-elect Donald Trump and his transition team have yet to sign the customary documents allowing the Federal Bureau of Investigation to conduct background checks on his nominees for important government posts, and it’s unclear whether those nominees will receive FBI background checks at all.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The background checks flag any serious concerns about the nominees — not just criminal activity but financial issues or relationships that could compromise their ability to carry out their jobs. They are also the basis for security clearances necessary for high-level national security officials tasked with handling sensitive information.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The checks are meant to reveal whether there’s reason to believe these potential officials might misuse the power of their offices or if they have any vulnerabilities that might be exploited, either by US citizens or foreign adversaries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s possible that the FBI will be asked to do background checks next year. According to a report in the Guardian, Trump will <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/26/trump-transition-team-fbi-security-clearances-background-checks">request the background checks</a> once his own officials are posted at the Department of Justice, which oversees the FBI. The transition team is <a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-fbi-gaetz-congress-background-vetting-cabinet-ac9afcd41d598a62ae34442ecf96a652">reportedly relying on internal vetting</a> as well as outside law firms and unspecified allied groups to conduct the background checks, but the FBI is better equipped and has the training and capacity necessary to conduct these investigations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An FBI background check for political appointees is only customary; there’s no legal backing for it. No other branch of government can compel the nominees to undergo them. Trump himself has been skeptical of the FBI, so it’s not that surprising that he’s eschewed the background checks. But they do serve several important purposes.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here’s what you need to know about the FBI background checks.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What’s the standard background check process?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The FBI background check process is straightforward, if arduous.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">First, the incoming administration signs a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Justice outlining what kinds of information they are looking for about their nominees and what resources the DOJ can provide to help uncover that information. Nominees who will be working in national security have to fill <a href="https://www.opm.gov/forms/pdf_fill/sf86.pdf">out a special form</a> (the same one the&nbsp; Department of Defense uses in evaluating staff for security clearances).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The FBI can question the nominee and their contacts if necessary but cannot collect documents or compel evidence. Cooperation is voluntary, but as Llewelyn Engel, an attorney at the Washington, DC, firm Emery Will &amp; Henry, told Vox, “From an interview perspective, if the FBI calls you to ask about somebody, you might be more forthcoming” than with a law firm or other private entity conducting investigations.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once complete, the full background check then goes to the president-elect who, based on the findings, can either refer the nominee to the Senate or decide to withdraw the nomination. If the nomination is for a high-level position, like a Cabinet member or an ambassador, the investigations go to the appropriate Senate committee —&nbsp;for example, the Senate Armed Services Committee for a Defense secretary nominee.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The Senate committee is in charge of looking at all this information, so they&#8217;ll get a big binder of all the material, and they can also do their own investigations as well,” Engel said. “They can always request that more information is collected about this individual.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, the process isn’t mandated by law. The practice started when <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/us-politics/trump-cabinet-picks-fbi-background-checks-senate-b2649239.html">President Dwight Eisenhower</a> chose to have his nominees subject to a background check and has continued since then.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Is Trump following the usual process?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus far, Trump has deviated from the usual process, although the incoming administration did sign other important transition agreements <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/11/26/trump-signs-transition-agreement-white-house-00191754">with the Biden White House on Tuesday</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration told <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2024/11/26/trump-signs-transition-agreement-white-house-00191754">Politico</a> that “progress has been made towards an agreement” between the Trump team and the DOJ, but how much progress remains unclear.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">&#8220;The Trump-Vance transition lawyers continue to constructively engage with the Biden-Harris Administration lawyers regarding all agreements contemplated by the Presidential Transition Act,&#8221; Brian Hughes, a spokesperson for Trump’s transition team, <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/11/22/nx-s1-5196441/the-trump-transition-team-is-breaking-with-norms-in-selecting-cabinet-picks">told NPR</a>. &#8220;We will update you once a decision is made.&#8221;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Justice Department said in a statement that it is “prepared to deliver briefings to the transition team on our operations and responsibilities, and we stand ready to process requests for security clearances for those who will need access to national security information.&#8221;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why isn’t Trump following the standard process?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">No other president-elect has eschewed the FBI background check process “in recent memory,” Heath Brown, a professor of public policy at John Jay College of Criminal Justice, told Vox.&nbsp; And Trump hasn’t said why he hasn’t tasked the FBI with doing background checks.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He does, however, have a noted <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/trump-facing-criminal-charges-calls-defunding-fbi-2023-04-05/">distrust of the FBI</a> following investigations into his <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/8/3/23818752/trump-investigations-classified-documents-live-updates">handling of secret documents after he left office in 2021</a>, as well as <a href="https://www.fbi.gov/wanted/capitol-violence">FBI investigations into the January 6, 2021, insurrection</a> and attempt to overturn the 2020 election.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And as previously noted, there’s no law requiring Trump to follow the normal process. <a href="https://beyer.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=6315">Reps. Ted Lieu of California and Dan Beyer of Virginia</a> introduced a bill in November to codify the practice in the law, but it hasn’t passed yet.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Instead of following the typical process, Trump’s transition team plans to have the FBI checks go forward only after he has taken office —&nbsp;that is, after he is in control of the agency and has his own appointees in place, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/nov/26/trump-transition-team-fbi-security-clearances-background-checks">the Guardian reported Wednesday</a>. According to that report, Trump also plans to grant blanket security clearances, though it’s unclear whether or how the DOD will be involved in that process.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What happens now?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Without the FBI background checks, the various Senate committees can conduct their own investigations into nominees, according to Engel and Jennifer Selin, associate professor at the Arizona State University Sandra Day O&#8217;Connor College of Law. Those investigations may or may not become public.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even without FBI investigations, potential red flags with nominees will sometimes emerge through reporting. The press resurfaced allegations of sexual misconduct on the part of <a href="https://www.vox.com/donald-trump/384967/matt-gaetz-donald-trump-attorney-general">former Attorney General nominee Matt Gaetz</a>. And <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/387404/trump-cabinet-nominations-matt-gaetz-pete-hegseth-rfk-elon-musk-linda-mcmahon">Defense Secretary nominee Pete Hegseth’s</a> alleged sex crime also came to light through news stories. Both men have denied wrongdoing.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The media is in some ways a good ally for the Senate because it&#8217;s not just the senators delving into and using their subpoena power and their background and connections with various agencies to get information and to conduct their own investigations,” Selin said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Senate will ideally <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/11/14/politics/cabinet-confirmation-recess-what-matters/index.html">begin confirmation hearings</a> —&nbsp;with or without the FBI reports —&nbsp;<a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-fbi-gaetz-congress-background-vetting-cabinet-ac9afcd41d598a62ae34442ecf96a652">before Inauguration Day on January 20, 2025</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Vox Staff</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Wicked, explained]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/387821/wicked-explained-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-oz-guide-holding-space" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?post_type=vm_stream&#038;p=387821</id>
			<updated>2024-11-27T15:00:41-05:00</updated>
			<published>2024-11-27T13:10:11-05:00</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Theater" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vox Guides" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wicked, the highly anticipated adaptation of the popular Broadway musical, is just about everywhere. The first half of the saga, released on November 22, made $114 million in its opening weekend domestically, and it has already generated some early Oscars buzz. Wicked: Part Two is set to premiere in November 2025.&#160; Directed by Jon M. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/11/gettyimages-2184796941.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Wicked</em>, the highly anticipated adaptation of the popular Broadway musical, is just about everywhere. The first half of the saga, released on November 22, made $114 million in its opening weekend domestically, and it has already generated some early Oscars buzz. <em>Wicked: Part Two</em> is set to premiere in November 2025.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Directed by Jon M. Chu, who also directed<em> Crazy Rich Asians</em>, the movie’s plot dives into the “true story” of Elphaba, the &#8220;Wicked Witch of the West,&#8221; and Glinda the &#8220;Good Witch,” reimagined from the classic book series and film <em>The Wizard of Oz</em>. It stars Cynthia Erivo and Ariana Grande as Elphaba and Glinda, respectively, along with Jonathan Bailey, Michelle Yeoh, and Jeff Goldblum as other residents of the Land of Oz.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From its backstory to its politics to understanding why fans are “holding space” for it, follow along here for everything you need to know about the film.</p>
<ul>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/388499/wicked-elphaba-animal-rights-dillamond">How did Elphaba become wicked? There’s a hidden message people keep missing.</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/388703/wicked-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-tiktok-instagram">Wicked hits Instagram and TikTok, with more than a little help from fans </a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/388522/wicked-politics-explained-movie-musical-wizard-trump">Why Wicked’s politics feel so bizarrely timely</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/386247/wicked-2024-movie-novel-ending-explained-ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo">Wondering what’s what in Wicked? We can help.</a>
		</li>
			<li>
			<a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/387545/ariana-grande-cynthia-erivo-wicked-dont-worry-darling-it-ends-with-us">Fans are “holding space”  for Wicked’s press tour</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
