<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
	xml:lang="en-US"
	>
	<title type="text">Vox</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2024-08-14T21:59:17Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com" />
	<id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml" />

	<icon>https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/vox_logo_rss_light_mode.png?w=150&amp;h=100&amp;crop=1</icon>
		<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Adam Clark Estes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The hidden reason why your power bill is so high]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/technology/366885/utility-power-bill-price-clean-energy" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366885</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T21:59:17Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-15T12:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Even Better" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Renewable Energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Solar energy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Technology" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your utility bill confuses you and makes you sweat every month when it demands hundreds of your hard-earned dollars, you’re not alone. The price of electricity is continuing to rise across the United States, and there’s no end in sight.&#160; Why are our electricity bills getting so expensive? Energy prices have been creeping up [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Three utility workers wearing masks, jumpsuits, goggles and hard hats." data-caption="Southern California Edison workers after installing new equipment for reliability in Ventura, California." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-1213009686.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Southern California Edison workers after installing new equipment for reliability in Ventura, California.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">If your utility bill confuses you and makes you sweat every month when it demands hundreds of your hard-earned dollars, you’re not alone. The price of electricity is continuing to rise across the United States, and there’s no end in sight.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Why are our electricity bills getting so expensive? Energy prices have been creeping up across the nation for over a decade. The latest consumer price index <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/08/14/business/cpi-inflation-fed">saw inflation dip below 3 percent</a> for the first time since 2021, but inflation for electricity prices nationwide <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/cpi.nr0.htm">remains stubbornly high at 4.9 percent</a>. There’s no single reason why electricity keeps getting more expensive in any one place, however.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The drivers behind rising energy costs <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-09/interest-rate-cuts-unlikely-to-lower-energy-costs-for-americans?sref=qYiz2hd0">are myriad, overlapping, and vexing</a>. Inflation, rising energy demands, volatile natural gas prices, and extreme weather are all contributing factors. The transition to renewable energy is, too.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite <a href="https://www.eenews.net/articles/electricity-prices-get-political-in-trumps-world/">what you’re hearing from Republicans</a>, the transition to clean energy is not the driving force behind rising electricity costs, <a href="https://energyinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Clean-Energy-Isnt-Driving-Power-Price-Spikes.pdf">according to a July report from Energy Innovation</a>, a think tank. Building wind, solar, and battery infrastructure is expensive, and connecting those new clean energy resources to the grid is complicated. Rather than making those investments, which save customers money in the long run, many utilities are doubling down on fossil fuel and existing infrastructure in an effort to ensure the grid is reliable.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For example, PJM, a utility company that serves customers from the mid-Atlantic region to the Great Lakes, <a href="https://www.pjm.com/-/media/about-pjm/newsroom/2024-releases/20240730-pjm-capacity-auction-procures-sufficient-resources-to-meet-rto-reliability-requirement.ashx">recently picked mostly natural gas over renewables</a> at its annual capacity auction, where it buys the electricity it needs to keep the lights on for the year ahead, and its customers <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/transmission/prices-just-spiked-in-the-biggest-us-power-market-blame-the-grid-backlog">will see more big price spikes</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The United States electric grid <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/02/22/why-we-need-nationwide-electric-grid-in-the-us-but-dont-have-one.html">is a messy patchwork of thousands of local utilities</a>, many of which are for-profit businesses governed by a complex web of policies and regulations. Throw in those aforementioned variables — inflation, growing energy demand, volatile fuel prices, extreme weather — and you can start to make sense of why your electricity bill won’t stop rising.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, there’s good evidence that by <a href="https://www.iea.org/news/rapid-rollout-of-clean-technologies-makes-energy-cheaper-not-more-costly#">updating those regulations and investing more in clean energy</a>, we can meet that demand, confront those challenges, and keep prices down for decades to come. And we’re only going to need more electricity in the future.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“As [cooking our food] gets electrified, transportation gets electrified, and weather gets more extreme, those demand spikes are becoming larger,” said Paul McDonald, VP of product strategy at Oracle Water and Power, whose team builds AI-powered software that helps shift utility customer behavior towards better energy efficiency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s a lot you can do to make sure you’re using your energy efficiently, even without the help of AI: Even a few degrees on your thermostat makes a big difference, and cranking it up past 72, even past 76 (<a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358898/best-thermostat-setting-save-energy-money-ac">yes! really</a>) on hot days will save you money and still keep you pretty comfortable. Heat pumps or solar panels, if you can afford the up-front cost, will save you money in the long term. You can also take a closer look at where your energy comes from and play a more assertive role in how you spend your kilowatt hours.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before we get into what behavior changes big and small could mean for your out-of-control electric bill, however, it’s helpful to take a deep dive into the numbers on that bill and what’s behind them.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Your electric bill is more complicated than it looks</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In recent years, inflation has been the easy explanation for rising energy prices in the US. The cost of electricity <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-04-09/interest-rate-cuts-unlikely-to-lower-energy-costs-for-americans?sref=qYiz2hd0">has outpaced rising prices for food and the wider consumer price index</a> since early 2021, and there are strong indicators that those prices will keep rising as inflation cools.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand why this is happening, it’s helpful to understand that your electric bill is actually two bills: You’re paying one for supply and the other for delivery.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages_1213009672.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.729057198914,100,78.541885602173" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Utility companies often replace aging or damaged infrastructure components, rather than repair them. | Brent Stirton/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brent Stirton/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Electricity supply is the stuff that comes from power plants. Those plants might be powered by coal or natural gas, or by renewables, like wind and solar. The cost of delivery, or transmission and distribution, reflects the many moving parts it takes to get that supply from the power plant to your living room. This includes operating and maintaining the grid as well as any big investments to repair or upgrade the grid by, for example, installing new high-voltage transmission lines that could be used to connect renewable energy sources to the grid.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That said, clean energy is not the culprit when it comes to rising electricity prices, <a href="https://energyinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Clean-Energy-Isnt-Driving-Power-Price-Spikes.pdf">according to the recent report from Energy Innovation</a>. Volatility in natural gas prices, including the huge spikes following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, has certainly contributed to some price increases on the supply side. But the transmission and distribution costs have actually been going up at twice the rate of inflation nationwide, the report’s author, Brendan Pierpont, told me. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“That trend of increasing transmission and distribution costs is something that is noticeable all across the country, and so I think it’s an underlying factor in rate increases everywhere,” Pierpont said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Utility companies have a lot of freedom in setting rates for transmission and distribution — and that directly contributes to how much profit they make. Utilities get to pick what gets upgraded when, and they also have an incentive to spend heavily, thanks to regulations that allow them to collect return on investment, <a href="https://www.spglobal.com/marketintelligence/en/news-insights/research/electric-beats-gas-in-exceeding-authorized-equity-returns-over-past-15-years">usually around 10 percent</a>, for those expenditures. This is actually built into the price most people pay for electricity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here’s how it works: Every year, utility companies ask regulators to approve a “revenue requirement,” which is basically a budget for what the utilities think it will cost to deliver enough electricity to their customers. Those estimates include spending on new equipment but not the cost of repairing old equipment. It also includes that return on investment, or profit, which regulators <a href="https://haas.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/WP329.pdf">regularly approve</a>. In Pierpont’s words, “That rate of return has a direct link to the costs that customers pay for electricity.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">What utilities don’t seem to be doing, however, is expanding the grid in a way that would benefit clean energy producers, the Energy Innovation report finds. Investments tend to cover local upgrades, like installing new metering equipment, rather than installing the high-voltage transmission lines that renewable energy sources need to connect to the grid. Meanwhile, consumers <a href="https://www.eia.gov/electricity/annual/html/epa_11_01.html">are facing more frequent outages that last longer</a>, while utilities keep making more money for installing new, potentially unnecessary equipment.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s like the utilities have a rewards credit card,” said Joel Rosenberg of Rewiring America, a nonprofit focused on electrification. “And they get to keep the rewards for how much they spend, and the [customers] have to pay off the bill, even if that bill takes 80 years to pay off.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This plays right into the misconception that investment in renewables leads to higher rates.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Many of the states leading the way to clean energy are actually seeing lower energy prices than the rest of the country. Data from the US Energy Information Administration shows that 17 states, including California and Massachusetts, <a href="https://energyinnovation.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Clean-Energy-Isnt-Driving-Power-Price-Spikes.pdf">have increased their share of renewable energy sources by more than 20 percent</a> since 2010. And with the exception of California, all of those states have seen the price of residential rate increases rise more slowly than inflation. The higher rates in California can be explained, in part, by <a href="https://www.kqed.org/science/1985398/california-regulators-set-to-vote-on-pges-newest-rate-increase-plan">rate increases to account for wildfire prevention</a>. In Massachusetts, natural gas is the problem.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">States where residents are seeing electricity bills that outpace inflation tend to be the ones with the highest reliance on natural gas, as highlighted in the Energy Innovation report. Some states in New England, including Massachusetts, have depended on natural gas for around 60 percent of electricity generation since 2020 and have seen prices increase by around 10 percent in the same period. Volatility in the price of natural gas also means that some of the highest price spikes <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/inflation-electricity-bills-higher-summer-2023/">are spread out over several years</a>, so there could be more high prices in these states’ futures. </p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages_1213009661.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.729057198914,100,78.541885602173" alt="Utility workers look up as they work on power lines." title="Utility workers look up as they work on power lines." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Many utilities focus their investment on local equipment upgrades instead of things like long-distance transmission lines, which would make it easier to connect more renewable sources to the grid. | Brent Stirton/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Brent Stirton/Getty Images" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">And none of this takes into account the effects of extreme weather. Hurricane season <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/366041/climate-hurricane-debby-drenches-the-southeast">is just now approaching its peak</a>, after Hurricane Debby already <a href="https://apnews.com/article/hurricane-tropical-storm-debby-flooding-d90428b0417df35fa1cae8b24793f5c5">dumped rivers of rain</a> on the southeast US, and La Niña, which brings colder and stormier conditions in the north, <a href="https://weather.com/news/weather/news/2024-08-08-la-nina-outlook-august-update-noaa">is forecast to emerge in the fall</a>. Thanks to climate change, extreme weather events <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/352234/how-one-weather-extreme-can-make-the-next-one-even-more-dangerous">are compounding</a> and getting even more extreme. That’s <a href="https://www.axios.com/2024/04/24/us-grid-outages-extreme-weather">taking a toll on the grid</a>, and somebody has to pay.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Biden administration, for its part, has taken several steps toward making the grid more resilient without raising prices. It’s spent <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-federal-state-initiative-to-bolster-americas-power-grid/">over $10 billion</a> on grid resilience and innovation, while also providing local utilities <a href="https://liftoff.energy.gov/innovative-grid-deployment/">with guidance</a> on how to invest in the grid in the near term without passing costs along to customers. This week, the Department of Energy <a href="https://www.energy.gov/policy/articles/clean-energy-resources-meet-data-center-electricity-demand">also released a plan to use clean energy to power data centers</a>, which account for a large share of growing energy demand.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Policy typically takes time to change the lives of everyday Americans, who might feel powerless when confronted with the rising cost of electricity. This tension has fueled <a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/energy-and-utilities/whats-the-difference-between-an-electric-co-op-and-a-utility/">the rise of energy cooperatives</a>, where customers have a say in how the grid gets upgraded and how prices are set. If that’s an option where you live, it’s worth a look. Otherwise, you can look inside your home to save money on your next electric bill.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>When all else fails, use less electricity</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">On any given day, there’s not a lot you can do to control how utility companies set the price for electricity transmission and distribution. If you live in a state with a deregulated energy market, <a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/energy-and-utilities/compare-electricity-rates-new-york/">like New York</a>, you might be able to choose where your energy supply comes from. You can also decide to lessen your reliance on the grid by <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/guides-and-how-tos/ask-these-10-questions-if-you-want-to-get-rooftop-solar">installing solar panels on your roof</a> or <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/guides-and-how-tos/what-is-community-solar-and-how-can-you-sign-up">participating in a community solar project</a>. Otherwise, you can just choose to control your electricity usage.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You’ve probably already heard about some easy tricks to bring down your power bill. You can <a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358898/best-thermostat-setting-save-energy-money-ac">set your thermostat higher in the summer</a> or install a smart thermostat. You can <a href="https://www.cnet.com/home/energy-and-utilities/peak-and-off-peak-energy-explainer-heres-the-cheapest-time-to-use-electricity/">run big appliances like dishwashers and dryers at night</a>, when energy might be cheaper. You can turn down your hot water heater, which comes with the benefit of <a href="https://www.energy.gov/energysaver/do-it-yourself-savings-project-lower-water-heating-temperature">hundreds of dollars in potential savings</a> as well as not being scalded by your shower.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The harder problem is planning for a future in which electricity costs continue to rise. In order to prepare for that — and it is somewhat inevitable, if only because you’ll use more electricity <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/electrification/home-of-the-future-climate-friendly-electrified-and-closer-than-ever">as more of your life becomes electrified</a> — there are a few steps to consider. The first is to <a href="https://homes.rewiringamerica.org/projects/energy-audit-homeowner">do an energy audit</a> and make a plan from there.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Un<strong>derstanding how to save energy — and money</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Electrifying our future requires, well, a lot of electricity. And that comes at a cost, not only for the planet but also for consumers. Vox writers have been explaining how we got here and what you can do to adapt:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/23340991/power-demand-response-blackout-consumer-climate-change-california-texas-cop27">Consumers, not corporations, saved the power grid. What else can we do?</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/358898/best-thermostat-setting-save-energy-money-ac">Stop setting your thermostat at 72</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24047383/winter-storm-heating-electricity-grid-power-polar-vortex">Your home’s cleaner, better heating system comes with one major cost</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/24126621/energy-efficiency-appliances-stove-washing-machine-climate">Our appliances are more efficient than ever. Why doesn’t it feel like it?</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.vox.com/climate/2023/4/7/22954507/inflation-reduction-act-renters-home-rebates">A renter’s guide to the Inflation Reduction Act</a></p>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Making a plan is a really important thing,” Rosenberg told me, “particularly because when these big appliances fail, it becomes an emergency replacement situation, whether it’s your water heater or your air conditioner or your furnace,” said Rosenberg, pointing me to <a href="https://www.rewiringamerica.org/electrify-home-guide">Rewiring America’s guide to electrifying everything in your home</a>. If your furnace fails in the middle of winter, you might be inclined to pay for the quickest fix, rather than the most efficient or cost-effective.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If any of those three big appliances break, by the way, you should get in the heat pump game. Integrating heat pumps both for heating and cooling as well as hot water can save the average homeowner <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/products/ask-the-experts/heat-pump-water-heater-right-your-home#:~:text=Compared%20to%20a%20standard%20electric,savings%20of%20more%20than%20%245%2C600!">over</a> <a href="https://carbonswitch.com/heat-pump-carbon-reduction-and-savings-potential-report/">$1,000 a year</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Buying a heat pump doesn’t mean you have to rip out your furnace, either. You can <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/heat-pumps/renters-you-too-can-get-a-heat-pump-a-micro-one-at-least">install micro heat pumps</a>, some of which look like window unit ACs, to supplement your existing system during all seasons. Micro heat pumps don’t yet qualify for rebates under the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA), so it’s worth considering a regular heat pump. Installing a heat pump air conditioner/heater or heat pump water heater lets you <a href="https://www.energystar.gov/about/federal-tax-credits/air-source-heat-pumps">claim a $2,000 tax credit</a> in any single year. The IRA offers <a href="https://www.irs.gov/credits-deductions/energy-efficient-home-improvement-credit">an additional $1,200 for other energy-saving improvements, like new insulation</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That’s up to $3,200 of free government money every year, so if you want to install a heat pump this year and get free money and then install another one next year and get free money, the US government welcomes that ambition. (For a handy guide to the IRA’s consumer incentives, <a href="https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/electrification/your-cheat-sheet-to-the-climate-laws-consumer-incentives">check out Canary Media’s cheat sheet</a>, and you can check your state’s rebate offers <a href="https://www.energy.gov/save">at the Department of Energy’s website</a>.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The list of tips for saving electricity in the long and short term goes on, and <a href="https://www.energy.gov/energysaver/do-it-yourself-savings-project-lower-water-heating-temperature">the Energy Star website is a great resource</a> if you’re interested in learning about them. If your life is even more electrified — if you <a href="https://advocacy.consumerreports.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Maintenance-Cost-White-Paper-9.24.20-1.pdf">drive an EV</a> or <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/guides/solar/savings-with-solar-panels/">have solar panels installed</a>, for instance — there are even more opportunities for savings. Many of these efforts require a significant upfront investment, though. <a href="https://www.nrdc.org/stories/how-where-speak-out-climate-action">Reaching out to your local leaders</a> to see what can be done to connect more low-cost renewable energy sources to the grid, well, that’s free.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ellen Ioanes</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why does it feel like everyone is getting Covid?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19/367150/covid-surge-summer-wave-pandemic-vaccine-booster-mask" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367150</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T20:43:36Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-15T11:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Covid-19" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health Care" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Infectious Disease" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Monkeypox" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Science" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Today, Explained newsletter" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vaccines" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re presently in what appears to be the worst Covid-19 summer surge in several years, especially in the southern US. According to data from the Centers for Disease Control (CDC), all of the metrics related to Covid-19 that we should be worried about are going up — not just cases, but hospitalizations and deaths, too. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A woman in a blue blouse and green hijab wears a mask as she descends and escalator. " data-caption="A masked commuter is seen on the metro in Washington, DC, on May 25, 2024. | Rosem Morton for the Washington Post via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Rosem Morton for the Washington Post via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2154183194.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A masked commuter is seen on the metro in Washington, DC, on May 25, 2024. | Rosem Morton for the Washington Post via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re presently in what appears to be the <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/health-news/covid-us-largest-summer-wave-cdc-high-transmission-rcna165765">worst Covid-19 summer surge in several years</a>, especially in the southern US. According to data from the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/forecast-outbreak-analytics/about/rt-estimates.html">Centers for Disease Control (CDC)</a>, all of the metrics related to Covid-19 that we should be worried about are going up — not just cases, but hospitalizations and deaths, too.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if we’re no longer in the depths of the pandemic, and we have treatments to lessen its severity and vaccines for protection, contracting Covid-19 carries risks. That’s particularly true for people over 65, people with comorbidities like heart or lung disease, or those who are immunocompromised. And the lingering health challenges of <a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19/2023/3/13/23627229/long-covid-science-symptoms-treatments">long Covid</a> remain a risk.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The good news is that on the whole, Americans are much better protected than we once were against serious illness, because most people have been infected, vaccinated, or both. However, it’s still important to take precautions as Covid-19 cases increase <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/forecast-outbreak-analytics/about/rt-estimates.html">in most states across the US</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Here’s what we know so far about the surge this year, and what you can do to keep yourself and your community healthy.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How do we know we’re in a summer surge?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Centers for Disease Control has found that cases are increasing or likely increasing in 32 states. This follows a seasonal pattern that’s begun to emerge with Covid. We saw a similar surge last summer, though according to CDC data, cases are <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#datatracker-home">exceeding levels from around this time last year</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It&#8217;s not just last summer — even when we were having the pandemic, if you look at the graphs, infection was always very high during the summer and also during the winter,” said <a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/profile/kizzmekia-s-corbett/">Kizzmekia Corbett-Helaire</a>, assistant professor of immunology and infectious diseases at Harvard’s School of Public Health.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We don’t know exactly why the summer surge happens, Corbett-Helaire said. Some of it could be due to the underlying characteristics of the virus, and some due to human behavior, like increased travel.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the moment, <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#datatracker-home">Covid hospitalizations and deaths</a> are rising but still relatively low — the latest data shows that 1.5 percent of deaths in the US are the result of Covid, and 2.3 percent of emergency room visits during the week ending August 3 were diagnosed as Covid-19.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">CDC data comes from a variety of sources. But one important source for tracking transmission rates is wastewater testing, which involves tracking the amount of virus in local sewage. Early in the pandemic, before at-home testing was accessible, data from clinical testing was used to track infection rates. Now, however, fewer Americans are testing and reporting their status, making test-based tracking unreliable.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That makes wastewater testing the best available metric for getting a timely picture of the presence of illness in a community, according to <a href="https://centerforhealthsecurity.org/who-we-are/our-people/amesh-adalja-md-fidsa">Amesh Adalja</a>, senior scholar at Johns Hopkins Center for Health Security.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s kind of becoming the way of the future” and is being used to test for the presence of other illnesses, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/366903/mpox-monkeypox-africa-continental-emergency-drc-who-clade">including mpox</a>, he told Vox.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#wastewater-surveillance">the wastewater says</a> the US is in the midst of a surge approaching infection levels not seen since last winter, which was the worst increase since 2022.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What are the variants driving it? And how are they transmitted?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There’s no one variant of the virus that’s dominant right now — there’s a group of variants referred to as FLiRT, which come from the <a href="https://publichealth.jhu.edu/2024/what-to-know-about-covid-flirt-variants">JN.1 variant</a>. The <a href="https://www.today.com/health/coronavirus/new-covid-variant-flirt-name-meaning-rcna152650">name FLiRT</a> refers to the technical names for where the mutations that created this variant occurred; in this case, on the spike protein on the virus, which helps it connect to a cell and infect it.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">LB.1, which has many similarities with the FLiRT variants, but has one additional mutation, is also circulating. LB.1 may be more transmissible than other dominant variants, but experts don’t know that for sure. And, as a CDC spokesperson told Vox, “there are no data at this time indicating that this variant causes more severe COVID-19.” The symptoms, the spokesperson said, are similar to that of other variants.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the <a href="https://covid.cdc.gov/covid-data-tracker/#variant-summary">latest CDC data</a> (from July 21 to August 3, 2024) LB.1 accounted for about 16 percent of US Covid cases. The FLiRT variants, meanwhile, represented more than half of all cases.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In terms of transmission, not much has changed, either — you can still get these strains of Covid from an infected person if you’re in close quarters with them, especially indoors in a crowded or poorly ventilated space. Masking and vaccination remain the best ways to prevent transmission.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>When are you contagious if you have Covid?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">FLiRT is no different from other variants when it comes to contagion — you are definitely contagious as long as you are testing positive on an at-home test.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You might be contagious one to two days before you have symptoms, though, <a href="https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/yellowbook/2024/infections-diseases/covid-19#:~:text=People%20with%20COVID%2D19%20can,few%20days%20of%20symptom%20onset">and that’s when you tend to be most likely to infect others</a>. Sneezing, coughing, talking, singing, cheering, or breathing heavily (like you might during exercise) transmit the virus through aerosol particles, which can stay in a room and infect others even after you’ve departed.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>If I have Covid, what should I do?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Covid-positive people should isolate until at least 24 hours after their symptoms are improving and they no longer have a fever, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/respiratory-viruses/guidance/faqs.html">according to the latest CDC guidance</a> (which applies to the flu and RSV as well). </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But you may still be contagious even if you’re feeling better. So if you must break your isolation, it’s important to wear a mask that fits well (<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/niosh/topics/publicppe/community-ppe.html">ideally one like an N95 or KN95</a>), maintain distance from others, and ensure you’re in well-ventilated areas for at least the next five days.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Do boosters help protect against the latest variants?</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Boosters can help prevent the spread of Covid, but <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/12/well/coronavirus-vaccine-booster.html">current boosters</a> are unlikely to be as effective against the latest variants. Current boosters were formulated to be effective against pre-JN.1 omicron variants, and the lastest mutations hadn’t happened yet when the inoculations now available were released. Still, you might consider getting one if you meet the following criteria:</p>

<ul>
<li>Are 65 years of age and older</li>



<li>Are moderately or severely immunocompromised or have underlying medical conditions</li>



<li>Living in a long-term care facility</li>



<li>Have never received any doses of a Covid-19 vaccine</li>



<li>Are pregnant and have not received a 2023–2024 dose — especially those in late pregnancy</li>
</ul>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The good news is a new formulation that targets the FLiRT variants should be available soon, in preparation for a likely winter surge. The CDC recommends that everyone ages 6 months and older receive an updated 2024–2025 COVID-19 vaccine when it is available this fall, though those vaccines haven’t been approved or authorized yet. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Again, while most Americans do have a baseline level of immunity against the virus, the new version of the vaccine will, at the very least, help prevent serious illness, hospitalization, and death, especially for vulnerable populations like the elderly and immunocompromised.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The CDC continuously updates its recommendations for boosting; <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/covid-19/clinical-considerations/interim-considerations-us.html">the latest can be found on its website</a>.  </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for exactly how protective the new vaccine will be against infection, that’s impossible to know: “The last two updates have missed targets in terms of preventing infections, but we know they protect against serious disease and death,” Adalja said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even if the newest vaccines aren’t as effective as we hope, there are several tools available for the treatment of at-risk populations, including Paxlovid, and a monoclonal antibody called Pemgarda, <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/covid/hcp/clinical-care/outpatient-treatment.html#:~:text=Pemivibart%20(Pemgarda%E2%84%A2)%20is%20a,FDA%2Dauthorized%20conditions%20for%20use.">which can be used as a prophylactic for the severely immunocompromised</a>. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Amid the surge, perhaps the most important thing to keep in mind is that Covid “is always going to be a threat,” Adalja said. “It’s an endemic respiratory illness that is part of the human condition.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This summer’s surge is making that very clear.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Joseph Lee</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[We’re in a deadly cycle of mega fires. The way out is to burn more.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/climate/366765/megafires-climate-indigenous-controlled-burns" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366765</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T21:55:00Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-15T10:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Climate" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Down to Earth" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Natural Disasters" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This story is the second feature in a Vox special project,&#160;Changing With Our Climate, a limited-run series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future. Silas Yamamoto’s favorite part of his job is starting fires.&#160; As a prescribed fire technician with the Karuk Tribe and the Mid Klamath Watershed Council [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/Vox_Fires2.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>This story is the second feature in a Vox special project,&nbsp;</em>Changing With Our Climate<em>, a limited-run series exploring Indigenous solutions to extreme weather rooted in history — and the future.</em> </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Silas Yamamoto’s favorite part of his job is starting fires.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As a prescribed fire technician with the Karuk Tribe and the <a href="https://www.mkwc.org/">Mid Klamath Watershed Council</a> based in Happy Camp, a small town in Northern California, Yamamoto sets controlled burns — smaller, deliberate fires that can help prevent bigger wildfires, reduce habitat for invasive species, and improve plant and soil health. Yamamoto has been setting a lot of fires in his ancestral homelands and lately, he’s been traveling around the country to help set fires in other communities, too. The goal is to decolonize our relationship to wildfires, remove barriers to using good fire, and prepare us for a world more impacted by the effects of climate change. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But he’s still not burning nearly as often as he would like to.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Across the country, wildfires <a href="https://www.wri.org/insights/global-trends-forest-fires#:~:text=Using%20data%20from%20researchers%20at,year%20over%20that%20time%20period.">are getting worse</a>. In addition to the billions of dollars in damage from destroyed homes and infrastructure, these fires are increasingly deadly: Every year, wildfire smoke <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/04/18/1245068810/wildfire-smoke-contributes-to-thousands-of-deaths-each-year-in-the-u-s">contributes to thousands of deaths</a> in the US alone, not to mention other <a href="https://www.epa.gov/wildfire-smoke-course/health-effects-attributed-wildfire-smoke">health impacts</a> like reduced lung function and increased risk of <a href="https://aaic.alz.org/releases-2024/exposure-wildfire-smoke-raises-dementia-risk.asp">dementia</a>.<strong> </strong>And climate change makes extreme wildfires all the more likely as landscapes <a href="https://www.unep.org/resources/report/spreading-wildfire-rising-threat-extraordinary-landscape-fires?gad_source=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwiOy1BhDCARIsADGvQnBT5YUJwv7RW_kcUWMkwR9ohpBhffrHmWmKVIq37-GguASuKzozUQ8aAps0EALw_wcB">become warmer, drier, and more flammable</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this means that understanding how to control wildfires is more important than ever.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Yamamoto, fire is a way of connecting with his tribal community and land, but he has bigger ambitions, too: He wants to organize major collaborative projects — between different states, sovereign Indigenous nations — that would spread fire across arbitrary property lines. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the barriers to effective fire management is the tangled web of property ownership across the country. Good fire mitigation techniques — like clearing flammable understory on corporate-owned land — aren’t as effective if the family land next door doesn’t do the same. To truly confront out-of-control wildfires and climate change, fire management will have to transcend those lines, which means understanding the land we live on as a shared responsibility, rather than a collection of individual properties. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Fire doesn’t recognize property lines, right?” Yamamoto said. “That’s a very human construction.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fire has always been a part of Yamamoto’s Karuk culture, but until recently, state and federal authorities saw all fires as bad — a force of nature to suppress, not live with. For decades, the US embraced a <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/about-agency/features/only-you">policy of fire suppression</a>, underscored by Smokey Bear’s “Only you can prevent forest fires” ads, that caused forests to become denser, and fires more frequent and powerful. Fire suppression in California, for example, undid generations of Indigenous land stewardship, which cultivated a landscape where fire, people, and plants could coexist. By lighting frequent, smaller fires, they created a sustainable cycle that cleared underbrush, regenerated plants and soils, and prevented the sort of “mega fires” we see today. But that stewardship was mercilessly extinguished in the 19th and 20th centuries: According to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2020/sep/16/california-wildfires-cultural-burns-indigenous-people">Bill Tripp</a>, the director of natural resources and environmental policy for the Karuk Tribe, up until the 1930s, Karuk people were shot by white settlers for starting fires. </p>

<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>“Fire doesn&#8217;t recognize property lines, right? That’s a very human construction.”</p></blockquote></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Today there’s been an important and encouraging <a href="https://www.nps.gov/subjects/fire/indigenous-fire-practices-shape-our-land.htm">shift</a> back toward more Indigenous burning practices. But even as Indigenous fire management finally begins to <a href="https://www.hcn.org/issues/55-1/indigenous-affairs-wildfire-what-if-indigenous-women-ran-controlled-burns/">gain more respect</a>, Indigenous fire practitioners are still limited by restrictive burning policies, land access, resources, and bureaucracy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We’re caught in a negative feedback loop of scarier and more destructive fires. Yamamoto believes we should be spreading fire — not suppressing it: That’s why Yamamoto is working to spread Indigenous fire culture to non-Native fire practitioners across the country and develop partnerships that can tackle these challenges together.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Prescribed fire isn’t going to be the one way that we’re going to be able to get out of this, it needs to be a variety of different factors,” Yamamoto said. “Whether or not we’re going to be able to start doing all of that before the whole forest burns down is something that’s on my mind.” </p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>It’s not just fire — it’s healing</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When he was around 10 years old, Yamamoto’s mother started taking him to burn bear grass for regalia and baskets. Those more positive experiences shaped the way he thinks about fire just as much as the negative impacts he has seen. “It’s always been a part of our culture,” Yamamoto said. “Always has been, always will be, but folks outside of it are just now starting to realize the importance of it.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2020, Silas Yamamoto’s family home burned down in the Slater fire, a devastating blaze that destroyed over 100 homes in his hometown of Happy Camp, California. The Slater fire was part of a <a href="https://www.ucdavis.edu/climate/news/californias-2020-wildfire-season-numbers">record-breaking fire season</a> in California that saw thousands of fires burn millions of acres across the state, leading to dozens of deaths and billions in damage. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yamamoto and his parents were forced to live out of a hotel room for over a month. After Red Cross money for the hotel ran out, they moved to a rental trailer that he says was way too small for three adults and their dogs. Yamamoto eventually moved out, renting a room from a local family. Yamamoto’s parents are still living in a trailer and have considered leaving the area completely. “It’s hard to live in an area that used to be so lush and green and beautiful that is now brush and standing matchsticks that will burn in the future,” he said. “It’s going to burn in the future. It’s just when.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These days, Yamamoto is constantly juggling a busy schedule — traveling across the country or quickly shifting gears from a meeting with Cal Fire to helping out with an <a href="https://www.hcn.org/issues/55-1/indigenous-affairs-wildfire-what-if-indigenous-women-ran-controlled-burns/">Indigenous Women-in-Fire Training Exchange</a> program or heading out on fire assignment somewhere in state. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Starting this fall, with funding from the US Fish and Wildlife Service, Yamamoto plans to lead a crew dedicated to prescribed burns in California, but they will also travel three months out of the year, learning from communities across the country. Yamamoto also hopes that his crew can bring an Indigenous perspective of cultural fire to areas that may be comfortable with fire but less familiar with an Indigenous approach to it. As fire risk and intensity increases, this kind of collaborative approach may be the key to surviving a more fiery world.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Fire is just a part of the natural order of things, and if you remove that for long periods of time, you get these devastating mega fires where absolutely everything is burned up,” Yamamoto said. “You can’t fight nature, and it’s pointless to try to fight something that we don’t fully control.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although fire has always been a part of Yamamoto’s life, Indigenous-controlled burns have <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/about-agency/features/tribal-and-indigenous-fire-tradition">steadily gained </a><a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/12/3/new-california-law-affirms-indigenous-right-to-controlled-burns">wider acknowledgment</a> in recent years. These practices work because they embrace the beneficial role that fire can have on plants and land. Prescribed burning can clear the landscape of fuels that might lead to larger and less controllable wildfires. Fire can also help <a href="https://www.uow.edu.au/media/2024/research-shows-indigenous-cultural-burning-promotes-soil-health-ecosystem.php">soil health</a> and <a href="https://esajournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ecs2.3851">seed germination</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But Indigenous fire has long been about more than just reducing the risk of a destructive wildfire.</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/ACullen_Happy-Camp-wildfires_07.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,32.549738219895,100,34.900523560209" alt="" title="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Silas Yamamoto poses for a portrait at the property where his mother and stepfather live in Happy Camp, California. Some of the family’s property and belongings burned during the Slater fire in 2020. | Andrew Cullen" data-portal-copyright="Andrew Cullen" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">“It’s not just fire,” said <a href="https://geog.ku.edu/people/melinda-adams">Melinda Adams</a>, a member of the N’dee San Carlos Apache Tribe and an assistant professor at the University of Kansas. Adams’s research focuses on cultural fire, particularly in California and the Midwest. “It’s healing a lot of trauma that our peoples went through, and healing the landscapes that have also gone through degradation and trauma.” </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For Indigenous people, cultural and community fire has always been a way of building a relationship with land and each other. “Not only are you tending to that space with fire, but then you&#8217;re coming back in and utilizing and having a relationship with that space because of the fire stewardship,” said <a href="https://www.csuchico.edu/geop/department/dhankins.shtml">Don Hankins</a>, a Miwkoʔ (Miwok) traditional cultural practitioner and a professor of geography and planning at California State University, Chico.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As climate change continues to threaten our way of life, Hankins says that these relationships will become even more essential. If you understand the land and the fact that you cannot control it, you are more likely to find ways of adapting to it, rather than trying to force it to adapt to you. Hankins says that Indigenous people have always embraced this kind of evolution, responding to different conditions in the climate.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So even as climate change and the legacy of fire suppression present new challenges, he believes Indigenous ways of thinking are ready to meet the moment. But that means that policymakers need to start listening to Indigenous people more.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Hankins is working to push for changes like recognizing the role of Indigenous stewardship and prescribed burning under the National Environmental Policy Act, the law that requires federal agencies to assess the environmental impacts of their actions, and the Endangered Species Act and Clean Air Act. These changes could make more space for Indigenous fire management, and pave the way for more resources and freedom for Indigenous fire practitioners. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One idea that Yamamoto is especially keen to get moving is cross-boundary burns. The Forest Service, for example, might start a burn on federal land that continues onto private land, where a partner organization like the Mid Klamath Watershed Council can take it over. But developing processes and systems to coordinate those projects requires a level of collaboration that is unfamiliar to some partners more used to operating on their own.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As land co-management agreements pop up between tribes and government agencies, Indigenous experts stress that while these partnerships are a good step, they only work if tribes are not treated as junior partners. “We will never achieve what we need to do at scale until everybody’s participating together,” Don Hankins said. “I think that’s a really important thing, but it has to be Indigenous-led.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To ensure that happens, Hankins, Yamamoto, and others are working to find the kind of scientific evidence that policymakers might find more convincing than generations of successful Indigenous stewardship. To do that successfully, Indigenous experts say a mindset shift is needed just as much as a policy shift. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“There’s definitely a lot of education that needs to happen with the public understanding the importance of Indigenous knowledges and not just conceptualizing them as a trope or as something that’s in the past,” Melinda Adams said. “This is something that’s going to save our planet.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Ian Millhiser</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[What can be done about this Supreme Court’s very worst decisions?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/366855/supreme-court-trump-immunity-betrayal-worst-decisions-anticanon" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366855</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T15:31:27Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-15T10:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Abortion" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Criminal Justice" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Gun Violence" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Student Loan Debt" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Supreme Court" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you solve a problem like Trump v. United States? The Supreme Court’s recent opinion in Trump, which held that presidents have sweeping immunity from criminal prosecution for any official act — even something like ordering the Justice Department to round up and arrest their political foes — is such an unimaginable betrayal of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="John Roberts greeting Donald Trump." data-caption="Chief Justice John Roberts and the man Roberts said was allowed to commit crimes. | Olivier Douliery/AFP via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Olivier Douliery/AFP via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1198669899_ea5cf4.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Chief Justice John Roberts and the man Roberts said was allowed to commit crimes. | Olivier Douliery/AFP via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">How do you solve a problem like <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-939_e2pg.pdf"><em>Trump v. United States</em></a>?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Supreme Court’s recent opinion in <em>Trump</em>, which held that presidents have <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">sweeping immunity from criminal prosecution</a> for any official act — even something like ordering the Justice Department to round up and arrest their political foes — is such an unimaginable betrayal of the justices’ oath to “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/28/453#:~:text=Each%20justice%20or%20judge%20of,that%20I%20will%20faithfully%20and">administer justice without respect to persons</a>” that it casts a shadow over every decision these justices have ever handed down.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s like if you learned that your daughter’s third-grade teacher gave her cocaine. Some acts of betrayal are so profound that they shatter your ability to trust someone again and cause you to rethink every single thing they’ve done in the past — even the good things.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under the <em>Trump </em>decision<em>, </em>a president who took advantage of the powers that decision grants would be the type of dictator the United States’ political structure is meant to guard against — a leader fully incompatible with the idea of constitutional democracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">That easily makes <em>Trump</em> the worst decision the Roberts Court has ever handed down, but it is only the latest in a series of decisions that weaken our democracy and our Constitution. In the few years since former President Donald Trump remade the Supreme Court, the Court’s new majority has allowed states to <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/7/25/23277211/supreme-court-gavin-newsom-sb-8-abortion-guns-california-assault-rifle-law">nullify entire constitutional rights</a>. They’ve claimed so much power that they now effectively <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">control both the judiciary and most of the executive branch</a> — they’ve literally <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/357900/supreme-court-loper-bright-raimondo-chevron-power-grab">given themselves a veto power</a> over any regulatory decision made by a federal agency — of the federal government. And as they’ve done so, they’ve thrown lower courts into chaos by <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/356267/supreme-court-us-rahimi-domestic-abuse-guns-second-amendmen">creating nonsensical new legal standards</a> judges across the nation have struggled to follow. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Worse, only one of America’s two major political parties appears to have a problem with how the Supreme Court is reshaping America’s institutions. While Republicans have mostly cheered the Court’s actions, top Democrats have proposed several solutions to the legal mess the Court has created.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the wake of the uniquely awful <em>Trump </em>decision, President Joe Biden <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/363557/supreme-court-biden-kamala-harris-reform-term-limits-ethics">proposed a constitutional amendment to eradicate <em>Trump</em></a>, along with separate proposals for term limits and a binding code of ethics for the justices. Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY), meanwhile, wants to use a rarely invoked congressional power known as “<a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/364438/supreme-court-chuck-schumer-trump-immunity">jurisdiction stripping</a>” to neutralize Trump’s immunity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Realistically, however, none of these ideas are likely to rein in the Court because they are unlikely to ever become fully enforceable law. Amending the Constitution is <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/364438/supreme-court-chuck-schumer-trump-immunity">virtually impossible</a>, and it is literally impossible if either major political party opposes an amendment. Even if some of these reforms can be enacted through ordinary legislation, moreover, the Court’s Republican majority would probably just strike them down anyway.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Another solution is court-packing — adding seats to the Supreme Court to relegate the Court’s Republicans to the minority. This idea has the virtue of being constitutional — the Court has had <a href="https://www.vox.com/23186373/supreme-court-packing-roe-wade-voting-rights-jurisdiction-stripping">as few as five seats and as many as 10 in the past</a> — and it could be done at any time through ordinary legislation. But it also comes with enormous risks. Packing the Court would almost certainly <a href="https://democracyjournal.org/magazine/51/lets-think-about-court-packing-2/">destroy the legitimacy of the federal judiciary</a> in the eyes of many Republicans and would lead to massive resistance from red states. It’s also unlikely to happen unless Democrats win massive majorities in Congress; even at the height of his popularity, President Franklin Roosevelt <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/10/30/20930662/pete-buttigieg-court-packing-anthony-kennedy-citizens-united">struggled to sell a court-packing plan</a> after the Court tried to sabotage the New Deal.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet, as the Republican Party has shown with its own successful takeover of the Court, there are steps that Democrats — and supporters of constitutional democracy more broadly — can take now to start undermining this Court’s worst decisions. The Republican takeover of the federal judiciary, and the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/7/8/23784320/supreme-court-2022-term-affirmative-action-religion-voting-rights-abortion">rush of decisions overruling seminal Supreme Court precedents</a> that quickly followed, was the culmination of decades of organizing, fixating on decisions that Republicans wanted to see overruled, campaigning against those decisions as illegitimate, and identifying candidates for judicial office who could be counted on to overrule those decisions.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Roe v. Wade</em>, for example, fell because the Republican Party unified around treating <em>Roe </em>as illegitimate. State lawmakers <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/25/23182753/roe-overturned-abortion-access-reproductive-rights-trigger-laws">routinely passed legislation defying it</a>, and forced the courts to strike that legislation down. These legal fights, in turn, reinforced the Republican Party’s identity as the anti-abortion party and reminded voters who oppose abortion that the way to end <em>Roe</em> was to vote for the GOP.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Similar things can be said about other Supreme Court precedents which until recently were good law, including the Court’s affirmative action decision in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/438/265/"><em>Regents of the University of California v. Bakke</em></a> (1978), its <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/12/2/21726876/supreme-court-religious-liberty-revolutionary-roman-catholic-diocese-cuomo-amy-coney-barrett">mostly overruled</a> decision establishing that religious conservatives have to follow the same laws as everyone else in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/494/872/"><em>Employment Division v. Smith</em></a> (1990), its church/state separation decision in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/403/602/"><em>Lemon v. Kurtzman</em></a> (1971), and its decision limiting the scope of the Court’s policymaking authority in <a href="https://supreme.justia.com/cases/federal/us/467/837/"><em>Chevron v. National Resources Defense Council</em></a> (1984).</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In all of these cases, the basic pattern is the same. Republicans — whether at the grassroots level or through elite <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/5/2/23706535/supreme-court-chevron-deference-loper-bright-raimondo">groups like the Federalist Society</a> — identified the cases they wanted to destroy. They united in opposition to them. They appointed justices who would loyally follow the GOP’s judicial agenda. And then they won.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This is a playbook those concerned about the current Court’s anti-democratic tendencies can follow, but it also requires them to unite much like Republicans did. Before they can get to that point, Democrats, and others concerned about the Court’s actions, need to reach a consensus about which of the Court’s decisions deserve the same treatment that the GOP gave to <em>Roe</em>.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several recent Supreme Court decisions arguably belong on this list of irredeemable decisions, but I would like to propose four. These four cases<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/12/14/22832257/supreme-court-gavin-newsom-abortion-guns-assault-weapons">undermine the very concept of a written constitution</a>. They <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">centralize power in an unelected judiciary</a>. They are <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/356267/supreme-court-us-rahimi-domestic-abuse-guns-second-amendmen">so incompetently drafted</a> that even sitting judges complain that they are unworkable. And they <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">invite rule by gangsters and thugs</a>. In short, all of them are fundamentally incompatible with constitutional democracy.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Trump v. United States</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-939_e2pg.pdf"><em>Trump v. United States</em></a> (2024) is the rare Supreme Court decision that grows more alarming as you dig deeper into the nuance of the decision.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The six Republican justices held that Trump, a man who <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2022/6/10/23162442/january-6-committee-hearing-june-10-trump-fascist">literally tried to overthrow the duly elected government of the United States</a>, had broad freedom to commit crimes while he was in office and that he would also be free to violate criminal laws if he returned to the White House. The Court’s holding that presidents may use their official powers to commit crimes has no basis in constitutional text or American legal tradition, and it’s hard to imagine a decision more incompatible with the idea that the United States is a democratic nation governed by the rule of law.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <em>Trump</em> decision breaks down presidential actions into three categories and gives <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/358292/supreme-court-trump-immunity-dictatorship">different levels of immunity to each</a>. The most important thing to understand about the opinion, however, is that it places some of the most authoritarian actions a president could possibly take in the category with the highest level of immunity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican justices held that when the president exercises authority vested exclusively in them by “the Constitution itself,” they may do so even if those actions are “incompatible with the expressed or implied will of Congress” — including an Act of Congress declaring such actions to be criminal. Similarly, the Republican justices concluded that “the courts have ‘no power to control [the President’s] discretion’ when he acts pursuant to the powers invested exclusively in him by the Constitution.” So a court cannot try a president who commits a crime while exercising these powers.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One reason why this decision is so alarming is that the Constitution states that “the President <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/constitution/articleii">shall be commander in chief</a> of the Army and Navy of the United States.” As Justice Sonia Sotomayor warned in dissent, “when [the president] uses his official powers in any way, under the majority’s reasoning, he now will be insulated from criminal prosecution. <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-939_e2pg.pdf">Orders the Navy’s Seal Team 6 to assassinate a political rival? Immune</a>. Organizes a military coup to hold onto power? Immune. Takes a bribe in exchange for a pardon? Immune. Immune, immune, immune.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In fairness, the majority opinion did not explicitly state that Trump could order Navy SEALs to assassinate his rivals — it only implied it — but it rather explicitly says that Trump could have ordered the Justice Department to round up and arrest those rivals. “Investigation and prosecutorial decisionmaking is ‘the special province of the Executive Branch,’” the Republican justices conclude, adding that “the Constitution vests the entirety of the executive power in the President.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Indeed, the Republican justices went even further, holding that Trump could not be prosecuted even if he ordered the Justice Department to act based on “shams” or “for an improper purpose.” Under <em>Trump</em>, that type of behavior does “not divest the President of exclusive authority over the investigative and prosecutorial functions of the Justice Department and its officials.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican justices’ decision does not even attempt to make the case that presidential immunity can be found anywhere in the Constitution. Instead, the opinion is rooted in the GOP justices’ policy judgment that the president should not be chilled from taking “bold and unhesitating action” by “<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/23pdf/23-939_e2pg.pdf">the threat of trial, judgment, and imprisonment</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this is why the <em>Trump </em>immunity decision is one of the most reckless decisions ever handed down by a court of the United States. It strongly suggests that a president can have their rivals killed, and it explicitly permits a president to round up their enemies and prosecute them on fabricated charges. And it does all of this in response to the prosecution against a former president who tried to illegally remain in office after he lost his bid for reelection.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Whole Woman’s Health v. Jackson</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/21-463_3ebh.pdf"><em>Whole Woman’s Health v. Jackson</em></a> (2021) established that any state can neutralize literally any constitutional right, simply by writing a law that is enforced solely by private bounty hunters.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While the law at issue in <em>Jackson</em>, a Texas law known as SB 8, targeted abortion rights, <em>Jackson</em>’s reasoning <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/7/25/23277211/supreme-court-gavin-newsom-sb-8-abortion-guns-california-assault-rifle-law">would apply equally</a> to a law allowing bounty hunters target anyone who criticizes a state governor, or that sics these bounty hunters on any Black family that sends their child to a majority-white public school.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Like the <em>Trump</em> immunity decision, <em>Jackson</em> is incompatible with constitutional democracy and must be overruled.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand <em>Jackson</em>, it’s important to first understand the <a href="https://www.vox.com/2021/8/31/22650303/supreme-court-abortion-texas-sb8-jackson-roe-wade-greg-abbott">Rube Goldberg-like mechanism</a> that SB 8 uses to ban nearly all abortions in the state of Texas. In <a href="https://caselaw.findlaw.com/court/us-supreme-court/209/123.html"><em>Ex parte Young</em></a> (1908), the Supreme Court established that a plaintiff alleging that a state law is unconstitutional should sue the state officer charged with enforcing that law. So, for example, if Texas had passed a law requiring state troopers to blockade abortion clinics, a plaintiff might sue the chief of the state’s police force.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">SB 8, however, provides that this anti-abortion law “<a href="https://legiscan.com/TX/text/SB8/2021">shall be enforced exclusively through … private civil actions</a>.” It provides that “any person, other than an officer or employee of a state or local governmental entity in this state” may bring a lawsuit against anyone who performs an abortion after the sixth week of pregnancy. Plaintiffs who prevail collect a bounty of at least $10,000 from the abortion provider, and there is no cap on the size of this bounty.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, the law sought to make an end run around <em>Young</em> by preventing state officials from directly enforcing the law. And five of the Supreme Court’s six Republicans signed onto this gambit, prohibiting anyone from filing a federal lawsuit seeking to block the law.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As Roberts, the only Republican to dissent in <em>Jackson</em>, said of the Texas law, “the clear purpose and actual effect of S. B. 8 has been to nullify this Court’s rulings” in <em>Roe</em> and <em>Casey</em> (<em>Jackson</em> was decided several months before the Supreme Court overruled those decisions). <em>Jackson</em> established that a state can effectively immunize an unconstitutional law from federal judicial review simply by using bounty hunters to enforce it.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In fairness, <em>Jackson</em> does allow someone who has already been sued by a bounty hunter to argue in that lawsuit that SB 8 is unconstitutional and that the suit should be shut down. But this remedy is meaningless because SB 8 also places no limit on the number of suits that could be filed against any one individual. A single person who is suspected of performing an abortion in Texas could potentially be hit by thousands of lawsuits. Even if they win all of them, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/7/25/23277211/supreme-court-gavin-newsom-sb-8-abortion-guns-california-assault-rifle-law">their legal bills would bankrupt them</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And, again, nothing in <em>Jackson</em> prevents other states from enacting SB 8-style laws to nullify any other constitutional right.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Jackson</em>, in other words, must be overruled because it is fundamentally hostile to the idea that states must respect the constitutional rights of individuals.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Biden v. Nebraska</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf"><em>Biden v. Nebraska</em></a><em> </em>(2023) involved a significant policy dispute between the Democratic and Republican parties. The Biden administration announced a new policy that would have <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">forgiven at least $10,000 worth of student loans for most borrowers</a>. Republicans almost universally opposed this policy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reasonable people can disagree about who was right about the wisdom of this policy. But there’s <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">no plausible argument</a> that the Biden administration’s policy was illegal. The loan forgiveness policy was authorized by a federal law known as the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/STATUTE-117/pdf/STATUTE-117-Pg904.pdf#page=1">Heroes Act</a>, which gives the US secretary of education the power to forgive student loans during a national crisis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, despite unambiguous statutory authorization, the six Republican justices decided to implement their party’s preferred student loan policy from the bench.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Under the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/STATUTE-117/pdf/STATUTE-117-Pg904.pdf#page=1">Heroes Act</a>, the education secretary has broad authority to “waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to the student financial assistance programs &#8230; as the Secretary deems necessary in connection with a war or other military operation or national emergency.” The Biden administration’s student loan program was one of many financial relief programs tied to the Covid-19 pandemic. Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2023/02/10/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-concerning-the-coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-pandemic-3/">declared the pandemic a national emergency in 2020</a>, and Biden left his declaration in place until mid-2023.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Several other provisions of the law, moreover, should have removed any doubt that the Secretary of Education, and not the Supreme Court, got to decide whether to forgive loans during the Covid pandemic.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Among other things, the Heroes Act waives a lengthy process known as “notice and comment” that federal agencies normally must undergo before changing a federal policy — allowing officials to prioritize quick and decisive action over following normal procedural rules. The law also provides that the secretary may dole out student loan relief <em>en masse</em> (“the Secretary is not required to exercise the waiver or modification authority under this section on a case-by-case basis”). And the law even contained a provision instructing courts not to interpret other federal statutes to limit the secretary’s authority unless that statute was “enacted with specific reference to” the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Thus, even if the Republican justices had been able to point to a statute that explicitly forbids the very same loan forgiveness program created by the Biden administration, courts were still required to uphold that program unless this hypothetical statute specifically stated that it overrides the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, all six Republican justices <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">reached the implausible conclusion</a> that the Heroes Act did not authorize the Biden administration’s student loan forgiveness program.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Perhaps recognizing that their statutory argument is weak, the same six Republicans also claimed that the program violates something called the “<a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">major questions doctrine</a>,” a doctrine that was recently invented by the Supreme Court, and that calls for courts to treat significant policy decisions by federal agencies with skepticism, unless that decision is unambiguously authorized by Congress. As the Court has described this doctrine, “<a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/pdf/12-1146.pdf">we expect Congress to speak clearly</a> if it wishes to assign to an agency decisions of vast ‘economic and political significance.’”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, even setting aside the fact that the major questions doctrine <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">appears nowhere in the Constitution or in any federal statute</a>, Congress spoke clearly when it enacted the Heroes Act. It gave the secretary broad authority. It waived procedural constraints on the secretary. It explicitly gave the secretary power to dole out relief to many borrowers at a time. And it forbade courts from reading any federal statute to limit the secretary’s authority unless that statute specifically mentioned the Heroes Act.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican justices, in other words, claimed the power to override both elected branches of government, even when no law or constitutional provision authorizes them to do so. That realignment of power — like the ones seen in <em>Trump</em> and <em>Jackson</em> — is not compatible with the American system of constitutional democracy.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><em>New York State Rifle &amp; Pistol Association v. Bruen</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At least on the surface, <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/20-843_7j80.pdf"><em>New York State Rifle &amp; Pistol Association v. Bruen</em></a> (2022), a Second Amendment decision that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/6/23/23180205/supreme-court-new-york-rifle-pistol-clarence-thomas-second-amendment-guns">cast a cloud of uncertainty over every single gun law in the United States</a>, has a greater claim to legitimacy than the other cases on this list. Unlike, say, the major questions doctrine, the Second Amendment is a real thing that actually can be found somewhere in the Constitution.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But <em>Bruen</em> is also a showcase of the Roberts Court’s arrogance and incompetence. The New York State gun law struck down by <em>Bruen</em>, which limited who could carry a gun in public, was <a href="https://www.vox.com/22745312/supreme-court-guns-second-amendment-nyc-bruen">108 years old</a> when it reached the Supreme Court. So, for more than a century, no court took issue with this law until the current crop of Republican justices suddenly claimed that they’d found a constitutional problem with it that every other judge in the last century had somehow missed.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The Republican justices’ decision in <em>Bruen</em>, moreover, is an unworkable mess. One federal judge, a Trump appointee, complained that “the Supreme Court has <a href="https://casetext.com/case/united-states-v-love-206">created mountains of work for district courts</a> that must now deal with <em>Bruen</em>-related arguments in nearly every criminal case in which a firearm is found.” Another judge wrote that <em>Bruen</em> is “<a href="https://s3.documentcloud.org/documents/23863670/reeves-order.pdf">filled with methodological flaws</a>.” In a 2024 opinion criticizing <em>Bruen</em>, Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson quoted a dozen lower court opinions <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/356267/supreme-court-us-rahimi-domestic-abuse-guns-second-amendmen">begging the Court to tell them how <em>Bruen</em> is supposed to work</a>. One of them warns that “courts, operating in good faith, are <a href="https://www.ca5.uscourts.gov/opinions/pub/22/22-60596-CR0.pdf">struggling at every stage of the <em>Bruen</em> inquiry</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Briefly, <em>Bruen</em> held that all gun laws are unconstitutional unless the government can “demonstrate that the regulation is consistent with this Nation’s <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/20-843_7j80.pdf">historical tradition of firearm regulation</a>.” As the lower courts’ confusion shows, no one seems to know what the hell that means.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Bruen</em> also casts special scorn on gun laws that seek to address “a general societal problem that has persisted since the 18th century” — like murder — if 18th-century lawmakers did not seek to solve that problem in the same way as modern-day legislatures.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Almost immediately after <em>Bruen</em> was decided, a federal appeals court declared, in <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/united-states-v-rahimi/"><em>United States v. Rahimi</em></a>, that a federal law prohibiting people subject to domestic violence restraining orders from possessing guns is unconstitutional. And the most astounding thing about this lower court decision is that <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/10/24/23914235/supreme-court-domestic-violence-abusers-gun-policy-us-rahimi">it was correctly decided under <em>Bruen</em></a>. Domestic violence, after all, existed in the 18th century. But no state made it a crime for a married person to beat their own spouse until 1871.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To its credit, the Supreme Court recognized in the <em>Rahimi</em> case that allowing people who are a violent threat to their own romantic partners to arm themselves is untenable, and it upheld the federal law at issue in that case. But <em>Rahimi </em>did nothing to clarify the incomprehensible legal rule announced in <em>Bruen</em>. Now, under <em>Rahimi</em>, “a court must ascertain whether the new law is <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/356267/supreme-court-us-rahimi-domestic-abuse-guns-second-amendmen">‘relevantly similar’ to laws that our tradition is understood to permit</a>” — again, whatever the hell that means.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This whole saga exposes a Republican Supreme Court majority that is <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/359206/supreme-court-incompetent-abortion-trump-immunity">simply terrible at their jobs</a>. Set aside the policy question of how much gun regulation should exist in the United States. The core job of the Supreme Court is to articulate legal rules that can be consistently applied by all of the thousands of judges in the United States. Yet, in <em>Bruen</em>, they failed at that task so miserably that judges from across the political spectrum complained that they simply could not figure out how <em>Bruen </em>is supposed to operate.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then, when confronted with those complaints, the Court doubled down on its vague appeal to “tradition” that no one can figure out.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The uncertain case of <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Having identified four of the least defensible decisions handed down by the Court’s current Republican majority, allow me to finish this essay by saying something controversial: I am unsure whether <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/21pdf/19-1392_6j37.pdf"><em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization</em></a> (2022), the decision overruling <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, belongs on the list of cases that are fundamentally hostile to constitutional democracy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">I say this, not because <em>Dobbs</em> was correctly decided, and not because I have a wavering commitment to abortion rights. Rather, I say it because <em>Dobbs</em> revealed an unfortunate truth about all constitutional rights. A Supreme Court decision protecting a particular right — whether it is the right to abortion, the <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/365418/supreme-court-first-amendment-donald-trump-thomas-alito-gorsuch">right to free speech</a>, or any other right — is only worth something as long as there are five justices who will uphold that decision. Once that majority is lost, the right disappears.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Worse, while a precedent like <em>Roe v. Wade</em> cannot protect abortion patients from the whims of the Supreme Court, it can lull them into a sense of false security.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One lesson we’ve learned since <em>Dobbs</em> is that the right to have an abortion <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/religion/fact-sheet/public-opinion-on-abortion/">enjoys overwhelming majority support</a> among US voters, even in some very red states. Fifty-nine percent of <a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23290714/kansas-abortion-referendum-primary-turnout-charts">Kansas voters decided to keep abortion legal</a> in a 2022 referendum. Abortion rights <a href="https://www.vox.com/2023/11/8/23952090/ohio-election-results-issue-1-abortion-virginia-kentucky-roe-dobbs">won by a 13-point margin in red Ohio</a>. In Gov. Ron DeSantis’s Florida, a new abortion rights ballot measure appears to be cruising to victory — a recent poll found that <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2024/05/20/arizona-florida-could-send-big-message-abortion-rights/">60 percent of Floridians</a> believe that the right to an abortion should be written explicitly into the state’s constitution. Only 20 percent oppose that position.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And yet, when <em>Roe</em> was still good law, many voters who support the right to choose nonetheless voted for Republicans like Donald Trump, who appointed three members of the <em>Dobbs</em> majority to the Supreme Court. <em>Roe</em> convinced many of these voters that abortion rights were safe, even though Republicans <a href="https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/whole-womans-health-v-cole/">only needed to replace one member</a> of the Court’s pro-abortion majority to eliminate <em>Roe</em> on the day that Trump was elected.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If two members of the <em>Dobbs</em> majority leave the Court tomorrow, to be immediately replaced by Biden appointees, then I would support overruling <em>Dobbs</em>. Among other things, such a decision would end the suffering of women who are being <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/3/12/23631278/supreme-court-abortion-texas-medically-necessary-sepsis-zurawski">forced to wait until their lives are in danger</a> before their red-state doctors are willing to risk jail time by terminating their pregnancy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But, realistically, clawing back the Court’s Republican majority will probably take years, or even decades. By that point, abortion may once again be legal throughout the United States — either because of state-by-state campaigns like the Ohio ballot initiative or because <a href="https://www.vox.com/20930358/codify-roe-wade-womens-health-protection-act-supreme-court-nancy-pelosi-democrats">Congress enacts legislation legalizing abortion in all 50 states</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In that world, it is far from clear that overruling <em>Dobbs</em> would help the cause of abortion rights. Again, as <em>Dobbs</em> itself shows, a Supreme Court precedent is a weak guarantor of fundamental rights. And, as Trump’s election shows, a Supreme Court decision protecting abortion rights can fool voters into thinking that it is safe to elect anti-abortion candidates.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Leaving <em>Dobbs</em> on the books, by contrast, could lead to a durable electoral majority that will lock out of power any party that attempts to take away the right to reproductive freedom. That’s a far more powerful safeguard against abortion bans than some rinky-dink court decision.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In any event, there is no need to resolve this question of whether <em>Dobbs</em> belongs on the same roll of dishonor as <em>Trump</em> or <em>Bruen</em> today. We will know a great deal more about how <em>Dobbs</em> has changed the political landscape after the 2024 election. And it is very likely that there will be several more elections before the Court’s current, Republican majority can be broken up.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Jessica Craig</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mpox never stopped spreading in Africa. Now it’s an international public health emergency. Again.]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/366903/mpox-monkeypox-africa-continental-emergency-drc-who-clade" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366903</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T19:29:09Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T19:26:57Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Infectious Disease" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Monkeypox" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Public Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Vaccines" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="World Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The World Health Organization has declared mpox an international public health emergency for the second time in two years as cases and deaths surge across several east and central African countries. The announcement comes one day after the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention declared mpox a continent-wide public health emergency. Although many countries [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A person holds out the backs of both hands, showing many bumps and mpox scars." data-caption="A patient with mpox in 1997 in the Democratic Republic of Congo. | CDC/Image Point FR/BSIP/Universal Images Group via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="CDC/Image Point FR/BSIP/Universal Images Group via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2163384885_eb3cde.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>A patient with mpox in 1997 in the Democratic Republic of Congo. | CDC/Image Point FR/BSIP/Universal Images Group via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">The World Health Organization has <a href="https://apnews.com/article/who-mpox-africa-health-emergency-cc9bdf31b49d06bec5efd44fb55d5e42" data-type="link" data-id="https://apnews.com/article/who-mpox-africa-health-emergency-cc9bdf31b49d06bec5efd44fb55d5e42">declared</a> mpox an international public health emergency for the second time in two years as cases and deaths surge across several east and central African countries. The announcement comes one day after the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention <a href="https://time.com/7010665/mpox-health-emergency-africa/">declared</a> mpox a continent-wide public health emergency.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although many countries outside of Africa rapidly contained an mpox pandemic that began <a href="https://www.vox.com/2022/7/25/23277404/worldwide-monkeypox-outbreak-2022">in 2022</a>, large outbreaks continued unabated in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in central Africa. Unfortunately, the strain circulating there is a deadlier version of the one that earlier made its way to the US and Europe. In recent months, this strain has spread from the DRC into four other east and central African nations.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mpox, previously known as monkeypox, is an infectious disease closely related to but much less severe than smallpox, and is suspected to originate in <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/about/index.html#:~:text=Monkeypox%20virus%20was%20discovered%20in,regions%20where%20mpox%20is%20endemic.">African rodents and non-human primates</a>. Mpox <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/if-sick/transmission.html">spreads</a> through close contact with an infected person, including from sexual and skin-to-skin-contact. Pregnant people can also pass the virus to their child during pregnancy and after birth. The most common <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/symptoms/index.html">symptom</a> of mpox is a blister-like rash that typically lasts for two to four weeks. Other symptoms include fever, fatigue, muscle aches, cough, and sore throat.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/monkeypox#:~:text=The%20monkeypox%20virus%20was%20discovered,occasionally%20from%20animals%20to%20people.">For decades</a>, mpox caused sporadic cases and outbreaks in Nigeria, the Democratic Republic of the Congo, and several&nbsp;other African countries.<strong> </strong>There are two <a href="https://www.niaid.nih.gov/diseases-conditions/mpox#:~:text=Mpxv%20virus%20variants%20are%20referred,Clade%20IIa%20and%20Clade%20IIb.">main strains</a> of mpox: <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/about/index.html">clade I</a>, which causes more severe illness and has historically been confined to central Africa, and clade II, which has historically caused infections in west Africa.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In <a href="https://www.who.int/europe/emergencies/situations/monkeypox">May 2022</a>, countries outside of Africa suddenly started recording mpox cases which were caused by the clade II type. That July, the World Health Organization declared the pandemic a public health emergency of international concern for the first time. By May 2023, more than <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/response/2022/world-map.html">100 countries</a> had recorded nearly 90,000 mpox cases and over <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/mpox">150 deaths</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fortunately, public health agencies around the world acted quickly to improve disease surveillance efforts, increasing awareness among high-risk populations, particularly men who have sex with men, and <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/monkeypox-response-in-europe">encouraging</a> safe sex practices. In the US and Europe, where there were just over 30,000 and 25,000 mpox cases respectively between May 2022 and May 2023, officials also disseminated over a <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/72/wr/mm7220a2.htm">million</a> vaccine doses. Consequently, mpox transmission in most countries quickly dwindled. In <a href="https://www.who.int/europe/emergencies/situations/monkeypox">May 2023</a>, the World Health Organization lifted the emergency status.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although at the time the World Health Organization no longer considered mpox an international health emergency, countries around the world continued to report cases. In June 2024, there were 175 cases reported across North, Central, and South America; 100 cases were reported in Europe, and 11 cases were reported in Southeast Asian countries, according to a <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20240812_mpox_external-sitrep_35.pdf?sfvrsn=62a5fea1_4&amp;download=true">situation report</a> published by the World Health Organization.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2024-DON522">outbreak</a> in the DRC remained particularly bad. Unlike in the rest of the world, the mpox strain causing infections in the DRC is the more severe <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20240812_mpox_external-sitrep_35.pdf?sfvrsn=62a5fea1_4&amp;download=true">clade I type</a>. As of May 2024, there have been <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2024-DON522">7,851</a> mpox cases and 384 deaths reported in the country.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding mpox</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-none">Vox diligently covered the outbreak of mpox, formerly known as monkeypox, back in 2022. Check out our previous work here:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23516469/2022-public-health-community-led-mpox-vaccine-peer" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/23516469/2022-public-health-community-led-mpox-vaccine-peer">One public health lesson from 2022 worth remembering</a><br></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23282687/monkeypox-centers-for-disease-control-covid-world-health-organization-lgbtq" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23282687/monkeypox-centers-for-disease-control-covid-world-health-organization-lgbtq">Monkeypox should have been easily controllable. How did we fail so badly?</a><br></li>



<li><a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2022/8/17/23298665/sex-monkeypox-sti-sexually-transmitted-spread-anal-oral-vaginal-condoms" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2022/8/17/23298665/sex-monkeypox-sti-sexually-transmitted-spread-anal-oral-vaginal-condoms">Anal and oral sex spread monkeypox. Let’s talk about it.</a></li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the past few months, the clade I mpox spread from the DRC to <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/08/1153141">four countries in east Africa</a> — Burundi, Kenya, Rwanda, and Uganda — which spurred concerns that a deadlier mpox pandemic might be on the horizon and triggered the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention and the World Health Organization to designate the ongoing mpox outbreaks as health emergencies.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Africa CDC is the public health <a href="https://africacdc.org/">agency</a> of the African Union, which represents 55 African states. It is the first time the agency has designated any outbreak a continental emergency.&nbsp;Other African countries are also facing resurging mpox outbreaks caused by the clade II virus. In May, there were a total of <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20240812_mpox_external-sitrep_35.pdf?sfvrsn=62a5fea1_4&amp;download=true">465</a> mpox cases documented across all African countries and in June there were 567, a 22 percent increase.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We declare today this public health emergency of continental security to mobilize our institutions, our collective will, and our resources to act swiftly and decisively,” said Africa CDC Director General Jean Kaseya in a press briefing Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But outbreak response efforts in the DRC and other African countries have once again been hamstrung by the same challenges health officials faced during previous outbreaks and pandemics, <a href="https://www.vox.com/22759707/covid-19-vaccine-gap-covax-rich-poor-countries-boosters">including Covid</a>: a lack of global solidarity and an unwillingness to share life-saving resources. While vaccine doses were rapidly disseminated in the US and Europe in 2022, vaccines are only now starting to trickle into the DRC. But even so, only a couple hundred thousand vaccines will be available for a population of more than <a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SP.POP.TOTL">100 million</a> people.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Slowly, national governments and multinational organizations such as the African Union are working to <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/2024/1/24/24048361/mpox-covid-outbreak-africa-cdc-public-health">improve</a> domestic public health infrastructure and technical capacity and to reduce dependency on donor countries. While Africa CDC’s unprecedented move to designate the mpox outbreaks a regional health emergency signals a continuation of these efforts, it is unclear if the designation will help spur the rapid influx of resources needed to respond to the mpox outbreaks.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Mpox origins and unknowns</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Mpox was first discovered in <a href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/monkeypox#:~:text=The%20monkeypox%20virus%20was%20discovered,occasionally%20from%20animals%20to%20people.">1958</a> in a colony of monkeys in a research facility in Denmark, and the first case of mpox in a human — a nine-month-old infant — was not documented until <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/about/index.html">1970</a> in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Researchers and physicians could <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2480792/pdf/bullwho00192-0028.pdf">not determine</a> exactly how the infant became infected; however, close contact with an infected monkey may have caused the infection. Small rodents, monkeys, and mammals <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/about/index.html">can pass</a> the virus on to humans but outbreaks typically take off when humans infect each other.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In 2005, additional mpox cases in humans were recorded in the DRC, and thousands of suspected cases have been reported every year since then. Since 2017, mpox has also caused frequent infections in Nigeria.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Although mpox has been around for a long time, there are still many unknowns about how the virus spreads and why it suddenly spread around the world in 2022. What researchers do know is that the virus has been rapidly mutating in recent years.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Interestingly and maybe worryingly, while most genetic mutations have no effect at all, some can cause viruses to become deadlier or more effective at spreading. When geneticists compared the 2022 mpox genome to a sample collected in 2017, they <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-023-02456-8">found</a> some <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2022/06/02/mutations-in-monkeypox-virus-explainer/">40</a> genetic <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41392-023-01675-2#Sec4">mutations</a> had occurred. Some researchers have <a href="https://theconversation.com/mpox-why-the-viruss-continued-rapid-mutation-since-the-2022-global-outbreak-remains-a-concern-228338">suggested</a> that these mutations have improved how easily the virus can spread from person to person, but it seems that there is no firm <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2022/06/02/mutations-in-monkeypox-virus-explainer/">consensus</a> yet.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In September 2023, an entirely new mpox clade I variant, tentatively called clade IB, was <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2024-DON522">discovered</a> in the DRC. The World Health Organization has not confirmed if the new variant causes more severe disease or can be spread more easily.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Rosamund Lewis, the mpox technical lead at the World Health Organization, posits that genetic mutations are not behind the sudden global surge of mpox. Instead, she suggests that the virus happened to start infecting new populations — sex workers and men who have sex with men — and that has in turn fueled wider transmission. Mpox is reminiscent of the origins of HIV, when <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3234451/#:~:text=Approximately%20one%20century%20ago%20in,the%20AIDS%20pandemic%20in%20humans.">chimpanzees</a> infected humans in southwestern Cameroon before taking firm <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/why-kinshasa-1920s-was-perfect-place-hiv-go-global-180952953/">root</a> in the booming urban center — and among the large sex worker population — of Kinshasa, the capital of the DRC.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Sexual transmission among adults may only be one of the main drivers of mpox transmission. In the DRC, some <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/forecast-outbreak-analytics/about/mpox-risk-assessment.html">70 percent</a> of mpox cases recorded this year were among children who were likely exposed through close contact with infected animals or household members who were infected.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">One of the biggest risk factors for severe mpox infection and <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(23)00273-8/fulltext">death</a> is preexisting <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/mpox/prevention/hiv.html">HIV infection</a>. Unfortunately, about <a href="https://www.afro.who.int/health-topics/hivaids#:~:text=There%20are%2025.6%20million%20people%20living%20with%20HIV%20in%20the%20African%20region.&amp;text=In%202022%2C%20about%20380%2C000%20people,AIDS%20related%20illness%20in%202022.">25.6 million</a> people in Africa have HIV, <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/363716/africa-hiv-aids-sub-saharan-progress">more</a> than any other region in the world,<strong> </strong>meaning many African nations may experience deadlier outbreaks than other parts of the world. The dual burden of mpox and HIV was also a major factor that prompted the Africa CDC to declare the mpox outbreaks a continental emergency, Kaseya explained.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>There is an mpox vaccine shortage. Will emergency designations help?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are at least two vaccines — <a href="https://www.fda.gov/vaccines-blood-biologics/jynneos">Jynneos</a>, also called <a href="https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/imvanex">Imvanex</a> in Europe, which is made by Danish company Bavarian Nordic, and <a href="https://www.precisionvaccinations.com/vaccines/lc16-kmb-mpox-smallpox-vaccine#:~:text=LC16%20is%20a%203rd%20generation,emergency%20investigational%20new%20drug%20program.">LC16</a>, which is manufactured by Japanese company KM Biologics — that are effective against mpox. The US Food and Drug Administration <a href="https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-first-live-non-replicating-vaccine-prevent-smallpox-and-monkeypox">approved </a>the Jynneos vaccine for use against smallpox and mpox in 2019.&nbsp;LC16 was developed for smallpox but is also effective against mpox.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">When the US and Europe started recording mpox cases in 2022, health officials quickly disseminated millions of doses of existing vaccines. For the first two years of the pandemic, however, no vaccines were available in the DRC.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The DRC, like most countries in Africa, <a href="https://africacdc.org/news-item/africa-calls-for-new-public-health-order/">does not have</a> the infrastructure to produce its own vaccines nor can it afford to pay for millions of doses. (The mpox vaccine costs just under $100 per dose, according to Kaseya; GDP per capita in the <a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.PCAP.CD?locations=CD">DRC is just $649</a>.) Thus, these countries must rely on donations from the US, Europe, and other countries. Following the Covid-19 pandemic, the Africa CDC started leading <a href="https://africacdc.org/news-item/africa-calls-for-new-public-health-order/">efforts</a> to fill this crucial gap, but progress has been slow.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In the void, officials in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and other African countries have been carrying on their outbreak responses without vaccines. It wasn’t until last month that the first shipments of mpox vaccines started arriving in the DRC. But the country received only 200,000 doses, according to Lewis, forcing personnel to cobble together a plan outlining how they will utilize such finite resources. Kaseya did not elaborate on how Africa CDC will aid in this process.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Donor governments have been providing technical and financial support for mpox outbreak responses in Africa. Last week, the US Agency for International Development, or USAID, announced that it will surge <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/aug-07-2024-united-states-announces-424-million-additional-assistance-democratic-republic-congo">$10 million</a> in funds to support the mpox response in DRC.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It remains unclear if the new emergency designations will have any impact on mpox vaccine availability. Still, the Africa CDC and World Health Organization are increasing financial resources for the mpox response.  Earlier this month, the African Union released <a href="https://africacdc.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Emergency-Approval-of-10.4-Million-to-Africa-CDC-for-Mpox-Outbreak-Respons.pdf">$10.4 million</a> in funds for the mpox response. The World Health Organization has promised <a href="https://news.un.org/en/story/2024/08/1153176">$1.45 million</a> in emergency funds, according to WHO Director-General Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus, with more to follow in the coming days.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is a fight for all Africans and we will fight it together,” Kaseya said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, August 14, 3:30 pm: </strong>This story, originally published August 13, has been updated with news of the WHO&#8217;s emergency declaration.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Nicole Narea</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The inflation crisis appears to be over. What happens next?]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/business-and-finance/367103/inflation-report-cpi-ppi-us-economy-fed-rate-cut" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367103</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T18:06:04Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T18:10:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Business &amp; Finance" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Economy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Money" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Policy" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Politics" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Economic data released this week suggests inflation is continuing to cool, paving the way for the Federal Reserve to lower interest rates, which would relieve some of the pressure high borrowing costs put on consumers and businesses.&#160; According to the July Consumer Price Index (CPI) report released Wednesday, year-over-year inflation dipped to 2.9 percent overall, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="People shop at a grocery store in Brooklyn on July 11, 2024, in New York City. Stocks rose on Thursday following a morning report by the Bureau of Labor Statistics showing that inflation eased more than expected in June. | Spencer Platt/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Spencer Platt/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2161665953.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>People shop at a grocery store in Brooklyn on July 11, 2024, in New York City. Stocks rose on Thursday following a morning report by the Bureau of Labor Statistics showing that inflation eased more than expected in June. | Spencer Platt/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Economic data released this week suggests inflation is continuing to cool, paving the way for the Federal Reserve to lower interest rates, which would relieve some of the pressure high borrowing costs put on consumers and businesses.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the July Consumer Price Index (CPI) report released Wednesday, year-over-year inflation dipped to 2.9 percent overall, lower than any month since March 2021. The CPI captures the change in prices of representative goods and services purchased by consumers compared to the same month in the previous year and is considered a standard measure of inflation. Though the report found costs associated with <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/livecoverage/cpi-report-for-july-inflation-expected-to-rise-again-after-last-month-s-surprise-fall/card/child-care-costs-keep-rising-faster-than-overall-prices-4wnNJD91W3xygHPTPbbU">child care</a> and <a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/livecoverage/cpi-report-for-july-inflation-expected-to-rise-again-after-last-month-s-surprise-fall/card/shelter-inflation-increase-disappointing-but-not-worrying-economists-say-UoGbmaBktFEPNbh6Jjyg">renting a home</a> continue to rise at a higher rate than prices overall, inflation has dropped significantly since its peak of 9.1 percent in June 2022, and it is now inching closer to the Fed’s 2 percent target rate. And if it were not for rental inflation, the overall inflation rate would be below that 2 percent target. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It follows another good day of data on Tuesday, when the latest Producer Price Index report, which measures the change in prices for goods and services sold by producers to retailers, indicated that wholesale inflation had also come down to 0.1 percent, on par with low pre-pandemic levels. High wholesale inflation can sometimes indicate that prices will rise for consumers because retailers have to recoup higher costs.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These numbers suggest a better economy for consumers, but the overall picture certainly isn’t perfect. The US only added <a href="https://apnews.com/article/economy-recession-jobs-unemployment-c7f1985b1ab3a7b781920c2693cd0438">114,000 jobs</a> in July, below expectations of about 150,000, and unemployment rose to 4.3 percent — higher than any month since October 2021.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">These numbers are not in and of themselves a crisis: The unemployment rate is still relatively low, and the underperformance in hiring isn’t catastrophic, but both have been taken as signals that the US economy might be showing some cracks.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>What low inflation means for the economy and interest rates</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This week’s news has many economists and finance experts arguing that the time has come for the US Federal Reserve — which sets interest rates, manages the money supply, and purchases assets as a steward of the US economy — should cut interest rates. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Today’s inflation data provides further support for aggressive Fed rate cuts beginning in September,” said Morningstar’s chief US economist Preston Caldwell.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">An interest rate cut would make it easier for consumers and businesses alike to pay off debt and borrow money. That could eventually improve hiring and lead to overall economic growth. But there’s some uncertainty about just how much a rate cut would help the overall economy.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Fed chair Jerome Powell has been making statements in the last month that left open the possibility the Fed will cut rates at its September 17 meeting without fully committing. “The overall sense of the committee … is that we&#8217;re getting closer to the point at which it will be appropriate to begin to dial back restriction. We&#8217;re not at the point yet,” he said on August 1. “We want to see more good data.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Caldwell said that Morningstar is projecting a 0.25 percent cut in September, rather than the 0.5 percent cut that other analysts are expecting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The urgency of cutting rates has increased in recent weeks given the troubling job numbers as well as a <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed">brief global stock market meltdown</a> linked to trading activity in Japan. Both were seen as signs the economy could use a little stimulation. But even lower interest rates might not immediately relieve the existing pressures on the economy.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is growing unease, among both financial analysts and consumers, that a recession is on the horizon. Caldwell said Morningstar is projecting a deceleration in economic activity in the next year. Some other analysts warn that the US economy could <a href="https://qz.com/ubs-ceo-sergio-ermotti-slowdown-1851621953">see a downturn</a> even without an official recession — which is defined as two straight quarters of negative economic growth. And there’s a question of how much Fed policy can actually avert that.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Consumer confidence also dipped in July, with <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/08/14/heres-why-the-economy-feels-recession-like-for-many-americans.html">3 in 5 Americans</a> falsely believing the US is already in a recession in a recent survey by Affirm. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The fundamentals of the economy are still relatively strong. As Matt Colyar, an economist at Moody’s Analytics, <a href="https://www.vox.com/money/365271/stocks-dow-nasdaq-recession-us-economy-fed">recently told me</a>, households and businesses have handled their debt relatively well, and hiring has remained solid for much longer than most people anticipated. But it might take a while before individuals struggling with inflation or to find jobs in a tough market feel the relief they’re looking for.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Dean Peterson</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How pit bulls got a bad reputation]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/videos/367080/how-pit-bulls-got-a-bad-reputation" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367080</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T17:57:26Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T18:00:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Video" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pit bulls are one of the most controversial and misunderstood dogs in America. They are subject to breed-specific legislation (BSL), which exists in over 700 US cities and communities. BSL refers to laws that restrict or ban ownership of dogs based on breeds, particularly pit bulls, due to their reputation for being dangerous and aggressive. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="" data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/VDC_XCL_030_pit_bulls_cleanThumb.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption></figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Pit bulls are one of the most controversial and misunderstood dogs in America. They are subject to breed-specific legislation (BSL), which exists in over 700 US cities and communities. BSL refers to laws that restrict or ban ownership of dogs based on breeds, particularly pit bulls, due to their reputation for being dangerous and aggressive.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Once regarded as great family dogs, pit bulls have been featured as the lovable sidekick in <em>The Little Rascals</em> and even appear in US patriotism campaigns. However, like many other dogs in American history, pit bulls have gone through cycles of stigmatization driven by both societal and cultural forces. Before pit bulls were demonized, the first dog that caused the public to panic was the Spitz — a pomeranian-like breed that’s now considered a “toy” dog. But back in the 19th century, they were called “venomous beasts” on the pages of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1876/11/17/archives/a-venomous-beast.html?searchResultPosition=1">the New York Times</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">So how did pit bulls go from family friend to national foe? We speak to Bronwen Dickey, the author of the book <a href="https://www.bronwendickey.com/book-1"><em>Pit Bull: The Battle Over an American Ico</em>n</a>, who was also <a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/23919628/dog-breed-bans-american-bully-xl-pit-bulls-rishi-sunak">interviewed</a> for an episode of <em>Today, Explained</em>. Dickey takes us through the history of their reputation, explains why the term “pit bull” is technically a misnomer, and shares how the stigma against pit bulls affects both dog owners and animal welfare.</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Aja Romano</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[How Raygun earned her spot — fair and square — as an Olympics breaker]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/367059/raygun-olympic-controversy-breaking-corruption" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=367059</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T18:57:33Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T17:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Explainers" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Internet Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Olympics" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Sports" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October 2023, members of the World DanceSport Federation, or WDSF, learned breaking, the sport they’d been trying to make happen at the Olympics for years, would not be appearing at the 2028 Los Angeles Games. In response, the organization’s president, Shawn Tay, made a grand proclamation. “Ensuring the success of breaking’s Olympic debut at [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Raygun, in a dark teal shirt, cap and pants, performs a “kangaroo hop” move in front of a panel of white-shirted Olympics breaking judges against a purple backdrop reading Paris 2024." data-caption="B-girl Raygun of Team Australia competes during the b-girls’ round robin at the Olympic Games Paris 2024. | Ezra Shaw/Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="Ezra Shaw/Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-2166052398.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>B-girl Raygun of Team Australia competes during the b-girls’ round robin at the Olympic Games Paris 2024. | Ezra Shaw/Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">In October 2023, members of the <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/">World DanceSport Federation</a>, or WDSF, learned breaking, the sport they’d been trying to make happen at the Olympics for years, would not be appearing at the 2028 Los Angeles Games.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In response, the organization’s president, Shawn Tay, made a grand proclamation. “Ensuring the success of breaking’s Olympic debut at Paris 2024 is therefore on the forefront of the WDSF agenda,” he <a href="https://www.insidethegames.biz/articles/1141612/breaking-world-dance-sport-los-angeles">said</a>. “Our performance in Paris will define the future of dance sport within the Olympic Movement.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">…Oops?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Going into the games, <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366017/breaking-olympic-sport-what-to-know">breaking had a lot riding</a> on its shoulders. But no one counted on Raygun — the newly infamous, 36-year-old, last-place Australian b-girl (as breakers are called) whose <a href="https://twitter.com/jwdaddy80/status/1822828281617666084">performance</a> on the Paris stage included bizarre floor-writhing, awkward freezes, and “original” moves like kangaroo hops.&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">my five year old niece after she says “watch this!” :  <a href="https://t.co/KBAMSkgltj">pic.twitter.com/KBAMSkgltj</a></p>&mdash; alex (@alex_abads) <a href="https://twitter.com/alex_abads/status/1821945716064821450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2024</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Raygun, real name Rachael Gunn, instantly became a viral sensation — notoriety that only skyrocketed when the public learned that Gunn, who won none of her Olympics battles, actually has a PhD in breakdancing. <a href="https://researchers.mq.edu.au/en/persons/rachael-gunn">Yes, really</a>. Gunn’s performance has not only overshadowed the two actual breaking gold medalists, Japan’s <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gfc_ami/">Yuasa Ami</a> and Canada’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qXMkP2zTXY0">Phil Wizard</a> (plus 16-year-old Australian b-boy <a href="https://www.instagram.com/j__attack/?">Jeff Dunne</a>), it’s arguably become the defining moment of a Parisian Games <a href="https://www.vox.com/sports/364856/olympics-boxing-imane-khelif-angela-carini">marked</a> by <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/08/12/sport/jordan-chiles-bronze-olympics-controversy-explained/index.html">controversy</a> and <a href="https://apnews.com/article/2024-olympics-seine-river-illness-02d937f2d5f0fd20efafbf2250264aea">absurdity</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But alongside widespread mockery of Gunn herself runs speculation that Gunn’s presence at the Games had to be some sort of mistake, even corruption. Surely, this couldn’t be the best Australia had to offer? How did Raygun wind up at the Olympics when, for example, last weekend in Melbourne a couple of b-girls were serving these moves?&nbsp;</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-instagram wp-block-embed-instagram"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="14"><div> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank"> <div> <div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div><div></div> <div></div><div> <div>View this post on Instagram</div></div><div></div> <div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div></div><div> <div></div> <div></div> <div></div></div></div> <div> <div></div> <div></div></div></a><p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-j58k_SuxM/?utm_source=ig_embed&#038;utm_campaign=loading" target="_blank">A post shared by Ayvee (@__ayvee__)</a></p></div></blockquote>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To answer this question, we have to go on a bit of a deep dive — so let’s (sorry) hop on in.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Reports Raygun manipulated her way into the Olympics couldn’t be further from the truth…</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For decades, the WDSF was <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366017/breaking-olympic-sport-what-to-know">devoted to ballroom dancing</a>. The association started in the late ’90s with a focus on winning a place in the Olympics for ballroom dancing before its subsequent pivot, around 2017, toward breaking. A quizzical backstory, yes — but it doesn’t make the organization less legitimate. <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/Officials/Te-Hiiritanga-Robert-Wepiha-5ea90df8-2e8b-4bc4-adfe-ae66008749d0">Te Hiiritanga Wepiha</a>, a.k.a. Rush, one of the judges in the women’s breaking final for the Oceania championship Gunn won, posted a 90-minute livestreamed <a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/C-nA98kS4lL/?igsh=eWJuNTltMXZseW40">Instagram commentary</a> on Tuesday in response to the controversy. He pointed out that the WDSF judging system, used in the Olympics and its breaking qualifiers, requires judges to be veterans in the breaking scene, both as competitors and as judges, as well as to pass multiple exams. “You have to be trained to be a judge,” he insisted. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">This wasn’t Gunn’s first rodeo either. Prior to her Olympics appearance, she represented Australia at multiple World Championship competitions between 2021 and 2023. She <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--hnj1cNLL4">judged</a> Red Bull’s preeminent BC One breaking contest. She’s an established local champ.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet following Gunn’s appearance at the Olympics, a <a href="https://www.change.org/p/hold-raygun-rachel-gunn-anna-mears-accountable-for-unethical-conduct-olympic-selection">petition</a> circulated claiming, without sources, that Gunn and her husband, breaking coach Samuel Free, had manipulated the entire WDSF system in order to gain a spot at the Olympics. The petition falsely claimed Gunn had judged herself at the qualifying Oceania championship competition — despite the judges’ list for the event being <a href="https://www.worlddancesport.org/Competitions/Officials/Oceania-Championship-Sydney-Adult-Breaking-1vs1-B-Girls-60318">readily available</a> on the WDSF website.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other rumors further <a href="https://twitter.com/CLouvres/status/1823211157014085981">alleged</a>, again without any apparent sourcing, that Gunn and her husband were the masterminds behind the Australian Breaking Association, better known as <a href="https://ausbreak.org/">AUSBreaking</a> — another <a href="https://www.acnc.gov.au/charity/charities/582aa363-5afb-e911-a811-000d3ad1f29c/people">easily debunked</a> claim. An AUSBreaking spokesperson further confirmed to Vox in an email that Gunn and her husband did not found the organization. Gunn doesn’t appear to be directly responsible for managing, or funding, any breaking group, which likely also negates the petition’s claim that she denied travel funding to a marginalized dance crew from Australia’s Northern Territory.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>…But that doesn’t mean it’s easy to understand how she got there</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The subtext of this criticism — that Gunn benefited from her whiteness — has merit. Gunn was educated at one of Sydney’s most elite high schools; she had the opportunity to get a PhD in an obscure field, and the wealth to fund appearances at international breaking competitions. Her white privilege in a dance scene rife with cultural appropriation makes her an easy target for criticism. At the same time, some have tried to argue she represents exactly the opposite — a “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iudBeuoA2RA">diversity hire</a>” and Australian “<a href="https://twitter.com/ConceptualJames/status/1823012007324385763">wokeness</a>” gone wrong. “People have jumped on and used her as the new scapegoat to further their cause,” Wepiha observed in his livestream.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“We never thought this would happen,” he told me. “She’s getting torn down by a lot of people.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Still, while the rest of the world has put Gunn through the ringer since her Paris appearance, the actual breaking community seems to have <a href="https://www.ktiv.com/2024/08/12/breaking-community-defends-b-girl-raygun-breaking-is-all-about-originality-bringing-something-new-table/">rallied</a> behind her.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“This is what happens when people outside of our dance want to control the narrative but have absolutely no expertise of technical knowledge on our dance, particularly in an Oceania context,” Dujon Cullingford, a veteran New Zealand breaker who attended the Oceania qualifiers, told me. Cullingford <a href="https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=10160560771447967&amp;id=536182966&amp;mibextid=WC7FNe&amp;rdid=HzSLKjOFKIwxikNK">wrote a Facebook post</a> arguing against the idea Gunn benefited from any factor besides a small talent pool.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He emphasized that Oceania’s breaking community is tiny; one of Gunn’s own <a href="https://research-management.mq.edu.au/ws/portalfiles/portal/338493337/Publisher_version.pdf">articles</a> placed the number of Australian breakers at around 400, total, and Wepiha claimed the WDSF had to “get people out of retirement in order to make up the numbers” of competitors. One of the main criticisms being bandied about concerns a public <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MorhA98eK7M&amp;lc=Ugxxry-kM60vXoyI98V4AaABAg">perception</a> that the WDSF must not have been promoting their events among “real” breaking scenes, but rather elitist communities like universities. But both Cullingford and Wepiha rejected this idea. “It’s very easy to know if there’s a jam on because the scene is tiny,” Wepiha said.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Down here, like other countries, we feel the squeeze of cost of living, and the breaking scene is small so it doesn&#8217;t produce a lot of people who have time to teach, lead crews, and mobilize the community in the same way,” Cullingford said.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">He noted that, further diminishing the small talent pool, many breakers chose not to compete in the Olympics qualifiers because they didn’t want to shell out the cash needed to travel to the competition in Sydney last November. Additionally, many breakers simply had no interest in participating due to the feeling that the efforts of the establishment to rope breaking into the rigid organizational structure of the Games was antithetical to street dance culture. According to Wepiha, many dancers felt informal jams are more expressive with less strict judging — the kind of breaking they want to do, as opposed to Olympic-level battling.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And then there was Raygun.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“She rocked up like everybody else,” Wepiha said in his livestream regarding Gunn’s Oceania qualifier. “She won fair and square.” He pointed out that of the 10 judges at the event, only one was white and none were Australian — a fact AUSBreaking also confirmed to Vox. “She won by majority decision, she battled like everyone else … it’s not that deep.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You can judge for yourself: in the Oceania Championships Raygun won which secured her spot in the Olympics, she netted 51 overall points to 50 scored by her opponent Holy Molly (Molly Chapman). The crucial final points came in this battle when the pair faced off, with Raygun winning two of three rounds.</p>

<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div><div><iframe title="RAYGUN VS MOLLY | FINAL BGIRL | WDSF OCEANIA BREAKING CHAMPIONSHIPS 2023" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MorhA98eK7M?rel=0" allowfullscreen allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share;"></iframe></div></div>
</div></figure>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Since Gunn became a viral sensation, many people have watched this battle and claimed that Molly was the clear winner, but it’s not so simple. For one thing, these judges had seen their overall performances throughout the competition. If Molly was recycling moves from previous battles while Raygun kept things unique, the judges probably would have favored Raygun. Other factors to keep in mind include things like who was more on beat, which dancer spent more time on floor moves as opposed to the transitional dance moves called toprock, whose movements were stronger and more fluid, whose moves were crisper and more precise, and whose transitions were more interesting.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Prior to this, both Chapman and Gunn competed in the World Championships in Belgium in September 2023. While neither of them qualified then, out of 80 competitors, Gunn <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/culture/celebrity/the-inside-story-of-how-raygun-broke-into-the-olympics-20240812-p5k1mg.html">ranked</a> 64th — a full 15 slots ahead of Chapman, who came in next to last.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">All of this means, despite the viral narrative that’s attached to her, it isn’t as simple as writing Gunn’s Olympics entrance off as a hilarious fluke or a mark of privileged corruption. Indeed,&nbsp;according to Gunn, she intended to bring a style of movement to the Paris Games that was less about meeting expectations and more about making an indelible impact.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“What I wanted to do was come out here and do something new and different and creative — that’s my strength, my creativity,” Gunn <a href="https://www.espn.com/olympics/story/_/id/40798973/paris-2024-olympics-raygun-fails-fire-breakdancing-breaking-debut">told ESPN</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“I was never going to beat these girls on what they do best, the dynamic and the power moves, so I wanted to move differently, be artistic and creative because how many chances do you get … in a lifetime to do that.”</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Score by score, Raygun’s dancing isn’t actually that bad. Really.</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Gunn has been reflecting on what her style is for some time. In one of her academic articles on breaking, she <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/305519064_Don't_Worry_it's_Just_a_Girl_Negotiating_and_Challenging_Gendered_Assumptions_in_Sydney's_Breakdancing_Scene">argues</a>, “Gender norms both articulate and limit my corporeal potential.” Gunn has also written about what she sees as the dance’s “normative construction” of masculinity.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, the weirdness of Gunn’s dance … might be the whole point. Moreover, in more informal breaking venues, it’s not even that weird. “What Raygun showcased at the Olympics is that breaking is a spectrum,” Wepiha said in his livestream. He argued her style represents that more informal, self-expressive side of street dance. “She went up there and did what a lot of you complaining could never do. She was her authentic self.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You may well ask: But don’t we have to hold Olympians to a higher standard of excellence? Even if that excellence is forged from a masculinist construction of athleticism and dance?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Well… do we? There’s every indication Gunn is currently the most famous b-girl in the world, and while most people are laughing at her, not with her, somewhere in the wide vast world of breaking, other b-girls may feel inspired rather than shamed and mortified.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">After all, even by the Olympic standards, Gunn didn’t do that badly. If you look at the <a href="https://olympics.com/en/paris-2024/results/breaking/b-girls/gpb-000200--">judges’ scoring</a>, for example, of her battle with US breaker Logistx, you can see that while she nabbed zero rounds, a handful of judges had her beating Logistx in some subcategories, usually originality. Meanwhile, while Logistx won most categories, she typically<em> </em>only won by a few percentage points at best.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">In other words, Gunn arguably held her own at the Olympics under a once-in-a-lifetime amount of pressure, and she did it while trying out her own unique style.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Was it great? No. Was it bad? Evidently not as bad as we thought.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The ambiguity leaves us with a mess; many (though certainly <a href="https://x.com/wrong_speak/status/1823002717905711398">not all</a>) of the people heaping criticism upon Gunn are people who barely knew what breaking was a fortnight ago, while many of the people rushing to defend her are breaking veterans. In between are the people who just want to meme. The situation has some Australian breakers <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/article/2024/aug/14/raygun-breaking-paris-olympics-australian-dance-industry">worried</a> the backlash will drive away sponsors and support — which, Wepiha told me, was already a concern given the lack of government funding for breaking as an art form.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">As for Gunn, “Above all she’s a human being,” Wepiha said. “We first and foremost just hope that she’s all right.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Yet if there’s one thing we know about breaking, it’s that it takes a lot more than ridicule to, well, break it.&nbsp;</p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Kyndall Cunningham</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The It Ends With Us drama is the new Don’t Worry Darling drama]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/366523/blake-lively-drama-justin-baldoni-it-ends-with-us-hoover-movie-feud" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366523</id>
			<updated>2024-08-14T13:55:13Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T13:50:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Celebrity Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Culture" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Movies" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You might have seen previews or even bought tickets for the new film adaptation of Colleen Hoover’s best-selling romance novel It Ends With Us, starring Blake Lively. But have you heard about the online soap opera surrounding a rumored rift among the film’s cast, its director and co-star Justin Baldoni, and possibly Deadpool?&#160;Once again, a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="Brandon Sklenar, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds, from left to right, against a background of bright pink letters reading It Ends With Us." data-caption="Brandon Sklenar, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds attend the It Ends With Us New York premiere on August 6, 2024." data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165608450.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>Brandon Sklenar, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds attend the It Ends With Us New York premiere on August 6, 2024.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">You might have seen previews or even bought tickets for the new film adaptation of Colleen Hoover’s best-selling romance novel <em>It Ends With Us</em>, starring Blake Lively. But have you heard about the online soap opera surrounding a rumored rift among the film’s cast, its director and co-star Justin Baldoni, and possibly Deadpool?&nbsp;Once again, a film’s press tour is already stirring up more conversation than the movie itself.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The week leading up to the <em>It Ends With Us</em> premiere is already bringing back memories of the weeks-long, <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-features/chris-pine-harry-styles-spit-gate-dont-worry-darling-memes-1235338698/">spit-covered</a> scandal surrounding <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2022/9/6/23339631/dont-worry-darling-wilde-pugh-feud-explained"><em>Don’t Worry Darling</em></a> in 2022. In fact, it seems like the excitement of that previous drama has incited social media users to pull out their Sherlock caps and magnifying glasses. So far, any concrete details about this supposed on-set drama are sparse. Nor has anyone from <em>It Ends With Us</em> commented on the gossip directly. But the internet is still having a ball speculating.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It all started with <em>It Ends With Us</em>’s New York premiere on August 6, when fans noticed that Lively and Baldoni hadn’t been photographed on the red carpet together, nor have they been paired for interviews. Initially all signs of trouble pointed to Baldoni, but the narrative began to shift when a <a href="https://www.eonline.com/news/1405851/blake-lively-reveals-ryan-reynolds-wrote-iconic-it-ends-with-us-scene">quote</a> from Lively about her husband Ryan Reynolds’s involvement in the film’s script went viral. And on Friday, insiders <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/movies/movie-news/blake-lively-justin-baldoni-it-ends-with-us-drama-what-we-know-1235969708/">confirmed</a> to the Hollywood Reporter that there was a power struggle between the two parties when it came to the film’s final cut. At the same time, remarks from Baldoni <a href="https://x.com/people/status/1821568076267085985">praising Lively</a>, while also hinting at a creative overhaul, are coming out. Most recently, Baldoni <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/08/it-ends-with-us-justin-baldoni-melissa-nathan-blake-lively-1236039853/">hired</a> crisis publicist Melissa Nathan, who represented Johnny Depp during his <a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/23043519/johnny-depp-amber-heard-defamation-trial-fairfax-county-domestic-abuse-violence-me-too">highly publicized defamation trial</a> in 2022. </p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Despite any PR manager’s recent attempts to smooth out drama, the internet has already made up its mind. It’s maybe not surprising that this has turned into yet another game of optics and who has the most goodwill online. It speaks to the quick, sometimes dangerous escalation of gossip in the post-Deuxmoi world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>Who is Justin Baldoni — and does his cast hate him?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Before we get into whether the<em> It Ends With Us</em> cast hates Baldoni, some information about the actor-turned-director. You might recognize Baldoni from the hit CW <em>Jane the Virgin</em> where he played Rafael, the hunky father of Jane’s child. In 2019, he co-founded the production company Wayfarer Studios with billionaire entrepreneur Steve Sarowitz. Baldoni has directed and produced a few movies under his Wayfarer banner, including the teen cancer romance <em>Five Feet Apart</em> in 2019 and the 2020 Disney+ musical drama <em>Clouds</em>. In 2022, it was reported that Sarowitz <a href="https://variety.com/2022/film/news/wayfarer-studios-125-million-investment-justin-baldoni-steve-sarowitz-1235295142/">invested $125 million</a> into the independent production company.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Even with all this power, you might still be wondering why this fairly new director was selected to helm such a massive IP about a woman’s experience with domestic abuse.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The answer seems to partially lie in his extracurricular work. As a vocal feminist ally, discussing women’s issues — or more accurately, men’s issues — has been a huge, if not defining, part of Baldoni’s brand. In 2017, the actor launched a panel series called <em>Man Enough</em> through Wayfarer, featuring actors Matt McGorry and Javier Munoz, exploring, in his words, “what it means to be a man.” In 2021, he published a memoir titled <a href="https://manenough.com/podcast/"><em>Man Enough? Undefining My Masculinity</em></a> about his journey overcoming the expectations of traditional manhood. He later launched a podcast of the same name with co-hosts Jamey Heath and former Vox political correspondent Liz Plank. Like McGorry, he’s one of several self-identifying male feminists who emerged during the Trump era and gained both praise for their activism and criticism for a <a href="https://pittnews.com/article/130284/opinions/editorial-justin-baldonis-feminism-male-focused/">male-centered</a>, “<a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/iexplorer/woke-bae-day">mansplain-y</a>” approach to that activism.&nbsp;</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-800668332.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,9.3509154173848,100,81.29816916523" alt="Actor Justin Baldoni speaks into a microphone, wearing a gray suit and white shirt, in front of a red-curtain backdrop." title="Actor Justin Baldoni speaks into a microphone, wearing a gray suit and white shirt, in front of a red-curtain backdrop." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Actor Justin Baldoni speaks onstage at the 2017 NALIP Latino Media Awards. | Phillip Faraone/Getty Images for NALIP" data-portal-copyright="Phillip Faraone/Getty Images for NALIP" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Nevertheless, it seems appropriate that Baldoni would go after Hoover’s novel about domestic abuse. After he sent Hoover a <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/it-ends-with-us-author-colleen-hoover-says-justin-baldoni-struggled-a-little-bit-with-idea-of-playing-ryle-184652889.html">letter</a> about his love for the book, his production company <a href="https://variety.com/2019/film/news/justin-baldoni-it-ends-with-us-movie-jane-the-virgin-1203268293/">optioned the project</a> in 2019. Blake Lively was brought on as an executive producer in 2017, and from there, the project seemed to descend into chaos.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Throughout the press tour, Baldoni has been noticeably isolated not just from Lively but the entire main cast, <a href="https://deadline.com/gallery/it-ends-with-us-premiere-red-carpet-photos/it-ends-with-us-new-york-premiere-arrivals/">posing by himself</a> on the red carpet (or with other people not involved in the film) and <a href="https://youtu.be/nc-wVlkAGGA?feature=shared">giving</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/niSOhLp-jdE?feature=shared">solo</a> <a href="https://youtu.be/dpD9OEzZFZc?feature=shared">interviews</a>. His co-host Plank was also at the premiere but was not photographed with Baldoni. Baldoni and Plank did not immediately respond to Vox’s requests for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Meanwhile, Lively has been doing press with her co-stars Jenny Slate and Brandon Sklenar and author Colleen Hoover. When Lively and Sklenar appeared on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8DrE3Ih46Y0"><em>CBS Mornings</em></a> to promote the film, as well as other media outlets, there was no mention of the director. A <a href="https://x.com/camis_unicorn/status/1821272044866039992">video of Slate</a> at the premiere sparked further speculation, when she gave an indirect response to a reporter’s question about working with Baldoni as a boss and screen partner. Lively and Slate did not immediately respond to Vox’s requests for comment.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The cast’s Instagram activity doesn’t look great for Baldoni either. Based on quick searches, it looks like none of the main cast — aside from comedian Hasan Minhaj, who has a supporting role — are following him on the platform. Slate also made a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-V5m85yUhl/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link&amp;igsh=MzRlODBiNWFlZA==">post</a> on Instagram earlier this week, shouting out Lively with no acknowledgement of Baldoni. The director is also absent from Sklenar’s <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C93CsR8yDi6/?hl=en&amp;img_index=2">recent</a><em> It Ends With Us</em> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C8aMoXDyT4x/?hl=en&amp;img_index=2">posts</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong>How is Deadpool involved in this?&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Reynolds’s supposed involvement in this scandal went from confusion to outrage. A claim from Lively that her husband wrote the movie’s “iconic rooftop scene” at the premiere began to circulate. “He works on everything I do,&#8221; Lively told <a href="https://www.eonline.com/news/1405851/blake-lively-reveals-ryan-reynolds-wrote-iconic-it-ends-with-us-scene">E! News</a>. “I work on everything he does. So his wins, his celebrations are mine, and mine are his. He’s all over this film.”&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">People began to theorize that Lively and Reynolds seized creative control of the film from Baldoni, which led to the rift — although, that wouldn’t exactly explain why the rest of the cast has seemingly distanced themselves from him. At the premiere, Baldoni also made a telling comment about Lively. When asked about directing <em>It Ends With Us</em>’s inevitable sequel, he <a href="https://people.com/justin-baldoni-blake-lively-direct-it-ends-with-us-sequel-8693095">said</a>, “I think that there are better people for that one. I think Blake Lively’s ready to direct, that’s what I think.”</p>
<img src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/GettyImages-2165630299.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,10.732984293194,100,78.534031413613" alt="Actors Hugh Jackman, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds, from left to right, stand in front of a promotional backdrop." title="Actors Hugh Jackman, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds, from left to right, stand in front of a promotional backdrop." data-has-syndication-rights="1" data-caption="Actors Hugh Jackman, Blake Lively, and Ryan Reynolds attend the&lt;em&gt; It Ends With Us&lt;/em&gt; New York premiere on August 6, 2024. " data-portal-copyright="" />
<p class="has-text-align-none">Lively’s comments about Reynolds set off a wave of <a href="https://x.com/valyonce/status/1821731891537703305">accusations</a> that Reynolds was <a href="https://x.com/stonelovebot/status/1821670994748026882">too</a> <a href="https://x.com/choneybuttr/status/1821635870493163742">involved</a> in Lively’s career. It also sparked discourse on whether the pair were appropriately promoting a film about domestic violence.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Based on their combined marketing efforts, it seems that Lively and Reynolds were looking to create their own “Barbenheimer” with the closely timed releases of <em>Deadpool vs. Wolverine</em> and <em>It Ends With Us</em> this summer. Leading up to the premiere, Blake Lively and her husband’s co-star Hugh Jackman covered <em>Vogue</em>. Jackman also made a cameo at the <em>It Ends With Us</em> premiere, while Reynolds filmed a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/C-VeN9WJhmG/?hl=en">skit</a> where he pretended to interview Sklenar for the film. Lively also released her new hair care line, <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/lifestyle/shopping/blake-lively-haircare-brand-blake-brown-beauty-launch-date-pricing-collection-1235963366/">Blake Brown</a>, during the movie’s press run, a move some <a href="https://x.com/gnuyear/status/1821706923596525866">online</a> <a href="https://x.com/SailorSammy93/status/1821521540606828950">critics</a> found insensitive given the film’s subject matter.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none"><strong><em>Don’t Worry, Darling</em></strong><strong> is written all over this scandal&nbsp;</strong></h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s fair to say that the <em>Don’t Worry, Darling</em> kerfuffle both destroyed our brains and heightened our thirst for this kind of behind-the-scenes drama. It’s hardly the first time that the rumors of hostility between co-stars have made headlines, especially on <a href="https://www.buzzfeed.com/ellendurney/jamie-dornan-dakota-johnson-friendship-update-fifty-shades">high-profile romantic films</a>, although, typically, they do not cause this much of a hullabaloo. The specific players involved in the <em>Don’t Worry, Darling</em> fiasco — namely, director Olivia Wilde, her ex-fiancé Jason Sudeikis, and her co-star Harry Styles — seemed to color everyone’s assessments of who was guilty and who was innocent, to the point where the internet was supporting <a href="https://variety.com/2022/film/news/shia-labeouf-denies-fired-olivia-wilde-dont-worry-darling-1235350529/">claims</a> about Wilde made by alleged abuser <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/11/arts/music/fka-twigs-shia-labeouf-abuse.html">Shia LaBeouf</a>. Social media’s perceptions of the people and relationships involved seemed to matter more than whatever actually occurred on-set.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">You could argue that is happening with the suspicion toward Lively and Reynolds, but for perhaps more legitimate reasons than Wilde dumping Ted Lasso. Despite their power in Hollywood, Lively and Reynolds don’t have a ton of goodwill on social media — mainly for their controversial plantation wedding in 2012 that they eventually <a href="https://www.eonline.com/news/1185191/a-look-at-blake-lively-and-ryan-reynolds-deeply-controversial-wedding">apologized for in 2020</a>. (There was also that <a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/10/13/6969341/blake-lively-preserve-slavery-antebellum">weird write-up</a> celebrating antebellum fashion on Lively’s now-defunct lifestyle website Preserve.)&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">At the same time, the internet — although, certainly not <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/08/deadpool-wolverine-global-box-office-milestone-mcu-top-10-1236033748/">moviegoers</a> — has seemingly had enough of Reynolds’s snarky take on Deadpool. There’s also the couple’s highly documented friendship with <a href="https://www.usmagazine.com/celebrity-news/pictures/taylor-swifts-friendship-with-blake-lively-ryan-reynolds-pics/">Taylor Swift</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Whether we’ll actually get to the bottom of Baldoni and Lively’s alleged issues, the internet has already taken sides. As with <em>Don’t Worry Darling</em>, we’ll probably end up discovering that there are no winners in this whole mess.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em><strong>Update, August 14, 9:50 am ET:&nbsp;</strong>This story was originally published on August 9 and has been updated to include Baldoni’s hiring of publicist Melissa Nathan.</em></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
			<entry>
			
			<author>
				<name>Sam Delgado</name>
			</author>
			
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[The youth mental health crisis is hitting LGBTQ+ teens hardest]]></title>
			<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect/366899/youth-teen-mental-health-crisis-lgbtq" />
			<id>https://www.vox.com/?p=366899</id>
			<updated>2024-08-13T23:38:25Z</updated>
			<published>2024-08-14T12:30:00Z</published>
			<category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Future Perfect" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="LGBTQ" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Life" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="Mental Health" /><category scheme="https://www.vox.com" term="The Future of the Mind" />
							<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) released a report on their 2023 Youth Risk Behavior Survey (YRBS). The report includes data on a wide range of health-related behaviors of high school students in the United States, and breaks down these behaviors across different demographics. The results underscore the fact that we’re [&#8230;]]]></summary>
			
							<content type="html">
											<![CDATA[

						
<figure>

<img alt="A hand raising the Philadelphia Pride Flag and the Rainbow Pride Flag. In the background is a classroom full of adults." data-caption="People raise pride flags to support the book Gender Queer, a graphic novel about a nonbinary teen, at a school board meeting in 2022. | H. Rick Bamman/Pioneer Press/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-portal-copyright="H. Rick Bamman/Pioneer Press/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2024/08/gettyimages-1255159872.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" />
	<figcaption>People raise pride flags to support the book Gender Queer, a graphic novel about a nonbinary teen, at a school board meeting in 2022. | H. Rick Bamman/Pioneer Press/Chicago Tribune/Tribune News Service via Getty Images</figcaption>
</figure>
<p class="has-text-align-none">Last week, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) released a report on their <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/yrbs/dstr/index.html">2023 Youth Risk Behavior Survey</a> (YRBS). The report includes data on a wide range of health-related behaviors of high school students in the United States, and breaks down these behaviors across different demographics. The results underscore the fact that we’re in the middle of a youth mental health crisis that has been <a href="https://www.apa.org/monitor/2023/01/trends-improving-youth-mental-health">steadily worsening for years</a> — one that is particularly acute for LGBTQ+ youth.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">According to the report, 41 percent of LGBTQ+ teens seriously considered suicide during the previous 12 months, 32 percent made a plan to do so, and 20 percent attempted to end their own life. By comparison, 13 percent of cisgender and heterosexual students seriously considered suicide, 11 percent made a plan, and 6 percent attempted suicide.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While LGBTQ+ representation and rights have improved in the last few decades, large swaths of queer and trans kids are still living in an environment that is deeply hostile to their very existence. There’s a long and ongoing <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/9/1/23853694/war-on-woke-wokeness-republicans">conservative culture war</a> that aims to reverse what progress has been made in recent years for the LGBTQ+ community, culminating in legislation and policies that harm LGBTQ+ youth, like <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/23631262/trans-bills-republican-state-legislatures">restricting gender-affirming health care</a>, forcing schools <a href="https://www.lgbtmap.org/equality-maps/youth/forced_outing">to out queer and trans students</a> to their parents, and <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/report-lgbtq-content-drove-book-banning-efforts-2023/story?id=108992375">banning books</a> that have LGBTQ+ content.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To understand how we can help bring down these stark mental health disparities for LGBTQ+ teens, it’s critical that we first look at the overall youth mental health crisis, and the unique challenge that LGBTQ+ teens are facing on top of it.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">The state of youth mental health</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s never been easy to be a teenager, but today’s youth are clearly facing a mental health crisis. Suicide <a href="https://www.nami.org/about-mental-illness/mental-health-by-the-numbers/">is one of the leading causes</a> of death for teens in the United States. They’re more <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/childrensmentalhealth/data.html">depressed and anxious</a>. And it’s only been getting worse since the early 2010s.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">For the 2023 report, which is conducted every other year, over 20,000 questionnaires were filled out by students from 155 schools across the US. The CDC researchers found that while some improvements have been made for youth health and well-being, largely all other mental health indicators worsened.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">We shouldn’t overlook the small glimmers of hope, though. Hispanic youth who made a plan to kill themselves dropped from 19 percent in 2021 to 16 percent in 2023. And in that same time period, Black students who attempted suicide dropped from 14 percent to 10 percent.</p>

<div class="wp-block-vox-media-highlight vox-media-highlight">
<h5 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">Worried about a child or teen’s mental well-being? Here are some online resources to learn more about symptoms, treatment strategies, and how to help.</h5>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://effectivechildtherapy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Effective Child Therapy</a> is a resource from the Society of Clinical Child and Adolescent Psychology. The website has information on the emotional concerns, symptoms, and disorders that commonly impact teens (divorce, bullying, body image, anxiety, depression, and more) — and the evidence-based therapies that can help.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.aacap.org/AACAP/Families_and_Youth/Resource_Centers/Home.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry</a> has information for parents on how to spot symptoms of mental health issues, and where to seek help.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.mghclaycenter.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Clay Center for Young Healthy Minds</a> has educational articles on mental health issues, as well as many links for <a href="https://www.mghclaycenter.org/where-to-turn/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">where to turn</a> when searching for particular support groups, programs, and therapies.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.crisistextline.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Crisis Text Line</a> is a text messaging-based service for people enduring “any type of crisis.” And the <a href="http://www.suicidepreventionlifeline.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Suicide Prevention Lifeline</a> is a phone-based service.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.thetrevorproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Trevor Project</a> is a crisis helpline for LGBTQ+ youth. It can be reached at 1-866-488-7386.</li>
</ul>
</div>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But for LGBTQ+ youth — which the report indicated had higher rates of suicidality than all other groups —&nbsp; there just isn’t enough comparable data yet to show a trend over time in the YRBS. 2015 was the first year that the CDC started measuring sexuality as a demographic, but it only included lesbian, gay, and bisexual as options to pick from. In 2021, they adjusted that to include students who were questioning their sexuality. Only this most recent report now includes transgender students. Because of these changes in measurement, it will take years for us to get a more accurate picture of how LGBTQ+ mental health is faring.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">And while the report gives us a lot of helpful information, it doesn’t give us data for youth who hold multiple identities, like LGBTQ+ youth of color — who face unique challenges of their own.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Queer youth of color, trans youth of color, are dealing with stigma tied to not just being queer and youth of color, but also the intersecting stigma of both,” said <a href="https://ehe.osu.edu/human-sciences/directory?id=mallory.102">Allen Mallory</a>, an assistant professor of human development at Ohio State University. Navigating the intersection of these identities can be stressors for LGBTQ+ teens of color, Mallory says.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There is no one singular force to blame for why teens are suffering from poor mental health and suicidal thoughts, but researchers have some hypotheses. A <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2024/05/09/smartphone-social-media-mental-health-teens/">big debate</a> in youth mental health is the use of social media and smartphones, with <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-gray-area/353979/this-is-your-kid-on-smartphones">some researchers</a> pointing to these digital tools as a major driver in worsening trends. But <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-00902-2">other experts argue</a> that phones and social media are not the driving force behind declining mental health for youth — and have pointed out that for kids who lack connection in real life, finding community online is a real solace.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The developmental collision</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It might seem surprising that LGBTQ+ youth mental health appears to be worsening even as the social atmosphere on LGBTQ+ rights has <a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/1651/gay-lesbian-rights.aspx">largely improved in recent decades</a>. So why hasn’t that translated to improved mental health?</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The apparent paradox may have an explanation. Broader acceptance of LGBTQ+ people has allowed for more visibility and for people to come out as queer or trans at younger ages. That means instead of coming out as a young adult or even later on, kids are coming out in early adolescence.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">But that particular period of human development — being a teenager — is a heightened time of self-consciousness and peer regulation, especially for precisely those younger teens who are also in the process of coming out. <a href="https://he.utexas.edu/component/cobalt/item/14-human-ecology/2391-russell-stephen?Itemid=1481">Stephen Russell</a>, a professor and director of University of Texas at Austin’s School of Human Ecology, calls this “<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6786797/">developmental collision</a>.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“Kids are coming out right at this time that, developmentally, is the most they’re most attuned to regulating each other,” says Russell. For LGBTQ+ youth, this period of peer regulation can mean facing bullying and discrimination from their classmates on the basis of their sexuality or gender — a unique challenge that comes on top of typical teenage challenges. (Staying in the closet isn’t a solution, either. Kids deserve to be their authentic selves, not shamed into hiding.)</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“The dynamic of coming out at a younger age in these times elicits and invites and creates the possibility for wonderful things, but also for stigma and other kinds of vulnerability,” he added.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">Other bigger, structural and environmental issues play a part in this mental health crisis. From <a href="https://www.apa.org/pubs/reports/climate-change-mental-health-children-2023">climate change</a> to growing <a href="https://www.vox.com/gun-violence-shootings">gun violence</a>, finding safety and stability — crucial for mental and physical well-being — has taken a toll. The Covid-19 pandemic, in which <a href="https://www.covidcollaborative.us/initiatives/hidden-pain">over 200,000 kids under 18 lost a parent or caregiver</a> as of 2022, can’t be ruled out either. And <a href="https://www.vox.com/politics/2023/9/1/23853694/war-on-woke-wokeness-republicans">a culture war on “wokeness,”</a> raised by conservative politicians and pundits, has aimed to reinvigorate animosity toward youth of color<em> </em>and LGBTQ+ teens.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">To be clear, the fault is not on these teenagers for going through basic developmental periods, or for being LGBTQ+, or for struggling with big issues. What it does mean is that LGBTQ+ youth are facing unique challenges that must be recognized when creating and implementing interventions for their mental health.</p>

<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-none">How to help LGBTQ+ youth</h2>

<p class="has-text-align-none">The field of LGBTQ+ youth mental health is still evolving, and along with it, how to approach the subject from a clinical and public health perspective. But there are a lot of promising interventions to tackle this crisis.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">From a more macro perspective, implementing practices that reach people in their day-to-day life is key. For teens, a big part of everyday life involves school. One simple (and almost painfully obvious) practice to start with is inclusive, enumerated policies for LGBTQ+ youth — basically, protection from bullying and discrimination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These policies we see at the state and school district level have really big implications for how LGBTQ youth experience school in their day to day life,” said <a href="https://sph.umd.edu/people/jessica-fish">Jessica Fish</a>, an associate professor and the director of the <a href="https://sph.umd.edu/research-impact/laboratories-projects-and-programs/sexual-orientation-gender-identity-and-health-sogi-health-research-group#:~:text=LGBTQ%20Young%20People-,The%20Sexual%20Orientation%2C%20Gender%20Identity%2C%20and%20Health%20(SOGI%20Health,of%20Maryland%20Prevention%20Research%20Center.">Sexual Orientation, Gender Identity, and Health Research Group</a> at University of Maryland’s School of Public Health.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><a href="https://storiesandnumbers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/StoriesandNumbersReport_English.pdf">Multiple</a> studies <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6555145/">have shown</a> that LGBTQ+ students at schools with <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/health_and_academics/bullying/anti_bullying_policies_infobrief-basic.htm">inclusive, enumerated policies</a> experience less victimization and bullying — two things that can really impact a kid’s mental health. But according to the <a href="https://www.lgbtmap.org/equality-maps/safe_school_laws">Movement Advancement Project</a>, a nonprofit think tank focused on equality and democracy,<strong> </strong>53 percent of LGBTQ+ people live in a state with no law protecting LGBTQ+ students from bullying in school, and 42 percent live in a state with no law protecting these teens from discrimination.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">If tackling state law feels too big, starting with an individual school community can work too. Take gender and sexuality alliances (GSAs, formerly known as gay-straight alliances). They’re student-led clubs that give LGBTQ+ and allied students a way to connect, support one another, and learn from each other. All of the public health experts I spoke to brought up GSAs — and there’s a lot of strong evidence that shows these groups can create a safer school climate and <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0044118X20951045">lower the risk of suicide and depression</a>.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">While researchers<strong> </strong>have a lot of good information on what’s working for improving the mental health of LGBTQ+ youth, there’s still a lot of room for more data. This is especially true when it comes to understanding what works for trans youth and LGBTQ+ youth of color.&nbsp;</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">It’s also important to note that while there is absolutely a mental health crisis for LGBTQ+ youth, many go on to become content, productive adults. It’s not their identity that sentences them to depression or suicide — it’s the stigma and discrimination they face in their homes, schools, and institutions, at a time when their age makes them deeply vulnerable and reliant on their surroundings.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">There are many barriers to getting clinical help or implementing measures in schools. Understandably, that can feel like an uphill battle for LGBTQ+ youth and their families. But nothing is impossible, says Fish.</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none">“These are things that will take mobilization, that will take a large degree of advocacy and grassroots support within the community,” she told me. “So I do think all of these are possible, but I think it&#8217;s just trying to figure out where the vantage point for change is.”</p>

<p class="has-text-align-none"><em>A version of this story originally appeared in the&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/future-perfect"><em><strong>Future Perfect</strong></em></a><em>&nbsp;newsletter.&nbsp;</em><a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/future-perfect-newsletter-signup"><em><strong>Sign up here!</strong></em></a></p>
						]]>
									</content>
			
					</entry>
	</feed>
